<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82366</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82366</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>NCTE_Scoilnet</catalog>
            <entry>4351</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Getting started on the wordprocessor</string>
            <string language="es">Los comienzos con el procesador de textos</string>
            <string language="ga">Ag tosú ar an bpróiseálaí focal</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erhalten begonnen auf dem Wortprozessor</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Obtenir commencé sur le traitement de texte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Começar começado no wordprocessor</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ottenere iniziato sul wordprocessor</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Να πάρει αρχισμένος στον επεξεργαστή κειμένου</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This exercise is interesting to read thus it will not be boring to type. It introduces the student to the DEL and BACKSPACE key. The cursor movement keys are learnt as are the RETURN and SPACEBAR. Therefore by the end of this exercise the students will have typed ,learnt how to delete and know how to move around the screen. All these are essential before the teacher can progress any further on the word-processing course for LCAP.</string>
            <string language="es">Es interesante leer este ejercicio para que teclear no resulte aburrido. Introduce al estudiante las teclas Supr. y la tecla de RETROCESO. Las teclas de movimiento del cursor se aprenden con las de CAMBIO DE LÍNEA y el ESPACIADOR. Por lo tanto, al final d</string>
            <string language="ga">Tá an cheacht seo suimiúil le léamh mar sin ní bheidh sé leadránach le clóscríobh. Cuireann sé cnaipí DEL agus BACKSPACE faoi bhráid na ndaltaí. Foghlaimítear gluaiseacht na n-eochracha chomh maith le RETURN agus SPACEBAR. Mar sin, beidh na daltaí tar éis</string>
          </description>
          <language>en</language>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">LCA</string>
            <string language="es">LCA. Hoja de trabajo</string>
            <string language="ga">ATF</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Worksheet</string>
            <string language="ga">Bileog Oibre</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Übung ist interessant, ihn folglich zu 
lesen wird nicht bohren, um zu schreiben. Sie stellt den 
Kursteilnehmer zur DEL und Rücktaste vor. Die Cursorbewegung 
Tasten werden erlernt, wie die RÜCKKEHR und die LEERTASTE. 
Folglich Ende dieser Übung haben die Kursteilnehmer 
geschrieben, erlernt, wie man löscht und kann um den Bildschirm 
bewegen. Alles sind diese wesentlich, bevor der Lehrer irgendwie
weiterkommen, kann auf dem Textverarbeitungskurs für LCAP zu 
fördern.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cet exercice est intéressant pour le lire ainsi 
n'alésera pas pour taper. Il présente l'étudiant à la touche
de DEL et de RAPPEL ARRIÈRE. Les clés de mouvement de curseur 
sont apprises de même que le RETOUR et la BARRE D'ESPACE. Par 
conséquent vers la fin de cet exercice les étudiants auront tapé, 
appris comment effacer et savoir se déplacer autour de l'écran. 
Tout ce sont essentiels avant que le professeur puisse 
progresser  pour promouvoir sur le cours de traitement de texte pour 
LCAP.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este exercício é interessante lê-lo assim não 
estará furando para datilografar. Introduz o estudante à chave
de DEL e de RETROCESSO. As chaves do movimento do cursor são 
aprendidas como são o RETORNO e a BARRA ESPAÇADORA. 
Conseqüentemente para o fim deste exercício os estudantes 
terão datilografado, aprendido como suprimir e saber mover-se em 
torno da tela. Todo o estes são essenciais antes que o 
professor possa progredir  para promover no curso de processo de texto
para LCAP.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa esercitazione è interessante da leggerlo 
così non aleserà per digitare. Introduce l'allievo al tasto di
RITORNO e di DEL. I tasti del movimento del cursore sono 
imparati come sono il RITORNO e la BARRA SPAZIATRICE. Di 
conseguenza per la fine di questa esercitazione gli allievi avranno 
digitato, imparato come cancellare e sapere muoversi intorno allo 
schermo. Tutto questi sono essenziali prima che l'insegnante 
possa progredire affatto per avanzare sul corso elaborato a parole per
LCAP.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η άσκηση είναι ενδιαφέρουσα να διαβάσει ότι 
έτσι δεν θα είναι τρυπώντας για να δακτυλογραφήσει. Εισάγει
το σπουδαστή στο πλήκτρο DEL και ΟΠΙΣΘΟΔΙΑΣΤΗΜΑΤΩΝ. Τα 
πλήκτρα μετακίνησης δρομέων μαθαίνονται όπως είναι η ΕΠΙΣΤΡΟΦΗ 
και το ΠΛΗΚΤΡΟ ΔΙΑΣΤΉΜΑΤΟΣ. Επομένως μέχρι το τέλος αυτής 
της άσκησης οι σπουδαστές θα έχουν δακτυλογραφήσει, μαθημένος 
πώς να διαγράψουν και να ξέρουν πώς να κινηθούν γύρω από την 
οθόνη. Όλα αυτά είναι ουσιαστικά προτού να μπορέσει ο 
δάσκαλος να προχωρήσει περαιτέρω στη σειρά μαθημάτων 
επεξεργασίας κειμένου για LCAP.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">LCA</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bogen</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">LCA</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Tableau</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">LCA</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Folha</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">LCA</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Foglio di lavoro</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">LCA</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Φύλλο εργασίας</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>NCTE_Scoilnet</catalog>
            <entry>4351</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE)
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE)
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE)
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <language>en</language>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">16-18</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>open activity</value>
          </learningResourceType>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The content on this site is protected by copyright under Irish and European law. All materials may be downloaded and copied for non-commercial purposes only, provided that the source is acknowledged. The reproduction of material for commercial purposes is strictly prohibited.

Material within the linked sites outside of Scoilnet may also have copyright restrictions and this should be checked on these websites should you plan to use their content in any way.</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE)
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE)
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE)
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Cleary;John;
FN:John Cleary
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>1369</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>652</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82366</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://test.scoilnet.ie/Res/johncleary060899220810_2.html</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
