<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/79553</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>79553</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/ammatilliset_kielet/potilashuone/eimg/index.html</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/ammatilliset_kielet/potilashuone/eimg/index.html</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/ammatilliset_kielet/potilashuone/eimg/index.html</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Hospital Room</string>
            <string language="fi">Hospital Room</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Krankenhaus-Raum</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pièce D'Hôpital</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quarto Do Hospital</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Stanza Dell'Ospedale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δωμάτιο νοσοκομείων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sitio Del Hospital</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A learning object for professional language learning.
The object forms a learning path of its own, in which the idea is to approach the topic step by step. First the language learner is introduced to the words through pictures, then dives into the rich spoken language and does various things under the guidance of a native speaker. After this, s/he practises the same language material (vocabulary and structures) in various ways through the aid of different types of tasks.
In the interactive state (Step 2) the learner has to filter the vocabulary and structural tips that are important to him/her from a native speaker’s substantial linguistic material. If the learner does not grasp the guide’s speech straightaway in the first listening session, the learner can listen to the section as many times as s/he considers necessary. The core of the object paths is for the learner to have to continuously react to the guide’s encouragements and requests (functioning ability).</string>
            <string language="fi">Oppimisaihio ammatilliseen kielenoppimiseen.
Aihio muodostaa oman oppimispolkunsa, jossa ideana on, että aihepiiriä lähestytään askel askeleelta. Ensin kielen oppija tutustuu sanoihin kuvien kautta, sukeltaa sitten rikkaaseen puhuttuun kieleen ja tekee erilaisia asioita syntyperäisen puhujan opastamana. Tämän jälkeen samaa kieliainesta (sanastoa ja rakenteita) harjoitetaan monipuolisesti erilaisten tehtävätyyppien avulla.
Interaktiivisessa tilassa (Vaihe / Step 2) oppija joutuu suodattamaan äidinkielisen puhujan runsaasta kielellisestä aineksesta hänelle tärkeät sanastolliset ja rakenteelliset vihjeet. Mikäli opastajan puhe ei aukea heti ensimmäisellä kuuntelukerralla, kohtaa voi kuunnella niin monta kertaa kuin tarpeelliseksi katsoo. Aihiopolkujen ydin on, että oppija joutuu jatkuvasti reagoimaan opastajan kehotuksiin ja pyyntöihin (toiminnallisuus).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="fi">sairaala,</string>
            <string language="fi">sanastot:</string>
            <string language="fi">virtuaalikoulu</string>
            <string language="en">sanastot:</string>
            <string language="en">sairaala</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine erlernennachricht für professionelle 
Sprachenlearning.The Nachricht bildet einen erlernenpfad von seinen 
Selbst, in denen die Idee ist, sich dem Thema Schritt für Schritt zu 
nähern. Zuerst wird der Sprachenanfänger zu den Wörtern durch
Abbildungen eingeführt, dann taucht in die reiche gesprochene Sprache
und tut verschiedene Sachen unter der Anleitung eines 
Muttersprachlers. Nach diesem übt s/he das gleiche 
Sprachenmaterial (Wortschatz und Strukturen) in den verschiedenen 
Methoden durch das Hilfsmittel der unterschiedlichen Typen von 
tasks.In der interaktive Zustand (Jobstep 2) der Anfänger muß den 
Wortschatz und die strukturellen Spitzen filtern, die zu him/her von 
einem gebürtige speaker?s erheblichen linguistischen Material wichtig
sind. Wenn der Anfänger nicht die guide?s Rede faßt, die in 
der ersten hörenden Sitzung straightaway ist, kann der Anfänger zum 
Kapitel hören bis zu Male, s/he notwendig betrachtet. Der Kern 
der Nachricht Pfade ist, damit der Anfänger ununterbrochen zu den 
guide?s Ermutigungen und zu den Anträgen (arbeitende Fähigkeit) 
reagieren muß.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un objet d'étude pour l'objet professionnel du 
langage learning.The forme une voie d'accès d'étude de ses propres, 
dans lesquels l'idée est d'approcher le sujet point par point. 
D'abord l'étudiant de langage est présenté aux mots par des 
images, puis plonge dans le langage parlé riche et fait de diverses 
choses sous les conseils d'un naturel. Après ceci, s/he 
pratique le même matériel de langage (vocabulaire et structures) 
dans diverses voies par l'aide de différents types de tasks.In 
l'état interactif (étape 2) l'étudiant doit filtrer le vocabulaire 
et les extrémités structurales qui sont importants pour him/her d'un
matériel linguistique substantiel de speaker?s indigènes. Si 
l'étudiant ne saisit pas le discours de guide?s straightaway en la 
première session d'écoute, l'étudiant peut écouter la section 
autant de fois pendant que s/he considère nécessaire. Le noyau
des voies d'accès d'objet est pour que l'étudiant doive sans 
interruption réagir aux encouragements de guide?s et aux demandes 
(capacités de fonctionnement).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um objeto de aprendizagem para o objeto 
profissional da língua learning.The dá forma a um trajeto de 
aprendizagem do seus próprios, em que a idéia é aproximar a etapa 
do tópico pela etapa. Primeiramente o learner de língua é 
introduzido às palavras através dos retratos, então mergulha na 
língua falada rica e faz várias coisas sob a orientação de um 
altofalante nativo. Após este, s/he pratica o mesmo material da
língua (vocabulário e estruturas) em várias maneiras através do 
dae (dispositivo automático de entrada) de tipos diferentes de 
tasks.In o estado interativo (etapa 2) o learner tem que filtrar o 
vocabulário e as pontas estruturais que são importantes para him/her
de um material lingüístico substancial dos speaker?s nativos. 
Se o learner não agarrar o discurso dos guide?s straightaway na
primeira sessão escutando, o learner pode escutar a seção tantas 
como vezes enquanto s/he considera necessário. O núcleo dos 
trajetos do objeto é para que o learner tenha que continuamente 
reagir aos incentivos dos guide?s e aos pedidos (abilidade 
funcionando).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un oggetto imparante per l'oggetto professionale 
di linguaggio learning.The forma un percorso imparante dei relativi 
propri, in cui l'idea è avvicinarsi al soggetto per gradi. In 
primo luogo lo studente di lingue è introdotto alle parole attraverso
le immagini, allora si tuffa nel linguaggio parlato ricco e fa le 
varie cose sotto il consiglio di un indigeno. Dopo questo, s/he 
si esercita nello stesso materiale di linguaggio (vocabolario e 
strutture) in vari modi attraverso il sussidio dei tipi differenti di 
tasks.In che il interattivi dichiarano (punto 2) il principiante 
deve filtrare il vocabolario e le punte strutturali che sono 
importanti a him/her da un materiale linguistico notevole degli 
speaker?s natali. Se il principiante non afferra il discorso dei
guide?s straightaway nella prima sessione ascoltante, il principiante 
può ascoltare la sezione altretante volte mentre s/he considera 
necessario. Il nucleo dei percorsi dell'oggetto è affinchè il 
principiante debba continuamente reagire agli incoraggiamenti dei 
guide?s ed alle richieste (abilità di funzionamento).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα αντικείμενο εκμάθησης για την επαγγελματική 
εκμάθηση γλωσσών Το αντικείμενο διαμορφώνει ένα μονοπάτι 
εκμάθησης δικού του, στο οποίο η ιδέα είναι να προσεγγιστεί το 
θέμα βαθμιαία. Πρώτα ο γλωσσικός αρχάριος εισάγεται στις 
λέξεις μέσω των εικόνων, κατόπιν βουτά σε πλούσια προφορική 
γλώσσα και κάνει τα διάφορα πράγματα κάτω από την καθοδήγηση 
ενός φυσικού ομιλητή. Μετά από αυτό, s/he ασκεί το 
ίδιο γλωσσικό υλικό (λεξιλόγιο και δομές) με τους διάφορους 
τρόπους μέσω της ενίσχυσης των διαφορετικών τύπων στοιχειωδών 
εργασιών Στο διαλογικό κράτος (το βήμα 2) ο αρχάριος 
πρέπει να φιλτραρίσει το λεξιλόγιο και τις δομικές άκρες που 
είναι σημαντικά σε τον/την από ένα εγγενές speaker?s 
ουσιαστικό γλωσσικό υλικό. Εάν ο αρχάριος δεν πιάνει την 
ομιλία guide?s αμέσως στην πρώτη περίοδο επικοινωνίας 
ακούσματος, ο αρχάριος μπορεί να ακούσει το τμήμα τόσοι χρόνοι 
όσοι και s/he θεωρεί απαραίτητο. Ο πυρήνας των 
μονοπατιών αντικειμένου πρόκειται για τον αρχάριο να πρέπει 
συνεχώς να αντιδράσει στις ενθαρρύνσεις και τα αιτήματα guide?s
(λειτουργούσα δυνατότητα).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un objeto que aprende para el objeto profesional 
del lenguaje learning.The forma un camino que aprende sus el propios, 
en las cuales la idea es acercar al asunto gradualmente. Primero
introducen a las palabras a través de cuadros, entonces se zambulle 
en el lenguaje hablado rico y hace al principiante de lenguaje varias 
cosas bajo dirección de un nativo. Después de esto, s/he 
practica el mismo material del lenguaje (vocabulario y las 
estructuras) de varias maneras a través de la ayuda de diversos tipos
de tasks.In el estado interactivo (el paso de progresión 2) el 
principiante tiene que filtrar el vocabulario y las extremidades 
estructurales que son importantes para him/her de un material 
lingüístico substancial de los speaker?s nativos. Si el 
principiante no agarra el discurso de los guide?s straightaway en la 
primera sesión que escucha, el principiante puede escuchar la 
sección tantas veces mientras que s/he considera necesario. La 
base de los caminos del objeto está para que el principiante tenga 
que continuamente reaccionar a los estímulos y a las peticiones 
(capacidad de funcionamiento) de los guide?s.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">sanastot:</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">sairaala</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">sanastot :</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">sairaala</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">sanastot:</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">sairaala</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">sanastot:</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">sairaala</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">sanastot:</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">sairaala</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">sanastot:</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">sairaala</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/093099E8-5C98-F2AF-161C-FE149681C950</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/093099E8-5C98-F2AF-161C-FE149681C950</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pertti Siekkinen
n:Siekkinen;Pertti 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:47:07.60Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>vocational education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">16-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd-nc/1.0/</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>1367</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1369</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>603</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/ammatilliset_kielet/potilashuone/eimg/index.html</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/ammatilliset_kielet/potilashuone/eimg/index.html</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
