<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/223080</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>223080</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/tarinanetti</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/tarinanetti</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/tarinanetti</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Tarinanetti [Talenet]</string>
            <string language="fi">Tarinanetti - oppimateriaalin etusivu</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Tarinanetti [ Talenet ]</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Tarinanetti [ Talenet ]</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Tarinanetti [ Talenet ]</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Tarinanetti [ Talenet ]</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Tarinanetti [ Talenet ]</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Tarinanetti [ Talenet ]</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Talenet’s Story Workshop and Tale Stream provide drama-based health information teaching methods. During the tale lessons, tales are produced, presented and interpreted in groups of various sizes. In the Story Workshop, the work is clearly two-phase. The first time, the pupils develop the tales in groups. They are written down and given to the teacher, who uses them to prepare a closing discussion. In Tale Stream, the tales are not written down. The work method is based clearly on improvisation, and the presentation, interpretation, adaptation and verbal discussion on the theme are interspersed with no precise boundaries. The drama work develops self-knowledge, imagination, social skills – and what is most important, feelings are involved in the learning. For example, it is rewarding and natural to deal with topics related to tolerance, bullying, dating and sexuality and the use of intoxicants by means of a tale. The material contains instructions on using the drama method, examples and ready exercises.</string>
            <string language="fi">Opas opettajille ja kouluttajille draamaan perustuvien opetusmenetelmien käyttöön eri oppilaitoksissa ja luokkatasoilla. Aineisto sisältää ohjeita draamamenetelmän käyttämiseen, esimerkkejä ja valmiita harjoituksia. Kontekstina käytetään erityisesti terveyskasvatusta.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Talenet?s Geschichte-Werkstatt und 
Geschichte-Strom liefern Drama-gegründete Gesundheit Informationen 
unterrichtende Methoden. Während der Geschichtelektionen werden
Geschichten in den Gruppen der verschiedenen Größen produziert, 
dargestellt und gedeutet. In der Geschichte-Werkstatt ist die 
Arbeit offenbar Zweiphasen. Das erste mal, die Pupillen die 
Geschichten in den Gruppen entwickeln. Sie werden notiert und 
gegeben dem Lehrer, der sie benutzt, um eine schließende Diskussion 
vorzubereiten. Im Geschichte-Strom werden die Geschichten nicht 
notiert. Die Arbeit Methode basiert offenbar auf Improvisation,
und die Darstellung, die Deutung, die Anpassung und die mündliche 
Diskussion auf dem Thema werden ohne exakte Grenzen vermischt. 
Die Dramaarbeit entwickelt Self-knowledge, Phantasie, 
Sozialfähigkeiten? und was das meiste wichtige ist, Gefühle im
Lernen miteinbezogen werden. Z.B. zu beschäftigen ist belohnend
und natürlich, die Themen, die auf Toleranz, Tyrannisieren, Datierung
und Sexualität und der Gebrauch der Rauschmittel mittels einer 
Geschichte in Verbindung gestanden werden. Das Material enthält
Anweisungen im Verwenden der Dramamethode, der Beispiele und der 
betriebsbereiten Übungen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'atelier d'histoire de Talenet?s et le jet de 
conte fournissent des méthodes d'enseignement drame-basées de 
l'information de santé. Pendant les leçons de conte, des 
contes sont produits, présentés et interprétés dans les groupes de
diverses tailles. Dans l'atelier d'histoire, le travail est 
clairement biphasé. La première fois que, les pupilles 
développent les contes dans les groupes. Elles sont notées et 
données au professeur, qui les emploie pour préparer une discussion 
de fermeture. Dans le jet de conte, les contes ne sont pas 
notés. La méthode de travail est basée clairement sur 
l'improvisation, et la présentation, la traduction, l'adaptation et 
la discussion verbale sur le thème sont entremêlées sans des bornes
précises. Le travail de drame développe art de l'auto-portrait-knowledge, 
imagination, qualifications sociales ? et ce qui est la plupart 
des important, des sentiments sont impliqués dans l'étude. Par
exemple, il est récompensant et normal de traiter des sujets liés à
la tolérance, intimider, dater et la sexualité et l'utilisation des 
intoxicants au moyen d'un conte. Le matériel contient des 
instructions sur utiliser la méthode de drame, les exemples et les 
exercices prêts.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A oficina da história de Talenet?s e o córrego 
do tale fornecem métodos ensinando drama-baseados da informação da 
saúde. Durante as lições do tale, os tales são produzidos, 
apresentados e interpretados nos grupos de vários tamanhos. Na 
oficina da história, o trabalho é claramente bifásico. A 
primeira vez que, as pupilas desenvolvem os tales nos grupos. 
São escritos para baixo e dados ao professor, que os usa 
preparar uma discussão de fechamento. No córrego do tale, os 
tales não são escritos para baixo. O método do trabalho é 
baseado claramente no improvisation, e a apresentação, a 
interpretação, a adaptação e a discussão verbal no tema 
interspersed com nenhuns limites precisos. O trabalho do drama 
desenvolve o self-knowledge, imaginação, habilidades sociais? 
e o que é a maioria de importante, os sentimentos são 
envolvidos na aprendizagem. Para o exemplo, é recompensando e 
natural tratar dos tópicos relacionados à tolerância, bullying, 
datar e o sexuality e o uso dos intoxicants por meio de um tale. 
O material contem instruções em usar o método do drama, os 
exemplos e os exercícios prontos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il gruppo di lavoro di storia di Talenet?s ed il 
flusso di racconto forniscono i metodi d'istruzione dramma-basati 
delle informazioni di salute. Durante le lezioni di racconto, i 
racconti sono prodotti, presentati ed interpretati nei gruppi di vari 
formati. Nel gruppo di lavoro di storia, il lavoro è 
chiaramente bifase. La prima volta, le pupille sviluppano i 
racconti nei gruppi. Sono annotate e sono date all'insegnante, 
che le usa per preparare una discussione di chiusura. Nel flusso
di racconto, i racconti non sono annotati. Il metodo del lavoro 
è basato chiaramente su improvvisazione e la presentazione, 
l'interpretazione, l'adattamento e la discussione verbale sul tema 
sono sparpagliati senza i contorni precisi. Il lavoro di dramma 
sviluppa l'autocoscienza, l'immaginazione, abilità sociali? e 
che cosa è la maggior parte del importante, le sensibilità sono 
coinvolte nell'imparare. Per esempio, è ricompensante e 
naturale da occuparsi dei soggetti relativi a tolleranza, bullying, 
datare e sexuality e l'uso degli intossicanti per mezzo di un 
racconto. Il materiale contiene le istruzioni sul usando il 
metodo di dramma, esempi e aspetta le esercitazioni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το εργαστήριο ιστορίας Talenet?s και το ρεύμα 
ιστορίας παρέχουν τις δράμα-βασισμένες στον μεθόδους διδασκαλίας
πληροφοριών υγείας. Κατά τη διάρκεια των μαθημάτων 
ιστορίας, οι ιστορίες παράγονται, παρουσιάζονται και ερμηνεύονται
στις ομάδες διάφορων μεγεθών. Στο εργαστήριο ιστορίας, η 
εργασία είναι σαφώς διφασική. Ο πρώτος χρόνος, οι μαθητές
αναπτύσσει τις ιστορίες κατά ομάδες. Γράφονται κάτω και 
δίνονται στο δάσκαλο, ο οποίος τους χρησιμοποιεί για να 
προετοιμάσει μια συζήτηση κλεισίματος. Στο ρεύμα ιστορίας, 
οι ιστορίες δεν γράφονται κάτω. Η μέθοδος εργασίας είναι 
βασισμένη σαφώς στον αυτοσχεδιασμό, και η παρουσίαση, η ερμηνεία,
η προσαρμογή και η λεκτική συζήτηση σχετικά με το θέμα 
διανθίζονται χωρίς τα ακριβή όρια. Η εργασία δράματος 
αναπτύσσει self-knowledge, φαντασία, κοινωνικές δεξιότητες; 
και ποιος είναι ο περισσότερος σημαντικός, τα συναισθήματα 
περιλαμβάνονται στην εκμάθηση. Παραδείγματος χάριν, 
ανταμείβει και φυσικός να εξετάσει τα θέματα σχετικά με την 
ανοχή, τη φοβέρα, τη χρονολόγηση και τη σεξουαλικότητα και τη 
χρήση των οινοπνευματωδών ποτών με τη βοήθεια μιας ιστορίας. 
Το υλικό περιέχει τις οδηγίες για τη χρησιμοποίηση της 
μεθόδου δράματος, παραδείγματα και αναμένει τις ασκήσεις.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El taller de la historia de Talenet?s y la 
secuencia del cuento proporcionan a métodos de enseñanza 
drama-basados de la información de la salud. Durante las 
lecciones del cuento, los cuentos se producen, se presentan y se 
interpretan en los grupos de varias tallas. En el taller de la 
historia, el trabajo es claramente bifásico. La primera vez 
que, las pupilas desarrollan los cuentos en grupos. Se anotan y 
se dan al profesor, que las utiliza para preparar una discusión de 
cierre. En secuencia del cuento, los cuentos no se anotan. 
El método del trabajo se basa claramente en la improvisación, 
y la presentación, la interpretación, la adaptación y la discusión
verbal sobre el tema se entremezclan sin límites exactos. ¿El 
trabajo del drama desarrolla el conocimiento de sí mismo, 
imaginación, habilidades sociales? y cuál es la mayoría del 
importante, las sensaciones están implicadas en aprender. Por 
ejemplo, es de recompensa y natural ocuparse de los asuntos 
relacionados con la tolerancia, el bullying, el fechar y sexualidad y 
el uso de productos tóxicos por medio de un cuento. El material
contiene instrucciones en usar el método del drama, los ejemplos y 
los ejercicios listos.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Elämäntapaliitto
n:Elämäntapaliitto
org:Elämäntapaliitto
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/2EEB8054-E47B-5680-ABF8-C8753E43F4A6</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/2EEB8054-E47B-5680-ABF8-C8753E43F4A6</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Eeva-Liisa Vihinen
n:Vihinen;Eeva-Liisa 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T12:02:47.42Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>role play</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>lesson plan</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>exploration</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>tool</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>guide</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>vocational education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>higher education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">7-19</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Ei mainintaa</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>1024</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1269</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1353</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>620</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>355</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>583</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>37</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/tarinanetti</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/tarinanetti</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
