<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222861</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222861</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/ammatilliset_kielet/potilashuone/fimg</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/ammatilliset_kielet/potilashuone/fimg</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/ammatilliset_kielet/potilashuone/fimg</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Potilashuone [Hospital room]</string>
            <string language="fi">Potilashuone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Potilashuone [ Krankenhausraum ]</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Potilashuone [ pièce d'hôpital ]</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Potilashuone [ quarto do hospital ]</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Potilashuone [ stanza dell'ospedale ]</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Potilashuone [ δωμάτιο νοσοκομείων ]</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Potilashuone [ sitio del hospital ]</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The program teaches Finnish health care vocabulary. The student is introduced to spoken Finnish and does various things under the guidance of a native speaker. After this, s/he practises the same language material (vocabulary and structures) in various ways through the aid of different types of tasks.

In the interactive state, the learner has to filter the vocabulary and structural tips that are important to him/her from a native speaker’s substantial linguistic material. The core of the object paths is for the learner to have to continuously react to the guide’s encouragements and requests (functioning ability).

In order to work, the program requires a Flash add-on as well as a loudspeaker or earphone function.</string>
            <string language="fi">Ohjelma opettaa terveydenhoitoalan suomenkielistä sanastoa. Opiskelija tutustuu puhuttuun suomenkieleen ja tekee erilaisia asioita syntyperäisen puhujan opastamana. Tämän jälkeen samaa kieliainesta (sanastoa ja rakenteita) harjoitetaan monipuolisesti erilaisten tehtävätyyppien avulla. 

Interaktiivisessa tilassa oppija joutuu suodattamaan äidinkielisen puhujan runsaasta kielellisestä aineksesta hänelle tärkeät sanastolliset ja rakenteelliset vihjeet. Aihiopolkujen ydin on, että oppija joutuu jatkuvasti reagoimaan opastajan kehotuksiin ja pyyntöihin (toiminnallisuus).

Ohjelma vaatii toimiakseen uusimman Flash-laajennuksen sekä kaiutin- tai kuuloketoiminnon.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="fi">sairaalavälineistö</string>
            <string language="en">sairaalavälineistö</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Programm unterrichtet finnischen 
Gesundheitspflegewortschatz. Der Kursteilnehmer wird zu 
gesprochenem finnischem eingeführt und verschiedene Sachen unter der 
Anleitung eines Muttersprachlers tut. Nach diesem übt s/he das 
gleiche Sprachenmaterial (Wortschatz und Strukturen) in den 
verschiedenen Methoden durch das Hilfsmittel der unterschiedlichen 
Typen von tasks.In der interaktive Zustand, muß der Anfänger den 
Wortschatz und die strukturellen Spitzen filtern, die zu him/her von 
einem gebürtige speaker?s erheblichen linguistischen Material wichtig
sind. Der Kern der Nachricht Pfade ist, damit der Anfänger 
ununterbrochen zu den guide?s Ermutigungen und zu den Anträgen 
reagieren muß (arbeitende ability).In Ordnung zur Arbeit, das 
Programm benötigt einen grellen Zusatz sowie eine Lautsprecher- oder 
Kopfhörerfunktion.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le programme enseigne le vocabulaire finlandais 
de santé. L'étudiant est présenté à finlandais parlé et 
fait de diverses choses sous les conseils d'un naturel. Après 
ceci, s/he pratique le même matériel de langage (vocabulaire et 
structures) dans diverses voies par l'aide de différents types de 
tasks.In l'état interactif, l'étudiant doit filtrer le vocabulaire 
et les extrémités structurales qui sont importants pour him/her d'un
matériel linguistique substantiel de speaker?s indigènes. Le 
noyau des voies d'accès d'objet est pour que l'étudiant doive sans 
interruption réagir aux encouragements de guide?s et aux demandes (la
commande de fonctionnement d'ability).In au travail, le programme 
exige une adjonction instantanée aussi bien qu'une fonction de 
haut-parleur ou d'écouteur.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O programa ensina o vocabulário finnish do 
cuidado de saúde. O estudante é introduzido a finnish falado e
faz várias coisas sob a orientação de um altofalante nativo. 
Após este, s/he pratica o mesmo material da língua 
(vocabulário e estruturas) em várias maneiras através do dae 
(dispositivo automático de entrada) de tipos diferentes de tasks.In o
estado interativo, o learner tem que filtrar o vocabulário e as 
pontas estruturais que são importantes para him/her de um material 
lingüístico substancial dos speaker?s nativos. O núcleo dos 
trajetos do objeto é para que o learner tenha que continuamente 
reagir aos incentivos dos guide?s e aos pedidos (a ordem funcionando 
de ability).In ao trabalho, o programa requer um add-on flash 
as.well.as uma função do loudspeaker ou do earphone.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il programma insegna il vocabolario finlandese di
sanità. L'allievo è introdotto a finlandese parlato e fa le 
varie cose sotto il consiglio di un indigeno. Dopo questo, s/he 
si esercita nello stesso materiale di linguaggio (vocabolario e 
strutture) in vari modi attraverso il sussidio dei tipi differenti di 
tasks.In che il interattivi dichiarano, il principiante deve 
filtrare il vocabolario e le punte strutturali che sono importanti a 
him/her da un materiale linguistico notevole degli speaker?s natali. 
Il nucleo dei percorsi dell'oggetto è affinchè il principiante
debba continuamente reagire agli incoraggiamenti dei guide?s ed alle 
richieste (l'ordine di funzionamento di ability).In a lavoro, il 
programma richiede un'adjunta istantanea così come una funzione del 
trasduttore auricolare o dell'altoparlante.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το πρόγραμμα διδάσκει το φινλανδικό λεξιλόγιο 
υγειονομικής περίθαλψης. Ο σπουδαστής είναι τα εισαχθέντα 
προφορικά φιλανδικά και κάνει τα διάφορα πράγματα κάτω από την 
καθοδήγηση ενός φυσικού ομιλητή. Μετά από αυτό, s/he 
ασκεί το ίδιο γλωσσικό υλικό (λεξιλόγιο και δομές) με τους 
διάφορους τρόπους μέσω της ενίσχυσης των διαφορετικών τύπων 
στοιχειωδών εργασιών Στο διαλογικό κράτος, ο αρχάριος 
πρέπει να φιλτραρίσει το λεξιλόγιο και τις δομικές άκρες που 
είναι σημαντικά σε τον/την από ένα εγγενές speaker?s 
ουσιαστικό γλωσσικό υλικό. Ο πυρήνας των μονοπατιών 
αντικειμένου πρόκειται για τον αρχάριο να πρέπει συνεχώς να 
αντιδράσει στις ενθαρρύνσεις και τα αιτήματα guide?s 
(λειτουργία ability). Προκειμένου να λειτουργήσει, το 
πρόγραμμα απαιτεί μια λάμψη πρόσθετη καθώς επίσης και μια 
λειτουργία μεγάφωνων ή ακουστικών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El programa enseña el vocabulario finlandés del
cuidado médico. Introducen a finlandés hablada y hace al 
estudiante varias cosas bajo dirección de un nativo. Después 
de esto, s/he practica el mismo material del lenguaje (vocabulario y 
las estructuras) de varias maneras a través de la ayuda de diversos 
tipos de tasks.In el estado interactivo, el principiante tiene que 
filtrar el vocabulario y las extremidades estructurales que son 
importantes para him/her de un material lingüístico substancial de 
los speaker?s nativos. La base de los caminos del objeto está 
para que el principiante tenga que continuamente reaccionar a los 
estímulos de los guide?s y a las peticiones (la orden de 
funcionamiento de ability).In al trabajo, el programa requiere una 
agregación de destello así como una función del altavoz o del 
auricular.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">sairaalavälineistö</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">sairaalavälineistö</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">sairaalavälineistö</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">sairaalavälineistö</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">sairaalavδlineistφ</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">sairaalavälineistö</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Lingonet Oy
n:Lingonet Oy
org:Lingonet Oy
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/4A64D1FE-4580-1783-5805-5DAB45F848E2</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/4A64D1FE-4580-1783-5805-5DAB45F848E2</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Terhikki Rimmanen
n:Rimmanen;Terhikki 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-03-20T01:00:34.25Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>vocational education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">15-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Nimeä-Epäkaupallinen-Ei muutettuja teoksia 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>909</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>603</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>634</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1367</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>493</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/ammatilliset_kielet/potilashuone/fimg</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/ammatilliset_kielet/potilashuone/fimg</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
