<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222753</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222753</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi/julkaisut/luonnontietpalatino.pdf</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/julkaisut/luonnontietpalatino.pdf</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/julkaisut/luonnontietpalatino.pdf</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Performing natural science research at school</string>
            <string language="fi">Luonnontieteellisen tutkimuksen tekeminen koulussa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Durchführen der natürlichen Wissenschaft 
Forschung an der Schule</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Exécuter la recherche normale de la science à 
l'école</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Executando a pesquisa natural da ciência na 
escola</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Realizzare ricerca naturale di scienza alla 
scuola</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εκτέλεση της έρευνας φυσικής επιστήμης στο σχολείο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ejecución de la investigación natural de la 
ciencia en la escuela</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The guide is intended as an aid and support for teachers and students when planning natural science research that is more extensive and independent than the ordinary experiment arrangement in a lesson. The aim of the work is to strive to lower the threshold for research carried out in schools. The work targeted at upper secondary school teaching is also suitable for basic teaching of the natural sciences in the upper forms. Free Adobe Reader software is required for reading the PDF-format guide.</string>
            <string language="fi">Opas on tarkoitettu opettajien ja opiskelijoiden avuksi ja tueksi suunniteltaessa tavallista oppitunnin koejärjestelyä suurempaa ja itsenäisempää luonnontieteellistä tutkimusta. Teoksen tavoitteena on pyrkiä madaltamaan kynnystä koulun piirissä tehtävälle tutkimukselle. Lukio-opetukseen suunnattu teos soveltuu myös luonnontieteiden perusopetukseen yläluokille. PDF-muotoisen oppaan lukemiseen tarvitaan maksuton Adobe Reader -ohjelma.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Anleitung wird da ein Hilfsmittel und ein 
Support für Lehrer und Kursteilnehmer beabsichtigt, wenn man 
natürliche Wissenschaft Forschung plant, die umfangreicher und 
Unabhängiges als die gewöhnliche Experimentanordnung in einer 
Lektion ist. Das Ziel der Arbeit ist sich zu bemühen, den 
Schwellwert für die Forschung zu senken, die in den Schulen 
durchgeführt wird. Die Arbeit, die am 
obersekundarschuleunterricht gezielt wird, ist auch für grundlegenden
Unterricht der natürlichen Wissenschaften in den oberen Formen 
verwendbar. Freie Ziegelstein-Lesersoftware wird für das 
Ablesen der Pdf-Format Anleitung benoetigt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le guide est destiné car une aide et un soutien 
des professeurs et des étudiants en projetant la recherche normale de
la science qui est plus étendue et indépendant que l'agencement 
ordinaire d'expérience dans une leçon. Le but du travail est 
de tâcher d'abaisser le seuil pour la recherche effectuée dans les 
écoles. Le travail visé à l'enseignement secondaire deuxième
cycle d'école est également approprié à l'enseignement de base des
sciences normales sous les formes supérieures. Le logiciel 
libre de lecteur d'adobe est exigé pour lire le guide de Pdf-format.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A guia é pretendida porque um dae (dispositivo 
automático de entrada) e uma sustentação para professores e 
estudantes ao planear a pesquisa natural da ciência que é mais 
extensiva e independent do que o arranjo ordinário da experiência em
uma lição. O alvo do trabalho é strive abaixar o ponto 
inicial para a pesquisa realizada nas escolas. O trabalho 
alvejado no ensino superior da escola secundária é também 
apropriado para o ensino básico das ciências naturais nos 
formulários superiores. O software livre do leitor do adôbe é
requerido lendo a guia do Pdf-formato.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La guida è intesa poichè un sussidio e un 
sostegno gli insegnanti e gli allievi quando progetta la ricerca 
naturale di scienza che è più vasta ed independent che la 
disposizione ordinaria di esperimento in una lezione. Lo scopo 
del lavoro è sforzarsi abbassare la soglia per ricerca effettuata in 
scuole. Il lavoro designato ad insegnamento superiore-secondario
della scuola è egualmente adatto ad insegnamento di base delle 
scienze naturali nelle forme superiori. Il software libero del 
lettore dell'adobe è richiesto per la lettura della guida di 
Pdf-formato.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο οδηγός προορίζεται ως ενίσχυση και υποστήριξη για 
τους δασκάλους και τους σπουδαστές κατά τον προγραμματισμό της 
έρευνας φυσικής επιστήμης που είναι πιό εκτενής και ανεξάρτητη 
από τη συνηθισμένη ρύθμιση πειράματος σε ένα μάθημα. Ο 
στόχος της εργασίας είναι να προσπαθήσει να χαμηλώσει τη μεγάλη 
μονάδα για την έρευνα που διεξάγεται στα σχολεία. Η εργασία
που στοχεύει στην ανώτερη διδασκαλία δευτεροβάθμιας εκπαίδευσης 
είναι επίσης κατάλληλη για τη βασική διδασκαλία των φυσικών 
επιστημών στις ανώτερες μορφές. Το ελεύθερο λογισμικό 
αναγνωστών πλίθας απαιτείται για την ανάγνωση του οδηγού 
πδφ-μορφής.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Se piensa la guía pues una ayuda y una ayuda 
para los profesores y los estudiantes al planear la investigación 
natural de la ciencia que es más extensa y independiente que el arreglo 
ordinario del experimento en una lección. La puntería del 
trabajo es esforzarse bajar el umbral para la investigación realizada
en escuelas. El trabajo apuntado en la enseñanza 
superior-secundaria de la escuela es también conveniente para la 
enseñanza básica de las ciencias naturales en las formas superiores.
El software libre del programa de lectura del adobe se requiere 
para leer la guía del Pdf-formato.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Maija Flinkman
n:Flinkman;Maija
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Elina Näsäkkälä
n:Näsäkkälä;Elina
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Maija Aksela
n:Aksela;Maija
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/B2B7D645-2FC9-7D20-CF69-B17B3F4768CD</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/B2B7D645-2FC9-7D20-CF69-B17B3F4768CD</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Ilkka Mäkitalo
n:Mäkitalo;Ilkka 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-03-14T00:43:58.10Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>guide</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">12-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd-nc/1.0/</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>978</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1282</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>875</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>195</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi/julkaisut/luonnontietpalatino.pdf</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>application/pdf</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/julkaisut/luonnontietpalatino.pdf</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
