<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222557</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222557</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.oph.fi/instancedata/prime_product_julkaisu/oph/embeds/30224_hyva_koulukirjasto.pdf</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/instancedata/prime_product_julkaisu/oph/embeds/30224_hyva_koulukirjasto.pdf</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/instancedata/prime_product_julkaisu/oph/embeds/30224_hyva_koulukirjasto.pdf</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A good school library</string>
            <string language="fi">Hyvä koulukirjasto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine gute Schulebibliothek</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une bonne bibliothèque d'école</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uma biblioteca boa da escola</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Una buona libreria della scuola</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια καλή σχολική βιβλιοθήκη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una buena biblioteca de la escuela</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The objective of the 'Good school library’ publication is to create even better school libraries in Finland than at present. This joint publication by the Finnish School Library Association and the Finnish National Board of Education offers the municipalities and schools officially partaking in the project, as well as others interested in the matter, a development vision and practical descriptions as well as instructions on a well-functioning school library. These include the premises, equipment and materials, staff and operations, as well as organising information retrieval and including the school library as part of the school curriculum. The publication can be downloaded in PDF format.</string>
            <string language="fi">Hyvä koulukirjasto -julkaisun tavoitteena on luoda Suomeen nykyistä parempia koulukirjastoja. Suomen koulukirjastoyhdistyksen ja Opetushallituksen
yhteisjulkaisussa tarjotaan niin virallisille hankekunnille ja kehittäjäkouluille
kuin muillekin kiinnostuneille sekä kehittämisvisioita että
käytännöllisiä kuvauksia ja ohjeita siitä, millaisia ovat hyvin
toimivat koulukirjastot. Kuvattuja osa-alueita ovat muun muassa koulukirjaston tilat, varustus ja aineisto, henkilökunta ja toiminta sekä tiedonhaun järjestäminen ja koulukirjaston liittäminen osaksi koulujen opetussuunnitelmaa. Julkaisu on ladattavissa pdf-muotoisena.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Lernziel der ' guten Schulebibliothek? 
Publikation soll sogar bessere Schulebibliotheken in Finnland 
als zur Zeit herstellen. Diese gemeinsame Publikation durch die 
finnische Schule-Bibliothek-Verbindung und das finnische nationale 
Brett der Ausbildung bietet die Stadtbezirke und die Schulen offiziell
partaking im Projekt an, sowie andere interessiert an dem Stoff, im 
Entwicklung Anblick und in den praktischen Beschreibungen sowie 
Anweisungen in einer gutgehenden Schulebibliothek. Diese 
schließen die Voraussetzungen, die Ausrüstung und die Materialien, 
Stab und Operationen, sowie organisierende Information Retrieval und 
das Enthalten der Schulebibliothek als Teil des Schulelehrplans ein. 
Die Publikation kann im pdf Format downloadet werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'objectif de la 'bonne bibliothèque d'école ? 
la publication doit créer encore de meilleures bibliothèques 
d'école en Finlande qu'actuellement. Cette publication commune 
par l'association finlandaise de bibliothèque d'école et l'office 
national finlandais de l'éducation offre les municipalités et les 
écoles participant officiellement l'au projet, aussi bien que 
d'autres intéressé à la matière, à de la vision de développement
et aux descriptions pratiques aussi bien que des instructions sur une 
bibliothèque fiable d'école. Celles-ci incluent les lieux, le 
matériel et les matériaux, personnel et exécutions, aussi bien que 
la recherche documentaire d'organisation et inclure la bibliothèque 
d'école en tant qu'élément du programme d'études d'école. 
La publication peut être téléchargée dans le format de pdf.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O objetivo ' da biblioteca boa da escola? a
publicação deve criar mesmo bibliotecas melhores da escola em 
Finland do que no presente. Esta publicação comum pela 
associação finnish da biblioteca da escola e pela placa nacional 
finnish da instrução oferece as municipalidades e as escolas que 
partaking oficialmente o no projeto, as.well.as outra interessado na 
matéria, na visão do desenvolvimento e em descrições práticas 
as.well.as instruções em uma biblioteca well-functioning da escola. 
Estes incluem as premisoes, o equipamento e os materiais, equipe
de funcionários e operações, as.well.as a recuperação de 
informação organizando e incluir a biblioteca da escola como a parte
do curriculum da escola. A publicação pode downloaded no 
formato do pdf.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'obiettivo 'di buona libreria della scuola? 
la pubblicazione deve creare ancora le librerie migliori della 
scuola in Finlandia che attualmente. Questa pubblicazione unita 
dall'associazione finlandese della libreria della scuola e dal 
Bordo nazionale finlandese di formazione offre i comuni e le 
scuole che partecipano ufficialmente al progetto, così come altre 
interessato alla materia, ad una visione di sviluppo ed alle 
descrizioni pratiche così come le istruzioni su una libreria ben 
funzionante della scuola. Questi includono i locali, le 
attrezzature ed i materiali, personale e funzionamenti, così come 
reperimento delle informazioni d'organizzazione ed includere la 
libreria della scuola come componente del programma di studi della 
scuola. La pubblicazione può essere trasferita nel formato del 
pdf.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο στόχος της "καλής σχολικής βιβλιοθήκης; η 
δημοσίευση είναι να δημιουργηθούν ακόμα οι καλύτερες σχολικές 
βιβλιοθήκες στη Φινλανδία από αυτή τη στιγμή. Αυτή η 
κοινή δημοσίευση από τη φινλανδική ένωση σχολικής βιβλιοθήκης 
και το φινλανδικό εθνικό συμβούλιο της εκπαίδευσης προσφέρει τους
δήμους και τα σχολεία συμμετέχοντας επίσημα στο πρόγραμμα, καθώς
επίσης και άλλων ενδιαφερόμενων στο θέμα, ένα όραμα ανάπτυξης 
και πρακτικές περιγραφές καθώς επίσης και τις οδηγίες για μια με 
καλή λειτουργία σχολική βιβλιοθήκη. Αυτοί περιλαμβάνουν 
τις εγκαταστάσεις, τον εξοπλισμό και τα υλικά, το προσωπικό και 
τις διαδικασίες, καθώς επίσης και οργανώνοντας την ανάκτηση 
πληροφοριών και συμπεριλαμβανομένης της σχολικής βιβλιοθήκης ως 
τμήμα του σχολικού προγράμματος σπουδών. Η δημοσίευση 
μπορεί να μεταφορτωθεί με τη μορφή PDF.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿El objetivo de la ' buena biblioteca de la 
escuela? la publicación es crear incluso bibliotecas mejores de
la escuela en Finlandia que actualmente. Esta publicación 
común por la asociación finlandesa de la biblioteca de la escuela y 
la tarjeta nacional finlandesa de la educación ofrece los municipios 
y las escuelas que participan oficialmente en el el proyecto, así 
como otras interesado en la materia, visión del desarrollo y las 
descripciones prácticas así como instrucciones en una biblioteca 
fiable de la escuela. Éstos incluyen las premisas, el equipo y 
los materiales, personal y operaciones, así como la recuperación de 
datos de ordenación e incluir la biblioteca de la escuela como parte 
del plan de estudios de la escuela. La publicación se puede 
descargar en formato del pdf.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Seija Salminen
n:Salminen;Seija
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Hannele Frantsi
n:Frantsi;Hannele
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Kaarina Kolu
n:Kolu;Kaarina
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Heikki Sallinen
n:Sallinen;Heikki
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Suomen koulukirjastoyhdistys ry
n:Suomen koulukirjastoyhdistys ry
org:Suomen koulukirjastoyhdistys ry
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/BD9D7290-4BF2-3FC5-94DA-2451F8E797A2</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/BD9D7290-4BF2-3FC5-94DA-2451F8E797A2</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Annika Ranta
n:Ranta;Annika 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:54:03.88Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">6-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Nimeä-Epäkaupallinen-Ei muutettuja teoksia 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>1024</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1131</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1353</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.oph.fi/instancedata/prime_product_julkaisu/oph/embeds/30224_hyva_koulukirjasto.pdf</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oph.fi/instancedata/prime_product_julkaisu/oph/embeds/30224_hyva_koulukirjasto.pdf</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
