<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/235352</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>235352</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/lontoo</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/lontoo</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/lontoo</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Virtual Walk in London</string>
            <string language="fi">Virtual Walk in London</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Virtueller Weg in London</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Promenade virtuelle à Londres</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Caminhada virtual em Londres</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Camminata virtuale a Londra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εικονικός περίπατος στο Λονδίνο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Caminata virtual en Londres</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this learning object, we travel along a route from London’s British Museum to Covent Garden guided by instructions on a tape. The screen shows a digital image of the view which someone walking along the route would see in reality. The screen shows arrows pointing in various directions, which are pressed to move on. The pupil has to travel in the direction advised from the crossroads en route. Choosing a wrong route results in the pupil being returned to the start of the game. The game is a downloadable application.</string>
            <string language="fi">Oppimisaihiossa kuljetaan ääninauhalta kuuluvien ohjeiden opastamana reitti Lontoon British Museumista Convent Gardeniin. Kuvaruudulla näkyy digitaalikuva näkymästä, jonka reittiä kävelevä näkisi todellisuudessa. Ruudulla on näkyvissä eri suuntiin osoittavia nuolia, joita painamalla liikkuminen tapahtuu. Oppilaan on kuljettava matkan varrella eteen tulevista risteyksistä neuvottuun suuntaan. Virheellisen reitin valinnasta seuraa palautus pelin alkuun. Peli on ladattava sovellus.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="fi">Lontoo</string>
            <string language="en">Lontoo</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In dieser erlernennachricht reisen wir entlang 
einen Weg London?s vom britischen Museum zum Covent Garten, der durch 
Anweisungen in einem Band geführt wird. Der Bildschirm zeigt 
ein digitalisiertes Bild der Ansicht, welches jemand, der entlang den 
Weg geht, in Wirklichkeit sehen würde. Der Bildschirm zeigt die
Pfeile, die in den verschiedenen Richtungen zeigen, die betätigt 
werden, um an zu bewegen. Die Pupille muß in die Richtung 
reisen, die auf dem Weg von der Querstraße geraten wird. Das 
Wählen eines falschen Weges ergibt die Pupille, die zum Anfang des 
Spiels zurückgegangen wird. Das Spiel ist eine 
downloadableanwendung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cet objet d'étude, nous voyageons le long 
d'un itinéraire de musée britannique de London?s au jardin de Covent
guidé par des instructions sur bande. L'écran montre une image
digitale de la vue ce que quelqu'un marchant le long de l'itinéraire 
verrait en réalité. L'écran montre des flèches se dirigeant 
dans diverses directions, qui sont appuyées pour passer. La 
pupille doit voyager dans la direction informée du carrefour en 
route. Le choix d'un itinéraire faux a comme conséquence la 
pupille étant retournée au début du jeu. Le jeu est une 
application downloadable.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Neste objeto de aprendizagem, nós viajamos ao 
longo de uma rota do museu britânico de London?s ao jardim de Covent 
guiado por instruções em uma fita adesiva. A tela mostra uma 
imagem digital da vista qual alguém que anda ao longo da rota veria 
na realidade. A tela mostra as setas que apontam nos vários 
sentidos, que são pressionados para se mover sobre. A pupila 
tem que viajar no sentido recomendado do crossroads a caminho. 
Escolher uma rota errada resulta na pupila que está sendo 
retornada ao começo do jogo. O jogo é uma aplicação 
downloadable.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questo oggetto imparante, viaggiamo lungo un 
itinerario dal museo britannico di London?s al giardino di Covent 
guidato tramite le istruzioni su nastro. Lo schermo mostra 
un'immagine digitale della vista quale qualcuno che cammina lungo 
l'itinerario vedrebbe in realtà. Lo schermo mostra le frecce 
che indicano in vari sensi, che sono premuti per passare. La 
pupilla deve viaggiare nel senso raccomandato dalla strada trasversale
in viaggio. La scelta dell'itinerario errato provoca la pupilla 
che è rinviata all'inizio del gioco. Il gioco è 
un'applicazione downloadable.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτό το αντικείμενο εκμάθησης, ταξιδεύουμε κατά 
μήκος μιας διαδρομής από το βρετανικό μουσείο London?s στον 
κήπο Covent που καθοδηγείται από τις οδηγίες για μια ταινία. 
Η οθόνη εμφανίζει ψηφιακή εικόνα της όψης που κάποιος που 
περπατά κατά μήκος της διαδρομής θα έβλεπε στην 
πραγματικότητα. Η οθόνη εμφανίζει βέλη δείχνοντας στις 
διάφορες κατευθύνσεις, οι οποίες πατιούνται για να προχωρήσουν. 
Ο μαθητής πρέπει να ταξιδεψει στην κατεύθυνση που 
ενθαρρύνεται από τα σταυροδρόμια καθ'οδόν. Η επιλογή μιας 
λανθασμένης διαδρομής οδηγεί στο μαθητή που επιστρέφεται στην 
έναρξη του παιχνιδιού. Το παιχνίδι είναι μια 
τηλεκατεγραφόμενη εφαρμογή.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En este objeto que aprende, viajamos a lo largo de
una ruta del museo británico de London?s al jardín de Covent 
dirigido por instrucciones en una cinta. La pantalla muestra una
imagen digital de la opinión cuál alguien que recorre a lo largo de 
la ruta vería en realidad. La pantalla muestra las flechas que 
señalan en las varias direcciones, que se presionan para moverse 
encendido. La pupila tiene que viajar en la dirección 
aconsejada de la encrucijada en el camino. Elegir una ruta 
incorrecta da lugar a la pupila que es vuelta al comienzo del juego. 
El juego es una aplicación downloadable.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lontoo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Lontoo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Lontoo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lontoo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Lontoo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Lontoo</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Lingonet Oy
n:Lingonet Oy
org:Lingonet Oy
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/2A7A3B57-64F3-391F-D1DD-62322797F70A</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/2A7A3B57-64F3-391F-D1DD-62322797F70A</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pertti Siekkinen
n:Siekkinen;Pertti 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:36:24.07Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>simulation</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>educational game</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">12-16</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Creative commons Nimeä-epäkaupallinen-Ei muutettuja teoksia 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>750</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>709</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/lontoo</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/lontoo</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
