<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/80299</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>80299</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/fysiikka/sahko/electricity_2/index.html</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/fysiikka/sahko/electricity_2/index.html</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="fi">Sähköiset alkeispiirit - mittaaminen</string>
            <string language="en">Electrical elementary circuits – measurement</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Elektrische grundlegende Stromkreise? 
Messen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Circuits élémentaires électriques ? 
mesure</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Circuitos elementares elétricos? medida</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Circuiti elementari elettrici? misura</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ηλεκτρικά στοιχειώδη κυκλώματα; μέτρηση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿Circuitos elementales eléctricos? medida</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Oppimisaihio on tarkoitettu perusopetuksen fysiikan sähköopin opiskeluun ja kertaukseen. Aihio sopii parhaiten verkossa tapahtuvaan ryhmätyöskentelyyn, mutta sitä voidaan hyödyntää myös itsenäisessä opiskelussa. Sivusto sisältää opettajan ohjeet ja ehdotuksen opiskelun kuluksi. Sivuston käyttö edellyttää selaimelta Macromedia Shockwave -laajennusta. Oppilaiden olisi hyvä tuntea etukäteen virta ja jännite. Koulussa oppilaiden pitäisi lisäksi olla jo tutustunut piirilevyn ja komponenttien käyttöön. Aihiossa oppilas tutustuu ensin teoriaan, tekee kokeita jännitteen ja virran mittaamisesta ja lopuksi testaa, osaako kytkennät.</string>
            <string language="en">The learning object is intended for the study and revision of the theory of electricity in basic physics teaching. The object is best suited to online group work, but it can also be utilised in independent study. The website contains the teacher’s instructions and a suggestion for the progress of study. Use of the website requires a browser with a Macromedia Shockwave add-on. It would be good for the pupils to be familiar in advance with current and voltage. At school, pupils ought in addition to have already learnt about use of a circuit board and components. In the object, the pupil first learns about theory, performs tests on the measurement of voltage and current and finally tests whether s/he is able to perform couplings.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">alkeispiirit</string>
            <string language="fi">alkeispiirit</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die erlernennachricht ist für die Studie und die
Änderung der Theorie von Elektrizität im grundlegenden 
Physikunterricht bestimmt. Die Nachricht wird gut entsprochen, 
um Arbeit online zu gruppieren, aber sie kann in der unabhängigen 
Studie auch verwendet werden. Die Web site enthält die 
teacher?s Anweisungen und einen Vorschlag für den Fortschritt der 
Studie. Gebrauch von der Web site benötigt eine 
Datenbanksuchroutine mit einem Macromedia Shockwavezusatz. Es 
würde gut für die Pupillen sein, im voraus mit Strom und Spannung 
vertraut zu sein. An der Schule sollen Schüler zusätzlich zu 
über Gebrauch von einer Leiterplatte und Bestandteilen bereits 
erlernt haben. In der Nachricht erlernt die Schüler zuerst 
über Theorie, führt Tests auf dem Messen der Spannung und des 
Stromes und schließlich der Tests durch, ob s/he kann, Koppelungen 
durchzuführen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'objet d'étude est destiné pour l'étude et la
révision de la théorie de l'électricité dans l'enseignement de 
base de physique. L'objet est plus adapté pour grouper en ligne
le travail, mais il peut également être utilisé dans l'étude 
indépendante. Le site Web contient les instructions de 
teacher?s et une suggestion pour le progrès de l'étude. 
L'utilisation du site Web exige un navigateur avec une 
adjonction d'onde de choc de Macromedia. Il serait bon que les 
pupilles soient au courant à l'avance du courant et de la tension. 
À l'école, les élèves doivent en plus de s'être déjà 
renseignés sur l'utilisation d'une carte et des composants. 
Dans l'objet, l'élève d'abord se renseigne sur la théorie, 
réalise des essais sur la mesure de la tension et le courant et 
finalement les essais si s/he peut exécuter des couplages.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O objeto de aprendizagem é pretendido para o 
estudo e a revisão da teoria da eletricidade no ensino básico da 
física. O objeto é servido melhor para agrupar em linha o 
trabalho, mas pode também ser utilizado no estudo independente. 
O Web site contem as instruções dos teacher?s e uma sugestão 
para o progresso do estudo. O uso do Web site requer um browser 
com um add-on do shockwave de Macromedia. Seria bom para as 
pupilas ser familiar adiantado com a corrente e a tensão. Na 
escola, os alunos ought além já ter aprendido sobre o uso de uma 
placa e de componentes de circuito. No objeto, o aluno 
primeiramente aprende sobre a teoria, executa testes na medida da 
tensão e a corrente e finalmente os testes se s/he pode  executar 
acoplamentos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'oggetto imparante è inteso per lo studio e la 
revisione della teoria di elettricità nell'insegnamento di base di 
fisica. L'oggetto è più adatto in linea raggruppare il lavoro,
ma può anche essere utilizzato nello studio indipendente. Il 
Web site contiene le istruzioni dei teacher?s e un suggerimento per il
progresso dello studio. L'uso del Web site richiede un browser 
con un'adjunta di shockwave di Macromedia. Sarebbe in anticipo 
buono affinchè le pupille abbia familiarità con la corrente e la 
tensione. Alla scuola, gli allievi devono oltre che già 
imparare circa uso di un bordo e dei componenti del circuito. 
Nell'oggetto, l'allievo in primo luogo impara circa la teoria, 
effettua le prove sulla misura di tensione e corrente ed infine prove 
se s/he può effettuare gli accoppiamenti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το αντικείμενο εκμάθησης προορίζεται για τη μελέτη και
την αναθεώρηση της θεωρίας της ηλεκτρικής ενέργειας στη βασική 
διδασκαλία φυσικής. Το αντικείμενο είναι καταλληλότερο για 
να ομαδοποιήσει on-line την εργασία, αλλά μπορεί επίσης να 
χρησιμοποιηθεί στην ανεξάρτητη μελέτη. Ο ιστοχώρος περιέχει
τις οδηγίες teacher?s και μια πρόταση για την πρόοδο της 
μελέτης. Η χρήση του ιστοχώρου απαιτεί έναν ξεφυλλιστή με 
shockwave Macromedia πρόσθετο. Θα ήταν καλό για τους 
μαθητές για να εξοικειωθεί εκ των προτέρων με το ρεύμα και την 
τάση. Στο σχολείο, οι μαθητές πρέπει εκτός από να έχουν 
μάθει ήδη για τη χρήση ενός πίνακα κυκλωμάτων και των 
συστατικών. Στο αντικείμενο, ο μαθητής μαθαίνει αρχικά για 
τη θεωρία, εκτελεί τις δοκιμές στη μέτρηση της τάσης και το 
ρεύμα και τελικά τις δοκιμές εάν s/he είναι σε θέση να 
εκτελέσει τις συζεύξεις.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El objeto que aprende se piensa para el estudio y
la revisión de la teoría de la electricidad en la enseñanza básica
de la física. El objeto se satisface lo más mejor posible en 
línea para agrupar el trabajo, pero puede también ser utilizado en 
estudio independiente. El Web site contiene las instrucciones de 
los teacher?s y una sugerencia para el progreso del estudio. El 
uso del Web site requiere un browser con una agregación de la onda de
choque de Macromedia. Sería bueno que las pupilas sean familiar
por adelantado con la corriente y el voltaje. En la escuela, las
pupilas ought además de haber aprendido ya sobre uso de una tarjeta y
de los componentes de circuito. En el objeto, la pupila primero 
aprende sobre teoría, realiza pruebas en la medida del voltaje y 
corriente y finalmente las pruebas si s/he puede realizar acopladores.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">alkeispiirit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">alkeispiirit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">alkeispiirit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">alkeispiirit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">alkeispiirit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">alkeispiirit</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Oppomedia Oy
n:Oppomedia Oy
org:Oppomedia Oy
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/A790C9B2-0929-4021-89FE-42EB23FC8D87</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/A790C9B2-0929-4021-89FE-42EB23FC8D87</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Anna-Elina Häkkilä
n:Häkkilä;Anna-Elina 
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>fi</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE)
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE)
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE)
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2009-04-09T19:44:02.53Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>project</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">13-15</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Creative commons Nimeä-epäkaupallinen-Ei muutettuja teoksia 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>978</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>411</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>793</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>80299</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/fysiikka/sahko/electricity_2/index.html</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
