<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/80737</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>80737</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/ict/kuvankasittely</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/ict/kuvankasittely</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="fi">Digitaalinen kuvankäsittely</string>
            <string language="en">Digital image processing</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Verarbeitung des Digitalisierten Bildes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Traitement d'image de Digital</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Processar de imagem de Digital</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Elaborazione di immagini di Digital</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ψηφιακή επεξεργασία εικόνας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Proceso de imagen de Digital</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Sivusto sisältää kolme osiota. Ensimmäisen linkin kautta pääsee oppilaille suunnattuun esitykseen, jossa Maija on työharjoittelussa lehdessä ja pääsee käsittelemään kuvia digitaalisesti. Materiaalia opettajalle sisältää kaksi osiota. "Digitaaliset kuvat: ohjeita opettajalle" sisältää vastaukset seuraaviin kysymyksiin: Mitä opettajan tulee tietää? Kenelle aineisto on tarkoitettu? Mitä oppilaan tulee osata? Miten oppiminen/opinnot etenevät? Toinen osio on pdf-dokumentti "Digitaalisen kuvan perusteet", jossa käydään läpi seuraavat aiheet: Analoginen versus digitaalinen, Originaalit, Digitaalisen kuvan lähteet, Muut lähteet, Resoluutio, Bittikarttagrafiikka, Digitaalisen kuvan päätyypit, Grafiikka ja värit, Vektorigrafiikka, Skannaaminen tasoskannerilla, Yleisimmät kuvaformaatit ja Kuvan tallentaminen verkkoon.</string>
            <string language="en">The website contains three sections. The first link leads to a presentation targeted at pupils, in which Maija is engaged in practical work experience for a newspaper and gets the chance to process images digitally. The material for the teacher contains two sections. "Digital images: instructions for the teacher" contains answers to the following questions: What should a teacher know? Who is the material intended for? What should the pupil be able to do? How is learning/studies progressing? The second part is a PDF document "The bases of the digital image", which examines the following topics: Analogue versus digital, Originals, The sources of a digital image, Other sources, Resolution, Bitmap graphics, The main types of digital image, Graphics and colours, Vector graphics, Scanning with a flatbed scanner, The commonest image formats and Saving an image on the web.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">viestintä</string>
            <string language="fi">viestintä</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Web site enthält drei Kapitel. Das 
erste Link führt zu eine Darstellung, die an den Pupillen gezielt 
wird, in denen Maija an praktischer Arbeit Erfahrung für eine Zeitung
teilnimmt und die Wahrscheinlichkeit erhält, Bilder digital zu 
verarbeiten. Das Material für den Lehrer enthält zwei Kapitel.
"Digitalisierte Bilder: Anweisungen für den Lehrer 
"enthält Antworten zu den folgenden Fragen: Was sollte ein 
Lehrer wissen? Für wem ist das Material bestimmt? Was 
sollte die Pupille können, zu tun? Wie kommt learning/studies 
weiter? Das zweite Teil ist ein pdf Dokument "die Unterseiten 
des digitalisierten Bildes", das die folgenden Themen überprüft: 
Entsprechung gegen digitales, Vorlagen, die Quellen eines 
digitalisierten Bildes, andere Quellen, Zerlegung, 
Bit-Übersichtsgraphiken, die Haupttypen des digitalisierten Bildes, 
die Graphiken und die Farben, vektorgraphiken, absuchend mit einem 
Flachbettscanner, die geläufigsten Bildformate und sichern ein Bild 
auf dem Web.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le site Web contient trois sections. Le 
premier lien mène à une présentation visée aux pupilles, dans 
lesquelles Maija est engagé dans l'expérience professionnelle 
pratique pour un journal et obtient la chance de traiter des images 
digitalement. Le matériel pour le professeur contient deux 
sections. "images de Digital : les instructions pour le 
professeur "contient des réponses aux questions suivantes : 
Qu'un professeur devrait-il savoir ? Pour qui le matériel
est-il destiné ? Que la pupille devrait-elle pouvoir faire ? 
Comment learning/studies progresse-t-il ? La deuxième 
partie est un document de pdf "les bases de l'image digitale", qui 
examine les sujets suivants : Analogue contre digital, des 
originaux, les sources d'image digitale, toute autre sources, 
résolution, affichages par mémoire d'image, les types principaux 
d'image digitale, des graphiques et des couleurs, graphiques de 
vecteur, balayant avec un module de balayage à plat, les formats 
d'image les plus communs et sauvegardant une image sur le Web.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Web site contem três seções. A primeira
ligação conduz a uma apresentação alvejada nas pupilas, em que 
Maija é acoplado na experiência de trabalho prática para um jornal 
e começa a possibilidade processar digital imagens. O material 
para o professor contem duas seções. de "imagens Digital: 
as instruções para o professor "contêm respostas às 
seguintes perguntas: Que deve um professor saber? Quem o 
material é pretendido para? Que deve a pupila poder  fazer? 
Como learning/studies está progredindo? A segunda parte 
é um original do pdf "as bases da imagem digital", que examina os 
seguintes tópicos: Analogue contra digital, originais, as 
fontes de uma imagem digital, as outras fontes, definição, gráficos
bitmap, os tipos principais de imagem digital, gráficos e cores, 
gráficos do vetor, fazendo a varredura com um varredor flatbed, os 
formatos os mais comuns da imagem e conservando uma imagem no Web.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Web site contiene tre sezioni. Il primo 
collegamento conduce ad una presentazione designata alle pupille, in 
cui Maija è agganciato nell'esperienza di lavoro pratica per un 
giornale ed ottiene la probabilità elaborare le immagini 
digitalmente. Il materiale per l'insegnante contiene due 
sezioni. "immagini di Digital: le istruzioni per 
l'insegnante "contiene le risposte alle seguenti domande: Che 
cosa dovrebbe un insegnante conoscere? Chi il materiale è 
inteso per? Che cosa dovrebbe la pupilla potere fare? Come
learning/studies sta progredendo? La seconda parte è un 
documento del pdf "le basi dell'immagine digitale", che esamina i 
seguenti soggetti: Analogo contro digitale, gli originali, le 
sorgenti di un'immagine digitale, le altra sorgenti, risoluzione, i 
grafici a memoria d'immagine, i tipi principali di immagini digitali, 
i grafici ed i colori, grafici di vettore, esploranti con un 
dispositivo d'esplorazione a base piatta, i formati di immagine più 
comuni e salvanti un'immagine sul Web.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο ιστοχώρος περιέχει τρία τμήματα. Η πρώτη 
σύνδεση οδηγεί σε μια παρουσίαση που στοχεύει στους μαθητές, στην
οποία Maija συμμετέχει στην πρακτική επαγγελματική εμπειρία 
για μια εφημερίδα και παίρνει την πιθανότητα να υποβληθούν σε 
επεξεργασία οι εικόνες ψηφιακά. Το υλικό για το δάσκαλο 
περιέχει δύο τμήματα. "Ψηφιακές εικόνες: οι οδηγίες 
για το δάσκαλο "περιέχουν τις απαντήσεις στις ακόλουθες 
ερωτήσεις: Τι θα έπρεπε ένας δάσκαλος να ξέρει; 
Ποιους το υλικό προορίζεται για; Τι θα έπρεπε ο 
μαθητής να είναι σε θέση να κάνει; Πώς η εκμάθηση/οι 
μελέτες προχωρεί; Το δεύτερο μέρος είναι ένα έγγραφο 
PDF "οι βάσεις της ψηφιακής εικόνασ", η οποία εξετάζει τα 
ακόλουθα θέματα: Ανάλογο εναντίον ψηφιακού, των 
πρωτοτύπων, οι πηγές μιας ψηφιακής εικόνας, άλλες πηγές, 
ψήφισμα, γραφική παράσταση πινάκων δυαδικών ψηφίων, οι βασικοί 
τύποι ψηφιακών εικόνας, γραφικών παραστάσεων και χρωμάτων, 
διανυσματική γραφική παράσταση, που ανιχνεύουν με έναν επίπεδης 
βάσης σαρωτή, τις πιό κοινές μορφές εικόνας και τη διάσωση μιας
εικόνας σχετικά με τον Ιστό.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Web site contiene tres secciones. La 
primera conexión conduce a una presentación apuntada en las pupilas,
en las cuales Maija se contrata a la experiencia profesional práctica
para un periódico y consigue la ocasión de procesar imágenes 
digital. El material para el profesor contiene dos secciones. 
"imágenes de Digital: las instrucciones para el profesor 
"contienen respuestas a las preguntas siguientes: ¿Qué debe un 
profesor saber? ¿Para quién el material se piensa? ¿Qué 
debe la pupila poder hacer? ¿Cómo learning/studies está 
progresando? La segunda parte es un documento del pdf "las bases
de la imagen digital", que examina los asuntos siguientes: 
Análogo contra el digital, las originales, las fuentes de una 
imagen digital, las otras fuentes, resolución, gráficos a memoria de
imagen, los tipos principales de imagen digital, los gráficos y los 
colores, gráficos del vector, explorando con un explorador flatbed, 
los formatos más comunes de la imagen y salvando una imagen en el 
Web.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">viestintä</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">viestintä</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">viestintä</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">viestintä</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">viestintδ</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">viestintä</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Mia Ristimäki
n:Ristimäki;Mia
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Christian Komonen
n:Komonen;Christian
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Peter Westerlund
n:Westerlund;Peter
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Set Erdman
n:Erdman;Set
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Tove Enkvist
n:Enkvist;Tove
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/663C335B-C854-C6E0-4FAB-57B89D8EB52F</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/663C335B-C854-C6E0-4FAB-57B89D8EB52F</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Anna-Elina Häkkilä
n:Häkkilä;Anna-Elina 
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>fi</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE)
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE)
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE)
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2009-04-09T19:44:02.23Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>presentation</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>guide</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">13-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Creative commons Nimeä-epäkaupallinen-Ei muutettuja teoksia 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>238</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>717</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>80737</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/ict/kuvankasittely</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
