<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222643</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222643</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi/page.asp?path=498;1329;1528;21094;19155;53312</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/page.asp?path=498;1329;1528;21094;19155;53312</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/page.asp?path=498;1329;1528;21094;19155;53312</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Cross-country skiing</string>
            <string language="fi">Maastohiihto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Querfeldeinskiing</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ski de fond</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Skiing cross-country</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Corsa con gli sci che attraversa il paese</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανώμαλο να κάνει σκι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esquí a campo través</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Cross-country skiing as a form of school sport can offer a host of positive experiences and excitement in winter nature. Cross-country skiing is an outdoor sport that stresses the body in a variety of ways and can be used to develop one’s own physical capacity and basic motor skills. The purpose of the website is for the teacher to find quickly and effectively support for the planning and implementation of the content of his/her lessons. The website contains instructions for the teacher, information on equipment and lubrication, guidance on various skiing techniques, tips for skiing play and games as well as instructions arranged by age-group, the purpose of which is to help the teacher to choose appropriate teaching contents.</string>
            <string language="fi">Maastohiihto koululiikuntamuotona voi tarjota runsaasti positiivisia kokemuksia ja elämyksiä talvisessa luonnossa. Maastohiihto on monipuolisesti kehoa kuormittava ulkoliikuntalaji, jonka avulla voi hyvin kehittää omaa fyysistä toimintakykyä ja motorisia perusvalmiuksia. Verkkosivuston tarkoituksena on, että opettaja löytäisi nopeasti ja tehokkaasti tuen oppituntiensa sisällön suunnitteluun ja toteutukseen. Sivusto sisältää ohjeita opettajalle, tietoa välineistä ja voitelusta, opastuksen eri hiihtotekniikoihin, vinkkejä hiihtoleikeiksi ja -peleiksi sekä vuosiluokittain jäsennettyjä ohjeita, joiden tarkoituksena on auttaa opettajaa tarkoituksenmukaisten opetussisältöjen valitsemisessa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Querfeldeinskiing als Formular des Schulesports 
kann einen Hauptrechner der positiven Erfahrungen und der Aufregung in
der Winternatur anbieten. Querfeldeinskiing ist ein im 
Freiensport, der den Körper in einer Vielzahl von Methoden betont und
verwendet werden kann, one?s zu entwickeln, die körperliche 
Kapazität und die grundlegenden Bewegungsfähigkeiten zu besitzen. 
Der Zweck der Web site ist, damit der Lehrer schnell findet und 
effektiv für die Planung und die Implementierung des Inhalts sein/ihr
Lektionen unterstützt. Die Web site enthält Anweisungen zu dem
Lehrer, Information über Ausrüstung und Schmierung, Anleitung auf 
verschiedenen Skiingtechniken, Spitzen für Skiingspiel und Spielen 
sowie die Anweisungen, die durch Altersklasse geordnet werden, dessen 
Zweck ist, dem Lehrer zu helfen, passenden unterrichtenden Inhalt zu 
wählen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le ski de fond comme forme de sport d'école peut
offrir un centre serveur des expériences et d'excitation positives en
nature d'hiver. Le ski de fond est un sport en plein air qui 
souligne le corps par une multitude de moyens et peut être utilisé 
pour développer des one?s pour posséder la capacité physique et les
habiletés motrices de base. Le but du site Web est pour que le 
professeur trouve rapidement et à supporte pertinemment pour la 
planification et la mise en place de la teneur de ses leçons. 
Le site Web contient des instructions pour le professeur, 
l'information sur le matériel et la lubrification, des conseils sur 
de diverses techniques de ski, des extrémités pour le jeu de ski et 
des jeux comme des instructions disposées par le groupe d'âge, dont 
le but est d'aider le professeur à choisir le contenu d'enseignement 
approprié.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O skiing cross-country como um formulário do 
esporte da escola pode oferecer um anfitrião de experiências e do 
excitamento positivos na natureza do inverno. O skiing 
cross-country é um esporte ao ar livre que force o corpo em uma 
variedade das maneiras e possa ser usado desenvolver one?s para 
possuir a capacidade física e habilidades de motor básicas. A 
finalidade do Web site é para que o professor encontre rapidamente e 
suporte eficazmente para o planeamento e a execução do índice de 
his/her lições. O Web site contem instruções para o 
professor, a informação no equipamento e na lubrificação, a 
orientação em várias técnicas do skiing, as pontas para o jogo do 
skiing e os jogos assim como as instruções arranjadas pelo 
age-group, a finalidade de que é ajudar ao professor escolher 
índices ensinando apropriados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La corsa con gli sci che attraversa il paese come
forma dello sport della scuola può offrire un calcolatore centrale 
delle esperienze e dell'eccitamento positivi in natura di inverno. 
La corsa con gli sci che attraversa il paese è uno sport 
esterno che sollecita il corpo in una varietà di modi e può essere 
usato sviluppare i one?s per possedere la capienza fisica e le 
abilità motorie di base. Lo scopo del Web site è affinchè 
l'insegnante trovi rapidamente e da contributo efficacemente alla 
progettazione ed all'implementazione del contenuto delle sue lezioni. 
Il Web site contiene le istruzioni per l'insegnante, le 
informazioni su apparecchiatura e su lubrificazione, il consiglio 
sulle varie tecniche di corsa con gli sci, le punte per il gioco di 
corsa con gli sci ed i giochi come pure le istruzioni organizzate 
dalla fascia d'età, lo scopo di cui è aiutare l'insegnante a 
scegliere il soddisfare d'istruzione adatto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανώμαλο να κάνει σκι ως μορφή του σχολικού αθλητισμού
μπορεί να προσφέρει έναν πλήθο της θετικών εμπειρίας και του 
ενθουσιασμού στη χειμερινή φύση. Ανώμαλο να κάνει σκι 
είναι ένας υπαίθριος αθλητισμός που τονίζει το σώμα με 
ποικίλους τρόπους και μπορεί να χρησιμοποιηθεί για να αναπτύξει 
τη φυσική ικανότητα one?s και τις βασικές δεξιότητες μηχανών. 
Ο σκοπός του ιστοχώρου είναι για το δάσκαλο να βρεί 
γρήγορα και αποτελεσματικά υποστήριξη για τον προγραμματισμό και 
την εφαρμογή του περιεχομένου των μαθημάτων του/της. Ο 
ιστοχώρος περιέχει τις οδηγίες για το δάσκαλο, τις πληροφορίες 
για τον εξοπλισμό και τη λίπανση, καθοδήγηση στις διάφορες να 
κάνει σκι τεχνικές, τις άκρες για να κάνει σκι το παιχνίδι και τα
παιχνίδια καθώς επίσης και τις οδηγίες που τακτοποιούνται από 
την κλάση, ο σκοπός της οποίας είναι να ενισχυθεί ο δάσκαλος για
να επιλέξει το κατάλληλο περιεχόμενο διδασκαλίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El esquí a campo través como forma de deporte 
de la escuela puede ofrecer un ordenador principal de experiencias y 
del entusiasmo positivos en naturaleza del invierno. El esquí a
campo través es un deporte al aire libre que tensiona el cuerpo en 
una variedad de maneras y se puede utilizar desarrollar one?s para 
poseer capacidad física y habilidades de motor básicas. El 
propósito del Web site está para que el profesor encuentre 
rápidamente y utilice con eficacia para las hojas de operación 
(planning) y la puesta en práctica del contenido de su lecciones. 
El Web site contiene las instrucciones para el profesor, la 
información sobre el equipo y la lubricación, la dirección en 
varias técnicas del esquí, las extremidades para el juego del esquí
y los juegos tan bien como las instrucciones dispuestas por el grupo 
de misma edad, el propósito de el cual es ayudar al profesor a elegir
contenido de enseñanza apropiado.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Suomen hiihtoliitto
n:Suomen hiihtoliitto
org:Suomen hiihtoliitto
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/439D79F1-AC55-96C4-7D08-2310E718D21A</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/439D79F1-AC55-96C4-7D08-2310E718D21A</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Annika Ranta
n:Ranta;Annika 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-03-14T00:43:18.75Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>guide</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>vocational education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">7-15</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://www.edu.fi/page.asp?path=498,507,19640</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>1392</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>974</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi/page.asp?path=498;1329;1528;21094;19155;53312</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/page.asp?path=498;1329;1528;21094;19155;53312</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
