<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222696</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222696</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/markkinointisuunnitelma</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/markkinointisuunnitelma</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/markkinointisuunnitelma</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Marketing plan</string>
            <string language="fi">Markkinointisuunitelma</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Marketing-Plan</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Plan de vente</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Planta do marketing</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Programma di vendita</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σχέδιο μάρκετινγκ</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Plan de la comercialización</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The web material can be used to draw up a company’s marketing plan. The first section of the website provides background information on the marketing of a small or medium-sized business and on drawing up a marketing plan. The material contains links which can be used to search for information also in materials outside the study material. Mastery of learned content can be tested with exercises and tasks. In the second section of the website, students are shown how to draw up a marketing plan, which opens in doc format.</string>
            <string language="fi">Verkkomateriaalin avulla voidaan laatia yrityksen markkinointisuunnitelma. Sivuston ensimmäinen osio tarjoaa taustatietoa pienen tai keskisuuren yrityksen markkinoinnista ja markkinointisuunnitelman laatimisesta. Aineisto sisältää linkkejä, joiden avulla voi etsiä tietoa myös oppimateriaalin ulkopuolisista aineistoista. Harjoituksilla ja tehtävillä voidaan testata opittujen sisältöjen hallintaa. Sivuston toisessa osiossa laaditaan ohjatusti markkinointisuunnitelma, joka avautuu doc-muodossa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Web-Material kann benutzt werden, um einen 
company?s Marketing-Plan aufzustellen. Das erste Kapitel der Web
site stellt Hintergrundinformationen auf dem Marketing eines kleinen 
oder mittelgrossen Geschäfts und auf dem Aufstellen eines 
Marketing-Planes zur Verfügung. Das Material enthält Links, 
die verwendet werden können, um nach Informationen in den Materialien
außerhalb des Studie Materials auch zu suchen. Beherrschung des
gelehrten Inhalts kann mit Übungen und Aufgaben geprüft werden. 
Im zweiten Kapitel der Web site, werden Kursteilnehmer gezeigt, 
wie man einen Marketing-Plan aufstellt, der im Doc. Format sich 
öffnet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le matériel de Web peut être employé pour 
élaborer un plan de vente de company?s. La première section du
site Web fournit l'information de fond sur le marketing de petites ou 
moyennes affaires et sur élaborer un plan de vente. Le 
matériel contient les liens qui peuvent être employés pour 
rechercher l'information également en matériaux en dehors du 
matériel d'étude. La maîtrise du contenu instruit peut être 
testée avec des exercices et charge. Dans la 
deuxième section du site Web, des étudiants sont montrés comment 
élaborer un plan de vente, qui s'ouvre dans le format de Doc..</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O material do Web pode ser usado desenhar acima 
de uma planta do marketing dos company?s. A primeira seção do 
Web site fornece a informação de fundo no marketing de um negócio 
pequeno ou de tamanho médio e em desenhar acima de uma planta do 
marketing. O material contem as ligações que podem ser usadas 
procurarar também pela informação nos materiais fora do material do
estudo. O mastery de índice instruído pode ser testado com 
exercícios e tarefas. Na segunda seção do Web site, os 
estudantes são mostrados como desenhar acima de uma planta do 
marketing, que abra no formato do doc.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il materiale di Web può essere usato per 
elaborare un programma di vendita dei company?s. La prima 
sezione del Web site fornisce le informazioni di base 
sull'introduzione sul mercato di piccolo o commercio di medie 
dimensioni e sull'elaborazione del programma di vendita. Il 
materiale contiene i collegamenti che possono essere usati per cercare
le informazioni anche in materiali fuori del materiale di studio. 
La padronanza del soddisfare istruito può essere esaminata con 
le esercitazioni e le mansioni. Nella seconda sezione del Web 
site, gli allievi sono indicati come elaborare un programma di 
vendita, che si apre nel formato del documento.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το υλικό Ιστού μπορεί να χρησιμοποιηθεί για να 
συντάξει ένα σχέδιο μάρκετινγκ company?s. Το πρώτο 
τμήμα του ιστοχώρου παρέχει τις βασικές πληροφορίες για το 
μάρκετινγκ μιας μικρής ή μεσαίας επιχείρησης και για τη σύνταξη 
ενός σχεδίου μάρκετινγκ. Το υλικό περιέχει τις συνδέσεις 
που μπορούν να χρησιμοποιηθούν στην αναζήτηση των πληροφοριών 
επίσης στα υλικά έξω από το υλικό μελέτης. Η κυριότητα 
του μαθημένου περιεχομένου μπορεί να εξεταστεί με τις ασκήσεις 
και τις στοιχειώδεις εργασίες. Στο δεύτερο τμήμα του 
ιστοχώρου, οι σπουδαστές εμφανίζονται πώς να συντάξουν ένα 
σχέδιο μάρκετινγκ, το οποίο ανοίγει με τη μορφή εγγράφου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El material del Web se puede utilizar para trazar
encima de un plan de la comercialización de los company?s. La 
primera sección del Web site proporciona a la información de fondo 
en la comercialización de un negocio pequeño o de tamaño mediano y 
en la elaboración de un plan de la comercialización. El 
material contiene las conexiones que se pueden utilizar para buscar 
para la información también en materiales fuera del material del 
estudio. La maestría del contenido docto se puede probar con 
ejercicios y tareas. En la segunda sección del Web site, 
muestran los estudiantes cómo trazar encima de un plan de la 
comercialización, que se abre en formato del doc..</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Eila Jussila
n:Jussila;Eila
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Teijo Human
n:Human;Teijo
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/73A2EE1A-B4CA-6A2F-0A31-6D94AEC80812</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/73A2EE1A-B4CA-6A2F-0A31-6D94AEC80812</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pertti Siekkinen
n:Siekkinen;Pertti 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-03-14T00:45:51.67Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>guide</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>vocational education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">16-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Nimeä-Epäkaupallinen-Ei muutettuja teoksia 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>1369</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>428</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>238</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>168</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>784</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/markkinointisuunnitelma</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/markkinointisuunnitelma</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
