<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222597</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222597</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www2.edu.fi/etalukio/yrittajyysvayla/?page=11</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www2.edu.fi/etalukio/yrittajyysvayla/?page=11</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www2.edu.fi/etalukio/yrittajyysvayla/?page=11</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Entrepreneurship on the individual level</string>
            <string language="fi">Yrittäjyys yksilötasolla</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Unternehmergeisten auf der einzelnen Stufe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Esprit d'entreprise au niveau individuel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Empreendimento no nível individual</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Attività imprenditoriale al livello specifico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιχειρηματικό πνεύμα στο μεμονωμένο επίπεδο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Espíritu emprendedor en el nivel individual</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Looks at factors influencing entrepreneurship on the individual level in five parts. The objective is to view entrepreneurship from the individual's perspective and create an overview of the debate on the characteristics, motivation and values of the entrepreneur, as well as the problems attached to their scrutiny. An additional aim is to form an understanding of the entrepreneurial process and the close networks of the entrepreneur as well as their principal components. Includes exercises, tests, links and further reading.</string>
            <string language="fi">Käsittelee yrittäjyyteen yksilötasolla vaikuttavia tekijöitä viidessä eri osiossa. Tavoitteena on esitellä yrittäjyyttä yksilön näkökulmasta ja tuottaa kokonaisvaltainen näkökulma yrittäjän ominaisuuksiin, motivaatioon ja arvoihin liittyvästä keskustelusta sekä niiden tarkasteluun liittyvistä ongelmista. Tavoitteena on lisäksi muodostaa ymmärrys yrittäjyysprosessista ja yrittäjän lähiverkoista, sekä niihin liittyvistä keskeisistä osatekijöistä. Sisältää tehtäviä, testejä, linkkejä ja lisäkirjallisuutta.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Blicke auf die Faktoren, die Unternehmergeisten 
auf der einzelnen Stufe in fünf Teilen beeinflussen. Das 
Lernziel ist, Unternehmergeisten von der Perspektive der Einzelperson 
anzusehen und einen Überblick über die Debatte auf den 
Eigenschaften, dem Beweggrund und den Werten des Unternehmers, sowie 
die Probleme zu erstellen, die zu ihrer Nachforschung angebracht 
werden. Ein zusätzliches Ziel ist, ein Verständnis des 
unternehmerischen Prozesses und die nahen Netze des Unternehmers sowie
ihre allgemeinen Bestandteile zu bilden. Schließt Übungen, 
Tests, Links und weiteren Messwert ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Regards aux facteurs influençant l'esprit 
d'entreprise au niveau individuel dans cinq parts. L'objectif 
est visualiser l'esprit d'entreprise de la perspective de l'individu 
et de créer une vue d'ensemble de la discussion sur les 
caractéristiques, la motivation et les valeurs de l'entrepreneur, 
comme les problèmes attachés à leur examen minutieux. Un but 
supplémentaire est de former un arrangement du processus entreprenant
et les réseaux étroits de l'entrepreneur aussi bien que leurs 
composants principaux. Inclut des exercices, des essais, des 
liens et davantage de lecture.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Olhares nos fatores que influenciam o 
empreendimento no nível individual em cinco porções. O 
objetivo é ver o empreendimento do perspective do indivíduo e criar 
uma vista geral do debate nas características, no motivation e nos 
valores do empreendedor, assim como os problemas unidos a seu 
scrutiny. Um alvo adicional é dar forma a uma compreensão do 
processo entrepreneurial e às redes próximas do empreendedor 
as.well.as seus componentes principais. Inclui exercícios, 
testes, ligações e uma leitura mais adicional.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sguardi ai fattori che influenzano attività 
imprenditoriale al livello specifico in cinque parti. 
L'obiettivo è di osservare l'attività imprenditoriale dalla 
prospettiva dell'individuo e creare una descrizione del dibattito 
sulle caratteristiche, sulla motivazione e sui valori 
dell'imprenditore, come pure i problemi fissati al loro esame 
accurato. Uno scopo supplementare è formare una comprensione 
del processo imprenditoriale e le reti vicine dell'imprenditore così 
come le loro componenti principali. Include le esercitazioni, le
prove, i collegamenti ed ulteriore lettura.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εξετάζει τους παράγοντες που επηρεάζουν το 
επιχειρηματικό πνεύμα στο μεμονωμένο επίπεδο σε πέντε μέρη. 
Ο στόχος είναι να εμφανιστεί το επιχειρηματικό πνεύμα από 
την προοπτική του ατόμου και να δημιουργηθεί μια επισκόπηση της 
συζήτησης σχετικά με τα χαρακτηριστικά, το κίνητρο και τις τιμές 
του επιχειρηματία, καθώς επίσης και τα προβλήματα που συνδέονται 
με τη διερεύνησή τους. Ένας πρόσθετος στόχος είναι να 
διαμορφωθεί μια κατανόηση της επιχειρηματικής διαδικασίας και τα 
στενά δίκτυα του επιχειρηματία καθώς επίσης και των κύριων 
συστατικών τους. Περιλαμβάνει τις ασκήσεις, τις δοκιμές, τις
συνδέσεις και την περαιτέρω ανάγνωση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Miradas en los factores que influencian espíritu 
emprendedor en el nivel individual en cinco porciones. El 
objetivo es visión espíritu emprendedor de la perspectiva del 
individuo y crear una descripción del discusión sobre las 
características, la motivación y los valores del empresario, tan 
bien como los problemas asociados a su escrutinio. Una puntería
adicional es formar una comprensión del proceso emprendedor y las 
redes cercanas del empresario así como sus componentes principales. 
Incluye ejercicios, pruebas, conexiones y la lectura adicional.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Turun kauppakorkeaekoulun PK-Instituutti
n:Turun kauppakorkeaekoulun PK-Instituutti
org:Turun kauppakorkeaekoulun PK-Instituutti
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/46354609-1684-B276-4B38-5C45AE72C8EB</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/46354609-1684-B276-4B38-5C45AE72C8EB</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pekka Pirhonen
n:Pirhonen;Pekka 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:49:42.45Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>course</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">15-19</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://www02.oph.fi/etalukio/kayttoehdot/</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>428</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>846</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>429</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>169</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www2.edu.fi/etalukio/yrittajyysvayla/?page=11</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www2.edu.fi/etalukio/yrittajyysvayla/?page=11</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
