<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222536</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222536</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www02.oph.fi/etalukio/aidinkieli/kurssin_etusivu.html</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www02.oph.fi/etalukio/aidinkieli/kurssin_etusivu.html</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www02.oph.fi/etalukio/aidinkieli/kurssin_etusivu.html</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Text structures and meanings</string>
            <string language="fi">Tekstin rakenteita ja merkityksiä</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Textstrukturen und -bedeutungen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Structures et significations des textes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Estruturas e meanings do texto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Strutture e significati del testo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δομές και έννοιες κειμένων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Estructuras y significados del texto</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Support material for the course of factual texts with basic instructions for writing, text interpretation and reading. Teaches to observe the characteristics of various text genres and to take account of the listener or reader of the speech or text. Challenges to gradual improvement of one’s work, i.e., so-called process writing. Also revises information retrieval and correct spelling. Contains exercises. The subject matter of most texts preparing for the exercises deals with work or the relation to work.</string>
            <string language="fi">Tukimateriaalia asiatekstien kurssille, jossa saa kirjoittamisen sekä tekstin tulkinnan ja lukemisen perusohjeita. Opettaa tarkkailemaan eri tekstilajien piirteitä ja ottamaan huomioon puheen tai kirjoitelman kuulijan tai lukijan. Haastaa vaiheittaiseen työn parantamiseen eli ns. prosessikirjoittamiseen. Kertaa myös tiedonhankintaa ja oikeinkirjoitusta. Sisältää tehtäviä. Useimpien tehtäviin virittävien tekstien aihepiiri käsittelee työntekoa, suhdetta työhön.
Valikossa luvattu sanasto ei ole vielä valmis - tulossa myöhemmin.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hilfsmaterial für den Kurs der auf Tatsachen 
beruhenden Texte mit grundlegenden Anweisungen für Schreiben, 
Textdeutung und Messwert. Unterrichtet, um die Eigenschaften der
verschiedenen Textgenren zu beobachten und den Zuhörer oder den Leser
der Rede oder des Textes zu berücksichtigen. Herausforderungen 
zur stufenweisen Verbesserung von one?s bearbeiten d.h. sogenanntes 
Prozeßschreiben. Verbessert auch Information Retrieval und 
korrekte Rechtschreibung. Enthält Übungen. Das Thema der
meisten Texte, die für die Übungen sich vorbereiten, beschäftigt 
Arbeit oder die Relation, um zu arbeiten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Matériel de support pour le cours des textes 
effectifs avec des instructions de base pour l'écriture, la 
traduction des textes et la lecture. Enseigne à observer les 
caractéristiques de divers genres des textes et à tenir compte de 
l'auditeur ou du lecteur du discours ou du texte. Les défis à 
l'amélioration progressive des one?s fonctionnent, c.-à-d., la 
prétendue écriture de processus. Met à jour en outre la 
recherche documentaire et l'épellation correcte. Contient des 
exercices. Les thèmes de la plupart des textes se préparant 
aux exercices traitent le travail ou la relation pour fonctionner.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Material de sustentação para o curso de textos 
factual com instruções básicas para a escrita, a interpretação do
texto e a leitura. Ensina para observar as características de 
vários genres do texto e para fazer exame do cliente do ouvinte ou do
leitor do discurso ou do texto. Os desafios à melhoria gradual 
dos one?s trabalham, isto é, escrita process so-called. Revisa 
também a recuperação de informação e a soletração correta. 
Contem exercícios. A matéria sujeita de a maioria de 
textos que preparam-se para os exercícios trata do trabalho ou da 
relação para trabalhar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Materiale di sostegno per il corso dei testi 
effettivi con le istruzioni di base per scrittura, l'interpretazione 
del testo e la lettura. Insegna per osservare le caratteristiche
di vari generi del testo e per tenere conto dell'ascoltatore o 
del lettore del discorso o del testo. Le sfide a miglioramento 
graduale dei one?s funzionano, cioè, la cosiddetta scrittura 
trattata. Egualmente modifica il reperimento delle informazioni 
e l'ortografia corretta. Contiene le esercitazioni. Il 
tema della maggior parte dei testi che si preparano per le 
esercitazioni si occupa di lavoro o del rapporto per funzionare.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Υλικό υποστήριξης για την πορεία των πραγματικών 
κειμένων με τις βασικές οδηγίες για το γράψιμο, την ερμηνεία 
κειμένων και την ανάγνωση. Διδάσκει για να παρατηρηθούν τα 
χαρακτηριστικά των διάφορων υφών κειμένων και για να ληφθεί 
υπόψη ο ακροατής ή ο αναγνώστης της ομιλίας ή του κειμένου. 
Οι προκλήσεις στη βαθμιαία βελτίωση one?s λειτουργούν, 
δηλ., το αποκαλούμενο γράψιμο διαδικασίας. Επίσης αναθεωρεί
την ανάκτηση πληροφοριών και τη σωστή ορθογραφία. Περιέχει 
τις ασκήσεις. Το περιεχόμενο των περισσότερων κειμένων που 
προετοιμάζονται για τις ασκήσεις εξετάζει την εργασία ή τη σχέση
με την εργασία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Material de ayuda para el curso de textos 
efectivos con las instrucciones básicas para la escritura, la 
interpretación del texto y la lectura. Enseña para observar 
las características de los varios géneros del texto y para tomar 
cuenta del módulo de escucha o del programa de lectura del discurso o
del texto. Los desafíos a la mejora gradual de one?s trabajan, 
es decir, la escritura de proceso supuesta. También revisa la 
recuperación de datos y el deletreo correcto. Contiene 
ejercicios. El tema de la mayoría de los textos que se preparan
para los ejercicios se ocupa del trabajo o de la relación para 
trabajar.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Marita Peltoniemi
n:Peltoniemi;Marita
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Lassi Peltoniemi
n:Peltoniemi;Lassi
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/CE6F9DA4-0667-CB5F-09A4-9B986707DD91</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/CE6F9DA4-0667-CB5F-09A4-9B986707DD91</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pekka Pirhonen
n:Pirhonen;Pekka 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:50:22.65Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>course</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>glossary</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">15-19</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://www02.oph.fi/etalukio/kayttoehdot/</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>556</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1306</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1411</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1018</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1410</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www02.oph.fi/etalukio/aidinkieli/kurssin_etusivu.html</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www02.oph.fi/etalukio/aidinkieli/kurssin_etusivu.html</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
