<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/26232</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>26232</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
    <entry>skolverket_7073</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:spindeln.iml.umu.se:skolverket_7073</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
            <entry>skolverket_7073</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">21F.151 Chinese I (Regular), Spring 2006 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Chinese 21F.151 I (Regelmäßig), Frühling 2006 
(MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Chinois 21F.151 I (Régulier), Le Printemps 2006 
(MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Chinês 21F.151 I (Regular), Mola 2006 (Mit)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">21F.151 Cinese I (Normale), Primavera 2006 
(Mit)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">21F.151 κινεζικό ι (κανονικό), άνοιξη του 2006 
(MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Chino 21F.151 I (Regular), Resorte 2006 (Mit)</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An online course from the MIT OpenCourseWare website (http://ocw.mit.edu) operated by Massachusetts Institute of Technology. This course material is free for anyone to use who accept the terms and conditions of use. The description of this course, published on the MIT OpenCourseWare website, is: "Introduction to modern standard Chinese (Mandarin) with emphasis on developing conversational skills by using fundamental grammatical patterns and vocabulary in functional and cultural suitable contexts. Basic reading and writing are also taught. Work in the language laboratory is coordinated with, and supplemented to, class work. For graduate credit, see 21F.151.  Description from course home page:  This subject is the first semester of two that form an introduction to modern standard Chinese, commonly called Mandarin. Though not everyone taking this course will be an absolute beginner, the course presupposes no prior background in the language. The purpose of this course is to develop:  Basic conversational abilities (pronunciation, fundamental grammatical patterns, common vocabulary, and standard usage)  Basic reading and writing skills (in both the traditional character set and the simplified)  An understanding of the language learning process so that you are able to continue studying effectively on your own.  The main text is Wheatley, J. K. Learning Chinese: A Foundation Course in Mandarin. Part I. (unpublished, but available online). (Part II of the book forms the basis of 21F.102 / 152, which is also published on OpenCourseWare.)  "</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Foreign Languages and Literatures</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Chinese</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Speaking</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Writing</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Chinese Language and Literature</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">China</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Asia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mandarin</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">21F.151</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Language</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Culture</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Onlinekurs von der MIT OpenCourseWare Web site
(http://ocw.mit.edu) funktionierte durch Massachusetts Institute of 
Technology. Dieses Kursmaterial ist frei, damit jedermann 
verwendet, wem die Bedingungen des Gebrauches annehmen. Die 
Beschreibung dieses Kurses, veröffentlicht auf der MIT OpenCourseWare
Web site, ist: "Einleitung in einen modernen Standardchinesen 
(Mandarine) mit Betonung auf dem Entwickeln von von 
Unterhaltungsfähigkeiten durch das Verwenden der grundlegenden 
grammatischen Muster und des Wortschatzes in den Funktions- und 
kulturellen verwendbaren Kontexten. Grundlegender Messwert und 
Schreiben werden auch unterrichtet. Arbeit im Sprachenlabor wird
mit koordiniert und ergänzt zu, Kategorie Arbeit. Für 
graduierte Gutschrift sehen Sie Beschreibung 21F.151. vom Kurshome 
Page: Dieses Thema ist das erste Semester von zwei, die eine 
Einleitung zu modernem Standardchinesischem bilden, geläufig genannt 
Mandarin. Obwohl nicht jeder, der diesen Kurs nimmt, ein 
absoluter Anfänger ist, setzt der Kurs keinen vorherigen Hintergrund 
in der Sprache voraus. Der Zweck dieses Kurses ist sich zu 
entwickeln: Grundlegende Unterhaltungsfähigkeiten (Aussprache, 
grundlegende grammatische Muster, geläufiger Wortschatz und 
Standardverbrauch) grundlegende Lese- und Schreibenfähigkeiten (im 
traditionellen Zeichensatz und in vereinfacht) ein Verständnis des 
Erlernen der Spracheprozesses, damit Sie können, effektiv, zu 
studieren auf Ihren Selbst fortzufahren. Der Haupttext ist 
Wheatley, J. K. Learning Chinese: Ein Grundlage Kurs in der 
Mandarine. Teil I. (unveröffentlicht, aber vorhandenes Online).
(der Teil II des Buches bildet die Grundlage von 21F.102/152, 
das auch auf OpenCourseWare. veröffentlicht wird) "</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un cours en ligne du site Web de MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) a fonctionné par 
massachusetts.institute.of.technology. Ce matériel de cours est
libre pour que n'importe qui utilise qui reçoivent les modalités et 
les conditions de l'utilisation. La description de ce cours, 
éditée sur le site Web de MIT OpenCourseWare, est : 
"introduction au Chinois standard moderne (mandarine) avec 
l'accent sur développer des qualifications conversationnelles en 
utilisant les configurations et le vocabulaire grammaticaux 
fondamentaux dans des contextes appropriés fonctionnels et culturels.
On enseigne également la lecture et l'écriture de base. 
Le travail dans le laboratoire de langage est coordonné avec, 
et supplément, au travail de classe. Pour le degré de solvabilité 
gradué, voir la description 21F.151. du Home Page de cours : Ce
sujet est le premier semestre de deux qui forment une introduction à 
chinois standard moderne, généralement appelé Mandarin. Bien 
que pas chacun prenant ce cours soit un débutant absolu, le cours ne 
présuppose aucun fond antérieur dans le langage. Le but de ce 
cours est de se développer : Qualifications de base 
conversationnelles de base de lecture et d'écriture de capacités 
(prononciation, configurations grammaticales fondamentales, 
vocabulaire commun, et utilisation standard) (dans le jeu de 
caractères traditionnel et simplifiés) un arrangement du processus 
de connaissance des langues de sorte que vous puissiez continuer 
d'étudier pertinemment sur vos propres. Le texte principal est 
Wheatley, J. K. Learning Chinese : Un cours de base en 
mandarine. Partie I. (non publiée, mais accessible en ligne). 
(la partie II du livre forme la base de 21F.102/152, qui est 
également édité sur OpenCourseWare.) "</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um curso em linha do Web site do MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) operou-se por Instituto de 
Tecnología de Massachusetts. Este material do curso está livre
para que qualquer um use-se quem aceitam os termos e as condições do
uso. A descrição deste curso, publicada no Web site do MIT 
OpenCourseWare, é: "introdução ao chinês padrão moderno 
(mandarin) com ênfase em desenvolver habilidades de conversação 
usando testes padrões e o vocabulário gramaticais fundamentais em 
contextos apropriados funcionais e cultural. A leitura e a 
escrita básicas são ensinadas também. O trabalho no 
laboratório da língua é coordenado com, e suplementado, a trabalho 
da classe. Para o crédito graduado, veja a descrição 21F.151.
do Home Page do curso: Este assunto é o primeiro semester de 
dois que dão forma a uma introdução a chinês padrão moderno, 
chamado geralmente Mandarin. Embora não todos que faz exame 
deste curso será um novato absoluto, o curso não presupposes nenhum 
fundo prévio na língua. A finalidade deste curso é tornar-se:
Habilidades básicas de conversação básicas da leitura e da 
escrita das abilidades (pronunciação, testes padrões gramaticais 
fundamentais, vocabulário comum, e uso padrão) (em ambos o jogo e 
tradicionais do caráter simplificados) uma compreensão do processo 
de aprendizagem da língua de modo que você possa  continuar 
estudando eficazmente no seus próprios. O texto principal é 
Wheatley, J. K. Learning Chinês: Um curso da fundação no 
mandarin. Parte I. (unpublished, mas em linha disponível). 
(a parte II do livro dá forma à base de 21F.102/152, que é 
publicado também em OpenCourseWare.) "</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un corso in linea dal Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) ha funzionato da Massachusetts 
Institute of Technology. Questo materiale di corso è libero 
affinchè chiunque usi chi accettano i termini e le condizioni di uso.
La descrizione di questo corso, pubblicata sul Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare, è: "introduzione al cinese standard 
moderno (mandarino) con l'enfasi sullo sviluppare le abilità 
colloquiali usando i modelli e vocabolario grammaticali fondamentali 
nei contesti adatti funzionali e culturali. La lettura e la 
scrittura di base egualmente sono insegnate. Il lavoro nel 
laboratorio di linguaggio è coordinato con e supplemento, al lavoro 
del codice categoria. Per accreditamento laureato, veda la 
descrizione 21F.151. dal Home Page di corso: Questo oggetto è 
il primo semestre di due che formano un'introduzione a cinese 
standard moderno, comunemente chiamato Mandarin. Benchè non 
tutto che prende questo corso sia un principiante assoluto, il corso 
non presuppone priorità bassa anteriore nel linguaggio. Lo 
scopo di questo corso è svilupparsi: Abilità di base 
colloquiali di base della lettura e di scrittura di abilità 
(pronuncia, modelli grammaticali fondamentali, vocabolario comune ed 
uso standard) (sia nella serie di caratteri tradizionale che in 
semplificati) una comprensione del processo di apprendimento delle 
lingue in modo che possiate continuare a studiare efficacemente sui 
vostri propri. Il testo principale è Wheatley, cinese del 
J. K. Learning: Un corso del fondamento in mandarino. 
Parte I. (non pubblicata, ma accessibile in linea). (parte
II del libro costituisce la base di 21F.102/152, che egualmente è 
pubblicato su OpenCourseWare.) "</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια σε απευθείας σύνδεση σειρά μαθημάτων από τον 
ιστοχώρο MIT OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) που 
χρησιμοποιείται από το ίδρυμα της Μασαχουσέτης τεχνολογίας. 
Αυτό το υλικό σειράς μαθημάτων είναι ελεύθερο για καθένα 
να χρησιμοποιήσει ποιοι αποδέχονται τους όρους και τους όρους 
χρησιμοποίησης. Η περιγραφή αυτής της σειράς μαθημάτων, που
δημοσιεύεται στον ιστοχώρο MIT OpenCourseWare, είναι: 
"Εισαγωγή στα σύγχρονα πρότυπα κινέζικα (κινεζική γλώσσα) 
με έμφαση στην ανάπτυξη των συνομιλητικών δεξιοτήτων με τη 
χρησιμοποίηση των θεμελιωδών γραμματικών προτύπων και του 
λεξιλογίου στα λειτουργικά και πολιτιστικά κατάλληλα πλαίσια. 
Η βασική ανάγνωση και το γράψιμο διδάσκονται επίσης. 
Η εργασία στο γλωσσικό εργαστήριο συντονίζεται με, και 
συμπληρώνεται, στην εργασία κλάσης. Για τη διαβαθμισμένη 
πίστωση, δείτε την περιγραφή 21F.151. από την αρχική
σελίδα σειράς μαθημάτων: Αυτό το θέμα είναι το πρώτο 
εξάμηνο δύο που διαμορφώνουν μια εισαγωγή σύγχρονο πρότυπο σε 
κινεζικό, αποκαλούμενος συνήθως κινεζική γλώσσα. Αν και 
όχι ο καθένας που παίρνει αυτήν την σειρά μαθημάτων θα είναι 
απόλυτος αρχάριος, η σειρά μαθημάτων δεν προϋποθέτει κανένα 
προγενέστερο υπόβαθρο στη γλώσσα. Ο σκοπός αυτής της 
σειράς μαθημάτων είναι να αναπτυχθεί: Βασικές 
συνομιλητικές δεξιότητες ανάγνωσης και σύνταξης εγγράφου 
δυνατοτήτων (προφορά, θεμελιώδη γραμματικά πρότυπα, κοινό 
λεξιλόγιο, και πρότυπη χρήση) βασικές (και στον παραδοσιακό 
κώδικα χαρακτήρα και σε απλουστευμένη) Μια κατανόηση της 
διαδικασίας εκμάθησης γλωσσών έτσι ώστε είστε σε θέση να 
συνεχίσετε αποτελεσματικά από μόνος σας. Το βασικό κείμενο
είναι Wheatley, Θ*ι. Κ. Learning Chinese: Μια 
προπαρασκευαστική σειρά μαθημάτων στην κινεζική γλώσσα. Part Ι. (αδημοσίευτο, αλλά απευθείας προσβάσιμο). (Το 
μέρος ΙΙ του βιβλίου αποτελεί τη βάση 21F.102/$l*152, η οποία 
δημοσιεύεται επίσης σε OpenCourseWare.) "</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un curso en línea del Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) funcionó por Instituto de 
Tecnología de Massachusetts. Este material del curso está 
libre para que cualquier persona utilice quiénes validan los 
términos y las condiciones del uso. La descripción de este 
curso, publicada en el Web site del MIT OpenCourseWare, es: 
"introducción al chino estándar moderno (mandarín) con 
énfasis sobre desarrollar habilidades conversacionales usando modelos
y vocabulario gramaticales fundamentales en contextos convenientes 
funcionales y culturales. La lectura y la escritura básicas 
también se enseñan. El trabajo en el laboratorio del lenguaje 
se coordina con, y se suple, al trabajo de la clase. Para el 
crédito graduado, vea la descripción 21F.151. del Home Page del 
curso: Este tema es el primer semestre de dos que formen una 
introducción a chino estándar moderno, comúnmente llamado Mandarin.
Aunque no cada uno que toma este curso será un principiante 
absoluto, el curso no presupone ningún fondo anterior en el lenguaje.
El propósito de este curso es convertirse: Habilidades 
básicas conversacionales básicas de la lectura y de la escritura de 
las capacidades (pronunciación, modelos gramaticales fundamentales, 
vocabulario común, y uso estándar) (en el juego de caracteres 
tradicional y simplificados) una comprensión del proceso del 
aprendizaje de idiomas de modo que usted pueda continuar estudiando 
con eficacia en sus el propios. El texto principal es Wheatley, 
J. K. Learning chinese: Un curso de la fundación en mandarín. 
Parte I. (inédita, pero accesible en línea). (la parte 
II del libro forma la base de 21F.102/152, que también se publica en 
OpenCourseWare.) "</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Fremdsprachen und Literatures</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Chinesisch</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sprechen</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Schreiben</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Chinesische Sprache und Literatur</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">China</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Asien</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mandarine</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">21F.151</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sprache</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kultur</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Langues étrangères et Literatures</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Chinois</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Parler</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Écriture</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Langue et littérature chinoises</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Chine</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">l'Asie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mandarine</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">21F.151</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Langage</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Culture</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Línguas extrangeiras e Literatures</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Chinês</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Discurso</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Escrita</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Língua e literatura chinesas</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">China</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ásia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Mandarin</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">21F.151</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Língua</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Cultura</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lingue straniere e Literatures</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Cinese</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Parlare</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scrittura</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Linguaggio cinese e letteratura</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Cina</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'Asia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Mandarino</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">21F.151</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Linguaggio</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Coltura</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ξένες γλώσσες και Literatures</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κινεζικά</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ομιλία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γράψιμο</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κινεζική γλώσσα και λογοτεχνία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κίνα</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ασία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κινεζική γλώσσα</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">21F.151</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γλώσσα</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πολιτισμός</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Idiomas extranjeros y Literatures</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Chino</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Discurso</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Escritura</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Lenguaje y literatura chinos</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">China</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Asia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mandarín</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">21F.151</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Lenguaje</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cultura</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Taawo;Alma
FN:Alma Taawo
ORG:skolverket
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>course</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>higher education</value>
          </context>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">18-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>707</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">language and literature</string>
                <string language="sv">-</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:spindeln.iml.umu.se:skolverket_7073-M</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
            <entry>skolverket_7073-M</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Taawo;Alma
FN:Alma Taawo
ORG:skolverket
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2009-03-15T19:49:30.0Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
N:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
ORG:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T06:34:22.87Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
      <entry>skolverket_7073</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://ocw.mit.edu/OcwWeb/Foreign-Languages-and-Literatures/21F-101Spring-2006/CourseHome/index.htm</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
