<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/227677</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>227677</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-UL-id</catalog>
    <entry>aspect:evizus_sl/10007</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:atlas.fri.uni-lj.si:aspect:evizus_sl/10007</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>lre</catalog>
            <entry>aspect:evizus_sl/10007</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="sl">Preglednice</string>
            <string language="en">Spreadsheets</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kalkulationstabellen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Tableurs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Spreadsheets</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fogli elettronici</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Υπολογισμοί με λογιστικό φύλλο (spreadsheet)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Hojas de balance</string>
          </title>
          <language>sl</language>
          <description>
            <string language="sl">Preglednice so, podobno kot druga orodja, obstajale mnogo pred programskimi orodji, kot jih poznamo in uporabljamo danes. Preglednice so uporabljala podjetja za lepši in razvidnejši prikaz poslovanja, računovodstva in podobnih dejavnosti, ki zahtevajo veliko količino finančnih podatkov za skupni prikaz in analizo. Pisati jih je bilo potrebno na roke, in pri spremembi enega podatka je bilo potrebno ročno popraviti cel niz drugih podatkov. To je zahtevalo ogromno časa in natančnosti, saj je najmanjša napaka pirpeljala do cele kopice napačnih podatkov. 

Danes je s programskimi paketi to mnogo lažje. Zato ogromno poklicev zahteva poznavanje osnov programov za delo s preglednicami. To znanje je priročno tudi za domačo uporabo pri mnogih opravilih (računanje, finance, statistika, ...). V nadaljevanju si bomo ogledali delo v dveh najpogosteje uporabljenih programih za delo s pregednicami in podali nekaj primerov uporabe.</string>
            <string language="en">Spreadsheets were developed long before computers were made and software we use today was developed. They were used by companies for better and clear presentation of reports, accounting and presentation of similar activities that need a lot of financial data for reviews and analysis. First they had to write them with hands, so imagine the time used to change one data and then repairing the whole sheet.

Today is much easier with computers. Basic spreadsheets knowledge is almost obligatory on most job positions. And this knowledge can be used elsewhere as well (calculus, statistics, finances, ...). We will so take a look at common features in two most widespread software packages for spreadsheets.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="sl">evizus</string>
            <string language="en">evizus</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="sl">preglednica</string>
            <string language="en">spreadsheet</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="sl">računovodstvo</string>
            <string language="en">accounting</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="sl">program</string>
            <string language="en">program</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kalkulationstabellen wurden entwickelt, lange 
zuvor Computer gebildet wurden und Software, die wir heute benutzen, 
entwickelt wurde. Sie wurden von den Firmen für bessere und 
freie Darstellung von Reports, von Buchhaltung und von Darstellung der
ähnlichen Aktivitäten benutzt, die eine Menge finanzielle Daten für
Zusammenfassungen und Analyse benötigen. Zuerst mußten sie sie
mit den Händen schreiben, also stellen Sie vor sich, daß die Zeit, 
die verwendet wird, um eine Daten und das vollständige sheet.Today 
dann reparieren zu ändern, mit Computern viel einfacher ist. 
Grundlegendes Kalkulationstabellen Wissen ist auf den meisten 
Jobpositionen fast obligatorisch. Und dieses Wissen kann 
anderwohin außerdem verwendet werden (Kalkül, Statistiken, 
Finanzen...). Wir werden, also nehmen Sie einen Blick an den 
geläufigen Merkmalen in zwei weitverbreitetesten Anwendungspaketen 
für Kalkulationstabellen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Des tableurs ont été développés longtemps 
avant que des ordinateurs aient été faits et le logiciel que nous 
utilisons aujourd'hui a été développé. Ils ont été 
employés par des compagnies pour une meilleure et claire 
présentation des états, de la comptabilité et de la présentation 
des activités semblables qui ont besoin de beaucoup de données 
financières pour des revues et l'analyse. D'abord ils ont dû 
les écrire avec des mains, ainsi imaginez que le temps employé pour 
changer une données et puis réparer le sheet.Today entier est 
beaucoup plus facile avec des ordinateurs. La connaissance de 
base de tableurs est presque obligatoire sur la plupart des positions 
du travail. Et cette connaissance peut être utilisée ailleurs 
aussi bien (calcul, statistiques, finances...). Nous  ainsi 
jetez un coup d'oeil aux dispositifs communs dans deux progiciels les 
plus répandus pour des tableurs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os spreadsheets foram desenvolvidos por muito 
tempo antes que os computadores estiveram feitos e o software que nós
nos usamos fosse desenvolvido hoje. Foram usados por companhias 
para a apresentação melhor e desobstruída dos relatórios, da 
contabilidade e da apresentação das atividades similares que 
necessitam muitos de dados financeiros para revisões e análise. 
Primeiramente tiveram que escrevê-los com mãos, assim que 
imagine que o tempo usado mudar um dados e então reparar o 
sheet.Today inteiro é muito mais fácil com computadores. O 
conhecimento básico dos spreadsheets é quase obligatory em a maioria
de posições do trabalho. E este conhecimento pode ser usado em
outra parte também (cálculo, statistics, finanças...). Nós  
assim que faça exame de um olhar em características comuns em dois 
pacotes de software os mais difundidos para spreadsheets.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I fogli elettronici sono stati sviluppati molto 
prima che i calcolatori fossero fatti ed il software che usiamo oggi 
fosse sviluppato. Sono stati usati dalle aziende per la 
presentazione migliore e libera dei rapporti, della contabilità e 
della presentazione delle attività analoghe che hanno bisogno dei 
dati finanziari molto per le revisioni e l'analisi. In 
primo luogo hanno dovuto scriverli con le mani, in modo da immagini 
che il tempo usato per cambiare un dato ed allora riparare lo 
sheet.Today intero è molto più facile con i calcolatori. La 
conoscenza di base dei fogli elettronici è quasi obbligatoria sulla 
maggior parte delle posizioni di lavoro. E questa conoscenza 
può essere usata altrove pure (calcolo, statistiche, finanze...). 
in modo da dia un'occhiata alle caratteristiche comuni in due 
pacchetti di programmi i più diffusi per i fogli elettronici.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι υπολογισμοί με λογιστικό φύλλο (spreadsheet) 
αναπτύχθηκαν πολύ πριν να γίνουν οι υπολογιστές και το λογισμικό 
που χρησιμοποιούμε σήμερα αναπτύχθηκε. Χρησιμοποιήθηκαν από
τις επιχειρήσεις για την καλύτερη και σαφή παρουσίαση των 
εκθέσεων, της λογιστικής και της παρουσίασης των παρόμοιων 
δραστηριοτήτων που χρειάζονται πολλά οικονομικά στοιχεία για τις 
αναθεωρήσεις και την ανάλυση. Πρώτα έπρεπε να τους γράψουν 
με τα χέρια, έτσι φαντάζονται το χρόνο που χρησιμοποιήθηκε για να
αλλάξει ένα στοιχείο και έπειτα επισκευή ολόκληρου του φύλλου 
Σήμερα είναι πολύ ευκολότερο με τους υπολογιστές. Η 
βασική γνώση υπολογισμών με λογιστικό φύλλο (spreadsheet) 
είναι σχεδόν υποχρεωτική στις περισσότερες θέσεις εργασίας. 
Και αυτή η γνώση μπορεί να χρησιμοποιηθεί αλλού επίσης 
(υπολογισμός, στατιστικές, πόροι χρηματοδότησης...). Θα 
ρίξουμε έτσι μια ματιά στα κοινά χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα σε 
δύο πιό διαδεδομένα πακέτα λογισμικού για τους υπολογισμούς με 
λογιστικό φύλλο (spreadsheet).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las hojas de balance fueron desarrolladas mucho 
antes los ordenadores fueron hechos y el software que utilizamos fue 
desarrollado hoy. Fueron utilizadas por las compañías para una
presentación mejor y clara de informes, de las estadísticas y de la 
presentación de las actividades similares que necesitan muchos de los
datos financieros para las revisiones y el análisis. Primero 
tuvieron que escribirlas con las manos, así que imagínese que el 
tiempo usado para cambiar un datos y después la reparación del 
sheet.Today entero es mucho más fácil con los ordenadores. El 
conocimiento básico de las hojas de balance es casi obligatorio en la
mayoría de las posiciones del trabajo. Y este conocimiento se 
puede utilizar a otra parte también (cálculo, estadística, las 
finanzas...). así que heche una ojeada las características 
comunes en dos paquetes de software más extensas para las hojas de 
balance.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">evizus</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kalkulationstabelle</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Buchhaltung</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Programm</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">evizus</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">tableur</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">comptabilité</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">programme</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">evizus</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">spreadsheet</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">contabilidade</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">programa</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">evizus</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">foglio elettronico</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">contabilità</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">programma</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">evizus</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">υπολογισμός με λογιστικό φύλλο (spreadsheet)</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">λογιστική</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">πρόγραμμα</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">evizus</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">hoja de balance</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">estadísticas</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">programa</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
FN:Matjaž Kljun
N:Kljun;Matjaž;;;
ORG:UP PEF
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2008-04-28</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:atlas.fri.uni-lj.si:aspect:evizus_sl/10007</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>lre</catalog>
            <entry>aspect:evizus_sl/10007</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
FN:Jernej Južna
N:Južna;Jernej;;;
ORG:UL FRI
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-02-23</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
FN:OAI Atlas UL FRI
N:OAI Atlas UL FRI;;;;
ORG:UL FRI
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-02-23T17:00:00.00Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>sl</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:University of Ljubljana
N:University of Ljubljana
ORG:University of Ljubljana
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-27T00:59:21.13Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>course</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>vocational education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">14-18</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.5/deed.sl</string>
            <string language="sl">Creative Commons - Priznanje avtorstva-Nekomercialno-Deljenje pod enakimi pogoji 2.5</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons - Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>657</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="sl">informacijski sistem</string>
                <string language="en">information system</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>251</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="sl">računalnik</string>
                <string language="en">computer</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>252</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="sl">računalniška aplikacija</string>
                <string language="en">computer application</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-UL-id</catalog>
      <entry>aspect:evizus_sl/10007:scorm</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>package in</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.packageInValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>scorm_v1p2</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <identifier>
        <catalog>item-UL-id</catalog>
        <entry>aspect:evizus_sl/10007:scorm:item</entry>
      </identifier>
      <location>
        <uri>http://lgm.fri.uni-lj.si/jernejj/evizus/scorm/rac_sl_preglednice.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-UL-id</catalog>
      <entry>aspect:evizus_sl/10007:cc</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>package in</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.packageInValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>imscc_v1p0</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <identifier>
        <catalog>item-UL-id</catalog>
        <entry>aspect:evizus_sl/10007:cc:item</entry>
      </identifier>
      <location>
        <uri>http://lgm.fri.uni-lj.si/jernejj/evizus/cc/rac_sl_preglednice.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
