<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/80626</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>80626</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/ihmisenamaailmassa</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/ihmisenamaailmassa</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/ihmisenamaailmassa</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Human rights handbook</string>
            <string language="fi">Ihmisoikeuksien käsikirja</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Handbuch der menschlichen Rechte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Manuel de droits de l'homme</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Manual das direitas humanas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Manuale di diritti dell'uomo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εγχειρίδιο των ανθρώπινων δικαιωμάτων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Manual de los derechos humanos</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">As a Person in the World is comprehensive support material for cultural and natural heritage education and for human rights education. The World Heritage section includes a presentation of cultural and natural heritage sites. The world heritage handbook is designed to help and illustrate world heritage education and related topics and values. Also included is an archive and an image bank. The Human Rights section contains information on human rights education in Finland and globally. Also included is a Human Rights handbook, which serves as a practical support pack in the planning of teaching. The Unesco Schools section presents the network of Unesco's ASP schools, which already embraces over 7,500 educational institutions in 172 countries.</string>
            <string language="fi">Opettajalle suunnattu tietolähde. Ihmisenä maailmassa on kattava kulttuuri- ja luonnonperintöopetuksen sekä ihmisoikeuskasvatuksen tukimateriaali. Maailmanperintö-osiossa on mm. esittely kulttuuri- ja luonnonperintökohteista. Maailmanperintökäsikirja on suunniteltu auttamaan ja havainnollistamaan maailmanperintöopetusta ja siihen liittyviä aiheita ja arvoja. Mukana on myös arkisto ja kuvapankki. Ihmisoikeudet-osiossa on tietoa ihmisoikeuskasvatuksesta Suomessa ja maailmalla. Mukana on myös Ihmisoikeuskäsikirja, joka toimii käytännöllisenä tukipakettina mm. opetuksen suunnittelussa. Unescokoulut-osiossa esitellään Unescon ASP-kouluverkko, jossa on mukana jo yli 7500 koulutusalan instituutiota 172:ssa maassa.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="fi">Opetushallitus</string>
            <string language="en">luonnonperintö</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Da eine Person in der Welt komplettes 
Hilfsmaterial für kulturelle und natürliche Erbeausbildung und für 
Ausbildung der menschlichen Rechte ist. Das Welterbekapitel 
schließt eine Darstellung der kulturellen und natürlichen Erbesites 
ein. Das Welterbehandbuch ist konzipiert, um Welterbeausbildung 
zu helfen und zu veranschaulichen und in Verbindung gestandene Themen 
und Werte. Auch geschlossen ein Archiv und eine Bildbank ein. 
Das Kapitel der menschlichen Rechte enthält Informationen über
Ausbildung der menschlichen Rechte in Finnland und global. Auch 
geschlossen ein Handbuch der menschlichen Rechte ein, das während ein
praktischer Unterstützungssatz in der Planung des Unterrichtens 
dient. Die UNESCO schult Kapitelgeschenke das Netz der Schulen 
Asp UNESCO, das bereits über 7.500 pädagogischen Anstalten in 172 
Ländern umfaßt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Car une personne dans le monde est matériel de 
support complet pour l'éducation culturelle et normale d'héritage et
pour l'éducation de droits de l'homme. La section d'héritage 
du monde inclut une présentation des sites culturels et normaux 
d'héritage. Le manuel d'héritage du monde est conçu pour 
aider et illustrer l'éducation d'héritage du monde et les sujets et 
les valeurs associés. En outre incluses sont des archives et 
une banque d'image. La section de droits de l'homme contient 
l'information sur l'éducation de droits de l'homme en Finlande et 
globalement. En outre inclus est un manuel de droits de l'homme,
qui sert  un paquet pratique de support dans la planification de 
l'enseignement. L'UNESCO instruit des présents de section le 
réseau des écoles de l'ASP de l'UNESCO, qui embrasse déjà plus de 
7.500 établissements éducatifs dans 172 pays.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Porque uma pessoa no mundo é material de 
sustentação detalhado para a instrução cultural e natural do 
heritage e para a instrução das direitas humanas. A seção do
heritage do mundo inclui uma apresentação de locais cultural e 
naturais do heritage. O manual do heritage do mundo é projetado
ajudar e ilustrar à instrução do heritage do mundo e tópicos e 
valores relacionados. São incluídos também um arquivo e um 
banco da imagem. A seção das direitas humanas contem a 
informação na instrução das direitas humanas em Finland e global. 
É incluído também um manual das direitas humanas, que sirva 
enquanto um bloco prático da sustentação no planeamento de ensinar.
O Unesco educa presentes da seção a rede de escolas do ASP do 
Unesco, que embraces já sobre 7.500 instituições educacionais em 
172 países.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Poichè una persona nel mondo è materiale 
completo di sostegno per formazione culturale e naturale di eredità e
per formazione di diritti dell'uomo. La sezione di eredità del 
mondo include una presentazione dei luoghi culturali e naturali di 
eredità. Il manuale di eredità del mondo è destinato per 
aiutare ed illustrare la formazione di eredità del mondo e soggetti e
valori riferiti. Egualmente è incluso un archivio e una 
banca di immagine. La sezione di diritti dell'uomo 
contiene le informazioni su formazione di diritti dell'uomo in 
Finlandia e globalmente. Egualmente è incluso un manuale di 
diritti dell'uomo, che serve mentre un pacchetto pratico di sostegno 
nella progettazione dell'istruzione. L'Unesco istruisce i 
presenti della sezione la rete delle scuole di ASP dell'Unesco, che 
già abbraccia oltre 7.500 istituti scolastici in 172 paesi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δεδομένου ότι ένα πρόσωπο στον κόσμο είναι την 
εκπαίδευση περιεκτικό υποστηρίξτε το υλικό για την πολιτιστική 
και φυσική εκπαίδευση κληρονομιάς και για των ανθρώπινων 
δικαιωμάτων. Το τμήμα παγκόσμιας κληρονομιάς περιλαμβάνει 
μια παρουσίαση των πολιτιστικών και φυσικών περιοχών κληρονομιάς.
Το εγχειρίδιο παγκόσμιας κληρονομιάς σχεδιάζεται για να 
βοηθήσει και να επεξηγήσει την εκπαίδευση παγκόσμιας κληρονομιάς 
και τα σχετικές θέματα και τις τιμές. Επίσης 
περιλαμβάνονται ένα αρχείο και μια τράπεζα εικόνας. Το 
τμήμα των ανθρώπινων δικαιωμάτων περιέχει τις πληροφορίες για την
εκπαίδευση των ανθρώπινων δικαιωμάτων στη Φινλανδία και συνολικά.
Επίσης περιλαμβάνεται ένα εγχειρίδιο των ανθρώπινων 
δικαιωμάτων, το οποίο χρησιμεύει ως ένα πρακτικό πακέτο 
υποστήριξης στον προγραμματισμό της διδασκαλίας. Το σχολικό 
τμήμα της ΟΥΝΕΣΚΟ παρουσιάζει το δίκτυο ASP της ΟΥΝΕΣΚΟ των 
σχολείων, το οποίο αγκαλιάζει ήδη πάνω από 7.500 
εκπαιδευτικά όργανα σε 172 χώρες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Pues una persona en el mundo es material de ayuda
comprensivo para la educación cultural y natural de la herencia y 
para la educación de los derechos humanos. La sección de la 
herencia del mundo incluye una presentación de los sitios culturales 
y naturales de la herencia. El manual de la herencia del mundo 
se diseña para ayudar y para ilustrar a la educación de la herencia 
del mundo y los asuntos y los valores relacionados. También se 
incluye un archivo y una batería de la imagen. La sección de 
los derechos humanos contiene la información sobre la educación de 
los derechos humanos en Finlandia y global. También se incluye 
un manual de los derechos humanos, que sirve mientras que un paquete 
práctico de la ayuda en las hojas de operación (planning) de la 
enseñanza. La UNESCO enseña presentes de la sección la red de
las escuelas del ASP de la UNESCO, que abraza ya sobre 7.500 
instituciones educativas en 172 países.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">luonnonperintö</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">luonnonperintö</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">luonnonperintö</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">luonnonperintö</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">luonnonperintφ</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">luonnonperintö</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/101094BE-2E9F-4419-8EC0-402F720D1DA7</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/101094BE-2E9F-4419-8EC0-402F720D1DA7</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pekka Pirhonen
n:Pirhonen;Pekka 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:49:22.96Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>guide</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">13-19</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Nimeä-Epäkaupallinen-Ei muutettuja teoksia 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>668</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>213</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>298</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>388</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>612</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1160</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/ihmisenamaailmassa</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/ihmisenamaailmassa</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
