<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/80248</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>80248</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/terveellinenateria/index_ff.html</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/terveellinenateria/index_ff.html</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/terveellinenateria/index_ff.html</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Healthy meal 2</string>
            <string language="fi">Terveellinen ateria 2</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gesunde Mahlzeit 2</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Repas sain 2</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Refeição saudável 2</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Pasto sano 2</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Υγιές γεύμα 2</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Comida sana 2</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Healthy meal is an interactive program, in which the user is able to put together a lunch according to nutritional recommendations for sample individuals. The user can also feed his/her own data into the program  and practise putting together a meal according to his/her own energy need. The Healthy Meal program is based on a Finnish nutrition model, the plate model. The model can be adapted to the needs of various diners. The program helps the student to illustrate the effect of the portion size chosen for the meal and of the dishes on the total amount of energy. The Healthy Meal object goes through the plate and provides tips on how to develop it. The aim is to guide the student to achieve permanent weight management and ensure wide-ranging and healthy nutrition. The material contains links to both Finnish and foreign websites relating to nutrition.</string>
            <string language="fi">Laajalle osallistujajoukolle soveltuva interaktiivinen ohjelma, jossa käyttäjä pääsee kokoamaan ravitsemussuositusten mukaisen lounaan esimerkkihenkilöille. Käyttäjä voi myös syöttää ohjelmaan omat tietonsa ja harjoitella aterikokonaisuuden kokoamista oman energiantarpeensa mukaan. Tavoitteena on opastaa pysyvään painonhallintaan ja sekä monipuoliseen että terveelliseen ravitsemukseen. Materiaali sisältää linkkejä sekä kotimaisiin että ulkomaisiin ravitsemukseen liittyviin sivustoihin.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="fi">terveellisyys</string>
            <string language="en">terveellisyys</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gesunde Mahlzeit ist ein Dialogprogramm, in dem 
der Benutzer kann, ein Mittagessen entsprechend 
Ernährungsempfehlungen für Beispieleinzelpersonen zusammenzufügen. 
Der Benutzer kann seine/ihr eigene Daten in das Programm auch 
einziehen und eine, Mahlzeit entsprechend seiner/ihr eigener 
Energienotwendigkeit zusammenzufügen üben. Das gesunde 
Mahlzeitprogramm basiert auf einem finnischen Nahrungmodell, das 
Platte Modell. Das Modell kann den Notwendigkeiten der 
verschiedenen Restaurants angepaßt werden. Das Programm hilft 
dem Kursteilnehmer, den Effekt zu veranschaulichen der Teilgröße, 
die für die Mahlzeit gewählt wird und der Teller auf der Gesamtmenge
von Energie. Die gesunde Mahlzeitnachricht läuft die Platte 
durch und stellt Spitzen auf zur Verfügung, wie man sie entwickelt. 
Das Ziel ist, den Kursteilnehmer zu führen, um permanentes 
Gewichtmanagement zu erzielen und weitreichende und gesunde Nahrung 
sicherzustellen. Das Material enthält Links zu den finnischen 
und fremden Web site in bezug auf Nahrung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le repas sain est un programme interactif, dans 
lequel l'utilisateur peut remonter un déjeuner conformément aux 
recommandations alimentaires pour des individus témoin. 
L'utilisateur peut également introduire ses propres données 
dans le programme et pratiquer remonter un repas selon son propre 
besoin énergétique. Le programme sain de repas est basé sur 
un modèle finlandais de nutrition, le modèle de plat. Le 
modèle peut être adapté aux besoins de divers wagon-restaurants. 
Le programme aide l'étudiant à illustrer l'effet de la taille 
de partie choisie pour le repas et des plats sur le montant total 
d'énergie. L'objet sain de repas passe par le plat et fournit 
des extrémités sur la façon dont le développer. Le but est 
de guider l'étudiant pour réaliser la gestion permanente de poids et
pour assurer la nutrition étendue et saine. Le matériel 
contient des liens aux sites Web finlandais et étrangers concernant 
la nutrition.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A refeição saudável é um programa interativo, 
em que o usuário pode  unir um lunch de acordo com recomendações 
nutritivas para indivíduos da amostra. O usuário pode também 
alimentar his/her próprios dados no programa e praticá-los unir uma 
refeição de acordo com his/her própria necessidade de energia. 
O programa saudável da refeição é baseado em um modelo 
finnish do nutrition, o modelo da placa. O modelo pode ser 
adaptado às necessidades de vários diners. O programa ajuda ao
estudante ilustrar o efeito do tamanho da parcela escolhido para a 
refeição e dos pratos na quantidade total de energia. O objeto
saudável da refeição atravessa a placa e fornece pontas em como 
desenvolvê-la. O alvo é guiar o estudante para conseguir a 
gerência permanente do peso e para assegurar o nutrition wide-ranging
e saudável. O material contem as ligações  aos Web site 
finnish e extrangeiros que relacionam-se ao nutrition.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il pasto sano è un programma interattivo, in cui 
l'utente può unire un pranzo conformemente alle raccomandazioni 
nutrizionali per gli individui del campione. L'utente può anche
inserire i suoi propri dati nel programma ed esercitarsi in unire un 
pasto secondo il suo proprio bisogno di energia. Il programma 
sano del pasto è basato su un modello finlandese di nutrizione, il 
modello della piastra. Il modello può essere adattato ai 
bisogni di vari diners. Il programma aiuta l'allievo ad 
illustrare l'effetto del formato della parte scelto per il pasto e dei
piatti sulla quantità totale di energia. L'oggetto sano del 
pasto passa tramite la piastra e fornisce le punte su come 
svilupparla. Lo scopo è guidare l'allievo per realizzare la 
gestione permanente del peso e per accertare la vasta e nutrizione 
sana. Il materiale contiene i collegamenti sia ai Web site 
finlandesi che stranieri concernente nutrizione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το υγιές γεύμα είναι ένα διαλογικό πρόγραμμα, στο 
οποίο ο χρήστης είναι σε θέση να βάλει μαζί ένα μεσημεριανό 
γεύμα σύμφωνα με τις θρεπτικές συστάσεις για τα άτομα δειγμάτων.
Ο χρήστης μπορεί επίσης να τροφοδοτήσει τα στοιχεία του/της
το πρόγραμμα και να ασκήσει μαζί ένα γεύμα σύμφωνα με την 
ενεργειακή ανάγκη του/της. Το υγιές πρόγραμμα γεύματος 
είναι βασισμένο σε ένα φινλανδικό μοντέλο διατροφής, το μοντέλο
πιάτων. Το μοντέλο μπορεί να προσαρμοστεί στις ανάγκες των 
διάφορων γευματιζόντων. Το πρόγραμμα βοηθά το σπουδαστή για
να επεξηγήσει την επίδραση του μεγέθους μερίδας που επιλέγεται 
για το γεύμα και των πιάτων στο συνολικό ποσό ενέργειας. Το
υγιές αντικείμενο γεύματος περνά από το πιάτο και παρέχει τις 
άκρες στο πώς να τον αναπτύξει. Ο στόχος είναι να 
καθοδηγηθεί ο σπουδαστής για να επιτύχει τη μόνιμη διαχείριση 
βάρους και να εξασφαλίσει εκτεταμένη και υγιή διατροφή. Το 
υλικό περιέχει τις συνδέσεις και με τους φινλανδικούς και ξένους 
ιστοχώρους σχετικά με τη διατροφή.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La comida sana es un programa interactivo, en el 
cual el utilizador puede poner junto un almuerzo según las 
recomendaciones alimenticias para los individuos de la muestra. 
El utilizador puede también alimentar su propios datos en el 
programa y practicar el juntar de una comida según su propia 
necesidad energética. El programa sano de la comida se basa en 
un modelo finlandés de la nutrición, el modelo de la placa. El
modelo se puede adaptar a las necesidades de varios diners. El 
programa ayuda al estudiante a ilustrar el efecto de la talla de la 
porción elegida para la comida y de los platos en la cantidad total 
de energía. El objeto sano de la comida pasa a través de la 
placa y proporciona a extremidades en cómo desarrollarla. La 
puntería es dirigir al estudiante para alcanzar la gerencia 
permanente del peso y para asegurar la nutrición vasta y sana. 
El material contiene conexiones a los Web site finlandeses y no 
nativos referente a la nutrición.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">terveellisyys</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">terveellisyys</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">terveellisyys</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">terveellisyys</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">terveellisyys</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">terveellisyys</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Jan Rosnell
n:Rosnell;Jan
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Sinikka Orkomaa
n:Orkomaa;Sinikka
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Juho Helminen
n:Helminen;Juho
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Janomedia
n:Janomedia
org:Janomedia
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/EFC61F1D-D60B-972A-53AB-B02A4DF4E259</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/EFC61F1D-D60B-972A-53AB-B02A4DF4E259</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Eeva-Liisa Vihinen
n:Vihinen;Eeva-Liisa 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:55:18.16Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>tool</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>simulation</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>guide</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>parent</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>vocational education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">10-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Ei mainintaa</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>911</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>583</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/terveellinenateria/index_ff.html</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/terveellinenateria/index_ff.html</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
