<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/235310</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>235310</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi/perusopetus/liikunta/opetusmateriaalit_eri_lajeista/salibandy</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/perusopetus/liikunta/opetusmateriaalit_eri_lajeista/salibandy</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/perusopetus/liikunta/opetusmateriaalit_eri_lajeista/salibandy</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Floorball</string>
            <string language="fi">Salibandy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Floorball</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Floorball</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Floorball</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Floorball</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Floorball</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Floorball</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">As types of exercise, Finnish floorball and floorball resemble each other a lot, and the website covers both sports. The purpose of the website is for the teacher to find quickly and effectively support for the planning and implementation of the content of his/her lessons. The website contains instructions for the teacher, descriptions of the rules and basic skills of the sports and of the equipment required; as well as instructions organised according to age-group, the purpose of which is to help the teacher to choose appropriate teaching contents. Some of the material is in PDF format, and there are also links to websites relating to the sports.</string>
            <string language="fi">Liikuntalajeina sähly ja salibandy muistuttavat paljon toisiaan, ja verkkosivustolla käsitelläänkin molempia lajeja. Sivuston tarkoituksena on, että opettaja löytäisi nopeasti ja tehokkaasti tuen oppituntiensa sisällön suunnitteluun ja toteutukseen. Sivusto sisältää ohjeita opettajalle, kuvaukset lajien säännöistä ja perustaidoista sekä tarvittavista varusteista; sekä vuosiluokittain jäsennetyt ohjeet, joiden tarkoituksena on auttaa opettajaa tarkoituksenmukaisten opetussisältöjen valitsemisessa. Osa aineistosta on pdf-muodossa, ja lisänä on myös linkkejä lajiin liittyville verkkosivustoille.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Als Typen der Übung, ähneln sich finnisches 
floorball und floorball viel, und die Web site umfaßt beiden Sport. 
Der Zweck der Web site ist, damit der Lehrer schnell findet und 
effektiv für die Planung und die Implementierung des Inhalts sein/ihr
Lektionen unterstützt. Die Web site enthält Anweisungen für 
den Lehrer, die Beschreibungen der Richtlinien und die grundlegenden 
Fähigkeiten des Sports und der benötigten Ausrüstung; sowie 
die Anweisungen, die entsprechend Altersklasse, dessen organisiert 
werden Zweck ist zu helfen, stellt der, Lehrer, um das passendes 
Unterrichten zu wählen zufrieden. Etwas von dem Material ist im
pdf Format, und es gibt auch Links zu den Web site in bezug auf den 
Sport.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Comme types d'exercice, le floorball finlandais et
le floorball se ressemblent beaucoup, et le site Web couvre les deux 
sports. Le but du site Web est pour que le professeur trouve 
rapidement et à supporte pertinemment pour la planification et la 
mise en place de la teneur de ses leçons. Le site Web contient 
des instructions pour le professeur, des descriptions des règles et 
des qualifications de base des sports et du matériel exigé ; 
aussi bien que des instructions organisées selon le groupe 
d'âge, dont le but est d'aider le professeur pour choisir 
l'enseignement approprié contente. Une partie du matériel est 
dans le format de pdf, et il y a également des liens aux sites Web 
concernant les sports.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Como tipos de exercício, o floorball finnish e o 
floorball assemelham-se a muito, e o Web site cobre ambos os esportes.
A finalidade do Web site é para que o professor encontre 
rapidamente e suporte eficazmente para o planeamento e a execução do
índice de his/her lições. O Web site contem instruções para
o professor, descrições das réguas e habilidades básicas dos 
esportes e do equipamento requerido; as.well.as as instruções 
organizadas de acordo com o age-group, a finalidade de que é ajudar o
professor para escolher ensinar apropriado satisfaz. Algum do 
material está no formato do pdf, e há também umas ligações aos 
Web site que relacionam-se aos esportes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Come tipi di esercitazioni, il floorball 
finlandese ed il floorball si assomigliano mólto ed il Web site 
riguarda entrambi gli sport. Lo scopo del Web site è affinchè 
l'insegnante trovi rapidamente e da contributo efficacemente alla 
progettazione ed all'implementazione del contenuto delle sue lezioni. 
Il Web site contiene le istruzioni per l'insegnante, le 
descrizioni delle regole e le abilità di base degli sport e 
dell'apparecchiatura richiesta; così come le istruzioni 
organizzate secondo la fascia d'età, lo scopo di cui è aiutare 
l'insegnante per scegliere l'istruzione adatta soddisfa. Alcuno 
del materiale è nel formato del pdf e ci sono egualmente collegamenti
ai Web site concernente gli sport.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σαν τύπους ασκήσεων, το φινλανδικό floorball και 
floorball μοιάζει με το ένα το άλλο πολύ, και ο ιστοχώρος 
καλύπτει και τον δύο αθλητισμό. Ο σκοπός του ιστοχώρου 
είναι για το δάσκαλο να βρεί γρήγορα και αποτελεσματικά 
υποστήριξη για τον προγραμματισμό και την εφαρμογή του 
περιεχομένου των μαθημάτων του/της. Ο ιστοχώρος περιέχει τις
οδηγίες για το δάσκαλο, τις περιγραφές των κανόνων και τις 
βασικές δεξιότητες του αθλητισμού και του εξοπλισμού που 
απαιτείται  όπως και τις οδηγίες που οργανώνονται σύμφωνα 
με την κλάση, ο σκοπός της οποίας είναι να ενισχυθεί ο δάσκαλος 
για να επιλέξει το κατάλληλο περιεχόμενο διδασκαλίας. 
Μερικά από το υλικό είναι με τη μορφή PDF, και υπάρχουν
επίσης συνδέσεις με τους ιστοχώρους σχετικά με τον αθλητισμό.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Como tipos de ejercicio, el floorball finlandés y
el floorball se asemejan mucho, y el Web site cubre ambos deportes. 
El propósito del Web site está para que el profesor encuentre 
rápidamente y utilice con eficacia para las hojas de operación 
(planning) y la puesta en práctica del contenido de su lecciones. 
El Web site contiene las instrucciones para el profesor, las 
descripciones de las reglas y las habilidades básicas de los deportes
y del equipo requerido; así como las instrucciones ordenadas 
según el grupo de misma edad, el propósito de el cual es ayudar el 
profesor para elegir la enseñanza apropiada contenta. Algo del 
material está en formato del pdf, y hay también conexiones a los Web
site referente a los deportes.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Suomen Salibandyliitto
n:Suomen Salibandyliitto
org:Suomen Salibandyliitto
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/7A0314E6-41F0-DF65-E6CF-EC1FFBC447EC</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/7A0314E6-41F0-DF65-E6CF-EC1FFBC447EC</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Katja Pajuluoma
n:Pajuluoma;Katja 
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:36:08.32Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>guide</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">6-16</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://www.edu.fi/prime102.aspx</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>974</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>987</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1285</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1024</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi/perusopetus/liikunta/opetusmateriaalit_eri_lajeista/salibandy</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/perusopetus/liikunta/opetusmateriaalit_eri_lajeista/salibandy</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
