<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/25960</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>25960</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
    <entry>M248_2</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM       http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:openlearn.open.ac.uk:M248_2</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>LearningSpace</catalog>
            <entry>M248_2</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en-gb">Interpreting data: boxplots and tables</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Deutung von von Daten: boxplots und 
Tabellen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Interprétation des données : boxplots et 
tables</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Interpretando dados: boxplots e tabelas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Interpretazione dei dati: boxplots e 
tabelle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ερμηνεία των στοιχείων: boxplots και πίνακες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Interpretar datos: boxplots y vectores</string>
          </title>
          <language>en-gb</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en-gb">This unit is concerned with two main topics. In Section 1, you will learn about another kind of graphical display, the boxplot. A boxplot is a fairly simple graphic, which displays certain summary statistics of a set of data. Boxplots are particularly useful for assessing quickly the location, dispersion, and symmetry or skewness of a set of data, and for making comparisons of these features in two or more data sets. Boxplots can also be useful for drawing attention to possible outliers in a data set. The other topic, which is covered in Sections 2 and 3, is that of dealing with data presented in tabular form. You are, no doubt, familiar with such tables: they are common in the media and in reports and other documents. Yet it is not always straightforward to see at first glance just what information a table of data is providing, and it often helps to carry out certain calculations and/or to draw appropriate graphs to make this clearer. In this unit, some other kinds of data tables and some different approaches are covered.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en-gb">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en-gb">Communicating_maths</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en-gb">Data</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en-gb">Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>linear</value>
          </structure>
          <aggregationLevel>
            <source>aggregationLevelValues</source>
            <value>2</value>
          </aggregationLevel>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Maßeinheit wird mit zwei Hauptthemen 
betroffen. In Kapitel 1, erlernen Sie über eine andere Art 
graphische Bildschirmanzeige, das boxplot. Ein boxplot ist eine 
ziemlich einfache Graphik, die bestimmte zusammenfassende Statistiken 
eines Sets Daten anzeigt. Boxplots sind für den Standort, die 
Zerstreuung und die Symmetrie oder die Schrägheit eines Sets Daten 
schnell festsetzen und für das Vergleichen dieser Merkmale in zwei 
oder mehr Dateien besonders nützlich. Boxplots kann für das 
Lenken von von Aufmerksamkeit auf mögliche Ausreißer in einer Datei 
nützlich auch sein. Das andere Thema, das in Kapiteln 2 und 3 
umfaßt wird, ist das des Beschäftigens die Daten, die in 
tabellarischer Darstellung dargestellt werden. Sie sind, kein 
Zweifel, der mit solchen Tabellen vertraut ist: sie sind in den 
Media und in den Reports und in anderen Dokumenten geläufig. 
Noch ist er nicht immer direkt, am ersten flüchtigen Blick zu 
sehen, gerade welche Informationen eine Tabelle von Daten zur 
Verfügung stellen, und sie hilft häufig, bestimmte Berechnungen 
durchzuführen und/oder passende Diagramme zu zeichnen, um diesen 
Reiniger zu bilden. In dieser Maßeinheit werden einige andere 
Arten Datentabellen und einige unterschiedliche Annäherungen umfaßt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette unité est concernée par deux sujets 
principaux. Dans la section 1, vous vous renseignerez sur un 
autre genre d'affichage graphique, le boxplot. Un boxplot est un
graphique assez simple, qui affiche certaines statistiques sommaires 
d'un ensemble de données. Boxplots sont particulièrement utile
pour évaluer rapidement l'emplacement, la dispersion, et la symétrie
ou l'obliquité d'un ensemble de données, et pour la fabrication des 
comparaisons de ces dispositifs dans deux Modem ou plus. 
Boxplots peut également être utile pour appeler l'attention 
sur des annexes possibles dans un Modem. L'autre sujet, qui est 
couvert dans les sections 2 et 3, est celui de traiter des données 
présentées en forme de tableaux. Vous êtes, aucun doute, 
familier avec de telles tables : elles sont communes dans les 
medias et dans les états et d'autres documents. Pourtant il 
n'est pas toujours franc pour voir à première vue au juste quelle 
information une table des données fournit, et elle aide souvent à 
effectuer certains calculs et/ou à tracer les graphiques appropriés 
pour faire ce clairifiant. Dans cette unité, quelques autres 
genres de tables de données et quelques différentes approches sont 
couverts.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta unidade é concernida com os dois tópicos 
principais. Na seção 1, você aprenderá sobre um outro tipo 
do indicador gráfico, o boxplot. Um boxplot é um gráfico 
razoavelmente simples, que indique determinados statistics sumários 
de um jogo dos dados. Boxplots é particularmente útil para 
avaliar rapidamente a posição, a dispersão, e a simetria ou o 
skewness de um jogo dos dados, e para fazer comparações destas 
características em dois ou mais séries de dados de. Boxplots 
pode também ser útil para desenhar a atenção aos outliers 
possíveis em uma série de dados de. O outro tópico, que é 
coberto nas seções 2 e 3, é aquele de tratar dos dados apresentados
no formulário tabular. Você é, nenhuma dúvida, familiar com 
tais tabelas: são comum nos media e nos relatórios e nos 
outros originais. Contudo não é sempre direta ver no primeiro 
glance apenas que informação uma tabela dos dados está fornecendo, 
e ajuda frequentemente realizar determinados cálculos e/ou desenhar 
gráficos apropriados para fazer este clearer. Nesta unidade, 
alguns outros tipos de tabelas dos dados e algumas aproximações 
diferentes são cobertos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa unità è interessata di due soggetti 
principali. Nella parte 1, imparerete circa un altro genere di 
rappresentazione grafica, il boxplot. Un boxplot è un grafico 
ragionevolmente semplice, che visualizza determinati dati statistici 
sommari di un insieme dei dati. Boxplots è particolarmente 
utile per valutare rapidamente la posizione, la dispersione e la 
simmetria o l'obliquità di un insieme dei dati e per fare i confronti
di queste caratteristiche in due o più insiemi di dati. 
Boxplots può anche essere utile per attirare l'attenzione sui 
valori erratici possibili in un insieme di dati. L'altro 
soggetto, che è coperto nelle parti 2 e 3, è quello di occuparsi dei
dati presentati sotto forma di tabella. Siete, senza dubbio, 
esperto con tali tabelle: sono comuni nei media e nei rapporti 
ed in altri documenti. Tuttavia non è sempre diretto vedere 
alla prima occhiata le appena che informazioni una tabella dei dati 
stanno fornendo e contribuiscono spesso ad effettuare determinati 
calcoli e/o a tracciare i grafici adatti per fare questo pulitore. 
In questa unità, alcuni altri generi di tabelle di dati ed 
alcuni metodi differenti sono coperti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η μονάδα ενδιαφέρεται για δύο βασικά θέματα. 
Στην παράγραφο 1, θα μάθετε για ένα άλλο είδος γραφικής 
παρουσίασης, το boxplot. Ένα boxplot είναι αρκετά 
απλό ένα γραφικό, το οποίο παρουσιάζει ορισμένες συνοπτικές 
στατιστικές ενός συνόλου στοιχείων. Το Boxplots είναι 
ιδιαίτερα χρήσιμο για γρήγορα τη θέση, τη διασπορά, και τη 
συμμετρία ή την εκτροπή ενός συνόλου στοιχείων, και για την 
παραγωγή των συγκρίσεων αυτών των χαρακτηριστικών γνωρισμάτων σε 
δύο ή περισσότερα σύνολα στοιχείων. Το Boxplots μπορεί 
επίσης να είναι χρήσιμο για την προσοχή πιθανά outliers σε 
ένα σύνολο στοιχείων. Το άλλο θέμα, που καλύπτεται στις 
παραγράφους 2 και 3, είναι αυτό της εξέτασης των στοιχείων που 
παρουσιάζονται υπό μορφήν πίνακος. Εξοικειώνεστε, καμία 
αμφιβολία, με τέτοιους πίνακες: είναι κοινοί στα μέσα και 
στις εκθέσεις και άλλα έγγραφα. Ακόμα είναι όχι πάντα 
απλό για να δει στην πρώτη ματιά ακριβώς ποιες 
πληροφορίες ένας πίνακας των στοιχείων παρέχουν, και βοηθά 
συχνά να πραγματοποιήσει ορισμένους υπολογισμούς ή/και να σύρει 
τις κατάλληλες γραφικές παραστάσεις για να κάνει αυτόν τον 
καθαριστή. Σε αυτήν την μονάδα, μερικά άλλα είδη πινάκων 
στοιχείων και μερικές διαφορετικές προσεγγίσεις καλύπτονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta unidad se refiere a dos asuntos principales. 
En la sección 1, usted aprenderá sobre otra clase de 
visualización gráfica, el boxplot. Un boxplot es un gráfico 
bastante simple, que visualiza cierta estadística sumaria de un 
conjunto de datos. Boxplots es determinado útil para evaluar 
rápidamente la localización, la dispersión, y la simetría o la 
oblicuidad de un conjunto de datos, y para hacer comparaciones de 
estas características en dos o más modems. Boxplots puede 
también ser útil para trazar la atención a los afloramientos 
posibles en un modem. El otro asunto, que se cubre en las 
secciones 2 y 3, es el de ocuparse de los datos presentados en forma 
tabular. Usted es, ninguna duda, familiar con tales vectores: 
son comunes en los media y en informes y otros documentos. 
Con todo no es siempre directa ver en el primer vistazo apenas 
qué información un vector de datos está proporcionando, y ayuda a 
menudo a realizar ciertos cálculos y/o a trazar gráficos apropiados 
para hacer este clarificante. En esta unidad, algunas otras 
clases de vectores de los datos y algunos diversos acercamientos se 
cubren.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Communicating_maths</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Daten</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Communicating_maths</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Données</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Communicating_maths</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Dados</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Communicating_maths</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dati</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Communicating_maths</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στοιχεία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Communicating_maths</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Datos</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <version>
            <string>1.0</string>
          </version>
          <status>
            <source>statusValues</source>
            <value>final</value>
          </status>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:Open University
N:Open University
ORG:Open University
ADR:Walton Hall, Milton Keynes, Buckinghamshire, MK7 6AA, United Kingdom
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:Open University
N:Open University
ORG:Open University
ADR:Walton Hall, Milton Keynes, Buckinghamshire, MK7 6AA, United Kingdom
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:openlearn.open.ac.uk:M248_2</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>LearningSpace</catalog>
            <entry>M248_2</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:Open University
N:Open University
ORG:Open University
ADR:Walton Hall, Milton Keynes, Buckinghamshire, MK7 6AA, United Kingdom
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <language>en-gb</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:OpenLearn
N:OpenLearn
ORG:OpenLearn
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T17:14:30.30Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <technical>
          <format>text/html</format>
          <location>http://openlearn.open.ac.uk/M248_2</location>
        </technical>
        <educational>
          <interactivityType>
            <source>interactivityTypeValues</source>
            <value>mixed</value>
          </interactivityType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>text</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <interactivityLevel>
            <source>interactivityLevelValues</source>
            <value>low</value>
          </interactivityLevel>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>higher education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="en-gb">18+</string>
            <string language="x-t-lre">18-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <difficulty>
            <source>difficultyValues</source>
            <value>medium</value>
          </difficulty>
          <typicalLearningTime>
            <duration>PT16H</duration>
          </typicalLearningTime>
          <description>
            <string language="en-gb">Independent self-study</string>
          </description>
          <language>en-gb</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en-gb">Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution - NonCommercial-ShareAlike 2.0 Licence - see http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/uk/ - Original copyright The Open University</string>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/uk/</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <relation>
          <kind>
            <source>LRE.kindValues</source>
            <value>references</value>
          </kind>
          <resource>
            <description>
              <string language="en-gb">An OU course on this topic</string>
            </description>
            <identifier>
              <catalog>URL</catalog>
              <entry>http://www3.open.ac.uk/courses/bin/p12.dll?C01M248</entry>
            </identifier>
          </resource>
        </relation>
        <relation>
          <kind>
            <source>LRE.kindValues</source>
            <value>references</value>
          </kind>
          <resource>
            <description>
              <string language="en-gb">Study this topic at the OU</string>
            </description>
            <identifier>
              <catalog>URL</catalog>
              <entry>http://www3.open.ac.uk/courses/classifications/mathematics_and_statistics.shtm</entry>
            </identifier>
          </resource>
        </relation>
        <relation>
          <kind>
            <source>LRE.kindValues</source>
            <value>references</value>
          </kind>
          <resource>
            <description>
              <string language="en-gb">open2.net: Science &amp; Nature</string>
            </description>
            <identifier>
              <catalog>URL</catalog>
              <entry>http://www.open2.net/sciencetechnologynature/</entry>
            </identifier>
          </resource>
        </relation>
        <relation>
          <kind>
            <source>LRE.kindValues</source>
            <value>isbasedon</value>
          </kind>
          <resource>
            <description>
              <string language="en-gb">This is the title and course code of the source course material</string>
            </description>
            <identifier>
              <catalog>Open University course</catalog>
              <entry>Mathematics and Computing Level 2 - M248</entry>
            </identifier>
          </resource>
        </relation>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
      <entry>M248_2 - web site</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <identifier>
        <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
        <entry>M248_2 - web site</entry>
      </identifier>
      <location>
        <uri>http://openlearn.open.ac.uk/M248_2</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
      <entry>M248_2 - Common Cartridge 1.0</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>package in</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.packageInValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>imscc_v1p0</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <identifier>
        <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
        <entry>M248_2 - Common Cartridge 1.0</entry>
      </identifier>
      <location>
        <uri>http://openlearn.open.ac.uk/blocks/formats/logrequest.php?url=/file.php/1712/downloads/M248_2_ims_cc.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
      <entry>M248_2 - Content Package</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>package in</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.packageInValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>imscp_v1p1p4</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <identifier>
        <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
        <entry>M248_2 - Content Package</entry>
      </identifier>
      <location>
        <uri>http://openlearn.open.ac.uk/blocks/formats/logrequest.php?url=/file.php/1712/downloads/M248_2_ims_cp.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
