<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/26827</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>26827</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
    <entry>TL_DANCE1</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM       http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:openlearn.open.ac.uk:TL_DANCE1</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>LearningSpace</catalog>
            <entry>TL_DANCE1</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en-gb">Dance skills</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Tanzfähigkeiten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Qualifications de danse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Habilidades da dança</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Abilità di ballo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δεξιότητες χορού</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Habilidades de la danza</string>
          </title>
          <language>en-gb</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en-gb">Dance communicates ideas through movement and is an expressive art form. Students need to learn how to use their body in a safe and healthy way, whilst developing a wide-ranging movement vocabulary. The use of different dance techniques can be an effective way of building vocabulary and developing different kinds of skills and abilities. Technical dance skills can form the foundation on which to develop and enhance each individual's performance. As dance teachers, we may have a range of skills, but it isn't always possible to possess expertise in every type of dance style and technique. Having the knowledge and experience to teach African Dance forms, Jazz Dance or Hip Hop to students is a great way of introducing them to a variety of styles and can be a rich and rewarding process. However, many teachers in schools and colleges work within a Contemporary Dance style because it will have been the basis of their education and training; it is also the point of reference for this unit.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en-gb">Education</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en-gb">Dance</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en-gb">Students</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en-gb">Teachers</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en-gb">Teaching_dance</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en-gb">Teaching_techniques</string>
          </keyword>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>linear</value>
          </structure>
          <aggregationLevel>
            <source>aggregationLevelValues</source>
            <value>2</value>
          </aggregationLevel>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Tanzen Sie mitteilt Ideen durch Bewegung und ist 
eine ausdrucksvolle Kunstform. Kursteilnehmer müssen erlernen, 
wie man ihren Körper in einer sicheren und gesunden Methode benutzt, 
während, einen weitreichenden Bewegung Wortschatz entwickelnd. 
Der Gebrauch von unterschiedlichen Tanztechniken kann eine 
wirkungsvolle Methode des Aufbauens des Wortschatzes und des 
Entwickelns der unterschiedlichen Arten von Fähigkeiten und von 
Fähigkeiten sein. Technische Tanzfähigkeiten können die 
Grundlage bilden, auf der jede Einzelleistung entwickeln und erhöhen.
Als Tanzlehrer können wir eine Strecke der Fähigkeiten haben, 
aber es ist nicht immer möglich, Sachkenntnis in jedem Typen Tanzart 
und -technik zu besitzen. Das Wissen und die Erfahrung zum 
Unterrichten den Kursteilnehmern afrikanische Tanzformulare, Jazz-Tanz
oder Hüfte-Hopfen zu haben ist eine große Methode des Vorstellens 
sie zu einer Vielzahl von Arten und kann sein Rich und lohnender 
Prozeß. Jedoch arbeiten viele Lehrer in den Schulen und in den 
Hochschulen innerhalb einer zeitgenössischen Tanzart, weil es die 
Grundlage ihrer Ausbildung und Trainings gewesen ist; es ist 
auch der Punkt der Referenz für diese Maßeinheit.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dansez communique des idées par le mouvement et 
est une forme d'art expressive. Les étudiants doivent apprendre
comment utiliser leur corps dans une voie sûre et saine, tout en 
développant un vocabulaire étendu de mouvement. L'utilisation 
de différentes techniques de danse peut être une voie pertinente 
d'établir le vocabulaire et de développer différents genres de 
qualifications et de capacités. Les qualifications techniques 
de danse peuvent former la base sur laquelle pour développer et 
mettre en valeur chaque exécution individuelle. Comme 
professeurs de danse, nous pouvons avoir un intervalle des 
qualifications, mais il n'est pas toujours possible de posséder 
l'expertise dans chaque type de modèle et de technique de danse. 
Avoir la connaissance et l'expérience pour enseigner les formes
de danse, la danse de jazz ou l'houblon africaine de hanche aux 
étudiants est une grande voie de les présenter à une variété de 
modèles et peut être des riches et processus enrichissant. 
Cependant, beaucoup de professeurs dans les écoles et les 
universités travaillent dans un modèle contemporain de danse parce 
que c'aura été la base de leur éducation et formation ; c'est
également le point de référence pour cette unité.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Dance comunica idéias através do movimento e é
um formulário de arte expressive. Os estudantes necessitam 
aprender como usar seu corpo em uma maneira segura e saudável, whilst
desenvolvendo um vocabulário wide-ranging do movimento. O uso 
de técnicas diferentes da dança pode ser uma maneira eficaz de 
construir o vocabulário e de desenvolver tipos diferentes das 
habilidades e das abilidades. As habilidades técnicas da dança
podem dar forma à fundação em que para desenvolver e realçar cada 
desempenho individual. Como professores da dança, nós podemos 
ter uma escala das habilidades, mas não é sempre possível possuir a
perícia em cada tipo de estilo e de técnica da dança. Ter o 
conhecimento e a experiência para ensinar formulários da dança, a 
dança do jazz ou o hop africano do hip aos estudantes é uma maneira 
grande de introduzi-los a uma variedade dos estilos e pode ser rich e 
processo recompensando. Entretanto, muitos professores nas 
escolas e nas faculdades trabalham dentro de um estilo contemporary da
dança porque terá sido a base de seus instrução e treinamento; 
é também o ponto da referência para esta unidade.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Balli comunica le idee attraverso movimento ed è
una forma di arte espressiva. Gli allievi devono imparare come 
usare il loro corpo in un modo sicuro e sano, mentre sviluppando un 
vasto vocabolario del movimento. L'uso delle tecniche differenti
di ballo può essere un modo efficace di sviluppo del vocabolario e di
sviluppare i generi differenti di abilità e di abilità. Le 
abilità tecniche di ballo possono formare il fondamento su cui 
sviluppare ed aumentare ogni prestazioni specifiche. Come 
insegnanti di ballo, possiamo avere una gamma di abilità, ma non è 
sempre possibile possedere la perizia in ogni tipo di stile e di 
tecnica di ballo. Avere la conoscenza e l'esperienza per 
insegnare le forme di ballo, il ballo di jazz o il luppolo africano 
dell'anca agli allievi è un modo grande di introduzione loro ad una 
varietà di stili e può essere rich e processo ricompensante. 
Tuttavia, molti insegnanti in scuole ed in università lavorano 
all'interno di uno stile contemporaneo di ballo perché sarà stato la
base della loro istruzione e formazione; è egualmente il punto 
di riferimento per questa unità.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο χορός επικοινωνεί τις ιδέες μέσω της μετακίνησης 
και είναι μια εκφραστική μορφή τέχνης. Οι σπουδαστές 
πρέπει να μάθουν πώς να χρησιμοποιήσουν το σώμα τους με έναν 
ασφαλή και υγιή τρόπο, ταυτόχρονα αναπτυσσόμενοι ένα εκτεταμένο
λεξιλόγιο μετακίνησης. Η χρήση των διαφορετικών τεχνικών 
χορού μπορεί να είναι ένας αποτελεσματικός τρόπος το λεξιλόγιο 
και τα διαφορετικά είδη δεξιοτήτων και δυνατοτήτων. Οι 
τεχνικές δεξιότητες χορού μπορούν να διαμορφώσουν το ίδρυμα στο 
οποίο να αναπτύξει και να ενισχύσει την απόδοση κάθε ατόμου. 
Σαν δασκάλους χορού, μπορούμε να έχουμε μια σειρά των 
δεξιοτήτων, αλλά είναι όχι πάντα δυνατό να κατέχεται η πείρα 
σε κάθε τύπο ύφους και τεχνικής χορού. Η κατοχή της 
γνώσης και της εμπειρίας για να διδάξει τις αφρικανικές μορφές 
χορού, το χορό τζαζ ή το λυκίσκο ισχίων στους σπουδαστές είναι 
ένας μεγάλος τρόπος τους σε ποικίλες μορφές και μπορεί να είναι
μια πλούσια και ανταμείβοντας διαδικασία. Εντούτοις, πολλοί
δάσκαλοι στα σχολεία και τα κολλέγια εργάζονται μέσα σε ένα 
σύγχρονο ύφος χορού επειδή θα είναι η βάση της εκπαίδευσης και 
της κατάρτισής τους  είναι επίσης το σημείο της αναφοράς 
για αυτήν την μονάδα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Baile comunica ideas a través del movimiento y 
es una forma de arte expresiva. Los estudiantes necesitan 
aprender cómo utilizar su cuerpo en una manera segura y sana, 
mientras que desarrollan un vasto vocabulario del movimiento. El
uso de diversas técnicas de la danza puede ser una manera eficaz de 
construir vocabulario y de desarrollar diversas clases de habilidades 
y de capacidades. Las habilidades técnicas de la danza pueden 
formar la fundación en la cual desarrollar y realzar cada 
funcionamiento individual. Como profesores de la danza, podemos 
tener un rango de habilidades, pero no es siempre posible poseer 
maestría en cada tipo de estilo y de técnica de la danza. 
Tener el conocimiento y la experiencia para enseñar formas de 
la danza, danza del jazz o el salto africana de la cadera a los 
estudiantes es una gran manera de introducirlos a una variedad de 
estilos y puede ser los ricos y proceso de recompensa. Sin 
embargo, muchos profesores en escuelas y universidades trabajan dentro
de un estilo contemporáneo de la danza porque habrá sido la base de 
su educación y entrenamiento; es también la punta de la 
referencia para esta unidad.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ausbildung</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Tanz</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kursteilnehmer</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lehrer</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Teaching_dance</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Teaching_techniques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Éducation</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Danse</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Étudiants</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Professeurs</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Teaching_dance</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Teaching_techniques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Instrução</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Dança</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Estudantes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Professores</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Teaching_dance</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Teaching_techniques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Formazione</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ballo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Allievi</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Insegnanti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Teaching_dance</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Teaching_techniques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εκπαίδευση</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Χορός</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σπουδαστές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δάσκαλοι</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Teaching_dance</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Teaching_techniques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Educación</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Danza</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Estudiantes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Profesores</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Teaching_dance</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Teaching_techniques</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <version>
            <string>1.0</string>
          </version>
          <status>
            <source>statusValues</source>
            <value>final</value>
          </status>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:Open University
N:Open University
ORG:Open University
ADR:Walton Hall, Milton Keynes, Buckinghamshire, MK7 6AA, United Kingdom
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:Open University
N:Open University
ORG:Open University
ADR:Walton Hall, Milton Keynes, Buckinghamshire, MK7 6AA, United Kingdom
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:openlearn.open.ac.uk:TL_DANCE1</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>LearningSpace</catalog>
            <entry>TL_DANCE1</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:Open University
N:Open University
ORG:Open University
ADR:Walton Hall, Milton Keynes, Buckinghamshire, MK7 6AA, United Kingdom
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <language>en-gb</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:OpenLearn
N:OpenLearn
ORG:OpenLearn
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T17:14:12.07Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <technical>
          <format>text/html</format>
          <location>http://openlearn.open.ac.uk/TL_DANCE1</location>
        </technical>
        <educational>
          <interactivityType>
            <source>interactivityTypeValues</source>
            <value>mixed</value>
          </interactivityType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>text</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <interactivityLevel>
            <source>interactivityLevelValues</source>
            <value>low</value>
          </interactivityLevel>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>higher education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="en-gb">18+</string>
            <string language="x-t-lre">18-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <difficulty>
            <source>difficultyValues</source>
            <value>medium</value>
          </difficulty>
          <typicalLearningTime>
            <duration>PT12H</duration>
          </typicalLearningTime>
          <description>
            <string language="en-gb">Independent self-study</string>
          </description>
          <language>en-gb</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en-gb">Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution - NonCommercial-ShareAlike 2.0 Licence - see http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/uk/ - Original copyright The Open University</string>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/uk/</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <relation>
          <kind>
            <source>LRE.kindValues</source>
            <value>references</value>
          </kind>
          <resource>
            <description>
              <string language="en-gb">Study this topic at the OU</string>
            </description>
            <identifier>
              <catalog>URL</catalog>
              <entry>http://www3.open.ac.uk/courses/classifications/education_and_teacher_training.shtm</entry>
            </identifier>
          </resource>
        </relation>
        <relation>
          <kind>
            <source>LRE.kindValues</source>
            <value>references</value>
          </kind>
          <resource>
            <description>
              <string language="en-gb">open2.net: Society</string>
            </description>
            <identifier>
              <catalog>URL</catalog>
              <entry>http://www.open2.net/society/</entry>
            </identifier>
          </resource>
        </relation>
        <relation>
          <kind>
            <source>LRE.kindValues</source>
            <value>isbasedon</value>
          </kind>
          <resource>
            <description>
              <string language="en-gb">This is the title and course code of the source course material</string>
            </description>
            <identifier>
              <catalog>Open University course</catalog>
              <entry>TeachandLearn.net - E500</entry>
            </identifier>
          </resource>
        </relation>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
      <entry>TL_DANCE1 - web site</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <identifier>
        <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
        <entry>TL_DANCE1 - web site</entry>
      </identifier>
      <location>
        <uri>http://openlearn.open.ac.uk/TL_DANCE1</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
      <entry>TL_DANCE1 - Common Cartridge 1.0</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>package in</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.packageInValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>imscc_v1p0</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <identifier>
        <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
        <entry>TL_DANCE1 - Common Cartridge 1.0</entry>
      </identifier>
      <location>
        <uri>http://openlearn.open.ac.uk/blocks/formats/logrequest.php?url=/file.php/2536/downloads/TL_DANCE1_ims_cc.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
      <entry>TL_DANCE1 - Content Package</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>package in</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.packageInValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>imscp_v1p1p4</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <identifier>
        <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
        <entry>TL_DANCE1 - Content Package</entry>
      </identifier>
      <location>
        <uri>http://openlearn.open.ac.uk/blocks/formats/logrequest.php?url=/file.php/2536/downloads/TL_DANCE1_ims_cp.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
