<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222921</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222921</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.oph.fi/etalukio/saksa/k5/index.html</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/etalukio/saksa/k5/index.html</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/etalukio/saksa/k5/index.html</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Then and now</string>
            <string language="fi">Ennen ja nyt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dann und jetzt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Puis et maintenant</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Então e agora</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Allora ed ora</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατόπιν και τώρα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Entonces y ahora</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <language>de</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Examines life before and now from the individual’s and society’s point of view. Contains texts to gain skills in telling about history, society, health or yourself in German. As the studies progress, the subject matters become more diverse and the texts become more challenging. Presents the strategies of text comprehension, helping you to read and understand more demanding texts and authentic content. Some of the texts are also available as listening exercises when you can decide whether you want to practise listening comprehension first or move straight to the text. The texts and study tips help to find individually suitable ways to read and understand new texts, even with strange subject matter.</string>
            <string language="fi">Tarkastelee elämää ennen ja nyt sekä yksilön että yhteiskunnan kannalta. Käsittää tekstejä, joiden avulla saa valmiuksia kertoa saksaksi historiasta, yhteiskunnasta, terveydestä tai itsestä. Opiskelun edetessä käsiteltävät aihepiirit monipuolistuvat ja tekstit muuttuvat haasteellisemmiksi. Esitelee tekstinymmärtämisen strategioita, jotka auttavat vaativampien tekstien ja autenttisten sisältöjen lukemisessa ja ymmärtämisessä. Osa teksteistä on myös kuunteluina, jolloin on itse päätettävissä, haluaako harjoitella ensin kuullunymmärtämistä vai siirtyä suoraan tekstiin. Tekstit ja opiskeluvihjeet auttavat löytämään itselle sopivia tapoja uuden, aihepiiriltään vieraankin, tekstin lukemiseen ja ymmärtämiseen.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="fi">Opetushallitus</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Überprüft das Leben vorher und jetzt von den 
individual?s und vom society?s Gesichtspunkt. Enthält Texte, um
Fähigkeiten, beim Erklären über Geschichte, Gesellschaft, 
Gesundheit oder sich auf Deutsch zu gewinnen. Als die Studien 
kommen Sie weiter, werden die Themen verschiedener und die Texte 
werden schwieriger. Stellt die Strategien des 
Textverständnisses dar und hilft Ihnen, mehr fordernde Texte und 
authentischen Inhalt zu lesen und zu verstehen. Einige der Texte
sind auch als hörende Übungen vorhanden, wenn Sie entscheiden 
können, ob Sie hörendes Erfassen zuerst üben oder auf den Text 
gerade umziehen möchten. Die Texte und die Studie Spitzen 
helfen, verwendbare Wege einzeln zu finden, die neuen Texte zu lesen 
und zu verstehen, die mit merkwürdigem Thema gleichmäßig sind.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Examine la vie avant et maintenant des 
individual?s et du point de vue de society?s. Contient des 
textes pour gagner les qualifications en disant au sujet de 
l'histoire, la société, la santé ou vous-même en allemand. 
Comme études progressez, les thèmes deviennent plus divers et 
les textes deviennent plus provocants. Présente les stratégies
de la compréhension des textes, vous aidant à lire et comprendre 
plus de textes exigeants et de contenu authentique. Certains des
textes sont également disponibles en tant qu'exercices d'écoute 
quand vous pouvez décider si vous voulez pratiquer la compréhension 
d'écoute d'abord ou vous déplacer directement au texte. Les 
textes et les extrémités d'étude aident à trouver individuellement
des moyens appropriés de lire et comprendre de nouveaux textes, même
avec les thèmes étranges.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Examina a vida antes e agora dos individual?s e 
do ponto dos society?s da vista. Contem textos para ganhar 
habilidades em dizer sobre o history, sociedade, saúde ou você mesmo
no alemão. Como os estudos progrida, as matérias sujeitas 
tornam-se mais diversas e os textos tornam-se mais challenging. 
Apresenta as estratégias da compreensão de texto, ajudando a 
lhe ler e compreender mais textos exijindo e índice authentic. 
Alguns dos textos estão também disponíveis como exercícios 
escutando quando você pode se decidir se você quer praticar 
primeiramente a compreensão escutando ou se mover em linha reta para 
o texto. Os textos e as pontas do estudo ajudam encontrar 
individualmente maneiras apropriadas ler e compreender os textos 
novos, uniformes com matéria sujeita estranha.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Prima ed ora esamina la vita dai individual?s e 
dal punto di vista dei society?s. Contiene i testi per 
guadagnare le abilità nel dire circa la storia, la società, la 
salute o voi stessi in tedesco. Come gli studi progredisca, i 
temi diventano più vari ed i testi diventano più challenging. 
Presenta le strategie di comprensione del testo, aiutandoli a 
leggere e capire più testi esigenti e soddisfare autentico. 
Alcuni dei testi sono egualmente disponibili come esercitazioni 
ascoltanti quando potete decidere se desiderate esercitarsi nella 
comprensione ascoltante in primo luogo o muoversi diritto verso il 
testo. I testi e le punte di studio contribuiscono a trovare 
individualmente i modi adatti leggere e capire i nuovi testi, anche 
con il tema sconosciuto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εξετάζει τη ζωή πριν από και τώρα από τα 
individual?s και society?s την άποψη. Περιέχει τα 
κείμενα για να κερδίσει τις δεξιότητες στην αφήγηση για την 
ιστορία, την κοινωνία, την υγεία ή τους ίδιους στα γερμανικά. 
Καθώς οι μελέτες προχωρούν, τα περιεχόμενα γίνονται πιό 
διαφορετικά και τα κείμενα γίνονται πιό προκλητικά. 
Παρουσιάζει τις στρατηγικές της κατανόησης κειμένων, που 
βοηθά σας για να διαβάσει και να καταλάβει τα κείμενα απαίτησης 
και το αυθεντικό περιεχόμενο. Μερικά από τα κείμενα είναι 
επίσης διαθέσιμα ως ασκήσεις ακούσματος όταν μπορείτε να 
αποφασίσετε εάν θέλετε να ασκήσετε την κατανόηση ακούσματος 
πρώτα ή να κινηθείτε κατ' ευθείαν προς το κείμενο. Τα 
κείμενα και οι άκρες μελέτης βοηθούν να βρούν τους χωριστά 
κατάλληλους τρόπους να διαβαστούν και να γίνουν κατανοητά τα νέα
κείμενα, ακόμη και με το παράξενο περιεχόμενο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Antes y ahora examina vida de los individual?s y 
del punto de vista de los society?s. Contiene los textos para 
ganar habilidades en hablar de historia, la sociedad, la salud o usted
mismo en alemán. Como los estudios progrese, los temas llegan a
ser más diversos y los textos llegan a ser más desafiadores. 
Presenta las estrategias de la comprensión de texto, 
ayudándole a leer y a entender más textos exigentes y contenido 
auténtico. Algunos de los textos están también disponibles 
como ejercicios que escuchan cuando usted puede decidir si usted desea
practicar la comprensión que escucha primero o trasladarse derecho al
texto. Los textos y las extremidades del estudio ayudan a 
encontrar individualmente maneras convenientes de leer y de entender 
los nuevos textos, uniformes con el tema extraño.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Katri Oldendorff
n:Oldendorff;Katri
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Lingonet
n:Lingonet
org:Lingonet
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/B5CDDA77-07D5-E031-BA52-8C0FC8C85048</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/B5CDDA77-07D5-E031-BA52-8C0FC8C85048</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pekka Pirhonen
n:Pirhonen;Pekka 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:49:39.45Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>glossary</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>course</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">15-19</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://www.oph.fi/etalukio/kayttoehdot/</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>1353</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>345</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>710</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>590</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1387</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>548</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.oph.fi/etalukio/saksa/k5/index.html</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oph.fi/etalukio/saksa/k5/index.html</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
