<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/79515</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>79515</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www2.edu.fi/etalukionterveystieto</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www2.edu.fi/etalukionterveystieto</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www2.edu.fi/etalukionterveystieto</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Distance general upper secondary school – Health and hygiene - Courses 1-2</string>
            <string language="fi">Etalukio - terveystieto - kurssit 1-2</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Abstand allgemeine obersekundarschule? 
Gesundheit und Hygiene - Kurse 1-2</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">École secondaire deuxième cycle générale de 
distance ? Santé et hygiène - cours 1-2</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Escola secundária superior geral da distância? 
Saúde e higiene - cursos 1-2</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scuola superiore-secondaria generale di distanza? 
Medicina e igiene del lavoro - corsi 1-2</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γενική ανώτερη δευτεροβάθμια εκπαίδευση απόστασης; 
Υγεία και υγιεινή - σειρές μαθημάτων 1-2</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿Escuela superior-secundaria general de la 
distancia? Salud e higiene - cursos 1-2</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The distance general upper secondary school health and hygiene education provides information on taking care of one's own health as well as health in society and the world, and expands ideas about the factors around us that affect our health. The distance general upper secondary school Health and Hygiene e-material consists of a core segment with related independent entities.  The e-material is designed for independent study and requires other supporting material, such as upper secondary school textbooks. References are made to the other material in the various elements.</string>
            <string language="fi">Etälukion terveystiedon opetus tarjoaa tietoa oman terveyden hoitamisesta sekä terveydestä yhteiskunnassa ja maailmassa ja laajentaa käsitystä siitä, mitkä tekijät ympärillämme vaikuttavat terveyteen. Etälukion terveystiedon verkkoaineisto koostuu ydinosasta, johon liittyy itsenäisiä kokonaisuuksia. Verkkoaineisto on tarkoitettu itsenäiseen opiskeluun ja tarvitsee tuekseen muuta aineistoa, kuten lukion oppikirjoja. Muuhun aineistoon on viitattu eri osakokonaisuuksissa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Abstand allgemeine 
obersekundarschulegesundheit und -hygieneausbildung stellt 
Informationen auf dem Kümmern von von um irgendjemandes eigener 
Gesundheit sowie Gesundheit in der Gesellschaft und in der Welt zur 
Verfügung und erweitert Ideen über die Faktoren um uns, daß unsere 
Gesundheit beeinflussen Sie. Das Abstand allgemeine 
obersekundarschule Gesundheit und Hygiene Ematerial besteht aus einem 
Kernsegment mit in Verbindung stehenden unabhängigen Instanzen. 
Das Ematerial ist für unabhängige Studie bestimmt und anderes 
Hilfsmaterial, wie obersekundarschulelehrbücher benötigt. 
Bezuge werden auf das andere Material in den verschiedenen 
Elementen genommen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'éducation secondaire deuxième cycle générale
de santé et d'hygiène d'école de distance fournit des informations 
sur prendre soin de sa propre santé aussi bien que la santé dans la 
société et le monde, et augmente des idées au sujet des facteurs 
autour de nous qu'affectez notre santé. L'e-matériel 
secondaire deuxième cycle général de santé et d'hygiène d'école 
de distance se compose d'un segment de noyau avec les entités 
indépendantes relatives. L'e-matériel est conçu pour l'étude
indépendante et exige l'autre matériel de support, tel que les 
manuels secondaires deuxième cycle d'école. Des références 
sont faites à l'autre matériel dans les divers éléments.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A instrução superior geral da saúde e da 
higiene de escola secundária da distância fornece a informação em 
tomar cuidado de one's própria saúde as.well.as a saúde na 
sociedade e no mundo, e expande idéias sobre os fatores em torno de 
nós que afete nossa saúde. O e-material superior geral da 
saúde e da higiene de escola secundária da distância consiste em um
segmento do núcleo com as entidades independentes relacionadas. 
O e-material é projetado para o estudo independente e requer o 
outro material suportando, tal como textbooks superiores da escola 
secundária. As referências são feitas ao outro material nos 
vários elementos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La formazione superiore-secondaria generale di 
medicina e igiene del lavoro della scuola di distanza fornisce le 
informazioni sulla presa della cura della sua propria salute così 
come la salute nella società e nel mondo ed espande le idee circa i 
fattori intorno noi che interessi la nostra salute. Il 
e-materiale superiore-secondario generale di medicina e igiene del 
lavoro della scuola di distanza consiste di un segmento di nucleo con 
le entità indipendenti relative. Il e-materiale è progettato 
per lo studio indipendente e richiede l'altro materiale di sostegno, 
quali i manuali superiori-secondarii della scuola. I riferimenti
sono fatti all'altro materiale nei vari elementi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η γενική ανώτερη εκπαίδευση υγείας και υγιεινής 
δευτεροβάθμιας εκπαίδευσης απόστασης παρέχει τις πληροφορίες για 
τη φροντίδα της υγείας κάποιου καθώς επίσης και της υγείας στην 
κοινωνία και τον κόσμο, και επεκτείνει τις ιδέες για τους 
παράγοντες γύρω από μας ότι επιρροή η υγεία μας. Το 
γενικό ανώτερο ε-υλικό υγείας και υγιεινής δευτεροβάθμιας 
εκπαίδευσης απόστασης αποτελείται από ένα τμήμα μνήμης πυρήνων
με τις σχετικές ανεξάρτητες οντότητες. Το ε-υλικό 
σχεδιάζεται για την ανεξάρτητη μελέτη και απαιτεί άλλο 
ενισχυτικό υλικό, όπως τα ανώτερα εγχειρίδια δευτεροβάθμιας 
εκπαίδευσης. Οι αναφορές γίνονται στο άλλο υλικό στα 
διάφορα στοιχεία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La educación superior-secundaria general de la 
salud y de la higiene de la escuela de la distancia proporciona a la 
información en tomar cuidado de su propia salud así como salud en 
sociedad y el mundo, y amplía ideas sobre los factores alrededor de 
nosotros que afecte nuestra salud. El e-material 
superior-secundario general de la salud y de la higiene de la escuela 
de la distancia consiste en un segmento de la base con las entidades 
independientes relacionadas. El e-material se diseña para el 
estudio independiente y requiere el otro material que utiliza, tal como 
libros de textos superiores-secundarios de la escuela. Las 
referencias se hacen al otro material en los varios elementos.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Harri Vertio
n:Vertio;Harri
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Twinkle Oy
n:Twinkle Oy
org:Twinkle Oy
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/65CD1A69-329A-D5CC-C349-4FAC1493C397</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/65CD1A69-329A-D5CC-C349-4FAC1493C397</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pekka Pirhonen
n:Pirhonen;Pekka 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:49:41.69Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>course</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">15-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://www02.oph.fi/etalukio/kayttoehdot/</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>582</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>583</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>620</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>345</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www2.edu.fi/etalukionterveystieto</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www2.edu.fi/etalukionterveystieto</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
