<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222657</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222657</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www2.edu.fi/etalukio/psykka_ruotsi/?cmscid=56&amp;oid=57&amp;subid=57</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www2.edu.fi/etalukio/psykka_ruotsi/?cmscid=56&amp;oid=57&amp;subid=57</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www2.edu.fi/etalukio/psykka_ruotsi/?cmscid=56&amp;oid=57&amp;subid=57</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Mental functions, learning and social interaction</string>
            <string language="fi">Psyykkinen toiminta, oppiminen ja vuorovaikutus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geistesfunktionen, Lernen und Sozialinteraktion</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Fonctions mentales, étude et interaction 
sociale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Funções mentais, aprendizagem e interação 
social</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Funzioni mentali, imparare ed interazione 
sociale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διανοητικές λειτουργίες, εκμάθηση και κοινωνική 
αλληλεπίδραση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Funciones mentales, el aprender e interacción 
social</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The objective of the upper secondary school first psychology course is to introduce psychology as a science and its applications in the various areas of society, to help in understanding various ways of studying and explaining human functions, and to teach the main topics in psychology and teach students to observe and consider human activities using the appropriate descriptive concepts. Moreover, students learn to understand learning applying psychological knowledge and use their knowledge to think about their own studying, as well as applying their knowledge of social psychology in examining social interaction and understanding themselves as members of groups. The course pictures and diagrams may also be printed in PDF format for teaching purposes. Includes exercises.</string>
            <string language="fi">Lukion ensimmäisen psykologian kurssin tavoitteena on tutustuttaa psykologiaan tieteenä ja psykologian soveltamiseen yhteiskunnan eri alueilla, auttaa ymmärtämään erilaisia tapoja tutkia ja selittää ihmisen toimintaa, sekä opettaa psykologian keskeisiä aihepiirejä ja opettaa havainnoimaan ja pohtimaan ihmisen toimintaa näitä kuvaavien käsitteiden avulla. Lisäksi opitaan ymmärtämään oppimista psykologiseen tietoon tukeutuen ja pohtimaan psykologisen tiedon avulla omaa opiskelua, sekä soveltamaan sosiaalipsykologista tietoa sosiaalisen vuorovaikutuksen tarkastelussa ja ymmärtämään itseä ryhmän jäsenenä. Kurssin kuvat ja kaaviot myös tulostettavassa pdf-muodossa opetuskäyttöä varten. Sisältää tehtäviä.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Lernziel des ersten Psychologiekurses der 
obersekundarschule ist, Psychologie als Wissenschaft und seine 
Anwendungen in den verschiedenen Bereichen der Gesellschaft 
vorzustellen, im Verstehen der verschiedenen Methoden des Studierens 
und des Erklärens der menschlichen Funktionen zu helfen, und, die 
Hauptthemen in der Psychologie zu unterrichten und Kursteilnehmer zu 
unterrichten, menschliche Aktivitäten mit den passenden 
beschreibenden Konzepten zu beobachten und zu betrachten. 
Außerdem erlernen Kursteilnehmer, das Lernen zu verstehen, 
psychologisches Wissen anwendend und ihr Wissen zu verwenden, um an 
ihr eigenes Studieren zu denken, sowie das Anwenden ihres Wissens von 
Sozialpsychologie in dem Überprüfen von von Sozialinteraktion und 
verstehend als Bauteile der Gruppen. Die Kursabbildungen und 
-diagramme können im pdf Format zu unterrichtenden Zwecken auch 
gedruckt werden. Schließt Übungen ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'objectif du premier cours de psychologie 
d'école secondaire deuxième cycle est présenter la psychologie 
comme science et ses applications dans les diverses zones de la 
société, aider de diverses voies d'arrangement d'étudier et 
d'expliquer des fonctions humaines, et pour enseigner les sujets 
principaux en psychologie et d'enseigner des étudiants à observer et
considérer des activités humaines en utilisant les concepts 
descriptifs appropriés. D'ailleurs, les étudiants apprennent 
à comprendre l'étude appliquant la connaissance psychologique et à 
employer leur connaissance pour penser à leur propre étudier, aussi 
bien qu'appliquer leur connaissance de la psychologie sociale en 
examinant l'interaction et l'arrangement sociaux eux-mêmes comme 
membres des groupes. Les images et les diagrammes de cours 
peuvent également être imprimés dans le format de pdf pour 
l'enseignement. Inclut des exercices.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O objetivo curso superior do psychology da escola
secundária do primeiro é introduzir o psychology como uma ciência e
as suas aplicações nas várias áreas de sociedade, ajudá-lo em 
compreender várias maneiras de estudar e de explicar funções 
humanas, e para ensinar os tópicos principais no psychology e ensinar
estudantes observar e considerar atividades humanas usando os 
conceitos descritivos apropriados. Além disso, os estudantes 
aprendem compreender a aprendizagem aplicando o conhecimento 
psicológico e usar seu conhecimento pensar sobre seu próprio 
estudar, as.well.as aplicar seu conhecimento do psychology social em 
examinar a interação social e em compreender-se como membros dos 
grupos. Os retratos e os diagramas do curso podem também ser 
imprimidos no formato do pdf para finalidades ensinando. Inclui 
exercícios.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'obiettivo del primo corso di psicologia della 
scuola superiore-secondaria è di introdurre la psicologia come 
scienza e le relative applicazioni nelle varie zone della società, di
aiutare nel capire i vari modi di studiare e di spiegazione delle 
funzioni umane e per insegnare i soggetti principali in psicologia ed 
insegnare gli allievi osservare e considerare le attività umane 
usando i concetti descrittivi adatti. Inoltre, gli allievi 
imparano capire imparare applicando la conoscenza psicologica ed usare
la loro conoscenza per pensare a loro proprio studiare, così come 
l'applicazione della loro conoscenza della psicologia sociale 
nell'esaminare l'interazione sociale e nel capirsi come membri dei 
gruppi. Le immagini e gli schemi di corso possono anche essere 
stampati nel formato del pdf per gli scopi d'istruzione. Include
le esercitazioni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο στόχος της ανώτερης σειράς μαθημάτων ψυχολογίας 
δευτεροβάθμιας εκπαίδευσης πρώτης είναι να εισαχθεί η ψυχολογία 
ως επιστήμη και οι αιτήσεις του στους διάφορους τομείς της 
κοινωνίας, να βοηθήσει στην κατανόηση των διάφορων τρόπων και τις
ανθρώπινες λειτουργίες, και να διδαχθούν τα βασικά θέματα στην 
ψυχολογία και να διδαχθούν οι σπουδαστές για να παρατηρήσει και να
εξετάσει τις ανθρώπινες δραστηριότητες που χρησιμοποιούν τις 
κατάλληλες περιγραφικές έννοιες. Επιπλέον, οι σπουδαστές 
μαθαίνουν να καταλαβαίνουν την εκμάθηση εφαρμόζοντας την 
ψυχολογική γνώση και να χρησιμοποιούν τη γνώση τους για να 
σκεφτούν για τη μελέτη τους, καθώς επίσης και εφαρμόζοντας τη 
γνώση κοινωνικής ψυχολογίας τους στην εξέταση της κοινωνικής 
αλληλεπίδρασης και την κατανόηση ως μέλη των ομάδων. Οι 
εικόνες και τα διαγράμματα σειράς μαθημάτων μπορούν επίσης να 
τυπωθούν με τη μορφή PDF για λόγους διδασκαλίας. 
Περιλαμβάνει τις ασκήσεις.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El objetivo del primer curso de la psicología de
la escuela superior-secundaria es introducir la psicología como 
ciencia y sus aplicaciones en las varias áreas de la sociedad, ayudar
en entender varias maneras de estudiar y de explicar funciones 
humanas, y para enseñar los asuntos principales en psicología y 
enseñar a estudiantes a observar y a considerar actividades humanas 
usando los conceptos descriptivos apropiados. Por otra parte, 
los estudiantes aprenden entender aprender aplicando conocimiento 
psicologico y utilizar su conocimiento para pensar de su propio 
estudiar, así como la aplicación de su conocimiento de la 
psicología social en examinar la interacción social y entenderse 
como miembros de grupos. Los cuadros y los diagramas del curso 
se pueden también imprimir en el formato del pdf para los propósitos
de enseñanza. Incluye ejercicios.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Anne Rongas
n:Rongas;Anne
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Asko Korpela
n:Korpela;Asko
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/A7ED5003-6818-4D46-879B-23C13BB5D051</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/A7ED5003-6818-4D46-879B-23C13BB5D051</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pekka Pirhonen
n:Pirhonen;Pekka 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:49:42.55Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>course</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">15-19</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://www.oph.fi/etalukio/kayttoehdot/</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>1040</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1353</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>345</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>727</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www2.edu.fi/etalukio/psykka_ruotsi/?cmscid=56&amp;oid=57&amp;subid=57</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www2.edu.fi/etalukio/psykka_ruotsi/?cmscid=56&amp;oid=57&amp;subid=57</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
