<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/80421</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>80421</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/musiikki/folkbox_3/index.html</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/musiikki/folkbox_3/index.html</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="fi">Perinnemusiikin elementtejä - Osa 3: Sävelkulku eri viritysjärjestelmissä</string>
            <string language="en">Elements of traditional music - Part 3: Pitch in various tuning systems</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Elemente der traditionellen Musik - Teil 3: 
Taktabstand in den verschiedenen justierensystemen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Éléments de la musique traditionnelle - partie 3
: Lancement dans divers systèmes d'accord</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Elementos da música tradicional - parte 3: 
Passo em vários sistemas ajustando</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Elementi di musica tradizionale - parte 3: 
Passo in vari sistemi di sintonia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στοιχεία της παραδοσιακής μουσικής - μέρος 3: 
Πίσσα στα διάφορα συντονίζοντας συστήματα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Elementos de la música tradicional - parte 3: 
Echada en varios sistemas que templan</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Perinnemusiikin elementtejä on neljän oppimisaihion sarja, joka on tarkoitettu 11-vuotiaille ja sitä vanhemmille musiikin opetukseen ja monikulttuuriseen kasvatukseen. Tavoitteena on antaa valmiuksia eri maiden kansanmusiikin ymmärtämiseen. Aihiot sopivat itsenäiseen työskentelyyn, mutta paras hyöty saadaan ryhmässä. Tässä Sävelkulku eri viritysjärjestelmissä -aihiossa tutustutaan sävelkulkuun luonnonviritysjärjestelmässä ja tasavireisessä järjestelmässä. Aihiot on toteutettu Flash-tekniikalla. Toimiakseen ne tarvitsevat selaimeen Flash-laajennuksen, jonka voit ladata ilmaiseksi tietokoneellesi.</string>
            <string language="en">Elements of traditional music is a series of four learning objects that is meant for 11-year-olds and older pupils for music teaching and multicultural education. The aim is to equip pupils to understand the folk music of various countries. The objects are suitable for independent work, but the best benefit is obtained in a group. This Pitch in Various Tuning Systems object introduces the pupil to pitch in a natural tuning system and in a tempered system. The objects have been implemented with Flash technology. In order for them to work, they need a Flash add-on in the browser, which you can download for free onto your computer.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">sävelkulku,</string>
            <string language="en">viritysjärjestelmät</string>
            <string language="fi">sävelkulku,</string>
            <string language="fi">viritysjärjestelmät</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Elemente der traditionellen Musik ist Reihen von 
vier erlernennachrichten, die für 11-year-olds und ältere Pupillen 
für Musikunterricht und multikulturelle Ausbildung bedeutet wird. 
Das Ziel ist ausrüsten Pupillen, um die Volksmusik der 
verschiedenen Länder zu verstehen. Die Nachrichten sind für 
unabhängige Arbeit verwendbar, aber der beste Nutzen wird in einer 
Gruppe erreicht. Dieser Taktabstand in der verschiedenen 
justierensysteme Nachricht führt die Pupille ein, um in ein 
natürliches justierensystem und in ein gemildertes System zu werfen. 
Die Nachrichten sind mit greller Technologie eingeführt worden.
Damit sie, um zu arbeiten, sie einen Blitzzusatz in der 
Datenbanksuchroutine benötigen, die Sie für freies auf Ihren 
Computer downloaden können.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les éléments de la musique traditionnelle est 
des séries de quatre objets d'étude qui sont signifiées pour 
11-year-olds et pupilles plus anciennes pour l'enseignement de musique
et l'éducation multiculturelle. Le but est équipent des 
pupilles pour comprendre la musique folklorique de divers pays. 
Les objets conviennent au travail indépendant, mais le meilleur
avantage est obtenu en groupe. Ce lancement dans le divers objet
d'accord de systèmes présente la pupille pour lancer dans un 
système d'accord normal et dans un système gâché. Les objets
ont été mis en application avec la technologie instantanée. 
Afin qu'ils puissent pour fonctionner, ils aient besoin d'une 
adjonction d'instantané dans le navigateur, que vous pouvez 
télécharger pour libre sur votre ordinateur.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os elementos da música tradicional são umas 
séries de quatro objetos de aprendizagem que sejam significadas para 
11-year-olds e umas pupilas mais velhas para o ensino da música e a 
instrução multicultural. O alvo é equipa as pupilas para 
compreender a música popular de vários países. Os objetos 
são apropriados para o trabalho independente, mas o mais melhor 
benefício é obtido em um grupo. Este passo no vário objeto 
ajustando dos sistemas introduz a pupila para lançar em um sistema 
ajustando natural e em um sistema moderado. Os objetos foram 
executados com tecnologia flash. Para que para trabalhar, eles 
necessitam um add-on do flash no browser, que você pode download para
livre em seu computador.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli elementi di musica tradizionale è una serie 
di quattro oggetti imparanti che è significata per 11-year-olds e le 
più vecchie pupille per insegnamento di musica e formazione 
multicultural. Lo scopo è dota le pupille per capire la musica 
di piega di vari paesi. Gli oggetti sono adatti a lavoro 
indipendente, ma il beneficio migliore è ottenuto in gruppo. 
Questo passo in vario oggetto di sintonia dei sistemi introduce 
la pupilla per lanciare in un sistema di sintonia naturale ed in un 
sistema temperato. Gli oggetti sono stati effettuati con 
tecnologia istantanea. Nell'ordine affinchè loro funzionino, 
hanno bisogno di un'adjunta dell'istantaneo nel browser, che dal 
sistema centrale verso i satelliti potete trasferire per libero sul 
vostro calcolatore.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα στοιχεία της παραδοσιακής μουσικής είναι μια σειρά
τεσσάρων αντικειμένων εκμάθησης που σημαίνουν για το 11-έτος και 
τους παλαιότερους μαθητές για τη διδασκαλία μουσικής και την 
πολυπολιτισμική εκπαίδευση. Ο στόχος είναι να εξοπλιστούν 
οι μαθητές για να καταλάβει τη λαϊκή μουσική των διάφορων 
χωρών. Τα αντικείμενα είναι κατάλληλα για την ανεξάρτητη 
εργασία, αλλά το καλύτερο όφελος λαμβάνεται σε μια ομάδα. 
Αυτή η πίσσα στο διάφορο συντονίζοντας αντικείμενο 
συστημάτων εισάγει το μαθητή για να ρίξει σε ένα φυσικό 
συντονίζοντας σύστημα και σε ένα μετριασμένο σύστημα. Τα 
αντικείμενα έχουν εφαρμοστεί με την τεχνολογία λάμψης. Για 
λειτουργούν, χρειάζονται μια λάμψη πρόσθετη στον ξεφυλλιστή, τον 
οποίο μπορείτε να μεταφορτώσετε δωρεάν επάνω στον υπολογιστή 
σας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los elementos de la música tradicional son las 
series de cuatro objetos que aprenden que se significan para 
11-year-olds y pupilas más viejas para la enseñanza de la música y 
la educación multicultural. La puntería es equipa pupilas para
entender la música tradicional de varios países. Los objetos 
son convenientes para el trabajo independiente, pero la mejor ventaja se 
obtiene en un grupo. Esta echada en vario objeto de los sistemas
que templa introduce la pupila para echar en un sistema que templa 
natural y en un sistema templado. Los objetos se han puesto en 
ejecucio'n con tecnología de destello. En la orden para que 
trabajen, necesitan una agregación del flash en el browser, que usted
puede descargar para libre sobre su ordenador.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">sävelkulku,</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">viritysjärjestelmät</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">sävelkulku,</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">viritysjärjestelmät</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">sävelkulku,</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">viritysjärjestelmät</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">sävelkulku,</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">viritysjärjestelmät</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">sδvelkulku,</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">viritysjδrjestelmδt</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">sävelkulku,</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">viritysjärjestelmät</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/DAD47B71-F638-189A-38BD-18D76331F580</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/DAD47B71-F638-189A-38BD-18D76331F580</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Anna-Elina Häkkilä
n:Häkkilä;Anna-Elina 
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>fi</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE)
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE)
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE)
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2009-04-09T19:44:34.79Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">11-15</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://www.edu.fi/page.asp?path=498,507,19640</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>856</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>80421</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/musiikki/folkbox_3/index.html</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
