<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/235328</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>235328</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.oph.fi/instancedata/prime_product_julkaisu/oph/embeds/49141_iloa_tutkimuksesta.pdf</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/instancedata/prime_product_julkaisu/oph/embeds/49141_iloa_tutkimuksesta.pdf</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/instancedata/prime_product_julkaisu/oph/embeds/49141_iloa_tutkimuksesta.pdf</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Joy of studying</string>
            <string language="fi">Iloa tutkimisesta</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Freude am Studieren</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Joie d'étudier</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Alegria de estudar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gioia di studiare</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Χαρά</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Alegría de estudiar</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The material is meant primarily as a support for preschool and class teachers. The material is designed to assist the teaching of environmental and natural history by providing experimental work and study topics as well as advice and instructions on carrying out teaching. Natural phenomena are examined on the macroscopic level, and a problem-centred, investigative approach is employed in teaching. Performing experimental work does not require the teacher to have special knowledge of the natural sciences, but it guides the teacher and pupils together to examine, discuss and find out about things. Adobe Reader software is required for accessing the PDF material.</string>
            <string language="fi">Materiaali on tarkoitettu ensisijaisesti esikoulun- ja luokanopettajien
tueksi. Materiaalin tarkoituksena on auttaa ympäristö- ja luonnontiedon
opetusta tarjoamalla kokeellisia töitä ja tutkimusaiheita sekä neuvoja ja
ohjeita opetuksen toteuttamiseen. Luonnontieteellisiin ilmiöihin tutustutaan
makroskooppisella tasolla, ja opetuksessa käytetään ongelmakeskeistä,
tutkivaa lähestymistapaa. Kokeellisten töiden tekeminen ei vaadi opettajalta
erityistä luonnontieteellistä tietämystä, mutta se ohjaa opettajaa ja oppilaita
yhdessä tutkimaan, pohtimaan ja ottamaan selvää asioista. PDF-materiaalin käyttöön tarvitaan Adobe Reader -ohjelma.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Material wird hauptsächlich als Support für
Vortraining und Kategorie Lehrer bedeutet. Das Material wird 
konzipiert, um den Unterricht der Klima- und Naturgeschichte zu 
unterstützen, indem man experimentelle Arbeit zur Verfügung stellt 
und Themen sowie Rat und Anweisungen zu studieren auf dem 
durchführendem Unterrichten. Natürliche Phänomene werden auf 
der makroskopischen Stufe überprüft, und eine Problem-zentrierte, 
Untersuchungsannäherung wird beim Unterrichten eingesetzt. Das 
Durchführen der experimentellen Arbeit benötigt nicht den Lehrer, 
spezielles Wissen der natürlichen Wissenschaften zu haben, aber es 
führt den Lehrer und die Schüler zusammen sind, um zu überprüfen, 
behandelt und findet über Sachen heraus. 
Ziegelstein-Lesersoftware wird für das Zugreifen auf das pdf 
Material benoetigt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le matériel est signifié principalement comme 
soutien des professeurs de précours et de classe. Le matériel 
est conçu pour aider l'enseignement de l'histoire naturelle 
environnementale et en fournissant le travail expérimental et pour 
étudier des sujets aussi bien que le conseil et des instructions 
sur l'enseignement de mise en oeuvre. Des phénomènes normaux 
sont examinés au niveau macroscopique, et une approche 
problème-centrée et investigatrice est utilisée dans 
l'enseignement. Exécuter le travail expérimental n'exige pas 
du professeur d'avoir la connaissance spéciale des sciences normales,
mais il guident le professeur et les élèves ensemble pour examiner, 
les discutent et découvrent au sujet des choses. Le logiciel de
lecteur d'adobe est exigé pour accéder au matériel de pdf.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O material é significado primeiramente como uma 
sustentação para professores do pré-escolar e da classe. O 
material é projetado ajudar ao ensino do history ambiental e natural 
fornecendo o trabalho experimental e estudar tópicos as.well.as o 
conselho e instruções em ensinar realizando-se. Os fenômenos 
naturais são examinados no nível macroscópico, e uma aproximação 
problema-centrada, investigative é empregada em ensinar. 
Executar o trabalho experimental não requer o professor ter o 
conhecimento especial das ciências naturais, mas guia o professor e 
os alunos junto para examinar, discute-os e encontra-os para fora 
sobre coisas. O software do leitor do adôbe é requerido 
alcançando o material do pdf.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il materiale è significato soprattutto come 
sostegno gli insegnanti del codice categoria e dell'addestramento 
preliminare. Il materiale è destinato per aiutare 
l'insegnamento della storia naturale ambientale e fornendo il lavoro 
sperimentale e per studiare i soggetti così come consiglio e le 
istruzioni sull'istruzione d'avanzamento. I fenomeni naturali 
sono esaminati al livello macroscopico e un metodo problema-centrato e
investigativo è impiegato nell'istruzione. Realizzare il lavoro
sperimentale non richiede all'insegnante di avere conoscenza speciale 
delle scienze naturali, ma guida insieme l'insegnante e gli allievi 
per esaminare, discute e scopre circa le cose. Il software del 
lettore dell'adobe è richiesto per l'accesso a del materiale del pdf.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το υλικό σημαίνουν πρώτιστα ως υποστήριξη για τις 
καθηγητές παιδικών σταθμών και τάξης. Το υλικό σχεδιάζεται
για να βοηθήσει τη διδασκαλία της περιβαλλοντικής και φυσικής 
ιστορίας με την παροχή των θεμάτων πειραματικής εργασίας και 
μελέτης καθώς επίσης και των συμβουλών και των οδηγιών για την 
πραγματοποίηση της διδασκαλίας. Τα φυσικά φαινόμενα 
εξετάζονται στο μακροσκοπικό επίπεδο, και μια 
πρόβλημα-κεντροθετημένη, εξεταστική προσέγγιση υιοθετείται στη 
διδασκαλία. Η εκτέλεση της πειραματικής εργασίας δεν 
απαιτεί το δάσκαλο για να έχει την ειδική γνώση των φυσικών 
επιστημών, αλλά καθοδηγεί το δάσκαλο και τους μαθητές μαζί για 
να εξετάσει, να συζητήσει και να βρεί έξω για τα πράγματα. 
Το λογισμικό αναγνωστών πλίθας απαιτείται για την πρόσβαση 
του υλικού PDF.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El material se significa sobre todo como ayuda 
para los profesores del pre-entrenamiento y de la clase. El 
material es diseñado para asistir a la enseñanza de la historia 
ambiental y natural proporcionando al trabajo experimental y para 
estudiar asuntos así como consejo e instrucciones en la enseñanza 
que realiza. Los fenómenos naturales se examinan en el nivel 
macroscópico, y un acercamiento problema-centrado, investigador se 
emplea en la enseñanza. La ejecución del trabajo experimental 
no requiere a profesor tener conocimiento especial de las ciencias 
naturales, pero dirige al profesor y a pupilas juntas para examinar, 
los discute y descubre sobre cosas. El software del programa de 
lectura del adobe se requiere para tener acceso al material del pdf.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pirjo Nylund
n:Nylund;Pirjo
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Kirsi-maaria Vakkilainen
n:Vakkilainen;Kirsi-maaria
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Jukka Nikkonen
n:Nikkonen;Jukka
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Taloudellinen Tiedotustoimisto
n:Taloudellinen Tiedotustoimisto
org:Taloudellinen Tiedotustoimisto
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/D216C0F5-A4A6-2635-3A4C-ED9983EC7B39</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/D216C0F5-A4A6-2635-3A4C-ED9983EC7B39</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Katja Pajuluoma
n:Pajuluoma;Katja 
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:36:44.71Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>guide</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>exploration</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>pre-school</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">7-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Creative commons Nimeä-epäkaupallinen-Ei muutettuja teoksia 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>431</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1282</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>430</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>875</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.oph.fi/instancedata/prime_product_julkaisu/oph/embeds/49141_iloa_tutkimuksesta.pdf</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>application/pdf</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oph.fi/instancedata/prime_product_julkaisu/oph/embeds/49141_iloa_tutkimuksesta.pdf</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
