<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222716</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222716</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/metallituotemaalaus</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/metallituotemaalaus</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/metallituotemaalaus</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Support and additional material for the textbook Painting of Metal Products</string>
            <string language="fi">Oppikirjan metallituotteiden maalaus - Tuki- ja lisämateriaali</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Support und zusätzliches Material für den 
Lehrbuch Anstrich der Metallprodukte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Soutien et matériel supplémentaire de la 
peinture de manuel des produits en métal</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Sustentação e material adicional para a pintura
do textbook de produtos do metal</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sostegno e materiale supplementare la pittura del
manuale dei prodotti del metallo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Υποστήριξη και πρόσθετο υλικό για τη ζωγραφική 
εγχειριδίων των προϊόντων μετάλλων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ayuda y material adicional para la pintura del 
libro de textos de los productos del metal</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The website contains printable revision tasks related to the textbook Metal Product Painting, comprising multiple-choice tasks as well as verbal tasks in Word format, as well as additional material and a set of transparencies related to the subjects of the textbook, which can be used as a support for teaching. The website has a link to a collection of links on the surface treatment sector.
The web tasks include revision tasks related to the textbook to be done on a PC, which include instructions for use.</string>
            <string language="fi">Sivusto sisältää oppikirjaan Metallituotemaalaus  liittyvät tulostettavat kertaustehtävät, jotka koostuvat monivalintatehtävistä sekä Word -muotoisista sanallisista tehtävistä, sekä oppikirjan aiheisiin liittyvän lisämateriaalin ja kalvosarjan, jota voidaan käyttää opetuksen tukena. Sivustolta on linkki pintakäsittelyalan linkkikokoelmaan.  
Verkkotehtävät sisältävät oppikirjaan liittyviä PC:llä tehtäviä kertaustehtäviä, jotka sisältävät käyttöohjeet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Web site enthält die bedruckbaren 
Änderungaufgaben, die auf dem Lehrbuch Metallprodukt-Anstrich in 
Verbindung gestanden werden und enthält Mehrfachwahl Aufgaben sowie 
mündliche Aufgaben im Wortformat, sowie zusätzliches Material und 
ein Set Transparente, die auf den Themen des Lehrbuchs in Verbindung 
gestanden werden, das als Support für das Unterrichten benutzt werden
kann. Die Web site läßt ein Link zu einer Ansammlung Links auf
den OberflächenWeb-Aufgaben der behandlung sector.The die 
Änderungaufgaben einschließen, die auf dem auf in Verbindung 
gestanden werden einem PC getan zu werden Lehrbuch,, die 
Anwendungsvorschriften einschließen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le site Web contient la révision imprimable 
charge connexe à la peinture de produit en métal de manuel,
comportant le multiple-choix charge comme verbal 
charge dans le format de mot, aussi bien que le matériel 
supplémentaire et un ensemble de transparents liés aux sujets du 
manuel, qui peut être utilisé comme support pour l'enseignement. 
Le site Web a un lien à une collection de liens sur le Web 
extérieur du traitement sector.The charge incluent la 
révision charge connexes au manuel à faire sur un PC, qui 
incluent des instructions pour l'usage.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Web site contem as tarefas printable da 
revisão relacionadas à pintura do produto do metal do textbook, 
compreendendo tarefas da múltiplo-escolha as.well.as tarefas verbais 
no formato da palavra, as.well.as o material adicional e um jogo das 
transparências relacionadas aos assuntos do textbook, que pode ser 
usado como uma sustentação ensinando. O Web site manda uma 
ligação a uma coleção das ligações nas tarefas de superfície do
Web do tratamento sector.The incluir as tarefas da revisão 
relacionadas ao textbook a ser feito em um PC, que incluem 
instruções para o uso.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Web site contiene le mansioni stampabili di 
revisione relative alla pittura del prodotto del metallo del manuale, 
contenente le mansioni di multiplo-scelta così come le mansioni 
verbali nel formato di parola, così come il materiale supplementare e
un insieme degli acetati relativi agli argomenti di manuale, che può 
essere usato come supporto per insegnare. Il Web site fa 
includere un collegamento ad una collezione di collegamenti sulle 
mansioni di superficie di Web di trattamento sector.The le mansioni di
revisione relative al manuale da fare su un pc, che includono le 
istruzioni per uso.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο ιστοχώρος περιέχει τις εκτυπώσιμες στοιχειώδεις 
εργασίες αναθεώρησης σχετικές με τη ζωγραφική προϊόντων 
μετάλλων εγχειριδίων, περιλαμβάνοντας τις πολλαπλής επιλογής 
στοιχειώδεις εργασίες καθώς επίσης και τις λεκτικές στοιχειώδεις
εργασίες με τη μορφή του Word, καθώς επίσης και το πρόσθετο 
υλικό και ένα σύνολο διαφανειών σχετικών με τα θέματα του 
εγχειριδίου, το οποίο μπορεί να χρησιμοποιηθεί ως υποστήριξη για 
τη διδασκαλία. Ο ιστοχώρος έχει μια σύνδεση με μια συλλογή 
των συνδέσεων στον τομέα της επεξεργασίας επιφάνειας Οι 
στοιχειώδεις εργασίες Ιστού περιλαμβάνουν τις στοιχειώδεις 
εργασίες αναθεώρησης σχετικές με το εγχειρίδιο που γίνεται σε 
ένα PC, οι οποίες περιλαμβάνουν τις οδηγίες για τη χρήση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Web site contiene las tareas imprimibles de la
revisión relacionadas con la pintura del producto del metal del libro
de textos, abarcando tareas de la mu'ltiple-opcio'n así como tareas 
verbales en formato de la palabra, así como el material adicional y 
un conjunto de transparencias relacionadas con los temas del libro de 
textos, que se puede utilizar como ayuda para enseñar. El Web 
site hace que una conexión a una colección de conexiones en las 
tareas superficiales del Web del tratamiento sector.The incluya las 
tareas de la revisión relacionadas con el libro de textos que se 
hará en una PC, que incluyen las instrucciones para el uso.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Isto Jokinen
n:Jokinen;Isto
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/96B59D97-F56E-01A1-3D32-61E1979994A2</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/96B59D97-F56E-01A1-3D32-61E1979994A2</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pertti Siekkinen
n:Siekkinen;Pertti 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:55:17.97Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>vocational education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">16-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd-nc/1.0/</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>812</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1369</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>939</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>811</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/metallituotemaalaus</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/metallituotemaalaus</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
