<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/235290</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>235290</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi/perusopetus/uskonto_ja_elamankatsomustieto/uskontonetti</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/perusopetus/uskonto_ja_elamankatsomustieto/uskontonetti</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/perusopetus/uskonto_ja_elamankatsomustieto/uskontonetti</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Religion web</string>
            <string language="fi">Uskontonetti</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Religionweb</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Web de religion</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Web da religião</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Web di religione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ιστός θρησκείας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Web de la religión</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The website has been compiled to develop the teaching of religion in small groups in comprehensive and upper secondary schools. The objective is to support the teachers’ work by offering them various tools for the planning and implementation of teaching. The website also includes a lot of information on religions that can be utilised by the organisers of teaching, headmasters, parents and any interested parties.
Religions and religious communities are presented in alphabetical order according to the principles of the curriculum for religion. The different principles for the categories of religions and religious movements are presented in the section entitled Religions in a nutshell.  The sections include the basics of curricula, implementation of teaching, on the teaching of religion, religions in a nutshell, materials for teaching, and frequently asked questions. The cooperation bodies are also listed on a separate page.</string>
            <string language="fi">Sivut on koottu kehittämään pienryhmäisten uskontojen opetusta peruskoulussa ja lukiossa. Tarkoitus on tukea opettajien työtä tarjoamalla heille erilaisia välineitä opetuksen suunnitteluun ja toteutukseen. Sivuilta löytyy myös paljon sellaista tietoa uskonnoista, jota voivat hyödyntää niin opetuksen järjestäjät, rehtorit, vanhemmat kuin muutkin kiinnostuneet. 

Uskonnot ja uskonnolliset yhdyskunnat on laitettu aakkosjärjestykseen uskonnon opetussuunnitelmien perusteiden mukaisesti. Uskontojen ja uskonnollisten liikkeiden erilaisiin lajitteluperiaatteisiin voi tutustua Uskonnot pähkinänkuoressa -osiossa. Osa-alueet ovat petussuunnitelmien perusteet, opetuksen toteuttaminen, uskonnon opettamisesta, uskonnot pähkinänkuoressa, materiaaleja opetukseen ja usein kysyttyä. Omalla sivullaan luetellaan lisäksi yhteistyötahot.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="fi">Myöempien</string>
            <string language="fi">Kanssa</string>
            <string language="fi">Kristuksen</string>
            <string language="fi">Pyhien</string>
            <string language="fi">Kirstiyhteisö,</string>
            <string language="fi">ry,</string>
            <string language="fi">Vapaakirkollinen</string>
            <string language="fi">Jeesuksen</string>
            <string language="fi">Kirkko,</string>
            <string language="fi">aikojen</string>
            <string language="fi">Herran</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Web site ist kompiliert worden, um den 
Unterricht der Religion in den kleinen Gruppen in den kompletten und 
obersekundarschulen zu entwickeln. Das Lernziel ist, die Lehrer 
zu unterstützen? arbeiten Sie, indem Sie ihnen verschiedene 
Hilfsmittel für die Planung und die Implementierung des Unterrichtens
anbieten. Die Web site schließt auch eine Menge Informationen 
über Religionen ein, die von den Organisatoren des Unterrichtens, 
Rektoren, Eltern verwendet werden können und alle interessierten 
parties.Religions- und frommen Gemeinschaften in alphabetischer 
Reihenfolge entsprechend den Grundregeln des Lehrplans für Religion 
dargestellt werden. Die unterschiedlichen Grundregeln für die 
Kategorien von Religionen und von frommen Bewegungen werden im Kapitel
dargestellt, das Religionen in einer Nußschale erlaubt wird. 
Die Kapitel schließen die Grundlagen von Lehrplänen, 
Implementierung des Unterrichtens, auf dem Unterricht der Religion, 
Religionen in einer Nußschale, Materialien für das Unterrichten und 
häufig gestellte Fragen ein. Die Mitarbeitkörper werden auch 
auf einer unterschiedlichen Seite ausgedruckt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le site Web a été compilé pour développer 
l'enseignement de la religion dans de petits groupes dans les écoles 
complètes et secondaires deuxième cycle. L'objectif est de 
supporter les professeurs ? travaillez à côté de leur offrir 
de divers outils pour la planification et la mise en place de 
l'enseignement. Le site Web inclut également beaucoup 
d'information sur les religions qui peuvent être utilisées par les 
organisateurs de l'enseignement, directeurs, parents et toutes les 
communautés intéressées de parties.Religions et religieuses sont 
présentées dans l'ordre alphabétique selon les principes du 
programme d'études pour la religion. Les différents principes 
pour les catégories des religions et des mouvements religieux sont 
présentés dans la section autorisée des religions en un mot. 
Les sections incluent les fondations des programmes d'études, 
la mise en place de l'enseignement, sur l'enseignement de la religion,
les religions en un mot, les matériaux pour enseigner, et les 
questions fréquemment posées. Les corps de coopération sont 
également énumérés à une page séparée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Web site foi compilado para desenvolver o 
ensino da religião em grupos pequenos em escolas secundárias 
detalhadas e superiores. O objetivo é suportar os professores? 
trabalhe oferecendo lhes várias ferramentas para o planeamento 
e a execução de ensinar. O Web site inclui também muitos da 
informação nas religiões que podem ser utilizadas pelos organisers 
de ensinar, headmasters, pais e todas as comunidades interessadas de 
parties.Religions e religiosas são apresentadas na ordem alfabética 
de acordo com os princípios do curriculum para a religião. Os 
princípios diferentes para as categorias de religiões e de 
movimentos religiosos são apresentados na seção intitulada 
religiões em um nutshell. As seções incluem os princípios 
dos curricula, a execução de ensinar, no ensino da religião, as 
religiões em um nutshell, os materiais para ensinar, e perguntas 
freqüentemente feitas. Os corpos da cooperação são alistados
também em uma página separada.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Web site è stato compilato per sviluppare 
l'insegnamento della religione nei piccoli gruppi in scuole complete e
superiori-secondarie. L'obiettivo è sostenere gli insegnanti? 
funzioni offrendo loro i vari strumenti per la progettazione e 
l'implementazione di istruzione. Il Web site egualmente include 
le informazioni molto sulle religioni che possono essere 
utilizzate dai organisers di istruzione, i headmasters, genitori e 
tutte le Comunità religiose interessate e di parties.Religions sono 
presentate nell'ordine alfabetico secondo i principii del programma di
studi per la religione. I principii differenti per le categorie 
di religioni e di movimenti religiosi sono presentati nella sezione 
intitolata religioni in un nutshell. Le sezioni includono i 
principi fondamentali dei programmi di studi, l'implementazione di 
istruzione, sull'insegnamento della religione, le religioni in un 
nutshell, i materiali per l'istruzione e le domande frequentemente 
fatte. I corpi di cooperazione egualmente sono elencati ad una 
pagina separata.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο ιστοχώρος έχει μεταγλωττιστεί για να αναπτύξει τη 
διδασκαλία της θρησκείας στις μικρές ομάδες στη δημόσια και 
ανώτερη δευτεροβάθμια εκπαίδευση. Ο στόχος είναι να 
υποστηριχθούν οι δάσκαλοι; εργασία με την προσφορά τους των 
διάφορων εργαλείων για τον προγραμματισμό και την εφαρμογή της 
διδασκαλίας. Ο ιστοχώρος περιλαμβάνει επίσης πολλές 
πληροφορίες για τις θρησκείες που μπορούν να χρησιμοποιηθούν από 
τους διοργανωτές της διδασκαλίας, οι διευθυντές, οι γονείς και 
οποιεσδήποτε ενδιαφερόμενες κοινότητες θρησκειών συμβαλλόμενων 
μερών θρησκευτικών και παρουσιάζονται κατά αλφαβητική σειρά 
σύμφωνα με τις αρχές του προγράμματος σπουδών για τη θρησκεία. 
Οι διαφορετικές αρχές για τις κατηγορίες θρησκειών και 
θρησκευτικών μετακινήσεων παρουσιάζονται στο τμήμα που 
τιτλοφορείται θρησκείες εν συντομία. Τα τμήματα 
περιλαμβάνουν τα βασικά των προγραμμάτων σπουδών, την εφαρμογή 
της διδασκαλίας, στη διδασκαλία της θρησκείας, τις θρησκείες εν 
συντομία, τα υλικά για τη διδασκαλία, και τις συχνά ερωτήσεις. 
Οι οργανισμοί συνεργασίας παρατίθενται επίσης σε μια 
χωριστή σελίδα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Web site se ha compilado para desarrollar la 
enseñanza de la religión en grupos pequeños en escuelas 
comprensivas y superiores-secundarias. ¿El objetivo es apoyar a 
los profesores? trabaje ofreciéndoles las varias herramientas 
para las hojas de operación (planning) y la puesta en práctica de la
enseñanza. El Web site también incluye muchos de información 
sobre las religiones que se pueden utilizar por los organizadores de 
la enseñanza, directores, padres y presentan cualquier comunidad 
interesada de parties.Religions y religiosa en orden alfabético 
según los principios del plan de estudios para la religión. 
Los diversos principios para las categorías de religiones y de 
movimientos religiosos se presentan en la sección titulada las 
religiones en una cáscara de nuez. Las secciones incluyen los 
fundamentos de planes de estudios, la puesta en práctica de la 
enseñanza, en la enseñanza de la religión, religiones en una 
cáscara de nuez, los materiales para enseñar, y preguntas con 
frecuencia hechas. Los cuerpos de la cooperación también se 
enumeran en una paginación separada.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pekka IIvonen
n:IIvonen;Pekka
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Anna-Elina Karjalainen
n:Karjalainen;Anna-Elina
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Måns Broo
n:Broo;Måns
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Irene Alvarez
n:Alvarez;Irene
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Kari Haikkola
n:Haikkola;Kari
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Duh Abdalla Ali
n:Ali;Duh Abdalla
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pentti Kaiponen
n:Kaiponen;Pentti
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Leila Taittonen
n:Taittonen;Leila
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Mariam Varjonen
n:Varjonen;Mariam
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Irmeli Lehtovaara
n:Lehtovaara;Irmeli
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Tapio Paljakka
n:Paljakka;Tapio
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Timo Kuivanen
n:Kuivanen;Timo
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Jukka Helenius
n:Helenius;Jukka
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Jukka Hongisto
n:Hongisto;Jukka
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/6E9ED8D5-972A-1AF8-4B98-A0A773BF7D38</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/6E9ED8D5-972A-1AF8-4B98-A0A773BF7D38</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Katja Pajuluoma
n:Pajuluoma;Katja 
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:36:11.55Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>guide</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>parent</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">16-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd-nc/1.0/</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>693</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>182</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1087</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1085</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>159</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>304</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>934</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>681</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi/perusopetus/uskonto_ja_elamankatsomustieto/uskontonetti</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/perusopetus/uskonto_ja_elamankatsomustieto/uskontonetti</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
