<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/78977</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>78977</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/eng/physics/electricity/electricity_4/home.htm</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/eng/physics/electricity/electricity_4/home.htm</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/eng/physics/electricity/electricity_4/home.htm</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Basic electrical circuits - resistance</string>
            <string language="fi">Basic electrical circuits - resistance</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Grundlegende elektrische Stromkreise - 
Widerstand</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Circuits électriques de base - résistance</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Circuitos elétricos básicos - resistência</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Circuiti elettrici di base - resistenza</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βασικά ηλεκτρικά κυκλώματα - αντίσταση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Circuitos eléctricos básicos - resistencia</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This English-language learning object is designed for the study and revision of the theory of electricity in basic physics teaching. The object is best-suited to online group work, but it can also be utilised in independent study. The website contains teacher’s instructions and a suggestion for the progress of study. Use of the website requires a Macromedia Shockwave add-on to be installed in the browser. It would be good for the pupils to be familiar beforehand with current and voltage. At school, pupils also ought to have already familiarised themselves with use of a circuit board and components. In the object, the pupil examines first the theory, performs tests related to resistance and to the resistance of a metal conductor, and finally tests his/her knowledge.</string>
            <string language="fi">Englanninkielinen oppimisaihio on tarkoitettu perusopetuksen fysiikan sähköopin opiskeluun ja kertaukseen. Aihio sopii parhaiten verkossa tapahtuvaan ryhmätyöskentelyyn, mutta sitä voidaan hyödyntää myös itsenäisessä opiskelussa. Sivusto sisältää opettajan ohjeet ja ehdotuksen opiskelun kuluksi. Sivuston käyttö edellyttää selaimelta Macromedia Shockwave -laajennusta. Oppilaiden olisi hyvä tuntea etukäteen virta ja jännite. Koulussa oppilaiden tulisi lisäksi olla jo tutustunut piirilevyn ja komponenttien käyttöön. Aihiossa oppilas tutustuu ensin teoriaan, tekee vastukseen ja metallijohtimen vastukseen liittyviä kokeita ja lopuksi testaa tietonsa.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="fi">alkeispiirit</string>
            <string language="en">alkeispiirit</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese englischsprachige erlernennachricht ist 
für die Studie und die Änderung der Theorie von Elektrizität im 
grundlegenden Physikunterricht bestimmt. Die Nachricht wird 
gut-entsprochen, um Arbeit online zu gruppieren, aber sie kann in der 
unabhängigen Studie auch verwendet werden. Die Web site 
enthält teacher?s Anweisungen und einen Vorschlag für den 
Fortschritt der Studie. Gebrauch von der Web site benötigt 
einen Macromedia Shockwavezusatz, in die Datenbanksuchroutine 
installiert zu werden. Es würde gut für die Pupillen sein, 
vorher mit Strom und Spannung vertraut zu sein. An der Schule 
sollen Pupillen mit auch Gebrauch von einer Leiterplatte und 
Bestandteilen bereits sich vertraut gemacht haben. In der 
Nachricht überprüft die Schüler zuerst die Theorie, führt die 
Tests durch, die auf Widerstand und auf dem Widerstand eines 
Metallleiters in Verbindung gestanden werden und prüft schließlich 
seins/ihr Wissen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cet objet d'étude de langue anglaise est conçu 
pour l'étude et la révision de la théorie de l'électricité dans 
l'enseignement de base de physique. L'objet meilleur-est convenu
pour grouper en ligne le travail, mais il peut également être 
utilisé dans l'étude indépendante. Le site Web contient des 
instructions de teacher?s et une suggestion pour le progrès de 
l'étude. L'utilisation du site Web exige d'une adjonction 
d'onde de choc de Macromedia d'être installée dans le navigateur. 
Il serait bon que les pupilles soient au courant à l'avance du 
courant et de la tension. À l'école, les pupilles doivent 
également s'être déjà familiarisées avec l'utilisation d'une 
carte et des composants. Dans l'objet, l'élève examine d'abord
la théorie, réalise des essais liés à la résistance et à la 
résistance d'un conducteur en métal, et teste finalement sa 
connaissance.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este objeto de aprendizagem english-language é 
projetado para o estudo e a revisão da teoria da eletricidade no 
ensino básico da física. O objeto melhor-é servido para 
agrupar em linha o trabalho, mas pode também ser utilizado no estudo 
independente. O Web site contem instruções dos teacher?s e uma
sugestão para o progresso do estudo. O uso do Web site requer 
um add-on do shockwave de Macromedia ser instalado no browser. 
Seria bom para as pupilas ser familiar de antemão com a 
corrente e a tensão. Na escola, as pupilas também ought já 
ter-se familiarizado com o uso de uma placa e de componentes de 
circuito. No objeto, o aluno examina primeiramente a teoria, 
executa os testes relacionados à resistência e à resistência de um
condutor do metal, e testa finalmente his/her conhecimento.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo oggetto imparante english-language è 
progettato per lo studio e la revisione della teoria di elettricità 
nell'insegnamento di base di fisica. L'oggetto migliore-è 
soddisfatto in linea per raggruppare il lavoro, ma può anche essere 
utilizzato nello studio indipendente. Il Web site contiene le 
istruzioni dei teacher?s e un suggerimento per il progresso dello 
studio. L'uso del Web site richiede un'adjunta di shockwave di 
Macromedia essere installato nel browser. Sarebbe in anticipo 
buono affinchè le pupille abbia familiarità con la corrente e la 
tensione. Alla scuola, le pupille anche devono già rendersi 
familiare ad uso di un bordo e dei componenti del circuito. 
Nell'oggetto, l'allievo esamina in primo luogo la teoria, 
effettua le prove relative a resistenza ed alla resistenza di un 
conduttore del metallo ed infine verifica la sua conoscenza.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το της αγγλικής γλώσσας αντικείμενο εκμάθησης 
σχεδιάζεται για τη μελέτη και την αναθεώρηση της θεωρίας της 
ηλεκτρικής ενέργειας στη βασική διδασκαλία φυσικής. Το 
αντικείμενο είναι καλύτερος-ταιριαγμένο στη σε απευθείας σύνδεση
εργασία ομάδας, αλλά μπορεί επίσης να χρησιμοποιηθεί στην 
ανεξάρτητη μελέτη. Ο ιστοχώρος περιέχει teacher?s τις 
οδηγίες και μια πρόταση για την πρόοδο της μελέτης. Η χρήση
του ιστοχώρου απαιτεί shockwave Macromedia πρόσθετο για να 
εγκατασταθεί στον ξεφυλλιστή. Θα ήταν καλό για τους μαθητές
για να εξοικειωθεί εκ των προτέρων με το ρεύμα και την τάση. 
Στο σχολείο, οι μαθητές οφείλουν επίσης να έχουν 
εξοικειωθεί ήδη με τη χρήση ενός πίνακα κυκλωμάτων και των 
συστατικών. Στο αντικείμενο, ο μαθητής εξετάζει πρώτα τη 
θεωρία, εκτελεί τις δοκιμές σχετικές με την αντίσταση και με την 
αντίσταση ενός αγωγού μετάλλων, και εξετάζει τελικά τη γνώση 
του/της.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este objeto que aprende de lengua inglesa se 
diseña para el estudio y la revisión de la teoría de la 
electricidad en la enseñanza básica de la física. El objeto 
mejor-se satisface en línea para agrupar el trabajo, pero puede 
también ser utilizado en estudio independiente. El Web site 
contiene instrucciones de los teacher?s y una sugerencia para el 
progreso del estudio. El uso del Web site requiere una 
agregación de la onda de choque de Macromedia ser instalado en el 
browser. Sería bueno que las pupilas sean familiar de antemano 
con la corriente y el voltaje. En la escuela, las pupilas 
también ought haberse familiarizado ya con uso de una tarjeta y de 
los componentes de circuito. En el objeto, la pupila examina 
primero la teoría, realiza las pruebas relacionadas con la 
resistencia y con la resistencia de un conductor del metal, y 
finalmente prueba su conocimiento.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">alkeispiirit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">alkeispiirit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">alkeispiirit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">alkeispiirit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">alkeispiirit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">alkeispiirit</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Oppomedia Oy
n:Oppomedia Oy
org:Oppomedia Oy
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/A624FF51-F3ED-5143-C8EB-7D41F816ECFF</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/A624FF51-F3ED-5143-C8EB-7D41F816ECFF</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pertti Siekkinen
n:Siekkinen;Pertti 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:36:24.19Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>simulation</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>project</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">13-15</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Creative commons Nimeä-epäkaupallinen-Ei muutettuja teoksia 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>411</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>978</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/eng/physics/electricity/electricity_4/home.htm</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/eng/physics/electricity/electricity_4/home.htm</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
