<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/79752</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>79752</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/kello</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/kello</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/kello</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Speaking clock</string>
            <string language="fi">Puhuva kello</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sprechender Taktgeber</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Horloge parlante</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Pulso de disparo falador</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Orologio parlante</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μιλώντας ρολόι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Reloj de discurso</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A game-like multimedia object for studying times. By clicking the Play button, the pupil hears a fragment of speech containing the time. The pupil should identify it from the rest of the speech and click first the hour and then the minute hand on the dial. When the pupil hits the right places, the clock switches to showing that time. At the same time, the pupil hears a spoken response. In the case of a wrong answer, the pupil is urged to continue trying and, in addition, s/he hears the time once again. The object covers a variety of different expressions of time. The program is a downloadable application.</string>
            <string language="fi">Pelimäinen multimedia-aihio kellonaikojen opiskeluun. Napauttamalla Play-nappulaa oppilas kuulee katkelman puhetta, joka sisältää kellonajan. Oppilaan tulee tunnistaa se muun puheen joukosta ja napauttaa kellotaulusta ensin tunti- ja sitten minuuttiviisarin kohtaa. Kun oppilas osuu oikeisiin kohtiin, kello siirtyy osoittamaan tuota aikaa. Samalla oppilas kuulee puhutun palautteen. Väärän vastauksen kohdalla oppilas saa kehotuksen jatkaa yrittämistä ja lisäksi hän kuulee ajan vielä uudelleen. Aihio kattaa monipuolisesti eri ajanilmaisut. Ohjelma on ladattava sovellus.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="fi">kellonajat</string>
            <string language="en">kellonajat</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">A Spiel-wie Multimedianachricht für das Studieren
von von Zeiten. Indem er die Spieltaste anklickt, hört die 
Schüler ein Fragment der Rede, die Zeit zu enthalten. Die 
Pupille sollte sie vom Rest der Rede kennzeichnen und die Stunde und 
dann die minuziöse Hand auf dem Vorwahlknopf zuerst klicken. 
Wenn die Pupille die rechten Plätze schlägt, schaltet der 
Taktgeber zum Zeigen dieses mal. Gleichzeitig hört die Schüler
eine gesprochene Antwort. Im Fall von einer falschen Antwort, 
wird die Pupille gedrängt, zu versuchen fortzufahren und zusätzlich 
hört s/he die Zeit noch einmal. Die Nachricht umfaßt eine 
Vielzahl der unterschiedlichen Ausdrücke der Zeit. Das Programm
ist eine downloadableanwendung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">A jeu-comme l'objet de multimédia pour étudier 
des périodes. En cliquant le bouton de jeu, l'élève 
entend un fragment de la parole contenir le temps. La pupille 
devrait l'identifier du reste du discours et cliquer d'abord 
l'heure et puis la main minutieuse sur le cadran. Quand la 
pupille frappe les bons endroits, l'horloge commute à montrer cette 
fois. En même temps, l'élève entend une réponse parlée. 
Dans le cas d'une réponse fausse, la pupille est invitée à 
continuer d'essayer et, en outre, s/he entend le temps de nouveau. 
L'objet couvre une variété de différentes expressions de 
temps. Le programme est une application downloadable.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A jogo-como o objeto dos multimedia para estudar 
épocas. Estalando a tecla do jogo, o aluno ouve um fragmento do
discurso conter o tempo. A pupila deve identificá-lo do 
descanso do discurso e estalar primeiramente a hora e então a mão 
minuciosa no seletor. Quando a pupila bate os lugares direitos, 
o pulso de disparo comuta a mostrar essa vez. Ao mesmo tempo, o 
aluno ouve uma resposta falada. No exemplo de uma resposta 
errada, a pupila é incitada continuar tentando e, além, s/he ouve o 
tempo uma vez outra vez. O objeto cobre uma variedade de 
expressões diferentes do tempo. O programa é uma aplicação 
downloadable.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">A gioco-come l'oggetto di multimedia per studiare 
i periodi. Scattando il tasto del gioco, l'allievo sente un 
frammento di discorso contenere il tempo. La pupilla dovrebbe 
identificarla dal resto del discorso e scattare in primo luogo l'ora 
ed allora la mano minuscola sulla manopola. Quando la pupilla 
colpisce i giusti posti, l'orologio passa a mostrare quel volta. 
Allo stesso tempo, l'allievo sente una risposta parlata. 
Nel caso di una risposta errata, la pupilla è invitata a 
continuare a provare e, in più, s/he sente ancora una volta il tempo.
L'oggetto riguarda una varietà di espressioni differenti di 
tempo. Il programma è un'applicazione downloadable.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα game-like πολυμέσα αντιτίθενται για τη μελέτη των
χρόνων. Με τον κρότο του κουμπιού παιχνιδιού, ο μαθητής 
ακούει ένα τεμάχιο της ομιλίας το χρόνο. Ο μαθητής πρέπει
να το προσδιορίσει από το υπόλοιπο της ομιλίας και να χτυπήσει 
πρώτα την ώρα και έπειτα το μικρό χέρι στον πίνακα. Όταν 
ο μαθητής χτυπά τις σωστές θέσεις, το ρολόι μεταπηδά να δείξει 
εκείνο τον χρόνο. Συγχρόνως, ο μαθητής ακούει μια 
προφορική απάντηση. Στην περίπτωση μιας λανθασμένης 
απάντησης, ο μαθητής ωθείται για να συνεχίσει και, επιπλέον, 
s/he ακούει το χρόνο άλλη μια φορά. Το αντικείμενο 
καλύπτει ποικίλες διαφορετικές εκφράσεις του χρόνου. Το 
πρόγραμμα είναι μια τηλεκατεγραφόμενη εφαρμογή.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">A juego-como el objeto de las multimedias para 
estudiar épocas. Haciendo clic el botón del juego, la pupila 
oye un fragmento del discurso el contener del tiempo. La pupila 
debe identificarlo del resto del discurso y hacer clic primero la hora
y entonces la mano minuciosa en el dial. Cuando la pupila golpea
los lugares derechos, el reloj cambia a mostrar ese vez. En el 
mismo tiempo, la pupila oye una respuesta hablada. En el caso de
una respuesta incorrecta, la pupila se impulsa continuar intentando y,
además, s/he oye el tiempo de nuevo. El objeto cubre una 
variedad de diversas expresiones del tiempo. El programa es una 
aplicación downloadable.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">kellonajat</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">kellonajat</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">kellonajat</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">kellonajat</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">kellonajat</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">kellonajat</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Lingonet OY
n:Lingonet OY
org:Lingonet OY
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/B2922ABF-2FD0-5079-D1A8-1A9C7D0FCB8E</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/B2922ABF-2FD0-5079-D1A8-1A9C7D0FCB8E</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Annika Ranta
n:Ranta;Annika 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:50:25.97Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">11-13</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Creative commons Nimeä-epäkaupallinen-Ei muutettuja teoksia 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>1313</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>461</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/kello</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/kello</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
