<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103321</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103321</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770210040</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Making the Mississippi Over Again: The Development of River Control in Mississippi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Den Mississippi Überschuß wieder bilden: 
Die Entwicklung der Fluss-Steuerung in Mississippi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Faisant l'excédent du Mississippi encore : 
Le développement de la commande de fleuve au Mississippi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fazendo o excesso de Mississippi outra vez: 
O desenvolvimento do controle do rio em Mississippi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Facendo l'eccedenza del Mississippi ancora: 
Lo sviluppo di controllo del fiume nel Mississippi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κάνοντας το Μισισιπή πέρα από πάλι: Η ανάπτυξη
του ελέγχου ποταμών στο Μισισιπή</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Haciendo el excedente de Mississippi otra vez: 
El desarrollo del control del río en Mississippi</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This website is part of the Mississippi History Now web newspaper. The feature story discusses engineering of river control in the Mississippi. Topics discussed in the story include the need for river control, efforts to control the river, the 1927 flood and impacts on the environment. The story includes suggested readings and a lesson plan associated with the story.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Web site ist ein Teil der Mississippi 
Geschichte jetzt Web-Zeitung. Die Merkmal Geschichte behandelt 
Technik der Flußsteuerung im Mississippi. Die Themen, die in 
der Geschichte behandelt werden, schließen die Notwendigkeit an der 
Flußsteuerung, die Bemühungen, den Fluß zu steuern, die 1927 Flut 
und die Auswirkungen auf die Umgebung ein. Die Geschichte 
schließt vorgeschlagene Messwerte und einen Lektionplan, der mit der 
Geschichte verbunden ist ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site Web fait partie du journal de Web 
d'histoire du Mississippi maintenant. L'histoire de dispositif 
discute l'ingénierie de la commande de fleuve au Mississippi. 
Les sujets discutés dans l'histoire incluent le besoin de la 
commande de fleuve, des efforts de contrôler le fleuve, les 1927 
inondation et des impacts sur l'environnement. L'histoire inclut
des lectures suggérées et un plan de leçon lié à l'histoire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Web site é parte do jornal do Web do history
de Mississippi agora. A história da característica discute a 
engenharia do controle do rio no Mississippi. Os tópicos 
discutidos na história incluem a necessidade para o controle do rio, 
esforços controlar o rio, os 1927 inundação e impactos no ambiente.
A história inclui leituras sugeridas e uma planta da lição 
associada com a história.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Web site ora fa parte del giornale di Web 
di storia del Mississippi. La storia della caratteristica 
discute l'ingegneria del controllo del fiume nel Mississippi. I 
soggetti discussi nella storia includono la necessità per controllo 
del fiume, gli sforzi di gestire il fiume, i 1927 inondazione e gli 
effetti sull'ambiente. La storia include le letture suggerite e 
un programma di lezione connesso con la storia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος είναι μέρος της εφημερίδας Ιστού 
ιστορίας του Μισισιπή τώρα. Η ιστορία χαρακτηριστικών 
γνωρισμάτων συζητά την εφαρμοσμένη μηχανική του ελέγχου ποταμών 
στο Μισισιπή. Τα θέματα που συζητούνται στην ιστορία 
περιλαμβάνουν την ανάγκη για τον έλεγχο ποταμών, προσπάθειες να 
ελεγχθεί ο ποταμός, η πλημμύρα του 1927 και οι επιδράσεις στο 
περιβάλλον. Η ιστορία περιλαμβάνει τις προτεινόμενες 
αναγνώσεις και ένα σχέδιο μαθήματος που συνδέεται με την 
ιστορία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este Web site ahora es parte del periódico del 
Web de la historia de Mississippi. La historia de la 
característica discute la ingeniería del control del río en el 
Mississippi. Los asuntos discutidos en la historia incluyen la 
necesidad del control del río, esfuerzos de controlar el río, los 
1927 inundación y los impactos en el ambiente. La historia 
incluye lecturas sugeridas y un plan de la lección asociado a la 
historia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:GREG O'BRIEN
FN:GREG O'BRIEN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MISSISSIPPI HISTORICAL SOCIETY
FN:MISSISSIPPI HISTORICAL SOCIETY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770210040</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103321</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/making-the-mississippi-over-again</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
