<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105796</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105796</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201385</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Earth System Science in a Nutshell</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Masse System Wissenschaft in einer Nußschale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science de système de la terre en un mot</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência do sistema da terra em um nutshell</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza del sistema della terra in un nutshell</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη γήινων συστημάτων εν συντομία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia del sistema de la tierra en una cáscara 
de nuez</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Starting Point module describes what Earth System Science is and why it is useful to employ the Earth System Science perspective in teaching the geosciences. There is information about the different spheres in the system and how they interact. The module also provides links to relevant learning resources and example classes that employ the ESS approach.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Ausgangspunktmodul beschreibt, was Masse 
System Wissenschaft ist und warum es nützlich ist, die Masse System 
Wissenschaft Perspektive einzusetzen, wenn man die geosciences 
unterrichtet. Es gibt Informationen über die unterschiedlichen 
Bereiche im System und wie sie zusammenwirken. Das Modul stellt 
auch Links zu den relevanten erlernenbetriebsmitteln und zu den 
Beispielkategorien zur Verfügung, die die ESS Annäherung einsetzen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce module de point de départ décrit ce qu'est la
Science de système de la terre et pourquoi il est utile d'utiliser la
perspective de la Science de système de la terre en enseignant les 
geosciences. Il y a des informations sur les différentes 
sphères dans le système et comment ils agissent l'un sur l'autre. 
Le module fournit également des liens aux ressources et aux 
classes d'étude appropriées d'exemple qui utilisent l'approche 
d'ESS.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este módulo do ponto começar descreve o que a 
ciência do sistema da terra é e porque é útil empregar o 
perspective da ciência do sistema da terra em ensinar os geosciences.
Há uma informação sobre as esferas diferentes no sistema e 
como interagem. O módulo fornece também as ligações aos 
recursos e às classes de aprendizagem relevantes do exemplo que 
empregam a aproximação de ESS.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo modulo del punto di partenza descrive che 
cosa la scienza del sistema della terra è e perchè è utile 
impiegare la prospettiva di scienza del sistema della terra 
nell'istruzione dei geosciences. Ci sono le informazioni sulle 
sfere differenti nel sistema e come si interagiscono. Il modulo 
egualmente fornisce i collegamenti alle risorse ed ai codici categoria
imparanti relativi di esempio che impiegano il metodo di ESS.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η ενότητα αφετηρίας περιγράφει ποια επιστήμη 
γήινων συστημάτων είναι και γιατί είναι χρήσιμο να υιοθετηθεί η
προοπτική επιστήμης γήινων συστημάτων στη διδασκαλία των 
geosciences. Υπάρχουν πληροφορίες για τις διαφορετικές 
σφαίρες στο σύστημα και πώς αλληλεπιδρούν. Η ενότητα 
παρέχει επίσης τις συνδέσεις με τα σχετικές στοιχεία 
συμπεριφοράς εκμάθησης και τις κλάσεις παραδείγματος που 
υιοθετούν την προσέγγιση ESS.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este módulo del punto de partida describe cuáles
es la ciencia del sistema de la tierra y porqué es útil emplear la 
perspectiva de la ciencia del sistema de la tierra en la enseñanza de
los geosciences. Hay información sobre las diversas esferas en 
el sistema y cómo obran recíprocamente. El módulo también 
proporciona a conexiones a los recursos y a las clases relevantes del 
ejemplo que aprenden que emplean el acercamiento de ESS.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MARTIN RUZEK
FN:MARTIN RUZEK
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201385</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105796</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/earth-system-science-in-a-nutshell</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
