<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107182</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107182</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087366</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Air Waves "are in the Public Domain": Public Television Advocacy in the 1950s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Radiowellen "sind im public domain": 
Allgemeine Fernsehen-Befürwortung in den fünfziger Jahren</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les vagues d'air "sont dans le public domain" : 
Recommandation publique de télévision dans les années 50</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As ondas de ar "estão no public domain": 
Advocacy público da televisão nos 1950s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le onde di aria "sono nel public domain": 
Avvocatura pubblica della televisione negli anni 50</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα κύματα αέρα "είναι στο δημόσιο τομέα": 
Δημόσια τηλεοπτική υπεράσπιση στη δεκαετία του '50</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las ondas de aire "están en el public domain": 
Defensa pública de la televisión en los años 50</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Although educational radio stations flourished in the early 1920s--more than 200 existed prior to the introduction of network radio in 1926--most faltered shortly thereafter. One reason was the alignment of the Federal Radio Commission (FRC), created by legislation declaring that the airwaves belonged to the public, with commercial interests. When the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) replaced the FRC in 1934, educational, religious, and labor groups promoted an amendment requiring the allocation of one-fourth of all broadcast licenses to nonprofit organizations. The amendment failed to pass, and by 1937, only 38 educational radio stations remained in operation. In 1948, as sales of televisions skyrocketed, Freida B. Hennock, the first female FCC commissioner, began a campaign to assign channel frequencies for nonprofit, educational use. Advocates backing Hennock documented the high number of acts or threats of violence shown to children every week on commercial television broadcasts. Consequently, when the FCC in 1952 added UHF (ultra high frequency) channels to the existing VHF (very high frequency) channels, they reserved 10 percent for use by nonprofit educational organizations. In the following testimony to a 1955 Congressional subcommittee, Hennock advocated oversight of commercial television by governmental and civic bodies and championed educational television. The testimony from the general manager of a new Pittsburgh educational station, William Wood, follows. Wood emphasized the lack of violence in his 'poverty stricken' station_s programming and included excerpts from fan mail praising an acclaimed children_s show,  The Children's Corner , a program co-produced by Fred Rogers, who later created,  Mr. Rogers' Neighborhood . Until 1967, however, when the Federal government established the Corporation for Public Broadcasting to appropriate funds for public television, non-commercial stations struggled to survive.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Obgleich pädagogisch, blühten Radiostationen in 
den frühen zwanziger Jahren -- mehr als 200 existiert vor der 
Einleitung des Netzradios 1926 -- kurz danach geschwankt. Ein 
Grund war die Ausrichtung der Bundesradiokommission (FRC), erstellt 
durch die Gesetzgebung, die erklärt, daß die Airwaves der 
Öffentlichkeit gehörten, mit Handelsinteressen. Als die 
Bundeskommunikationen Kommission (FCC) das FRC 1934 ersetzte, 
förderten pädagogische, fromme und Arbeitsgruppen eine Änderung, 
welche die Belegung von ein viertel aller Sendung Lizenzen zu den 
gemeinnützigen Organisationen benötigt. Die Änderung konnte 
und bis zum 1937 überschreiten nicht, nur 38 pädagogische 
Radiostationen in Kraft blieben. 1948 während Verkäufe der 
Fernsehen emporschnellten, fing Freida B. Hennock, der erste Frau FCC 
Beauftragte, eine Kampagne an, um Führung Frequenzen für 
gemeinnützigen, pädagogischen Gebrauch zuzuweisen. Die 
Fürsprecher, die Hennock unterstützen, dokumentierten die hohe Zahl 
Taten, oder die Drohungen der Gewalttätigkeit gezeigt den Kindern, 
die jede Woche auf kommerziellem Fernsehen überträgt. 
Infolgedessen als das FCC in 1952 UHF (ultra Hochfrequenz) 
Führungen den vorhandenen VHF (sehr Hochfrequenz) Führungen 
hinzufügte, hoben sie 10 Prozent für Gebrauch durch gemeinnützige 
pädagogische Organisationen auf. Im folgenden Zeugnis zu einer 
Kongreßunterausschuß 1955, befürwortete Hennock Aufsicht des 
kommerziellen Fernsehens durch die Regierungs- und bürgerlichen 
Körper und verfocht pädagogisches Fernsehen. Das Zeugnis vom 
Generaldirektor einer neuen Pittsburgh pädagogischen Station, William
Holz, folgt. Holz hob den Mangel an Gewalttätigkeit in seinen '
Armut getroffenen ' station_s hervor, die programmieren und 
eingeschlossene Excerpts vom Fanpostpreisen mit Beifall begrüßte 
children_s stellen, die Ecke der Kinder, ein Programm dar, das von 
Fred Rogers Co-produziert wird, der später erstellte, Herr Rogers' 
Neighborhood. Bis 1967 jedoch als die Bundesregierung die 
Korporation für die Öffentlichkeit herstellte, die überträgt, um 
Kapital für allgemeines Fernsehen zu verwenden, kämpften nicht 
gewerbliche Stationen, um zu überleben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bien qu'éducatif les stations par radio se sont 
épanouies au début des années 20 -- plus de 200 existés avant 
l'introduction de la radio de réseau en 1926 -- les plus hésités 
sous peu ensuite. Une raison était le cadrage de la Commission 
par radio fédérale (FRC), créé par la législation déclarant que 
les ondes hertziennes ont appartenu au public, avec des intérêts 
commerciaux. Quand la Commission fédérale de transmissions 
(FCC) a substitué le FRC en 1934, les groupes éducatifs, religieux, 
et de travail ont favorisé un amendement exigeant l'allocation d'un 
quart de tous les permis d'émission aux organisations à but non 
lucratif. L'amendement n'a pas passé, et d'ici 1937, seulement 
38 stations par radio éducatives sont demeurées en fonction. 
En 1948, pendant que les ventes des télévisions montaient en 
flèche, Freida B. Hennock, le premier commissaire de FCC de femelle, 
a commencé une campagne pour assigner des fréquences de canal pour 
l'usage sans but lucratif et éducatif. Les avocats soutenant 
Hennock ont documenté le nombre élevé d'actes ou des menaces de 
violence montrées aux enfants que chaque semaine pendant la 
télévision commerciale annonce. En conséquence, quand la FCC 
dans 1952 a ajouté les canaux (ultra à haute fréquence) À 
FRÉQUENCE ULTRA-HAUTE aux canaux existants de VHF (très à haute 
fréquence), ils ont réservé 10 pour cent à l'usage des organismes 
éducatifs sans but lucratif. Dans le témoignage suivant à un 
sous-comité 1955 congressionnel, Hennock a préconisé l'inadvertance
de la télévision commerciale par les organismes gouvernementaux et 
civiques et a soutenu la télévision éducative. Le témoignage
du directeur général d'une nouvelle station éducative de 
Pittsburgh, bois de William, suit. Le bois a souligné le manque
de violence dans ses station_s frappés 'par pauvreté 'programmant et
les extraits inclus de l'éloge de courrier de ventilateur les 
children_s acclamés montrent, le coin des enfants, un programme 
Co-produit par Fred Rogers, qui plus tard a créé, Neighborhood de M.
Rogers'. Jusqu'en 1967, cependant, quand le gouvernement 
fédéral a établi la société pour le public annonçant pour 
s'approprier des fonds pour la télévision publique, les stations 
non-commerciales ont lutté pour survivre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Embora educacional as estações de rádio 
floresceram nos 1920s adiantados -- mais de 200 existidos antes da 
introdução do rádio da rede em 1926 -- faltered logo depois disso. 
Uma razão era o alinhamento do commission de rádio federal 
(FRC), criado pela legislação que declara que os airwaves 
pertenceram ao público, com os interesses comerciais. Quando o 
commission federal das comunicações (FCC) substituiu o FRC em 1934, 
os grupos educacionais, religiosos, e labor promoveram uma emenda que 
requer o alocamento de um quarto de todas as licenças da transmissão
às organizações nonprofit. A emenda não passou, e por 1937, 
only 38 estações de rádio educacionais remanesceram na operação. 
Em 1948, enquanto as vendas das televisões skyrocketed, Freida 
B. Hennock, primeiro comissário do FCC da fêmea, começou uma 
campanha a atribuir freqüências da canaleta para o uso nonprofit, 
educacional. Os advogados que suportam Hennock documentaram o 
número elevado dos atos ou as ameaças da violência mostradas às 
crianças que cada semana na televisão comercial transmite. 
Conseqüentemente, quando o FCC em 1952 adicionou as canaletas 
(ultra de alta freqüência) DE FREQUÊNCIA ULTRAELEVADA às canaletas
existentes do VHF (muito de alta freqüência), reservaram 10 por 
cento para o uso por organizações educacionais nonprofit. No 
seguinte testimony a uma subcomissão 1955 congressional, Hennock 
advogou o oversight da televisão comercial por corpos governamentais 
e civic e championed a televisão educacional. O testimony do 
gerente geral de uma estação educacional nova de Pittsburgh, madeira
de William, segue. A madeira emfatizou a falta da violência em 
seus station_s golpeados ' pobreza ' que programam e os excerpts 
incluídos de elogiar do correio de ventilador children_s aclamados 
mostram, o canto das crianças, um programa co-produzido por Fred 
Rogers, que criou mais tarde, Vizinhança do Sr. Rogers'. Até 
1967, entretanto, quando o governo federal estabeleceu o corporation 
para o público que transmite para apropriar fundos para a televisão 
pública, as estações non-commercial esforçaram-se para sobreviver.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Anche se educativo le stazioni radiofoniche sono 
fiorito nell'inizio degli anni 20 -- più di 200 esistiti prima 
dell'introduzione della radio della rete in 1926 -- esitato presto da 
allora in poi. Un motivo era l'allineamento della Commissione 
radiofonica federale (FRC), creato da legislazione che dichiara che i 
airwaves hanno appartenuto al pubblico, con gli interessi commerciali.
Quando la Commissione federale di comunicazioni (FCC) ha 
sostituito il FRC in 1934, i gruppi educativi, religiosi e di lavoro
hanno promosso una correzione che richiede la ripartizione di 
one-quarto di tutte le autorizzazioni di radiodiffusione alle 
organizzazioni senza scopo di lucro. La correzione non è 
riuscito a passare ed entro 1937, solo 38 stazioni radiofoniche 
educative sono rimasto in funzione. In 1948, mentre le vendite 
delle televisioni skyrocketed, Freida B. Hennock, il primo commissario
del FCC della femmina, ha cominciato una campagna per assegnare le 
frequenze della scanalatura per uso senza scopo di lucro e educativo. 
I fautori che sostengono Hennock hanno documentato l'alto numero
di atti o minacce della violenza indicate ai bambini ch'ogni settimana
sulla televisione commerciale trasmette per radio. Di 
conseguenza, quando il FCC in 1952 ha aggiunto le scanalature (ultra 
ad alta frequenza) A FREQUENZA ULTRAELEVATA alle scanalature attuali 
di VHF (molto ad alta frequenza), hanno riservato 10 per cento ad uso 
delle organizzazioni educative senza scopo di lucro. Nella 
seguente testimonianza ad un sottocomitato congressuale 1955, Hennock 
ha sostenuto la svista della televisione commerciale dagli organismi 
di governo e civici ed ha sostenuto la televisione educativa. La
testimonianza dal direttore generale di nuova stazione educativa de 
Pittsburgh, legno del William, segue. Il legno ha dato risalto 
alla mancanza di violenza nei suoi station_s impressionanti 'povertà 
'che si programmano ed i brani inclusi dall'elogio della posta di 
ventilatore children_s applauditi mostrano, il angolo dei bambini, un 
programma co-prodotto da Fred Rogers, che più successivamente ha 
creato, Neighborhood del sig. Rogers. Fino al 1967, tuttavia, 
quando il governo federale ha stabilito la società per pubblico che 
trasmette per radio per appropriare i fondi monetari per la 
televisione pubblica, le stazioni non commerciali hanno lottato per 
sopravvivere.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αν και εκπαιδευτικό ραδιοσταθμοί που ακμάζουν στις 
αρχές της δεκαετίας του '20 -- περισσότερο από 200 υπήρξε πριν
από την εισαγωγή του ραδιοφώνου δικτύων το 1926 -- που 
υποχωρείται σύντομα έκτοτε. Ένας λόγος ήταν η 
ευθυγράμμιση της ομοσπονδιακής ραδιο Επιτροπής (frc), που 
δημιουργήθηκε από τη νομοθεσία δηλώνοντας ότι τα airwaves 
άνηκαν στο κοινό, με τα εμπορικά ενδιαφέροντα. Όταν η 
ομοσπονδιακή Επιτροπή ανακοινώσεων (FCC) αντικατέστησε frc 
το 1934, οι εκπαιδευτικές, θρησκευτικές, και ομάδες εργασίας 
προώθησαν μια τροποποίηση που απαιτεί την κατανομή της ένας 
τέταρτο όλων των αδειών ραδιοφωνικής μετάδοσης στις μη 
κερδοσκοπικές οργανώσεις. Η τροποποίηση απέτυχε να περάσει,
και μέχρι το 1937, μόνο 38 εκπαιδευτικό ραδιοσταθμοί 
παρέμειναν σε λειτουργία. Το 1948, καθώς οι πωλήσεις των 
τηλεοράσεων ανέβασαν στα ύψη, Freida Β. Hennock, ο πρώτος 
θηλυκός Επίτροπος της FCC, άρχισε μια εκστρατεία για να 
αναθέτει τις συχνότητες καναλιών για τη μη κερδοσκοπική, 
εκπαιδευτική χρήση. Υποστηρίζει ότι η υποστήριξη Hennock
τεκμηρίωσε τον υψηλό αριθμό πράξεων ή απειλών της βίας που 
εμφανίστηκαν στα παιδιά κάθε εβδομάδα στις εμπορικές τηλεοπτικές
ραδιοφωνικές μεταδόσεις. Συνεπώς, όταν πρόσθεσε η FCC το
1952 τα UHF (εξαιρετικά υψηλή συχνότητα) κανάλια στα 
υπάρχοντα κανάλια VHF (πολύ υψηλή συχνότητα), διατήρησαν 10 
τοις εκατό προς χρήση από τις μη κερδοσκοπικές εκπαιδευτικές 
οργανώσεις. Στην ακόλουθη κατάθεση σε μια του Κογκρέσου 
υποεπιτροπή του 1955, Hennock υποστήριξε την παράλειψη της 
εμπορικής τηλεόρασης από τους κυβερνητικούς και πολιτικούς 
οργανισμούς και υπερασπίστηκε την εκπαιδευτική τηλεόραση. Η 
κατάθεση από το γενικό διευθυντή ενός νέου εκπαιδευτικού 
σταθμού του Πίτσμπουργκ, William Wood, ακολουθεί. Το 
ξύλο υπογράμμισε την έλλειψη βίας στον κτυπημένο "προγραμματισμό
station_s" ένδειάς του και περιέλαβε τα αποσπάσματα από το 
ταχυδρομείο ανεμιστήρων εγκωμιάζοντας επευφημημένη children_s 
εμφανίζει, η γωνία των παιδιών, ένα πρόγραμμα που παρήχθη από 
κοινού από το Fred Rogers, ο οποίος δημιούργησε αργότερα, 
γειτονιά του κ. Rogers'. Έως το 1967, εντούτοις, όταν 
καθιέρωσε η ομοσπονδιακή κυβέρνηση την εταιρία για τη δημόσια 
ραδιοφωνική αναμετάδοση στα κατάλληλα κεφάλαια για τη δημόσια 
τηλεόραση, οι μη εμπορικοί σταθμοί αγωνίστηκαν να επιζήσουν.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Aunque es educativo las estaciones de radio 
prosperaron en los años 20 tempranos -- más de 200 existidos antes 
de la introducción de la radio de la red en 1926 -- vacilados pronto 
después de eso. Una razón era la alineación de la Comisión 
de radio federal (FRC), creada por la legislación que declaraba que 
los airwaves pertenecieron al público, con intereses comerciales. 
Cuando la Comisión federal de las comunicaciones (FCC) 
substituyó el FRC en 1934, los grupos educativos, religiosos, y de 
trabajo promovieron una enmienda que requería la asignación de un 
cuarto de todas las licencias de la difusión a las organizaciones no 
lucrativas. La enmienda no pudo pasar, y antes de 1937, sólo 
seguía habiendo 38 estaciones de radio educativas en la operación. 
En 1948, como se elevaron súbitamente las ventas de 
televisiones, Freida B. Hennock, la primera comisión de la FCC de la 
hembra, comenzó una campaña para asignar las frecuencias del canal 
para el uso no lucrativo, educativo. Los abogados que movían 
hacia atrás Hennock documentaron el alto número de actos o las 
amenazas de la violencia mostradas a los niños que cada semana en la 
televisión comercial difunde. Por lo tanto, cuando la FCC en 
1952 agregó los canales (ultra de alta frecuencia) DE FRECUENCIA 
ULTRAELEVADA a los canales existentes del VHF (muy de alta 
frecuencia), reservaron 10 por ciento para el uso por organizaciones 
educativas no lucrativas. En el testimonio siguiente a un 
subcomité del congreso 1955, Hennock abogó descuido de la 
televisión comercial por los cuerpos gubernamentales y cívicos y 
defendió la televisión educativa. El testimonio del director 
general de una nueva estación educativa de Pittsburgh, madera de 
Guillermo, sigue. La madera acentuó la carencia de la violencia
en sus station_s pulso ' pobreza ' que programaban y los extractos 
incluidos del elogio del correo de ventilador los children_s aclamados
muestran, la esquina de los niños, un programa co-producido por Fred 
Rogers, que creó más adelante, Neighborhood de Sr. Rogers. 
Hasta 1967, sin embargo, cuando el gobierno federal estableció 
la corporación para el público que difundía para apropiarse de los 
fondos para la televisión pública, las estaciones no comerciales 
lucharon para sobrevivir.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087366</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107182</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/air-waves-are-in-the-public-domain-public-television-advocacy-in-the-1950s</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
