<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104783</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104783</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087023</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The power of pictures.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Energie der Abbildungen.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La puissance des images.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A potência dos retratos.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'potenza delle immagini.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η δύναμη των εικόνων.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La potencia de cuadros.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A week after his April, 1917, declaration of war on Germany, President Woodrow Wilson established the Committee on Public Information (CPI), a propaganda agency that used sophisticated mass-marketing techniques to sell the war and the sacrifices it would entail to a wary American public. The CPI distributed 75 million pamphlets, placed magazine ads, produced films, and sent out 75,000 speakers to give short, pro-war speeches. As part of this war mobilization effort, the government also relied on the power of effective, if often fantastic, imagery to shape public opinion. Even though most illustrators and editorial cartoonists eagerly produced pro-war work, the government instituted a Bureau of Cartoons, which issued a weekly  Bulletin for Cartoonists . The bulletin included suggestions about appropriately patriotic themes and, in some cases, instructions for specific pictures. This dramatically illustrated poster from 1918 urged Americans to purchase Liberty Bonds</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Woche nach seinem April, 1917, stellte Erklärung des
Krieges auf Deutschland, Präsident Woodrow Wilson den Ausschuß für 
allgemeine Informationen (CPI), eine Propagandaagentur her, die hoch 
entwickelte Masse-Marketing Techniken verwendete, um den Krieg und die
Opfer zu verkaufen, die, sie zu einer vorsichtigen amerikanischen 
Öffentlichkeit zur Folge haben würde. Das CPI verteilte 75 
Million Flugschriften, plazierte Zeitschrift ADS, produzierte Filme, 
und ausgesendet 75.000 Lautsprechern, um kurz zu geben, Pro-Krieg 
Reden. Als Teil dieser Kriegmobilisierungbemühung beruhte die 
Regierung auch auf der Energie von wirkungsvolle, wenn häufig 
fantastische, Bilder, öffentliche Meinung zu formen. Obwohl die
meisten Illustratoren und die redaktionellen Karikaturenzeichner 
begeistert Pro-Krieg Arbeit produzierten, leitete die Regierung ein 
Büro der Karikaturen ein, die eine wöchentliche Nachricht für 
Karikaturenzeichner herausgaben. Die Nachricht schloß 
Vorschläge über passend patriotische Themen und in einigen Fällen 
Anweisungen für spezifische Abbildungen ein. Dieses drastisch 
erläuterte Plakat von 1918 drängte Amerikaner, Freiheit-Bindungen zu
kaufen</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une semaine après son avril, 1917, la déclaration de la 
guerre sur l'Allemagne, le Président Woodrow Wilson a établi le 
comité de l'information publique (CPI), une agence de propagande qui 
a employé des techniques sophistiquées de masse-marketing pour 
vendre la guerre et les sacrifices qu'elle nécessiterait à un public
américain circonspect. La CPI a distribué 75 millions de 
brochures, a placé le magasin ADS, films produits, et envoyé 75.000 
haut-parleurs pour donner sous peu, des discours de pro-guerre. 
En tant qu'élément de cet effort de mobilisation de guerre, le
gouvernement s'est également fondé sur la puissance de, langage 
figuré pertinent, si souvent fantastique de former l'opinion 
publique. Quoique la plupart des illustrateurs et réalisateurs 
de dessins animés éditoriaux aient ardemment produit le travail de 
pro-guerre, le gouvernement a institué un bureau des dessins animés,
qui ont émis un bulletin hebdomadaire pour des réalisateurs de 
dessins animés. Le bulletin a inclus des suggestions au sujet 
des thèmes convenablement patriotiques et, dans certains cas, des 
instructions pour les images spécifiques. Cette affiche 
excessivement illustrée de 1918 a invité des Américains à acheter 
des Obligations de liberté</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uma semana após seu abril, 1917, a declaração da guerra
em Germany, presidente Woodrow Wilson estabeleceu o comitê na 
informação pública (CPI), uma agência do propaganda que usasse 
técnicas sofisticadas do massa-mass-marketing vender a guerra e os 
sacrifícios que envolveria a um público americano wary. O CPI 
distribuiu 75 milhão panfletos, colocou o compartimento ads, 
películas produzidas, e emitido para fora 75.000 altofalantes ao 
short da elasticidade, discursos da pro-guerra. Como a parte 
deste esforço do mobilization da guerra, o governo confiou também na
potência de, imagery eficaz, se frequentemente fantástico dar forma 
à opinião pública. Mesmo que a maioria illustrators e de 
cartoonists editorial produzissem ansiosamente o trabalho da 
pro-guerra, o governo instituiu um departamento dos cartoons, que 
emitiram um boletim semanal para cartoonists. O boletim incluiu 
sugestões sobre temas apropriadamente patriotic e, em algumas caixas,
instruções para retratos específicos. Este poster dramàtica 
ilustrado de 1918 incitou americanos comprar ligações da liberdade</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Una settimana dopo suo aprile, del 1917, la dichiarazione 
della guerra con Germania, il presidente Woodrow Wilson ha istituito 
il comitato delle informazioni pubbliche (caratteri per pollice), 
un'agenzia di propaganda che ha usato le tecniche specializzate di 
massa-introduzione sul mercato per vendere la guerra ed i sacrifici 
che richiederebbero ad un pubblico americano prudente. I 
caratteri per pollice hanno distribuito 75 milione opuscoli, hanno 
disposto lo scomparto il ads, pellicole prodotte e spedito 75.000 
altoparlanti per dare bruscamente, discorsi di pro-guerra. Come 
componente di questo sforzo di mobilizzazione di guerra, il governo 
egualmente ha contato sull'potenza di, linguaggio figurato efficace, 
se spesso fantastico modellare l'opinione pubblica. Anche se la 
maggior parte di illustrators e dei cartoonists editoriali hanno 
prodotto ardentemente il lavoro di pro-guerra, il governo ha istituito
un ufficio dei fumetti, che numero un bollettino settimanale per i 
cartoonists. Il bollettino ha incluso i suggerimenti circa i 
temi giustamente patriotic e, in alcuni casi, le istruzioni per le 
immagini specifiche. Questo manifesto drammaticamente 
illustrato da 1918 ha invitato gli Americani a comprare i legami di 
libertà</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια εβδομάδα μετά από τον τον Απρίλιό του, του 
1917, δήλωση του πολέμου στη Γερμανία, Πρόεδρος Woodrow 
Wilson καθιέρωσε την Επιτροπή των δημόσιων πληροφοριών (ΔΤΚ), 
μια αντιπροσωπεία προπαγάνδας που χρησιμοποίησε τις περίπλοκες 
τεχνικές μάζα-μάρκετινγκ για να πωλήσει τον πόλεμο και τις 
θυσίες που θα συνεπαγόταν σε ένα προσεκτικό αμερικανικό κοινό. 
Ο ΔΤΚ διένειμε 75 εκατομμύριο τεύχη, τοποθέτησε τις 
αγγελίες περιοδικών, παραχθείσες ταινίες, και σταλμένος 75.000
ομιλητές που δίνουν απότομα, υπέρ-πολεμικές ομιλίες. Ως 
τμήμα αυτής της προσπάθειας πολεμικής κινητοποίησης, η κυβέρνηση
στηρίχθηκε επίσης στη δύναμη αποτελεσματικά, εάν συχνά 
φανταστικά, καλολογικά στοιχεία κατά την κοινή γνώμη μορφής. 
Ακόμα κι αν οι περισσότεροι εικονογράφοι και εκδοτική 
παραχθείσα υπέρ-πολεμική εργασία σκιτσογράφων ανυπόμονα, η 
κυβέρνηση καθιέρωσαν ένα γραφείο των κινούμενων σχεδίων, το 
οποίο εξέδωσε ένα εβδομαδιαίο δελτίο για τους σκιτσογράφους. 
Το δελτίο περιέλαβε τις προτάσεις για τα κατάλληλα 
πατριωτικά θέματα και, σε μερικές περιπτώσεις, τις οδηγίες για 
τις συγκεκριμένες εικόνες. Αυτή η εντυπωσιακά 
διευκρινισμένη αφίσα από το 1918 ώθησε Αμερικανούς για να 
αγοράσει τους δεσμούς ελευθερίας</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una semana después de su abril de 1917, el declaración 
de la guerra en Alemania, presidente Woodrow Wilson estableció a 
comité sobre la información pública (CPI), una agencia de la 
propaganda que utilizó técnicas sofisticadas de la 
masa-comercializacio'n para vender la guerra y los sacrificios que 
exigiría a un público americano cuidadoso. El CPI distribuyó 
75 millones de folletos, colocó el compartimiento ads, películas 
producidas, y enviado 75.000 altavoces para dar brevemente, los 
discursos de la favorable-guerra. Como parte de este esfuerzo de
la movilización de la guerra, el gobierno también confió en la 
potencia de, las imágenes eficaces, si a menudo fantásticas de 
formar la opinión pública. Aunque la mayoría de los 
ilustradores y de los dibujantes editoriales produjeron con 
impaciencia el trabajo de la favorable-guerra, el gobierno instituyó 
una oficina de las historietas, que publicaron un boletín semanal 
para los dibujantes. El boletín incluyó sugerencias sobre 
temas apropiadamente patrióticos y, en algunas cajas, las 
instrucciones para los cuadros específicos. Este cartel 
dramáticamente ilustrado a partir del 1918 impulsó a americanos 
comprar enlaces de la libertad</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087023</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104783</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-power-of-pictures</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
