<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105634</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105634</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205982</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">USA Mathematics and Statisticsematical Talent Search</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">USA Mathematik und Statisticsematical 
Talent-Suche</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques des Etats-Unis et recherche de 
talent de Statisticsematical</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática dos EUA e busca do talent de 
Statisticsematical</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica degli S.U.A. e ricerca di talento di 
Statisticsematical</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΑ μαθηματικά και αναζήτηση ταλέντου 
Statisticsematical</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas de los E.E.U.U. y búsqueda del 
talento de Statisticsematical</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a mathematics competition open to all U.S. middle and high school students. Problems are published on the website four times a year one month before solutions are due. Problems range in difficulty from being within the reach of most high school students to challenging the best students in the nation. Students may use any materials -- books, calculators, computers -- but all work must be their own. This year's special topic is expected value.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist eine Mathematikkonkurrenz, die zu allen 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN mittlere und High School Kursteilnehmern geöffnet 
ist. Probleme werden auf der Web site vier Mal pro Jahr 
veröffentlicht, ein Monat bevor Lösungen passend sind. 
Probleme erstrecken sich in der Schwierigkeit vom Sein innerhalb
der Reichweite der meisten High School Kursteilnehmer zu schwierigem 
die besten Kursteilnehmer in der Nation. Kursteilnehmer können 
alle mögliche Materialien benutzen -- Bücher, Rechner, Computer -- 
aber alle Arbeit muß ihr Selbst sein. Diesjähriges spezielles 
Thema ist erwarteter Wert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est un concours de mathématiques général de 
tous les étudiants de lycée moyen et des ETATS-UNIS. Des 
problèmes sont édités sur le site Web quatre fois par année 
pendant un mois avant que les solutions sont dues. Les 
problèmes s'étendent en difficulté d'être dans l'extension de la 
plupart des étudiants de lycée à provocant les meilleurs étudiants
dans la nation. Les étudiants peuvent utiliser tous les 
matériaux -- livres, calculatrices, ordinateurs -- mais tout le 
travail doit être leur propre. Le sujet spécial de cette 
année est valeur prévue.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é uma competição da matemática aberta a todos 
os estudantes da High School média e de ESTADOS UNIDOS. Os 
problemas estão publicados no Web site quatro vezes um o ano um mês 
antes que as soluções estejam devidas. Os problemas variam na 
dificuldade de ser dentro do alcance de a maioria de estudantes da 
High School a challenging os mais melhores estudantes na nação. 
Os estudantes podem usar todos os materiais -- livros, 
calculadoras, computadores -- mas todo o trabalho deve ser seu 
próprio. O tópico especial deste ano é valor previsto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è una gara di matematica aperta a tutti a tutti 
gli allievi della High School centrale e degli STATI UNITI. I 
problemi sono pubblicati sul Web site quattro volte l'all'anno un mese
prima che le soluzioni siano dovute. I problemi variano in 
difficoltà da essere all'interno dell'estensione della maggior parte 
dei allievi della High School a challenging gli allievi migliori nella
nazione. Gli allievi possono usare tutti i materiali -- libri, 
calcolatori, calcolatori -- ma tutto il lavoro deve essere il loro 
proprio. Il soggetto speciale relativo a quest'anno è valore 
previsto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι ένας ανταγωνισμός μαθηματικών ανοικτός σε 
όλους τους σπουδαστές ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΩΝ μεσών και γυμνασίου. Τα 
προβλήματα δημοσιεύονται στον ιστοχώρο τέσσερις φορές ετησίως 
έναν μήνα προτού οι λύσεις να οφειλόμενες. Τα προβλήματα 
κυμαίνονται στη δυσκολία από την ύπαρξη μέσα στην προσιτότητα 
των περισσότερων σπουδαστών γυμνασίου στην πρόκληση των καλύτερων
σπουδαστών στο έθνος. Οι σπουδαστές μπορούν να 
χρησιμοποιήσουν οποιαδήποτε υλικά -- βιβλία, υπολογιστές, 
υπολογιστές -- αλλά όλη η εργασία πρέπει να είναι τους δικοί. 
Το φετινό ειδικό θέμα είναι αναμενόμενη αξία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es una competición de las matemáticas abierta a 
todos los estudiantes de la High School media y secundaria de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS. Los problemas se publican en el Web site cuatro veces al
año un mes antes de que las soluciones son debidas. Los 
problemas se extienden en dificultad de ser dentro del alcance de la 
mayoría de los estudiantes de la High School secundaria a desafiador 
los mejores estudiantes de la nación. Los estudiantes pueden 
utilizar cualquier material -- libros, calculadoras, ordenadores -- 
pero todo el trabajo debe ser su el propio. El asunto especial 
relativo a este año es valor previsto.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205982</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105634</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/usa-mathematics-and-statisticsematical-talent-search</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
