<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105836</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105836</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087435</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Better Late Than Never?: Rickover Clears Spain of the Maine Explosion</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Verbessern Sie Spät Als Nie?: Rickover 
macht Spanien von der Maine Explosion frei</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mieux vaut tard que jamais ? : Rickover 
efface l'Espagne de l'explosion du Maine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Melhore Tarde Do que Nunca?: Rickover 
cancela Spain da explosão de Maine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Migliori In ritardo Che Mai?: Rickover 
annulla la Spagna dell'esplosione della Maine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Καλύτερα αργά από ποτέ;: Το Rickover 
καθαρίζει την Ισπανία της έκρηξης του Maine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mejore Tarde Que Nunca?: Rickover borra 
España de la explosión de Maine</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">On February 15, 1898, an explosion ripped through the American battleship  Maine , anchored in Havana Harbor, sinking the ship and killing 260 sailors. Americans responded with outrage, assuming that Spain, which controlled Cuba as a colony, had sunk the ship. Many newspapers presented Spanish culpability as fact, with headlines such as "The War Ship  Maine  was Split in Two by an Enemy's Secret Infernal Machine." Two months later, the slogan "Remember the  Maine " carried the U.S. into war with Spain. In the midst of the hysteria, few Americans paid much attention to the report issued two weeks before the U.S. entry into the war by a Court of Inquiry appointed by President McKinley. The report stated that the committee could not definitively assign blame to Spain for the sinking of the  Maine . In 1911, the  Maine  was raised in Havana harbor and a new board of inquiry again avoided a definite conclusion. In 1976, however, in the aftermath of the Vietnam War, Admiral Hyman Rickover conducted a new investigation. Rickover, something of a maverick in the Navy, came to the conclusion that the explosion was caused by spontaneous combustion in the ship's coal bins, a problem that afflicted other ships of the period.   But controversy over the sinking of the  Maine  continues; some recent authors have, for example, rejected Rickover's account and argued that rogue, anti-American Spanish officers used primitive mines to destroy the ship.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Auf Februar 15, 1898, einer Explosion zerrissen 
durch das amerikanische Linienschiff Maine, befestigt im Havana Hafen,
das Schiff sinkend und beenden 260 Seeleute. Amerikaner 
reagierten mit dem Verbrechen und nahmen dieses Spanien an, dem 
kontrolliertes Kuba als Kolonie, das Schiff gesunken hatte. 
Viele Zeitungen stellten spanische Strafbarkeit als Tatsache, 
mit Schlagzeilen wie "dem Krieg-Schiff Maine wurden aufgespaltet in 
zwei durch die geheime Infernal Maschine eines Feindes." dar 
Zwei Monate später, erinnern sich der Slogan ", daß das Maine"
die VEREINIGTEN STAATEN in Krieg mit Spanien trug. In der Mitte 
der Hysterie, lenkten wenige Amerikaner viel Aufmerksamkeit auf 
den Report herausgaben zwei Wochen bevor der VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Eintrag in den Krieg durch eine Untersuchungskommission ernannt vom 
Präsidenten McKinley. Der Report gab an, daß der Ausschuß 
nicht Schuld nach Spanien für das Sinken des Maines endgültig 
zuweisen könnte. 1911 wurde das Maine in Havana Hafen angehoben
und ein neues Brett der Anfrage vermied wieder eine definitive 
Zusammenfassung. 1976 jedoch in der Nachmahd des Vietnam 
Krieges, Admiral Hyman Rickover leitete eine neue Untersuchung. 
Rickover, etwas eines Außenseiters in der Marine, kam zur 
Zusammenfassung, daß die Explosion durch spontane Verbrennung in den 
Kohlesortierfächern des Schiffs verursacht wurde, ein Problem, das 
andere Schiffe der Periode betrübte. Aber 
Kontroverseüberschuß, den das Sinken des Maines fortsetzt; 
einige neue Autoren haben, z.B. Konto Rickovers zurückgewiesen 
und diesen Gauner argumentiert, benutzten Anti-Amerikanische 
spanische Offiziere ursprüngliche Gruben, um das Schiff zu 
zerstören.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">15 février 1898, une explosion déchirée par le
cuirassé américain Maine, ancré dans le port de La Havane, 
descendant le bateau et détruisant 260 marins. Les Américains 
ont répondu avec l'outrage, assumant la cette Espagne, que le Cuba 
commandé en tant que colonie, était descendu le bateau. 
Beaucoup de journaux ont présenté la culpabilité espagnole 
comme fait, avec des titres tels que "le bateau de guerre Maine ont 
été dédoublés dans deux par la machine infernale secrète d'un 
ennemi." Pendant deux mois plus tard, le slogan "se rappellent 
que le Maine" a porté les ETATS-UNIS dans la guerre avec l'Espagne. 
Au milieu de l'hystérie, peu d'Américains ont prêté beaucoup
d'attention à l'état ont émis deux semaines avant que l'entrée des
ETATS-UNIS dans la guerre par une cour d'enquête désignée par le 
Président McKinley. L'état a déclaré que le comité ne 
pourrait pas définitivement assigner le blâme en Espagne pour la 
descente du Maine. En 1911, le Maine a été augmenté dans le 
port de La Havane et une nouvelle commission d'enquête a encore 
évité une conclusion définie. En 1976, cependant, au 
lendemain de la guerre de Vietnam, amiral Hyman Rickover a conduit une
nouvelle recherche. Rickover, quelque chose d'un franc-tireur 
dans la marine, est arrivé à la conclusion que l'explosion a été 
provoquée par combustion spontanée dans les coffres du charbon du 
bateau, un problème qui a affligé d'autres bateaux de la période. 
Mais excédent de polémique que la descente du Maine continue ;
quelques auteurs récents ont, par exemple, rejeté le compte de
Rickover et discuté cet escroc, les officiers espagnols 
anti-Américains avaient l'habitude les mines primitives pour 
détruire le bateau.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fevereiro em 15, 1898, em uma explosão rasgada 
através do cruzador de batalha americano Maine, escorado no porto de 
Havana, afundando o navio e matando 260 sailors. Os americanos 
responderam com o ultraje, supondo esse Spain, que Cuba controlada 
como uma colônia, tinha afundado o navio. Muitos jornais 
apresentaram o culpability espanhol como o fato, com headlines tais 
como "o navio de guerra Maine foram rachados em dois pela máquina 
infernal secreta de um inimigo." Dois meses mais tarde, o slogan
"recorda que o Maine" carregou os ESTADOS UNIDOS na guerra com o 
Spain. No meio do hysteria, poucos americanos pagaram muita 
atenção ao relatório emitiram duas semanas antes que a entrada de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS na guerra por uma corte de inquérito apontada pelo 
presidente McKinley. O relatório indicou que o comitê não 
poderia definitively atribuir a culpa a Spain para se afundar do 
Maine. Em 1911, o Maine foi levantado no porto de Havana e uma 
placa de inquérito nova evitou outra vez uma conclusão definitiva. 
Em 1976, entretanto, no aftermath da guerra de Vietnam, 
almirante Hyman Rickover conduziu uma investigação nova. 
Rickover, algo de um maverick na marinha, veio à conclusão que
a explosão estêve causada pela combustão espontânea nos escaninhos
de carvão do navio, um problema que afflicted outros navios do 
período. Mas excesso que da controvérsia se afundar do Maine 
continua; alguns autores recentes têm, para o cliente de 
Rickover rejeitado do exemplo, e discutido esse rogue, os oficiais 
espanhóis anti-Americanos usaram minas primitivas destruir o navio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il 15 febbraio 1898, un'esplosione strappata 
tramite il battleship americano Maine, ancorata nel porto de Avana, 
affondante la nave e mortale 260 marinai. Gli Americani hanno 
risposto con l'oltraggio, ammettente la quella Spagna, che la Cuba 
controllata come colonia, aveva affondato la nave. Molti 
giornali hanno presentato il culpability spagnolo come fatto, con i 
titoli quale "la nave di guerra Maine sono stati spaccati in due dalla
macchina infernal segreta del nemico." Due mesi più 
successivamente, lo slogan "si ricorda di che la Maine" ha trasportato
gli STATI UNITI nella guerra con la Spagna. In mezzo a il 
hysteria, pochi Americani ha prestato molta attenzione al rapporto ha 
pubblicato due settimane prima che l'entrata degli STATI UNITI nella 
guerra da una corte dell'inchiesta nominata dal presidente McKinley. 
Il rapporto ha dichiarato che il comitato non potrebbe 
definitivo assegnare la colpa in Spagna per l'abbassamento della 
Maine. In 1911, la Maine è stata alzata nel porto de Avana e un
nuovo bordo dell'inchiesta ha evitato ancora una conclusione 
definita. In 1976, tuttavia, nel guaime della guerra di Vietnam,
l'ammiraglio Hyman Rickover ha condotto una nuova ricerca. 
Rickover, qualcosa di un non conformista nel blu marino, è 
giunto alla conclusione che l'esplosione è stata causata da 
combustione spontanea negli scomparti del carbone della nave, un 
problema che ha afflitto altre navi del periodo. Ma eccedenza 
che di polemica l'abbassamento della Maine continua; alcuni 
autori recenti hanno, per esempio, rifiutato il cliente del Rickover e
discusso quel rogue, gli ufficiali spagnoli anti-Americani hanno usato
le miniere primitive per distruggere la nave.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στις 15 Φεβρουαρίου ..1898, μια έκρηξη έσχισε 
μέσω του αμερικανικού θωρηκτού Maine, που δέθηκε στο λιμάνι 
της Αβάνας, που βυθίζει το σκάφος και που σκοτώνει 260 
ναυτικούς. Αμερικανοί αποκρίθηκαν με την προσβολή, 
υποθέτοντας ότι η Ισπανία, που έλεγξε την Κούβα ως αποικία, 
είχε βυθίσει το σκάφος. Πολλές εφημερίδες παρουσίασαν την 
ισπανική ενοχή όπως το γεγονός, με τους τίτλους όπως "το 
πολεμικό σκάφος Maine χωρίστηκε σε δύο από τη μυστική 
σατανική μηχανή ενός εχθρού." Δύο μήνες αργότερα, το 
σύνθημα "θυμάται ότι το Maine" έφερε τις ΗΠΑ στον πόλεμο με 
την Ισπανία. Στη μέση της υστερίας, λίγοι Αμερικανοί 
έδωσαν πολλή προσοχή στην έκθεση που παρουσιάστηκε δύο 
εβδομάδες πριν από την ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ είσοδο μέσα σε τον πόλεμο από
ένα δικαστήριο της έρευνας που διορίστηκε από τον Πρόεδρο 
McKinley. Η έκθεση δήλωσε ότι η επιτροπή δεν θα μπορούσε
να αναθέσει οριστικά την επίπληξη στην Ισπανία για τη βύθιση του 
Maine. Το 1911, το Maine αυξήθηκε στο λιμάνι της 
Αβάνας και ένας νέος πίνακας της έρευνας απέφυγε πάλι ένα 
καθορισμένο συμπέρασμα. Το 1976, εντούτοις, στη συνέπεια 
του πολέμου του Βιετνάμ, ο ναύαρχος Hyman Rickover διεξήγαγε
μια νέα έρευνα. Το Rickover, κάτι μιας εκκεντρικής 
παρατήρησης στο ναυτικό, κατέληξε στο συμπέρασμα ότι η έκρηξη 
προκλήθηκε από την αυθόρμητη καύση στα δοχεία άνθρακα του 
σκάφους, ένα πρόβλημα που στενοχώρησε άλλα σκάφη της περιόδου. 
Αλλά η διαμάχη πέρα από τη βύθιση του Maine συνεχίζεται
μερικοί πρόσφατοι συντάκτες, παραδείγματος χάριν, έχουν 
απορρίψει τον απολογισμό Rickover και έχουν υποστηρίξει ότι ο 
απατεώνας, αντι-αμερικανικοί ισπανικοί ανώτεροι υπάλληλοι 
χρησιμοποίησε τα πρωτόγονα ορυχεία για να καταστρέψει το σκάφος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">15 de febrero de 1898, una explosión rasgada a
través del acorazado americano Maine, asegurado en el puerto de La 
Habana, hundiendo la nave y matando a 260 marineros. Los 
americanos respondieron con el ultraje, si se asume esa España, que 
Cuba controlada como colonia, había hundido la nave. Muchos 
periódicos presentaron culpabilidad española como hecho, con los 
títulos tales como "la nave de guerra Maine fueron partidos en dos 
por la máquina infernal secreta de un enemigo." Dos meses más 
adelante, el lema "recuerda que el Maine" llevó los ESTADOS UNIDOS en
guerra con España. En el medio de la histeria, pocos americanos
prestaron mucha atención al informe publicaron dos semanas antes de 
que la entrada de ESTADOS UNIDOS en la guerra por una corte de la 
pregunta designada por presidente McKinley. El informe indicó 
que el comité no podría asignar definitivo culpa a España para 
hundirse del Maine. En 1911, el Maine fue levantado en el puerto
de La Habana y una nueva tarjeta de la pregunta evitó otra vez una 
conclusión definida. En 1976, sin embargo, en las consecuencias
de la guerra de Vietnam, almirante Hyman Rickover condujo una nueva 
investigación. Rickover, algo de un rebelde en la Marina de guerra, 
vino a la conclusión que la explosión fue causada por la combustión
espontánea en los compartimientos del carbón de la nave, un problema
que afligió otras naves del período. Pero excedente de la 
controversia que el hundirse del Maine continúa; algunos 
autores recientes tienen, por ejemplo, rechazado la cuenta de Rickover
y discutido ese granuja, los oficiales españoles contra-Americanos
utilizaron minas primitivas para destruir la nave.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087435</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105836</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/better-late-than-never-rickover-clears-spain-of-the-maine-explosion</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
