<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105896</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105896</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205704</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Romantic Circles High School</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Romantische Kreis-High School</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Lycée de Cercles Romantiques</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">High School Dos Círculos Românticos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">High School Dei Cerchi Romantici</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ρομαντικό γυμνάσιο κύκλων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">High School Secundaria De los Círculos 
Románticos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a real-time multi-user environment that includes online classrooms designed and occupied by classes across the country, a library of Romantic electronic texts, a teachers' lounge, and shared spaces for special events and social interaction. The class is meeting inside Villa Diodati, the house that Lord Byron rented in the summer of 1816 and that served as the impetus for Mary Shelley's Frankenstein.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist eine Echtzeitgemeinschaftsumgebung, die die 
Onlineklassenzimmer enthält, die durch Kategorien über dem Land, 
einer Bibliothek der romantischen elektronischen Texte, einem 
Aufenthaltsraum der Lehrer und geteilten Platz für spezielle Fälle 
und Sozialinteraktion konzipiert sind und besetzt sind. Die 
Kategorie trifft innerhalb des Landhauses Diodati, das Haus, das Lord 
Byron am Sommer von 1816 mietete und das als der Antrieb für Mary 
Shelleys Frankenstein diente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est un environnement multi-utilisateur en temps 
réel qui inclut les salles de classe en ligne conçues et occupées 
par des classes à travers le pays, une bibliothèque des textes 
électroniques romantiques, un salon des professeurs, et les espaces 
partagés pour des événements spéciaux et l'interaction sociale. 
La classe se réunit à l'intérieur de la villa Diodati, la 
maison que seigneur Byron a louée en été de 1816 et qui a servi 
d'impulsion à Frankenstein de Mary Shelley.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é um ambiente multi-user real-time que inclua as 
salas de aula em linha projetadas e ocupadas por classes através do 
país, de uma biblioteca de textos eletrônicos românticos, de um 
lounge dos professores, e dos espaços compartilhados para eventos 
especiais e a interação social. A classe está encontrando-se 
com dentro do villa Diodati, a casa que o senhor Byron alugou no 
verão de 1816 e que serviu como o ímpeto para Frankenstein de Mary 
Shelley.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è un ambiente multiutente in tempo reale che 
include le aule in linea progettate ed occupate dai codici categoria 
attraverso il paese, una libreria dei testi elettronici romantici, un 
salotto degli insegnanti e gli spazi comuni per gli eventi speciali e 
l'interazione sociale. Il codice categoria sta venendo a 
contatto di all'interno della villa Diodati, la casa che il signore 
Byron ha affittato di estate di 1816 e che ha servito da slancio per 
Frankenstein della Mary Shelley.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι ένα σε πραγματικό χρόνο πολλών χρηστών 
περιβάλλον που περιλαμβάνει τις σε απευθείας σύνδεση τάξεις που 
σχεδιάζονται και που καταλαμβάνονται από τις κλάσεις σε ολόκληρη 
τη χώρα, μια βιβλιοθήκη των ρομαντικών ηλεκτρονικών κειμένων, 
ένα σαλόνι των δασκάλων, και τα κοινά διαστήματα για τα ειδικά 
γεγονότα και την κοινωνική αλληλεπίδραση. Η κλάση συναντά 
την εσωτερική βίλα Diodati, το σπίτι που ο Λόρδος Byron 
νοικίασε το καλοκαίρι 1816 και που εχρησίμευσε ως η ώθηση για 
Frankenstein Mary Shelley's.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es un ambiente multiusos en tiempo real que 
incluye las salas de clase en línea diseñadas y ocupadas por las 
clases a través del país, de una biblioteca de textos electrónicos 
románticos, de un salón de los profesores, y de los espacios 
compartidos para los acontecimientos especiales y la interacción 
social. La clase se está reuniendo dentro del chalet Diodati, 
la casa que señor Byron alquiló en el verano de 1816 y que sirvió 
como el ímpetu para Frankenstein de Maria Shelley.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205704</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105896</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/romantic-circles-high-school</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
