<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107881</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107881</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087195</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"We Just Stood Up for Our Own Self:" James Justen Recalls Growing Up Gay in the 1950s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"wir standen gerade oben für unseren eigenen 
Selbst:" James Justen ruft wieder auf, herauf Homosexuelles in 
den fünfziger Jahren zu wachsen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"nous nous sommes juste levés pour notre propre 
Art de l'auto-portrait :" James Justen se rappelle accroître vers le 
haut du gay dans les années 50</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"nós estivemos apenas acima para nosso próprio 
self:" James Justen recorda crescer acima do gay nos 1950s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"abbiamo corrisposto appena in su al nostro 
proprio auto:" James Justen ricorda crescere sul Gay 
negli anni 50</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Αντιπροσωπεύσαμε ακριβώς επάνω μόνο μας:" James Justen Recalls Growing Up ομοφυλόφιλος στη 
δεκαετία του '50</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"acabamos de estar parados para arriba para 
nuestro propio uno mismo:" James Justen recuerda el crecer 
encima de Gay en los años 50</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Jim Justen grew up gay in Kenosha, Wisconsin during the 1950's, a time when homosexuality was considered a criminal offense that was thought to sap the moral fiber of both the individual and the nation. Gays were subjected to the same hysteria and persecution engendered by anti-communism, and pressured to conform to mainstream cultural and gender norms. During high school, Justen hid his sexuality but ran with a rough gay crowd in his hometown of Kenosha, Wisconsin. He dealt with potential problems by learning the basics of boxing and ju jitsu and developing a tough street-fighting reputation. When he finally told his parents that he was gay at the age of 19, Justen was lucky enough to find his family accepting and supportive.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Jim Justen wuchs Homosexuelles in Kenosha, 
Wisconsin während der fünfziger Jahre, eine Zeit auf, als 
Homosexualität als eine kriminelle Handlung galt, die zum Saft die 
moralische Faser der Einzelperson und der Nation gedacht wurde. 
Homosexuelle wurden der gleichen Hysterie und Verfolgung 
unterworfen, die durch anti-Kommunismus erzeugt wurden und gedrueckt 
waren, um sich an kulturelle und Geschlechthauptströmungsnormen 
anzupassen. Während der High School versteckte Justen, seine 
Sexualität aber lief mit einer rauhen homosexuellen Masse in 
seiner Heimatstadt von Kenosha, Wisconsin. Er beschäftigte 
mögliche Probleme, indem er die Grundlagen von Verpacken und ju jitsu
erlernte und ein haltbares Straße-kämpfendes Renommee entwickelte. 
Als er seinen Eltern, daß erklärte schließlich er am Alter 
von 19 homosexuell war, war Justen genug glücklich, seine Familie zu 
finden anzunehmen und unterstützend.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jim Justen a grandi le gay dans Kenosha, le 
Wisconsin pendant les années 50, un moment où l'homosexualité a 
été considérée une offense criminelle qui a été pensée à la 
sève la fibre morale de l'individu et de la nation. Des 
homosexuels ont été soumis à la mêmes hystérie et persécution 
engendrées par l'anti-communisme, et pressurisées pour se conformer 
aux normes traditionnelles culturelles et de genre. Pendant le 
lycée, Justen a caché sa sexualité mais a fonctionné avec une 
foule gaie rugueuse à sa ville natale de Kenosha, le Wisconsin. 
Il a traité des problèmes potentiels en apprenant les 
fondations du jitsu de boxe et de ju et en développant une 
réputation decombat dure. Quand il a finalement dit à ses 
parents qu'il était gai à l'âge de 19, Justen était assez chanceux
pour trouver sa famille recevoir et de support.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jim Justen cresceu acima o gay em Kenosha, 
Wisconsin durante os 1950's, uma época em que o homosexuality fosse 
considerado uma ofensa criminal que fosse pensada ao sap a fibra moral
do indivíduo e da nação. Os gays foram sujeitados ao mesmos 
hysteria e persecution engendered pelo anti-anti-communism, e 
exercidos pressão sobre para conformar-se às normas mainstream 
cultural e do gender. Durante a High School, Justen escondeu seu
sexuality mas funcionou-o com uma multidão gay áspera em seu 
hometown de Kenosha, Wisconsin. Tratou dos problemas potenciais 
aprendendo os princípios do jitsu do boxing e do ju e desenvolvendo 
uma reputação rua-de combate resistente. Quando disse 
finalmente a seus pais que era gay na idade de 19, Justen era 
afortunado bastante encontrar sua família aceitar e de suporte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Jim Justen ha sviluppato in su il gay in 
Kenosha, Wisconsin durante gli anni 50, un periodo in cui 
l'omosessualità è stata considerata un'offesa criminale che si è 
pensata per fiaccare la fibra morale sia dell'individuo che 
della nazione. I gay sono stati sottoposti allo stessi 
hysteria e persecution generati da anti-comunismo e pressured per 
essere conformi alle norme tradizionali di genere e culturali. 
Durante la High School, Justen ha nascosto il suo sexuality ma 
ha funzionato con una folla di massima di gay a suo hometown 
di Kenosha, Wisconsin. Si è occupato dei problemi potenziali 
imparando i principi fondamentali del jitsu di ju e di boxing e 
sviluppando una reputazione dura di street-combattimento. Quando 
infine ha detto ai suoi genitori a che sia gay all'età di 
19, Justen era abbastanza fortunato scoprire che la sua famiglia 
accetta e di appoggio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Jim Justen μεγάλωσε τον ομοφυλόφιλο σε 
Kenosha, Wisconsin κατά τη διάρκεια της δεκαετίας του '50, 
ένας χρόνος όταν θεωρήθηκε η ομοφυλοφυλία ποινικό αδίκημα που 
θεωρήθηκε για να υποσκάψει την ηθική ίνα και του ατόμου και του 
έθνους. Οι ομοφυλόφιλοι υποβλήθηκαν στην ίδιες υστερία και 
τη δίωξη που προκλήθηκαν από τον αντι-κομμουνισμό, και που 
πιέστηκαν προσαρμόζομαι στην επικρατούσα τάση πολιτιστική και 
τους κανόνες γένους. Κατά τη διάρκεια του γυμνασίου, 
Justen έκρυψε τη σεξουαλικότητά του αλλά έτρεξε με ένα τραχύ
ομοφυλοφιλικό πλήθος στο hometown Kenosha του, Wisconsin. 
Εξέτασε τα πιθανά προβλήματα με την εκμάθηση των βασικών 
του εγκιβωτισμού και ju jitsu και της ανάπτυξης μιας σκληρής 
φήμης οδός-πάλης. Όταν είπε τελικά στους γονείς του ότι 
ήταν εύθυμος στην ηλικία 19, Justen ήταν αρκετά τυχερό να 
βρεί την οικογένειά του και ενθαρρυντικός.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Jim Justen creció para arriba el gay en 
Kenosha, Wisconsin durante los años 50, una época en que la 
homosexualidad era considerada una ofensa criminal que fue pensada a 
la savia la fibra moral del individuo y de la nación. Los 
gays fueron sujetados a la misma histeria y persecución 
engendradas por el contra-comunismo, y ejercidas presión sobre para 
conformarse con las normas culturales y del género de corriente. 
Durante High School secundaria, Justen ocultó su sexualidad 
pero se ejecutó con una muchedumbre gay áspera en su ciudad 
natal de Kenosha, Wisconsin. Él se ocupó de problemas 
potenciales aprendiendo los fundamentos del jitsu del boxeo y del ju y
desarrollando una reputación calle-que luchaba resistente. 
Cuando él finalmente dijo a sus padres que él fuera gay
en la edad de 19, Justen era bastante afortunado encontrar a su 
familia el validar y de apoyo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087195</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107881</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/we-just-stood-up-for-our-own-self-james-justen-recalls-growing-up-gay-in-the-1950s</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
