<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106302</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106302</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087350</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A Woman's Work: Mary Lease Celebrates Women Populists</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Arbeit Einer Frau: Mary Miete Feiert 
Frau-Populisten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Travail D'une Femme : Le Bail de Mary 
Célèbre des Populistes de Femmes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Trabalho De uma Mulher: O Aluguer De Mary 
Comemora Populists Das Mulheres</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lavoro Della Donna: Il Contratto d'affitto 
Della Mary Celebra I Populists Delle Donne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η εργασία μιας γυναίκας: Θ*Μαρυ Lease 
Celebrates Women Populists</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Trabajo De una Mujer: El Arriendo De Maria 
Celebra A Populists De las Mujeres</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Women are not often thought of in association with the Populists, but the best-known orator of the movement in the early 1890s was a woman, Mary Elizabeth Lease. Born in Pennsylvania in 1850 to Irish parents, Lease became a school teacher in Kansas in 1870. She and her husband, a pharmacist, spent ten years trying to make a living farming, but finally gave up in 1883 and settled in Wichita. Lease entered political life as a speaker for the Irish National League, and later emerged as a leader of both the Knights of Labor and the Populists. Lease mesmerized audiences in Kansas, Missouri, the Far West, and the South with her powerful voice and charismatic speaking style. In this speech before the Women's Christian Temperance Union in 1890, Lease championed the power of women in late-19th century grassroots political movements.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Frauen sind nicht dachten häufig an in Verbindung
mit die Populisten, aber der bekannteste Redner der Bewegung im 
frühen 1890s war eine Frau, Mary Elizabeth Miete. Getragen in 
Pennsylvania 1850 zu den irischen Eltern, stand Miete einem 
Schulelehrer in Kansas 1870. Sie und ihr Ehemann, ein Apotheker,
ausgegeben 10 Jahre versuchend, ein lebendes Bewirtschaften zu bilden,
aber gaben schließlich oben 1883 und rechneten in Wichita ab. 
Miete erreichte politische Lebensdauer als Lautsprecher für die
irische nationale Liga, und später aufgetaucht als Führer der Ritter
der Arbeit und der Populisten. Miete hypnotisierte Publikum in 
Kansas, in Missouri, im weiten Westen und im Süden mit ihrer 
leistungsfähigen Stimme und charismatischen sprechenden Art. In
dieser Rede vor dem christlichen Anschluß Temperance der Frauen 1890,
verfocht Miete die Energie der Frauen in den politischen Bewegungen 
der des späten 19. jahrhunderts JahrhundertBasis.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les femmes ne sont pas ont souvent pensé à en 
association avec les populistes, mais l'orateur le plus connu du 
mouvement dans le 1890s tôt était une femme, bail de Mary 
Elizabeth. Soutenu en Pennsylvanie en 1850 aux parents 
irlandais, le bail est allé bien à un professeur d'école au Kansas 
en 1870. Elle et son mari, un pharmacien, dépensé dix ans 
essayant de faire un affermage vivant, mais finalement ont donné vers
le haut en 1883 et se sont établis à Wichita. Le bail a écrit
la vie politique comme haut-parleur pour la ligue nationale 
irlandaise, et plus tard émergé en tant qu'amorce des chevaliers du 
travail et des populistes. Le bail a hypnotisé des assistances 
au Kansas, au Missouri, à l'ouest lointain, et aux Sud avec 
sa voix puissante et modèle parlant charismatique. Dans ce 
discours devant l'union chrétienne de la Modération des femmes en 
1890, le bail a soutenu la puissance des femmes dans les mouvements 
politiques de fin du 19me bases de siècle.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As mulheres não são pensaram frequentemente na 
associação com os populists, mas o orator o mais best-known do 
movimento no 1890s adiantado era uma mulher, aluguer de Mary 
Elizabeth. Carregado em Pensilvânia em 1850 aos pais irish, o 
aluguer assentou bem em um professor da escola em Kansas em 1870. 
E seu marido, um pharmacist, gastado dez anos que tentam fazer 
cultivar vivo, mas deram finalmente acima em 1883 e estabeleciram-se 
em Wichita. O aluguer incorporou a vida política como um 
altofalante para a liga nacional irish, e emerso mais tarde como um 
líder  dos knights do trabalho e dos populists. O aluguer 
mesmerized audiências em Kansas, em Missouri, no oeste distante, e no
sul com seus voz poderosa e estilo falador charismatic. Neste 
discurso antes da união christian de Temperance das mulheres em 1890,
o aluguer championed a potência das mulheres em movimentos políticos
dos grassroots late-19th do século.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le donne non sono spesso hanno pensato in 
collaborazione con ai populists, ma il orator più noto del movimento 
nel 1890s iniziale era una donna, contratto d'affitto della Mary 
Elizabeth. Sopportato in Pensilvania in 1850 ai genitori 
irlandesi, il contratto d'affitto ha stato bene ad un insegnante della
scuola in Kansas in 1870. Lei ed il suo marito, un farmacista, 
speso dieci anni che provano a fare un'agricoltura vivente,
ma infine hanno dato in su in 1883 e si sono depositati a Wichita. 
Il contratto d'affitto ha fornito la vita politica come 
altoparlante per la lega nazionale irlandese e più successivamente è
emerso come capo sia dei cavalieri del Lavoro che dei 
populists. Il contratto d'affitto mesmerized i pubblici Kansas, 
nel Missouri, l'estremo ovest ed il sud con la suoi voce potente e 
stile parlante charismatic. In questo discorso prima dell'unione
cristiana di Temperance delle donne in 1890, il contratto d'affitto ha
sostenuto l'potenza delle donne nei movimenti politici dei fine del 
19esimo grassroots di secolo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι γυναίκες δεν θεωρούνται συχνά σε συνδυασμό με το 
Populists, αλλά ο πιό γνωστός ομιλητής της μετακίνησης στο 
πρόωρο 1890s ήταν γυναίκα, Mary Elizabeth Lease. 
Γεννημένος στην Πενσυλβανία το 1850 στους ιρλανδικούς 
γονείς, μίσθωση έγινε σχολικός δάσκαλος στο Κάνσας το 1870. 
Αυτή και ο σύζυγός της, ένας φαρμακοποιός, πέρασαν δέκα 
έτη προσπαθώντας να βγάλουν προς το ζειν καλλιεργώντας, αλλά 
τελικά σταμάτησαν το 1883 και εγκατέστησαν στο Wichita. 
Η μίσθωση εισήγαγε την πολιτική ζωή ως ομιλητή για την 
ιρλανδική εθνική ένωση, και προέκυψε αργότερα ως ηγέτης και των 
ιπποτών της εργασίας και του Populists. Η μίσθωση 
γοήτευσε τα ακροατήρια στο Κάνσας, το Μισσούρι, τη μακρινή δύση,
και το νότο με την ισχυρή φωνή και το χαρισματικό ύφος ομιλίας 
της. Σε αυτήν την ομιλία πριν από τη χριστιανική ένωση 
μετριοπάθειας των γυναικών το 1890, η μίσθωση υπερασπίστηκε τη 
δύναμη των γυναικών στις late-19th πολιτικές μετακινήσεις σε 
επίπεδο βάσης αιώνα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las mujeres no son pensaron a menudo en en la 
asociación con los populists, pero el orador más conocido del 
movimiento en el 1890s temprano era una mujer, arriendo de Maria 
Elizabeth. Llevado en Pennsylvania en 1850 a los padres 
irlandeses, el arriendo sintió bien a un profesor de la escuela en 
Kansas en 1870. Ella y su marido, farmacéutico, pasado diez 
años que intentaban hacer cultivar vivo, pero finalmente dieron para 
arriba en 1883 y colocaron en Wichita. El arriendo incorporó 
vida política como altavoz para la liga nacional irlandesa, y 
emergido más adelante como arranque de cinta de los caballeros del 
trabajo y de los populists. El arriendo mesmerized a audiencias 
en Kansas, Missouri, el oeste lejano, y el sur con su voz de gran 
alcance y estilo de discurso carismático. En este discurso 
antes de la unión cristiana de Temperance de las mujeres en 1890, el 
arriendo defendió la potencia de mujeres en movimientos políticos de
los pueblos de fines del siglo diecinueve del siglo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087350</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106302</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-womans-work-mary-lease-celebrates-women-populists</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
