<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102941</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102941</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087204</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"We Stand Defeated America": Sacco and Vanzetti in  U.S.A.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Wir Stehen Besiegtes Amerika": Sacco und 
Vanzetti in USA.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Nous Tenons l'Amérique Défaite" : Sacco 
et Vanzetti aux Etats-Unis.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Nós Estamos América Derrotada": Sacco e 
Vanzetti nos EUA.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Ci leviamo in piedi L'America Sconfitta": 
Sacco e Vanzetti negli S.U.A..</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Στεκόμαστε τη νικημένη Αμερική": Sacco και 
Vanzetti στις ΗΠΑ</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Estamos parada América Derrotada": Sacco y
Vanzetti en los E.E.U.U..</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The emotional and highly publicized case of Nicola Sacco and Bartolomeo Vanzetti became a touchstone and rallying cry for American radicals. The two Italian immigrants were accused in 1920 of murdering a paymaster in a holdup. Although the evidence against them was flimsy, they were readily convicted, in large part because they were immigrants and anarchists. Despite international protests, they were executed on August 23, 1927. Novelist John Dos Passos became deeply involved in the case after he visited Sacco and Vanzetti in Massachusetts prisons. The case and executions were commemorated in an outpouring of literary expression. Dos Passos returned to the subject of Sacco and Vanzetti in his epic three-volume work of fiction,  U.S.A.  In this excerpt, cops beat up the fictional character Mary French outside the Charlestown jail where Sacco and Vanzetti awaited their executions. "Newsreel LXVI" followed with a collage of contemporary headlines. Finally, "The Camera Eye (50)," a stream-of-consciousness montage, was Dos Passos's impassioned personal response.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der emotionale und in hohem Grade publizierte Kasten von 
Nicola Sacco und von Bartolomeo Vanzetti wurde ein Prüfstein und 
Sammelnschrei für amerikanische Radikale. Die zwei 
italienischen Immigranten wurden 1920 der Ermordung einer Zahlstelle 
in einem Holdup beschuldigt. Obgleich der Beweis gegen sie 
schwach war, wurden sie betriebsbereit, im großen Teil überführt, 
weil sie Immigranten und Anarchisten waren. Trotz der 
internationalen Proteste wurden sie an August 23, 1927 durchgeführt. 
Novelist-John DOS Passos wurde im Fall tief beteiligt, nachdem 
er Sacco und Vanzetti in den Massachusetts Gefängnissen besuchte. 
Der Fall und die Ausführungen wurden in einem Erguß des 
literarischen Ausdruckes gedacht. DOS Passos ging zum Thema von 
Sacco und von Vanzetti in seiner epischen Dreidatenträger Arbeit der 
Erfindung, USA zurück. In diesem Excerpt schlugen Spindeln 
herauf das fiktive Zeichen Mary, der außerhalb des Charlestown 
Gefängnisses französisch ist, in dem Sacco und Vanzetti ihre 
Ausführungen erwarteten. "Wochenschau LXVI" folgte mit einer 
Collage der zeitgenössischen Schlagzeilen. Schließlich "das 
Kamera-Auge (50)," ein Strom-von-Bewußtsein montage, war DOS Passoss 
aufgewühlte persönliche Antwort.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La caisse émotive et fortement annoncée de Nicola Sacco 
et de Bartolomeo Vanzetti est devenue une pierre de touche et cri de 
rassemblement pour les radicaux américains. Les deux immigrés 
italiens ont été accusés dans 1920 d'assassiner un caissier dans un
holdup. Bien que l'évidence contre eux ait été fragile, ils 
ont été aisément condamnés, dans la grande partie parce qu'ils 
étaient des immigrés et des anarchistes. En dépit des 
protestations internationales, on les a exécuté 23 août 1927. 
DOS Passos de John de romancier est devenu profondément 
impliqué dans le cas après qu'il ait visité Sacco et Vanzetti dans 
des prisons du Massachusetts. Le cas et les exécutions ont 
été commémorés dans un épanchement d'expression littéraire. 
DOS Passos est revenu sur le sujet de Sacco et de Vanzetti dans 
son travail épique de trois-volume de la fiction, Etats-Unis. 
Dans cet extrait, les cannettes de fil ont battu vers le haut du
caractère fictif Mary française en dehors de la prison de 
Charlestown où Sacco et Vanzetti ont attendu leurs exécutions. 
le "film d'actualités LXVI" a suivi avec un collage des titres 
contemporains. En conclusion, "l'oeil d'appareil-photo (50)," un
montage de jet-de-conscience, était réponse personnelle passionée 
pour de DOS Passos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A caixa emocional e altamente publicized de Nicola Sacco e
de Bartolomeo Vanzetti transformou-se um touchstone e grito rallying 
para radicais americanos. Os dois immigrants italianos foram 
acusados em 1920 de assassinar um paymaster em um holdup. Embora
a evidência de encontro a eles fosse frágil, convicted prontamente, 
na parte grande porque eram immigrants e anarquistas. Apesar dos
protestos internacionais, foram executados agosto em 23, 1927. O
Dos Passos de John do novelist tornou-se profundamente involvido no 
caso depois que visitou Sacco e Vanzetti em prisões de Massachusetts.
O caso e as execuções foram comemorados em um outpouring da 
expressão literária. O Dos Passos retornou ao assunto de Sacco
e de Vanzetti em seu trabalho epic do fiction, EUA do três-volume. 
Neste excerpt, as bobinas bateram acima do caráter fictional 
Mary francesa fora da cadeia de Charlestown onde Sacco e Vanzetti 
esperaram suas execuções. o "newsreel LXVI" seguiu com um 
collage de headlines contemporary. Finalmente, "o olho da 
câmera (50)," um montage do córrego-$$$-STREAM-OF-CONSCIOUSNESS, era
resposta pessoal impassioned do Dos Passos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La cassa impressionabile ed altamente divulg di Nicola 
Sacco e di Bartolomeo Vanzetti si è transformata in in un touchstone 
e radunandosi gridi per i radicali americani. I due 
immigranti italiani sono stati accusati in 1920 di assassinio del 
paymaster in un arresto. Anche se la prova contro di loro era 
fragile, sono stati condannati prontamente, nella grande parte perché
erano immigranti ed anarchici. Malgrado le proteste 
internazionali, sono stati eseguiti il 23 agosto 1927. Il DOS 
Passos del John del romanziere è stato profondamente implicato nel 
caso dopo che visitasse Sacco e Vanzetti nelle prigioni del 
Massachusetts. Il caso e le esecuzioni sono stati commemorati in
un outpouring dell'espressione letteraria. Il DOS Passos ha 
ritornato all'argomento di Sacco e Vanzetti nel suo lavoro epic di 
romanzo, S.U.A. del tre-volume. In questo brano, le spole hanno 
battuto sul carattere fictional Mary francese fuori della prigione di 
Charlestown in cui Sacco e Vanzetti hanno atteso le loro esecuzioni. 
"il cinegiornale LXVI" è seguito con un collage dei titoli 
contemporanei. Per concludere, "l'occhio della macchina 
fotografica (50)," un montage di flusso-de-coscienza, era risposta 
personale impassioned del DOS Passos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η συναισθηματική και ιδιαίτερα κοινοποιημένη περίπτωση
Nicola Sacco και του Bartolomeo Vanzetti έγινε μια 
κραυγή λύδιων λίθων και συνάθροισης για τους αμερικανικούς 
ριζοσπάστες. Οι δύο ιταλικοί μετανάστες κατηγορήθηκαν το 
1920 για τη δολοφονία ενός ταμία σε μια παύση. Αν και τα 
στοιχεία ενάντια σε τους ήταν ψιλά, καταδικάστηκαν εύκολα, στο 
μεγάλο μέρος επειδή ήταν μετανάστες και αναρχικοί. Παρά 
τις διεθνείς διαμαρτυρίες, εκτελέσθηκαν στις 23 Αυγούστου, 
1927, ο μυθιστοριογράφος John Dos Passos αναμίχθηκε 
βαθειά στην περίπτωση αφότου επισκέφτηκε Sacco και Vanzetti 
στις φυλακές της Μασαχουσέτης. Η περίπτωση και οι εκτελέσεις
τιμήθηκαν την μνήμη σε ένα ξέσπασμα της λογοτεχνικής έκφρασης. 
Το DOS Passos επέστρεψε στο θέμα Sacco και 
Vanzetti στην επική εργασία τρεις-έντασης του ήχου 
μυθιστοριογραφίας του, ΗΠΑ Σε αυτό το απόσπασμα, οι σπόλες 
κτύπησαν επάνω τον πλασματικό χαρακτήρα Mary French έξω 
από τη φυλακή Charlestown όπου Sacco και Vanzetti 
ανέμειναν τις εκτελέσεις τους. "Newsreel LXVI" 
ακολούθησε με ένα κολάζ των σύγχρονων τίτλων. Τέλος, "το 
μάτι φωτογραφικών μηχανών (50)," ένα montage 
ρεύμα-$$$-ΣΥΝΕΊΔΗΣΗΣ, ήταν εμπαθής προσωπική απάντηση DOS 
Passos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La caja emocional y altamente publicada de Nicola Sacco y 
de Bartolomeo Vanzetti se convirtió en una piedra de toque y grito de la 
reunión para los radicales americanos. Acusaron a los dos 
inmigrantes italianos en 1920 de asesinar un paymaster en una 
interrupción. Aunque la evidencia contra ellos era débil, los 
condenaron fácilmente, en parte grande porque eran inmigrantes y 
anarquistas. A pesar de protestas internacionales, los 
ejecutaron 23 de agosto de 1927. El DOS Passos de Juan del 
novelista llegó a estar profundamente implicado en el caso después 
de que él visitara Sacco y Vanzetti en las prisiones de 
Massachusetts. El caso y las ejecuciones fueron conmemorados en 
un flujo de expresión literaria. El DOS Passos volvió al 
tema de Sacco y de Vanzetti en su trabajo épico de la ficción, los 
E.E.U.U. del tres-volumen. En este extracto, los polis batieron 
encima del carácter ficticio Maria francesa fuera de la cárcel de 
Charlestown en donde Sacco y Vanzetti aguardaron sus ejecuciones. 
la "película de actualidades LXVI" siguió con un collage de 
títulos contemporáneos. Finalmente, "el ojo de la cámara 
fotográfica (50)," un montage del secuencia-de-sentido, era respuesta
personal apasionada del DOS Passos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087204</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102941</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/we-stand-defeated-america-sacco-and-vanzetti-in-u-s-a</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
