<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105206</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105206</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200851</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Cephalopod Lesson Plans</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kopffüßer-Lektion-Pläne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Plans de Leçon de Céphalopode</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Plantas Da Lição Do Cefalópode</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Programmi Di Lezione Del Cefalopodo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σχέδια μαθήματος κεφαλόποδων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Planes De la Lección Del Cefalópodo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This collection of lesson plans, created by the Bermuda Biological Station for Research, highlights color change in cephalopods. This page provides links to each lesson plan, which are in PDF format and feature an informative, image-rich introduction followed by a hands-on laboratory activity. The lesson plans highlight cephalopod color change, vision, light quality, and light quantity.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Ansammlung Lektionpläne, erstellt durch die
Bermuda biologische Station für Forschung, markiert Farbe Änderung 
in den Kopffüßern. Diese Seite stellt Links zu jedem 
Lektionplan zur Verfügung, die im pdf Format sind und eine 
informative, Bild-reiche Einleitung kennzeichnen, die von einer 
Blindeinschub Laboraktivität gefolgt wird. Die 
Lektionplanhöhepunktkopffüßer-Farbe Änderung, der Anblick, die 
helle Qualität und die helle Quantität.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette collection de plans de leçon, créée par 
la station biologique des Bermudes pour la recherche, met en valeur le
changement de couleur des céphalopodes. Cette page fournit les 
liens à chaque plan de leçon, qui sont dans le format de pdf et 
comportent une introduction instructive et image-riche suivie d'une 
activité à commande manuelle de laboratoire. Le changement de 
couleur de céphalopode de point culminant de plans de leçon, la 
vision, la qualité légère, et la quantité légère.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta coleção de plantas da lição, criada pela 
estação biológica de Bermuda para a pesquisa, destaca a mudança da
cor nos cefalópodes. Esta página fornece as ligações a cada 
planta da lição, que estão no formato do pdf e caracterizam uma 
introdução informative, imagem-rica seguida por uma atividade 
hands-on do laboratório. A mudança da cor do cefalópode do 
destaque das plantas da lição, a visão, a qualidade clara, e a 
quantidade clara.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa accumulazione dei programmi di lezione, 
creata dalla stazione biologica delle Bermude per ricerca, evidenzia 
il cambiamento di colore in cefalopodi. Questa pagina fornisce i
collegamenti ad ogni programma di lezione, che sono nel formato del 
pdf e caratterizzano un'introduzione informativa e immagine-ricca 
seguita da un'attività hands-on del laboratorio. Il cambiamento
di colore del cefalopodo di punto culminante di programmi di lezione, 
visione, la qualità chiara e la quantità chiara.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η συλλογή των σχεδίων μαθήματος, που 
δημιουργείται από το βιολογικό σταθμό των Βερμούδων για την 
έρευνα, δίνει έμφαση στην αλλαγή χρώματος στα κεφαλόποδα. 
Αυτή η σελίδα παρέχει τις συνδέσεις με κάθε σχέδιο 
μαθήματος, οι οποίες είναι με τη μορφή PDF και χαρακτηρίζουν 
μια πληροφοριακή, εικόνα-πλούσια εισαγωγή που ακολουθείται από 
μια εμπράγματη εργαστηριακή δραστηριότητα. Τα σχέδια 
μαθήματος δίνουν έμφαση στην αλλαγή χρώματος κεφαλόποδων, το 
όραμα, την ελαφριά ποιότητα, και την ελαφριά ποσότητα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta colección de planes de la lección, creada 
por la estación biológica de Bermudas para la investigación, 
destaca el cambio del color en cefalópodos. Esta paginación 
proporciona a las conexiones a cada plan de la lección, que están en
formato del pdf y ofrecen una introducción informativa, imagen-rica 
seguida por una actividad con manos del laboratorio. El cambio 
del color del cefalópodo del toque de luz de los planes de la 
lección, la visión, la calidad ligera, y la cantidad ligera.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JAMES B. WOOD
FN:JAMES B. WOOD
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CEPHSCHOOL, BERMUDA BIOLOGICAL STATION FOR RESEARCH
FN:CEPHSCHOOL, BERMUDA BIOLOGICAL STATION FOR RESEARCH
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200851</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105206</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/cephalopod-lesson-plans</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
