<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103134</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103134</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087202</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"We Ran Silent Movies For Years": An Italian Immigrant Goes Into Show Business in the Early 20th century</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Wir Ließen Leise Filme Für Jahre" Laufen: 
Ein italienischer Immigrant steigt in Erscheinen-Geschäft im 
frühen 20. Jahrhundert ein</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Nous Avons exécuté Des Films Silencieux Pendant
Des Années" : Un immigré italien entre dans le show business 
en début du 20ème siècle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Nós Funcionamos Filmes Silenciosos Por Anos": 
Um immigrant italiano entra no negócio da mostra no 20o século
adiantado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Abbiamo fatto funzionare I Film 
Silenziosi Per Gli Anni": Un immigrante italiano entra nel 
commercio di esposizione nell'inizio del 20esimo secolo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Τρέξαμε τους σιωπηλούς κινηματογράφους για χρόνια": 
Ένας ιταλικός μετανάστης πηγαίνει εμφανίζει επιχείρηση 
στις αρχές του 20ού αιώνα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Ejecutamos Las Películas Silenciosas Por Años":
Un inmigrante italiano entra negocio de la demostración en el 
vigésimo siglo temprano</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The advent of "talkies"in the early 20th century had an impact felt far from Hollywood. Immigrants made up a significant portion of the movie-going audience during the silent film era because the lack of (English) speech beckoned immigrants unable to comprehend the many facets of American life: a picture that didn't talk was particularly appealing to people who didn't speak or read English. In this oral history, recorded by Roy Rosenzweig in 1978, Italian immigrant Fred Fedeli recalled his experiences owning and operating a movie theater in an immigrant working-class neighborhood of Worcester, Massachusetts.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Aufkommen von "talkies"in, welches das frühe 
20. Jahrhundert eine Auswirkung hatte, glaubte weit von Hollywood. 
Immigranten bildeten einen bedeutenden Teil der Film-gehenden 
Publikum während der leisen Filmära, weil der Mangel an (Englisch) 
Rede den Immigranten zuwinkte, die nicht imstande sind, die vielen 
Facetten der amerikanischen Lebensdauer zu begreifen: eine 
Abbildung, die nicht sprach, gefiel besonders Leuten, die Englisch 
sprachen nicht oder lasen. In dieser Mundgeschichte gespeichert 
von Roy Rosenzweig 1978, erinnerte an italienisches einwanderndes Fred
Fedeli seine Erfahrungen ein Filmtheater in einer einwandernden 
Arbeiterklassenachbarschaft von Worcester, Massachusetts besitzend und
laufen lassend.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'arrivée des "films parlants que le début du 
20ème siècle a eu un impact s'est sentie loin de Hollywood. 
Les immigrés ont composé une partie significative des 
assistances film-allantes pendant l'ère silencieuse de film parce que
le manque de la parole (de l'anglais) a montré des immigrés du doigt
incapables de comprendre les nombreuses facettes de la vie américaine
: une image qui n'a pas parlé faisait en particulier appel aux 
gens qui n'ont pas parlé ou n'ont pas lu anglais. Dans cette 
histoire orale, enregistrée par Roy Rosenzweig en 1978, Fred immigré
italien Fedeli a rappelé ses expériences possédant et actionnant un
théâtre de film dans un voisinage immigré de classe ouvrier de 
Worcester, le Massachusetts.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O advent do "talkies"in que o 20o século 
adiantado teve um impacto sentiu longe de Hollywood. Os 
immigrants compuseram uma parcela significativa das audiências 
filme-indo durante a era silenciosa da película porque a falta do 
discurso (do inglês) beckoned os immigrants incapazes de compreender 
muitos facets da vida americana: um retrato que não falasse 
estava apelando particularmente aos povos que não falaram nem não 
leram o inglês. Neste history oral, gravado por Roy Rosenzweig 
em 1978, Fred immigrant italiano Fedeli recordou suas experiências 
possuindo e operando um teatro do filme em uma vizinhança immigrant 
do working-class de Worcester, Massachusetts.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'avvenimento "di talkies"in che l'inizio del 
20esimo secolo ha avuto un effetto ha ritenuto lontano da Hollywood. 
Gli immigranti hanno composto una parte significativa dei 
pubblici di film-going durante l'era silenziosa della pellicola 
perché la mancanza di discorso (di inglese) beckoned gli immigranti 
incapaci comprendere le molte sfaccettature di vita americana: 
un'immagine che non ha comunicato stava facendo appello 
specialmente alla gente che non ha parlato o non letto inglese. 
In questa storia orale, registrata da Roy Rosenzweig in 1978, 
Fred immigrato italiano Fedeli ha ricordato le sue esperienze 
possedente ed operante un teatro di film in una vicinanza 
immigrata della classe operaia di Worcester, Massachusetts.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η εμφάνιση "του talkies"in ο πρόωρος 20ός αιώνας 
άσκησε επίδραση που έγινε αισθητή μακριά από Hollywood. 
Οι μετανάστες αποτέλεσαν μια σημαντική μερίδα του 
κινηματογράφος-πηγαίνοντας ακροατηρίου κατά τη διάρκεια της 
σιωπηλής εποχής ταινιών επειδή η έλλειψη (αγγλική) νευόντων 
ομιλία μεταναστών ανίκανων να κατανοήσουν τις πολλές απόψεις της
αμερικανικής ζωής: μια εικόνα που δεν μίλησε ήταν 
ιδιαίτερα ελκυστική στους ανθρώπους που δεν μίλησαν ή δεν 
διάβασαν τα αγγλικά. Σε αυτήν την προφορική ιστορία, που 
καταγράφηκε από το Roy Rosenzweig το 1978, ο ιταλικός που 
έχουν μεταναστεύσει Fred Fedeli υπενθύμισε την εμπειρία του 
που είναι κύρια και που ενεργοποιεί ενός κινηματογράφου σε μια 
που έχουν μεταναστεύσει γειτονιά εργατικών τάξεων του 
Worcester, Μασαχουσέτη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El advenimiento del "talkies"in que el vigésimo 
siglo temprano tenía un impacto se sentía lejos de Hollywood. 
Los inmigrantes compusieron a porción significativa de las 
audiencias peli'cula-que iban durante la era silenciosa de la 
película porque la carencia del discurso (del inglés) hizo señas a 
inmigrantes incapaces comprender las muchas facetas de la vida 
americana: un cuadro que no habló abrogaba determinado a la 
gente que no habló ni leyó inglés. En esta historia oral, 
registrada por Roy Rosenzweig en 1978, Fred inmigrante italiano Fedeli
recordó sus experiencias poseyendo y funcionando un teatro de la 
película en una vecindad inmigrante de la clase obrera de Worcester, 
Massachusetts.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087202</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103134</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/we-ran-silent-movies-for-years-an-italian-immigrant-goes-into-show-business-in-the-early-20th-century</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
