<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108468</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108468</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207071</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Lakota Winter Counts</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lakota Winter-Zählimpulse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Comptes d'Hiver de Lakota</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Contagens Do Inverno De Lakota</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Conteggi Di Inverno Di Lakota</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Χειμερινές αριθμήσεις Lakota</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cuentas Del Invierno De Lakota</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">offers the world's largest database of Lakota winter counts -- pictures drawn on cloth or buffalo hide to remember each year's key events (1701 to 1905). Ten Lakota bands' winter counts are shown side by side on a timeline. Compare how the bands depicted a particular year. Search for an image. Watch interviews with Lakota. Learn about the culture of this Sioux tribe of the northern plains that followed buffalo herds for food. A teachers guide is included.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">bietet die größte Datenbank der Welt der Lakota 
Winterzählimpulse -- die Abbildungen an, die auf Tuch- oder 
Büffelfell gezeichnet werden, um sich an jedes Jahr Schlüsselfälle 
(1701 bis 1905) zu erinnern. 10 Winterzählimpulse der Lakota 
Bänder werden nebeneinander auf einem timeline gezeigt. 
Vergleichen Sie, wie die Bänder ein bestimmtes Jahr bildlich 
darstellten. Suchen Sie nach einem Bild. Überwachen Sie 
Interviews mit Lakota. Erlernen Sie über die Kultur dieses 
Sioux Stammes der Nordebenen, die Büffelherden für Nahrung folgten. 
Eine Lehreranleitung ist enthalten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">offre la plus grande base de données du monde des
comptes d'hiver de Lakota -- images dessinées sur la peau de tissu ou
de buffle pour se rappeler les événements tous les ans principaux 
(1701 à 1905). Dix comptes de l'hiver des bandes de Lakota sont
montrés côte à côte sur une chronologie. Comparez comment 
les bandes ont dépeint une année particulière. Recherchez une
image. Observez les entrevues avec Lakota. Renseignez-vous
sur la culture de cette tribu de Sioux des plaines nordiques qui ont 
suivi des troupeaux de buffle pour la nourriture. Un guide de 
professeurs est inclus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">oferece a base de dados a maior do mundo de 
contagens do inverno de Lakota -- retratos desenhados no hide de pano 
ou de búfalo para recordar os eventos chaves de cada ano (1701 a 
1905). Dez contagens do inverno das faixas de Lakota são 
mostradas de lado a lado em um timeline. Compare como as faixas 
descreveram um ano particular. Procurare por uma imagem. 
Preste atenção a entrevistas com Lakota. Aprenda sobre a
cultura deste tribe de Sioux das planícies do norte que seguiram 
rebanhos do búfalo para o alimento. Uma guia dos professores é
incluída.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">offre la più grande base di dati del mondo dei 
conteggi di inverno di Lakota -- immagini dissipate sul pellame del 
bufalo o del panno per ricordarsi degli eventi ogni anno chiave (1701 
- 1905). Dieci conteggi di inverno delle fasce di Lakota sono 
indicati parallelamente su un timeline. Confronti come le fasce 
hanno descritto un anno particolare. Cerchi un'immagine. 
Guardi le interviste con Lakota. Impari circa la coltura 
di questa tribù del Sioux delle pianure nordiche che hanno seguito le
greggi del bufalo per alimento. Una guida degli insegnanti è 
inclusa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">προσφέρει την παγκόσμια μεγαλύτερη βάση δεδομένων των
χειμερινών Lakota αριθμήσεων -- εικόνες που επισύρονται την 
προσοχή στη δορά υφασμάτων ή βούβαλων για να θυμηθούν τα βασικά
γεγονότα κάθε έτους (1701 έως 1905). Χειμερινές 
αριθμήσεις δέκα ζωνών Lakota οι "εμφανίζονται δίπλα-δίπλα σε 
μια υπόδειξη ως προς το χρόνο. Συγκρίνετε πώς οι ζώνες 
απεικόνισαν ένα ιδιαίτερο έτος. Αναζήτηση μιας εικόνας. 
Συνεντεύξεις ρολογιών με Lakota. Μάθετε για τον 
πολιτισμό αυτής της σιού φυλής των βόρειων πεδιάδων που 
ακολούθησαν τα κοπάδια βούβαλων για τα τρόφιμα. Ένας 
οδηγός δασκάλων συμπεριλαμβάνεται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece la base de datos más grande del mundo de 
las cuentas del invierno de Lakota -- cuadros trazados en piel del 
paño o del búfalo para recordar los acontecimientos dominantes de 
cada año (1701 a 1905). Diez cuentas del invierno de las vendas
de Lakota se muestran de lado a lado en un timeline. Compare 
cómo las vendas representaron un año determinado. Busque para 
una imagen. Mire las entrevistas con Lakota. Aprenda sobre
la cultura de esta tribu de Sioux de los llanos norteños que 
siguieron las manadas del búfalo para el alimento. Una guía de
los profesores es incluida.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207071</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108468</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/lakota-winter-counts</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
