<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106422</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106422</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213159</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Wheel of Geology</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Rad von Geologie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Roue de géologie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Roda da geologia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Rotella di geologia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ρόδα της γεωλογίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Rueda de la geología</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This game activity is meant to help liven up an exam review session. Multiple choice review questions are divided up into categories and students are organized into teams. The instructor spins a wheel to determine what category of question is asked and the teams compete to answer the question. On this Starting Point page, users can access information about the exercise's learning goals, context for use, teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment ideas, references and topics covered.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Spielaktivität wird bedeutet, um zu helfen 
liven herauf eine Prüfungzusammenfassungsitzung. Mehrfache 
auserlesene Zusammenfassungfragen werden oben in Kategorien geteilt 
und Kursteilnehmer werden in Teams organisiert. Der Ausbilder 
spinnt ein Rad, um festzustellen, welche Kategorie der Frage gefragt 
wird und die Teams konkurrieren, um die Frage zu beantworten. 
Auf dieser Ausgangspunktseite können Benutzer auf Informationen
über die erlernenziele der Übung, Kontext für Gebrauch-, die 
Unterrichtenumfaßten anmerkungen und Spitzen, Lehrmittel, 
Einschätzung Ideen, Referenzen und Themen zugreifen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette activité de jeu est censée pour aider 
liven vers le haut d'une session de revue d'examen. Des 
questions bien choisies multiples de revue sont divisées en 
catégories et des étudiants sont organisés en équipes. 
L'instructeur tourne une roue pour déterminer quelle catégorie
de question est demandée et les équipes concurrencent pour répondre
à la question. À cette page de point de départ, les 
utilisateurs peuvent accéder aux informations sur les buts d'étude 
de l'exercice, contexte pour les extrémités d'utilisation, 
d'enseignement les notes et, le matériel didactique, les idées 
d'évaluation, les références et les sujets couverts.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta atividade do jogo é significada ajudar liven
acima de uma sessão da revisão do exam. As perguntas bem 
escolhidas múltiplas da revisão são divididas acima em categorias e
os estudantes são organizados em equipes. O instrutor gira uma 
roda para determinar que categoria de pergunta é perguntada e as 
equipes competem para responder à pergunta. Nesta página do 
ponto começar, os usuários podem alcançar a informação sobre os 
objetivos de aprendizagem do exercício, contexto para as pontas do 
uso, ensinar as notas e, os materiais de ensino, as idéias da 
avaliação, as referências e os tópicos cobertos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa attività del gioco è significata per 
aiutare liven su una sessione di revisione del exam. Le domande 
choice multiple di revisione sono divise nelle categorie e gli allievi
sono organizzati nelle squadre. L'istruttore fila una rotella 
per determinare che categoria di domanda è chiesta e le squadre 
competono per rispondere alla domanda. A questa pagina del punto
di partenza, gli utenti possono accedere alle informazioni sugli 
obiettivi imparanti dell'esercitazione, contesto per le punte di 
istruzione, di uso note e, i materiali didattici, le idee di 
valutazione, i riferimenti ed i soggetti coperti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η δραστηριότητα παιχνιδιών προορίζεται να 
βοηθήσει επάνω μια περίοδος επικοινωνίας αναθεώρησης 
διαγωνισμών. Οι πολλαπλάσιες ερωτήσεις αναθεώρησης επιλογής
διαιρούνται επάνω σε κατηγορίες και οι σπουδαστές οργανώνονται 
στις ομάδες. Ο εκπαιδευτικός περιστρέφει μια ρόδα για να 
καθορίσει ποια κατηγορία ερώτησης ρωτιέται και οι ομάδες 
ανταγωνίζονται για να απαντήσουν στην ερώτηση. Σε αυτήν την 
σελίδα αφετηρίας, οι χρήστες μπορούν να έχουν πρόσβαση στις 
πληροφορίες για τους στόχους εκμάθησης της άσκησης, πλαίσιο για 
τη χρήση, τις σημειώσεις και τις άκρες διδασκαλίας, τα 
εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, τις ιδέες αξιολόγησης, τις αναφορές και τα 
θέματα που καλύπτονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta actividad del juego se significa para ayudar 
liven encima de una sesión de la revisión del examen. Las 
preguntas bien escogidas múltiples de la revisión se dividen para 
arriba en categorías y ordenan a los estudiantes en los equipos. 
El instructor hace girar una rueda para determinarse qué 
categoría de la pregunta se pregunta y los equipos compiten para 
contestar a la pregunta. En esta paginación del punto de 
partida, los utilizadores pueden tener acceso a la información sobre 
las metas que aprenden del ejercicio, contexto para las extremidades 
del uso, de la enseñanza las notas y, los materiales didácticos, las
ideas del gravamen, las referencias y los asuntos cubiertos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:REBECCA TEED
FN:REBECCA TEED
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213159</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106422</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/wheel-of-geology</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
