<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104556</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104556</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086733</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Pitchfork Ben" Tillman Addresses the 1896 Democratic Convention</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Heugabel Ben" Tillman adressiert die 
demokratische Vereinbarung 1896</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">la "fourche Ben" Tillman adresse la convention 
1896 démocratique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">o "pitchfork Ben" Tillman dirige-se à convenção
1896 democrática</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"il pitchfork Ben" Tillman parla alla convenzione 
democratica 1896</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Pitchfork Ben" Tillman απευθύνεται στη 
δημοκρατική Συνθήκη 1896</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">el "pitchfork Ben" Tillman se dirige a la 
convención democrática 1896</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The most famous speech in American political history was delivered by William Jennings Bryan on July 9, 1896, at the Democratic National Convention in Chicago, but it was preceded by two other significant speeches. The subject under debate was currency, a central issue in the 1896 presidential election. The issue was whether to endorse the free coinage of silver at a ratio of silver to gold of 16 to 1. (This inflationary measure would have increased the amount of money in circulation and aided cash-poor and debt-burdened farmers.) Senator Benjamin Tillman of South Carolina supported the measure, but misjudged his audience by framing the silver issue as a sectional one. Tillman's fiery and strange appearance only reinforced the belief of some delegates that he was a madman. His disastrous performance dashed his hopes to be the silverite candidate for the U.S. presidency.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die berühmteste Rede in der amerikanischen 
politischen Geschichte wurde von William Jennings Bryan an Juli 9, 
1896, an demokratischen Nationalkonventin Chicago geliefert, aber sie 
wurde von zwei anderen bedeutenden Reden vorangegangen. Das 
Thema unter Debatte war Währung, eine zentrale Ausgabe in der 
Präsidentenwahl 1896. Die Ausgabe war, ob man die freie 
Prägung des Silbers an einem Verhältnis des Silbers zum Gold von 16 
bis 1 indossiert. (dieses inflationistische Maß würde die 
Menge des Geldumlaufs erhöht haben und den Bargeld-schlechten und 
Schuld-belasteten Landwirten. geholfen) Senator Benjamin Tillman
von Südcarolina unterstützte das Maß, aber verkannte seine 
Publikum, indem er die silberne Ausgabe als Schnitt gestaltete. 
Tillmans brennendes und merkwürdiges Aussehen verstärkte nur 
den Glauben einiger Delegierter, daß er ein Irres war. Seine 
verhängnisvolle Leistung gestrichelt seine Hoffnungen, der silverite 
Anwärter für den VEREINIGTE STAATEN Vorsitz zu sein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le discours le plus célèbre dans l'histoire 
politique américaine a été fourni par William Jennings Bryan 
9 juillet 1896, à la convention nationale démocratique Chicago, 
mais il a été précédé par deux autres discours significatifs. 
Le sujet sous la discussion était la devise, une issue centrale
dans l'élection 1896 présidentielle. L'issue était si 
approuver l'invention libre de l'argent à un rapport d'argent à l'or
de 16 à 1. (cette mesure inflationniste aurait augmenté le 
montant d'argent dans la circulation et avait aidé les fermiers 
argent-pauvres et dette-chargés.) Le sénateur Benjamin Tillman
de la Caroline du sud a supporté la mesure, mais a méjugé ses
assistances en encadrant l'issue argentée en tant que sectionnelle. 
L'aspect ardent et étrange de Tillman a seulement renforcé la 
croyance de quelques délégués qu'il était un fou. Sa 
exécution désastreuse à tiret ses espoirs d'être le candidat de 
silverite pour la présidence des ETATS-UNIS.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O discurso o mais famoso no history político 
americano foi entregado por William Jennings Bryan julho em 9, 1896, 
na convenção nacional democrática em Chicago, mas foi precedido 
outros por dois discursos significativos. O assunto sob o debate
era a moeda corrente, uma edição central na eleição 1896 
presidencial. A edição era se endossar o coinage livre da 
prata em uma relação da prata a um ouro de 16 a 1. (esta 
medida inflationary aumentaria a quantidade de dinheiro na 
circulação e ajudaria a fazendeiros dinheiro-deficientes e 
débito-debt-burdened.) O senator Benjamin Tillman de carolina 
sul suportou a medida, mas misjudged suas audiências moldando a 
edição de prata como secional. A aparência impetuosa e 
estranha de Tillman reforçou somente a opinião de alguns delegados 
que era um madman. Seu desempenho desastroso tracejado suas 
esperanças ser o candidato do silverite para o presidency de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il discorso più famoso nella storia politica 
americana è stato trasportato da William Jennings Bryan il 9 luglio 
1896, alla convenzione nazionale democratica in Chicago, ma è stato 
preceduto altri da due discorsi significativi. L'oggetto sotto 
il dibattito era valuta, un'edizione centrale nell'elezione 
presidenziale 1896. L'edizione era se firmare l'invenzione 
libera di argento ad un rapporto di argento ad un oro di 16 - 1. 
(questa misura inflazionistica avrebbe aumentato l'importo di 
soldi nella circolazione ed aiutato cash-povero e debito-caricato i 
coltivatori.) Il senatore Benjamin Tillman di Carolina del Sud
ha sostenuto la misura, ma giudicato male i suoi pubblici 
incorniciando l'edizione d'argento come sezionale. L'apparenza 
ardenta e sconosciuta del Tillman ha rinforzato soltanto la credenza 
di alcuni delegati che era un pazzo. Le sue prestazioni 
disastrose tratteggiate le sue speranze essere il candidato del 
silverite per la presidenza degli STATI UNITI.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η διασημότερη ομιλία στην αμερικανική πολιτική 
ιστορία παραδόθηκε από William Jennings Bryan στις 9 
Ιουλίου ..1896, στη δημοκρατική εθνική Συνθήκη στο Σικάγο, 
αλλά προηγήθηκε από δύο άλλες σημαντικές ομιλίες. Το 
θέμα κάτω από τη συζήτηση ήταν νόμισμα, ένα κεντρικό ζήτημα 
στην προεδρική εκλογή 1896. Το ζήτημα ήταν εάν για να 
επικυρώσει την ελεύθερη δημιουργία του ασημιού σε μια αναλογία 
του ασημιού στο χρυσό 16 έως 1. (Αυτό το πληθωριστικό 
μέτρο θα είχε αυξήσει το χρηματικό ποσό στην κυκλοφορία και τους
βοηθημένους μετρητό-φτωχούς και τους χρέος-φορτωμένους αγρότες.)
Ο γερουσιαστής Benjamin Tillman της νότιας Καρολίνας 
υποστήριξε το μέτρο, αλλά εκτίμησε εσφαλμένα το ακροατήριό του 
με τη διαμόρφωση του ασημένιου ζητήματος ως ένα τμηματικό. 
Η φλογερή και παράξενη εμφάνιση του Tillman ενίσχυσε 
μόνο την πεποίθηση μερικών εκπροσώπων ότι ήταν madman. 
Η καταστρεπτική απόδοσή του όρμησε τις ελπίδες του να 
είναι ο υποψήφιος silverite για την ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ προεδρία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El discurso más famoso de la historia política 
americana fue entregado por Guillermo Jennings Bryan 9 de julio de 
1896, en la convención nacional democrática en Chicago, pero fue 
precedido por dos otros discursos significativos. El tema bajo 
discusión era la modernidad, una edición central en la elección 
presidencial 1896. La edición era si endosar la invención 
libre de la plata en una relación de transformación de la plata al 
oro de 16 a 1. (esta medida inflacionista habría aumentado la 
cantidad de dinero en la circulación y había ayudado a granjeros 
efectivo-pobres y deuda-cargados.) Senador Benjamin Tillman de 
Carolina del Sur utilizó la medida, pero misjudged a sus audiencias 
enmarcando la edición de plata como seccional. El aspecto 
ardiente y extraño de Tillman reforzó solamente la creencia de 
algunos delegados que él era un loco. Su funcionamiento 
desastroso rayado sus esperanzas de ser el candidato del silverite a 
la presidencia de ESTADOS UNIDOS.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086733</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104556</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/pitchfork-ben-tillman-addresses-the-1896-democratic-convention</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
