<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103452</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103452</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086383</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Killing the Messenger: Ida Wells-Barnett Protests a Postmaster's Murder in 1898</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Beenden des Kuriers: Ida 
Vertiefungen-Barnett protestiert den Mord eines postmaster 1898</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Détruire le messager : Les Puits-Barnett 
d'Ida proteste le meurtre d'un postmaster en 1898</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matando o mensageiro: Os Poços-Barnett de 
Ida protestam o assassinato de um postmaster em 1898</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Uccisione del messaggero: I Pozzi-Barnett di
Ida protesta l'omicidio del postmaster in 1898</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δολοφονία του αγγελιοφόρου: Η IDA φρεάτιο- 
Barnett διαμαρτύρεται τη δολοφονία διευθυντών ταχυδρομείου το 
1898</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matar al mensajero: Los Receptores de 
papel-Barnett de Ida protestan el asesinato de un postmaster en 1898</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The rising tide of lynchings of African Americans across the South launched a national anti-lynching crusade, led by Memphis, Tennessee, newspaper editor Ida Wells-Barnett, an outspoken advocate for the area's African-American citizens. As the leader of the national anti-lynching movement, Wells-Barnett joined a group of Illinois congressmen who visited the White House in March, 1898, to protest the murder of the newly-appointed Lake City, South Carolina Postmaster Baker, who was black. Wells-Barnett penned this petition to President William McKinley to urge punishment of those responsible for shooting.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die steigenden Gezeiten von lynchings der 
afrikanischen Amerikaner über dem Süden stießen einen nationalen 
Anti-lynchenden Kreuzzug aus, geführt durch Memphis, Tennessee, 
Zeitungsverleger Ida Vertiefungen-Barnett, ein freimütiger 
Fürsprecher für die Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Bürger des 
Bereiches. Als der Führer der nationalen Anti-lynchenden 
Bewegung, verbanden Vertiefungen-Barnett eine Gruppe Illinois 
Kongreßabgeordnete, die das Weiße Haus im März, 1898 besichtigten, 
um den Mord an der neu-festgesetzten See-Stadt, Südcarolina 
postmaster-Bäcker zu protestieren, der schwarz war. 
Vertiefungen-Barnett sperrten diese Petition zum Präsidenten 
William McKinley ein, um Bestrafung von denen zu drängen, die für 
das Schießen verantwortlich sind.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La marée de montée des lynchings des Américains
africains à travers les Sud a lancé une croisade 
anti-lynchante nationale, menée par Memphis, Tennessee, les 
Puits-Barnett d'Ida d'éditeur de journal, un avocat franc pour les 
citoyens afro-américains de la zone. En tant qu'amorce du 
mouvement anti-lynchant national, les Puits-Barnett ont joint un 
groupe de membres du Congrès de l'Illinois qui ont visité la Maison 
Blanche  en mars, 1898, pour protester le meurtre de la ville 
nouveau-désignée de lac, Baker du sud de postmaster de la 
Caroline, qui était noir. Les Puits-Barnett ont parqué cette 
pétition au Président William McKinley pour encourager la punition 
de ceux responsables du tir.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A maré levantando-se dos lynchings de americanos 
africanos através do sul lançou um crusade anti-anti-lynching 
nacional, conduzido por Memphis, Tennessee, Poços-Barnett de Ida do 
editor de jornal, um advogado outspoken para os cidadãos 
Africano-Americanos da área. Como o líder do movimento 
anti-anti-lynching nacional, os Poços-Barnett juntaram um grupo dos 
congressistas de Illinois que visitaram a casa branca em março, 1898,
para protestar o assassinato da cidade novo-apontada do lago, o 
padeiro do postmaster de carolina sul, que era preto. Os 
Poços-Barnett penned esta petição ao presidente William McKinley 
para incitar a punição daqueles responsáveis para disparar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La marea aumentante dei lynchings degli Americani 
africani attraverso il sud ha lanciato un crusade anti-anti-lynching 
nazionale, condotto da Memphis, Tennessee, i Pozzi-Barnett di Ida 
dell'editore di giornale, un fautore franco per i cittadini 
Africano-Americani della zona. Come il capo del movimento
anti-anti-lynching nazionale, i Pozzi-Barnett hanno unito un gruppo 
dei membri del Congresso dell'Illinois che hanno visitato la Casa 
Bianca in marzo, del 1898, per protestare l'omicidio della città 
nuovo-nominata del lago, panettiere del postmaster della Carolina del 
Sud, che era nero. I Pozzi-Barnett hanno rinchiuso questa 
petizione al presidente William McKinley per sollecitare la punizione 
di quelli responsabili della fucilazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η αυξανόμενη παλίρροια των λυντσαρισμάτων αφρικανικών 
Αμερικανών πέρα από το νότο προώθησε μια εθνική σταυροφορία 
αντι-λυντσαρίσματος, που οδηγήθηκε από τη Μέμφιδα, Tennessee, 
επεξεργαστής IDA φρεάτιο- Barnett, ένας ειλικρινής 
συνήγορος εφημερίδων για τους αφρικανικός-αμερικανικούς πολίτες 
της περιοχής. Σαν ηγέτη της εθνικής μετακίνησης 
αντι-λυντσαρίσματος, φρεάτιο- Barnett προσχώρησε σε μια ομάδα 
μελών του Κογκρέσσου του Ιλλινόις που επισκέφτηκαν το λευκό οίκο
το Μάρτιο, 1898, για να διαμαρτυρηθεί τη δολοφονία της 
πρόσφατα-διορισμένης πόλης λιμνών, διευθυντής ταχυδρομείου 
Baker της νότιας Καρολίνας, η οποία ήταν μαύρη. 
Φρεάτιο- Barnett περιέφραξε αυτήν την αίτηση στον 
Πρόεδρο William McKinley για να ωθήσει την τιμωρία των 
ατόμων για πυροβολισμός.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La marea de levantamiento de lynchings de 
americanos africanos a través del sur lanzó una cruzada 
contra-anti-lynching nacional, conducida por Memphis, Tennessee, 
Receptores de papel-Barnett de Ida del redactor, abogado abierto para 
los ciudadanos Africano-Americanos del área. Como el arranque 
de cinta del movimiento contra-anti-lynching nacional, los Receptores 
de papel-Barnett ensamblaron a grupo de los miembros del Congreso de 
Illinois que visitaron la casa blanca en marcha de 1898, para 
protestar el asesinato de la ciudad nuevo-designada del lago, el 
panadero del postmaster de Carolina del Sur, que era negro. Los 
Receptores de papel-Barnett encerraron esta petición a presidente 
Guillermo McKinley para impulsar el castigo de ésos responsables de 
tirar.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086383</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103452</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/killing-the-messenger-ida-wells-barnett-protests-a-postmasters-murder-in-1898</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
