<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105106</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105106</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206691</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Learning to Fly: The Wright Brothers' Adventure</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lernen zu fliegen: Das Abenteuer Der Wright 
Brüder</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Étude pour voler : l'Aventure des Frères 
De Wright</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Aprendizagem voar: A Aventura Dos Irmãos De
Wright</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Imparare volare: L'Avventura Dei Fratelli Di
Wright</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εκμάθηση να πετά: Η περιπέτεια των αδελφών 
Wright</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El aprender volar: La Aventura De los 
Hermanos De Wright</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">sends students undercover to Dayton and Kitty Hawk to report secretly on the activities of two brothers who are making a big glider in their bicycle shop. Students prepare by researching aviation history and then, posing as news reporters, interview the brothers (and neighbors). Instructions are included for building the Wright brothers' gliders and first plane.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">schickt Kursteilnehmer Innenabdeckung nach Dayton 
und Kitty-Falken zum Report geheim auf die Aktivitäten von zwei 
Brüdern, die ein grosses Segelflugzeug in ihrem Fahrrad kaufen 
lassen. Kursteilnehmer bereiten, sich indem sie 
Luftfahrtgeschichte und dann erforschen und als Nachrichten Reporter 
aufwerfen, interviewen die Brüder vor (und die Nachbarn). 
Anweisungen sind für das Aufbauen der Segelflugzeuge und ersten
der Fläche der Wright Brüder enthalten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">envoie à des étudiants le capot interne à 
Dayton et le faucon de Kitty à l'état secrètement sur les 
activités de deux frères qui font un grand planeur dans leur 
bicyclette faire des emplettes. Les étudiants préparent en 
recherchant l'histoire d'aviation et puis, posant comme journalistes 
de nouvelles, interviewent les frères (et des voisins). Les 
instructions sont incluses pour construire de Wright le premier avion 
des frères les planeurs et.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">emite a estudantes a capa interna a Dayton e o 
falcão do kitty ao relatório secreta nas atividades de dois irmãos 
que estão fazendo um planador grande em sua bicicleta comprar. 
Os estudantes preparam-se pesquisando o history da aviação e 
então, posing como repórteres da notícia, entrevistam os irmãos (e
vizinhos). As instruções são incluídas para construir o 
primeiro plano dos irmãos de Wright os planadores e.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">trasmette ad allievi la copertura inferiore a 
Dayton ed il hawk del kitty al rapporto segretamente sulle attività 
dei due fratelli che stanno facendo un aliante grande in loro 
bicicletta acquistare. Gli allievi si preparano ricercando la 
storia di aeronautica ed allora, proponendo come reporter di 
notizie, intervistano i fratelli (ed i vicinoi). Le istruzioni 
sono incluse per lo sviluppo del primo aereo dei fratelli di Wright 
gli alianti e.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">στέλνει τους σπουδαστές μυστικούς στο γεράκι του 
Νταίυτον και γατακιών για να υποβάλει έκθεση κρυφά σχετικά με 
τις δραστηριότητες δύο αδελφών που κάνουν ένα μεγάλο ανεμοπλάνο
στο κατάστημα ποδηλάτων τους. Οι σπουδαστές προετοιμάζονται 
με την έρευνα της ιστορίας αεροπορίας και έπειτα, θέτοντας 
δεδομένου ότι οι δημοσιογράφοι ειδήσεων, παίρνουν συνέντευξη 
από τους αδελφούς (και τους γείτονες). Οι οδηγίες 
συμπεριλαμβάνονται για την οικοδόμηση των του πρώτου αεροπλάνου 
των αδελφών Wright ανεμοπλάνων και.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">envía los estudiantes la cubierta interior a 
Dayton y el halcón del gatito al informe secretamente en las 
actividades de dos hermanos que estén haciendo que hace compras un 
planeador grande en su bicicleta. Los estudiantes se preparan 
investigando historia de la aviación y entonces, presentándose como 
reporteros de las noticias, se entrevistan con a los hermanos (y a 
vecinos). Las instrucciones son incluidas para construir el 
primer plano de los hermanos de Wright los planeadores y.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206691</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105106</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/learning-to-fly-the-wright-brothers-adventure</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
