<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107228</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107228</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201350</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Dying to be a Martyr</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sterben, zum ein Märtyrer zu sein</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mort à être un martyre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Morrer a ser um martyr</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Morire da essere un martyr</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θάνατος για να είναι μάρτυρας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El morir a ser un martyr</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Middle East conflict and terrorism are issues we hear about almost daily in the news. This lesson will use video clips from WIDE ANGLE's 'Suicide Bombers' (2004), Internet sites, and primary sources to examine the roots of the Middle East conflict. The video contains interviews with young Palestinians who participated -- or intended to participate -- in suicide bombings. These young Palestinians share the personal, religious, political and emotional reasons behind their participation in these suicide operations. This lesson could be used to review information about the three major monotheistic religions and their connections to Israel, to relate post-World War II policies to the current political state of the Middle East, and/or to get students to understand the roots of the terrorism that threatens the world we live in.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Mittlere Osten$überschneidung und -terrorismus 
sind Ausgaben, die wir ungefähr fast täglich in den Nachrichten 
hören. Diese Lektion benutzt videoclips von Wide.angle' ' 
Selbstmord-Bomber (2004), Internet-Sites, und die Primärquellen, zum 
der Wurzeln des Mittlere Ostens zu überprüfen widersprechen. 
Der Bildschirm enthält Interviews mit jungen Palästinensern, 
die -- oder beabsichtigt teilzunehmen -- an den 
Selbstmordbombardierungen teilnahmen. Diese jungen 
Palästinenser teilen die persönlichen, frommen, politischen und 
emotionalen Gründe hinter ihrer Teilnahme an diesen 
Selbstmordoperationen. Diese Lektion könnte verwendet werden, 
um Informationen über die drei monotheistic hauptsächlichreligionen 
und ihre Anschlüsse nach Israel zu wiederholen, des 
Pfosten-Weltkrieges II auf dem aktuellen politischen Zustand des 
Mittlere Ostens in Verbindung zu stehen politische Richtlinien, 
und/oder Kursteilnehmer zu beginnen, die Wurzeln des Terrorismus zu 
verstehen, der die Welt bedroht, die, wir innen leben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le conflit et le terrorisme de le Moyen-Orient 
sont des issues que nous entendons environ presque quotidiennement 
dans les nouvelles. Cette leçon utilisera les clips visuels 
bombardiers de suicide de Wide.angle'des '(2004), sites Internet, et 
les sources primaires pour examiner les racines de le Moyen-Orient 
sont en conflit. Le vidéo contient des entrevues avec les 
jeunes Palestiniens qui ont participé -- ou destiné pour participer 
-- aux bombardements de suicide. Ces jeunes Palestiniens 
partagent les raisons personnelles, religieuses, politiques et 
émotives derrière leur participation à ces exécutions de suicide. 
Cette leçon pourrait être employée pour passer en revue des 
informations sur les trois religions monotheistic principales et leurs
correspondances vers l'Israel, pour associer des politiques de la 
guerre II de poteau-Monde à l'état politique actuel de le 
Moyen-Orient, et/ou pour finir par des étudiants comprendre les 
racines du terrorisme qui menace le monde que nous vivons dedans.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O conflito e o terrorismo de o Oriente Médio são
edições que nós nos ouvimos aproximadamente quase diariamente na 
notícia. Esta lição usará os grampos video dos bombardeiros 
do suicide do ângulo LARGO ' (2004), locais de Internet, e as fontes 
preliminares para examinar as raizes de o Oriente Médio opõem. 
O vídeo contem entrevistas com palestinians novos que 
participaram -- ou pretendido participar -- em bombardeios do suicide.
Estes palestinians novos compartilham das razões pessoais, 
religiosas, políticas e emocionais atrás de sua participação 
nestas operações do suicide. Esta lição poderia ser usada 
rever a informação sobre as três religiões monotheistic principais
e suas conexões a Israel, relacionar políticas da guerra II do 
borne-Mundo ao estado político atual de o Oriente Médio, e/ou 
começar estudantes compreender as raizes do terrorismo que ameaça o 
mundo que nós vivemos dentro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il conflitto ed il terrorismo di Medio Oriente sono 
edizioni che ci sentiamo circa quasi giornalmente nelle notizie. 
Questa lezione utilizzerà le video clip bombardieri di suicide 
da Wide.angle''(2004), luoghi di Internet e le sorgenti primarie per 
esaminare le radici di Medio Oriente sono in conflitto. Il video 
contiene le interviste con i Palestinesi giovani che hanno partecipato
-- o progettato partecipare -- ai bombardamenti di suicide. 
Questi Palestinesi giovani ripartiscono i motivi personali, 
religiosi, politici ed impressionabili dietro la loro partecipazione a
questi funzionamenti di suicide. Questa lezione potrebbe essere 
usata per rivedere le informazioni sulle tre religioni monotheistic 
principali e sui loro collegamenti nell'Israele, per collegare le 
politiche di guerra II del alberino-Mondo al politico corrente 
dichiari di Medio Oriente e/o per convincere gli allievi a capire
le radici del terrorismo che minaccia il mondo che viviamo dentro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η σύγκρουση και η τρομοκρατία της Μέσης Ανατολής 
είναι ζητήματα που ακούμε περίπου σχεδόν καθημερινά στις 
ειδήσεις. Αυτό το μάθημα θα χρησιμοποιήσει τους 
τηλεοπτικούς συνδετήρες από WIDE.ANGLE'S "βομβαρδιστικά 
αεροπλάνα αυτοκτονίασ" (2004), χώροι διαδικτύου, και αρχικές 
πηγές για να εξετάσει τις ρίζες της σύγκρουσης της Μέσης 
Ανατολής. Το βίντεο περιέχει τις συνεντεύξεις με τους νέους
Παλαιστίνιους που συμμετείχαν -- ή σκόπευε να συμμετέχει -- στους
βομβαρδισμούς αυτοκτονίας. Αυτοί οι νέοι Παλαιστίνιοι 
μοιράζονται τους προσωπικούς, θρησκευτικούς, πολιτικούς και 
συναισθηματικούς λόγους πίσω από τη συμμετοχή τους σε αυτές τις 
διαδικασίες αυτοκτονίας. Αυτό το μάθημα θα μπορούσε να 
χρησιμοποιηθεί για να αναθεωρήσει τις πληροφορίες για τις τρεις 
σημαντικές monotheistic θρησκείες και τις συνδέσεις τους στο 
Ισραήλ, για να αφορά τον μετα-παγκόσμιο πόλεμο ΙΙ πολιτικές την 
παρούσα πολιτική κατάσταση της Μέσης Ανατολής, ή/και για να 
πάρει τους σπουδαστές για να καταλάβει τις ρίζες της τρομοκρατίας
που απειλεί τον κόσμο που ζούμε.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El conflicto y el terrorismo de el Oriente Medio 
son ediciones que oímos alrededor casi diariamente en las noticias. 
Esta lección utilizará los clips video bombarderos del 
suicidio de Wide.angle' los ' (2004), sitios de Internet, y las 
fuentes primarias para examinar las raíces de el Oriente Medio están
en conflicto. El vídeo contiene entrevistas con los palestinos 
jóvenes que participaron -- o prepuesto participar -- en bombardeos 
del suicidio. Estos palestinos jóvenes comparten las razones 
personales, religiosas, políticas y emocionales detrás de su 
participación en estas operaciones del suicidio. Esta lección 
se podría utilizar para repasar la información sobre las tres 
religiones monotheistic principales y sus conexiones a Israel, para 
relacionar políticas de la guerra II del poste-Mundo con el estado 
político actual de el Oriente Medio, y/o para conseguir a estudiantes
entender las raíces del terrorismo que amenaza el mundo que vivimos 
adentro.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:HEATHER AULETTA
FN:HEATHER AULETTA
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201350</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107228</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/dying-to-be-a-martyr</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
