<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103133</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103133</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086286</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Have Sung in Hobo Jungles, and I Have Sung for the Rockefellers": Pete Seeger Refuses to "Sing" for HUAC</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ich habe in den Hobo-Dschungeln gesungen, und ich
habe für das Rockefellers" gesungen: Peter Seeger lehnt 
"singen" für HUAC ab</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"j'ai chanté dans des jungles de hobo, et j'ai 
chanté pour le Rockefellers" : Peter Seeger refuse "chantent" 
pour HUAC</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"eu cantei em selvas do hobo, e eu cantei para o 
Rockefellers": Pete Seeger recusa "canta" para HUAC</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"ho cantato nelle giungle del hobo ed ho cantato 
per il Rockefellers": Pete Seeger rifiuta "canta" per HUAC</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"έχω τραγουδήσει στις ζούγκλες Hobo, και έχω 
τραγουδήσει για το Rockefellers": Pete Seeger 
Refuses "να τραγουδήσει" για HUAC</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"he cantado en selvas del hobo, y he cantado para 
el Rockefellers": Pete Seeger rechaza "canta" para HUAC</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">During the Cold War era, the House Committee on Un-American Activities (HUAC) interrogated more than 3,000 government officials, labor union leaders, teachers, journalists, entertainers, and others. They wanted to purge Communists, former Communists, and "fellow travelers" who refused to renounce their past and inform on associates from positions of influence within American society. Among the Committee's targets were performers at events held in support of suspect organizations. Pete Seeger acquired a love of American folk music while traveling through the South in the 1930s with his father, a musicologist and classical composer, and as an employee in the Library of Congress' Archive of American Folk Song. As a folksinger motivated by concerns for social justice, cross-cultural communication, and international peace, Seeger performed songs from diverse sources to many kinds of audiences, and in 1948 campaigned for Progressive Party candidate Henry Wallace as part of the folk music organization People's Songs. In the following testimony before HUAC, Seeger refused to invoke the Fifth Amendment, protecting citizens from self-incrimination. Instead he insisted that the Committee had no right to question him regarding his political beliefs or associations. This strategy resulted in prison terms for contempt of Congress for the Hollywood Ten in 1947. Seeger himself was sentenced to a year in prison for contempt, but the verdict was reversed in 1962. Nevertheless, Seeger remained on a network television blacklist until the late 1960s.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während der Ära des kalten Krieges fragte der 
Haus-Ausschuß für Un-Amerikanische Aktivitäten (HUAC) mehr als 
3.000 Regierungsbeamte, Arbeiterverbandführer, Lehrer, Journalisten, 
Unterhalter und andere ab. Sie wollten Kommunisten, ehemalige 
Kommunisten und "Mitreisende" löschen, wer- ablehnte, auf ihre 
Vergangenheit zu verzichten und auf Teilnehmern von den Positionen des
Einflusses innerhalb der amerikanischen Gesellschaft sich zu 
informieren. Unter dem Ausschuß waren die Ziele Ausführende an
den Fällen, die zur Unterstützung der vermutlich defekten 
Organisationen angehalten wurden. Peter Seeger erwarb eine Liebe
der amerikanischen Volksmusik beim Reisen durch den Süden in den 
dreißiger Jahren mit seinem Vater, einem Musikologen und klassischem 
Komponisten und als Angestellten in der Bibliothek des Archivs der 
Kongresse des amerikanischen Volkslieds. Als folksinger, das 
durch Interessen für Sozialgerechtigkeit motiviert wurde, warben 
Kreuz-kulturelle Kommunikation und internationaler Frieden, Seeger 
durchgeführte Liede von den verschiedenen Quellen zu vielen Arten 
Publikum und in 1948 für progressiven Parteianwärterhenry 
Wallace als Teil der Liede der Volksmusikorganisation Leute. Im 
folgenden Zeugnis vor HUAC, lehnte Seeger ab, die fünfte Änderung 
hervorzurufen und schützte Bürger vor Selbst-incrimination. 
Stattdessen beharrte er, daß der Ausschuß kein Recht hatte, 
ihn betreffend seinen politischen Glauben oder Verbindungen zu fragen.
Diese Strategie ergab Gefängnisbezeichnungen für Verachtung 
des Kongresses für das Hollywood 10 1947. Seeger selbst wurde 
zu einem Jahr im Gefängnis für Verachtung verurteilt, aber der 
Urteilsspruch wurde 1962 aufgehoben. Dennoch blieb Seeger auf 
einer Netzfernsehenschwarzen Liste bis die späten sechziger Jahre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant l'ère de guerre froide, le comité de 
Chambre des activités Un-Américaines (HUAC) a interrogé plus de 
3.000 fonctionnaires de gouvernement, amorces de syndicat, 
professeurs, journalistes, amuseurs, et d'autres. Ils ont voulu 
purger des communistes, de anciens communistes, et des "voyageurs de 
camarade" qui a refusé de renoncer à leur passé et d'informer sur 
des associés des positions d'influence chez la société américaine.
Parmi le Comité les cibles étaient des interprètes aux 
événements tenus à l'appui des organismes suspects. Peter 
Seeger a saisi un amour de la musique folklorique américaine tout en 
voyageant par les Sud dans les années 30 avec son père, un 
musicologue et le compositeur classique, et en tant qu'employé dans 
la bibliothèque des archives des congrès de la chanson folklorique 
américaine. Comme folksinger motivé par des soucis pour la 
justice sociale, la transmission croix-culturelle, et la paix 
internationale, les chansons exécutées par Seeger des sources 
diverses à beaucoup de sortes d'assistances, et dans 1948 ont fait 
campagne pour Henry Wallace de candidat de partie progressive en tant 
qu'élément des chansons des personnes d'organisation de musique 
folklorique. Dans le témoignage suivant avant HUAC, Seeger a 
refusé d'appeler le cinquième amendement, protégeant des citoyens 
contre l'auto-incrimination. Au lieu de cela il a insisté sur le fait 
que le Comité n'a eu aucun droit de l'interroger concernant sa 
croyance ou associations politique. Cette stratégie a eu comme 
conséquence des limites de prison pour le mépris du congrès pour 
Hollywood Dix de 1947. Seeger lui-même a été condamné à 
une année en prison pour le mépris, mais le verdict a été 
renversé en 1962. Néanmoins, Seeger est resté sur une liste 
noire de télévision de réseau jusqu'aux années 60 en retard.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Durante a era da guerra fria, o comitê da casa 
nas atividades Un-Americanas (HUAC) interrogated mais de 3.000 
oficiais de governo, líderes da união labor, professores, 
journalists, anfitriões, e outros. Quiseram remover comunistas,
comunistas anteriores, e do "viajantes companheiro" quem recusou 
renunciar seu passado e o informar em associados das posições da 
influência dentro da sociedade americana. Entre o comitê os 
alvos eram performers nos eventos prendidos na sustentação das 
organizações suspeitas. Pete Seeger adquiriu um amor da 
música popular americana ao viajar com o sul nos 1930s com seu pai, 
um musicologist e o compositor classical, e como um empregado na 
biblioteca do arquivo dos congress' da canção popular americana. 
Como um folksinger motivated por interesses para a justiça 
social, uma comunicação cruz-cross-cultural, e a paz internacional, 
as canções executadas Seeger das fontes diversas a muitos tipos das 
audiências, e em 1948 fizeram campanha para o Henry Wallace do 
candidato do partido progressivo como a parte das canções do pessoa 
da organização da música popular. No seguinte testimony antes
de HUAC, Seeger recusou invocar a quinta emenda, protegendo cidadãos 
do self-incrimination-incrimination. Instead insistiu que o 
comitê não teve nenhuma direita o questionar a respeito de suas 
opinião ou associações políticas. Esta estratégia resultou 
em termos da prisão para o contempt de congress para o Hollywood dez 
em 1947. Seeger ele mesmo foi sentenciado a um ano na prisão 
para o contempt, mas o verdict foi invertido em 1962. Não 
obstante, Seeger remanesceu em uma lista negra da televisão da rede 
até os 1960s atrasados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Durante l'era di guerra fredda, il comitato della 
Camera delle attività ONU-Americane (HUAC) ha consultato più di 
3.000 funzionari di governo, i capi di lavoro del sindacato, 
gli insegnanti, i giornalisti, i presentatori ed altri. Hanno 
desiderato eliminare l'inceppo i comunisti, gli ex comunisti e "i 
viaggiatori del collega" chi ha rifiutato di rinunciare alla loro 
esperienza e di informare sui soci dalle posizioni di influenza presso
la società americana. Fra il comitato gli obiettivi erano 
esecutori agli eventi tenuti a sostegno delle organizzazioni sospette.
Pete Seeger ha acquistato un amore di musica di piega americana 
mentre attraversava through il sud nei 1930s con il suo padre, un 
musicologist ed il compositore classico e come impiegato nella 
libreria dell'archivio dei congressi della canzone piega americana. 
Come folksinger motivato dalle preoccupazioni per giustizia 
sociale, la comunicazione traversa-culturale e la pace internazionale,
le canzoni effettuate Seeger dalle sorgenti varie a molti generi dei 
pubblici ed in 1948 hanno fatto una campagna per il henry Wallace del 
candidato del partito progressivo come componente delle canzoni di 
piega di musica della gente di organizzazione. Nella seguente 
testimonianza prima di HUAC, Seeger ha rifiutato di invocare la quinta
correzione, proteggente i cittadini dall'auto-incrimination. 
Invece ha insistito che il comitato non ha avuto destra 
interrogarlo per quanto riguarda la sua credenza o associazioni 
politica. Questa strategia ha provocato i termini della prigione
per contempt del congresso per il Hollywood dieci di 1947. 
Seeger egli stesso è stato sentenziato ad un anno in prigione 
per contempt, ma il verdetto è stato invertito in 1962. 
Tuttavia, Seeger è rimasto su una lista nera della televisione 
della rete fino agli anni 60 tardi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατά τη διάρκεια της εποχής ψυχρού πολέμου, η 
Επιτροπή Βουλών των αντιαμερικανικών δραστηριοτήτων (HUAC) 
ρώτησε περισσότερους από 3.000 κυβερνητικούς ανώτερους 
υπαλλήλους, τους ηγέτες εργατικού συνδικάτου, τους δασκάλους, 
τους δημοσιογράφους, τους διασκεδαστές, και άλλους. Θέλησαν 
να εξαγνίσουν τους κομμουνιστές, τους προηγούμενους κομμουνιστές, 
και τους "συντροφικούς ταξιδιώτεσ" ποιος αρνήθηκε να αρνηθεί 
προηγούμενό τους και να ενημερώσει για τους συνεταίρους από τις 
θέσεις της επιρροής μέσα στην αμερικανική κοινωνία. Μεταξύ
της Επιτροπής οι στόχοι ήταν εκτελεστές στις εκδηλώσεις που 
διοργανώθηκαν υπέρ των ύποπτων οργανώσεων. Pete 
Seeger απόκτησε μια αγάπη της αμερικανικής λαϊκής μουσικής 
διακινούμενο μέσω του νότου στη δεκαετία του '30 με τον πατέρα 
του, έναν μουσικολόγο και έναν κλασσικό συνθέτη, και ως υπάλληλο
στο αρχείο βιβλιοθήκης των συνεδρίων του αμερικανικού λαϊκού 
τραγουδιού. Σαν folksinger που παρακινήθηκε από τις 
ανησυχίες για την κοινωνική δικαιοσύνη, τη διαπολιτισμική 
επικοινωνία, και τη διεθνή ειρήνη, Seeger εκτέλεσε τα 
τραγούδια από τις διαφορετικές πηγές σε πολλά είδη ακροατηρίων,
και το 1948 έκανε εκστρατεία για τον προοδευτικό υποψήφιο 
Henry Wallace συμβαλλόμενου μέρους ως τμήμα των τραγουδιών 
των λαϊκών μουσικής ανθρώπων οργάνωσης. Στην ακόλουθη 
κατάθεση πριν από HUAC, Seeger αρνήθηκε να καλέσει την 
πέμπτη τροποποίηση, που προστατεύει τους πολίτες από την 
μόνος-ενοχοποίηση. Αντ' αυτού επέμεινε ότι η Επιτροπή δεν 
είχε κανένα δικαίωμα να εξετάσει τον σχετικά με τις πολιτικές 
πεποιθήσεις του ή τις ενώσεις. Αυτή η στρατηγική οδήγησε 
στους όρους φυλακών γιατί η περιφρόνηση του συνεδρίου για το 
Hollywood οι Δέκα σε 1947, Seeger ο ίδιος καταδικάστηκε σε
ένα έτος στη φυλακή για την περιφρόνηση, αλλά η απόφαση 
αντιστράφηκε το 1962. Εντούτοις, Seeger παρέμεινε σε 
μια τηλεοπτική μαύρη λίστα δικτύων μέχρι την πρόσφατη δεκαετία 
του '60.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Durante la era de la guerra fría, el comité de 
la casa sobre las actividades Un-Americanas (HUAC) interrogó a más 
de 3.000 oficiales del gobierno, a arranques de cinta del sindicato, a
profesores, a periodistas, a actores, y a otros. Desearon purgar
comunistas, comunistas anteriores, y a "hojas de ruta (traveler) del 
compañero" quién rechazó renunciar su pasado e informar en 
asociados de posiciones de la influencia dentro de la sociedad 
americana. Entre el comité las blancos eran ejecutantes en los 
acontecimientos llevados a cabo en la ayuda de las organizaciones 
sospechadas. Pete Seeger adquirió un amor de la música 
tradicional americana mientras que viajaba con el sur en los años 30 
con su padre, un musicologist y el compositor clásico, y como 
empleado en la biblioteca del archivo de los congresos de la canción 
popular americana. Como folksinger motivado por las 
preocupaciones por justicia social, la comunicación cruz-cultural, y 
la paz internacional, las canciones realizadas Seeger de fuentes 
diversas a muchas clases de audiencias, y en 1948 hicieron campaña 
para el Henrio Wallace del candidato del partido progresivo como parte
de las canciones de la música tradicional de la gente de la 
organización. En el testimonio siguiente antes de HUAC, Seeger 
rechazó invocar la quinto enmienda, protegiendo a ciudadanos contra 
el uno mismo-incrimination. En lugar él insistió que el 
comité no tenía ninguna derecha de preguntarlo con respecto su 
creencia o asociaciones política. Esta estrategia dio lugar a 
los términos de la prisión para el desprecio del congreso para el 
Hollywood diez de 1947. Seeger mismo fue condenado a un año en 
la prisión para el desprecio, pero el veredicto fue invertido en 
1962. Sin embargo, Seeger permanecía en una lista negra de la 
televisión de la red hasta los últimos años 60.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086286</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103133</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-have-sung-in-hobo-jungles-and-i-have-sung-for-the-rockefellers-pete-seeger-refuses-to-sing-for-huac</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
