<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107531</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107531</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211786</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Quahog Development and Growth</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Quahog Entwicklung und Wachstum</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Développement et croissance de Quahog</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Desenvolvimento e crescimento de Quahog</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sviluppo e sviluppo di Quahog</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Quahog εξέλιξη και αύξηση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Desarrollo y crecimiento de Quahog</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Rhode Island Sea Grant page features information regarding growth and development of a specific species (Mercenaria mencenaria) of Quahog, a hard-shell clam. The page begins with information about eggs and fertilization, takes readers through embryonic and larval stages, and concludes with a discussion on clam growth. Links direct users to related Sea Grant informational pages.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Rhode-Insel Seegrant Seite kennzeichnet die 
Informationen betreffend sind Wachstum und Entwicklung einer 
spezifischen Sorte (Mercenaria mencenaria) Quahog, eine Hartshell 
Muschel. Die Seite fängt mit Informationen über Eier und 
Düngung an, nimmt Leser durch die embryonalen und larvalen Stadien 
und folgert mit einer Diskussion auf Muschelwachstum. Links 
verweisen Benutzer auf in Verbindung stehendes Seegrant 
informatorische Seiten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette page de Grant de mer d'île de Rhode comporte 
l'information concernant la croissance et le développement de l'des 
espèces spécifiques (mencenaria de Mercenaria) de Quahog, une 
palourde de dur-interpréteur de commandes interactif. La page 
commence par des informations sur des oeufs et la fertilisation, prend
des lecteurs par les étapes embryonnaires et larvaires, et conclut 
avec une discussion sur la croissance de palourde. Les liens 
dirigent des utilisateurs vers les pages informationnelles de Grant de
mer relative.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta página de Grant do mar do console de Rhode 
caracteriza a informação a respeito do crescimento e do 
desenvolvimento de uma espécie específica (mencenaria de Mercenaria)
de Quahog, uns moluscos do duro-escudo. A página começa com a 
informação sobre ovos e fertilization, faz exame de leitores 
através dos estágios embryonic e larval, e concli-os com uma 
discussão no crescimento dos moluscos. As ligações dirigem 
usuários às páginas informativas de Grant do mar relacionado.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa pagina del Grant del mare dell'Rhode-isola 
caratterizza le informazioni per quanto riguarda sviluppo e sviluppo 
di una specie specifica (mencenaria di Mercenaria) di Quahog, un 
mollusco delle duro-coperture. La pagina comincia con le 
informazioni sulle uova e sulla fertilizzazione, prende i lettori 
attraverso le fasi embrionali e larvali e conclude con una discussione
su sviluppo del mollusco. I collegamenti dirigono gli utenti 
verso le pagine informative del Grant del mare relativo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η σελίδα επιχορήγησης θάλασσας της Ρόδου 
χαρακτηρίζει τις πληροφορίες σχετικά με την αύξηση και την 
εξέλιξη ενός συγκεκριμένου είδους (mencenaria Mercenaria) 
quahog, ένα μαλάκιο σκληρός-κοχυλιών. Η σελίδα αρχίζει 
με τις πληροφορίες για τα αυγά και τη λίπανση, παίρνει τους 
αναγνώστες μέσω των εμβρυικών και λαρβικών σταδίων, και 
ολοκληρώνει με μια συζήτηση σχετικά με την αύξηση μαλακίων. 
Συνδέει τους άμεσους χρήστες με τις σχετικές ενημερωτικές 
σελίδες επιχορήγησης θάλασσας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta paginación de Grant del mar de la Rhode-isla
ofrece la información con respecto crecimiento y al desarrollo de una
especie específica (mencenaria de Mercenaria) de Quahog, una almeja 
del duro-shell. La paginación comienza con la información 
sobre los huevos y la fertilización, toma a programas de lectura a 
través de etapas embrionarias y larvales, y concluye con una 
discusión sobre crecimiento de la almeja. Las conexiones 
dirigen a utilizadores a las paginaciones informativas de Grant del 
mar relacionado.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:RHODE ISLAND SEA GRANT
FN:RHODE ISLAND SEA GRANT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211786</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107531</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/quahog-development-and-growth</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
