<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107863</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107863</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087353</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A Year's Wage for Three Peaches: A Black Man Tells of Exploitation in the Late 19th century South</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lohn eines Jahres für drei Pfirsiche: Ein 
schwarzer Mann erklärt von der Ausnutzung im des späten 19. 
jahrhunderts Jahrhundert Süden</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le salaire d'une année pour trois pêches : 
Un homme noir raconte l'exploitation vers la fin des 19èmes 
Sud de siècle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Salário de um ano para três pêssegos: Um 
homem preto diz da exploração no sul atrasado do 1ø século</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Stipendio dell'anno per tre pesche: Un uomo 
nero dice a di sfruttamento verso la fine di diciannovesimo sud di 
secolo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η αμοιβή ενός έτους για τρία ροδάκινα: Ένα 
μαύρο άτομο λέει της εκμετάλλευσης προς το τέλος του νότου του 
19$ου αιώνα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Salario de un año para tres melocotones: Un
hombre negro dice de la explotación en el sur de la a fines del siglo
XIX</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The harsh brutality of race relations in the late nineteenth-century South was sometimes best expressed through small incidents. For William Robinson, the story that best encapsulated his own experience growing up African-American in rural Georgia in the 1880s involved three peaches. He was interviewed by oral historian Charles Hardy in 1983 when Robinson was 103 years old. Apparently, some ninety-five years earlier when he was eight years old, three black boys sneaked into a peach orchard on the way home from church and stole some peaches, three of which they gave to young Robinson. The white orchard owner caught Robinson and threatened him with the chain gang. He forced Robinson's father to pay $21 for the three peaches--a sum that could well have been a year's cash income for a sharecropping family in this period.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die rauhen Brutalitäten der Rennenrelationen im 
späten 19.-Jahrhundert Süden waren ausgedrückt durch kleine 
Ereignisse manchmal bestes. Für William Robinson, bezog 
Geschichtedieses gut eingekapselt seiner eigenen Erfahrung, die herauf
Afrikanisch-Amerikanisches in landwirtschaftlichem Georgia im 1880s 
wächst, drei Pfirsiche mit ein. Er wurde vom Mundhistoriker 
Charles interviewt, der 1983 robust ist, als Robinson 103 Jahre alt 
war. Anscheinend einige fünfundneunzig Jahre früher, als er 
acht Jahre alt war, schlichen drei schwarze Jungen in einen 
Pfirsichobstgarten auf der Methode nach Hause von der Kirche und 
stahlen einige Pfirsiche, von denen drei sie jungem Robinson gaben. 
Der weiße Obstgarten Inhaber abgefangenes Robinson und bedroht 
ihm mit der Sträflingskolonne. Er erzwang Vater Robinsons, $21 
für die drei Pfirsiche zu zahlen -- eine Summe, die hervorquellen 
könnte, sind Bareinnahme eines Jahres für eine Sharecroppingfamilie 
in dieser Periode gewesen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La brutalité dure des relations inter-raciales 
vers la fin des Sud de dix-neuvième-siècle était parfois 
meilleure exprimée par de petits incidents. Pour William 
Robinson, le ce d'histoire mieux encapsulé sa propre expérience 
accroissant vers le haut de l'Afro-Américain en Géorgie rurale dans le 
1880s a impliqué trois pêches. Il a été interviewé par 
l'historien oral Charles robuste en 1983 où Robinson avait 103 ans. 
Apparemment, environ quatre-vingt-quinze années plus tôt quand
il avait huit ans, trois garçons noirs ont parti furtivement dans un 
verger de pêche sur le chemin à la maison de l'église et ont volé 
quelques pêches, dont trois ils ont donné à jeune Robinson. 
Le propriétaire blanc de verger a attrapé Robinson et l'a 
menacé par la troupe à chaînes. Il a forcé le père de 
Robinson à payer $21 les trois pêches -- une somme qui pourrait 
jaillir ont été le revenu en espèces d'une année pour une famille 
de métayage dans cette période.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O brutality áspero de relações de raça no sul 
atrasado de décimo-século era às vezes o mais melhor expressado com
os incidents pequenos. Para William Robinson, o esse da 
história encapsulated melhor sua própria experiência que cresce 
acima de Africano-Americano em Geórgia rural no 1880s envolveu três 
pêssegos. Foi entrevistado pelo historian oral Charles hardy em
1983 em que Robinson tinha 103 anos velho. Aparentemente, uns 
ninety-five anos mais adiantados quando tinha oito anos velho, três 
meninos pretos sneaked em um pomar do pêssego na maneira para casa da
igreja e roubaram alguns pêssegos, três de que eles deram a Robinson
novo. O pomar branco Robinson travado proprietário e ameaçado 
lhe com o grupo chain. Forçou o pai de Robinson a pagar $21 
pelos três pêssegos -- uma soma que poderia jorrar foi renda de 
dinheiro de um ano para uma família do sharecropping neste período.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il brutality duro dei rapporti di corsa verso la 
fine di sud di diciannovesimo-secolo era a volte la cosa migliore 
espresso con i piccoli avvenimenti. Per William Robinson, il 
quel di storia il più bene incapsulato la sua propria esperienza che 
cresce su Africano-Americano nella Georgia rurale nel 1880s ha 
coinvolto tre pesche. È stato intervistato dallo storico orale 
Charles hardy in 1983 in cui Robinson aveva 103 anni. 
Apparentemente, circa novantacinque anni più in anticipo quando
aveva otto anni, tre ragazzi neri sneaked in un frutteto della pesca 
sul modo a casa dalla chiesa ed hanno rubato alcune pesche, tre di cui
hanno dato a Robinson giovane. Il proprietario bianco del 
frutteto ha interferito Robinson e lo ha minacciato per il gruppo 
chain. Ha forzato il padre del Robinson pagare $21 le tre pesche
-- una somma che potrebbe scaturire è stata reddito in denaro 
dell'anno per una famiglia di mezzadria in questo periodo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η σκληρή βιαιότητα των φυλετικών σχέσεων προς το 
τέλος του νότου δέκατος-αιώνα μερικές φορές καλύτερα 
εκφράστηκε μέσω των μικρών γεγονότων. Για William 
Robinson, η ιστορία που τοποθέτησε καλύτερα την εμπειρία του σε
κάψα που μεγαλώνει αφρικανικός-Αμερικανό στην αγροτική Γεωργία 
στο 1880s περιέλαβε τρία ροδάκινα. Πέρασε από 
συνέντευξη από τον προφορικό ιστορικό Charles Hardy το 
1983 όταν Robinson ήταν 103 ετών. Προφανώς, 
περίπου ενενήντα πέντε έτη νωρίτερα όταν ήταν οκτώ ετών, 
τρία μαύρα αγόρια γλίστρησαν σε έναν οπωρώνα ροδακινιών στον 
τρόπο το σπίτι από την εκκλησία και έκλεψαν μερικά ροδάκινα, 
τρία από τα οποία αυτοί έδωσαν σε νέο Robinson. Ο 
λευκός ιδιοκτήτης οπωρώνων επίασε Robinson και τον απείλησε με
τη συμμορία αλυσίδων. Ανάγκασε τον πατέρα Robinson για να
πληρώσει $21 για τα τρία ροδάκινα -- ένα ποσό που θα μπορούσε
καλά να είναι το εισόδημα μετρητών ενός έτους για μια 
sharecropping οικογένεια σε αυτήν την περίοδο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La brutalidad áspera de las relaciones de raza en
el último sur del diecinueveavo-siglo era a veces la mejor expresada 
con incidentes pequeños. Para Guillermo Robinson, el ese de la 
historia lo más mejor posible encapsulado su propia experiencia que 
crecía encima de Africano-Americano en Georgia rural en el 1880s 
implicó tres melocotones. Él fue entrevistado con por el 
historiador oral Charles robusto en 1983 en que Robinson era 103 años
de viejo. Al parecer, unos noventa y cinco años anteriores 
cuando él era ocho años de viejo, tres muchachos negros hicieron 
furtivamente en una huerta del melocotón en la manera a casa de 
iglesia y robaron algunos melocotones, tres de los cuales ellos dieron
a Robinson joven. La huerta blanca Robinson cogido propietario y
amenazado le con la cuadrilla de cadena. Él forzó a padre de 
Robinson pagar $21 los tres melocotones -- una suma que podría manar 
ha sido ingresos en efectivo de un año para una familia de la 
aparcería en este período.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087353</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107863</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-years-wage-for-three-peaches-a-black-man-tells-of-exploitation-in-the-late-19th-century-south</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
