<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107024</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107024</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086927</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Depression has Changed People's Outlook": The Beuschers Remember the Great Depression in Dubuque, Iowa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"der Tiefstand hat Aussicht der Leute" geändert: 
Das Beuschers erinnern sich den an großen Tiefstand in Dubuque,
Iowa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"la dépression a changé les perspectives des 
personnes" : Le Beuschers se rappellent la grande dépression 
dans Dubuque, Iowa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"o depression mudou o outlook do pessoa": O 
Beuschers recorda o depression grande em Dubuque, Iowa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la depressione ha cambiato la prospettiva della 
gente": Il Beuschers si ricorda della depressione grande in 
Dubuque, Iowa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η κατάθλιψη έχει αλλάξει την προοπτική των 
ανθρώπων": Το Beuschers θυμάται τη μεγάλη οικονομική 
κρίση σε Dubuque, Iowa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"la depresión ha cambiado la perspectiva de la 
gente": El Beuschers recuerda la gran depresión en Dubuque, 
Iowa</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Before the Great Depression of the 1930's the Beuschers--he was a sixty-two-year-old railroad worker; she was the mother of their eleven children--had been fairly prosperous: they owned their home and had several life-insurance policies serving as savings. But by the time the Works Progress Administration (WPA) interviewed them in 1937, their lives had dramatically changed: the father had lost his railroad job and the mother was taking in sewing. This interview summary, published by the WPA, showed how they struggled to make ends meet during The Great Depression.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Vor dem großen Tiefstand der dreißiger Jahre das
Beuschers -- er war ein sechzig-zwei-Jahr-alter Eisenbahnarbeiter; 
sie war die Mutter ihrer elf Kinder -- war ziemlich wohlhabend 
gewesen: sie besassen ihr Haus und hatten einige 
Lebensdauer-Versicherung politische Richtlinien, als Sparungen zu 
dienen. Aber, bis die Arbeiten Fortschritt-Leitung (WPA) sie 
1937 interviewte, hatten ihre Lebensdauern drastisch geändert: 
der Vater hatte seinen Eisenbahnjob verloren und die Mutter nahm
beim Nähen. Diese Interviewzusammenfassung, veröffentlicht 
durch das WPA, zeigte, wie sie kämpften, um Enden während des 
großen Tiefstands treffen zu lassen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Avant la grande dépression des années 30 le 
Beuschers -- il était un soixante-deux-année-vieil ouvrier de chemin
de fer ; elle était la mère de leurs onze enfants -- avait 
été assez prospère : ils ont possédé leur maison et ont eu 
plusieurs politiques de vie-assurance servir d'épargne. Mais 
avant que la gestion d'avancement de travaux (WPA) les ait 
interviewés en 1937, leurs vies avaient excessivement changé : 
le père avait détruit son travail de chemin de fer et la mère
prenait dans la couture. Ce sommaire d'entrevue, édité par le 
WPA, a montré comment ils ont lutté pour faire des extrémités se 
réunir pendant la grande dépression.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Antes do depression grande dos 1930's o Beuschers 
-- era um trabalhador sessenta-dois-ano-velho da estrada de ferro; 
era a matriz de suas onze crianças -- tinha sido razoavelmente 
próspero: possuíram sua HOME e tiveram diversas políticas do 
vida-seguro servir como economias. Mas pelo tempo onde a 
administração do progresso de trabalhos (WPA) os entrevistou em 
1937, suas vidas tinha mudado dramàtica: o pai tinha perdido 
seu trabalho da estrada de ferro e a matriz estava fazendo exame em 
sewing. Este sumário da entrevista, publicado pelo WPA, mostrou
como se esforçaram para fazer extremidades se encontrar com durante o
depression grande.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Prima della depressione grande dei 1930's il 
Beuschers -- era un sessanta-due-anno-vecchio operaio della ferrovia; 
era la madre dei loro undici bambini -- era stato 
ragionevolmente prosperoso: hanno posseduto la loro sede ed 
hanno avuti parecchie politiche di vita-assicurazione servire da 
risparmio. Ma per il momento in cui la gestione di progresso 
degli impianti (WPA) lo intervistasse in 1937, le loro vite erano 
cambiato drammaticamente: il padre aveva perso il suo lavoro 
della ferrovia e la madre stava prendendo nel cucito. Questo 
sommario di intervista, pubblicato dal WPA, ha mostrato come hanno 
lottato per fare le estremità venire a contatto di durante la 
depressione grande.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πριν από τη μεγάλη οικονομική κρίση της δεκαετίας του
'30 το Beuschers -- ήταν εξήντα-δύο-χρονών 
εργαζόμενος σιδηροδρόμου  ήταν η μητέρα ένδεκα παιδιών 
τους -- ήταν αρκετά ακμάζων: ήταν κύριοι του σπιτιού τους 
και είχαν διάφορες ζωή-ασφαλιστικές πολιτικές που χρησιμεύουν ως
η αποταμίευση. Αλλά ώσπου να τους πήρε συνέντευξη από η 
διοίκηση προόδου εργασιών (WPA) το 1937, οι ζωές τους είχαν
αλλάξει εντυπωσιακά: ο πατέρας είχε χάσει την εργασία 
σιδηροδρόμου του και η μητέρα έπαιρνε στο ράψιμο. Αυτή η 
περίληψη συνέντευξης, που δημοσιεύθηκε από το WPA, επέδειξε 
πώς αγωνίστηκαν να κάνουν τις άκρες να συναντηθούν κατά τη 
διάρκεια της μεγάλης οικονομικής κρίσης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Antes de la gran depresión de los años 30 el 
Beuschers -- él era sesenta-dos-año-viejo trabajador del 
ferrocarril; ella era la madre de sus once niños -- había sido
bastante próspero: poseyeron su hogar y tenían varias 
políticas del vida-seguro el servir como ahorros. Pero para el 
momento en que la administración del progreso de trabajos (WPA) se 
entrevistara con los en 1937, sus vidas habían cambiado 
dramáticamente: el padre había perdido su trabajo del 
ferrocarril y la madre tomaba en la costura. Este resumen de la 
entrevista, publicado por el WPA, mostró cómo lucharon para hacer 
que los extremos satisfacen durante la gran depresión.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086927</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107024</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-depression-has-changed-peoples-outlook-the-beuschers-remember-the-great-depression-in-dubuque-iowa</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
