<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108703</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108703</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087411</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"As They Had Been in Ancient Times": Pedro Naranjo Relates the Pueblo Revolt, 1680</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"wie sie in den alten Zeiten" gewesen waren: 
Pedro Naranjo steht den Pueblo-Aufruhr, 1680 in Verbindung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"comme elles avaient été dans des périodes 
antiques" : Pedro Naranjo associe la révolte de pueblo, 1680</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"como se tinham realizado em épocas antigas": 
Pedro Naranjo relaciona a revolta do povoado indígino, 1680</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"come avevano avute luogo nei periodi antichi": 
Pedro Naranjo collega la sommossa del pueblo, 1680</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Δεδομένου ότι ήταν στους αρχαίους χρόνουσ": 
Θ*Πεδρο Naranjo Relates η Pueblo επανάσταση, 1680</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"como habían sido en épocas antiguas": 
Pedro Naranjo relaciona la rebelión del pueblo, 1680</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the late 17th-century, Spain's empire in the Americas extended north to New Mexico, Texas, Arizona, and California, where Spanish soldiers, settlers, and missionaries began to settle. The missionaries resettled the indigenous Pueblo people into peasant communities, building forts and missions to subdue and convert them to Catholicism. The New Mexico Pueblo people resisted Spanish conversion efforts and forced labor demands. Their sporadic resistance became a concerted rebellion in 1680 under the leadership of the charismatic El Pope. The revolt was the most successful of Native American efforts to turn back European colonists, and for over a decade the Pueblos were free from intrusion. But in 1690 the Pueblos were weakened by drought and Apache and Comanche raiders from the north. Spain retook territory and interrogated and punished the rebels in their "reconquest" of the Pueblo. A Keresan Pueblo man called Pedro Naranjo offered his view of the rebellion and its causes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im späten 17th-century dehnte sich Reich Spaniens
im Amerika nördlich auf New-Mexico, Texas, Arizona und Kalifornien 
aus, in dem spanische Soldaten, Siedleren und Missionare anfingen 
abzurechnen. Die Missionare stellten die eingeborenen 
Pueblovölker in ländliche Gemeinschaften, in aufbauende Forts und in
Missionen wieder her, um sie in Katholizismus zu überwinden und 
umzuwandeln. Die New-Mexico Puebloleute widerstanden spanischen 
Konvertierung Bemühungen und erzwangen Arbeitsnachfragen. Ihr 
sporadischer Widerstand wurde ein beratener Aufstand in 1680 unter der
Führung des charismatischen EL Papstes. Der Aufruhr war der 
gebürtigen amerikanischen Bemühungen, europäische Kolonisten 
zurück zu drehen das erfolgreichste, und für über eine Dekade waren
die Pueblos vom Eindringen frei. Aber in 1690 wurden die Pueblos
durch Dürre und Apache und Komancheräuber vom Norden geschwächt. 
Spanien nahm Gegend wieder zurück und fragte ab und bestrafte 
die Aufrührer in ihrer "Zurückeroberung" des Pueblos. Ein 
Keresan Pueblo Mann angerufener Pedro Naranjo bot seine Ansicht des 
Aufstands und seiner Ursachen an.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Vers la fin de 17th-century, l'empire de l'Espagne
en Amériques a étendu au nord au Nouveau-Mexique, le Texas, en 
Arizona, et la Californie, où les soldats, les colons, et les 
missionnaires espagnols ont commencé à solder le compte. Les 
missionnaires ont reclassé le peuple autochtone de pueblo dans les 
communautés rurales, les forts de construction et les missions pour 
les soumettre et convertir en catholicisme. Les personnes de 
pueblo du Nouveau-Mexique ont résisté à des efforts espagnols de 
conversion et ont forcé des demandes de travail. Leur 
résistance sporadique est devenue une rébellion concertée dans 1680
sous la conduite du pape charismatique de EL. La révolte était
la plus réussie des efforts américains indigènes de tourner en 
arrière les colons européens, et pendant plus d'une décennie les 
pueblos étaient exempts de l'intrusion. Mais dans 1690 les 
pueblos ont été affaiblis par sécheresse et Apache et voleurs 
de Comanche du nord. l'Espagne a repris le territoire et a 
interrogé et a puni les rebelles dans leur "reconquête" du pueblo. 
Un pueblo Pedro Naranjo appelé par homme de Keresan a offert sa
vue de la rébellion et de ses causes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No 17th-century atrasado, o império de Spain nos 
Americas estendeu para o norte a Novo México, a Texas, a arizona, e a
Califórnia, onde os soldados, os settlers, e os missionários 
espanhóis começaram a se estabelecir. Os missionários 
resettled os povos indígenos do povoado indígino em comunidades 
peasant, em forts construindo e em missões para subdue e 
convertê-los ao catholicism. Os povos do povoado indígino de 
Novo México resistiram esforços espanhóis da conversão e forçaram
demandas labor. Sua resistência esporádica transformou-se uma 
rebelião concerted em 1680 sob a liderança do papa charismatic do 
EL. A revolta era a mais bem sucedida de esforços americanos 
nativos girar para trás colonos europeus, e por sobre uma década os 
povoados indíginos estavam livres do intrusion. Mas em 1690 os 
povoados indíginos foram enfraquecidos pela seca e pelos incursores 
de Apache e de comanche do norte. Spain retomou o território e 
interrogated e puniu os rebels em seu "reconquest" do povoado 
indígino. Um povoado indígino Pedro chamado homem Naranjo de 
Keresan ofereceu sua vista da rebelião e de suas causas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Verso la fine di 17th-century, l'impero della 
Spagna nei Americas si è esteso a nord nel Nuovo Messico, il Texas, 
in Arizona e la California, in cui i soldati, i settlers ed i 
missionari spagnoli hanno cominciato a depositarsi. I 
missionari hanno riassestato la gente indigena del pueblo nelle 
Comunità agricole, nei forts di costruzione e nelle missioni per 
sottometterli e convertire in catholicism. La gente del pueblo 
del Nuovo Messico ha resistito agli sforzi spagnoli di conversione ed 
ha forzato le richieste di lavoro. La loro resistenza sporadica
si è transformata in in una ribellione concordata in 1680 sotto la 
direzione del papa charismatic di EL. La sommossa riusciva il 
più degli sforzi americani natali girare indietro i colonizzatori 
europei e per sopra una decade i pueblos erano esenti dall'intrusione.
Ma in 1690 i pueblos sono stati indeboliti dalla siccità e dai 
raiders del comanche e del Apache dal nord. La Spagna ha ripreso
il territorio ed ha consultato e punito i ribelli nella loro 
"riconquista" del pueblo. Un pueblo Pedro Naranjo chiamato uomo 
di Keresan ha offerto il suo punto di vista della ribellione e delle
relative cause.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Προς το τέλος του 17$ος-αιώνα, η αυτοκρατορία της 
Ισπανίας στην Αμερική επέκτεινε το Βορρά στο New Mexico, το 
Τέξας, την Αριζόνα, και Καλιφόρνια, όπου οι ισπανικοί 
στρατιώτες, οι άποικοι, και οι ιεραπόστολοι άρχισαν να 
εγκαθιστούν. Οι ιεραπόστολοι ηπανεγκατάστησαν τους γηγενείς 
ανθρώπους Pueblo στις κοινότητες αγροτών, τα οχυρά οικοδόμησης
και τις αποστολές για να τους κατακτήσουν και να μετατρέψουν στον 
καθολικισμό. Οι άνθρωποι του New Mexico Pueblo 
αντιστάθηκαν στις ισπανικές προσπάθειες μετατροπής και ανάγκασαν 
τη ζήτηση εργασίας. Η σποραδική αντίστασή τους έγινε μια 
κοινή εξέγερση το 1680 κάτω από την ηγεσία του χαρισματικού 
παπά EL. Η επανάσταση ήταν η επιτυχέστερη των εγγενών 
αμερικανικών προσπαθειών να γυριστούν πίσω οι ευρωπαϊκοί 
άποικοι, και για κατά τη διάρκεια μιας δεκαετίας το Pueblos 
ήταν απαλλαγμένο από την παρείσφρυση. Αλλά το 1690 το 
Pueblos αποδυναμώθηκε από την ξηρασία και τους επιδρομείς 
Apache και Comanche από το Βορρά. Η Ισπανία ξαναπήρε 
το έδαφος και ρώτησε και τιμώρησε τους επαναστάτες "reconquest 
τουσ" του Pueblo. Ένα Keresan Pueblo αποκαλούμενος ο 
άτομο Pedro Naranjo πρόσφερε την όψη του της εξέγερσης και 
αιτιών του.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En el último 17th-century, el imperio de España 
en las Américas extendió al norte a New México, a Tejas, al 
Arizona, y a California, en donde los soldados, los colonos, y los 
misionarios españoles comenzaron a colocar. Los misionarios 
restablecieron a gente indígena del pueblo en comunidades campesinas,
fortalezas constructivas y misiones para someterlas y para convertir 
al catholicism. La gente del pueblo de New México se opuso a 
esfuerzos españoles de la conversión y forzó demandas de trabajo. 
Su resistencia esporádica se convirtió en una rebelión 
concertada en 1680 bajo dirección del papa carismático del EL. 
La rebelión era la más acertada de esfuerzos americanos 
nativos de dar vuelta detrás a colonos europeos, y por sobre una 
década los pueblos estaban libres de la intrusión. Pero en 
1690 los pueblos fueron debilitados por sequía y los raiders de 
Apache y del comanche del norte. España volvió a tomar el 
territorio e interrogó y castigó a rebeldes en su "reconquista" del 
pueblo. Un pueblo Pedro llamado hombre Naranjo de Keresan 
ofreció su opinión de la rebelión y de sus causas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087411</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108703</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/as-they-had-been-in-ancient-times-pedro-naranjo-relates-the-pueblo-revolt-1680</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
