<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105365</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105365</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206207</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Action Bioscience</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Tätigkeit Bioscience</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Biosciences d'action</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ação Bioscience</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Azione Bioscience</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βιοεπιστήμες ενέργειας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Acción Bioscience</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">offers scientific articles and lessons. Topics include the value of a garden, plant genebanks, bacteria (friend or foe?), biodiversity, real-life aliens (introduced species), apes, ecosystems, global warming, forest canopies, deforestation, water, genetic research, biotechnology, genetically modified foods, ancestry of modern people, microbes, evolution, DNA, how new species form, extinction, and more. Articles and lessons are correlated with academic standards.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">wissenschaftliche Artikel und Lektionen der 
Angebote. Themen schließen den Wert eines Gartens, 
Betriebsgenebanks, Bakterium ein (Freund oder Feind?), 
Biodiversity, real-life Ausländer (eingeführte Sorte), Affen, 
Oekosysteme, globales Wärmen, Waldhimmel, Abholzung, Wasser, 
genetische Forschung, Biotechnologie, änderte genetisch 
Nahrungsmittel, Geschlecht der modernen Leute, Mikroben, Entwicklung, 
DNA, wie neue Sorten sich bilden, Löschung und mehr. Artikel 
und Lektionen werden mit akademischen Standards aufeinander bezogen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">articles et leçons scientifiques d'offres. 
Les sujets incluent la valeur d'un jardin, genebanks d'usine, 
bactéries (ami ou ennemi ?), la biodiversité, étrangers 
réels (espèces présentées), singes, écosystèmes, chauffage 
global, voûtes de forêt, déboisement, l'eau, recherche génétique,
biotechnologie, a génétiquement modifié des nourritures, 
l'ascendance des personnes modernes, des microbes, l'évolution, 
l'ADN, comment les nouvelles espèces forment, l'extinction, et 
plus. Des articles et les leçons sont corrélés avec des 
normes d'universitaire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">artigos e lições científicos das ofertas. 
Os tópicos incluem o valor de um jardim, genebanks da planta, 
bactérias (amigo ou o foe?), o biodiversity, estrangeiros 
real-life (espécie introduzida), macacos, ecosystems, aquecer-se 
global, dosseis de floresta, deforestation, água, pesquisa genetic, 
biotechnology, modificou genetically alimentos, ancestry de povos 
modernos, micróbios, evolução, DNA, como as espécies novas dão 
forma, extinção, e mais. Os artigos e as lições são 
correlacionados com os padrões academic.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">articoli e lezioni scientifici di offerte. I 
soggetti includono il valore di un giardino, genebanks della pianta, 
batteri (amico o nemico?), il biodiversity, stranieri in 
vivo (specie introdotta), scimmie, ecosistemi, riscaldamento globale, 
volte di foresta, disboscamento, acqua, ricerca genetica, la 
biotecnologia, geneticamente ha modificato gli alimenti, l'ascendenza 
della gente moderna, i microbi, lo sviluppo, il DNA, come le nuove 
specie formano, l'estinzione e più. Gli articoli e le lezioni 
sono correlati con gli standard accademici.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">επιστημονικά άρθρα και μαθήματα προσφορών. Τα 
θέματα περιλαμβάνουν την αξία ενός κήπου, εγκαταστάσεις 
genebanks, βακτηρίδια (φίλος ή εχθρός;), η 
βιοποικιλότητα, πραγματικοί αλλοδαποί (εισαχθέντα είδη), 
πίθηκοι, οικοσυστήματα, παγκόσμια αύξηση της θερμοκρασίας λόγω 
του φαινομένου του θερμοκηπίου, δασικοί θόλοι, αποδάσωση, ύδωρ, 
γενετική έρευνα, βιοτεχνολογία, τροποποίησε γενετικά τα τρόφιμα,
καταγωγή των σύγχρονων ανθρώπων, μικρόβια, εξέλιξη, DNA, πώς 
τα νέα είδη διαμορφώνουν, εξάλειψη, και περισσότεροι. Τα 
άρθρα και τα μαθήματα συσχετίζονται με τα ακαδημαϊκά πρότυπα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">artículos y lecciones científicos de las ofertas.
Los asuntos incluyen el valor de un jardín, genebanks de la 
planta, bacterias (amigo o el enemigo?), la biodiversidad, 
extranjeros de la vida real (especie introducida), monos, ecosistemas,
el calentarse global, pabellones de bosque, tala de árboles, agua, 
investigación genética, biotecnología, genético modificó los 
alimentos, ascendencia de la gente moderna, microbios, la evolución, 
la DNA, cómo las nuevas especies forman, la extinción, y más. 
Los artículos y las lecciones se correlacionan con estándares 
académicos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206207</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105365</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/action-bioscience</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
