<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107488</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107488</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206807</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">VRoma Project</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">VRoma Projekt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Projet de VRoma</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Projeto De VRoma</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Progetto VRoma</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">VRoma πρόγραμμα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Proyecto De VRoma</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a community of teachers and students who help to create online resources for teaching Latin and ancient Roman culture and who use these resources in their courses. Students and instructors can interact live and share resources for the study of the ancient world.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist eine Gemeinschaft der Lehrer und 
Kursteilnehmer, die helfen, Onlinebetriebsmittel für das Unterrichten
der lateinischen und alten römischen Kultur zu erstellen und die 
diese Betriebsmittel in ihren Kursen benutzen. Kursteilnehmer 
und Ausbilder können zusammenwirken Phasen- und Anteilbetriebsmittel 
für die Studie der alten Welt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est une communauté des professeurs et les 
étudiants qui aident à créer les ressources en ligne pour enseigner
la culture romaine latine et antique et qui utilisent ces ressources 
dans leurs cours. Les étudiants et les instructeurs peuvent 
agir l'un sur l'autre les ressources de phase et de part pour l'étude
du monde antique.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">são uma comunidade dos professores e os 
estudantes que ajudam criar recursos em linha para ensinar a cultura 
roman latin e antiga e que usam estes recursos em seus cursos. 
Os estudantes e os instrutores podem interagir recursos vivos e 
da parte para o estudo do mundo antigo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è una Comunità degli insegnanti e gli allievi 
che contribuiscono a creare le risorse in linea per l'istruzione della
coltura romana latina ed antica e che usano queste risorse nei loro 
corsi. Gli allievi e gli istruttori possono interagirsi risorse 
della parte ed in tensione per lo studio del mondo antico.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι κοινότητα των δασκάλων και των σπουδαστών που 
βοηθούν να δημιουργήσουν τα σε απευθείας σύνδεση στοιχεία 
συμπεριφοράς για το λατινικό και αρχαίο ρωμαϊκό πολιτισμό 
διδασκαλίας και που χρησιμοποιούν αυτά τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς 
στις σειρές μαθημάτων τους. Οι σπουδαστές και οι 
εκπαιδευτικοί μπορούν να αλληλεπιδράσουν ζωντανά και στοιχεία 
συμπεριφοράς μεριδίου για τη μελέτη του αρχαίου κόσμου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es una comunidad de profesores y los estudiantes 
que ayudan a crear los recursos en línea para enseñar la cultura 
romana latina y antigua y que utilizan estos recursos en sus cursos. 
Los estudiantes y los instructores pueden obrar recíprocamente 
los recursos vivos y de la parte para el estudio del mundo antiguo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206807</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107488</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/vroma-project</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
