<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103206</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103206</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202779</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Percent Problem Solving</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Prozente Lösen- von Problemen$$ln</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pour cent de Résolution des problèmes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Por cento Resolver De Problema</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Percento Di Soluzione dei problemi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τοις εκατό επίλυσης προβλήματος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Por ciento Solucionar De Problema</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Students apply their knowledge of fractions, decimals, and percents to understand the relationship amongst the three. Students will solve basic percent number problems using the percent proportion or other methods and play a game using a resource of the Shodor Education Foundation, Inc. Permission has been granted to use the materials as part of the Interactivate Your Bored Math Students workshop. Students will also analyze and explain the results of their game by answering two exploration questions.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kursteilnehmer wenden ihr Wissen der Brüche, der 
Dezimalstriche und der Prozente an, um das Verhältnis unter den drei 
zu verstehen. Kursteilnehmer lösen grundlegende 
Prozentzahlprobleme mit dem Prozentanteil, oder andere Methoden und 
ein Spiel mit einem Hilfsmittel von zu spielen Shodor Education 
Foundation, Inc. Erlaubnis ist bewilligt worden, um die Materialien 
als Teil des Interactivate zu benutzen Ihre gebohrte 
Mathe-Kursteilnehmerwerkstatt. Kursteilnehmer auch analysieren 
und erklären die Resultate ihres Spiels durch das Beantworten von von
zwei Erforschungfragen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les étudiants appliquent leur connaissance des 
fractions, des décimales, et des pour cent pour comprendre le rapport
parmi les trois. Les étudiants résoudront des problèmes de 
base de nombre de pour cent en utilisant la proportion de pour cent ou
d'autres méthodes et jouer un jeu en utilisant une ressource de 
permission de Shodor Education Foundation, Inc. a été accordées 
pour utiliser les matériaux en tant qu'élément de l'Interactivate 
votre atelier alésé d'étudiants de maths. Les étudiants 
également analyseront et expliqueront les résultats de leur jeu en 
répondant à deux questions d'exploration.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os estudantes aplicam seu conhecimento das 
frações, dos decimais, e dos por cento para compreender o 
relacionamento amongst os três. Os estudantes resolverão 
problemas básicos do número dos por cento usando a proporção dos 
por cento ou outros métodos e para jogar um jogo usando um recurso do
permissão de Shodor Instrução Fundação, Inc. foram concedidos 
para usar os materiais como a parte do Interactivate sua oficina 
furada dos estudantes do math. Os estudantes também analisarão
e explicarão os resultados de seu jogo respondendo a duas perguntas 
da exploração.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli allievi applicano la loro conoscenza delle 
frazioni, dei decimali e dei percento per capire il rapporto fra i 
tre. Gli allievi risolveranno i problemi di base di numero di 
percento usando la proporzione di percento o altri metodi e giocare un
gioco usando una risorsa del permesso di Shodor Education Foundation, 
Inc. è stato assegnato per usare i materiali come componente del 
Interactivate il vostro gruppo di lavoro alesato degli allievi di per 
la matematica. Gli allievi egualmente analizzeranno e 
spiegheranno i risultati del loro gioco rispondendo a due domande di 
esplorazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι σπουδαστές εφαρμόζουν τη γνώση μερών τους, 
δεκαδικά, και percents για να καταλάβουν τη σχέση μεταξύ των 
τριών. Οι σπουδαστές θα λύσουν τα βασικά προβλήματα 
αριθμού τοις εκατό χρησιμοποιώντας την αναλογία τοις εκατό ή 
άλλες μέθοδοι και να παίξουν ένα παιχνίδι που χρησιμοποιεί ένα 
στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς του ιδρύματος εκπαίδευσης Shodor, 
δικαιοδοσία Α.Ε. έχουν χορηγηθεί για να χρησιμοποιήσουν τα υλικά 
ως τμήμα του Interactivate το τρυπημένο εργαστήριο σπουδαστών 
Math σας. Οι σπουδαστές θα αναλύσουν επίσης και θα 
εξηγήσουν τα αποτελέσματα του παιχνιδιού τους με την απάντηση δύο
ερωτήσεων εξερεύνησης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los estudiantes aplican su conocimiento de 
fracciones, de decimales, y de por ciento para entender el lazo entre 
los tres. Los estudiantes solucionarán problemas básicos del 
número de los por ciento usando la proporción de los por ciento u 
otros métodos y jugar un juego usando un recurso del permiso de 
Shodor Education Foundation, Inc. se han concedido para utilizar los 
materiales como parte del Interactivate su taller agujereado de los 
estudiantes de la matemáticas. Los estudiantes también 
analizarán y explicarán los resultados de su juego contestando a dos
preguntas de la exploración.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:VICTORIA LUNETTA
FN:VICTORIA LUNETTA
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202779</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103206</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/percent-problem-solving</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
