<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106699</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106699</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202766</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Setting and Symbolism in A Doll's House</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Einstellung und Symbolismus im Haus einer Puppe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Configuration et symbolisme dans la Chambre d'une 
poupée</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ajuste e simbolismo na casa de uma boneca</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Regolazione e symbolism nella Camera della 
bambola</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τιμή τών παραμέτρων και συμβολισμός στο σπίτι μιας 
κούκλας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Configuración y simbolismo en la casa de una 
muñeca</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This lesson is designed as a follow-up to the reading and discussion of the play "A Doll's House" by Henrik Ibsen. An understanding of the two literary terms setting and symbolism, and their impact on a work of literature, are essential to students' success in following the guidelines outlined in the North Carolina English Language Arts Standard Course of Study. This lesson has been modified for English Language Learners at the intermediate high proficiency level, but would also be adaptable for learners at the novice or advanced levels.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Lektion wird als Anschluß zum Messwert und 
zur Diskussion über das Spiel "das Haus der Puppe" von Henrik Ibsen 
konzipiert. Ein Verständnis der zwei literarischen die 
Bezeichnungen Einstellung und des Symbolismus und ihre Auswirkung auf 
eine Arbeit der Literatur, sind zum Erfolg der Kursteilnehmer 
wesentlich, wenn man den Korrekturlinien folgt, die im Nord-Carolina 
englische Sprachenkunst-Standardbildungsweg umrissen werden. 
Diese Lektion ist für englische Sprachenanfänger auf der hohen
Leistungsfähigkeitzwischenstufe geändert worden, aber würde auch 
für Anfänger am Anfänger oder an den hochentwickelten Stufen 
anpassungsfähig sein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette leçon est conçue comme suivi à la lecture
et à la discussion du jeu "la Chambre de la poupée" par Henrik 
Ibsen. Un arrangement des deux réglages et symbolismux 
littéraires des limites, et leur impact sur un travail de la 
littérature, sont essentiels au succès des étudiants en suivant les
directives tracées les grandes lignes dans le cours de la Caroline 
d'arts du nord d'anglais de l'étude standard. Cette leçon 
a été modifiée pour des étudiants d'anglais au niveau élevé 
intermédiaire de compétence, mais serait également adaptable pour 
des étudiants au débutant ou aux niveaux avançés.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta lição é projetada como uma continuação 
à leitura e à discussão casa do jogo "da boneca" por Henrik Ibsen. 
Uma compreensão de dois ajustes e simbolismos literários dos 
termos, e seu impacto em um trabalho da literatura, são essenciais ao
sucesso dos estudantes em seguir os guidelines esboçados no curso das
artes da língua inglesa de North.carolina de estudo padrão. 
Esta lição foi modificada para learners de língua inglesa no 
nível elevado intermediário da proficiência, mas seria também 
adaptable para learners no novice ou nos níveis avançados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa lezione è progettata come aggiornamento 
alla lettura ed alla discussione Camera sul gioco "della bambola" da 
Henrik Ibsen. Una comprensione della due regolazione e symbolism
letterari di termini ed il loro effetto su un lavoro di letteratura, 
sono essenziali a successo degli allievi in quanto segue la guida di 
riferimento descritta nel corso di arti di linguaggio inglese del 
North.carolina dello studio standard. Questa lezione è stata 
modificata per gli studenti di lingue inglesi al livello elevato 
intermedio di competenza, ma egualmente sarebbe adattabile per i 
principianti al debuttante o ai livelli avanzati.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το μάθημα σχεδιάζεται ως συνέχιση της ανάγνωσης 
και της συζήτησης του παιχνιδιού "το σπίτι μιας κούκλασ" από το 
Henrik Ibsen. Μια κατανόηση της δύο λογοτεχνικών τιμής
τών παραμέτρων και του συμβολισμού όρων, και ο αντίκτυπός τους 
σε μια εργασία της λογοτεχνίας, είναι ουσιαστικοί στην επιτυχία 
των σπουδαστών μέσα μετά από τις οδηγίες που περιγράφονται στις 
πρότυπες σπουδές τεχνών αγγλικής γλώσσας της βόρειας Καρολίνας.
Αυτό το μάθημα έχει τροποποιηθεί για τους αρχαρίους 
αγγλικής γλώσσας στο ενδιάμεσο υψηλό επίπεδο ικανότητας, αλλά 
θα ήταν επίσης προσαρμόσιμο για τους αρχαρίους στον αρχάριο ή τα
προηγμένα επίπεδα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta lección es diseñada como carta recordativa 
a la lectura y a la discusión la casa del juego "de la muñeca" por 
Henrik Ibsen. Una comprensión de dos fijar y simbolismos 
literarios de los términos, y su impacto en un trabajo de la 
literatura, son esenciales para el éxito de los estudiantes en el 
siguiente de las guías de consulta contorneadas en el curso estándar
de los artes del lenguaje inglés de Carolina del Norte del estudio. 
Esta lección se ha modificado para los principiantes de 
lenguaje inglés en el alto nivel intermedio de la habilidad, pero 
también sería adaptable para los principiantes en el principiante o 
los niveles avanzados.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:GUY HILL
FN:GUY HILL
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CRYSTAL BROWN
FN:CRYSTAL BROWN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202766</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106699</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/setting-and-symbolism-in-a-dolls-house</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
