<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105037</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105037</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086792</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Roll Hitler Out and Roll the Union In: The No-Strike Pledge</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Rollen Sie Hitler heraus und rollen Sie den 
Anschluß in: Der Nr.schlag Versprechen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Roulez Hitler dehors et roulez l'union dans : 
l'Engagement de Grève de Non</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Role Hitler para fora e role a união em: O 
Pledge Da Batida Do No.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Rotoli Hitler fuori e rotoli l'unione in: 
L'Impegno Di Colpo Di No</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο ρόλος hitler έξω και κυλά την ένωση σε: Η 
υποχρέωση κανένας-απεργίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ruede Hitler hacia fuera y ruede la unión en: 
El Compromiso De la Huelga De No</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In a total war like World War II, the question "Was everyone doing his or her 'part'?" inevitably arose. Equality of sacrifice took particularly sharp form in the debate over the no-strike pledge for labor unions. Communists, who had played key roles in the union organizing drives of the 1930s and were well represented among union leaders, were intensely patriotic during the war. Their commitment to defeat fascism and defend the Soviet Union, which was threatened by advancing German armies, made Communists among the strongest advocates of labor sacrifices to win the war. A vigorous expression of this point of view can be found in the ballad "UAW-CIO," composed by Baldwin "Butch" Hawes. Hawes was associated with the Almanac Singers--a group that was sympathetic to the Communist position and included such notable figures as Woody Guthrie and Pete Seeger.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In einem Gesamtkrieg mögen Sie den Zweiten 
Weltkrieg, die Frage "war jeder, das tut sein oder ' Teil '?" 
entstand unvermeidlich. Gleichheit des Opfers nahm 
besonders scharfe Gestalt im Debatteüberschuß an, den der Nr.schlag 
für Arbeiterverbände versprechen. Kommunisten, die hatten 
Schlüsselrollen in den organisierenden Laufwerken des Anschlußes der
dreißiger Jahre gespielt und wurden gut unter Anschlußführern 
dargestellt, waren während des Krieges intensiv patriotisch. 
Ihre Verpflichtung, zum des Faschismus zu besiegen und des 
Sowjet-Anschlußes zu verteidigen, der bedroht wurde, indem man 
deutsche Armeen vorrückte, ließ Kommunisten unter den stärksten 
Fürsprechern von Arbeitsopfern den Krieg gewinnen. Ein 
kräftiger Ausdruck dieses Gesichtspunkts kann in der Ballade "UAW-CIO
gefunden werden," bestanden worden von Baldwin "Butch" Hawes. 
Hawes bezog auf die Almanach-Sänger -- eine Gruppe, die in die 
kommunistische Position sympatisch war und solche angesehene Person 
Abbildungen wie waldiges Guthrie und Peter Seeger einschloß.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans une guerre totale aimez la deuxième guerre 
mondiale, la question "était chacun qui fait sa 'partie '?" a 
inévitablement surgi. L'égalité du sacrifice a pris en 
particulier à forme pointue dans l'excédent de discussion 
l'engagement de grève de non pour les syndicats. Les 
communistes, qui avaient joué les rôles principaux dans les lecteurs
d'organisation des syndicats des années 30 et ont été bien 
représentés parmi des amorces des syndicats, étaient intensément 
patriotes pendant la guerre. Leur engagement pour défaire le 
fascisme et pour défendre Union Soviétique, qui a été menacé en 
avançant les armées allemandes, a incité des communistes parmi les 
avocats les plus forts des sacrifices de travail pour gagner la 
guerre. Une expression vigoureuse de ce point de vue peut être 
trouvée dans la ballade "UAW-CIO," composé par Baldwin "Butch" 
Hawes. Hawes a été associé aux chanteurs d'almanach -- un 
groupe qui était bien disposé dans la position communiste et a 
inclus des chiffres de notable tels que Guthrie boisé et Peter 
Seeger.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em uma guerra total goste da segunda guerra 
mundial, a pergunta "era todos que faz sua ou sua ' parte '?" 
levantou-se inevitàvel. A igualdade do sacrifício fêz 
exame particularmente formulário afiado no excesso do debate do 
pledge da batida do No. para uniões labor. Os comunistas, que 
tinham jogado os papéis chaves nas movimentações organizando da 
união dos 1930s e foram representados bem entre líderes da união, 
eram intensa patriotic durante a guerra. Seu compromisso para 
derrotar o fascism e defender a Soviete-união, que foi ameaçada 
avançando exércitos alemães, fêz comunistas entre os advogados os 
mais fortes de sacrifícios labor para ganhar a guerra. Uma 
expressão vigorosa deste ponto da vista pode ser encontrada no ballad
"UAW-CIO," composto por Baldwin "Butch" Hawes. Hawes foi 
associado com os singers do almanac -- um grupo que fosse sympathetic 
à posição comunista e incluísse figuras do notable como Guthrie 
woody e Pete Seeger.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In una guerra totale gradisca la seconda guerra 
mondiale, la domanda "era tutto che fa la sua 'parte '?" ha 
presentato inevitabilmente. L'uguaglianza del sacrificio ha 
preso specialmente a forma tagliente nell'eccedenza di dibattito 
l'impegno di colpo di no per i sindacati di lavoro. I 
comunisti, che avevano svolto i ruoli chiave negli azionamenti 
d'organizzazione del sindacato dei 1930s e bene sono stati 
rappresentati fra i capi del sindacato, erano intensamente 
patriotic durante la guerra. Il loro impegno per sconfiggere il 
fascismo e difendere l'Soviet-unione, che è stata minacciata 
avanzando gli eserciti tedeschi, ha incitato i comunisti fra i fautori
più forti dei sacrifici di lavoro per vincere la guerra. 
Un'espressione vigorosa di questo punto di vista può essere 
trovata nel ballad "UAW-CIO," composto da Baldwin "Butch" Hawes. 
Hawes è stato associato con i cantanti del almanac -- un gruppo
che era simpatico alla posizione comunista ed ha incluso tali figure 
del notabile come Guthrie boscoso e Pete Seeger.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε έναν συνολικό πόλεμο όπως τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο 
ΙΙ, η ερώτηση "ήταν η καθεμία που κάνει" το μέρος του/της ";" 
αναπόφευκτα προέκυψε. Η ισότητα της θυσίας έλαβε 
ιδιαίτερα την αιχμηρή μορφή στη συζήτηση πέρα από την υποχρέωση
κανένας-απεργίας για τα εργατικά συνδικάτα. Οι 
κομμουνιστές, που είχαν διαδραματίσει τους βασικούς ρόλους στην 
ένωση οργανώνοντας τις κινήσεις της δεκαετίας του '30 και 
αντιπροσωπεύθηκαν καλά μεταξύ των ηγετών ένωσης, ήταν έντονα 
πατριωτικοί κατά τη διάρκεια του πολέμου. Η υποχρέωσή τους
να νικήσουν το φασισμό και να υπερασπίσουν τη Σοβιετική Ένωση, 
που απειλήθηκε με την προώθηση των γερμανικών στρατών, έκανε τους
κομμουνιστές μεταξύ των ισχυρότερων συνηγόρων των θυσιών 
εργασίας για να κερδίσει τον πόλεμο. Μια σφριγηλή έκφραση 
αυτής της άποψης μπορεί να βρεθεί στην μπαλάντα "uαω- CIO," 
αποτελούμενος από Baldwin "Butch" Hawes. Το Hawes 
συνδέθηκε με τους τραγουδιστές ημερολογίων -- μια ομάδα που ήταν 
συμπονετική στην κομμουνιστική θέση και περιέλαβε τέτοιους 
ξεχωριστούς αριθμούς όπως ξύλινοι Guthrie και pete 
Seeger.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En una guerra total tenga gusto de la Segunda 
Guerra Mundial, la pregunta "era cada una que hacía su o su ' parte 
'?" se presentó inevitable. La igualdad del sacrificio 
tomó determinado a forma sostenida en el excedente del discusión el 
compromiso de la huelga de no para los sindicatos. Los 
comunistas, que habían desempeñado los papeles dominantes en los 
mecanismos impulsores de ordenación de la unión de los años 30 y 
fueron representados bien entre arranques de cinta de la unión, eran 
intenso patrióticos durante la guerra. Su consolidación para 
derrotar fascismo y para defender la Soviet-unio'n, que fue amenazada 
avanzando a ejércitos alemanes, hizo a comunistas entre los abogados 
más fuertes de sacrificios de trabajo para ganar la guerra. Una
expresión vigorosa de este punto de vista se puede encontrar en la 
balada "UAW-CIO," compuesto por Baldwin "Butch" Hawes. Hawes fue
asociado a los cantantes del almanac -- grupo que era comprensivo a la
posición comunista e incluyó las figuras tales de la persona notable
como Guthrie arbolado y Pete Seeger.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086792</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105037</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/roll-hitler-out-and-roll-the-union-in-the-no-strike-pledge</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
