<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103063</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103063</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206115</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Inquiring Minds: Fermilab</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erkundigen Des Verstandes: Fermilab</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Investigation des Esprits : Fermilab</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Inquirindo Mentes: Fermilab</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Domanda Delle Menti: Fermilab</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μυαλά έρευνας: Fermilab</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Investigación De Mentes: Fermilab</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features an introduction to elementary particles and forces in our universe, physics questions answered by Fermilab scientists, an interactive timeline illustrating the history of high-energy physics, links to other high energy physics sites, and more. It is maintained by Fermilab, the high-energy physics lab devoted to studying the universe?what it is made of and how it works.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">kennzeichnet eine Einleitung zu den 
Elementarteilchen und Kräfte in unserem Universum, die Physikfragen, 
die von den Fermilab Wissenschaftlern beantwortet werden, ein 
interaktives timeline, welches die Geschichte der energiereichen 
Physik veranschaulichen, Links auf andere Sites der hohen 
Energiephysik und mehr. Sie wird von Fermilab, das energiereiche
Physiklabor beibehalten, das dem Studieren des universe?what gewidmet 
wird, das sie von gebildet wird und wie es funktioniert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">comporte une introduction aux particules 
élémentaires et les forces en notre univers, les questions de 
physique répondues par des scientifiques de Fermilab, une chronologie
interactive illustrant l'histoire de la physique de grande énergie, 
des liens à d'autres sites de physique d'énergie élevée, et plus. 
Elle est mise à jour par Fermilab, le laboratoire de grande 
énergie de physique consacré à étudier l'universe?what qu'elle est
faite de et comment cela fonctionne.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">caracteriza uma introdução às partículas 
elementares e as forças em nosso universo, as perguntas da física 
respondidas por cientistas de Fermilab, um timeline interativo que 
ilustram o history da física high-energy, as ligações a outros 
locais da física de energia elevada, e o mais. É mantida por 
Fermilab, o laboratório high-energy da física devotado a estudar o 
universe?what que é feita de e como trabalha.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">caratterizza un'introduzione alle particelle 
elementari e forze in nostro universo, domande di fisica risposte a 
dagli scienziati del Fermilab, un timeline interattivo che illustrano 
la storia della fisica ad alta energia, collegamenti ad altri luoghi 
di fisica delle particelle e più. È effettuata da Fermilab, il
laboratorio ad alta energia di fisica dedicato a studiare il 
universe?what che è fatta di e come funziona.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χαρακτηρίζει μια εισαγωγή στα στοιχειώδη μόρια και τις
δυνάμεις στον κόσμο μας, τις ερωτήσεις φυσικής που απαντιούνται 
από Fermilab τους επιστήμονες, μια διαλογική υπόδειξη ως προς 
το χρόνο που επεξηγούν την ιστορία της υψηλής ενέργειας φυσικής,
τις συνδέσεις με άλλες περιοχές υψηλής ενεργειακής φυσικής, και 
περισσότερων. Διατηρείται από Fermilab, το υψηλής 
ενέργειας εργαστήριο φυσικής που αφιερώνεται στη μελέτη του 
universe?what που αποτελείται από και πώς λειτουργεί.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece una introducción a las partículas 
elementales y las fuerzas en nuestro universo, las preguntas de la 
física contestadas por los científicos de Fermilab, un timeline 
interactivo que ilustra la historia de la física de gran energía, 
las conexiones a otros sitios de la alta física de energía, y más. 
Es mantenida por Fermilab, el laboratorio de gran energía de la
física dedicado a estudiar el universe?what que se hace de y cómo 
trabaja.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206115</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103063</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/inquiring-minds-fermilab</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
