<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104337</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104337</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087251</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Working for the Triangle Shirtwaist Company</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Arbeiten für Triangle Shirtwaist Company</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Travailler pour Triangle chemisier Company</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Trabalhar para o Triângulo Shirtwaist Companhia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Funzionando per il Triangle Shirtwaist Company</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εργασία για την επιχείρηση μπλουζών τριγώνων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Trabajo para el Triangle Shirtwaist Company</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this oral history interview conducted by historian Joan Morrison, Pauline Newman told of getting a job at the Triangle Company as a child, soon after arriving in the United States from Lithuania in 1901. Newman described her life as an immigrant and factory worker. Like many other young immigrant workers, she chafed at the strict regulations imposed by the garment manufacturers. One of the greatest industrial tragedies in U.S. history occurred on March 26, 1911, when 146 workers, mostly young women, died in a fire at the Triangle Shirtwaist Company. Although she was not working in the factory at the time of the fire, many of her friends perished. Newman later became an organizer and leader of the International Ladies Garment Workers' Union.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In diesem Mundgeschichte Interview, das mit 
Historiker Joan Morrison geleitet wurde, erklärte Pauline Newman vom 
Erhalten eines Jobs an Triangle Company als Kind, bald nachdem er in 
den Vereinigten Staaten von Litauen 1901 angekommen war. Newman 
beschrieb ihre Lebensdauer als Immigrant und Arbeiter. Wie viele
andere junge einwandernde Arbeiter rieb sie an den strengen 
Regelungen, die von den Kleidherstellern auferlegt wurden. Eine 
der größten industriellen Tragödien in der VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Geschichte trat an März 26, 1911, als 146 Arbeiter, meistens die 
jungen Frauen auf, gestorben in einem Feuer an Triangle Shirtwaist 
Company. Obgleich sie nicht in der Fabrik zu der Zeit des Feuers
arbeitete, kamen viele ihrer Freunde um. Newman stand später 
einem Organisator und einem Führer des internationalen Anschlußes 
der Dame-Kleid-Arbeiter.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cette entrevue orale d'histoire conduite par 
l'historien Joan Morrison, Pauline Newman a raconté obtenir un 
travail à Triangle Company en tant qu'enfant, peu après l'arrivée 
aux Etats-Unis de Lithuanie en 1901. Newman a décrit sa vie en 
tant qu'un immigré et ouvrier d'usine. Comme beaucoup d'autres 
jeunes ouvriers immigrés, elle a échauffé aux règlements stricts 
imposés par les constructeurs de vêtement. Une des plus 
grandes tragédies industrielles dans l'histoire des ETATS-UNIS s'est 
produite 26 mars 1911, quand 146 ouvriers, la plupart du temps jeunes
femmes, mortes dans un feu à Triangle chemisier Company. Bien 
qu'elle n'ait pas travaillé dans l'usine au moment du feu, plusieurs 
de ses amis ont péri. Newman plus tard est allé bien à un 
organisateur et à une amorce du syndicat international de vêtement 
de dames.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta entrevista oral do history conduzida pelo 
historian Joan Morrison, Pauline Newman disse de começar um trabalho 
no Triângulo Companhia como uma criança, logo após chegar nos 
estados unidos de Lithuania em 1901. Newman descreveu sua vida 
como um immigrant e um trabalhador de fábrica. Como muitos 
outros trabalhadores immigrant novos, aqueceu por atrito nos 
regulamentos estritos impostos pelos fabricantes do garment. Uma
das tragédias industriais as mais grandes no history de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS ocorreu março em 26, 1911, quando 146 trabalhadores, na maior 
parte mulheres novas, morridas em um fogo no Triângulo Shirtwaist 
Companhia. Embora não trabalhasse na fábrica na altura do 
fogo, muitos de seus amigos perished. Newman assentou bem mais 
tarde em um organizer e em um líder da união de trabalhadores 
internacional do garment das senhoras.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questa intervista orale di storia condotta 
dallo storico Joan Morrison, Pauline Newman ha detto a di ottenere un 
lavoro al Triangle Company come bambino, presto dopo essere arrivato 
nel unito Dichiara dalla Lituania in 1901. Newman ha 
descritto la sua vita come un immigrante ed operaio di fabbrica. 
Come molti altri operai immigrati giovani, si è logorata alle 
regolazioni rigorose imposte dai fornitori dell'indumento. Una 
delle tragedie industriali più grandi nella storia degli STATI UNITI 
si è presentata il 26 marzo 1911, quando 146 operai, principalmente 
donne giovani, morte in un fuoco al Triangle Shirtwaist Company. 
Anche se non stava lavorando nella fabbrica ai tempi del fuoco, 
molti dei suoi amici sono perito. Newman più successivamente ha
stato bene ad un organizzatore e ad un capo dell'unione degli 
operai internazionale dell'indumento delle signore.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτήν την προφορική συνέντευξη ιστορίας που 
πραγματοποιήθηκε από τον ιστορικό Joan Morrison, Pauline 
Newman είπε να πάρει μια εργασία στην επιχείρηση τριγώνων 
δεδομένου ότι ένα παιδί, σύντομα μετά από να φθάσει στις 
Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες από τη Λιθουανία σε 1901, Newman 
περι:γράφω τη ζωή της ως μετανάστη και εργαζόμενο εργοστασίων. 
Όπως πολλούς άλλους νέους που έχουν μεταναστεύσει 
εργαζομένους, θέρμανε στους ακριβείς κανονισμούς που επιβλήθηκαν 
από τους κατασκευαστές ενδυμάτων. Μια από τις μέγιστες 
βιομηχανικές τραγωδίες στην ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ ιστορία εμφανίστηκε στις 
26 Μαρτίου ..1911, όταν πέθαναν 146 εργαζόμενοι, συνήθως
νέες γυναίκες, σε μια πυρκαγιά στην επιχείρηση μπλουζών 
τριγώνων. Αν και δεν εργαζόταν στο εργοστάσιο κατά την 
διάρκεια της πυρκαγιάς, πολλοί από τους φίλους της που χάνονται.
Το Newman έγινε αργότερα διοργανωτής και ηγέτης της 
ένωσης των διεθνών εργαζομένων γυναικείων ενδυμάτων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta entrevista oral de la historia conducida 
por el historiador Joan Morrison, Pauline Newman dijo de conseguir un 
trabajo en el Triangle Company como niño, pronto después de llegar 
en los Estados Unidos de Lituania en 1901. Newman describió su 
vida como un inmigrante y trabajador de fábrica. Como muchos 
otros trabajadores inmigrantes jóvenes, ella frotó en las 
regulaciones terminantes impuestas por los fabricantes de la ropa. 
Una de las tragedias industriales más grandes de la historia de
ESTADOS UNIDOS ocurrió de marcha la 26 de 1911, cuando 146 
trabajadores, sobre todo mujeres jóvenes, muertas en un fuego en el 
Triangle Shirtwaist Company. Aunque ella no trabajaba en la 
fábrica a la hora del fuego, muchos de sus amigos fallecieron. 
Newman sintió bien más adelante a un organizador y a un 
arranque de cinta de la unión de trabajadores internacional de la 
ropa de las señoras.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087251</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104337</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/working-for-the-triangle-shirtwaist-company</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
