<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103713</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103713</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086051</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Cynthia Long Describes How the Women's Movement of the 1970s Changed Her Life</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lange Cynthia beschreibt, wie die Bewegung der 
Frauen der siebziger Jahre ihre Lebensdauer änderte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cynthia longue décrit comment le mouvement des 
femmes des années 70 a changé sa vie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Cynthia longa descreve como o movimento das 
mulheres dos 1970s mudou sua vida</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Cynthia lunga descrive come il movimento delle 
donne degli anni 70 ha cambiato la sua vita</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θ*Θυντχηα Long Describes How το κίνημα των 
γυναικών της δεκαετίας του '70 που αλλάζουν η ζωή της</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cynthia larga describe cómo el movimiento de las 
mujeres de los años 70 cambió su vida</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The women's movement of the 1970's sent shockwaves into every recess of American life. Women organized to seek enforcement of the ban on sex discrimination included in the 1964 Civil Rights Act, demanded equal pay at work, and sought access to jobs from which they had previously been barred. Despite its educated, middle class origins, the movement had a deep impact on the experience of working class women. Cynthia Long, one of the first women to gain access to the New York electrician's union, found a sense of empowerment and solidarity through her participation in International Women's Year and the group Asian Women United. Joining women's groups alleviated the sense of alienation felt by many women who worked in mostly male environments.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Bewegung der Frauen der siebziger Jahre 
sendete Shockwaves in jede Aussparung der amerikanischen Lebensdauer. 
Die Frauen, die organisiert werden, um Durchführung des Verbots
auf der Geschlechtunterscheidung zu suchen eingeschlossen ist in den 
1964 Zivilrechten, fungieren, verlangte gleiche Bezahlung an der 
Arbeit und gesuchter Zugriff zu den Jobs, von denen sie vorher 
abgehalten worden waren. Trotz seiner gebildete, mittlere 
Kategorie Ursprung hatte die Bewegung eine tiefe Auswirkung auf die 
Erfahrung der Funktion Kategorie Frauen. Cynthia sehnen sich, 
eine der ersten Frauen, um zum Anschluß des New York Elektrikers 
Zutritt zu erhalten, fand eine Richtung der Ermächtigung und 
solidarität durch ihre Teilnahme am Jahr der internationalen Frauen 
und die Gruppe asiatischen Frauen vereinigte. Gruppen der 
verbindenen Frauen verminderten die Richtung der Entfremdung gefühlt 
von vielen Frauen, die meistens in den männlichen Umgebungen 
arbeiteten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le mouvement des femmes des années 70 a envoyé 
des ondes de choc dans chaque cavité de vie américaine. Les 
femmes organisées pour rechercher l'application de l'interdiction de 
la discrimination de sexe incluse dans les 1964 droits civiques 
agissent, égalité de salaires exigée au travail, et accès 
recherché aux travaux desquels elles avaient été précédemment 
empêchées. En dépit de ses origines de la bourgeoisie 
instruite et, le mouvement a eu un impact profond sur l'expérience 
des femmes de classe ouvrière. Cynthia désirent ardemment, une
des premières femmes pour accéder à l'union de l'électricien de 
New York, a trouvé un sens d'habilitation et la solidarité par sa 
participation à l'année des femmes internationales et les femmes 
asiatiques de groupe a uni. Les groupes des femmes se joignantes
ont allégé le sens de l'aliénation senti par beaucoup de femmes qui
ont travaillé dans la plupart du temps les environnements mâles.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O movimento das mulheres dos 1970's emitiu 
shockwaves em cada rebaixo da vida americana. As mulheres 
organizadas para procurar o enforcement da proibição na 
discriminação de sexo incluída nas 1964 direitas civis agem, 
pagamento igual exijido no trabalho, e acesso procurado aos trabalhos 
de que tinham sido barradas previamente. Apesar de suas origens 
da classe educada, média, o movimento teve um impacto profundo na 
experiência de mulheres da classe de funcionamento. Cynthia 
long, uma das primeiras mulheres para ganhar o acesso à união do 
eletricista de New York, encontrou um sentido do empowerment e o 
solidarity através de sua participação no ano das mulheres 
internacionais e das mulheres asian do grupo uniu-se. Os grupos 
das mulheres juntando aliviaram o sentido do alienation sentido por 
muitas mulheres que trabalharam na maior parte nos ambientes 
masculinos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il movimento delle donne degli anni 70 ha 
trasmesso gli shockwaves in ogni incavo di vita americana. Le 
donne organizzate per cercare l'applicazione del divieto di 
discriminazione in base al sesso inclusa nei 1964 diritti civili si 
comportano, parità salariale richiesta sul lavoro ed accesso cercato 
ai lavori da cui precedentemente erano state escluse. Malgrado 
le relative origini del codice categoria istruito e centrale, il 
movimento ha avuto un effetto profondo sull'esperienza nelle donne del
codice categoria di funzionamento. Cynthia desidera, una delle 
prime donne per accedere all'unione dell'elettricista de New York, ha 
trovato un senso di empowerment e la solidarietà attraverso la sua 
partecipazione all'anno delle donne internazionali e le donne 
asiatiche del gruppo ha unito. I gruppi delle donne unentesi 
hanno alleviato il senso dell'alienazione ritenuto da molte donne che 
hanno lavorato principalmente negli ambienti maschii.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το κίνημα των γυναικών τη δεκαετία του '70 που 
στέλνεται shockwaves σε κάθε κοιλότητα της αμερικανικής ζωής. 
Οι γυναίκες που οργανώθηκαν από για να επιδιώξουν την 
επιβολή της απαγόρευσης στις διακρίσεις λόγω φύλου που 
περιλήφθηκαν στο νόμο αστικών δικαιωμάτων του 1964, απαίτησαν 
την ίση αμοιβή στην εργασία, και επιδίωξαν την πρόσβαση στις 
εργασίες τις οποίες ήταν φραγμένων προηγουμένως. Παρά την 
εκπαιδευμένη, μέση προέλευση κλάσης της, η μετακίνηση άσκησε 
βαθιά επίδραση στην εμπειρία των γυναικών εργατικής τάξης. 
Η Cynthia Long, μια από τις πρώτες γυναίκες για να 
αποκτήσει πρόσβαση στην ένωση του ηλεκτρολόγου της Νέας Υόρκης, 
βρήκε μια αίσθηση της ενδυνάμωσης και της αλληλεγγύης μέσω της 
συμμετοχής της στο έτος των διεθνών γυναικών και τις ασιατικές 
γυναίκες ομάδας που ενώθηκαν. Οι ενώνοντας ομάδες των 
γυναικών ανακούφισαν την αίσθηση της αλλοτρίωσης που έγινε 
αισθητή από πολλές γυναίκες που εργάστηκαν στα συνήθως αρσενικά
περιβάλλοντα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El movimiento de las mujeres de los años 70 
envió ondas de choque en cada receso de la vida americana. Las 
mujeres ordenadas para buscar la aplicación de la interdicción en la
discriminación de sexo incluida en las 1964 derechas civiles actúan,
igualdad de salario exigida en el trabajo, y acceso buscado a los 
trabajos de los cuales las habían barrado previamente. A pesar 
de sus orígenes de la clase educada, media, el movimiento tenía un 
impacto profundo en la experiencia de las mujeres de la clase obrera. 
Cynthia desea, una de las primeras mujeres para acceder a la 
unión del electricista de Nueva York, encontró un sentido del 
empowerment y la solidaridad a través de su participación en el año
de las mujeres internacionales y de las mujeres asiáticas del grupo 
unió. Los grupos de las mujeres que ensamblaban aliviaron el 
sentido de la enajenación sentido por muchas mujeres que trabajaron 
en sobre todo los ambientes masculinos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086051</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103713</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/cynthia-long-describes-how-the-womens-movement-of-the-1970s-changed-her-life</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
