<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108527</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108527</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086271</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Am Only a Piece of Machinery": Housewives Analyze Their Problems</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ich bin nur ein Stück Maschinerie": 
Hausfrauen Analysieren Ihre Probleme</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"je suis seulement un morceau de machines" : 
Les Femmes au foyer Analysent Leurs Problèmes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"eu sou somente uma parte de maquinaria": Os
Housewives Analisam Seus Problemas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"sono soltanto una parte di macchinario": Le
Casalinghe Analizzano I Loro Problemi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"είμαι μόνο ένα κομμάτι των μηχανημάτων": Οι 
νοικοκυρές αναλύουν τα προβλήματά τους</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"soy solamente un pedazo de maquinaria": Las
Amas de casa Analizan Sus Problemas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the early 20th century, new household technology was both accomplished and inspired by the tremendous increase in American industrial production. As in industry, mechanization and scientific management were part of a larger reorganization of work. And as in industry, efficient housekeeping was partially a response to labor unrest--both the "servant problem" and the growing disquiet of middle-class wives. Machines offered salvation through technology; scientific housework promised satisfaction through systematic and efficient methods. But middle-class wives themselves voiced a discontent that could not be addressed through new purchases or better systems. In 1923,  Woman's Home Companion  solicited readers' letters for a series that offered the magazine as a clearinghouse for women's household problems and solutions. In response, nearly two thousand women wrote letters to the magazine. Skeptical of the solutions afforded by washing machines and efficiency methods, many of them called for cooperative housekeeping, paid work, help from children and husbands, and equality in marriage--solutions not contemplated by the enthusiasts of either scientific housekeeping or the new household technology.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im frühen 20. Jahrhundert wurde neue Haushalt 
Technologie durch die enorme Zunahme der amerikanischen industriellen 
Industrieproduktion vollendet und angespornt. Wie in der 
Industrie, waren Mechanisierung und wissenschaftliche 
Unternehmensführung ein Teil einer größeren Reorganisierung der 
Arbeit. Und wie in der Industrie, war leistungsfähige 
Haushaltung teilweise eine Antwort zur Arbeitsruhelosigkeit -- das 
"Bedienstetproblem" und die wachsende Besorgnis der 
Mittelklassefrauen. Maschinen boten Rettung durch Technologie 
an; wissenschaftliche Hausarbeit versprach Zufriedenheit durch 
die systematischen und leistungsfähigen Methoden. Aber 
Mittelklassefrauen selbst äußerten eine Unzufriedenheit, die nicht 
durch neue Erwerbe oder bessere Systeme adressiert werden könnte. 
1923 erbat Hauptbegleiter der Frau Zeichen der Leser für eine 
Serie, die die Zeitschrift als Verrechnungszentrale für Probleme und 
Lösungen Haushalt der Frauen anbot. In der Antwort schrieben 
fast zwei tausend Frauen Briefe zur Zeitschrift. Skeptisch von 
den Lösungen, die durch Waschmaschinen und Leistungsfähigkeit 
Methoden, viele von ihnen geleistet wurden, verlangte kooperative 
Haushaltung, Arbeit, Hilfe von den Kindern und von den Ehemännern und
Gleichheit in der Verbindung gezahlt -- die Lösungen, die nicht von 
den Enthusiasten entweder der wissenschaftlichen Haushaltung oder der 
neuen Haushalt Technologie erwogen wurden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En début du 20ème siècle, la nouvelle 
technologie de ménage a été accomplie et inspirée par 
l'augmentation énorme de la production industrielle américaine. 
Comme dans l'industrie, la mécanisation et la gestion 
scientifique faisaient partie d'une plus grande réorganisation de 
travail. Et comme dans l'industrie, le ménage efficace était 
partiellement une réponse au malaise ouvrier -- le "problème 
d'domestique" et l'inquiétude croissante des épouses de classe 
moyenne. Les machines ont offert le salut par la technologie ; 
les travaux domestiques scientifiques ont promis la satisfaction
par des méthodes systématiques et efficaces. Mais les épouses
de classe moyenne elles-mêmes ont exprimé un mécontentement qui ne 
pourrait pas être adressé par de nouveaux achats ou meilleurs 
systèmes. En 1923, la compagne à la maison de la femme a 
sollicité les lettres des lecteurs pour une série qui a offert le 
magasin comme chambre de compensation pour les problèmes et les 
solutions du ménage des femmes. Dans la réponse, presque deux 
mille femmes ont écrit des lettres au magasin. Sceptique des 
solutions accordées par les machines à laver et les méthodes 
d'efficacité, bon nombre d'entre elles a nécessité le ménage 
coopératif, payé le travail, l'aide des enfants et des maris, et 
l'égalité dans le mariage -- solutions non contemplées par les 
fervents du ménage scientifique ou de la nouvelle technologie de 
ménage.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No 20o século adiantado, a tecnologia nova da 
casa  foi realizada e inspirada pelo aumento tremendo na produção 
industrial americana. Como na indústria, o mechanization e a 
gerência científica eram parte de um reorganization maior do 
trabalho. E como na indústria, as tarefas domésticas 
eficientes eram parcialmente uma resposta ao unrest labor --  do "o 
problema empregado" e o disquiet crescente de esposas do middle-class.
As máquinas ofereceram o salvation com a tecnologia; o 
housework científico prometeu a satisfação com os métodos 
sistemáticos e eficientes. Mas as esposas elas mesmas do 
middle-class exprimiram um discontent que não poderia ser dirigido 
através das compras novas ou dos sistemas melhores. Em 1923, o 
companheiro home da mulher solicited letras dos leitores para uma 
série que oferecesse o compartimento como um clearinghouse para 
problemas e soluções da casa das mulheres. Na resposta, quase 
dois mil mulheres escreveram letras ao compartimento. Skeptical 
das soluções tidas recursos para pelas máquinas de lavagem e pelos 
métodos da eficiência, muitas deles chamou-se para tarefas 
domésticas cooperativas, pago o trabalho, a ajuda das crianças e dos
maridos, e a igualdade na união -- soluções não contempladas pelos
entusiastas de tarefas domésticas científicas ou da tecnologia nova 
da casa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nell'inizio del 20esimo secolo, la nuova 
tecnologia della famiglia sia è stata compiuta che ispirato stata 
tramite l'incremento tremendo della produzione industriale americana. 
Come nell'industria, la meccanizzazione e la gestione 
scientifica facevano parte di più grande riorganizzazione di lavoro. 
E come nell'industria, il governo della casa efficiente era 
parzialmente una risposta ad agitazione di lavoro -- sia "il 
problema del servo" che l'inquietudine crescente delle mogli della 
classe media. Le macchine hanno offerto la salvezza con 
tecnologia; i lavori domestici scientifici hanno promesso la 
soddisfazione con i metodi sistematici ed efficienti. Ma le 
mogli essi stessi della classe media hanno espresso un discontent che 
non potrebbe essere indirizzato attraverso i nuovi acquisti o i 
sistemi migliori. In 1923, il compagno domestico della donna ha 
sollecitato le lettere dei lettori per una serie che ha offerto lo 
scomparto come stanza di compensazione per i problemi e le soluzioni 
della famiglia delle donne. Nella risposta, quasi due mila donne
hanno scritto le lettere allo scomparto. Scettico delle 
soluzioni accordate con le lavatrici ed i metodi di risparmio di temi,
molte di loro ha richiesto il governo della casa cooperativo, pagato 
il lavoro, l'aiuto dai bambini e dai mariti e l'uguaglianza 
nell'unione -- soluzioni non contemplate dagli entusiasti del governo 
della casa scientifico o di nuova tecnologia della famiglia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στις αρχές του 20ού αιώνα, η νέα οικιακή τεχνολογία 
και ολοκληρώθηκε και εμπνεύστηκε από την τεράστια αύξηση στην 
αμερικανική βιομηχανική παραγωγή. Όπως στη βιομηχανία, η 
μηχανοποίηση και η επιστημονική διαχείριση ήταν μέρος μιας 
μεγαλύτερης αναδιοργάνωσης της εργασίας. Και όπως στη 
βιομηχανία, η αποδοτική οικοκυρική ήταν μερικώς μια απάντηση 
στην ανησυχία εργασίας -- και το "πρόβλημα υπαλλήλων" και η 
αυξανόμενη ανησυχία των συζύγων μεσαίων τάξεων. Τις 
μηχανές που προσφέρονται τη σωτηρία μέσω της τεχνολογίας  
τα επιστημονικά οικιακά που υπόσχονται την ικανοποίηση μέσω
των συστηματικών και αποδοτικών μεθόδων. Αλλά οι σύζυγοι 
μεσαίων τάξεων οι ίδιοι εξέφρασαν μια δυσαρέσκεια που δεν θα 
μπορούσε να εξεταστεί μέσω των νέων αγορών ή των καλύτερων 
συστημάτων. Το 1923, ο σύντροφος "Οικιαών της γυναίκας 
ζήτησε τις επιστολές των αναγνωστών για μια σειρά που πρόσφερε το
περιοδικό ως γραφείο συμψηφισμού για τα οικιακές προβλήματα και 
τις λύσεις των γυναικών. Στην απάντηση, σχεδόν δύο χιλιάες
γυναίκες έγραψαν τις επιστολές στο περιοδικό. Δύσπιστες των
λύσεων που διατίθενται από τα πλυντήρια ρούχων και την 
αποδοτικότητα οι μέθοδοι, πολλές από τους απαιτήθηκαν τη 
συνεταιριστική οικοκυρική, που πληρώνεται την εργασία, τις 
οδηγίες από τα παιδιά και τους συζύγους, και την ισότητα στο 
γάμο -- λύσεις που δεν προβλέπονται από τους ενθουσιώδες είτε 
της επιστημονικής οικοκυρικής είτε της νέας οικιακής 
τεχνολογίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En el vigésimo siglo temprano, la nueva 
tecnología de la casa fue lograda e inspirada por el enorme aumento 
en la producción industrial americana. Como en industria, la 
mecanización y la gerencia científica eran parte de una 
reorganización más grande del trabajo. Y como en industria, 
las operacíones de entretenimiento eficientes eran parcialmente una 
respuesta al malestar de trabajo -- el "problema del criado" y la 
inquietud cada vez mayor de las esposas de la clase media. Las 
máquinas ofrecieron la salvación con tecnología; el quehacer 
doméstico científico prometió la satisfacción con métodos 
sistemáticos y eficientes. Pero las esposas ellos mismos de la 
clase media expresaron un descontento que no se podría tratar a 
través de nuevas compras o de sistemas mejores. En 1923, el 
compañero casero de la mujer solicitó las cartas de los programas de
lectura para una serie que ofreció el compartimiento como cámara de 
compensación para los problemas y las soluciones de la casa de las 
mujeres. En respuesta, casi dos mil mujeres escribieron letras 
al compartimiento. Escéptico de las soluciones producidas por 
las lavadoras y los métodos de la eficacia, muchas de ellos llamó 
para las operacíones de entretenimiento cooperativas, pagado el 
trabajo, la ayuda de niños y de maridos, y la igualdad en la unión 
-- soluciones no comtempladas por los entusiastas de las operacíones 
de entretenimiento científicas o de la nueva tecnología de la casa.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086271</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108527</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-am-only-a-piece-of-machinery-housewives-analyze-their-problems</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
