<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103160</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103160</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211291</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">NCBI: Education</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">NCBI: Ausbildung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">NCBI : Éducation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">NCBI: Instrução</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">NCBI: Formazione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">NCBI: Εκπαίδευση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">NCBI: Educación</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Web site from the National Center for Biotechnology Information (NCBI) offers a set of detailed tutorials to help users make full use of NCBI's bioinformatics tools. The tutorials, which target both new and veteran users, cover NCBI's BLAST and PSI-BLAST, Entrez data retrieval system, Cn3D molecular structure software, and more. Additionally, the Science Primer tutorial offers a "basic introduction to the science underlying NCBI resources" geared more toward the general reader.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Web site von der nationalen Mitte zu 
Biotechnologie-Information (NCBI) bietet ein Set ausführliche 
Tutorials an, um Benutzern zu helfen, vollen Gebrauch von den NCBI's 
bioinformatics Hilfsmitteln zu bilden. Die Tutorials, die die 
neue und Veteranbenutzer, Abdeckung NCBI's KNALL und PSI-BLAST, Entrez
Dateninformations-Retrievalsystem, Cn3D molekulare Struktursoftware 
und mehr zielen. Zusätzlich bietet der Wissenschaft Zündkapsel
Tutorial eine "grundlegende Einleitung zur Wissenschaft an, die 
zugrundeliegende NCBI Betriebsmittel" mehr in Richtung zum allgemeinen
Leser übersetzten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site de Web du centre national pour 
l'information de biotechnologie (NCBI) offre un ensemble de cours 
d'instruction détaillés pour aider des utilisateurs à utiliser 
pleinement des outils de bioinformatics de NCBI's. Les cours 
d'instruction, qui logiciel moléculaire visent utilisateurs de 
nouveaux et de vétéran, SOUFFLE de la couverture NCBI's et 
PSI-BLAST, système d'extraction de données d'Entrez, de Cn3D 
structure, et plus. Supplémentaire, le cours d'instruction 
d'amorce de la Science offre "une introduction de base à la science 
les ressources que fondamentales de NCBI" ont embrayé plus vers le 
lecteur général.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Web site do centro nacional para a 
informação do biotechnology (NCBI) oferece um jogo de tutorials 
detalhados ajudar a usuários fazer o uso cheio de ferramentas do 
bioinformatics de NCBI's. Os tutorials, que alvejam  usuários 
novos e do veteran, EXPLOSÃO da tampa NCBI's e PSI-BLAST, sistema de 
recuperação dos dados de Entrez, de estrutura de Cn3D software 
molecular, e mais. Adicionalmente, o tutorial do primer da 
ciência oferece "uma introdução básica à ciência que os recursos
subjacentes de NCBI" engrenaram mais para o leitor geral.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Web site dal centro nazionale per le 
informazioni di biotecnologia (NCBI) offre un insieme delle lezioni 
private dettagliate per aiutare gli utenti ad utilizzare pienamente 
gli strumenti di bioinformatics di NCBI's. Le lezioni private, 
che designano sia utenti del veterano che i nuovi, lo SCOPPIO della 
copertura NCBI's e PSI-BLAST, il sistema di reperimento dei dati di 
Entrez, software molecolare della struttura come bersaglio di Cn3D e 
più. Ulteriormente, la lezione privata dell'iniettore di 
scienza offre "un'introduzione di base alla scienza che le risorse 
di fondo di NCBI" hanno innestato più verso il lettore generale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος από το εθνικό κέντρο για τις 
πληροφορίες βιοτεχνολογίας (NCBI) προσφέρει ένα σύνολο 
λεπτομερών σεμιναρίων για να βοηθήσει τους χρήστες να 
αξιοποιήσουν πλήρως τα εργαλεία βιοπληροφορικής NCBI. Τα 
σεμινάρια, που στοχεύουν και στους νέους και χρήστες παλαιμάχων, 
καλύπτουν το ΦΎΣΗΜΑ NCBI και το PSI-FY'SIMA, σύστημα 
ανάκτησης στοιχείων Entrez, μοριακό λογισμικό δομών Cn3D, 
και περισσότεροι. Επιπλέον, το σεμινάριο εγχυτήρων 
επιστήμης προσφέρει μια "βασική εισαγωγή στην επιστήμη που 
κρύβεται κάτω από τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς NCBI" που 
συνδέονται περισσότερων προς το γενικό αναγνώστη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio del Web del centro nacional para
la información de la biotecnología (NCBI) ofrece un conjunto de 
guías detalladas para ayudar a utilizadores a hacer el uso completo 
de las herramientas del bioinformatics de NCBI's. Las guías, 
que apuntan utilizadores nuevos y del veterano, RÁFAGA de la cubierta
NCBI's y PSI-BLAST, el sistema de extracción de datos de Entrez, 
software molecular de la estructura de Cn3D, y más. Además, la
guía de la cartilla de la ciencia ofrece una "introducción básica a
la ciencia que los recursos subyacentes de NCBI" engranaron más hacia
el programa de lectura general.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:NATIONAL CENTER FOR BIOTECHNOLOGY INFORMATION
FN:NATIONAL CENTER FOR BIOTECHNOLOGY INFORMATION
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211291</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103160</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/ncbi-education</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
