<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103163</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103163</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1387102966</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Space Time Travel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Platz-Zeit-Spielraum</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Voyage de Temps de l'Espace</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Curso Do Tempo Do Espaço</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Corsa Di Tempo Dello Spazio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διαστημικό χρονικό ταξίδι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Recorrido Del Tiempo Del Espacio</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Black holes and travel at nearly the speed of light: Visualization of the theory of relativity. Online papers, images, movies and paper models.

What would it be like to experience fast motion or strong gravity? To move at nearly the speed of light for example? Or to look at a black hole from nearby? What should we see?

The website presents computer simulations that provide "virtual experiences" of this kind. The images and movies are correctly computed within the framework of the theory of relativity. They are carefully explained in an intuitive, non-mathematical way.

This is a (not yet complete) English version of the German site Tempolimit Lichtgeschwindigkeit (http://www.tempolimit-lichtgeschwindigkeit.de)

Additional contributions, available so far only in German, provide material for use in the classroom. This includes more detailed explanations using basic maths, suggestions for exercises, and instructions for building your own "paper model black hole".</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <language>de</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Schwarze Bohrungen und Spielraum mit fast der 
Lichtgeschwindigkeit: Sichtbarmachung der Theorie der 
Relativität. Onlinepapiere, Bilder, Filme und Papier 
models.What würde sie wie Zeitraffer oder starke Schwerkraft erfahren
sollen? Mit der Lichtgeschwindigkeit zum Beispiel fast bewegen? 
Oder eine schwarze Bohrung von in der Nähe betrachten? 
Was, wir see?The Web site Geschenk-Computersimulationen wenn, 
die "virtuelle Erfahrungen" dieser Art liefern. Die Bilder und 
die Filme werden richtig im Rahmen der Theorie der Relativität 
berechnet. Sie werden sorgfältig in einem intuitiven, 
unmathematischen way.This sind a (nicht schon komplett) englische 
Version der deutschen Sites Tempolimit Lichtgeschwindigkeit erklärt 
(die http://www.tempolimit-lichtgeschwindigkeit.de)Additional 
Beiträge, die bis jetzt nur auf Deutsch vorhanden sind, stellen 
Material für Gebrauch im Klassenzimmer zur Verfügung. Dieses 
schließt ausführlichere Erklärungen mit grundlegendem Mathe, 
Vorschlägen für Übungen und Anweisungen für das Aufbauen Ihre 
Selbst "vorbildliche schwarze Bohrung des Papiers" ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Trous noirs et voyage presque à la vitesse de la 
lumière : Visualisation de la théorie de relativité. 
Les papiers en ligne, les images, les films et le papier 
models.What devrait-elle comme éprouver le mouvement rapide ou la 
pesanteur forte ? Pour se déplacer presque à la vitesse de la 
lumière par exemple ? Ou pour regarder un trou noir de tout 
près ? Ce qui si nous les simulations sur ordinateur de 
présents de site Web de see?The qui fournissent "des expériences 
virtuelles" de cette sorte. Les images et les films sont 
correctement calculés dans le cadre de la théorie de relativité. 
Elles sont soigneusement expliquées dans un way.This intuitif 
et non-mathématique est version anglaise de a (pas encore complet) du
site allemand Tempolimit Lichtgeschwindigkeit (les contributions de 
http://www.tempolimit-lichtgeschwindigkeit.de)Additional, disponibles 
jusqu'ici seulement en allemand, fournissent le matériel pour l'usage
dans la salle de classe. Ceci inclut des explications plus 
détaillées en utilisant des maths de base, des suggestions pour des 
exercices, et des instructions pour construire vos propres "le trou 
noir modèle d'article".</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Furos pretos e curso quase na velocidade de luz: 
Visualization da teoria do relativity. Os papéis em 
linha, as imagens, os filmes e o papel models.What deveria como 
experimentar o movimento rápido ou a gravidade forte? Para 
mover-se quase na velocidade de luz para o exemplo? Ou para 
olhar um furo preto de próximo? Que se nós as simulações de 
computador dos presentes do Web site do see?The que fornecem 
"experiências virtuais" deste tipo. As imagens e os filmes são
computados corretamente dentro da estrutura da teoria do relativity. 
São explicados com cuidado em um way.This intuitive, 
non-mathematical são versão inglesa de a (não ainda completo) do 
local alemão Tempolimit Lichtgeschwindigkeit (as contribuições de 
http://www.tempolimit-lichtgeschwindigkeit.de)Additional, disponíveis
assim distante somente no alemão, fornecem o material para o uso na 
sala de aula. Isto inclui umas explanações mais detalhadas 
usando maths básicos, sugestões para exercícios, e instruções 
para construir seus próprios do "o furo preto modelo papel".</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fori neri e corsa quasi alla velocità di luce: 
Visualizzazione della teoria di relatività. Carte in 
linea, immagini, film e carta models.What dovrebbe come 
avvertire il movimento veloce o la gravità forte? Per muoversi 
quasi alla velocità di luce per esempio? O per guardare un foro
nero da qui vicino? Che cosa se simulazioni su elaboratore dei 
presenti di Web site del see?The che forniscono "le esperienze 
virtuali" in questo genere. Le immagini ed i film sono 
computati correttamente nel quadro della teoria della relatività. 
Sono spiegate con attenzione in un way.This intuitivo e non 
matematico sono versione inglese di a (non ancora completa) del luogo 
tedesco Tempolimit Lichtgeschwindigkeit (i contributi di 
http://www.tempolimit-lichtgeschwindigkeit.de)Additional, disponibili 
finora soltanto in tedesco, forniscono il materiale per uso nell'aula.
Ciò include le spiegazioni più dettagliate usando i per la 
matematica di base, i suggerimenti per le esercitazioni e le 
istruzioni per la costruzione dei vostri propri "foro nero di modello 
della carta".</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαύρες τρύπες και ταξίδι με σχεδόν την ταχύτητα του 
φωτός: Απεικόνιση της θεωρίας της σχετικότητας. Σε 
απευθείας σύνδεση έγγραφα, εικόνες, κινηματογράφοι και μοντέλα 
εγγράφου Τι θα ήταν όπως να δοκιμάσει τη γρήγορη κίνηση ή
την ισχυρή βαρύτητα; Για να κινηθεί με σχεδόν την ταχύτητα 
του φωτός παραδείγματος χάριν; Ή για να εξετάσει μια μαύρη
τρύπα από εδώ κοντά; Αυτό που εάν βλέπαμε τον 
ιστοχώρο παρουσιάζει τις προσομοιώσεις υπολογιστών που παρέχουν 
τη "εικονική εμπειρία" αυτού του είδους. Οι εικόνες και οι 
κινηματογράφοι υπολογίζονται σωστά μέσα στο πλαίσιο της θεωρίας 
της σχετικότητας. Εξηγούνται προσεκτικά με έναν 
διαισθητικό, μη-μαθηματικό τρόπο Αυτό είναι μια (όχι 
ακόμα πλήρης) αγγλική εκδοχή της γερμανικής περιοχής 
Tempolimit Lichtgeschwindigkeit (οι συνεισφορές 
http://www.tempolimit-lichtgeschwindigkeit.de)Additional, 
διαθέσιμη μέχρι τώρα μόνο στα γερμανικά, παρέχουν το υλικό για 
τη χρήση στην τάξη. Αυτό περιλαμβάνει τις πιό λεπτομερείς 
εξηγήσεις χρησιμοποιώντας τα βασικά μαθηματικά, τις προτάσεις για
τις ασκήσεις, και τις οδηγίες για την οικοδόμηση της "πρότυπης 
μαύρης τρύπας εγγράφου σασ".</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Calabozos y recorrido casi a la velocidad de la 
luz: Visualización de la teoría de la relatividad. ¿Los 
papeles en línea, las imágenes, las películas y el papel 
models.What debería como experimentar el movimiento rápido o la 
gravedad fuerte? ¿Para moverse casi a la velocidad de la luz por
ejemplo? ¿O para mirar un calabozo de cerca? Qué si las 
simulaciones de ordenador de los presentes del Web site del see?The 
que proporcionan a "experiencias virtuales" de esta clase. Las 
imágenes y las películas se computan correctamente en el marco de la
teoría de la relatividad. Se explican cuidadosamente en un 
way.This intuitivo, no matemático son versión inglesa de a (no 
todavía completa) del sitio alemán Tempolimit Lichtgeschwindigkeit 
(las contribuciones de 
http://www.tempolimit-lichtgeschwindigkeit.de)Additional, disponibles 
hasta ahora solamente en alemán, proporcionan al material para el uso
en la sala de clase. Esto incluye explicaciones más detalladas 
usando matemáticas básica, las sugerencias para los ejercicios, y 
las instrucciones para construir sus el propios el "calabozo modelo 
del papel".</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:UTE KRAUS
FN:UTE KRAUS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CORVIN ZAHN
FN:CORVIN ZAHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1387102966</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103163</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/space-time-travel</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
