<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108684</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108684</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207153</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Run for Your Lives! The Johnstown Flood of 1889</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Laufen Sie für Ihre Lebensdauern! Die 
Johnstown Flut von 1889</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Exécutez pendant vos vies ! La pléthore de
Johnstown de 1889</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Funcione por suas vidas! A inundação de 
Johnstown de 1889</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Funzioni per le vostre vite! La pletora di 
Johnstown di 1889</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τρέξιμο για τις ζωές σας! Η πλημμύρα Johnstown
1889</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Ejecútese por sus vidas! La inundación de
Johnstown de 1889</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Commemorates the most devastating flood in the U.S. in the 19th century. On the wet afternoon of 05/31, 1889, the inhabitants Johnston, Pennsylvania, heard a low rumble that grew to a roar like thunder. Some knew immediately what had happened: the South Fork Dam, after a night of heavy rain, had broken. The break sent a 36-foot wall of water rolling at 40 miles per hour toward Johnstown, a town of 30,000 people. More than 2,200 people were killed.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gedenkt die verheerendste Flut in den VEREINIGTEN 
STAATEN im 19. Jahrhundert. Am nassen Nachmittag von 05/31, 
hörte 1889, die Einwohner Johnston, Pennsylvania, ein niedriges 
Poltern, das zu ein Brüllen wie Donner sich entwickelte. Einige
wußten sofort, was geschehen war: die Südgabel-Verdammung, 
nach einer Nacht des schweren Regens, hatte gebrochen. Der Bruch
sendete eine 36-foot Wand des Wasserrollens bei 40 Meilen pro Stunde 
in Richtung zu Johnstown, eine Stadt von 30.000 Leuten. Mehr als
2.200 Leute wurden beendet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Commémore l'inondation la plus dévastatrice aux 
ETATS-UNIS au 19ème siècle. L'après-midi humide de 05/31, 
1889, les habitants Johnston, Pennsylvanie, a entendu un bas 
grondement qui a devenu un hurlement comme le tonnerre. Certains
ont su immédiatement ce qui s'était produit : le barrage 
Du sud de fourchette, après une nuit de forte pluie, s'était 
cassé. La rupture a envoyé 36-foot un mur du roulement de 
l'eau à 40 milles par heure vers Johnstown, une ville de 30.000 
personnes. Plus de 2.200 personnes ont été détruites.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Comemora a inundação a mais devastating nos 
ESTADOS UNIDOS no 1ø século. Na tarde molhada de 05/31, 1889, 
habitantes Johnston, Pensilvânia, ouviram um rumble baixo que viesse 
a um rugido como o trovão. Alguns souberam imediatamente o que 
tinha acontecido: a represa sul da forquilha, após uma noite da
chuva pesada, tinha quebrado. A ruptura emitiu 36-foot uma 
parede do rolling da água em 40 milhas por a hora para Johnstown, uma
cidade de 30.000 povos. Mais de 2.200 povos foram matados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Commemora l'inondazione più devastating negli 
STATI UNITI nel diciannovesimo secolo. Sul pomeriggio bagnato di
05/31, 1889, gli abitanti Johnston, Pensilvania, ha sentito un rumble 
basso che ha diventato un ruggito come tuono. Alcuni hanno 
conosciuto immediatamente che cosa era accaduto: la diga del sud
della forcella, dopo una notte di pioggia pesante, si era rotta. 
La rottura ha trasmesso 36-foot una parete del rolling 
dell'acqua a 40 miglia all'ora verso Johnstown, una città di 30.000 
genti. Più di 2.200 genti sono state uccise.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τιμά την μνήμη της πλημμύρας καταστροφής στις ΗΠΑ στο 
19$ο αιώνα. Στο υγρό απόγευμα του 05/31, 1889, οι 
κάτοικοι Johnston, Πενσυλβανία, άκουσαν ότι ένας χαμηλός 
βουίζει που αυξήθηκε σε έναν βρυχηθμό όπως τη βροντή. 
Μερικοί ήξεραν αμέσως τι είχε συμβεί: το φράγμα 
νότιων δικράνων, μετά από μια νύχτα της δυνατής βροχής, είχε 
σπάσει. Το σπάσιμο έστειλε έναν τοίχο 36-ποδιών του 
ύδατος που κυλά σε 40 μίλια ανά ώρα προς Johnstown, μια 
πόλη 30.000 ανθρώπων. Περισσότεροι από 2.200 άνθρωποι
σκοτώθηκαν.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Conmemora la inundación más devastadora de los 
ESTADOS UNIDOS en el diecinueveavo siglo. En la tarde mojada de 
05/31, 1889, los habitantes Johnston, Pennsylvania, oyó un estruendo 
bajo que vino un rugido como trueno. Algunos sabían 
inmediatamente qué había sucedido: la presa del sur de la 
fork, después de una noche de la lluvia pesada, se había roto. 
La rotura envió 36-foot una pared del balanceo del agua en 40 
millas por hora hacia Johnstown, una ciudad de 30.000 personas. 
Mataron a más de 2.200 personas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207153</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108684</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/run-for-your-lives-the-johnstown-flood-of-1889</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
