<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103943</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103943</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213222</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">WorldWatcher Project: Global Warming</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">WorldWatcher Projekt: Globales Wärmen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Projet de WorldWatcher : Chauffage Global</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Projeto De WorldWatcher: Aquecer-se Global</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Progetto WorldWatcher: Riscaldamento Globale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">WorldWatcher πρόγραμμα: Παγκόσμια αύξηση της 
θερμοκρασίας λόγω του φαινομένου του θερμοκηπίου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Proyecto De WorldWatcher: El Calentarse 
Global</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Starting Point webpage is a summary of a role-playing resource called Worldwatcher Project: Global Warming Project. In this exercise, students role-play advisors to various heads of state on the subject of global warming. The web site offers a short curriculum to help the students become experts on global warming. It offers lab activities, computer visualizations (using free WorldWatcher software), lots of background readings, and choose-your-own-adventure journeys through the carbon and water cycles. The unit concludes with a summit on global warming at which students give their presentations. For teachers, there is a pedagogical explanation for each activity and rubrics for the presentation and for an energy balance diagram assignment. This website explains the learning goals of the exercise and context for use of this exercise. It also provides teaching notes and tips, a list of necessary teaching materials, assessment techniques and additional resources. This website is part of the Starting Point collection.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Ausgangspunktwebseite ist eine 
Zusammenfassung eines Rolle spielendes Hilfsmittels, das Worldwatcher 
Project genannt wird: Globales Wärmendes Projekt. In 
dieser Übung spielen Kursteilnehmer Berater zu den verschiedenen 
Staatsoberhäuptern bezüglich des globalen Wärmens Rolle. Die 
Web site bietet einen kurzen Lehrplan an, um den Kursteilnehmern zu 
helfen, Experten auf dem globalen Wärmen zu stehen. Sie bietet 
Laboraktivitäten, die Computersichtbarmachungen (freie WorldWatcher 
Software verwendend), die Lots Hintergrundmesswerte und die 
Wählen-Ihr-eigenabenteuer Reisen durch die Carbon- und 
Wasserschleifen an. Die Maßeinheit folgert mit einem Gipfel auf
dem globalen Wärmen an, welchen Kursteilnehmern ihre Darstellungen 
geben. Für Lehrer gibt es eine pädagogische Erklärung für 
jede Aktivität und Rubriken für die Darstellung und für eine 
Energiebalance Diagrammanweisung. Diese Web site erklärt die 
erlernenziele der Übung und des Kontextes für Gebrauch von dieser 
Übung. Sie liefert auch unterrichtende Anmerkungen und Spitzen,
eine Liste der notwendigen Lehrmittel, Einschätzung Techniken und 
zusätzliche Betriebsmittel. Diese Web site ist ein Teil der 
Ausgangspunktansammlung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette page Web de point de départ est un 
sommaire d'une ressource jouante un rôle appelée Worldwatcher 
Project : Projet de Chauffage Global. Dans cet exercice, 
les étudiants jouent un rôle des conseillers à de divers chefs 
d'Etat au sujet du chauffage global. Le site Web offre un 
programme d'études court pour aider les étudiants à aller bien à 
des experts en chauffage global. Il offre des activités de 
laboratoire, des visualisations d'ordinateur (utilisant le logiciel 
libre de WorldWatcher), des un bon nombre de lectures de fond, et des 
voyages de choisir-votre-propre-aventure pendant les cycles de carbone
et d'eau. L'unité conclut avec un sommet sur le chauffage 
global à quels étudiants donnent leurs présentations. Pour 
des professeurs, il y a une explication pédagogique pour chaque 
activité et rubriques pour la présentation et pour une affectation 
de diagramme de bilan énergétique. Ce site Web explique les 
buts d'étude de l'exercice et du contexte pour l'usage de cet 
exercice. Il fournit également les notes et les extrémités 
d'enseignement, une liste de matériel didactique nécessaire, des 
techniques d'évaluation et des ressources supplémentaires. Ce 
site Web fait partie de la collection de point de départ.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Web page do ponto começar é um sumário de 
um recurso role-playing chamado Worldwatcher Projeto: Projeto 
Aquecendo-se Global. Neste exercício, os estudantes role-play 
conselheiros às várias cabeças de estado no assunto de aquecer-se 
global. O Web site oferece um curriculum curto ajudar aos 
estudantes assentar bem em peritos em aquecer-se global. Oferece
atividades do laboratório, visualizations do computador (que usam o 
software livre de WorldWatcher), lotes de leituras do fundo, e viagens
da escolh-seu-próprio-aventura através dos ciclos do carbono e da 
água. A unidade concli com um summit em aquecer-se global em 
que estudantes dão suas apresentações. Para professores, há 
uma explanação pedagogical para cada atividade e rubrics para a 
apresentação e para uma atribuição do diagrama do contrapeso de 
energia. Este Web site explica os objetivos de aprendizagem do 
exercício e do contexto para o uso deste exercício. Fornece 
também notas e pontas ensinando, uma lista de materiais de ensino 
necessários, técnicas da avaliação e recursos adicionais. 
Este Web site é parte da coleção do ponto começar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Web page del punto di partenza è un 
sommario di una risorsa d'atteggiamento chiamata Worldwatcher il 
Project: Progetto Di Riscaldamento Globale. In questa 
esercitazione, gli allievi si atteggiano consiglieri alle varie teste 
di dichiarano a proposito del riscaldamento globale. Il Web
site offre un programma di studi corto per aiutare gli allievi a stare
bene agli esperti sul riscaldamento globale. Offre le attività 
del laboratorio, le visualizzazioni del calcolatore (che usando il 
software libero di WorldWatcher), i lotti delle letture della 
priorità bassa ed i viaggi di scegli-vostro-proprio-avventura durante
i cicli dell'acqua e del carbonio. L'unità conclude con una 
sommità sul riscaldamento globale a quali allievi danno le loro 
presentazioni. Per gli insegnanti, ci è una spiegazione 
pedagogica per ogni attività e le rubriche per la presentazione e per
un'assegnazione dello schema del bilancio energetico. Questo Web
site spiega gli obiettivi imparanti dell'esercitazione e del contesto 
per uso di questa esercitazione. Egualmente fornisce le note e 
punte d'istruzione, una lista dei materiali didattici necessari, 
tecniche di valutazione e risorse supplementari. Questo Web site
fa parte dell'accumulazione del punto di partenza.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το webpage αφετηρίας είναι μια περίληψη ενός 
ρόλος-παίζοντας στοιχείου συμπεριφοράς αποκαλούμενου πρόγραμμα 
Worldwatcher: Σφαιρικό πρόγραμμα θέρμανσης. Σε 
αυτήν την άσκηση, σύμβουλοι ρόλος-παιχνιδιού σπουδαστών στους 
διάφορους αρχηγούς κράτους σχετικά με το θέμα της παγκόσμιας 
αύξησης της θερμοκρασίας λόγω του φαινομένου του θερμοκηπίου. 
Ο ιστοχώρος προσφέρει ένα σύντομο πρόγραμμα σπουδών για να
βοηθήσει τους σπουδαστές να γίνουν εμπειρογνώμονες στην παγκόσμια
αύξηση της θερμοκρασίας λόγω του φαινομένου του θερμοκηπίου. 
Προσφέρει τις δραστηριότητες εργαστηρίων, τις απεικονίσεις 
υπολογιστών (που χρησιμοποιούν το ελεύθερο λογισμικό 
WorldWatcher), τα μέρη των αναγνώσεων υποβάθρου, και τα ταξίδια
επι:λέγω-σας-$$$-ΠΕΡΙΠΈΤΕΙΑΣ μέσω των κύκλων άνθρακα και ύδατος.
Η μονάδα ολοκληρώνει με μια σύνοδο κορυφής στην παγκόσμια 
αύξηση της θερμοκρασίας λόγω του φαινομένου του θερμοκηπίου σε 
ποιους σπουδαστές κάνετε τις παρουσιάσεις τους. Για τους 
δασκάλους, υπάρχει μια παιδαγωγική εξήγηση για κάθε 
δραστηριότητα και ρουμπρίκες για την παρουσίαση και για μια 
ανάθεση διαγραμμάτων ενεργειακής ισορροπίας. Αυτός ο 
ιστοχώρος εξηγεί τους στόχους εκμάθησης της άσκησης και του 
πλαισίου για τη χρήση αυτής της άσκησης. Παρέχει επίσης 
τις σημειώσεις διδασκαλίας και τις άκρες, ένας κατάλογος 
απαραίτητων εκπαιδευτικών υλικών, τεχνικών αξιολόγησης και 
πρόσθετων στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς. Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος είναι 
μέρος της συλλογής αφετηρίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este Web page del punto de partida es un resumen de
un recurso de actuación de papeles llamado Worldwatcher Project: 
Proyecto Que se calienta Global. En este ejercicio, los 
estudiantes actúan en papel los consejeros a los varios jefes de 
estado a propósito de calentarse global. El Web site ofrece un 
plan de estudios corto para ayudar a los estudiantes a sentir bien a 
expertos en calentarse global. Ofrece actividades del 
laboratorio, las visualizaciones del ordenador (que usan el software 
libre de WorldWatcher), las porciones de lecturas del fondo, y los 
viajes de la elegir-su-propio-aventura durante los ciclos del carbón 
y del agua. La unidad concluye con una cumbre en calentarse 
global en qué estudiantes dan sus presentaciones. Para los 
profesores, hay una explicación pedagógica para cada actividad y las
rúbricas para la presentación y para una asignación del diagrama 
del balance energético. Este Web site explica las metas que 
aprenden del ejercicio y del contexto para el uso de este ejercicio. 
También proporciona a notas y extremidades de enseñanza, una 
lista de materiales didácticos necesarios, las técnicas del gravamen
y los recursos adicionales. Este Web site es parte de la 
colección del punto de partida.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:DANIEL EDELSON
FN:DANIEL EDELSON
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213222</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103943</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/worldwatcher-project-global-warming</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
