<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106773</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106773</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087363</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Against Isolationism: James F. Byrnes Refutes Lindbergh</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gegen Isolationismus: James F. Byrnes Refutes
Lindbergh</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Contre l'Isolationnisme : James F. 
Byrnes Refutes Lindbergh</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">De encontro A Isolationism: James F. Byrnes 
Refutes Lindbergh</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Contro Isolationism: James F. Byrnes Refutes
Lindbergh</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ενάντια στον απομονωτισμό: James F. 
Byrnes Refutes Lindbergh</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Contra Aislacionismo: James F. Byrnes Refutes 
Lindbergh</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The interwar peace movement was arguably the largest mass movement of the 1920s and 1930s, a mobilization often overlooked in the wake of the broad popular consensus that ultimately supported the U.S. involvement in World War II. The destruction wrought in World War I (known in the 1920s and 1930s as the "Great War") and the cynical nationalist politics of the Versailles Treaty had left Americans disillusioned with the Wilsonian crusade to save the world for democracy. Senate investigations of war profiteering and shady dealings in the World War I munitions industry both expressed and deepened widespread skepticism about wars of ideals. Charles Lindbergh, popular hero of American aviation, had been speaking in support of American neutrality for some time, and allies of FDR's interventionist foreign policy sought to counter the arguments of the famous aviator. In a May 19, 1940, radio speech, Senator James F. Byrnes of South Carolina refuted Lindbergh's position, specifically rebutting a speech Lindbergh had given on military spending.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die interwar Friedensbewegung war diskutierbar die 
größte Massenbewegung der zwanziger Jahre und der dreißiger Jahre, 
eine Mobilisierung, die häufig unmittelbar nach der ausgedehnten 
populären Übereinstimmung übersehen wurde, die schließlich die 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Miteinbeziehung im Zweiten Weltkrieg unterstützte.
Die Zerstörung, die im Ersten Weltkrieg wrought sind (bekannt 
in den zwanziger Jahren und in den dreißiger Jahren als der "große 
Krieg") und die zynische nationalistische Politik des Versailles 
Vertrags hatten die linken Amerikaner, die mit dem Wilsonian Kreuzzug 
ernüchtert wurden, um die Welt für Demokratie zu sichern. 
Senatuntersuchungen von Krieg Profiteering und schattige Umgang 
in der Erster Weltkrieg Munitionsindustrie drückten aus und 
vertieften weitverbreitete Skepsis über Kriege von Idealen. 
Charles Lindbergh, populärer Held der amerikanischen Luftfahrt,
hatte zur Unterstützung der amerikanischen Neutralität während 
einiger Zeit gesprochen, und Verbündete der fremden Politik des 
Interventionisten FDR suchten, den Argumenten des berühmten Fliegers 
zu widersprechen. In a Mai 19, 1940, Radiorede, Senator, den 
James F. Byrnes von Südcarolina die Position Lindberghs widerlegte 
und spezifisch widerlegte eine Rede Lindbergh, hatte auf 
militärischer Ausgabe gegeben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le mouvement de paix d'entre-deux guerres était 
discutablement le plus grand mouvement de masse des années 20 et des 
années 30, une mobilisation souvent négligée à la suite du large 
consensus populaire qui a finalement supporté l'intervention des 
ETATS-UNIS dans la deuxième guerre mondiale. La destruction 
travaillée dans la Première Guerre Mondiale (connue dans les années
20 et les années 30 comme "grande guerre") et la politique 
nationaliste cynique du Traité de Versailles ont eu les Américains 
gauches désillusionnés avec la croisade de Wilsonian pour 
sauvegarder le monde pour la démocratie. Les investigations de 
sénat sur le mercantilisme de guerre et les rapport d'affaires 
ombreuses dans l'industrie de munitions de Première Guerre Mondiale 
ont exprimé et ont approfondi le scepticisme répandu au sujet des 
guerres des idéaux. Charles Lindbergh, héros populaire 
d'aviation américaine, avait parlé à l'appui de la neutralité 
américaine pendant un certain temps, et les alliés de la politique 
étrangère de l'interventionniste du FDR ont recherché à parer les 
arguments de l'aviateur célèbre. Dans a 19 mai 1940, discours
par radio, sénateur que James F. Byrnes de la Caroline 
Du sud a réfuté la position de Lindbergh, réfutant 
spécifiquement un discours Lindbergh avait donné sur la dépense 
militaire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O movimento interwar da paz era arguably o 
movimento maciço o maior dos 1920s e dos 1930s, um mobilization 
negligenciado frequentemente na vigília do consenso popular largo que
suportou finalmente a participação de ESTADOS UNIDOS na segunda 
guerra mundial. A destruição feita no world.war.i (sabido nos 
1920s e nos 1930s como "a guerra grande") e a política nacionalista 
cínica do tratado de Versalhes tiveram os americanos esquerdos 
disillusioned com o crusade de Wilsonian para conservar o mundo para a
democracia. As investigações do senate do profiteering da 
guerra e as transações shady na indústria dos munitions do 
world.war.i  expressaram e aprofundaram skepticism difundido sobre 
guerras dos ideals. Charles Lindbergh, herói popular da 
aviação americana, tem falado na sustentação do neutrality 
americano por alguma hora, e os aliados da política extrangeira do 
interventionist do FDR procuraram opôr os argumentos do aviador 
famoso. Em a maio 19, 1940, discurso de rádio, senator que 
James F. Byrnes de carolina sul refuted a posição de Lindbergh, 
rebutting especificamente um discurso Lindbergh tinha dado na despesa 
militar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il movimento interwar di pace era discutibilmente 
il più grande movimento totale degli anni 20 e dei 1930s, una 
mobilizzazione trascurata spesso come conseguenza di vasto consenso 
popolare che infine ha sostenuto la partecipazione degli STATI UNITI 
alla seconda guerra mondiale. La distruzione modellata nel 
world.war.i (conosciuto negli anni 20 e nei 1930s come "la guerra 
grande") e la politica nazionalista cinica del Trattato de Versailles 
hanno avute Americani di sinistra disillusi con il crusade di 
Wilsonian per salvare il mondo per la democrazia. Le indagini 
del senato sull'affarismo di guerra ed i rapporti d'affari ombreggiati
nell'industria dei munitions di world.war.i sia hanno espresso che 
approfondito lo scetticismo diffuso circa le guerre degli ideali. 
Charles Lindbergh, hero popolare di aeronautica americana, stava
parlando a sostegno di neutralità americana per un certo tempo e gli 
alleati della politica straniera dell'interventista del FDR hanno 
cercato di ricambiare gli argomenti del aviator famoso. In a 
maggio 19, 1940, il discorso radiofonico, il senatore che James F. 
Byrnes di Carolina del Sud ha confutato la posizione del Lindbergh, 
specificamente rifiutante un discorso Lindbergh aveva dato sulla 
spesa militare.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η μετακίνηση ειρήνης μεσοπολέμου ήταν αμφισβητήσιμα η
μεγαλύτερη μαζική μετακίνηση της δεκαετίας του '20 και της 
δεκαετίας του '30, μια κινητοποίηση που αγνοήθηκε συχνά αμέσως 
μετά την ευρεία δημοφιλή συναίνεση που υποστήριξε τελικά την 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ συμμετοχή στον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο ΙΙ. Η καταστροφή
επεξεργασμένη στον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι (γνωστό στη δεκαετία του 
'20 και τη δεκαετία του '30 ως "μεγάλος πόλεμοσ") και η κυνική 
εθνικιστική πολιτική της Συνθήκης των Βερσαλλιών είχαν αφήσει 
Αμερικανούς απογοήτεψαν με τη σταυροφορία Wilsonian για να 
σώσουν τον κόσμο για τη δημοκρατία. Οι έρευνες Συγκλήτου 
για πολεμικό profiteering και τις σκιερές συναλλαγές στον 
παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι βιομηχανία πυρομαχικών και εξέφρασαν και 
εμβάθυναν το διαδεδομένο σκεπτικισμό για τους πολέμους των 
ιδανικών. Θ*Θχαρλες Lindbergh, δημοφιλής ήρωας της 
αμερικανικής αεροπορίας, μιλούσε υπέρ της αμερικανικής 
ουδετερότητας για κάποιο χρόνο, και των συμμάχων της εξωτερικής 
πολιτικής οπαδών του παρεμβατισμού FDR που επιδιώχθηκε για να 
αντιμετωπίσει τα ορίσματα του διάσημου αεροπόρου. Σε έναν 
Μάιος 19 ..1940, ραδιο ομιλία, γερουσιαστής james 
F. Byrnes του νότου αντικρουμένη η η Καρολίνα θέση 
Lindbergh, συγκεκριμένα που αντικρούει μια ομιλία Lindbergh 
είχε δώσει στα στρατιωτικά έξοδα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El movimiento interwar de la paz era discutible el
movimiento total más grande de los años 20 y de los años 30, una 
movilización pasada por alto a menudo en la estela del amplio 
consenso popular que utilizó en última instancia la implicación de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS en la Segunda Guerra Mundial. La destrucción 
labrada en la Primera Guerra Mundial (sabida en los años 20 y los 
años 30 como la "gran guerra") y la política nacionalista cínica 
del tratado de Versalles tenían americanos izquierdos desilusionados 
con la cruzada de Wilsonian para salvar el mundo para la 
democracia. Las investigaciones del senado del mercantilismo de 
la guerra y las reparticiones sombrías en la industria de las 
municiones de la Primera Guerra Mundial expresaron y profundizaron 
escepticismo extenso sobre guerras de ideales. Charles 
Lindbergh, héroe popular de la aviación americana, había estado 
hablando en ayuda de la neutralidad americana por una cierta hora, y 
los aliados de la política no nativa del intervencionista del FDR 
intentaron contradecir los argumentos del aviador famoso. En a 
19 de mayo de 1940, discurso de radio, senador que James F. Byrnes 
de Carolina del Sur refutó la posición de Lindbergh, refutando 
específicamente un discurso Lindbergh había dado en el gasto 
militar.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087363</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106773</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/against-isolationism-james-f-byrnes-refutes-lindbergh</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
