<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105474</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105474</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201590</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Evolution and the Nature of Science Institutes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Entwicklung und die Natur der Wissenschaft 
Institute</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Évolution et la nature des instituts de la 
Science</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Evolução e a natureza de institutos da ciência</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sviluppo e natura degli istituti di scienza</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εξέλιξη και η φύση των ιδρυμάτων επιστήμης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Evolución y la naturaleza de los institutos de la 
ciencia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This is a collection of classroom lessons to help high school biology teachers more effectively teach basic concepts in the areas of evolution and the nature of science. They were developed and tested during nine years of summer institutes by biology teachers from across the nation. This highly lab-oriented module is a very useful evolution and deep-time teaching site.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses ist eine Ansammlung Klassenzimmerlektionen, 
zum der High School Biologielehrer, effektiv zu helfen Grundmodelle in
den Bereichen der Entwicklung und in der Natur der Wissenschaft zu 
unterrichten. Sie wurden während neun Jahre Sommerinstitute von
den Biologielehrern über von der Nation entwickelt und geprüft. 
Dieses in hohem Grade Labor-orientierte Modul ist eine sehr 
nützliche Entwicklung und Tiefzeit unterrichtende Site.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">C'est une collection de leçons de salle de classe 
pour aider des professeurs de biologie de lycée plus pertinemment à 
enseigner des concepts de base dans les zones de l'évolution et la 
nature de la science. Elles ont été développées et testées 
pendant neuf ans d'instituts d'été par des professeurs de biologie 
de à travers la nation. Ce module fortement 
laboratoire-orienté est un site d'enseignement très utile 
d'évolution et de profond-temps.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta é uma coleção das lições da sala de aula 
para ajudar mais eficazmente a professores da biologia da High School 
ensinar conceitos básicos nas áreas de evolução e na natureza da 
ciência. Foram desenvolvidos e testados durante nove anos de 
institutos do verão por professores da biologia através da nação. 
Este módulo altamente laboratório-orientado é um local 
ensinando muito útil da evolução e do profundo-tempo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ciò è una collezione di lezioni dell'aula per 
aiutare più efficacemente gli insegnanti di biologia della High 
School ad insegnare i concetti di base nelle zone di sviluppo e nella 
natura della scienza. Sono state messe a punto e sperimentato 
state durante i nove anni degli istituti di estate dagli insegnanti di
biologia attraverso dalla nazione. Questo modulo altamente 
laboratorio-orientato è un luogo d'istruzione molto utile di 
profondo-tempo e di sviluppo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό είναι μια συλλογή των μαθημάτων τάξεων για να 
βοηθήσει τους δασκάλους της βιολογίας γυμνασίου να διδάξουν 
αποτελεσματικότερα τις βασικές έννοιες στους τομείς της εξέλιξης 
και τη φύση της επιστήμης. Αναπτύχθηκαν και εξετάστηκαν 
κατά τη διάρκεια εννέα ετών θερινών ιδρυμάτων από τους 
δασκάλους της βιολογίας από σε ολόκληρο το έθνος. Αυτή η 
ιδιαίτερα εργαστήριο-προσανατολισμένη στον ενότητα είναι μια 
πολύ χρήσιμη περιοχή διδασκαλίας εξέλιξης και βαθύς-χρόνου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ésta es una colección de lecciones de la sala de 
clase para ayudar a profesores de la biología de la High School 
secundaria más con eficacia a enseñar conceptos básicos en las 
áreas de la evolución y la naturaleza de la ciencia. Fueron 
desarrolladas y probadas durante nueve años de institutos del verano 
por los profesores de la biología a través de la nación. Este
módulo altamente laboratorio-orientado es un sitio de enseñanza muy 
útil de la evolución y del profundo-tiempo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JEAN BEARD
FN:JEAN BEARD
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CRAIG NELSON
FN:CRAIG NELSON
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MARTIN NICKLES
FN:MARTIN NICKLES
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201590</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105474</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/evolution-and-the-nature-of-science-institutes</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
