<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106044</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106044</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770210007</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Basic Electronics: Uncovering OHM's Law</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Grundlegende Elektronik: Aufdecken Des 
Gesetzes Des Ohms</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'Électronique de base : Découvrement de 
la Loi de l'Ohm</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Eletrônica Básica: Descobrindo A Lei Do 
Ohm</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Elettronica Di base: Scoprire Legge 
Dell'Ohm</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βασική ηλεκτρονική: Αποκάλυψη του νόμου του ΩΜ</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Electrónica Básica: Destapadura De la Ley 
Del Ohmio</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this simulation you will investigate relationships between voltage, resistance, and current that exists in an electric circuit. You will adjust voltage of the power source and resistance of the resistor and then use digital multimeter to obtain measurements. Then you will record these measurements and look for relationships that exist between voltage, resistance, and current.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In dieser Simulation forschen Sie Verhältnisse 
zwischen Spannung, Widerstand und Strom nach, der in einem 
elektrischen Stromkreis existiert. Sie justieren Spannung der 
Energiequelle und des Widerstandes des Widerstandes und benutzen dann 
Digitalmeßinstrument, um Messen zu erhalten. Dann speichern Sie
diese Messen und suchen nach Verhältnissen, die zwischen Spannung, 
Widerstand und Strom existieren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cette simulation vous étudierez des rapports
entre la tension, la résistance, et le courant qui existe dans un 
circuit électrique. Vous ajusterez la tension de la source 
d'énergie et de la résistance de la résistance et puis emploierez 
le multimètre digital pour obtenir des mesures. Alors vous 
enregistrerez ces mesures et rechercherez les rapports qui existent 
entre la tension, la résistance, et le courant.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta simulação você investigará 
relacionamentos entre a tensão, a resistência, e a corrente que 
existe em um circuito elétrico. Você ajustará a tensão da 
fonte de potência e da resistência do resistor e usará então o 
multímetro digital obter medidas. Então você gravará estas 
medidas e procurará os relacionamentos que existem entre a tensão, a
resistência, e a corrente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questa simulazione studierete i rapporti fra 
tensione, resistenza e la corrente che esiste in un circuito 
elettrico. Registrerete la tensione della fonte di energia e 
della resistenza del resistore ed allora userete il tester digitale 
per ottenere le misure. Allora registrerete queste misure e 
cercherete i rapporti che esistono fra tensione, resistenza e la 
corrente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτήν την προσομοίωση θα ερευνήσετε τις σχέσεις 
μεταξύ της τάσης, της αντίστασης, και του ρεύματος που υπάρχει σε
ένα ηλεκτρικό κύκλωμα. Θα ρυθμίσετε την τάση της πηγής 
ισχύος και της αντίστασης του αντιστάτη και χρησιμοποιείτε έπειτα
το ψηφιακό πολύμετρο για να λάβετε τις μετρήσεις. Κατόπιν 
θα καταγράψετε αυτές τις μετρήσεις και θα ψάξετε τις σχέσεις που 
υπάρχουν μεταξύ της τάσης, της αντίστασης, και του ρεύματος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta simulación usted investigará lazos entre
el voltaje, la resistencia, y la corriente que existe en un circuito 
eléctrico. Usted ajustará el voltaje de la fuente de energía 
y de la resistencia del resistor y después utilizará el multímetro 
digital para obtener medidas. Después usted registrará estas 
medidas y buscará los lazos que existen entre el voltaje, la 
resistencia, y la corriente.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:DR. DANIEL CHURCHILL
FN:DR. DANIEL CHURCHILL
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770210007</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106044</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/basic-electronics-uncovering-ohms-law</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
