<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103524</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103524</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087310</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A Japanese Soldier Describes the Horrors of Guadalcanal</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein japanischer Soldat beschreibt die 
Grausigkeiten von Guadalcanal</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un soldat japonais décrit les horreurs de 
Guadalcanal</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um soldado japonês descreve os horrors de 
Guadalcanal</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un soldato giapponese descrive gli orrori di 
Guadalcanal</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένας ιαπωνικός στρατιώτης περιγράφει τις φρίκες 
guadalcanal</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un soldado japonés describe los horrores de 
Guadalcanal</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The surprise attack on December 7, 1941, on U.S. military forces at Pearl Harbor, Hawaii, by the Japanese air force was quickly followed by a string of dazzling Japanese military forays. This Japanese "blitzkrieg" captured tens of thousands of Allied military personnel and civilians. Many were subjected to extraordinarily cruel treatment at the hands of the Japanese victors. One of the first and most important of these battles took place at Guadalcanal in the Solomon Islands, which U.S. marines invaded in August 1942. The Japanese forces on Guadalcanal managed to hold on to the island for five months, despite savage battles with the marines and a withering U.S. naval bombardment and blockade. Finally, as a simple poem by noncommissioned officer Yoshida Kashichi expressed, the Japanese forces were starved into submission, retreating from Guadalcanal in disarray on December 31, 1942.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Überraschung Angriff an Dezember 7, 1941, auf
VEREINIGTE STAATEN militärischen Kräften am Pearl Harbor, Hawaii, 
durch die japanische Luftwaffe wurde schnell von einer Zeichenkette 
des Blendens der japanischen militärischen Beutezüge gefolgt. 
Dieser japanische "Blitzkrieg" erfaßte 10 Tausenden des 
verbündeten militärischen Personals und der Zivilisten. Viele 
wurden außerordentlich grausamer Behandlung an den Händen der 
japanischen Victors unterworfen. Ein vom ersten und wichtigstes 
dieser Schlachten fanden bei Guadalcanal in den Solomon Inseln statt, 
die VEREINIGTE STAATEN Marinen im August 1942 eindrangen. Die 
japanischen Kräfte auf Guadalcanal handhatten, zur Insel für fünf 
Monate, trotz der wilden Schlachten mit den Marinen und eine 
verwelkende VEREINIGTE STAATEN Marinebombardierung und eine Blockade 
an anzuhalten. Schließlich wie ein einfaches Gedicht durch ohne
Patentoffizier Yoshida Kashichi, das, die japanischen Kräfte 
ausgedrückt wurde, in Unterordnung verhungert waren, ziehend von 
Guadalcanal in der Verwirrung an Dezember 31, 1942 zurück.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'attaque de surprise 7 décembre 1941, sur les 
forces militaires des ETATS-UNIS au port de perle, Hawaï, par 
l'Armée de l'Air japonaise a été rapidement suivie d'une chaîne de
caractères de briller des incursions militaires japonaises. 
Cette "guerre éclair" japonaise a capturé des dizaines de 
milliers de personnel et de civils militaires alliés. Beaucoup 
ont été soumis au traitement extraordinairement cruel aux mains des 
vainqueurs japonais. Un du premier et plus important de ces 
batailles ont eu lieu chez Guadalcanal dans les îles Salomon, que les
marines des ETATS-UNIS ont envahies en août 1942. Les forces 
japonaises sur Guadalcanal sont parvenues à se tenir en fonction sur 
l'île pendant cinq mois, en dépit des batailles sauvages avec les 
soldats de marine et un bombardement et un blocus navals de 
flétrissement des ETATS-UNIS. En conclusion, comme une poésie 
simple par l'officier non breveté Yoshida Kashichi exprimé, les 
forces japonaises étaient affamée dans la soumission, retraitant de 
Guadalcanal dans le désordre 31 décembre 1942.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O ataque da surpresa dezembro em 7, 1941, em 
forças militares de ESTADOS UNIDOS no porto de pérola, Havaí, pela 
força aérea japonesa foi seguido rapidamente por uma corda de 
dazzling forays militares japoneses. Este "blitzkrieg japonês" 
capturou dez dos milhares de pessoal e de civis militares aliados. 
Muitos foram sujeitados ao tratamento extraordinària cruel nas 
mãos dos vencedores japoneses. Um do primeiro e o mais 
importante destas batalhas ocorreu em Guadalcanal nos consoles de 
Solomon, que os fuzileiros navais de ESTADOS UNIDOS invadiram em 
agosto 1942. As forças japonesas em Guadalcanal controlaram 
prender sobre ao console por cinco meses, apesar das batalhas 
selvagens com os fuzileiros navais e um bombardeio e um blockade 
navais withering de ESTADOS UNIDOS. Finalmente, como um poema 
simples pelo oficial inferior Yoshida Kashichi expressado, as forças 
japonesas era starved na submissão, recuando de Guadalcanal em 
disarray dezembro em 31, 1942.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'attacco di sorpresa il 7 dicembre 1941, sulle 
forze militari degli STATI UNITI al porto di perla, Hawai, 
dall'aeronautica giapponese è stato seguito rapidamente da una serie 
di abbagliamento dei forays militari giapponesi. Questo 
"blitzkrieg" giapponese ha bloccato i dieci dei migliaia dei personali
e dei civili militari alleati. Molti sono stati sottoposti al 
trattamento straordinario crudele alle mani dei victors giapponesi. 
Uno del primo e più importante di queste battaglie hanno 
avvenuto a Guadalcanal nelle isole di Solomon, che i fanti di marina 
degli STATI UNITI hanno invaso nel mese di agosto del 1942. Le 
forze giapponesi su Guadalcanal sono riuscito a tenere sopra all'isola
per cinque mesi, malgrado le battaglie selvagge con i fanti di marina 
e un bombardamento e un blocco navali d'appassimento degli STATI 
UNITI. Per concludere, come un poem semplice dall'ufficiale 
noncommissioned Yoshida Kashichi espresso, le forze giapponesi era 
affamato nella presentazione, ritirandosi da Guadalcanal in disarray 
il 31 dicembre 1942.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η αιφνιδιαστική επίθεση στις 7 Δεκεμβρίου ..1941, 
στις ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΕΣ στρατιωτικές δυνάμεις στο λιμάνι μαργαριταριών, 
Χαβάη, από την ιαπωνική Πολεμική Αεροπορία ακολουθήθηκε γρήγορα
από μια συμβολοσειρά των εκθαμβωτικών ιαπωνικών στρατιωτικών 
εισβολών. Αυτό το ιαπωνικό "blitzkrieg" συνέλαβε τις 
δεκάδες χιλιάδων συνδεμένοι στρατιωτικοί προσωπικό και πολίτες. 
Πολλοί υποβλήθηκαν στην εξαιρετικά σκληρή επεξεργασία στα 
χέρια των ιαπωνικών victors. Ένας από τον πρώτο και ο 
σημαντικότερος αυτών των μαχών πραγματοποιήθηκε guadalcanal 
στις νήσους του Σολομώντος, στις οποίες τα ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΑ ναυτικά 
εισέβαλαν τον Αύγουστο του 1942. Οι ιαπωνικές δυνάμεις 
guadalcanal κατόρθωσαν να ισχύσουν προς το νησί για πέντε 
μήνες, παρά τις άγριες μάχες με τα ναυτικά και έναν ναυτικούς 
βομβαρδισμό και έναν αποκλεισμό μαρασμού ΗΠΑ. Τέλος, ως 
απλό ποίημα από τον noncommissioned ανώτερο υπάλληλο 
Yoshida Kashichi που εκφράστηκε, οι ιαπωνικές δυνάμεις ήταν 
πεινασμένες στην υποβολή, που υποχωρεί από guadalcanal στην 
αταξία στις 31 Δεκεμβρίου, το 1942.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El ataque de la sorpresa 7 de diciembre de 
1941, en las fuerzas militares de ESTADOS UNIDOS en el puerto de 
perla, Hawaii, por la fuerza aérea japonesa fue seguido rápidamente 
por una cadena de deslumbrar saqueos militares japoneses. 
Este "ataque relámpago japonés" capturó diez de millares de 
personal y de civiles militares aliados. Muchos fueron sujetados
al tratamiento extraordinario cruel en las manos de los vencedores 
japoneses. Uno del primer y la más importante de estas batallas
ocurrió en Guadalcanal en las islas de Solomon, que los infantes de 
marina de ESTADOS UNIDOS invadieron en agosto de 1942. Las 
fuerzas japonesas en Guadalcanal manejaron aferrarse a la isla por 
cinco meses, a pesar de batallas salvajes con los infantes de marina y
un bombardeo y un bloqueo navales de ESTADOS UNIDOS que marchitaban. 
Finalmente, como un poema simple del oficial noncommissioned 
Yoshida Kashichi expresado, las fuerzas japonesas era hambriento en la
sumisión, retirando de Guadalcanal en desorden 31 de diciembre 
de 1942.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087310</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103524</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-japanese-soldier-describes-the-horrors-of-guadalcanal</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
