<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108225</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108225</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087503</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Conclusions and Recommendations by the Committee of Six Disinterested Americans"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Zusammenfassungen und Empfehlungen durch den 
Ausschuß von sechs selbstlosen Amerikanern"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"conclusions et recommandations par le Comité de 
six Américains désintéressés"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"conclusões e recomendações pelo comitê de seis
americanos disinterested"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"conclusioni e raccomandazioni dal comitato di sei 
Americani disinterested"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Συμπεράσματα και συστάσεις από την Επιτροπή έξι 
ανιδιοτελών Αμερικανών"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"conclusiones y recomendaciones del comité de seis
americanos disinterested"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">U.S. marines occupied Haiti from 1915 to 1934. By 1919, Haitian Charlemagne Pralte had organized more than a thousand  cacos , or armed guerrillas, to militarily oppose the marine occupation. The marines responded to the resistance with a counterinsurgency campaign that razed villages, killed thousands of Haitians, and destroyed the livelihoods of even more. In 1926 the Women's International League for Peace and Freedom (WILPF) organized a committee to look into conditions in Haiti and offer alternatives to the American policy of routinely sending in the marines.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">VEREINIGTE STAATEN Marinen besetzten Haiti von 1915
bis 1934. Bis zum 1919 hatte haitianischer Karl der Große 
Pralte mehr als tausend cacos oder bewaffnete Bandenkämpfer 
organisiert, um der Marinebesetzung militärisch entgegenzusetzen. 
Die Marinen reagierten auf den Widerstand mit einer 
Gegenaufstandkampagne, die Dörfer razed, Tausenden Haitianer beendete
und die Lebensunterhalt von sogar mehr zerstörte. In 1926 
organisierte die internationale Liga der Frauen für Frieden und 
Freiheit (WILPF) einen Ausschuß, um in Bedingungen in Haiti zu 
schauen und Alternativen der amerikanischen Politik von in die Marinen
routinemäßig senden anzubieten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les soldats de marine des ETATS-UNIS ont occupé le
Haïti de 1915 à 1934. D'ici 1919, Charlemagne haïtien Pralte 
avait organisé plus que mille cacos, ou les guérilleros armés, pour
s'opposer militairement au métier marin. Les soldats de marine 
ont répondu à la résistance avec une campagne de 
contre-insurrection qui a rasé des villages, a détruit 
des milliers de haïtiens, et a détruit les vies d'encore plus. 
Dans 1926 la ligue internationale des femmes pour la paix et la 
liberté (WILPF) a organisé un comité pour examiner des conditions 
au Haïti et pour offrir des solutions de rechange à la politique 
américaine d'introduire par habitude les marines.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os fuzileiros navais de ESTADOS UNIDOS ocuparam 
Haiti de 1915 a 1934. Por 1919, Charlemagne haitian Pralte tinha
organizado mais do que mil cacos, ou guerrillas armados, para opôr 
militar a ocupação marinha. Os fuzileiros navais responderam 
à resistência com uma campanha do counterinsurgency que razed vilas,
matasse milhares dos haitians, e destruísse os meios de subsistência
de mesmo mais. Em 1926 a liga internacional das mulheres para a 
paz e a liberdade (WILPF) organizou um comitê para olhar em 
condições em Haiti e para oferecer alternativas à política 
americana rotineiramente da emissão nos fuzileiros navais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I fanti di marina degli STATI UNITI hanno occupato 
l'Haiti da 1915 a 1934. Entro 1919, Charlemagne haitian Pralte 
aveva organizzato più di mille cacos, o i guerriglieri muniti, per 
opporre militarmente l'occupazione marina. I fanti di marina 
hanno risposto alla resistenza con una campagna del counterinsurgency 
che razed i villaggi, ha ucciso i migliaia dei haitians ed ha 
distrutto le vite di ancor più. In 1926 la lega 
internazionale delle donne per pace e la libertà (WILPF) ha 
organizzato un comitato per esaminare i termini in Haiti e per offrire
le alternative alla politica americana ordinariamente di introdurre i 
fanti di marina.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ΗΠΑ κατειλημμένη ναυτικά Αϊτή από το 1915 ως το 
1934. Μέχρι το 1919, αϊτινό Charlemagne Pralte 
είχε οργανώσει περισσότερα από χίλια cacos, ή τους 
οπλισμένους αντάρτες, για να αντιτάξει στρατιωτικά το θαλάσσιο 
επάγγελμα. Τα ναυτικά αποκρίθηκαν στην αντίσταση με μια 
εκστρατεία αντιεξέγερσης που τα χωριά, σκότωσε χιλιάδες 
Αϊτινοί, και κατέστρεψε τα livelihoods ακόμη και περισσότερο. 
Το 1926 η διεθνής ένωση των γυναικών για την ειρήνη και 
την ελευθερία (WILPF) οργάνωσε μια επιτροπή για να εξετάσει 
τους όρους στην Αϊτή και να προσφέρει τις εναλλακτικές λύσεις 
στην αμερικανική πολιτική συνήθως να στείλει στα ναυτικά.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los infantes de marina de ESTADOS UNIDOS ocuparon 
Haití a partir de 1915 a 1934. Antes de 1919, Charlemagne 
haitiano Pralte había ordenado más que mil cacos, o a guerrillas 
armados, para oponer militar la ocupación marina. Los infantes 
de marina respondieron a la resistencia con una campaña del 
counterinsurgency que razed aldeas, mató a millares de haitianos, y
destruyó los sustentos de aún más. En 1926 la liga 
internacional de las mujeres para la paz y la libertad (WILPF) ordenó
a comité para mirar en condiciones en Haití y para ofrecer 
alternativas a la política americana rutinariamente de enviar en los 
infantes de marina.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087503</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108225</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/conclusions-and-recommendations-by-the-committee-of-six-disinterested-americans</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
