<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106759</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106759</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086390</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Labor Has To Be International:" David Abdulah Describes Workers Strategies for Organizing Transnational Corporations</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Arbeit Muß International Sein:" David 
Abdulah beschreibt Arbeiter-Strategien für das Organisieren der 
übernationalen Korporationen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le "Travail Doit Être International :" 
David Abdulah décrit des stratégies d'ouvriers pour organiser 
des entreprises transnationales</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O "Trabalho Tem que Ser Internacional:" 
David Abdulah descreve estratégias dos trabalhadores para 
organizar corporation transnational</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Il Lavoro Deve Essere Internazionale:" 
David Abdulah descrive le strategie degli operai per 
l'organizzazione delle società supernazionali</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η εργασία πρέπει να είναι διεθνής:" Δαβίδ 
Abdulah Describes Workers Strategies για τις διεθνικές 
εταιρίες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El "Trabajo Tiene que Ser Internacional:" 
David Abdulah describe las estrategias de los trabajadores para 
ordenar las corporaciones transnacionales</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The power, global reach, and flexibility of multi-national corporations increased dramatically during the 1980's and 1990's as a revolution in communications technology and the increasing adoption of free trade agreements between countries allowed companies to shift production easily from one part of the globe to another. Many companies could now pressure labor unions by negotiating favorable contracts wherever labor costs and local tax laws suited them. However, the increasingly interwoven global economy, along with the technology that facilitated it, also gave rise to international labor organizing. As David Abdulah, education director of the Oilfield Workers Trade Union of Trinidad and Tobago, relates, union organizing and activism has become global, as workers in different countries develop networks across borders to keep up with and combat the unfair labor practices of the multi-nationals.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Energie, die globale Reichweite und die 
Flexibilität der multinationalen Konzerne, die drastisch während der
achtziger Jahre und der neunziger Jahre als Umdrehung in der 
Kommunikationstechnik erhöht wurden und die zunehmende Annahme der 
Freihandelsverträge zwischen Ländern erlaubten Firmen, Produktion 
von einem Teil der Kugel auf andere leicht zu verschieben. Viele
Firmen konnten Arbeiterverbände jetzt druecken, indem sie über 
vorteilhafte Verträge verhandelten, wohin Arbeitskosten und 
Kommunalabgabegesetze ihnen entsprachen. Jedoch verursachte die 
in zunehmendem Maße verwobene globale Wirtschaft, zusammen mit der 
Technologie, die sie erleichterte, auch das internationale 
Arbeitsorganisieren. Als David Abdulah, steht Ausbildung 
Direktor der Ölfeld-Arbeiter-Gewerkschaft von Trinidad und von 
Tobago, in Verbindung, ist das Anschlußorganisieren und -aktivismus 
global geworden, während Arbeiter in den unterschiedlichen Ländern 
Netze über Rändern entwickeln, um mit oben zu halten und die unfaire
Arbeit Praxis der Multinationale zu bekämpfen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La puissance, l'extension globale, et la 
flexibilité des sociétés multinationales multinationales accrues 
excessivement pendant les années 80 et les années 90 comme 
révolution en technologie de transmissions et l'adoption croissante 
des accords de libre-échange entre les pays ont permis à des 
compagnies de décaler la production facilement d'une part du globe à
l'autre. Beaucoup de compagnies pourraient maintenant 
pressuriser les syndicats en négociant les contrats favorables 
partout où les coûts de la main-d'oeuvre de la main-d'oeuvre et les 
lois d'impôt local leur ont convenus. Cependant, l'économie 
globale de plus en plus entrelacée, avec la technologie qui l'a 
facilitée, a également provoqué l'organisation de travail 
internationale. Comme David Abdulah, le directeur d'éducation 
du syndicat d'ouvriers de gisement de pétrole des Trinité-et-Tabago,
rapporte, l'organisation et l'activisme des syndicats est devenue 
global, pendant que les ouvriers dans différents pays développent 
des réseaux à travers des cadres pour suivre et pour combattre les 
pratiques déloyales de travail des multinationales.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A potência, o alcance global, e a flexibilidade 
dos corporation multinacionais aumentados dramàtica durante os 1980's
e os 1990's como uma volta na tecnologia de comunicações e o 
adoption crescente de acordos de comércio livres entre países 
permitiram que as companhias deslocassem a produção fàcilmente de 
uma porção do globo a outra. Muitas companhias poderiam agora 
exercer pressão sobre uniões labor negociando contratos favoráveis 
onde quer que os custos labor e as leis de imposto local os serviram. 
Entretanto, a economia global cada vez mais interwoven, junto 
com a tecnologia que a facilitou, deu também a ascensão a organizar 
labor internacional. Como David Abdulah, o diretor da 
instrução da união de comércio dos trabalhadores do oilfield de 
trinidad e de tobago, relaciona-se, organizar e activism da união 
tornaram-se globais, enquanto os trabalhadores em países diferentes 
desenvolvem redes através das beiras para proseguir com e combater as
práticas de trabalho unfair das multinacionais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'potenza, l'estensione globale e la flessibilità
delle società multinazionali aumentate drammaticamente durante gli 
anni 80 e gli anni 90 come giro nella tecnologia di comunicazioni e 
l'approvazione aumentante degli accordi di libero scambio fra i paesi 
hanno permesso che le aziende spostassero facilmente la produzione da 
una parte del globo ad un altro. Molte aziende potrebbero ora 
pressure i sindacati di lavoro negoziando i contratti favorevoli 
dovunque i costi di lavoro e le leggi di imposta locale li 
soddisfacessero. Tuttavia, l'economia globale sempre più 
intrecciata, con la tecnologia che la ha facilitata, egualmente ha 
provocato l'organizzazione di lavoro internazionale. Come David
Abdulah, il direttore di formazione del sindacato degli operai del 
giacimento di petrolio dei Trinità e Tobago, riferisce, 
l'organizzazione ed il activism del sindacato sono diventato globali, 
mentre gli operai in paesi differenti sviluppano le reti attraverso i 
bordi per continuare con e combattere le pratiche di lavoro ingiuste
delle multinazionali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η δύναμη, η σφαιρική προσιτότητα, και η ευελιξία των 
πολυεθνικών εταιριών αυξήθηκαν εντυπωσιακά κατά τη διάρκεια της 
δεκαετίας του '80 και της δεκαετίας του '90 ως επανάσταση στην 
τεχνολογία επικοινωνιών και η αυξανόμενη υιοθέτηση των συμφωνιών 
ελευθεροποίησης των συναλλαγών μεταξύ των χωρών επέτρεψε στις 
επιχειρήσεις για να μετατοπίσει την παραγωγή εύκολα από ένα 
μέρος της σφαίρας σε άλλο. Πολλές επιχειρήσεις θα 
μπορούσαν τώρα να πιέσουν τα εργατικά συνδικάτα με τη 
διαπραγμάτευση των ευνοϊκών συμβάσεων οπουδήποτε οι δαπάνες 
εργασίας και οι τοπικοί φορολογικοί νόμοι τις ταιρίαξαν. 
Εντούτοις, η όλο και περισσότερο αναμειγμένη σφαιρική 
οικονομία, μαζί με την τεχνολογία που την διευκόλυνε, προκάλεσε 
επίσης τη διεθνή οργάνωση εργασίας. Σαν Δαβίδ Abdulah, ο
σκηνοθέτης εκπαίδευσης του συνδικάτου εργαζομένων πετρελαιοφόρων 
περιοχών του Τρινιδάδ και Τομπάγκο, αφορά, η οργάνωση και ο 
ακτιβισμός ένωσης έχουν γίνει σφαιρικοί, δεδομένου ότι οι 
εργαζόμενοι στις διαφορετικές χώρες αναπτύσσουν τα δίκτυα στα 
σύνορα που συμβαδίζουν με και που καταπολεμούν τις αθέμιτες 
πρακτικές εργασίας των πολυεθνικών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La potencia, el alcance global, y la flexibilidad 
de las corporaciones multinacionales crecientes dramáticamente 
durante los años 80 y los años 90 como revolución en tecnología de
comunicaciones y la adopción de aumento de los acuerdos de libre 
cambio entre los países permitieron que las compañías cambiaran de 
puesto la producción fácilmente a partir de una porción del globo a
otra. Muchas compañías podrían ahora ejercer presión sobre 
sindicatos negociando contratos favorables dondequiera que los costes 
de trabajo y los leyes de impuesto local los satisficieran. Sin 
embargo, la economía global cada vez más entretejida, junto con la 
tecnología que la facilitó, también dio lugar a ordenación de 
trabajo internacional. Como David Abdulah, el director de la 
educación del sindicato de los trabajadores del campo petrolífero de
Trinidad y de Trinidad y Tobago, se relaciona, la ordenación y el 
activismo de la unión ha llegado a ser globales, mientras que los 
trabajadores en diversos países desarrollan redes a través de las 
fronteras para continuar con y para combatir las prácticas de trabajo
injusto de las multinacionales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086390</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106759</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/labor-has-to-be-international-david-abdulah-describes-workers-strategies-for-organizing-transnational-corporations</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
