<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105116</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105116</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212926</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">United States Geologic Survey: Selected Volcano Information</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Vereinigte Staaten Geologische Übersicht: 
Ausgewählte Vulkan-Informationen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Enquête Géologique des Etats-Unis : 
l'Information Choisie de Volcan</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Exame Geologic Unido Dos Estados: 
Informação Selecionada Do Vulcão</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Unito Dichiara L'Indagine Geologica: 
Le Informazioni Selezionate Del Vulcano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ηνωμένη γεωλογική έρευνα: Επιλεγμένες 
πληροφορίες ηφαιστείων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Encuesta sobre Geológica Estados Unidos: 
Información Seleccionada Del Volcán</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This United States Geological Survey (USGS) Volcano Hazards Program site contains links to selected material related to volcanic hazards. Users can access information about the volcanic hazards program, publications, topical maps of volcanoes world wide, aviation safety reports, volcanic hazard reports, computer software, volcano digital series and educational videos. Several USGS fact sheets are also available for volcanoes in Alaska, Arizona, California, Hawaii, the Pacific Northwest and around the world. Fact sheets can be downloaded as pdf files or html. This site contains a wide variety of comprehensive material on the world's volcanoes and the hazards associated with them.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Vereinigte Staaten geologische Übersicht 
(USGS) Site des Vulkan-Gefahr-Programms enthält Links zu 
ausgewähltem materiellem in Verbindung stehendem mit vulkanischen 
Gefahren. Benutzer können auf Informationen über die 
vulkanischen Gefahren Programm, Publikationen, aktuelle Karten der 
Vulkane, Luftfahrtsicherheit Reports, vulkanische Gefahrreports, 
Computer-Software, digitale Serie des Vulkans und pädagogische videos
weltweit zugreifen. Einige USGS Tatsache Blätter sind auch für
Vulkane in Alaska, Arizona, Kalifornien, Hawaii, der pazifische 
Nordwesten und um die Welt vorhanden. Tatsache Blätter können 
als pdf Dateien oder HTML downloadet werden. Diese Site enthält
eine breite Vielzahl des kompletten Materials auf den Vulkanen und den
Gefahren der Welt, die mit ihnen verbunden sind.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site géologique de programme de risques de 
volcan de l'enquête des Etats-Unis (USGS) contient des liens à 
connexe matériel choisi aux risques volcaniques. Les 
utilisateurs peuvent accéder à des informations sur les risques 
volcaniques programme, publications, cartes topiques des volcans dans 
le monde entier, états de sûreté d'aviation, états volcaniques de 
risque, logiciel d'ordinateur, séries digitales de volcan et videos 
éducatifs. Plusieurs fiches documentaires  d'USGS sont 
également disponibles pour des volcans en Alaska, Arizona, la 
Californie, Hawaï, le nord-ouest Pacifique et autour du monde. 
Des fiches documentaires  peuvent être téléchargées comme 
fichiers de pdf ou HTML. Ce site contient une grande variété 
de matériel complet sur les volcans et les risques du monde liés à 
eux.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local geological unido do programa dos 
perigos do vulcão do exame dos estados (USGS) contem as ligações a 
relacionado material selecionado aos perigos vulcânicos. Os 
usuários podem alcançar a informação sobre os perigos vulcânicos 
programa, publicações, mapas tópicos de relatórios largos de mundo
dos vulcões, da aviação da segurança, de relatórios vulcânicos 
do perigo, de software de computador, de séries digitais do vulcão e
de videos educacionais. Diversas folhas do fato de USGS estão 
também disponíveis para vulcões em Alaska, arizona, Califórnia, 
Havaí, o noroeste pacífico e em torno do mundo. As folhas do 
fato podem downloaded como limas do pdf ou HTML. Este local 
contem uma variedade larga do material detalhado nos vulcões e nos 
perigos do mundo associados com eles.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ciò unita Dichiara i rischi geologici del 
vulcano di indagine (USGS) il luogo di programma che contiene i 
collegamenti a relativo materiale selezionato ai rischi vulcanici. 
Gli utenti possono accedere alle informazioni sui rischi 
vulcanici programma, pubblicazioni, programmi d'attualità dei vulcani
universalmente, rapporti di sicurezza di aeronautica, rapporti 
vulcanici di rischio, software di calcolatore, serie digitale del 
vulcano e videos educativi. Parecchi fogli di fatto di USGS sono
egualmente disponibili per i vulcani nell'Alaska, Arizona, la 
California, Hawai, il nord-ovest pacifico ed intorno al mondo. I
fogli di fatto possono essere trasferiti come gli archivi del pdf o 
HTML. Questo luogo contiene un'ampia varietà di materiale 
completo sui vulcani e sui rischi del mondo connessi con loro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή προγράμματος κινδύνων ηφαιστείων 
Ηνωμένων γεωλογική ερευνών (USGS) περιέχει τις συνδέσεις με το
επιλεγμένο υλικό σχετικός με τους ηφαιστειακούς κινδύνους. 
Οι χρήστες μπορούν να έχουν πρόσβαση στις πληροφορίες για 
το ηφαιστειακό πρόγραμμα κινδύνων, τις δημοσιεύσεις, τους 
επίκαιρους χάρτες των ηφαιστείων παγκοσμίως, τις εκθέσεις 
ασφάλειας αεροπορίας, τις ηφαιστειακές εκθέσεις κινδύνου, το 
λογισμικό υπολογιστών, τις ψηφιακές σειρές ηφαιστείων και τα 
εκπαιδευτικά βίντεο. Διάφορα ενημερωτικά δελτία USGS 
είναι επίσης διαθέσιμα για τα ηφαίστεια στην Αλάσκα, Αριζόνα, 
Καλιφόρνια, Χαβάη, τα ειρηνικά βορειοδυτικά και σε όλο τον 
κόσμο. Τα ενημερωτικά δελτία μπορούν να μεταφορτωθούν ως 
pdf αρχεία ή HTML. Αυτή η περιοχή περιέχει μια 
ευρεία ποικιλία του περιεκτικού υλικού στα παγκόσμια ηφαίστεια 
και τους κινδύνους που συνδέονται με τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio geológico del programa de los peligros
del volcán de la encuesta sobre Estados Unidos (USGS) contiene 
conexiones a relacionado material seleccionada a los peligros 
volcánicos. Los utilizadores pueden tener acceso a la 
información sobre los peligros volcánicos programa, publicaciones, 
correspondencias tópicas de volcanes por todo el mundo, informes de 
la seguridad de la aviación, informes volcánicos del peligro, 
software, serie digital del volcán y videos educativos. Varias 
hojas del hecho de USGS están también disponibles para los volcanes 
en Alaska, Arizona, California, Hawaii, el noroeste pacífico y 
alrededor del mundo. Las hojas del hecho se pueden descargar 
como ficheros del pdf o HTML. Este sitio contiene una variedad 
amplia de material comprensivo en los peligros del mundo los volcanes 
y asociados a ellos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212926</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105116</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/united-states-geologic-survey-selected-volcano-information</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
