<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104086</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104086</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087373</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"All To Me Was New and Strange": Mary Doolittle Leaves Her Family for a Shaker Community, 1830</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"alles zu mir war neu und" merkwürdig: Mary
Doolittle läßt ihre Familie für eine Schüttel-Apparatgemeinschaft,
1830</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"tout à moi était nouveau et étrange" : 
Mary Doolittle laisse sa famille pour une Communauté de 
dispositif trembleur, 1830</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"tudo a mim era novo e estranho": Mary 
Doolittle deixa sua família para uma comunidade do shaker, 1830</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"tutto a me era nuovo e sconosciuto": Mary 
Doolittle lascia la sua famiglia per una Comunità dell'agitatore, 
1830</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Όλος σε με ήταν νέος και παράξενοσ": Θ*Μαρυ 
Doolittle Leaves Her Family για μια Κοινότητα δονητών, 
1830</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"todo a mí era nuevo y extraño": Maria 
Doolittle deja a su familia para una comunidad de la coctelera, 1830</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">During the second quarter of the 19th century numerous radical movements emerged, and some withdrew from society and formed ideal or utopian communities. The Shakers (or Shaking Quakers) were the oldest and largest of these utopian movements, founded in Great Britain by Mother Ann Lee, who arrived in North America in 1774. Shakers abandoned the traditional family in favor of a new fellowship of men and women who lived as brothers and sisters, worked in agriculture and artisanal crafts, and adopted the practices of cooperation and celibacy. Many were attracted to their communitarian message, especially women like Mary Doolittle of New Lebanon, New York, who joined the local Shakers (the second of what became 19 communities stretching from New England, across New York, to Ohio and Kentucky). Doolittle narrates her initial emotional conflict between family and belief, and the suspicion, even hostility, of local people toward her new "Family," as Shaker units were called.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während des zweiten Viertels des 19. Jahrhunderts
zahlreichen radikalen tauchten die Bewegungen auf, und einige traten 
von der Gesellschaft zurück und bildeten die idealen oder utopischen 
Gemeinschaften. Die Schüttele-Apparat (oder das Rütteln der 
Quäker) waren von diesen utopischen Bewegungen das älteste und das 
am größten, gegründet in Großbritannien durch Motherann Schutze, 
die in Nordamerika 1774 ankamen. Schüttele-Apparat verließen 
die traditionelle Familie zugunsten eines neuen Stipendiums der 
Männer und der Frauen, die als Brüder und Schwestern lebten, 
Landwirtschaft und artisanal in den Fertigkeiten arbeiteten, und 
nahmen die Praxis von Mitarbeit und von Ehelosigkeit an. Viele 
wurden zu ihrer communitarian Meldung, besonders Frauen wie Mary 
Doolittle vom neuen Libanon, New York angezogen, das die lokalen 
Schüttele-Apparat verband (die Sekunde von, was 19 Gemeinschaften 
stand, die von Neu-England, über New York, nach Ohio und Kentucky 
ausdehnen). Doolittle berichtet ihre emotionale 
zuerst$überschneidung zwischen Familie und Glauben und das 
Misstrauen, sogar Feindseligkeit, der lokalen Leute in Richtung zu 
ihrer neuen "Familie,", wie Schüttel-Apparatmaßeinheiten benannt 
wurden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant le deuxième trimestre du 19ème siècle 
nombreux les mouvements radicaux ont émergé, et certains se sont 
retirés de la société et ont formé les communautés idéales ou 
utopiques. Les dispositifs trembleurs (ou la secousse des 
quakers) étaient les plus vieux et les plus grands de ces mouvements 
utopiques, fondé en Grande-Bretagne par la lie de Mother Ann, qui est
arrivée en Amérique du nord en 1774. Les dispositifs 
trembleurs ont abandonné la famille traditionnelle en faveur d'une 
nouvelle camaraderie des hommes et des femmes qui ont vécu comme 
frères et soeurs, ont travaillé dans des métiers d'agriculture et 
d'artisanal, et ont adopté les pratiques de la coopération et du 
célibat. Beaucoup ont été attirés à leur message 
communautaire, particulièrement femmes comme Mary Doolittle du nouveau 
Liban, New York, qui a adhéré aux dispositifs trembleurs locaux (la 
seconde de ce qui est allé bien aux 19 communautés s'étirant de 
Nouvelle Angleterre, à travers New York, en Ohio et au Kentucky). 
Doolittle relate son conflit émotif initial entre la famille et
la croyance, et le soupçon, même hostilité, des personnes locales 
vers sa nouvelle "famille," comme des unités de dispositif trembleur 
se sont appelées.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Durante o segundo quarto do 1ø século os 
movimentos radicais numerosos emergiram, e alguns retiraram-se da 
sociedade e deram-se forma a comunidades ideais ou utópicas. Os
shakers (ou a agitação de quakers) eram os mais velhos e os maiores 
destes movimentos utópicos, fundado em Grâ Bretanha pelos lee de 
Matriz Ann, que chegaram em America do Norte em 1774. Os shakers
abandonaram a família tradicional no favor de um fellowship novo dos 
homens e das mulheres que viveram como irmãos e irmãs, trabalharam 
em ofícios da agricultura e do artisanal, e adotaram as práticas da 
cooperação e do celibacy. Muitos foram atraídos a sua 
mensagem communitarian, especial mulheres como Mary Doolittle de 
Líbano novo, New York, que juntou os shakers locais (o segundo de o 
que assentou bem em 19 comunidades que esticam de Nova Inglaterra, 
através de New York, a Ohio e a Kentucky). Doolittle narra seu 
conflito emocional inicial entre a família e a opinião, e a 
suspeita, mesmo hostilidade, de povos locais para sua "família nova,"
como as unidades do shaker foram chamadas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Durante il secondo trimestre del diciannovesimo 
secolo i movimenti radicali numerosi sono emerso ed alcuni si sono 
ritirati dalla società ed hanno formato le Comunità ideali o 
utopian. Gli agitatori (o agitare i quakers) erano il più 
vecchio e più grande di questi movimenti utopian, fondato in Gran 
Bretagna dai rifugi della Mother Ann, che sono arrivato in America del
Nord in 1774. Gli agitatori hanno abbandonato la famiglia 
tradizionale per un nuovo fellowship degli uomini e delle donne che 
hanno vissuto come i fratelli e sorelle, hanno lavorato nei mestieri 
di artisanal e di agricoltura ed hanno adottato le pratiche della 
cooperazione e del celibacy. Molti sono stati attratti al loro 
messaggio communitarian, particolarmente donne come Mary Doolittle di 
nuovo Libano, New York, che ha aderito agli agitatori locali (il 
secondo di che cosa ha stato bene a 19 Comunità che allungano dalla 
Nuova Inghilterra, attraverso New York, nell'Ohio e nel Kentucky). 
Doolittle narra il suo conflitto impressionabile iniziale fra la
famiglia e la credenza ed il sospetto, persino ostilità, della gente 
locale verso la sua nuova "famiglia," come le unità dell'agitatore 
sono state chiamate.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατά τη διάρκεια του δεύτερου τετάρτου του 19$ου 
αιώνα οι πολυάριθμες ριζικές μετακινήσεις προέκυψαν, και μερικοί
απέσυραν από την κοινωνία και διαμόρφωσαν τις ιδανικές ή 
ουτοπιστικές κοινότητες. Οι δονητές (ή τίναγμα Quakers) 
ήταν οι παλαιότεροι και οι μεγαλύτεροι αυτών των ουτοπιστικών 
μετακινήσεων, ίδρυσαν στη Μεγάλη Βρετανία από τη μητέρα ANN 
Lee, η οποία έφθασε στη Βόρεια Αμερική σε 1774, δονητές 
εγκατέλειψε την παραδοσιακή οικογένεια υπέρ μιας νέας υποτροφίας
των ανδρών και των γυναικών που έζησαν όπως οι αδελφοί και οι 
αδελφές, εργάστηκαν στη γεωργία και τις χειρωνακτικές τέχνες, και
υιοθέτησαν τις πρακτικές της συνεργασίας και της αγαμίας. 
Πολλοί προσελκύστηκαν στο κοινοτικό μήνυμά τους, ειδικά 
γυναίκες όπως Mary Doolittle του νέου Λιβάνου, Νέα Υόρκη, 
η οποία ένωσε τους τοπικούς δονητέσυδεύτερος (' δεύτερος αυτό 
που έγινε 19 κοινότητες εκτειμένος από τη Νέα Αγγλία, πέρα 
από τη Νέα Υόρκη, στο Οχάιο και το Κεντάκυ). Το 
Doolittle διηγείται την αρχική συναισθηματική σύγκρουσή της 
μεταξύ της οικογένειας και της πεποίθησης, και την υποψία, ακόμη 
και εχθρότητα, των τοπικών ανθρώπων προς τη νέα "οικογένειά 
της," καθώς οι μονάδες δονητών κλήθηκαν.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Durante el segundo trimestre del diecinueveavo 
siglo los movimientos radicales numerosos emergieron, y algunos se 
retiraron de sociedad y formaron a comunidades ideales o utópicas. 
Las coctelera (o sacudarir a quakers) eran el el más viejo y 
más grande de estos movimientos utópicos, fundado en Gran Bretaña 
por las heces de Mother Ana, que llegaron en Norteamérica en 1774. 
Las coctelera abandonaron a familia tradicional en favor de una 
nueva beca de los hombres y de las mujeres que vivieron como hermanos 
y hermanas, trabajaron en artes de la agricultura y del artisanal, y 
adoptaron las prácticas de la cooperación y del celibato. 
Muchos fueron atraídos a su mensaje communitarian, 
especialmente mujeres como Maria Doolittle de Líbano nuevo, Nueva 
York, que ensambló las coctelera locales (el segundo de qué sintió 
bien a 19 comunidades que estiraban de Nueva Inglaterra, a través de 
Nueva York, a Ohio y a Kentucky). Doolittle narra su conflicto 
emocional inicial entre la familia y la creencia, y la suspicacia, 
incluso hostilidad, de la gente local hacia su nueva "familia," como 
las unidades de la coctelera fueron llamadas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087373</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104086</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/all-to-me-was-new-and-strange-mary-doolittle-leaves-her-family-for-a-shaker-community-1830</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
