<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108520</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108520</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212652</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Modern Atmospheric CO2 Record</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Moderne Atmosphärische CO2 Satz</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">l'Enregistrement Atmosphérique Moderne de CO2</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Registro Atmosférico Moderno do CO2</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Record Atmosferico Moderno del CO2</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το σύγχρονο ατμοσφαιρικό αρχείο του CO2</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Expediente Atmosférico Moderno del CO2</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this activity, students compare carbon dioxide (CO2) data from Mauna Loa Observatory , Barrow (Alaska) , and the South Pole over the past 40 years to help them better understand what controls atmospheric (CO2). On this Starting point page, users can access information about the exercise's learning goals, context for use, teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment ideas, references and topics covered.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In dieser Aktivität vergleichen Kursteilnehmer 
Daten des Kohlendioxyds (CO2) Mauna Loa von der Sternwarte, vom Karren
(Alaska) und vom Südpol über den letzten 40 Jahren, um ihnen besser,
zu helfen zu verstehen, welche Kontrollen atmosphärisch (CO2). 
Auf dieser Ausgangspunktseite können Benutzer auf Informationen
über die erlernenziele der Übung, Kontext für Gebrauch-, die 
Unterrichtenumfaßten anmerkungen und Spitzen, Lehrmittel, 
Einschätzung Ideen, Referenzen und Themen zugreifen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cette activité, les étudiants comparent des
données d'anhydride carbonique (CO2) d'observatoire de Mauna Loa, de 
brouette (Alaska), et du Polonais du sud au cours des 40 
dernières années pour les aider mieux à comprendre quelles 
commandes atmosphériques (CO2). À cette page de point de 
départ, les utilisateurs peuvent accéder aux informations sur les 
buts d'étude de l'exercice, contexte pour les extrémités 
d'utilisation, d'enseignement les notes et, le matériel didactique, 
les idées d'évaluation, les références et les sujets couverts.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta atividade, os estudantes comparam dados do 
dióxido de carbono (CO2) do obervatório de Mauna Loa, do carrinho de
mão (Alaska), e do pólo sul sobre os 40 anos passados para 
ajudar-lhes mais melhor compreender que controles atmosféricos (CO2).
Nesta página do ponto começar, os usuários podem alcançar a 
informação sobre os objetivos de aprendizagem do exercício, 
contexto para as pontas do uso, ensinar as notas e, os materiais de 
ensino, as idéias da avaliação, as referências e os tópicos 
cobertos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questa attività, gli allievi confrontano i 
dati dell'anidride carbonica (CO2) dall'osservatorio di Mauna Loa, 
dalla carriola (Alaska) e dal palo del sud in questi ultimi 40 anni 
per aiutarli più meglio a capire che comandi atmosferici (CO2). 
A questa pagina del punto di partenza, gli utenti possono 
accedere alle informazioni sugli obiettivi imparanti 
dell'esercitazione, contesto per le punte di istruzione, di uso note 
e, i materiali didattici, le idee di valutazione, i riferimenti ed i 
soggetti coperti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτήν την δραστηριότητα, οι σπουδαστές συγκρίνουν 
τα στοιχεία διοξειδίου του άνθρακα (CO2) από το παρατηρητήριο 
Mauna loa, το χειραμάξιο (Αλάσκα), και το νότιο Πολωνό κατά
τη διάρκεια των προηγούμενων 40 ετών για να τους βοηθήσουν να 
καταλάβουν καλύτερα ποιοι έλεγχοι ατμοσφαιρικοί (CO2). Σε
αυτήν την σελίδα αφετηρίας, οι χρήστες μπορούν να έχουν 
πρόσβαση στις πληροφορίες για τους στόχους εκμάθησης της άσκησης,
πλαίσιο για τη χρήση, τις σημειώσεις και τις άκρες διδασκαλίας, 
τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, τις ιδέες αξιολόγησης, τις αναφορές και τα
θέματα που καλύπτονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta actividad, los estudiantes comparan datos 
del bióxido de carbono (CO2) del observatorio de Mauna Loa, de la 
carretilla (Alaska), y del poste del sur sobre los últimos 40 años 
para ayudarles mejor a entender qué controles atmosféricos (CO2). 
En esta paginación del punto de partida, los utilizadores 
pueden tener acceso a la información sobre las metas que aprenden del
ejercicio, contexto para las extremidades del uso, de la enseñanza 
las notas y, los materiales didácticos, las ideas del gravamen, las 
referencias y los asuntos cubiertos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY EARTH AND ENVIRONMENTAL SCIENCE FACULTY
FN:COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY EARTH AND ENVIRONMENTAL SCIENCE FACULTY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212652</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108520</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-modern-atmospheric-co2-record</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
