<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106538</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106538</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206941</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Concord.org Five Lessons</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Concord.org Fünf Lektionen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Leçons de Concord.org Cinq</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Lições De Concord.org Cinco</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lezioni Di Concord.org Cinque</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Concord.org πέντε μαθήματα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Lecciones De Concord.org Cinco</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features activities and software for exploring key math and science concepts. A grapher without numeric values introduces calculus concepts in early grades. Students create populations that reproduce according to Mendelian genetics. They design molecules and watch molecules self-assemble. When keys on their calculator are disabled, students must develop work-around solutions.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Merkmale Aktivitäten und Software für 
erforschende Schlüsselmathe- und Wissenschaftskonzepte. Ein 
grapher ohne numerische Werte stellt Kalkülkonzepte in den frühen 
Graden vor. Kursteilnehmer stellen Bevölkerungen her, die 
entsprechend Mendelian Genetik reproduzieren. Sie konzipieren 
Moleküle und Uhrmoleküle Selbst-bauen zusammen. Wenn Tasten 
auf ihrem Rechner untauglich sind, müssen Kursteilnehmer 
Work-aroundlösungen entwickeln.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">activités et logiciel de dispositifs pour des 
concepts principaux les explorant de maths et de science. Un 
grapher sans valeurs numériques présente des concepts de calcul dans
les catégories tôt. Les étudiants créent les populations qui
se reproduisent selon la génétique de Mendelian. Ils 
conçoivent les molécules et les molécules art de l'auto-portrait-assemble de 
montre. Quand les clés sur leur calculatrice sont handicapées,
les étudiants doivent développer des solutions de work-around.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">atividades e software das características para 
conceitos chaves explorando do math e da ciência. Um grapher 
sem valores numéricos introduz conceitos do cálculo em classes 
adiantadas. Os estudantes críam as populações que reproduzem 
de acordo com o genetics de Mendelian. Projetam moléculas e as 
moléculas do relógio self-montam. Quando as chaves em sua 
calculadora são disabled, os estudantes devem desenvolver soluções 
do work-around.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">attività e software delle caratteristiche per i 
concetti chiave d'esplorazione di scienza e di per la matematica. 
Un grapher senza valori numerici introduce i concetti di calcolo
nei gradi in anticipo. Gli allievi creano le popolazioni che 
riproducono secondo la genetica di Mendelian. Progettano le 
molecole e le molecole della vigilanza auto-montano. Quando i 
tasti sul loro calcolatore sono disabled, gli allievi devono 
sviluppare le soluzioni di work-around.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">δραστηριότητες και λογισμικό χαρακτηριστικών 
γνωρισμάτων για να ερευνήσει τις βασικές έννοιες math και 
επιστήμης. Ένα grapher χωρίς αριθμητικές τιμές εισάγει 
τις έννοιες υπολογισμού στους πρόωρους βαθμούς. Οι 
σπουδαστές δημιουργούν τους πληθυσμούς που αναπαράγουν σύμφωνα με
τη μεντελική γενετική. Σχεδιάζουν τα μόρια και τα μόρια 
ρολογιών μόνος-συγκεντρώνουν. Όταν τα πλήκτρα στον 
υπολογιστή τους τίθενται εκτός λειτουργίας, οι σπουδαστές πρέπει
να αναπτύξουν work-around τις λύσεις.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">actividades y software de las características 
para los conceptos dominantes de la matemáticas que exploran y de la 
ciencia. Un grapher sin valores numéricos introduce conceptos 
del cálculo en grados tempranos. Los estudiantes crean a 
poblaciones que se reproducen según la genética de Mendelian. 
Diseñan las moléculas y las moléculas del reloj uno 
mismo-ensamblan. Cuando los claves en su calculadora son 
lisiados, los estudiantes deben desarrollar soluciones del 
work-around.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206941</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106538</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/concord-org-five-lessons</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
