<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107514</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107514</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086492</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Mug shot.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Becherschuß.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Projectile d'attaque à main armée.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Tiro da caneca.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Colpo della tazza.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πλάνο κουπών.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Tiro de la taza.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This 1903 police department arrest record reflects the faith in data and science espoused by some Progressives. The reputedly scientific measurements instituted by French anthropologist Alphonse Bertillon claimed to detect innate criminality and other character flaws, many associated with particular ethnic and racial groups, through physical evidence. Although it bore the stamp of scientific approval, this and other contemporary techniques for differentiating people based on race or physical characteristics incorporated widely held beliefs that Southern Europeans, Asians, and African Americans were inherently and biological different from and inferior to white Anglo Saxons. These beliefs, in turn, lent credence to the rise of Jim Crow and immigrant exclusion.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser Anhaltensatz die Abteilung mit 1903 Polizeien 
reflektiert den Glauben in den Daten und in Wissenschaft, die von 
einigen Progressisten unterstützt werden. Die angeblich 
wissenschaftlichen Messen, die vom French Anthropologen Alphonse 
Bertillon eingeleitet wurden, behaupteten, angeborene Kriminalität 
zu entdecken und andere Zeichenfehler, viele verbanden mit bestimmten 
ethnischen und rassischen Gruppen, durch körperlichen Beweis. 
Obgleich er Ausbohrung der Stempel der wissenschaftlichen 
Zustimmung, der dieser und anderer zeitgenössischer Techniken für 
das Unterscheiden der Leute, die auf Rennen basierten oder der 
körperlichen Eigenschaften weit angehaltenen Glauben enthielt, daß 
Südeuropäer, Asiaten und afrikanische Amerikaner in sich selbst und 
biologisches unterschiedliches zu und Untergebenes zu weißem 
Anglosaxons waren. Dieses verlieh Glaube der Reihe nach Glauben 
zum Anstieg des Jim Krähe- und Immigrantausschlusses.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cet enregistrement d'arrestation de service de 1903 
polices reflète la foi dans les données et la science embrassées 
par quelques progressifs. Les mesures d'après les informations 
reçues scientifiques instituées par l'anthropologue Alphonse 
Bertillon de French ont prétendu détecter la criminalité innée et 
d'autres imperfections de caractère, beaucoup se sont associées aux 
groupes ethniques et raciaux particuliers, par l'évidence physique. 
Bien qu'elle alésage le timbre de l'approbation scientifique, 
de ceci et d'autres techniques contemporaines pour différencier des 
personnes basées sur la course ou des caractéristiques physiques ait
incorporé la croyance largement tenue qu'Européens méridionaux, 
Asiatiques, et Américains africains étaient en soi et différent 
biologique de et subordonné à Saxons anglo blanc. Ces la 
croyance, à leur tour, a prêté la créance à l'élévation de 
l'exclusion de corneille et d'immigré de Jim.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este registro da apreensão do departamento de 1903 
polícias reflete a fé nos dados e na ciência espoused por alguns 
progressistas. As medidas reputedly científicas instituídas 
pelo antropólogo Alphonse Bertillon de Francês reivindicaram 
detectar o criminality innate e outras falhas do caráter, muitas 
associaram com os grupos étnicos e raciais particulares, com a 
evidência física. Embora furo o selo da aprovaçã0 
científica, desta e de outras técnicas contemporary para diferenciar
os povos baseados na raça ou características físicas incorporasse a
opinião extensamente prendida que Europeus do sul, os asians, e os 
americanos africanos eram inerente e diferente biológico de e 
inferior a Saxons anglo branco. Este a opinião, por sua vez, 
emprestou o credence à ascensão da exclusão do corvo e do immigrant
de Jim.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo record di arresto di reparto delle 1903 polizie 
riflette la fede nei dati e nella scienza espoused da alcuni 
progressives. Le misure reputato scientifiche istituite 
dall'antropologo Alphonse Bertillon del French hanno sostenuto 
rilevare il criminality innato ed altri difetti del carattere, molti 
si sono associati con i gruppi etnici e razziali particolari, con 
prova fisica. Anche se foro il bollo di approvazione 
scientifica, questa e di altre tecniche contemporanee per 
differenziare la gente basata sulla corsa o le caratteristiche fisiche
ha compreso la credenza ampiamente tenuta che Europei del sud, gli 
asiatici e gli Americani africani erano inerentemente e differente 
biologico da ed inferior a Saxons anglo bianco. Questo la 
credenza, a sua volta, ha prestato il credence all'aumento 
dell'esclusione del corvo e dell'immigrante di Jim.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το αρχείο σύλληψης τμημάτων αστυνομίας του 
1903 απεικονίζει την πίστη στα στοιχεία και την επιστήμη που 
παντρεύεται από κάποιο Progressives. Οι reputedly 
επιστημονικές μετρήσεις που καθιερώθηκαν από το γαλλικό 
ανθρωπολόγο Alphonse Bertillon υποστήριξαν ότι ανιχνεύουν 
την έμφυτη εγκληματικότητα και άλλες ρωγμές χαρακτήρα, πολλές 
που συνδέθηκαν με τις συγκεκριμένες εθνικές και φυλετικές ομάδες,
μέσω των φυσικών στοιχείων. Αν και άντεξε το γραμματόσημο 
της επιστημονικής έγκρισης, αυτό και άλλες σύγχρονες τεχνικές 
για τους ανθρώπους βασισμένα στη φυλή ή τα φυσικά χαρακτηριστικά
που ενσωματώθηκε ευρέως κράτησαν τις πεποιθήσεις ότι οι νότιοι 
Ευρωπαίοι, Ασιάτες, και αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί ήταν εγγενώς και 
βιολογικοί διαφορετικός από και κατώτερος από τους λευκούς 
Σάξονες Anglo. Αυτές οι πεποιθήσεις, στη συνέχεια, 
δάνεισαν credence στην άνοδο jim Crow και του που έχουν 
μεταναστεύσει αποκλεισμού.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este expediente de la detención del departamento de 1903 
policía refleja la fe en los datos y la ciencia espoused por algunos 
progresistas. Las medidas reputado científicas instituidas por 
el antropólogo Alphonse Bertillon french demandaron detectar 
criminalidad natural y otros defectos del carácter, muchos se asociaron
a los grupos étnicos y raciales determinados, con evidencia física. 
Aunque alesaje el sello de la aprobación científica, de ésta 
y de otras técnicas contemporáneas para distinguir la gente basada 
en la raza o características físicas incorporó creencia 
extensamente llevada a cabo que europeos meridionales, los asiáticos,
y los americanos africanos estaban intrínsecamente y diferente 
biológico de e inferior a Saxons anglo blanco. Este la 
creencia, alternadamente, prestó crédito a la subida de la 
exclusión del cuervo y del inmigrante de Jim.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086492</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107514</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/mug-shot</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
