<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107793</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107793</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086709</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Our People Were Dedicated": Organizing with the American G.I. Forum</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Unsere Leute Waren" Engagiert: Organisieren
mit amerikanischen G.I. Forum</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Nos Personnes Étaient Dédiées" : 
Organisation avec G.I. Forum américain</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Nossos Povos Eram Dedicados": Organizar com
o G.I. americano Forum</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"La Nostra Gente Era Dedicata": Organizzando
con il G.I. Forum americano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Οι άνθρωποί μας αφιερώθηκαν": Οργάνωση με το 
αμερικανικό G.I. φόρουμ</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Nuestra Gente Era Dedicada": Ordenación 
con el G.I. americano Forum</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Founded in 1948 as an advocacy group for Mexican American veterans of World War II, the American G.I. Forum evolved into one of the leading civil rights organizations of the postwar era. Led by a medical doctor from Corpus Christi, Texas, Dr. Hector P. Garcia (1914-1996), the group attained national recognition in 1949 when they organized protests against a funeral home that would not allow chapel services for a Mexican American soldier, Felix Longoria, who was killed in combat four years earlier in the Philippines. With the intervention of Senator Lyndon B. Johnson, Longoria was buried in Arlington National Cemetery. Patriotic in intent and constituted of locally-run units, the Forum sought to work from the "bottom up" to involve ordinary citizens in public life and to put an end to discriminatory practices that affected veterans and their families. Working in the communities and the courts, the Forum led poll tax drives and campaigned against segregated schools, for adequate health care, and to improve the lot of migrant workers. In 1958, the Forum became a national organization. With an earlier civil rights group that also originated in Texas, the League of United Latin American Citizens (LULAC), the Forum campaigned in 1960 in Viva Kennedy clubs, contributing to the future president's narrow victory in Texas that helped win the national election. Forum members worked with the Johnson administration to implement Great Society programs in Mexican American communities, and in 1967, Vicente Ximenes, a former national chairman, became the head of the Inter-Agency Cabinet Committee on Mexican American Affairs and EEOC commissioner. In the following interview, Ed Idar, a long-time colleague of Dr. Garcia, related the dedicated efforts of group leaders to organize throughout the state.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gegründet in 1948 als Befürwortung Gruppe für 
mexikanische amerikanische Veterane des Zweiten Weltkrieges, der 
Amerikaner G.I. Forum entwickelt in eine der führenden 
Zivilrechtorganisationen der Nachkriegsära. Geführt durch 
einen medizinischen Doktor von Corpus Christi, erreichte Texas, Dr. 
Tyrann P. Garcia (1914-1996), die Gruppe nationale Anerkennung 1949, 
als sie Proteste gegen ein Begräbnis- Haus, das nicht 
Kapelleservices für einen mexikanischen amerikanischen Soldaten 
erlauben würde, Felix Longoria organisierten, das im Kampf vier Jahre
früh in den Philippinen beendet wurde. Mit der Intervention des
Senators Lyndon B. Johnson, Longoria wurde im Arlington 
Staatsangehörig-Kirchhof begraben. Patriotisch in der Absicht 
und von festgesetzt lokal-lassen Sie Maßeinheiten, das Forum laufen, 
das gesucht wird, um von der "Unterseite oben zu arbeiten", um 
gewöhnliche Bürger in allgemeine Lebensdauer mit einzubeziehen und 
ein Ende zur diskriminierenden Praxis zu setzen, die Veterane und ihre
Familien beeinflußte. Arbeitend in den Gemeinschaften und in 
den Gerichten, führte das Forum Gemeindeabgabelaufwerke und warb 
gegen getrennte Schulen, für ausreichende Gesundheitspflege und das 
Lot der Gastarbeiter zu verbessern. 1958 wurde das Forum eine 
nationale Organisation. Mit gruppieren frühere Zivilrechte das,
das auch in Texas, die Liga der vereinigten lateinamerikanischen 
Bürger (LULAC) entstanden wird, das Forum warben 1960 Viva Kennedy in
den Vereinen und tragen zum zukünftigen schmalen Sieg des 
Präsidenten in Texas bei, das Gewinn die nationale Wahl half. 
Forumbauteile arbeiteten mit der Johnson Leitung, um große 
Gesellschaftprogramme in den mexikanischen amerikanischen 
Gemeinschaften und 1967, Vicente Ximenes, ein ehemaliger nationaler 
Vorsitzender einzuführen, wurden der Kopf des 
Vermittlungsagentur-Schrank-Ausschusses für mexikanische 
amerikanische Angelegenheiten und EEOC Beauftragten. Im 
folgenden Interview stand ED Idar, ein langfristiger Kollege von Dr. 
Garcia, die engagierten Bemühungen der Gruppe Führer in Verbindung, 
während des Zustandes zu organisieren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Fondé dans 1948 en tant que groupe de 
recommandation pour les vétérans américains mexicains de la 
deuxième guerre mondiale, l'Américain G.I. Forum transformé en un 
des principaux organismes de droits civiques de l'ère 
d'après-guerre. Mené par un docteur médical à partir de 
Corpus Christi, le Texas, Dr. fanfaron P. Garcia (1914-1996), le 
groupe a atteint l'identification nationale en 1949 où ils ont 
organisé des protestations contre une maison funèbre qui ne 
permettrait pas des services de chapelle pour un soldat américain 
mexicain, Felix Longoria, qui a été détruit dans le combat quatre 
ans plus tôt aux Philippines. Avec l'intervention du sénateur 
Lyndon B. Johnson, Longoria a été enterré dans le cimetière de 
national de Arlington. Patriotique dans l'intention et 
constitué de local-exécutez les unités, le forum recherché pour 
travailler du "bas vers le haut" pour faire participer les citoyens 
ordinaires dans la vie publique et pour mettre un terme aux pratiques 
discriminatoires qui ont affecté des vétérans et leurs familles. 
Travaillant dans les communautés et les cours, le forum a mené
des lecteurs d'impôt local et a fait campagne contre les écoles 
isolées, pour la santé adéquate, et pour améliorer le sort de 
travailleurs migrants. En 1958, le forum est devenu une 
organisation nationale. Avec plus tôt droits civiques groupent 
cela également provenu du Texas, la ligue des citoyens 
latino-américains unis (LULAC), le forum ont fait campagne en 1960 
dans des clubs de Viva Kennedy, contribuant du futur à la victoire
étroite président dans le Texas qui a aidé la victoire l'élection 
nationale. Les membres de forum ont travaillé avec la gestion 
de Johnson pour mettre en application de grands programmes de 
société dans les communautés américaines mexicaines, et en 1967, 
Vicente Ximenes, un ancien Président national, sont devenus le chef 
du comité de Module de médiation des affaires américaines 
mexicaines et du commissaire d'EEOC. Dans l'entrevue suivante, 
ED Idar, un collègue à long terme de Dr. Garcia, a associé les 
efforts dédiés des amorces de groupe d'organiser dans tout l'état.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fundado em 1948 como um grupo do advocacy para 
veterans americanos mexicanos da segunda guerra mundial, o americano 
G.I. Forum evoluído em uma das organizações principais das direitas
civis da era postwar. Conduzido por um doutor médico do corpus 
Christi, Texas, Dr. hector P. Garcia (1914-1996), o grupo alcançou o 
recognition nacional em 1949 em que organizou protestos de encontro a 
uma HOME funeral que não permitisse serviços de chapel para um 
soldado americano mexicano, Felix Longoria, que foi matado no combate 
quatro anos mais cedo nas Filipinas. Com a intervenção do 
senator Lyndon B. Johnson, Longoria foi enterrado no cemetery do 
nacional de Arlington. Patriotic na intenção e constituído de
local-funcione unidades, o forum procurado trabalhar acima do "fundo" 
para envolver cidadãos ordinários na vida pública e para pôr uma 
extremidade às práticas discriminatory que afetaram veterans e suas 
famílias. Trabalhando nas comunidades e nas cortes, o forum 
conduziu a movimentações do imposto de votação e fêz campanha de 
encontro às escolas segregadas, para o cuidado de saúde adequado, e 
para melhorar o lote de trabalhadores emigrantes. Em 1958, o 
forum transformou-se uma organização nacional. Com umas 
direitas civis mais adiantadas agrupam aquela originada também em 
Texas, liga dos cidadãos americanos latin unidos (LULAC), o forum 
fizeram campanha em 1960 nos clubes de Viva Kennedy, contribuindo à 
vitória estreita do presidente futuro em Texas que ajudou à vitória
a eleição nacional. Os membros do forum trabalharam com a 
administração de Johnson para executar programas grandes da 
sociedade em comunidades americanas mexicanas, e em 1967, Vicente 
Ximenes, um presidente nacional anterior, transformaram-se a cabeça 
do comitê do armário do inter-Agency em casos americanos mexicanos e
em comissário de EEOC. Na seguinte entrevista, o Ed Idar, um 
colega long-time do Dr. Garcia, relacionou os esforços dedicados de 
líderes do grupo organizar durante todo o estado.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fondato in 1948 come gruppo di avvocatura per i 
veterani americani messicani della seconda guerra mondiale, 
l'americano G.I. Forum evoluta in una delle organizzazioni principali 
di diritti civili dell'era dopoguerra. Condotto da un medico 
medico da Corpus Christi, il Texas, il Dott. il tormentatore P. Garcia
(1914-1996), il gruppo ha raggiunto il riconoscimento nazionale in 
1949 in cui hanno organizzato le proteste contro una sede funerea che 
non permetterebbe i servizi di chapel per un soldato americano 
messicano, Felix Longoria, che è stato ucciso nel combattimento 
quattro anni più presto nelle Filippine. Con l'intervento del 
senatore Lyndon B. Johnson, Longoria è stato sepolto nel cimitero del
cittadino de Arlington. Patriotic nell'intenzione e costituito 
di locale-faccia funzionare le unità, la tribuna cercata per lavorare
"dalla parte inferiore in su" per fare partecipare i cittadini 
ordinari nella vita pubblica e per mettere un termine alle pratiche 
discriminatorie che hanno interessato i veterani e le loro famiglie. 
Funzionando nelle Comunità e nelle corti, la tribuna ha 
condotto gli azionamenti di imposta di scrutinio ed ha fatto una 
campagna contro le scuole segregate, per sanità sufficiente e 
migliorare il lotto dei lavoratori migranti. In 1958, la tribuna
si è transformata in in un'organizzazione nazionale. Con i 
diritti civili più iniziali raggruppano quello anche provenuto dal 
Texas, la lega dei cittadini dell'America latina uniti (LULAC), la 
tribuna hanno fatto una campagna in 1960 nei randelli di Viva Kennedy,
contribuenti alla vittoria stretta del presidente futuro nel Texas che
ha aiutato la vittoria l'elezione nazionale. I membri della 
tribuna lavorati con la gestione di Johnson per effettuare i programmi
grandi della società nelle Comunità americane messicane ed in 1967,
Vicente Ximenes, un ex presidente nazionale, sono diventato la testa 
del comitato del Governo di mediazione per gli affari americani 
messicani ed il commissario di EEOC. Nella seguente intervista,
il Ed Idar, un collega long-time del Dott. Garcia, ha collegato gli 
sforzi dedicati dei capi del gruppo organizzare durante il 
dichiarare.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ιδρυμένο το 1948 ως ομάδα υπεράσπισης για τους 
μεξικάνικους αμερικανικούς παλαιμάχους του παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ,
το αμερικανικό G.I. φόρουμ εξελίχθηκε σε μια από τις κύριες 
οργανώσεις αστικών δικαιωμάτων της μεταπολεμικής εποχής. 
Οδηγημένος από έναν ιατρό από το Κόρπους Κρίστι, Τέξας, 
ο Δρ Hector P. Garcia (1914-1996), η ομάδα επέτυχε την 
εθνική αναγνώριση το 1949 όταν οργάνωσαν τις διαμαρτυρίες 
ενάντια σε ένα νεκρικό σπίτι που δεν θα επέτρεπε στις υπηρεσίες 
παρεκκλησιών για έναν μεξικάνικο αμερικανικό στρατιώτη, Felix 
Longoria, το οποίο σκοτώθηκε στον αγώνα τέσσερα έτη νωρίτερα 
στις Φιλιππίνες. Με την επέμβαση του γερουσιαστή Lyndon 
B. Johnson, Longoria θάφτηκε στο εθνικό νεκροταφείο 
Arlington. Πατριωτικό σε προσηλωμένο και αποτελεσμένο των 
μονάδων τοπικά-τρεξίματος, το φόρουμ επιδίωξε να εργαστεί από 
το "κατώτατο σημείο επάνω" για να περιλάβει τους απλούς πολίτες 
στη δημόσια ζωή και για να βάλει ένα τέλος στις μεροληπτικές 
πρακτικές που είχαν επιπτώσεις στους παλαιμάχους και τις 
οικογένειές τους. Εργαζόμενο στις κοινότητες και τα 
δικαστήρια, το φόρουμ οδήγησε τις κινήσεις κεφαλικού φόρου και 
έκανε εκστρατεία ενάντια στα διαχωρισμένα σχολεία, για την 
επαρκή υγειονομική περίθαλψη, και για να βελτιώσει το μέρος των 
διακινούμενων εργαζομένων. Το 1958, το φόρουμ έγινε 
εθνική οργάνωση. Με μια πιό πρώτη ομάδα αστικών 
δικαιωμάτων που δημιουργήθηκε επίσης στο Τέξας, η ένωση των 
ενωμένων λατινοαμερικανικών πολιτών (LULAC), το φόρουμ έκανε 
εκστρατεία το 1960 στις λέσχες Viva Kennedy, που 
συμβάλλουν στη στενή νίκη του μελλοντικού Προέδρου στο Τέξας που
βοήθησε να κερδίσει την εθνική εκλογή. Τα μέλη φόρουμ 
συνεργάστηκαν με την κυβέρνηση Johnson για να εκτελέσουν τα 
μεγάλα προγράμματα κοινωνίας στις μεξικάνικες αμερικανικές 
κοινότητες, και το 1967, Vicente Ximenes, ένας 
προηγούμενος εθνικός πρόεδρος, έγιναν ο προϊστάμενος της 
Επιτροπής γραφείου οργανισμού διαμεσολάβησης των μεξικάνικων 
αμερικανικών υποθέσεων και του Επιτρόπου EEOC. Στην 
ακόλουθη συνέντευξη, οι ΕΔ Idar, ένας μακροπρόθεσμος 
συνάδελφος του Δρ Garcia, αφορούσαν τις αφιερωμένες προσπάθειες
των ηγετών ομάδας που οργανώνουν σε όλο το κράτος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fundado en 1948 como grupo de la defensa para los 
veteranos americanos mexicanos de la Segunda Guerra Mundial, el 
americano G.I. Forum desarrollado en una de las organizaciones 
principales de las derechas civiles de la era de la posguerra. 
Conducido por un doctor médico de la recopilación Christi, 
Tejas, el Dr. matón P. Garcia (1914-1996), el grupo logró el 
reconocimiento nacional en 1949 en que él ordenó protestas contra 
una funeraria que no permitiría los servicios de capilla para un 
soldado americano mexicano, Felix Longoria, que fue matado en combate 
cuatro años anterior en las Filipinas. Con la intervención de 
senador Lyndon B. Johnson, Longoria fue enterrado en cementerio del 
nacional de Arlington. Patriótico en intento y constituido de 
local-ejecute las unidades, el foro intentado para trabajar del "fondo
para arriba" para implicar a ciudadanos ordinarios en vida pública y 
para poner fin a las prácticas discriminatorias que afectaron a 
veteranos y a sus familias. Trabajando en las comunidades y las 
cortes, el foro condujo mecanismos impulsores del impuesto de encuesta
e hizo campaña contra escuelas segregadas, para el cuidado médico 
adecuado, y mejorar a la porción de trabajadores emigrantes. En
1958, el foro se convirtió en una organización nacional. Con 
las derechas civiles anteriores agrupan eso también originada en 
Tejas, la liga de los ciudadanos americanos latinos unidos (LULAC), el
foro hicieron campaña en 1960 en los clubs de Viva Kennedy, 
contribuyendo a la victoria estrecha del presidente futuro en Tejas 
que ayudó a triunfo la elección nacional. Los miembros del 
foro trabajaron con la administración de Johnson para poner grandes 
programas de la sociedad en ejecucio'n en comunidades americanas 
mexicanas, y en 1967, Vicente Ximenes, presidente nacional anterior, 
hicieron la pista del comité de la cabina de la interagencia sobre 
asuntos americanos mexicanos y la comisión de EEOC. En la 
entrevista siguiente, el Ed Idar, colega de largo plazo del Dr. 
Garcia, relacionó los esfuerzos dedicados de los arranques de cinta 
del grupo de ordenar a través del estado.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086709</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107793</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/our-people-were-dedicated-organizing-with-the-american-g-i-forum</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
