<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104161</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104161</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206514</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Pearl Harbor Raid</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Pearl- Harborüberfall</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Incursion de Port de Perle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Invasão Do Porto De Pérola</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Incursione Del Porto Di Perla</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Λιμενική επιδρομή μαργαριταριών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Incursión Del Puerto De Perla</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a detailed account of the December 7, 1941, attack. More than 100 photos and descriptions look at the 7 U.S. battleships moored along Battleship Row that morning, attacks off Ford Island, attacks in the Navy yard area, attacks on airfields, Japanese aircraft and midget submarines used in the attacks, aerial combat, and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist eine spezifizierte Rechnung des Dezembers 7, 
1941, Angriff. Mehr als 100 Fotos und Beschreibungen betrachten 
die 7 VEREINIGTE STAATEN Linienschiffe, die entlang Linienschiff-Reihe
festgemacht werden, die Morgen, Angriffe weg von der Ford Insel, 
Angriffe im Marineyardbereich, Angriffe auf Flugplätzen, japanisches 
Flugzeug und Zwergunterseeboote in den Angriffen, im Luftkampf und in 
mehr verwendeten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est un compte détaillé décembre de 7, 1941, 
attaque. Plus de 100 photos et descriptions regardent les 7 
cuirassés des ETATS-UNIS amarrés le long de la ligne de cuirassé 
que le matin, les attaques outre de l'île de Ford, les attaques dans 
la zone de yard de marine, les attaques sur des terrains d'aviation, 
l'avion japonais et les sous-marins de miniature ont utilisée dans 
les attaques, le combat aérien, et les plus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é um cliente detalhado dezembro do 7, 1941, 
ataque. Mais de 100 fotos e descrições olham os 7 cruzadores 
de batalha de ESTADOS UNIDOS amarrados ao longo da fileira do cruzador
de batalha que a manhã, os ataques fora do console de Ford, os 
ataques na área da Arsenal de Marinha, os ataques em aeródromos, o 
avião japonês e os submarinos do anão usaram nos ataques, no 
combate aéreo, e no mais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è un cliente dettagliato de 7 dicembre 1941, 
attacco. Più di 100 foto e descrizioni guardano i 7 battleships
degli STATI UNITI attraccati lungo la fila del battleship che la 
mattina, gli attacchi fuori dell'isola del Ford, gli attacchi nella 
zona dell'iarda di blu marino, gli attacchi agli aerodromi, il 
velivolo giapponese ed i sommergibile del midget hanno usato negli 
attacchi, nel combattimento aereo e nei più.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι ένας λεπτομερής απολογισμός της 7ης Δεκεμβρίου 
..1941, επίθεση. Περισσότερες από 100 φωτογραφίες και 
περιγραφές εξετάζουν τα 7 ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΑ θωρηκτά που δένονται κατά 
μήκος της σειράς θωρηκτών που το πρωί, οι επιθέσεις από το νησί
διάβασης, οι επιθέσεις στην περιοχή ναυπηγείων ναυτικού, οι 
επιθέσεις στα αεροδρόμια, τα ιαπωνικά αεροσκάφη και τα 
μικροσκοπικά υποβρύχια χρησιμοποίησαν στις επιθέσεις, τον εναέριο
αγώνα, και περισσότεροι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es una cuenta detallada del de diciembre 7 de 
1941, ataque. Más de 100 fotos y descripciones miran los 7 
acorazados de ESTADOS UNIDOS amarrados a lo largo de la fila del 
acorazado que la mañana, los ataques de la isla de Ford, los ataques 
en el área de la yarda de la Marina de guerra, los ataques contra campos de
aviación, el avión japonés y los submarinos del enano utilizaron en
los ataques, el combate aéreo, y más.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206514</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104161</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/pearl-harbor-raid</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
