<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108477</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108477</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086457</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Making the World "Safe for Democracy": Woodrow Wilson Asks for War</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Welt "Safe bilden für Demokratie": 
Woodrow Wilson bittet um Krieg</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Faisant le monde "coffre-fort pour la démocratie"
: Woodrow Wilson demande la guerre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fazendo o mundo "cofre para a democracia": 
Woodrow Wilson pede guerra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Facendo il mondo "cassaforte per la democrazia": 
Woodrow Wilson chiede la guerra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κάνοντας τον κόσμο "χρηματοκιβώτιο για τη δημοκρατία":
Το Woodrow Wilson ζητά τον πόλεμο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Haciendo el mundo "caja fuerte para la 
democracia": Woodrow Wilson pide guerra</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">On April 2, 1917, President Woodrow Wilson went before a joint session of Congress to seek a Declaration of War against Germany in order that the world "be made safe for democracy." Four days later, Congress voted to declare war, with six senators and fifty congressmen dissenting. "It is a fearful thing," he told Congress in his speech, "to lead this great peaceful people into war, into the most terrible and disastrous of all wars, civilization itself seeming to be in the balance." Wilson did not exaggerate; in 1917 the war in Europe had already lasted two-and-a-half bloody years and had become one of the most murderous conflicts in human history. By the time the war ended a year and a half later, an entire generation was decimated--France alone lost half its men between the ages of twenty and thirty-two. The maimed bodies of millions of European men who survived bore mute testimony to the war's savagery.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">An April 2, 1917, Präsident Woodrow Wilson ging 
vor einer gemeinsamen Sitzung des Kongresses, eine Erklärung des 
Krieges gegen Deutschland zu suchen, so dass die Welt "wird gebildet 
sicher für Demokratie." Vier Tage später, wählte Kongreß, um
Krieg zu erklären, wenn sechs Senatoren und fünfzig 
Kongreßabgeordnete nicht übereinstimmen. "es ist eine 
ängstliche Sache," er erklärte Kongreß in seiner Rede, ", um diese 
großen ruhigen Leute in Krieg zu führen, in das schrecklichste und 
das verhängnisvoll von allen Kriegen, die Zivilisation selbst, die 
scheint, in der Balance zu sein." Wilson nicht übertreiben; 
in 1917 hatte der Krieg in Europa bereits Zwei-und-einhälfte 
blutige Jahre gedauert und gewordenes der mörderischesten 
$überschneidungen in der menschlichen Geschichte hatte. Bis der
später beendete Krieg ein Jahr und eine Hälfte, ein gesamtes 
Erzeugung dezimiert wurde -- Frankreich alleine verlorene Hälfte 
seine Mann zwischen dem Alter von Zwanzig und thirty-two. Die 
entstellten Körper von Millionen der europäischen Männer, die 
Ausbohrung stummes Zeugnis zur Unzivilisiertheit des Krieges überlebten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">2 avril 1917, le Président Woodrow Wilson est 
allé avant une session commune du congrès rechercher une 
déclaration de guerre contre l'Allemagne pour que le monde "soit 
rendu sûr pour la démocratie." Pendant quatre jours plus tard,
le congrès a voté pour déclarer la guerre, avec six sénateurs et 
cinquante membres du Congrès différant d'opinion. "c'est une 
chose craintive," il a dit le congrès dans son discours, "pour mener 
ces grandes personnes paisibles dans la guerre, dans le plus terrible 
et désastreux de toutes les guerres, la civilisation elle-même 
semblant être dans l'équilibre." Wilson pas  exagèrent ; 
dans 1917 la guerre en Europe avait déjà duré des années 
sanglantes de deux-et-un-moitié et a eu devenu des conflits les plus 
meurtriers dans l'histoire humaine. Avant que la guerre 
terminée une année et une moitié plus tard, une génération 
entière ait été décimée -- seule de la France moitié détruite 
hommes de ses entre les âges de vingt et le thirty-two. Les 
corps mutilés des millions d'hommes européens qui ont survécu 
témoignage muet d'être à la sauvagerie de la guerre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Abril em 2, 1917, presidente Woodrow Wilson foi 
antes de uma sessão comum do congress procurar uma declaração da 
guerra de encontro a Germany a fim de que o mundo "fosse feito seguro 
para a democracia." Quatro dias mais tarde, o congress votou 
para declarar a guerra, com os seis senators e os cinqüênta 
congressistas que dissenting. "é uma coisa temível," ele disse
o congress em seu discurso, "para conduzir a este pessoa calmo grande 
na guerra, no mais terrível e desastroso de todas as guerras, 
civilização própria que parece estar no contrapeso." Wilson 
não  exaggerate; em 1917 a guerra em Europa já tinha durado 
anos sangrentos da dois-e-um-metade e teve tornado dos conflitos os 
mais murderous no history humano. Pelo tempo a guerra terminada 
um ano e uma metade mais tarde, uma geração inteira foi dizimada -- 
de France metade perdida homens sozinho dos seus entre as idades de 
vinte e o thirty-two. Os corpos maimed dos milhões dos homens 
europeus que sobreviveram testimony mute do furo ao savagery da 
guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il 2 aprile 1917, il presidente Woodrow Wilson è 
andato prima di una sessione unita del congresso cercare una 
dichiarazione della guerra contro la Germania affinché il mondo "è 
reso sicuro per la democrazia." Quattro giorni più 
successivamente, il congresso ha votato per dichiarare la guerra, con 
sei senatori e cinquanta membri del Congresso che dissenting. 
"è una cosa spaventosa," lui ha detto al congresso nel suo 
discorso, "per condurre questa gente pacifica grande nella guerra, nel
più terribile e disastroso di tutte le guerre, la civilizzazione in 
se che sembra essere nell'equilibrio." Wilson non esagera; 
in 1917 la guerra in Europa già aveva durato gli anni 
sanguinanti di due-e-un-metà ed ha avuta quello diventato dei 
conflitti più murderous nella storia umana. Per il momento in 
cui la guerra si concluda più successivamente un anno e una metà, 
un'intera generazione è stata decimata -- della Francia uomini da 
solo metà persa dei relativi fra le età di venti ed il thirty-two. 
I corpi maimed di milioni di uomini europei che sono 
sopravvissuto testimonianza muta del foro al savagery della guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στις 2 Απριλίου ..1917, ο Πρόεδρος Woodrow 
Wilson πήγε πριν από μια κοινή περίοδο επικοινωνίας του 
συνεδρίου να επιδιώξει μια Διακήρυξη του πολέμου ενάντια στη 
Γερμανία για ο κόσμος "γίνεται ασφαλής για τη δημοκρατία." 
Τέσσερις ημέρες αργότερα, το συνέδριο ψήφισε να κηρύξει 
τον πόλεμο, με τη διαφωνία έξι γερουσιαστών και πενήντα μελών 
του Κογκρέσσου. "Είναι ένα έντρομο πράγμα," είπε το 
συνέδριο στην ομιλία του, "στο μόλυβδο αυτό μεγάλοι ειρηνικοί 
άνθρωποι στον πόλεμο, σε ο πιό φοβερός και καταστρεπτικός όλων 
των πολέμων, ο ίδιος πολιτισμός που φαίνονται να είναι στην 
ισορροπία." Θ*Ωηλσον δεν υπερέβαλε  το 1917 ο 
πόλεμος στην Ευρώπη είχε διαρκέσει ήδη δύο-και-α-μισά αιματηρά
έτη και είχε γίνει μια από τις πιό δολοφονικές συγκρούσεις στην
ανθρώπινη ιστορία. Ώσπου να τελείωσε ο πόλεμος ενάμιση 
χρόνο αργότερα, μια ολόκληρη παραγωγή αποδεκατίστηκε -- μισά 
από τα άτομα της Γαλλίας της μόνο χαμένα μεταξύ των ηλικιών 
είκοσι και τριάντα δύο. Οι ακρωτηριασμένοι οργανισμοί των 
εκατομμυρίων των ευρωπαϊκών ατόμων που επέζησαν κατέδειξαν 
βουβή την πολεμική αγριότητα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">2 de abril de 1917, presidente Woodrow Wilson 
fue antes de una sesión común del congreso a buscar un declaración 
de la guerra contra Alemania para hacer el mundo "seguro para la 
democracia." Cuatro días más adelante, el congreso votó para 
declarar guerra, con seis senadores y cincuenta miembros del Congreso 
dissenting. "es una cosa temerosa," él dijo a congreso en su 
discurso, "para conducir a esta gran gente pacífica en guerra, en el 
el más terrible y desastroso de todas las guerras, civilización sí 
mismo que se parece estar en el equilibrio." Wilson no  exagera;
en 1917 la guerra en Europa había durado años sangrientos de 
la dos-y-uno-mitad y tenía ya convertido de los conflictos más 
murderous de la historia humana. Para el momento en que la 
guerra terminada un año y una mitad más adelante, una generación 
entera fuera diezmada -- de Francia hombres solamente mitad perdida de
sus entre las edades de veinte y el thirty-two. Los cuerpos 
maimed de millones de hombres europeos que sobrevivieron testimonio 
mudo del alesaje al salvajismo de la guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086457</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108477</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/making-the-world-safe-for-democracy-woodrow-wilson-asks-for-war</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
