<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107611</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107611</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086707</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Our Nation Is Moving Toward Two Societies, One Black, One White--Separate and Unequal": Excerpts from the Kerner Report</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"unsere Nation bewegt in Richtung zu zwei 
Gesellschaften, ein Schwarzes, ein verschiedenes und ungleiches Weiß 
--": Excerpts vom Kerner Report</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"notre nation se déplace vers deux sociétés, un
noir, un blanc -- séparé et inégal" : Extraits de l'état 
Kerner</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"nossa nação está movendo-se para duas 
sociedades, um preto, um branco -- separado e desigual": 
Excerpts do relatório de Kerner</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la nostra nazione sta muovendosi verso due 
società, un nero, l'un bianco -- separato e disuguale": Brani 
dal rapporto Kerner</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Το έθνος μας κινείται προς δύο κοινωνίες, ένας 
Μαύρος, ένα λευκό -- χωριστό και άνισο": Αποσπάσματα από 
τη kerner έκθεση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"nuestra nación se está moviendo hacia dos 
sociedades, un negro, un blanco -- separado y desigual": 
Extractos del informe de Kerner</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">President Lyndon Johnson formed an 11-member National Advisory Commission on Civil Disorders in July 1967 to explain the riots that plagued cities each summer since 1964 and to provide recommendations for the future. The Commission's 1968 report, informally known as the Kerner Report, concluded that the nation was "moving toward two societies, one black, one white--separate and unequal." Unless conditions were remedied, the Commission warned, the country faced a "system of 'apartheid'" in its major cities. The Kerner report delivered an indictment of "white society" for isolating and neglecting African Americans and urged legislation to promote racial integration and to enrich slums--primarily through the creation of jobs, job training programs, and decent housing. President Johnson, however, rejected the recommendations. In April 1968, one month after the release of the Kerner report, rioting broke out in more than 100 cities following the assassination of civil rights leader Martin Luther King, Jr. In the following excerpts from the Kerner Report summary, the Commission analyzed patterns in the riots and offered explanations for the disturbances. In 1998, 30 years after the issuance of the Report, former Senator and Commission member Fred R. Harris co-authored a study that found the racial divide had grown in the ensuing years with inner-city unemployment at crisis levels. Opposing voices argued that the Commission's prediction of separate societies had failed to materialize due to a marked increase in the number of African Americans living in suburbs.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Präsident Lyndon Johnson bildete eine nationale 
beratende Kommission 11-member auf Zivilstörungen im Juli 1967, um 
die Aufstände zu erklären, die Städte jeder Sommer seit 1964 
quälten und Empfehlungen während der Zukunft zur Verfügung zu 
stellen. Der Report der Kommission 1968, formlos bekannt als der
Kerner Report, festgestellt, daß die Nation "in Richtung zu zwei 
Gesellschaften bewog, ein Schwarzes, ein Weiß -- verschieden und 
ungleich." Es sei denn Bedingungen behoben wurden, stellte die 
gewarnte Kommission, das Land ein "System von ' Apartheid '" in seinen
Hauptstädte gegenüber. Der Kerner Report lieferte eine Anklage
"der weißen Gesellschaft" für das Lokalisieren und das 
Vernachlässigen der afrikanischen Amerikaner und drängte auf 
Gesetzgebung, um rassische Integration zu fördern und Elendsviertel 
-- hauptsächlich durch die Kreation von Jobs, von Jobtrainingskursen 
und von annehmbarem Gehäuse anzureichern. Präsident Johnson 
wies jedoch die Empfehlungen zurück. Im April 1968, ein Monat 
nachdem die Freigabe des Kerner Reports, randalierend in mehr als 100 
Städte ausbrach, die der Ermordung Zivilrechtführer Martin Luther 
des Königs folgen, Jr. In den folgenden Excerpts von der Kerner
Reportzusammenfassung, analysierte die Kommission Muster in den 
Aufständen und gab Erklärungen für die Störungen. 1998 
Co-schrieben 30 Jahre nach der Austeilung des Reports, ehemaliges 
Senator- und Kommissionsmitglied Fred R. Harris eine Studie, die das 
rassische fand sich zu teilen war gewachsen in den folgenden Jahren 
mit Innerstadt Arbeitslosigkeit auf Krise Stufen. 
Entgegensetzende Stimmen argumentierten, daß die Vorhersage der
Kommission der unterschiedlichen Gesellschaften wegen einer markierten
Zunahme der Zahl den afrikanischen Amerikanern hatte verwirklichen 
nicht gekonnt, die in den Vororten leben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Président Lyndon Johnson a formé une 
Commission 11-member Consultative nationale sur des désordres civils 
en juillet 1967 pour expliquer les émeutes qui ont infesté des 
villes chaque été depuis 1964 et pour fournir des recommandations à
l'avenir. L'état de la Commission 1968, officieusement connu 
sous le nom d'état Kerner, conclu que la nation "se déplaçait vers 
deux sociétés, un noir, un blanc -- séparé et inégal." À 
moins que des conditions aient été remédiées à, la Commission 
avertie, le pays a fait face à un "système de la 'ségrégation '" 
dans ses villes principales. L'état Kerner a fourni un acte 
d'accusation "de la société blanche" pour isoler et négliger les 
Américains africains et a invité la législation pour favoriser 
l'intégration raciale et pour enrichir taudis -- principalement par 
la création des travaux, des programmes de formation du travail, et 
du logement décent. Président Johnson, cependant, a 
rejeté les recommandations. En avril 1968, pendant un mois 
après que la version de l'état Kerner, s'ameutant a éclaté dans 
plus de 100 villes suivant l'assassinat du roi de Martin Luther du 
Chef de droits civiques, Jr. Dans les extraits suivants du 
sommaire d'état Kerner, la Commission a analysé des configurations 
dans les émeutes et a offert des explications pour les perturbations.
En 1998, 30 ans après le établissement de l'état, ancien 
membre de la Commission Fred R. Harris de sénateur et Co-ont écrit 
une étude qui a trouvé le racial pour se diviser s'était 
développée en années suivantes avec le chômage d'intérieur-ville 
aux niveaux de crise. Les voix d'opposition ont argué du fait 
que la prévision de la Commission des sociétés séparées avait 
échoué pour matérialiser en raison d'une augmentation marquée du 
nombre d'Américains africains vivant dans les banlieues.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O presidente Lyndon Johnson deu forma a um 
commission 11-member consultivo nacional em disorders civis em julho 
1967 para explicar os motins que flagelaram cidades cada verão desde 
1964 e para fornecer recomendações para o futuro. O relatório
do commission 1968, sabido informal como o relatório de Kerner, 
conclído que a nação "se estava movendo para duas sociedades, um 
preto, um branco -- separado e desigual." A menos que as 
circunstâncias fossem remediadas, o commission advertido, o país 
enfrentou um "sistema ' do apartheid '" em suas cidades principais. 
O relatório de Kerner entregou um indictment "da sociedade 
branca" para isolar e negligenciar americanos africanos e incitou a 
legislação para promover a integração racial e para enriquecer 
slums -- primeiramente através da criação dos trabalhos, dos 
programas de treinamento do trabalho, e da carcaça decent. O 
presidente Johnson, entretanto, rejeitou as recomendações. Em 
abril 1968, um mês depois que a liberação do relatório de Kerner, 
se amotinando quebrou para fora em mais de 100 cidades que seguem o 
assassination do rei de Martin Luther de chefes dos direitos civis, 
Jr. Nos seguintes excerpts do sumário do relatório de Kerner, 
o commission analisou testes padrões nos motins e ofereceu 
explanações para os distúrbios. Em 1998, 30 anos após a 
emissão do relatório, o membro anterior Fred R. Harris do senator e 
de commission co-foram o autor de um estudo que encontrasse o racial 
para se dividir crescesse nos anos seguindo com desemprego da 
interno-cidade em níveis da crise. As vozes opondo-se 
discutiram que a predição do commission de sociedades separadas não
materialize  devido a um aumento marcado no número dos americanos 
africanos que vivem nos suburbs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il presidente Lyndon Johnson ha formato una 
Commissione consultiva nazionale 11-member sui disordini civili nel 
mese di luglio del 1967 per spiegare i tumulti che hanno contagiato le
città ogni estate dal 1964 e per fornire le raccomandazioni per il 
futuro. La relazione della Commissione 1968, conosciuta senza 
formalità come il rapporto Kerner, conclusivo che la nazione "stava 
muovendosi verso due società, un nero, un bianco -- separato e 
disuguale." A meno che le circostanze siano rimediate, la 
Commissione avvertita, il paese ha affrontato "un sistema 'di 
segregazione '" nelle relative città importanti. Il rapporto 
Kerner ha trasportato un atto d'accusa "della società bianca" per 
l'isolamento e trascurare degli Americani africani ed ha invitato la 
legislazione per promuovere l'integrazione razziale e per arricchire 
slums -- soprattutto attraverso la creazione dei lavori, dei programmi
di formazione di lavoro e dell'alloggiamento decent. Il 
presidente Johnson, tuttavia, ha rifiutato le raccomandazioni. 
Nel mese di aprile del 1968, un mese dopo che la versione del 
rapporto Kerner, sollevantesi scoppi in più di 100 città che seguono
l'assassinio del re del Martin Luther del capo di diritti 
civili, Jr. Nei seguenti brani dal sommario rapporto Kerner, nei
modelli analizzati Commissione nei tumulti e nelle spiegazioni offerte
per le dispersioni. In 1998, 30 anni dopo l'emissione del 
rapporto, l'ex membro Fred R. Harris della Commissione e del senatore 
co-hanno creato uno studio che ha trovato il razziale per dividersi si
era sviluppato durante gli anni seguenti con disoccupazione della 
interno-città ai livelli di crisi. Le voci avversarie hanno 
sostenuto che la previsione della Commissione delle società separate 
non era riuscito ad attuare dovuto un profondo aumento nel numero di 
Americani africani che vivono in periferia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο Πρόεδρος Lyndon Johnson διαμόρφωσε την εθνική 
συμβουλευτική Επιτροπή 11-μελών στις αστικές αναταραχές τον 
Ιούλιο του 1967 για να εξηγήσει τις ταραχές που μόλυναν τις 
πόλεις κάθε καλοκαίρι από το 1964 και για να προβεί στις 
συστάσεις για το μέλλον. Η έκθεση του 1968 της Επιτροπής,
ανεπίσημα γνωστή ως kerner έκθεση, κατέληξε στο συμπέρασμα 
ότι το έθνος "κινούταν προς δύο κοινωνίες, ένας Μαύρος, ένα 
λευκό -- χωριστό και άνισο." Εκτός αν οι όροι 
θεραπεύθηκαν, η Επιτροπή που προειδοποιήθηκε, η χώρα αντιμετώπισε
ένα "σύστημα" του απαρτχάιντ "" στις μεγάλες πόλεις της. Η 
kerner έκθεση παρέδωσε μια μήνυση της "λευκιάς κοινωνίασ" για 
την απομόνωση και την παραμέληση αφρικανικών Αμερικανών και ώθησε
τη νομοθεσία για να προωθήσει τη φυλετική ολοκλήρωση και για να 
εμπλουτίσει τις τρώγλες -- πρώτιστα μέσω της δημιουργίας των 
εργασιών, των προγραμμάτων επαγγελματικής κατάρτισης, και της 
κόσμιης κατοικίας. Ο Πρόεδρος Johnson, εντούτοις, 
απέρριψε τις συστάσεις. Τον Απρίλιο του 1968, έναν μήνα 
μετά από την έκδοση της kerner έκθεσης, η στάση ξέσπησε σε 
περισσότερες από 100 πόλεις μετά από τη δολοφονία του ηγέτη 
Martin Luther King, Jr αστικών δικαιωμάτων. Στα 
ακόλουθα αποσπάσματα από τη kerner περίληψη εκθέσεων, η 
Επιτροπή ανέλυσε τα πρότυπα στις ταραχές και πρόσφερε τις 
εξηγήσεις για τις διαταραχές. Το 1998 ..30 έτη μετά 
από την έκδοση της έκθεσης, του προηγούμενων γερουσιαστή και του 
μέλους Fred R. Harris της Επιτροπής συνυπογράφον μια 
μελέτη που βρήκε τη φυλετική διαίρεση είχε αυξηθεί στα επόμενα 
έτη με inner-city την ανεργία σε επίπεδα κρίσης. Οι 
αντιτιθέμενες φωνές υποστήριξαν ότι η πρόβλεψη της Επιτροπής των
χωριστών κοινωνιών είχε αποτύχει να υλοποιήσει λόγω μιας 
χαρακτηρισμένης αύξησης στον αριθμό αφρικανικών Αμερικανών που 
ζουν στα προάστια.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Presidente Lyndon Johnson formó una Comisión 
consultiva nacional 11-member en desórdenes civiles en julio de 1967 
para explicar los alborotos que plagaron ciudades cada verano desde 
1964 y para proporcionar a las recomendaciones para el futuro. 
El informe de la Comisión 1968, conocido informal como el 
informe de Kerner, concluido que la nación "se movía hacia dos 
sociedades, un negro, un blanco -- separado y desigual." A menos
que las condiciones fueran remediadas, la Comisión advertida, el 
país hizo frente a un "sistema del ' apartheid '" en sus ciudades 
importantes. El informe de Kerner entregó una acusación de la 
"sociedad blanca" para aislar y descuidar a americanos africanos e 
impulsó la legislación para promover la integración racial y para 
enriquecer los tugurios -- sobre todo a través de la creación de 
trabajos, de los programas de entrenamiento del trabajo, y de la 
cubierta decente. Presidente Johnson, sin embargo, rechazó las 
recomendaciones. En abril de 1968, un mes después de que el 
desbloquear del informe de Kerner, desenfrenándose explotó en más 
de 100 ciudades que seguían el asesinato del rey de Martin Luther del
arranque de cinta de las derechas civiles, Jr. En los extractos 
siguientes del resumen del informe de Kerner, la Comisión analizaba 
modelos en los alborotos y ofreció las explicaciones para los 
disturbios. En 1998, 30 años después de la emisión del 
informe, el miembro anterior Fred R. Harris del senador y de la 
Comisión co-fueron autor de un estudio que encontró el racial para 
dividirse había crecido en los años que sobrevenían con el 
desempleo de la interno-ciudad en los niveles de la crisis. Las 
voces de oposición discutieron que la predicción de la Comisión de 
sociedades separadas no había podido materializar debido a un aumento
marcado en el número de los americanos africanos que vivían en 
suburbios.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086707</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107611</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/our-nation-is-moving-toward-two-societies-one-black-one-white-separate-and-unequal-excerpts-from-the-kerner-report</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
