<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105254</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105254</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086223</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"He Lov'd the  English  Extraordinary Well": Enoe Will Guides John Lawson Through the Carolina Interior, 1709</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"er Lov'd die englische außerordentliche 
Vertiefung": Enoe Wille führen John Lawson durch das Carolina 
Inneren, 1709</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"il Lov'd le puits extraordinaire anglais" : 
La volonté d'Enoe guident John Lawson par l'intérieur de la 
Caroline, 1709</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"ele Lov'd o poço extraordinário inglês": 
A vontade de Enoe guia John Lawson através do interior de 
Carolina, 1709</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"lui Lov'd il pozzo straordinario inglese": 
La volontà di Enoe guida John Lawson attraverso l'interiore 
della Carolina, 1709</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Αυτός Lov'd αγγλικός ο εξαιρετικός καλά": Το
Enoe οδηγοί John Lawson μέσω του εσωτερικού της 
Καρολίνας, 1709</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"él Lov'd el receptor de papel extraordinario 
inglés": La voluntad de Enoe dirige a Juan Lawson a través del
interior de Carolina, 1709</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The entry of Europeans into the Indian's world caused a series of dislocations through disease, trade, and warfare. Indian leaders, who encountered new diplomatic and trading partners, found themselves caught between a familiar old and an unsettling new world. John Lawson, employed by Carolina's proprietor to explore the colony's backcounry and aspiring to a career as a natural scientist, spent months traveling through the Carolina interior in the company of colonists and Indians. This excerpt from Lawson's published account of the trip describes the final leg of the journey, when Lawson relied on Enoe Will, the chief of the Eno-Shakori. Will was a well known and trusted guide among colonial traders. He confided to Lawson that he feared he had alienated some of his own people, and now sought European protection. But Will remained close to his native religion and roundly rejected Lawson's offer of conversion to Christianity.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Eintrag von Europäern in die Welt des Inders 
verursachte eine Reihe Versetzungen durch Krankheit, Handel und 
Kriegsführung. Indische Führer, die neue diplomatische und 
Handelspartner antrafen, gefunden abgefangen zwischen einer vertrauten
alten und unsettling neuen Welt. John Lawson, eingesetzt vom 
Eigentümer Carolinas, um der Kolonie zu erforschen, die zu einer 
Karriere als natürlicher Wissenschaftler backcounry und gestrebt 
worden sein würde, verbrachte die Monate, die durch das Carolina 
Inneren in der Firma der Kolonisten und der Inder reisen. Dieses
Excerpt von Lawsons erschienenem Konto der Reise beschreibt den 
letzten Durchgang der Reise, als Lawson auf Enoe Willen beruhte, der 
Leiter des Eno-Shakori. Wille war eine weithin bekannte und 
verläßliche Anleitung unter Kolonialhändlern. Er vertraute zu
Lawson, das er fürchtete, daß er einige seiner eigenen Leute 
entfremdet und jetzt europäischen Schutz gesucht hatte. Aber 
Wille blieb nah an seiner gebürtigen Religion und Angebot rund 
zurückgewiesenen Lawsons der Konvertierung zum Christentum.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'entrée d'Européens au monde de l'Indien a 
causé une série de dislocations par la maladie, le commerce, et la 
guerre. Amorces indiennes, qui ont rencontré de nouveaux 
partenaires commerciaux diplomatiques et, trouvées attrapés entre un
vieux et nouveau monde ébranlant familier. John Lawson,
utilisé par le propriétaire de la Caroline pour explorer la colonie 
backcounry et aspirante à une carrière en tant que scientifique 
normal, a passé des mois voyageant par l'intérieur de la Caroline à
la compagnie des colons et des Indiens. Cet extrait du compte 
édité de Lawson du voyage décrit le parcours final du voyage, quand
Lawson s'est fondé sur la volonté d'Enoe, le chef de l'Eno-Shakori. 
La volonté était un guide bien connu et de confiance parmi les
commerçants coloniaux. Il s'est confié à Lawson qu'il ait 
craint qu'il avait aliéné certaines de ses propres personnes, et 
avait maintenant recherché la protection européenne. Mais la 
volonté est demeurée près de son religion indigène et offre de 
Lawson rondement rejeté de conversion en christianisme.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A entrada de Europeus no mundo do indian causou 
uma série dos dislocations com a doença, o comércio, e a guerra. 
Líderes indian, que encontraram sócios diplomatic e negociando
novos, encontrados travados entre um mundo novo velho e unsettling 
familiar. John Lawson, empregado pelo proprietor de Carolina 
para explorar a colônia backcounry e que aspiring a uma carreira como
um cientista natural, gastou os meses que viajam através do interior 
de Carolina na companhia dos colonos e dos indians. Este excerpt
do cliente publicado de Lawson do desengate descreve o pé final da 
viagem, quando Lawson confiou na vontade de Enoe, o chefe do 
Eno-Shakori. A vontade era uma guia sabida e confiada do poço 
entre comerciantes coloniais. Confiou a Lawson que temeu que 
alienated alguns de seus próprios povos, e tinha procurado agora a 
proteção européia. Mas a vontade remanesceu perto de suas 
religião nativa e oferta de Lawson redonda rejeitado da conversão ao
christianity.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'entrata di Europei nel mondo dell'indiano ha 
causato una serie di dislocazioni con la malattia, il commercio e la 
guerra. Capi indiani, che hanno incontrato i nuovi 
partner commerciali diplomatici e, trovati interferiti fra un vecchio 
e nuovo mondo sconvolgente esperto. John Lawson, impiegato dal 
proprietario della Carolina per esplorare la colonia backcounry e che 
aspira ad una carriera come scienziato naturale, ha speso 
i mesi che attraversano through l'interiore della Carolina 
nell'azienda dei colonizzatori e degli indiani. Questo brano dal
cliente pubblicato del Lawson del viaggio descrive il percorso finale 
del viaggio, quando Lawson ha contato sulla volontà di Enoe, il capo 
del Eno-Shakori. La volontà era una guida ben nota e di fiducia
fra i commercianti coloniali. Ha confidato a Lawson che ha 
temuto che aveva allontanato alcuna della sua propria gente ed ora 
aveva cercato la protezione europea. Ma la volontà è rimasto 
vicino alla sue religione natale ed offerta del Lawson in cerchio 
rifiutato della conversione a christianity.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η είσοδος των Ευρωπαίων μέσα σε τον κόσμο του Ινδού 
προκάλεσε μια σειρά εξαρθρώσεων μέσω της ασθένειας, του 
εμπορίου, και της εχθροπραξίας. Οι ινδικοί ηγέτες, που 
αντιμετώπισαν τους νέους διπλωματικούς και εμπορικούς εταίρους, 
βρέθηκαν πιασμένου μεταξύ ενός εξοικειωμένου παλαιού και 
συνταρακτικού νέου κόσμου. Θ*Ιοχν Lawson, που 
χρησιμοποιήθηκε από τον ιδιοκτήτη της Καρολίνας για να 
εξερευνήσει της αποικίας backcounry και που επιδιώκει σε μια 
σταδιοδρομία ως φυσικός επιστήμονας, πέρασε τους μήνες που 
ταξιδεύουν μέσω του εσωτερικού της Καρολίνας στην επιχείρηση των 
αποίκων και Ινδών. Αυτό το απόσπασμα από το δημοσιευμένο 
απολογισμό Lawson του ταξιδιού περιγράφει το τελικό πόδι του 
ταξιδιού, όταν στηρίχθηκε Lawson σε Enoe, προϊστάμενος του ενο-
Shakori. Ήταν ένας καλά γνωστός και εμπιστευμένος 
οδηγός μεταξύ των αποικιακών εμπόρων. Εμπιστεύτηκε σε 
Lawson ότι φοβισμένος αυτός είχε αλλοτριώσει μερικοί 
από τους ανθρώπους του, και την τώρα επιδιωκόμενη ευρωπαϊκή 
προστασία. Αλλά παρέμεινε κοντά στην εγγενή θρησκεία του 
και απέρριψε στρογγυλά την προσφορά Lawson της μετατροπής στο 
χριστιανισμό.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La entrada de europeos en el mundo del indio 
causó una serie de dislocaciones con enfermedad, comercio, y la 
guerra. Arranques de cinta indios, que encontraron a nuevos 
socios diplomáticos y que negociaban, encontrados cogidos entre un 
mundo nuevo viejo e inquietante familiar. Juan Lawson, empleado 
por el propietario de Carolina para explorar a la colonia backcounry y
que aspiraba a una carrera como científico natural, pasó los meses 
que viajaban a través del interior de Carolina en la compañía de 
colonos y de indios. Este extracto de la cuenta publicada de 
Lawson del viaje describe el trayecto final del viaje, cuando Lawson 
confió en la voluntad de Enoe, el jefe del Eno-Shakori. La 
voluntad era una guía bien conocida y confiada en entre comerciantes 
coloniales. Él confió a Lawson que él temió que él hubiera 
enajenado a alguna de su propia gente, y ahora que hubiera buscado la 
protección europea. Pero seguía habiendo la voluntad cerca de 
su religión nativa y oferta de Lawson redondo rechazado de la 
conversión al cristianismo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086223</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105254</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/he-lovd-the-english-extraordinary-well-enoe-will-guides-john-lawson-through-the-carolina-interior-1709</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
