<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104933</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104933</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086247</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Horatio Alger's American Fable: "The World Before Him"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Horatio Algers Amerikanische Fabel: "Die 
Welt Vor Ihm"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Fable Américaine de Horatio Alger : "Le 
Monde Avant Lui"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fable Americano De Horatio Alger: "O Mundo 
Antes DEle"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fable Americano Di Horatio Alger: "Il Mondo 
Prima Di Lui"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αμερικανικός μύθος Alger Horatio: "Ο κόσμος
ενώπιον του"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fable Americano De Horatio Alger: "El Mundo 
Antes De Él"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The ideology of success--the notion that anyone could make it with enough hard work--was widely promoted in Gilded Age America. One of its most famous proponents was the author Horatio Alger, whose novels showed how poor boys could move from "rags to respectability" through "pluck and luck." Between the late 1860s and his death in 1899, Alger published more than 100 of these formulaic stories about poor boys who made good more often because of fortunate accidents than because of hard work and denial. The tale of Frank Courtney's lucky break in  The World Before Him  (1880) was typical of these stories. In this selection, young Frank grabs the proverbial golden ring of success less by pluck than by sheer luck.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Ideologie des Erfolges -- der Begriff, die 
jedermann bilden könnte es mit genügender harten Arbeit -- wurde 
weit in vergoldetem Alter Amerika gefördert. Einer seiner 
berühmtesten Antragsteller war der Autor Horatio Alger, dessen Romane
zeigten, wie arme Jungen umziehen konnten von "Lappen zu 
Respectability" durch "zupfen und Glück." Zwischen dem späten 
1860s und seinem Tod 1899, veröffentlichte Alger mehr als 100 dieser 
formulaic Geschichten über arme Jungen, die gut häufig wegen der 
glücklichen Unfälle als wegen der harten Arbeit und der Ablehnung 
bildeten. Die Geschichte von aufrichtigen Courtneys glücklichem
Bruch in der Welt vor ihm (1880) war von diesen Geschichten typisch. 
In dieser Auswahl ergreift junger Freivermerk den 
sprichwörtlichen goldenen Ring des Erfolges weniger durch zupfen als 
durch blosses Glück.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'idéologie du succès -- la notion que n'importe
qui pourrait lui faire avec assez de travail dur -- a été largement 
favorisée dans l'âge doré Amérique. Un de ses partisans plus
célèbres était l'auteur Horatio Alger, dont les romans ont montré 
"par" comment les pauvres garçons pourraient se déplacer des 
"chiffons à la respectabilité plument et chance." Entre le 
1860s en retard et sa mort en 1899, Alger a édité plus de 100 de ces
histoires formulaic au sujet des pauvres garçons qui ont réparé 
plus souvent en raison des accidents chanceux qu'en raison du travail 
dur et du démenti. Le conte de la rupture chanceuse de Courtney
franc dans le monde avant lui (1880) était typique de ces histoires. 
Dans cette sélection, le jeune contreseing saisit la boucle 
d'or proverbiale du succès moins par plument que par la chance fine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O ideology do sucesso -- a noção que qualquer um
poderia lhe fazer com bastante trabalho duro -- foi promovido 
extensamente na idade gilded América. Um de seus proponents 
mais famosos era o autor Horatio Alger, cujas as novelas mostraram 
como os meninos deficientes poderiam se mover dos "panos ao 
respectability" com "arrancam e sorte." Entre o 1860s atrasado e
sua morte em 1899, Alger publicou mais de 100 destas histórias 
formulaic sobre os meninos deficientes que fizeram bom mais 
frequentemente por causa dos acidentes afortunados do que por causa do
trabalho duro e da negação. O tale da ruptura afortunada de 
Courtney frank no mundo antes dele (1880) era típico destas 
histórias. Nesta seleção, o franquia novo agarra o anel 
dourado proverbial do sucesso mais menos por arranca do que pela sorte
sheer.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'ideologia di successo -- la nozione che chiunque
potrebbe rendergli con abbastanza lavoro duro -- ampiamente è stata 
promossa nell'età gilded America. Uno dei relativi fautori più
famosi era l'autore Horatio Alger, di cui i romanzi hanno mostrato 
come i poveri ragazzi potrebbero muoversi "dai panni a 
respectability" con "colgono e fortuna." Fra il 1860s ritardato 
e la sua morte in 1899, Alger ha pubblicato più di 100 di queste 
storia formulaic circa i poveri ragazzi che hanno compensato più
spesso a causa degli incidenti fortunati che a causa di lavoro duro e 
della smentita. Il racconto della rottura fortunata del Courtney
franco nel mondo prima di lui (1880) era tipico di queste storia. 
In questa selezione, la firma di franchigia giovane afferra 
l'anello dorato proverbial di successo più di meno da coglie che da 
fortuna pura.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ιδεολογία της επιτυχίας -- η έννοια ότι καθεμία θα 
μπορούσε να την κάνει με αρκετή σκληρή εργασία -- προωθήθηκε 
ευρέως στην επιχρυσωμένη ηλικία Αμερική. Ένας από τους 
διασημότερους υπερασπιστές του ήταν ο συντάκτης Horatio 
Alger, τα ο οποίος μυθιστορήματα επέδειξαν πώς τα φτωχά 
αγόρια θα μπορούσαν να κινηθούν από "τα κουρέλια στη 
σεβασμιότητα" μέσω "μαδούν και τύχη." Μεταξύ του πρόσφατου
1860s και του θανάτου του το 1899, Alger δημοσίευσε 
περισσότερο από 100 αυτών των formulaic ιστοριών για τα 
φτωχά αγόρια που έκαναν καλός συχνότερα λόγω των τυχερών 
ατυχημάτων απ'ό,τι λόγω της σκληρής εργασίας και της άρνησης. 
Η ιστορία του τυχερού σπασίματος του Frank Courtney's 
στον κόσμο ενώπιον του (1880) ήταν χαρακτηριστική αυτών των 
ιστοριών. Σε αυτήν την επιλογή, ο νέος Frank επιλέγει το
παροιμιακό χρυσό δαχτυλίδι της επιτυχίας λιγότερο κοντά μαδά 
απ'ό,τι από την καθαρή τύχη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La ideología del éxito -- la noción que 
cualquier persona podría hacerle con bastante trabajo duro -- fue 
promovida extensamente en la edad dorada América. Uno de sus 
autores más famosos era el autor Horatio Alger, que novelas mostraron
"con" cómo los muchachos pobres podrían moverse desde los "trapos a 
la respetabilidad despluman y suerte." Entre el último 1860s y 
su muerte en 1899, Alger publicó más de 100 de estas historias 
formulaic sobre los muchachos pobres que hicieron bueno más a menudo 
debido a accidentes afortunados que debido a trabajo duro y la 
negación. El cuento de la rotura afortunada de Courtney franco 
en el mundo antes de él (1880) era típico de estas historias. 
En esta selección, la carta franca joven ase el anillo de oro 
proverbial del éxito por despluma menos que por suerte escarpada.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086247</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104933</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/horatio-algers-american-fable-the-world-before-him</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
