<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107835</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107835</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086323</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"In the Beginning . . .": A Knight's Sacred Oath</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"am Anfang. . . ": Heiliger Eid 
Eines Ritters</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"dans le début. . . ": Le 
Serment Sacré D'un Chevalier</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"no começo. . . ": Juramento 
Sacred De um Knight</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"nell'inizio. . . ": Giuramento 
Sacred Del Cavaliere</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Στην αρχή. ..": Ο ιερός όρκος ενός 
ιππότη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"en el principio. . . ": 
Juramento Sagrado De un Caballero</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Knights of Labor, a nineteenth-century labor union, employed elaborate rituals and symbols in their local assembly meetings. The initiation ceremony for new members, for example, relied heavily on religious imagery and language. It also drew on the rituals of other fraternal organizations like the Masons and the Odd Fellows, that had many working-class members. The ceremony emphasized that all that was valuable and worthy in society derived from human labor. New Knights agreed to commit themselves to improve the conditions of all working people.   Hundreds of thousands of workers in the 1880s were "baptized" in a Knights of Labor initiation ceremony that required the following promises.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Ritter der Arbeit, des 19.-Jahrhundert 
Arbeiterverbandes, der eingesetzten durchdachten Rituale und der 
Symbole in ihren lokalen Versammlung Sitzungen. Die 
Inbetriebnahmezeremonie für neue Bauteile z.B. beruhte schwer auf 
frommen Bildern und Sprache. Sie zeichnete auch auf die Rituale 
anderer brüderlicher Organisationen wie der Maurer und die ungeraden 
Gefährten, der hatten viele Arbeiterklassebauteile. Die 
Zeremonie hob hervor, daß alle, die wertvoll und in der Gesellschaft 
angemessen waren, von der Mensch Arbeit berechneten. Neue 
RitterWAREN damit einverstanden, sich festzulegen, um die Zustände 
aller Arbeitsleute zu verbessern. Hunderte Tausenden Arbeiter im
1880s wurden in Ritter der Arbeitsinbetriebnahmezeremonie "getauft", 
die die folgenden Versprechungen benötigten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les chevaliers du travail, d'un syndicat de 
dix-neuvième-siècle, des rituels raffinés utilisés et des symboles
lors de leurs réunions locales d'assemblage. La cérémonie de 
déclenchement pour de nouveaux membres, par exemple, s'est fondée 
fortement sur le langage figuré et le langage religieux. Elle a
également dessiné sur les rituels d'autres organismes fraternels 
comme les maçons et les camarades impairs, celui ont eu beaucoup de 
membres de classe ouvrier. La cérémonie a souligné que toute 
ce qui était valable et digne dans la société a dérivé du travail
d'humain. Les nouveaux chevaliers ont accepté de se commettre 
pour améliorer les conditions de toutes les personnes travaillantes. 
Des centaines de milliers d'ouvriers dans le 1880s "ont été 
baptisées" dans les chevaliers de la cérémonie de travail de 
déclenchement qui ont eu besoin des promesses suivantes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os knights do trabalho, de uma união labor de 
décimo-século, de rituals elaborados empregados e de símbolos em 
suas reuniões locais do conjunto. O ceremony da iniciação 
para membros novos, para o exemplo, confiou pesadamente no imagery e 
na língua religiosos. Desenhou também nos rituals de outras 
organizações fraternal como os masons e os companheiros impares, 
aquele tiveram muitos membros do working-class. O ceremony 
emfatizou que todos que eram valiosos e dignos na sociedade se 
derivaram do trabalho do ser humano. Os knights novos 
concordaram cometer-se para melhorar as condições de todos os povos 
trabalhando. As centenas dos milhares dos trabalhadores no 1880s
"baptized" no os knights do ceremony labor da iniciação que 
requereram as seguintes promessas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I cavalieri del Lavoro, un'unione di lavoro 
di diciannovesimo-secolo, rituali elaborati impiegati e simboli nelle 
loro riunioni locali del complessivo. La cerimonia di inizio per
i nuovi membri, per esempio, ha contato pesante sul linguaggio 
figurato e sul linguaggio religiosi. Egualmente ha dissipato sui
rituali di altre organizzazioni fraterne come i masons ed i colleghe 
dispari, quello hanno avuti molti membri della classe operaia. 
La cerimonia ha dato risalto a che tutte che fossero importanti 
e degne nella società hanno derivato dal lavoro umano. I 
nuovi cavalieri hanno accosentito per impegnarsi per migliorare 
gli stati di tutta la gente lavorante. Le centinaia dei migliaia
degli operai nel 1880s "baptized" in i cavalieri di cerimonia 
Di lavoro di inizio che hanno richiesto le seguenti promesse.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι ιππότες της εργασίας, ενός εργατικού συνδικάτου 
δέκατος-αιώνα, χρησιμοποιημένων επιμελημένων τελετουργικών και 
των συμβόλων στις τοπικές συνεδριάσεις των συμβολικών γλωσσών 
τους. Η τελετή έναρξης για τα νέα μέλη, παραδείγματος 
χάριν, στηρίχθηκε σε μεγάλο ποσοστό στα θρησκευτικές καλολογικά 
στοιχεία και τη γλώσσα. Επέσυρε την προσοχή επίσης στα 
τελετουργικά άλλων αδελφικών οργανώσεων όπως τους κτίστες και 
τους περίεργους συνεργάτες, οι οποίοι είχαν πολλά μέλη 
εργατικών τάξεων. Η τελετή υπογράμμισε ότι όλα αυτά ήταν
πολύτιμα και αντάξια στην κοινωνία που προήλθε από την ανθρώπινη
εργασία. Οι νέοι ιππότες συμφώνησαν να δεσμευθούν να 
βελτιώσουν τους όρους όλων των εργαζόμενων ανθρώπων. Οι 
εκατοντάδες χιλιάδες των εργαζομένων στο 1880s "βαφτίστηκαν" 
τους ιππότες της τελετής έναρξης εργασίας που απαίτησαν τις 
ακόλουθες υποσχέσεις.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los caballeros del trabajo, de un sindicato del 
diecinueveavo-siglo, de rituales elaborados empleados y de símbolos 
en sus reuniones locales del ensamblaje. La ceremonia del 
lanzamiento para los nuevos miembros, por ejemplo, confió pesadamente
en imágenes y lenguaje religiosos. También trazó en los 
rituales de otras organizaciones fraternales como los masones y los 
compañeros impares, de que tenían muchos miembros de la clase 
obrera. La ceremonia acentuó que toda que eran valiosos y 
dignos en sociedad derivó de trabajo del ser humano. Los nuevos
caballeros acordaron confiarse para mejorar las condiciones de toda la
gente de trabajo. Los centenares de millares de trabajadores en 
el 1880s "fueron bautizados" en a caballeros de la ceremonia de 
trabajo del lanzamiento que requirieron las promesas siguientes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086323</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107835</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/in-the-beginning-a-knights-sacred-oath</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
