<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107120</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107120</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201378</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Earth Science Education Activities: Prof. Larry Braile</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geowissenschaft-Ausbildung Aktivitäten: 
Prof Larry Braile</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Activités D'Éducation de Science de la terre : 
Prof. Larry Braile</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Atividades Da Instrução Da Ciência De Terra: 
Prof. Larry Braile</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Attività Di Formazione Di Scienze della terra: 
Prof. Larry Braile</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δραστηριότητες εκπαίδευσης γήινης επιστήμης: Ο 
καθ. Larry Braile</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Actividades De la Educación De la Geología: 
Profesor Larry Braile</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This collection of activities and lesson plans covers grade levels 7-12, with notes on how some of the plans might be adapted for other age groups. Topics fall mainly within tectonics, with some structural geology and planetary science projects. The PDF files include activities, hand outs, maps, and even directions for building a simple seismometer and seismograph. Also included are suggestions for incorporating specific media, such as video, into the classroom, and an essay on the state of K-12 science education.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Ansammlung Aktivitäten und 
Lektionplanabdeckunggradstufen 7-12, mit Anmerkungen über, wie einige
der Pläne für andere Altersklassen angepaßt werden konnten. 
Themen fallen hauptsächlich innerhalb des Tectonics, mit 
einiger struktureller Geologie und planetarischen Wissenschaft 
Projekten. Die pdf Dateien schließen Aktivitäten, Handheraus, 
Karten und sogar Richtungen für das Aufbauen eines einfachen 
seismometer und des Seismographen ein. Auch geschlossen 
Vorschläge für das Enthalten der spezifischen Media, wie Bildschirm,
in das Klassenzimmer und ein Versuch auf dem Zustand der Wissenschaft 
K-12 Ausbildung ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette collection de niveaux de catégorie de 
couvertures d'activités et de plans de leçon 7-12, avec des notes 
sur la façon dont certains des plans pourraient être adaptés pour 
d'autres catégories d'âge. Les sujets tombent principalement 
dans la tectonique, avec quelques géologie structurale et projets 
planétaires de la science. Les fichiers de pdf incluent des 
activités, des sorties de main, des cartes, et même des directions 
pour construire un sismomètre et un sismographe simples. En 
outre inclus sont des suggestions pour incorporer des medias 
spécifiques, tels que le vidéo, dans la salle de classe, et un essai
sur l'état d'éducation de la science K-12.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta coleção de níveis da classe das tampas das
atividades e das plantas da lição 7-12, com notas em como algumas 
das plantas puderam ser adaptadas para outros grupos de idade. 
Os tópicos caem principalmente dentro do tectonics, com alguns 
geologia estrutural e projetos planetários da ciência. As 
limas do pdf incluem atividades, saídas da mão, mapas, e mesmo 
sentidos para construir um seismometer e um seismograph simples. 
São incluídos também as sugestões para incorporar media 
específicos, tais como o vídeo, na sala de aula, e um essay no 
estado da instrução da ciência K-12.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa accumulazione dei Livelli del grado delle 
coperture di programmi di lezione e di attività 7-12, con le note su 
come alcuni dei programmi potrebbero essere adattati per altri gruppi 
d'età. I soggetti cadono pricipalmente all'interno della 
tettonica, con alcuni geologia strutturale e progetti planetari di 
scienza. Gli archivi del pdf includono le attività, i outs 
della mano, i programmi e perfino i sensi per la costruzione un 
seismometer e del sismografo semplici. Egualmente sono inclusi i
suggerimenti per comprendere i media specifici, quale il video, 
nell'aula e un saggio sul dichiarare di formazione di scienza K-12.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η συλλογή των δραστηριοτήτων και των σχεδίων 
μαθήματος καλύπτει τα επίπεδα 7-12 βαθμού, με τις σημειώσεις 
για τον τρόπο με τον οποίο μερικά από τα σχέδια να προσαρμοστούν
για άλλες ομάδες ηλικίας. Τα θέματα εμπίπτουν κυρίως στην 
τεκτονική, με μερικά δομική γεωλογία και πλανητικά προγράμματα 
επιστήμης. Τα αρχεία PDF περιλαμβάνουν τις 
δραστηριότητες, το χέρι outs, τους χάρτες, και ακόμη και τις 
κατευθύνσεις για την οικοδόμηση ενός απλών σεισμομέτρου και 
seismograph. Επίσης περιλαμβάνονται οι προτάσεις για τα 
συγκεκριμένα μέσα, όπως το βίντεο, στην τάξη, και ένα δοκίμιο 
στην κατάσταση της εκπαίδευσης Κ- 12 επιστήμης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta colección de niveles del grado de las 
cubiertas de las actividades y de los planes de la lección 7-12, con 
las notas sobre cómo algunos de los planes se pudieron adaptar para 
otras categorías de edad. Los asuntos bajan principalmente 
dentro de la tectónica, con alguna geología estructural y proyectos 
planetarios de la ciencia. Los ficheros del pdf incluyen 
actividades, salidas de la mano, correspondencias, e incluso las 
direcciones para construir un seismometer y un sismógrafo simples. 
También se incluyen las sugerencias para incorporar media 
específicos, tales como vídeo, en la sala de clase, y un ensayo en 
el estado de la educación de la ciencia K-12.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:LARRY BRAILE
FN:LARRY BRAILE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201378</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107120</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/earth-science-education-activities-prof-larry-braile</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
