<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107188</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107188</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205874</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Woody Guthrie and the Archive of American Folk Song: Correspondence, 1940-1950</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Waldiges Guthrie und das Archiv des amerikanischen
Volkslieds: Korrespondenz, 1940-1950</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Guthrie boisé et les archives de la chanson 
folklorique américaine : Correspondance, 1940-1950</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Guthrie woody e o arquivo da canção popular 
americana: Correspondência, 1940-1950</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Guthrie boscoso e l'archivio della canzone piega 
americana: Corrispondenza, 1940-1950</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ξύλινο Guthrie και το αρχείο του αμερικανικού 
λαϊκού τραγουδιού: Αλληλογραφία, 1940-1950</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Guthrie arbolado y el archivo de la canción 
popular americana: Correspondencia, 1940-1950</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">highlights letters Guthrie wrote in the early 1940s after moving to New York City, where he pursued broadcasting and recording careers, met artists and social activists, and gained a reputation as a songwriter and performer. The site includes a biographical essay, a timeline of Guthrie's life, and an encoded finding aid of Guthrie materials at the Library of Congress.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Höhepunktzeichen Guthrie schrieben in die frühen
vierziger Jahre, nachdem sie nach New York City bewogen hatten, in dem
er das Übertragen und speichernde Karrieren, getroffene Künstler und
Sozialaktivisten ausübte, und gewannen ein Renommee als songwriter 
und Ausführendes. Die Site schließt einen biographischen 
Versuch, ein timeline von Leben Guthries und ein verschlüsseltes 
findenes Helfer der Guthrie Materialien an der Bibliothek des 
Kongresses ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les lettres Guthrie de points culminants ont 
écrit au début des années 40 après s'être déplacé à New York 
City, où il a poursuivi l'annonce et les carrières d'enregistrement,
les artistes rencontrés et les activistes sociaux, et ont gagné une 
réputation en tant qu'un parolier et interprète. Le site 
inclut un essai biographique, une chronologie de la vie de Guthrie, et
une aide de conclusion encodée des matériaux de Guthrie à la 
bibliothèque du congrès.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">as letras Guthrie dos destaques escreveram nos 
1940s adiantados após mover-se para New York City, onde perseguiu 
transmitir e carreiras de gravação, artistas encontrados com e 
activistas sociais, e ganharam uma reputação como um songwriter e um
performer. O local inclui um essay biographical, um timeline da 
vida de Guthrie, e um dae (dispositivo automático de entrada) 
encontrando codificado de materiais de Guthrie na biblioteca do 
congress.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">le lettere Guthrie di punti culminanti hanno 
scritto nell'inizio degli anni 40 dopo essere mosssi verso New York 
City, in cui ha perseguito la radiodiffusione e carriere di 
registrazione, artisti venuti a contatto di e attivisti sociali ed 
hanno guadagnato una reputazione come un songwriter ed esecutore. 
Il luogo include un saggio biographical, un timeline di vita del
Guthrie e un sussidio d'individuazione messo dei materiali di Guthrie 
alla libreria del congresso.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">οι κυριώτερες επιστολές Guthrie έγραψαν στις αρχές 
της δεκαετίας του '40 μετά από να κινηθούν προς την πόλη της 
Νέας Υόρκης, όπου ακολούθησε τις σταδιοδρομίες ραδιοφωνικής 
αναμετάδοσης και καταγραφής, συνάντησε τους καλλιτέχνες και τα 
κοινωνικά ενεργά στελέχη, και κέρδισαν μια φήμη ως τραγουδοποιό 
και εκτελεστή. Η περιοχή περιλαμβάνει ένα βιογραφικό 
δοκίμιο, μια υπόδειξη ως προς το χρόνο της ζωής Guthrie, και 
μια κωδικοποιημένη ενίσχυση εύρεσης των υλικών Guthrie στη 
βιβλιοθήκη του συνεδρίου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">las cartas Guthrie de los toques de luz 
escribieron en los años 40 tempranos después de mover a New York 
City, en donde él persiguió difundir y las carreras de 
registración, los artistas satisfechos y los activistas sociales, y 
ganaron una reputación como un compositor y ejecutante. El 
sitio incluye a un ensayo biográfico, a un timeline de la vida de 
Guthrie, y a asistente que encuentra codificado de los materiales de 
Guthrie en la biblioteca del congreso.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205874</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107188</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/woody-guthrie-and-the-archive-of-american-folk-song-correspondence-1940-1950</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
