<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107128</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107128</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211703</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Properties of Contour Lines</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eigenschaften der Form-Zeilen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Propriétés des lignes de découpe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Propriedades de linhas do contorno</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Proprietà delle righe di profilo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ιδιότητες των γραμμών περιγράμματος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Características de las líneas del contorno</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site features several Flash animations that illustrate the concept of isopleths, or contour lines of equal value. Most of the animations are interactive and allow the user to interpret contour spacing, hachured lines, and valley/ridge placement. One animation allows the user to practice drawing contour lines. These resources are suitable for use in lectures, labs, or other teaching activities.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Situationsmerkmale einige grelle 
Animationen, die das Konzept von Isopleths veranschaulichen oder 
Formzeilen des gleichen Wertes. Die meisten Animationen sind 
interaktiv und erlauben dem Benutzer, Formabstand, schraffierte Zeilen
und valley/ridge Plazierung zu deuten. Eine Animation erlaubt 
dem Benutzer Form, zeilen zu zeichnen zu üben. Diese 
Betriebsmittel sind für Gebrauch in den Vorträgen, in den Labors 
oder in anderen unterrichtenden Aktivitäten verwendbar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dispositifs de ce site plusieurs animations 
instantanées qui illustrent le concept des lignes isoplèthes, ou 
lignes de découpe de valeur égale. La plupart des animations 
sont interactives et permettent à l'utilisateur d'interpréter 
l'interligne de découpe, les lignes en hachures, et le placement de 
valley/ridge. Une animation permet à l'utilisateur de pratiquer
tracer des lignes de découpe. Ces ressources conviennent pour 
l'usage dans les conférences, les laboratoires, ou d'autres 
activités d'enseignement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Características deste local diversos animations 
flash que ilustram o conceito dos isopleths, ou linhas do contorno do 
valor igual. A maioria dos animations são interativos e 
permitem que o usuário interprete o afastamento do contorno, linhas 
hachured, e colocação de valley/ridge. Um animation permite 
que o usuário pratique desenhar linhas do contorno. Estes 
recursos são apropriados para o uso nos lectures, nos laboratórios, 
ou em outras atividades ensinando.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Caratteristiche di questo luogo parecchie 
animazioni istantanee che illustrano il concetto dei isopleths, o 
righe di profilo di valore uguale. La maggior parte delle 
animazioni sono interattive e che permettono che l'utente interpreti 
il gioco di profilo, le righe hachured e la disposizione di 
valley/ridge. Una animazione permette che l'utente si eserciti 
in dissipare le righe di profilo. Queste risorse sono adatte ad 
uso nelle conferenze, in laboratori, o in altre attività 
d'istruzione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει διάφορες ζωτικότητες 
λάμψης που επεξηγούν την έννοια των ισοπληθών, ή τις γραμμές 
περιγράμματος ίσης αξίας. Οι περισσότερες από τις 
ζωτικότητες είναι διαλογικές και επιτρέπουν στο χρήστη για να 
ερμηνεύσουν το διάστημα περιγράμματος, οι γραμμές, και η 
τοποθέτηση κοιλάδων/κορυφογραμμών. Μια ζωτικότητα επιτρέπει
στο χρήστη στις γραμμές περιγράμματος σχεδίων πρακτικής. 
Αυτά τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς είναι κατάλληλα για τη χρήση
στις διαλέξεις, τα εργαστήρια, ή άλλες δραστηριότητες 
διδασκαλίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Características de este sitio varias animaciones 
de destello que ilustran el concepto de isopleths, o líneas del 
contorno del valor igual. La mayoría de las animaciones son 
interactivas y permiten que el utilizador interprete el espaciamiento 
del contorno, líneas rayadas, y la colocación de valley/ridge. 
Una animación permite que el utilizador practique el trazar de 
líneas del contorno. Estos recursos son convenientes para el 
uso en conferencias, laboratorios, u otras actividades de enseñanza.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211703</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107128</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/properties-of-contour-lines</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
