<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107631</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107631</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087347</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A warning.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein WARNING.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un avertissement.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um aviso.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un avvertimento.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια προειδοποίηση.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una alerta.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">When the Professional Air Traffic Controllers Organization (PATCO) went on strike against the Federal Aviation Administration in 1981, President Ronald Reagan waited just three days to fire all 10,000 of the striking federal employees. The President's action transformed every strike in the nation into a union-busting opportunity. The Los Angeles local of PATCO distributed a leaflet with this illustration during the summer and fall of 1981. The leaflet urged other airline and airport workers to support PATCO, warning that the Reagan Administration's suppression of the union would permit the airline companies to force layoffs and contract concessions from all workers in the industry.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Als die professionelle Fluglotse-Organisation (PATCO) 
gegen die Bundesluftfahrt-Leitung 1981 streikte, wartete Präsident 
Ronald Reagan, daß gerade drei Tage alle 10.000 der auffallenden 
Bundesangestellten feuern. Die Tätigkeit des Präsidenten 
wandelte jeden Schlag in der Nation in eine Anschluß-sprengende 
Gelegenheit um. Der Los Angeles Einheimische von PATCO verteilte
ein Blättchen mit dieser Abbildung während des Sommers und des 
Falles von 1981. Das Blättchen drängte andere Fluglinie und 
Flughafenarbeiter, PATCO zu unterstützen und warnte, daß der 
Ausgleich der Reagan Leitung des Anschlußes die Fluglinie Firmen 
ermöglichen würde, vorübergehende Entlassungen und Vertrag 
Zugeständnisse von allen Arbeitern in der Industrie zu erzwingen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Quand l'organisation professionnelle d'aiguilleurs du ciel
(PATCO) a fait la grève à lencontre la gestion fédérale d'aviation
en 1981, président Ronald Reagan a attendu juste trois jours 
pour mettre le feu à chacun des 10.000 des employés fédéraux 
saisissants. L'action du président a transformé chaque grève 
dans la nation en occasion union-éclatante. Les gens du pays de
Los Angeles de PATCO ont distribué un feuillet avec cette 
illustration pendant l'été et la chute de 1981. Le feuillet a 
invité d'autres ouvriers de ligne aérienne et d'aéroport à 
supporter PATCO, avertissant que la suppression de gestion de Reagan 
de l'union permettrait aux compagnies de ligne aérienne de forcer des
licenciements et des concessions de contrat de tous les ouvriers dans 
l'industrie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quando a organização profissional dos controladores de 
tráfego de ar (PATCO) foi na batida de encontro à administração 
federal da aviação em 1981, o presidente Ronald Reagan esperou 
apenas três dias para atear fogo a todos os 10.000 dos empregados 
federais impressionantes. A ação do presidente transformou 
cada batida na nação em uma oportunidade união-rebentando. O 
local de Los Angeles de PATCO distribuiu um leaflet com esta 
ilustração durante o verão e a queda de 1981. O leaflet 
incitou outros trabalhadores da linha aérea e do aeroporto suportar 
PATCO, advertindo que a supressão de administração de reagan da 
união permitiria as companhias da linha aérea forçar dispensas e 
concessões do contrato de todos os trabalhadores na indústria.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Quando l'organizzazione professionale dei regolatori di 
traffico æreo (PATCO) è andato sul colpo contro la gestione federale 
di aeronautica in 1981, il presidente Ronald Reagan ha atteso appena 
tre giorni per infornare tutti e 10.000 le degli impiegati federali 
notevoli. L'azione del presidente ha trasformato ogni colpo 
nella nazione in un'occasione unione-rompentesi. Il local de Los
Angeles di PATCO ha distribuito un opuscolo con questa illustrazione 
durante l'estate e la caduta di 1981. L'opuscolo ha invitato 
altri operai dell'aeroporto e di linea aerea a sostenere PATCO, 
avvertente che la soppressione della gestione di reagan dell'unione 
permetterebbe alle aziende di linea aerea di forzare i licenziamenti e
le concessioni del contratto da tutti gli operai nell'industria.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Όταν η επαγγελματική οργάνωση ελεγκτών εναέριας 
κυκλοφορίας (PATCO) πήγε στην απεργία ενάντια στην 
ομοσπονδιακή διοίκηση αεροπορίας το 1981, ο Πρόεδρος Ronald 
Reagan περίμενε ακριβώς τρεις ημέρες για να βάλει φωτιά σε και
τα 10.000 των εντυπωσιακών ομοσπονδιακών υπαλλήλων. Η 
ενέργεια του Προέδρου μετασχημάτισε κάθε απεργία στο έθνος σε 
μια ένωση- busting ευκαιρία. Το Λος Αντζελες τοπικό 
PATCO διένειμε ένα φυλλάδιο με αυτήν την απεικόνιση κατά τη 
διάρκεια του καλοκαιριού και του φθινοπώρου του 1981. Το 
φυλλάδιο ώθησε άλλους αερογραμμή και εργαζομένους αερολιμένων 
για να υποστηρίξει PATCO, προειδοποιώντας ότι η καταστολή της 
κυβέρνησης Reagan της ένωσης θα επέτρεπε στις επιχειρήσεις 
αερογραμμών για να αναγκάσει τις προσωρινές απολύσεις και τις 
παραχωρήσεις συμβάσεων από όλους τους εργαζομένους στη 
βιομηχανία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cuando la organización profesional de los reguladores de 
tráfico aéreo (PATCO) fue en huelga contra la administración 
federal de la aviación en 1981, presidente Ronald Reagan esperó 
apenas tres días para encender los 10.000 de los empleados federales 
llamativos. La acción del presidente transformó cada huelga en
la nación en una oportunidad unio'n-que reventaba. El local de 
Los Ángeles de PATCO distribuyó un prospecto con esta ilustración 
durante el verano y la caída de 1981. El prospecto impulsó a 
otros trabajadores de la línea aérea y del aeropuerto utilizar 
PATCO, advirtiendo que la supresión de la administración de reagan 
de la unión permitiría que las compañías de la línea aérea 
forzaran despidos y concesiones del contrato de todos los trabajadores
en la industria.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087347</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107631</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-warning</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
