<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107915</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107915</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086152</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">FDR versus Nine Old Men:  Schechter v. United States</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">FDR gegen neun alte Männer: Schechter V. 
Vereinigte Staaten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">FDR contre neuf vieux hommes : Schechter v. 
Etats-Unis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fdr contra nove homens velhos: Estados unidos
v. de Schechter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fdr contro nove uomini anziani: Schechter v. 
unito Dichiara</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">FDR εναντίον εννέα ηληκιωμένων: Schechter
V. Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fdr contra nueve viejos hombres: Schechter v.
Estados Unidos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Stocked with philosophical and economic conservatives, the U.S. Supreme Court proved to be the most consistent opponent to President Franklin Roosevelt's New Deal programs. In 1935 the Court struck down the National Recovery Administration (NRA) as an unconstitutional exercise of legislative authority by the executive branch. The NRA was supposed to work with labor and management to develop national wage, price, and production codes that would, theoretically, have systematized and rationalized prices and wages. The labor movement and large employers welcomed the NRA codes, but smaller companies resented the NRA's interference in their business, the domination of big business, and the administrative complexity required by adherence to the NRA's codes. In May 1935, the Supreme Court, in the case of  Schechter Poultry Corp. v. United States , invalidated the NRA and the legislation that created it. The lengthy, unanimous opinion, excerpted here, demonstrated the U.S. Supreme Court's complete unwillingness to endorse FDR's argument that a national crisis demanded innovation.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Auf Lager mit den philosophischen und ökonomischen
Konservativen, das VEREINIGTE STAATEN Höchste Gericht gewesen der 
gleichbleibendste Konkurrent Präsident Franklin Roosevelts zu den 
Programmen des neuen Abkommens. In 1935 das Gericht angeschlagen
hinunter die nationale Wiederanlauf-Leitung (NRA) als verfassungswidrige 
Übung der gesetzgebenden Berechtigung durch die Exekutive. Das 
NRA sollte mit Arbeits- und Management arbeiten, zum des nationalen 
Lohnes, des Preises und der Produktion Codes zu entwickeln, die 
theoretisch und rationalisierte Preise und Löhne systematisiert haben
würden. Die Arbeiterbewegung und die großen Arbeitgeber 
begrüßten die NRA Codes, aber kleinere Firmen nahmen die Störung 
des NRAs in ihrem Geschäft, die Herrschaft des Grossbetriebs und die 
administrative Kompliziertheit, die durch Haftfähigkeit zu den Codes 
des NRAs benötigt wurde übel. Im Mai 1935, erklärte das 
Höchste Gericht, im Fall von Schechter Poultry Corp. V. Vereinigte 
Staaten, das NRA und die Gesetzgebung ungültig, die ihn herstellten. 
Die langatmige, einmütige Meinung, hier excerptiert, komplette 
Abneigung des demonstrierten die VEREINIGTE STAATEN Höchsten 
Gerichts, um Argument FDR zu indossieren, daß eine nationale Krise 
Innovation verlangte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Stocké avec les conservateurs philosophiques et 
économiques, la cour suprême des ETATS-UNIS avérée être 
l'adversaire le plus conformé aux programmes de nouvelle affaire du 
Président Franklin Roosevelt's. Dans 1935 la cour heurtée en 
bas de la gestion nationale de reprise (NRA) comme exercice 
inconstitutionnel d'autorité législative par le branchement 
exécutif. Le NRA a été censé fonctionner avec partenaires 
sociaux pour développer le salaire, le prix, et les codes nationaux 
de production qui auraient théoriquement systématisé et des prix et
des salaires rationalisés. Le mouvement de travail et les 
grands employeurs ont fait bon accueil aux codes de NRA, mais de plus 
petites compagnies étaient offensées par l'interférence du NRA dans
leurs affaires, la domination de grandes affaires, et la complexité 
administrative priée par adhérence aux codes du NRA. En mai 
1935, la cour suprême, dans le cas de Schechter Poultry Corp. v. 
Etats-Unis, a infirmé le NRA et la législation qui l'ont créé. 
L'opinion prolongée et unanime, extraite ici, la réticence 
complète de cour suprême démontrée des ETATS-UNIS d'approuver 
l'argument du FDR qu'une crise nationale a exigé l'innovation.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Estocado com os conservadores filosóficos e 
econômicos, a corte suprema de ESTADOS UNIDOS provada ser o oponente 
o mais consistente aos programas do negócio novo do presidente 
Franklin Roosevelt. Em 1935 a corte golpeada abaixo a 
administração nacional da recuperação (NRA) como um exercício 
unconstitutional da autoridade legislativa pela filial executiva. 
O NRA foi suposto para trabalhar com o labor e gerência para 
desenvolver o salário, preço, e os códigos nacionais da produção 
que, teòrica, systematized e preços e salários rationalized. 
O movimento labor e os empregadores grandes deram boas-vindas 
aos códigos de NRA, mas as companhias menores ressentiram-se pela 
interferência do NRA em seu negócio, pelo domination do negócio 
grande, e pela complexidade administrativa requerida pelo adherence 
aos códigos do NRA. Em maio 1935, a corte suprema, na caixa de 
estados unidos v. de Schechter Aves domésticas Corp., invalidated o 
NRA e a legislação que a criaram. A opinião longa, unânime, 
excerpted aqui, o unwillingness completo de corte suprema demonstrada 
de ESTADOS UNIDOS endossar o argumento do FDR que uma crise nacional 
exijiu a inovação.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Immagazzinato con i conservatori filosofici ed 
economici, la Corte suprema degli STATI UNITI è risultato essere 
l'avversario più costante ai programmi di nuovo affare del presidente
Franklin Roosevelt. In 1935 la corte impressionante giù la 
gestione nazionale di recupero (NRA) come esercitazione 
inconstituzionale di autorità legislativa dal ramo esecutivo. 
Il NRA è stato supposto per funzionare con il lavoro e 
gestione per sviluppare lo stipendio, prezzo e codici nazionali di 
produzione che, avrebbero sistematizzato teoricamente e prezzi e 
stipendi razionalizzati. Il movimento di lavoro ed i grandi 
datori di lavoro hanno accolto favorevolmente i codici di NRA, ma le 
più piccole imprese si sono risentite dell'interferenza del NRA nel 
loro commercio, della dominazione del commercio grande e della 
complessità amministrativa richiesta da aderenza ai codici del NRA. 
Nel mese di maggio 1935, la Corte suprema, nel caso di Schechter
Poultry Corp. v. unito Dichiara, invalidato il NRA e la 
legislazione che lo hanno creato. L'opinione lunga e unanime, 
stralciata qui, il unwillingness completo della Corte suprema 
dimostrata degli STATI UNITI firmare argomento del FDR che una crisi 
nazionale ha richiesto l'innovazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εφοδιασμένο με τα φιλοσοφικά και οικονομικά 
συντηρητικά, το ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ ανώτατο δικαστήριο αποδείχθηκε ο 
συνεπέστερος αντίπαλος στα νέα προγράμματα διαπραγμάτευσης 
Προέδρου Franklin Roosevelt's. Το 1935 το δικαστήριο 
που χτυπιέται κάτω από την εθνική διοίκηση αποκατάστασης (ΕΚΑ) 
ως αντισυνταγματική άσκηση της νομοθετικής αρχής από τον 
εκτελεστικό κλάδο. Η ΕΚΑ ήταν υποτιθέμενη για να 
συνεργαστεί με την εργασία και τη διαχείριση για να αναπτύξει την 
εθνική αμοιβή, την τιμή, και τους κώδικες παραγωγής που, 
θεωρητικά, θα είχαν συστηματοποιήσει και θα είχαν οργανώσει 
ορθολογικά τις τιμές και αμοιβές. Η μετακίνηση εργασίας και
οι μεγάλοι εργοδότες χαιρέτισαν τους κώδικες ΕΚΑ, αλλά οι 
μικρότερες επιχειρήσεις αγανάκτησαν με την παρέμβαση της ΕΚΑ στην 
επιχείρησή τους, την κυριαρχία της μεγάλης επιχείρησης, και τη 
διοικητική πολυπλοκότητα που απαιτήθηκε από την εμμονή στους 
κώδικες της ΕΚΑ. Μάιος το 1935, το ανώτατο 
δικαστήριο, στην περίπτωση της εταιρίας V. Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες 
πουλερικών Schechter, ακύρωσε την ΕΚΑ και τη νομοθεσία που την 
δημιούργησαν. Η μεγάλη, ομόφωνη άποψη, εδώ, κατέδειξε την 
πλήρη απροθυμία του ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΥ ανώτατου δικαστηρίου να 
επικυρώσει το όρισμα FDR ότι μια εθνική κρίση απαίτησε την 
καινοτομία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Almacenado con conservadores filosóficos y 
económicos, el Tribunal Supremo de ESTADOS UNIDOS demostrado ser el 
opositor más constante a los programas del nuevo reparto de 
presidente Franklin Roosevelt. En 1935 la corte pulso abajo de 
la administración nacional de la recuperación (NRA) como ejercicio 
inconstitucional de la autoridad legislativa por la ramificación 
ejecutiva. El NRA fue supuesto para trabajar con de trabajo y 
gerencia para desarrollar el salario, precio, y los códigos 
nacionales de la producción que, habrían sistematizado teóricamente
y los precios y los salarios racionalizados. El movimiento de 
trabajo y los patrones grandes dieron la bienvenida a los códigos de 
NRA, pero compañías más pequeñas se resentían la interferencia 
del NRA en su negocio, la dominación del negocio grande, y la 
complejidad administrativa requerida por adherencia a los códigos del
NRA. En mayo de 1935, el Tribunal Supremo, en el caso de 
Schechter Poultry Corp. v. Estados Unidos, invalidó el NRA y la 
legislación que lo crearon. La opinión muy larga, unánime, 
extractada aquí, la desgana completa del Tribunal Supremo demostrado 
de ESTADOS UNIDOS de endosar el argumento del FDR que una crisis 
nacional exigió la innovación.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086152</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107915</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/fdr-versus-nine-old-men-schechter-v-united-states</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
