<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107958</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107958</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206053</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Hubble, a View to the Edge of Space</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hubble, eine Ansicht zum Rand des Platzes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Hubble, une vue au bord de l'espace</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Hubble, uma vista à borda do espaço</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Hubble, una vista al bordo di spazio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Hubble, μια όψη στην άκρη του διαστήματος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Hubble, una vista al borde del espacio</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">looks at the people, tools, ideas, and places of the Hubble Space Telescope. See how scientists on earth talk to the telescope in space. Dissect Hubble's images and see what they tell us about the universe. Take a tour of Hubble, from the telescope to the control rooms.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Blicke auf die Leute, die Hilfsmittel, die Ideen 
und die Orte des Hubble Platzes schieben ineinander. Sehen Sie, 
wie Wissenschaftler auf Masse mit dem Teleskop im Platz sprechen. 
Zergliedern Sie Bilder Hubbles und sehen Sie, was sie uns über 
das Universum erklären. Nehmen Sie eine Tour von Hubble, vom 
Teleskop zu den Steuerräumen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les regards aux personnes, aux outils, aux idées,
et aux endroits de l'espace de Hubble télescopent. Voyez 
comment les scientifiques sur terre parlent au télescope dans 
l'espace. Disséquez les images de Hubble et voyez ce qu'elles 
nous indiquent au sujet de l'univers. Prenez une excursion de 
Hubble, du télescope aux salles de commande.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">os olhares nos povos, nas ferramentas, nas 
idéias, e nos lugares do espaço de Hubble encurtam. Veja como 
os cientistas na terra falam ao telescópio no espaço. Dissect 
imagens de Hubble e veja o que nos diz sobre o universo. Faça 
exame de uma excursão de Hubble, do telescópio aos quartos de 
controle.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">gli sguardi alla gente, agli strumenti, alle idee 
ed ai posti dello spazio di Hubble si infilano. Veda come gli 
scienziati su terra comunicano con telescopio nello spazio. 
Dissechi le immagini del Hubble e veda che cosa ci dicono circa 
l'universo. Prenda un giro di Hubble, dal telescopio alle sale 
di controllo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει τους ανθρώπους, τα εργαλεία, τις ιδέες, και 
τις θέσεις του διαστημικού τηλεσκοπίου Hubble. 
Δείτε πώς οι επιστήμονες στη γη μιλούν στο 
τηλεσκόπιο στο διάστημα. Τεμαχίστε τις εικόνες Hubble και
δείτε τι μας λένε για τον κόσμο. Πάρτε έναν γύρο
Hubble, από το τηλεσκόπιο στα δωμάτια ελέγχου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">las miradas en la gente, las herramientas, las 
ideas, y los lugares del espacio de Hubble se telescopan. Vea 
cómo los científicos en la tierra hablan con el telescopio en 
espacio. Diseque las imágenes de Hubble y vea lo que él nos 
dice sobre el universo. Lleve un viaje de Hubble, del telescopio
las salas de mando.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206053</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107958</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/hubble-a-view-to-the-edge-of-space</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
