<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107010</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107010</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200945</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Collaborative Decision Making: NASA's Deep Impact Mission</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gemeinschaftliche Beschlußfassung: Tiefe 
Mission Auswirkung Der NASAS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Prise de décision de collaboration : 
Mission Profonde de l'Impact de la NASA</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fazer De Decisão Collaborative: Missão 
Profunda Do Impacto Da NASA</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Risoluzione Di collaborazione: Missione 
Profonda Di Effetto Della NASA</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Συνεργάσιμη λήψη απόφασης: Βαθιά αποστολή 
αντίκτυπου της NASA</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Toma De Decisión De colaboración: Misión 
Profunda Del Impacto De la NASA</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The NASA's Deep Impact Mission is used to teach collaborative decision making. This Starting Point Teaching Collection page describes the highly-developed unit plan involving collaborative problem solving using data. The subject is the launch of a probe to investigate the composition of a comet. The students will engage in quantitative risk analysis, role-playing, persuasive writing and speaking, and group decision-making procedures. The students will study the objectives and the risks of the project and make decisions about how to deal with them from the perspectives of NASA scientists, engineers, and members of the public involved with the project. On this page, teachers can find learning goals, teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment hints and references and resources dealing with this exercise. It also describes the context in which the unit is best used.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die tiefe Mission Auswirkung der NASAS wird 
verwendet, um gemeinschaftliche Beschlußfassung zu unterrichten. 
Diese Ausgangspunkt-unterrichtende Ansammlung Seite beschreibt 
den hochentwickelten Maßeinheit Plan, der das gemeinschaftliche 
Lösen von Problemen mit Daten mit einbezieht. Das Thema ist die
Produkteinführung einer Prüfspitze, zum des Aufbaus eines Kometen 
nachzuforschen. Die Kursteilnehmer engagieren sich in der 
quantitativen Gefahr Analyse und spielen, überzeugendes Schreiben und
Sprechen und Gruppe Entscheidungsprozesse Rolle. Die 
Kursteilnehmer studieren die Lernziele und die Gefahren des Projektes 
und treffen Entscheidungen über, wie man sie von den Perspektiven die
NASA der Wissenschaftler, der Ingenieure und der Bauteile der 
Öffentlichkeit beschäftigt, die in das Projekt mit einbezogen wird. 
Auf dieser Seite können Lehrer die erlernenziele, 
unterrichtende Anmerkungen und Spitzen, Lehrmittel, Einschätzung Tips
und Referenzen und Betriebsmittel beschäftigend diese Übung finden. 
Sie beschreibt auch den Kontext, in dem die Maßeinheit gut 
benutzt wird.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La mission profonde de l'impact de la NASA est 
employée pour enseigner la prise de décision de collaboration. 
Cette page d'enseignement de collection de point de départ 
décrit le plan fortement développé d'unité impliquant la 
résolution des problèmes de collaboration en utilisant des données.
Le sujet est le lancement d'une sonde pour étudier la 
composition d'une comète. Les étudiants s'engageront dans 
l'analyse quantitative de risque, jouant un rôle, écriture et parler
persuasif, et prises de décision de groupe. Les étudiants 
étudieront les objectifs et les risques du projet et prendront des 
décisions au sujet de la façon traiter elles des perspectives des 
scientifiques, des ingénieurs, et des membres de la NASA du public 
impliqué du projet. À cette page, les professeurs peuvent 
trouver des buts d'étude, des notes et des extrémités 
d'enseignement, matériel didactique, des conseils d'évaluation et 
des références et des ressources traitant cet exercice. Il 
décrit également le contexte dans lequel l'unité mieux est 
utilisée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A missão profunda do impacto da NASA é usada 
ensinar fazer de decisão collaborative. Esta página ensinando 
da coleção do ponto começar descreve a planta highly-developed da 
unidade que envolve resolver de problema collaborative usando dados. 
O assunto é o lançamento de uma ponta de prova para investigar
a composição de um cometa. Os estudantes acoplarão na 
análise quantitative do risco, role-playing, escrita e discurso 
persuasive, e procedimentos de tomada de decisão do grupo. Os 
estudantes estudarão os objetivos e os riscos do projeto e farão 
decisões sobre como tratar das elas dos perspectives de cientistas, 
de coordenadores, e de membros da NASA do público envolvido com o 
projeto. Nesta página, os professores podem encontrar os 
objetivos de aprendizagem, as notas e as pontas ensinando, os 
materiais de ensino, as sugestões da avaliação e as referências e 
os recursos tratando deste exercício. Descreve também o 
contexto em que a unidade é usada melhor.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La missione profonda di effetto della NASA è 
usata per insegnare la risoluzione di collaborazione. Questa 
pagina d'istruzione dell'accumulazione del punto di partenza descrive 
il programma fortemente sviluppato dell'unità che coinvolge la 
soluzione dei problemi di collaborazione usando i dati. 
L'oggetto è il lancio di una sonda per studiare la composizione
di una cometa. Gli allievi si agganceranno nell'analisi 
quantitativa di rischio, atteggiandosi, scrittura e parlare 
convincente e le prese di decisione del gruppo. Gli allievi 
studeranno gli obiettivi ed i rischi del progetto e prenderanno le 
decisioni circa come occuparsi di loro dalle prospettive degli 
scienziati, degli assistenti tecnici e dei membri della NASA del 
pubblico coinvolgere con il progetto. A questa pagina, gli 
insegnanti possono trovare gli obiettivi imparanti, note e punte 
d'istruzione, materiali didattici, suggerimenti di valutazione e 
riferimenti e risorse occupantesi di questa esercitazione. 
Egualmente descrive il contesto in cui l'unità è usata il più
bene.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η βαθιά αποστολή αντίκτυπου της NASA 
χρησιμοποιείται για να διδάξει τη συνεργάσιμη λήψη απόφασης. 
Αυτή η σελίδα συλλογής διδασκαλίας αφετηρίας περιγράφει το
υψηλής ανάπτυξης σχέδιο μονάδων που περιλαμβάνει τη συνεργάσιμη 
επίλυση προβλήματος χρησιμοποιώντας τα στοιχεία. Το θέμα 
είναι η έναρξη ενός ελέγχου για να ερευνήσει τη σύνθεση ενός 
κομήτη. Οι σπουδαστές θα συμμετάσχουν στην ποσοτική ανάλυση
κινδύνου, το ρόλος-παιχνίδι, πειστική γράψιμο και την ομιλία, 
και τις διαδικασίες λήψης αποφάσεων ομάδας. Οι σπουδαστές 
θα μελετήσουν τους στόχους και τους κινδύνους προγράμματος και θα 
λάβουν τις αποφάσεις για το πώς να τους εξετάσουν από τις 
προοπτικές των επιστημόνων, των μηχανικών, και των μελών της 
NASA του κοινού που ασχολείται με το πρόγραμμα. Σε αυτήν 
την σελίδα, οι δάσκαλοι μπορούν να βρούν τους στόχους εκμάθησης,
τις σημειώσεις και τις άκρες διδασκαλίας, τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, 
τους υπαινιγμούς αξιολόγησης και τις αναφορές και τα στοιχεία 
συμπεριφοράς εξετάζοντας αυτήν την άσκηση. Περιγράφει 
επίσης το πλαίσιο στο οποίο η μονάδα χρησιμοποιείται καλύτερα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La misión profunda del impacto de la NASA se 
utiliza para enseñar la toma de decisión de colaboración. 
Esta paginación de enseñanza de la colección del punto de 
partida describe el plan altamente desarrollado de la unidad que 
implica solucionar de problema de colaboración usando datos. El
tema es el lanzamiento de una punta de prueba para investigar la 
composición de un cometa. Los estudiantes engancharán a 
análisis cuantitativo del riesgo, actuando en papel, escritura y 
discurso persuasivo, y los procedimientos de toma de decisión del 
grupo. Los estudiantes estudiarán los objetivos y los riesgos 
del proyecto y tomarán decisiones sobre cómo ocuparse de ellas de 
las perspectivas de los científicos, de los ingenieros, y de los 
miembros de la NASA del público implicado con el proyecto. En 
esta paginación, los profesores pueden encontrar las metas que 
aprenden, las notas y las extremidades de enseñanza, los materiales 
didácticos, las indirectas del gravamen y las referencias y los 
recursos ocupándose de este ejercicio. También describe el 
contexto en el cual la unidad se utiliza lo más mejor posible.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:UNIVERSITY OF MARYLAND
FN:UNIVERSITY OF MARYLAND
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JET PROPULSION LABORATORY
FN:JET PROPULSION LABORATORY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:BALL AEROSPACE AND TECHNOLOGY CORP
FN:BALL AEROSPACE AND TECHNOLOGY CORP
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200945</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107010</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/collaborative-decision-making-nasas-deep-impact-mission</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
