<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105337</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105337</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085250</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Building Bridges, Dams, Power Plants</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gebäude-Brücken, Verdammungen, Kraftwerke</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Passerelles de Bâtiment, Barrages, Centrales</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Pontes Do Edifício, Represas, Plantas De 
Potência</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ponticelli Della Costruzione, Dighe, Centrali 
elettriche</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Χτίζοντας γέφυρες, φράγματα, εγκαταστάσεις παραγωγής 
ενέργειας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Puentes Del Edificio, Presas, Centrales 
eléctricas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The large development projects of the 1930s, designed to serve a growing population, helped shape California in many ways. Most are still integral today. Photographs show the progress of two massive Northern California projects: the Golden Gate Bridge, which links San Francisco and Marin County, and the Bay Bridge, which connects San Francisco with Oakland and the East Bay. The Golden Gate Bridge is one of the most recognized bridges in the world. It is unique not only because of its vermilion orange color: this steel suspension bridge, with a 4,200-foot-long central span and two towers that are 746 feet tall, is the largest ever built. The photographs in this group, taken between 1933 and 1934, show the various phases of construction from different perspectives, looking down, up, and across the span as it was being built. Some photos also show the workers who helped build this famous structure. The Golden Gate Bridge was built under the direction of Joseph Baermann Strauss, an Ohio-born engineer who built more than 400 bridges. The portrait of Strauss also shows the partially built bridge in the background. The Golden Gate Bridge opened to vehicles and pedestrians in 1937. The Bay Bridge construction began in 1933, and the span opened to vehicles in 1936. At 8.25 miles, it is the world?s longest steel bridge. The bridge consists of twin suspension bridges. Many of the photos show workers on catwalks with cables and pulleys, building the bridge. Growing cities also created greater demands for resources, including electrical power. The building of powerhouses like the Pitt River Power House and the Las Plumas Power House near Oroville, shown here, helped to meet this need. Southern California also saw large construction projects. One image in this group shows the San Vicente Dam under construction.A few of these images were taken by Jervie Henry Eastman, who established Eastman's Studio in 1921. His photographs were often turned into picture postcards, such as the one of the oil rigs along Ocean Boulevard in Huntington Beach, in 1935.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die großen Entwicklung Projekte der dreißiger 
Jahre, konzipiert, um eine wachsende Bevölkerung zu dienen, der 
geholfenen Form Kalifornien in vielen Methoden. Die meisten sind
noch Integral heute. Fotographien zeigen den Fortschritt von 
zwei massiven Nordkalifornien Projekten: die Golden- 
Gatebrücke, die San Francisco und Marin Grafschaft bindet, und die 
Bucht-Brücke, die San Francisco mit Oakland und der Ostbucht 
anschließt. Die Golden- Gatebrücke ist eine der anerkanntesten
Brücken in der Welt. Sie ist nicht nur wegen seiner vermilion 
orange Farbe eindeutig: diese Stahlaufhebungbrücke, wenn einer 
zentralen Überspannung 4,200-foot-long und zwei Aufsätze, die sind 
746 Fuß hoch, aufgebaut sind, überhaupt das größte ist. Die 
Fotographien in dieser Gruppe, genommen zwischen 1933 und 1934, zeigen
die verschiedenen Phasen des Aufbaus von den unterschiedlichen 
Perspektiven und unten schauen, herauf und über die Überspannung, 
wie sie aufgebaut wurde. Einige Fotos zeigen auch die Arbeiter, 
die Bau diese berühmte Struktur halfen. Die Golden- Gatebrücke
wurde unter der Richtung von Joseph Baermann Strauss, ein 
Ohio-getragener Ingenieur aufgebaut, der mehr als 400 Brücken 
aufbaute. Das Portrait von Strauss zeigt auch die teilweise 
aufgebaute Brücke im Hintergrund. Die Golden- Gatebrücke 
geöffnet zu den Trägern und zu den Fußgängern 1937. Der 
Bucht-Brücke Aufbau fing 1933 an, und die Überspannung öffnete sich
zu den Trägern 1936. Bei 8.25 Meilen ist es die world?s 
längste Stahlbrücke. Die Brücke besteht aus 
Doppelaufhebungbrücken. Viele der Fotos zeigen Arbeiter auf 
Catwalks mit den Kabeln und Riemenscheiben und bauen die Brücke auf. 
Wachsende Städte erstellten auch grössere Nachfragen nach 
Betriebsmitteln, einschließlich elektrische Energie. Das 
Gebäude der Elektrizitätskraftwerke mögen das Pitt Fluss-Energie 
Haus und das Las Plumas Energie Haus nahe Oroville, hier gezeigt, 
geholfen, um diese Notwendigkeit zu erfüllen. Südkalifornien 
sah auch große Bauvorhaben. Ein Bild in dieser Gruppe stellt 
dar, daß die San Vicente Verdammung unter construction.A wenige 
dieser Bilder von Jervie Henry Eastman genommen wurden, der Studio 
Eastmans 1921 herstellte. Seine Fotographien wurden häufig zu 
Abbildung Postkarten, wie die der Ölplattformen entlang 
Ozean-Prachtstraße in Huntington Beach, 1935 gemacht.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les grands projets de développement des années 
30, conçus pour servir une population croissante, de la forme aidée 
la Californie de beaucoup de voies. Les la plupart sont toujours
intégrale aujourd'hui. Les photographies montrent le progrès 
de deux projets nordiques massifs de la Californie : le pont en 
porte d'or, qui joint San Francisco et comté de Marin, et la 
passerelle de compartiment, qui relie San Francisco à Oakland et au 
compartiment est. Le pont en porte d'or est l'une des 
passerelles les plus identifiées au monde. Il est seul non 
seulement en raison de sa couleur orange vermillonne : cette 
passerelle en acier de suspension, avec une envergure 4,200-foot-long 
centrale et deux tours qui sont de 746 pieds de grands, est la plus 
grande jamais construites. Les photographies dans ce groupe, 
pris entre 1933 et 1934, montrent les diverses phases de la 
construction de différentes perspectives, regardant vers le bas, vers
le haut, et à travers de l'envergure comme elle était construite. 
Quelques photos montrent également les ouvriers qui ont aidé 
la construction cette structure célèbre. Le pont en porte d'or
a été construit sous la direction de Joseph Baermann Strauss, un 
ingénieur Ohio-soutenu qui a construit plus de 400 passerelles. 
La verticale de Strauss montre également la passerelle 
partiellement construite dans le fond. Le pont en porte d'or 
ouvert aux véhicules et aux piétons en 1937. La construction 
de passerelle de compartiment a commencé en 1933, et l'envergure 
s'est ouverte aux véhicules en 1936. À 8.25 milles, c'est la 
plus longue passerelle en acier de world?s. La passerelle se 
compose des passerelles jumelles de suspension. Plusieurs des 
photos montrent des ouvriers sur des passerelles avec des câbles et 
des poulies, construisant la passerelle. Les villes croissantes 
ont également créé de plus grandes demandes des ressources, y 
compris le courant électrique. Le bâtiment des centrales 
électriques aiment la Chambre de puissance de fleuve de Pitt et la 
Chambre de puissance de Las Plumas près d'Oroville, montré ici, 
aidé pour satisfaire ce besoin. La Californie méridionale a 
également vu de grands projets de construction. Une image dans 
ce groupe montre que le barrage de San Vicente sous construction.A peu
de ces images ont été pris par Jervie Henry Eastman, qui a établi 
le studio d'Eastman en 1921. Ses photographies ont été souvent
transformées en cartes postales d'image, telles que celle des 
plates-formes pétrolières le long du boulevard d'océan en 
Huntington Beach, en 1935.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os projetos grandes do desenvolvimento dos 1930s,
projetados servir a uma população de crescimento, da forma ajudada 
Califórnia em muitas maneiras. A maioria são ainda integral 
hoje. As fotografias mostram o progresso de dois projetos do 
norte maciços de Califórnia: a ponte da porta dourada, que 
liga San Francisco e condado de Marin, e a ponte da baía, que conecta
San Francisco com o Oakland e a baía do leste. A ponte da porta
dourada é uma das pontes as mais reconhecidas no mundo. É 
original não somente por causa de sua cor alaranjada do vermilion: 
esta ponte de aço da suspensão, com uma extensão 
4,200-foot-long central e as duas torres que têm 746 pés de altura, 
é a maior construídas sempre. As fotografias neste grupo, 
feito exame entre 1933 e 1934, mostram as várias fases da 
construção dos perspectives diferentes, olhando para baixo, acima, e
através da extensão como era construída. Algumas fotos 
mostram também os trabalhadores que ajudaram à configuração esta 
estrutura famosa. A ponte da porta dourada foi construída sob o
sentido de Joseph Baermann Strauss, um coordenador Ohio-carregado que 
construísse mais de 400 pontes. O retrato de Strauss mostra 
também a ponte parcialmente construída no fundo. A ponte da 
porta dourada aberta aos veículos e aos pedestrians em 1937. A 
construção da ponte da baía começou em 1933, e a extensão abriu 
aos veículos em 1936. Em 8.25 milhas, é a ponte de aço a mais
longa dos world?s. A ponte consiste em pontes gêmeas da 
suspensão. Muitas das fotos mostram trabalhadores em catwalks 
com os cabos e as polias, construindo a ponte. As cidades 
crescentes criaram também umas demandas mais grandes para recursos, 
including a potência elétrica. O edifício dos powerhouses 
gosta da casa da potência do rio de Pitt e da casa da potência de 
Las Plumas perto de Oroville, mostrado aqui, ajudado encontrar-se com 
esta necessidade. Califórnia do sul viu também projetos de 
construção grandes. Uma imagem neste grupo mostra que a 
represa do San Vicente sob construction.A poucas destas imagens 
estêve feita exame por Jervie Henry Eastman, que estabeleceu o 
estúdio de Eastman em 1921. Suas fotografias foram giradas 
frequentemente em postcards do retrato, tais como esse dos 
equipamentos de óleo ao longo do bulevar do oceano em Huntington 
Beach, em 1935.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Grandi progetti di sviluppo dei 1930s, destinati 
per servire una popolazione crescente, della figura aiutata California
in molti modi. La maggior parte sono ancora oggi integrale. 
Le fotografie mostrano il progresso di due progetti nordici 
voluminosi la California: il ponticello del cancello dorato, che
collega San Francisco e la contea di Marin ed il ponticello della 
baia, che collega San Francisco con Oakland e la baia orientale. 
Il ponticello del cancello dorato è uno dei ponticelli 
riconosciuti nel mondo. È unico non soltanto a causa del 
relativo colore arancione di vermilion: questo ponticello 
d'acciaio della sospensione, con una portata centrale 4,200-foot-long 
e due torrette che sono alti 746 piedi, è il più grande costruite 
mai. Le fotografie in questo gruppo, preso fra 1933 e 1934, 
mostrano le varie fasi di costruzione dalle prospettive differenti, 
osservanti giù, su ed attraverso la portata come stava costruenda. 
Alcune foto egualmente mostrano gli operai che hanno aiutato la 
configurazione questa struttura famosa. Il ponticello del 
cancello dorato è stato costruito sotto il senso di Joseph Baermann 
Strauss, un assistente tecnico Ohio-sopportato che ha costruito più 
di 400 ponticelli. Il ritratto di Strauss egualmente mostra 
il ponticello parzialmente costruito nei precedenti. Il 
ponticello del cancello dorato si è aperto ai veicoli ed ai pedoni in
1937. La costruzione del ponticello della baia ha cominciato in 
1933 e la portata si è aperta ai veicoli in 1936. A 8.25 
miglia, è il ponticello d'acciaio più lungo dei world?s. Il 
ponticello consiste dei ponticelli gemellati della sospensione. 
Molte delle foto mostrano gli operai sui catwalks con i cavi e 
le pulegge, costruenti il ponticello. Le città crescenti 
egualmente hanno creato le richieste più grandi delle risorse, 
compreso corrente elettrica. La costruzione delle centrali 
elettriche gradisce la Camera di potenza del fiume di Pitt e la Camera
di potenza di Las Plumas vicino a Oroville, indicato qui, contribuito 
per rispondere a questo bisogno. La California del sud inoltre 
ha visto i grandi progetti di costruzione. Un'immagine in questo
gruppo mostra che la diga di San Vicente sotto construction.A poche di
queste immagini è stata presa da Jervie Henry Eastman, che ha 
stabilito l'studio del Eastman in 1921. Le sue fotografie sono 
state trasformate spesso nelle cartoline dell'immagine, come quella 
degli impianti offshore lungo il boulevard dell'oceano in Huntington 
Beach, in 1935.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα μεγάλα αναπτυξιακά έργα της δεκαετίας του '30, με 
σκοπό να εξυπηρετήσουν έναν αυξανόμενο πληθυσμό, βοήθησαν τη 
μορφή Καλιφόρνια από πολλές απόψεις. Οι περισσότεροι 
είναι ακόμα ακέραιοι σήμερα. Οι φωτογραφίες εμφανίζουν την
πρόοδο δύο ογκωδών βόρειων προγραμμάτων Καλιφόρνιας: η 
χρυσή γέφυρα πυλών, που συνδέουν το Σαν Φρανσίσκο και το νομό 
του Marin, και η γέφυρα κόλπων, η οποία συνδέει το Σαν 
Φρανσίσκο με το Όουκλαντ και τον ανατολικό κόλπο. Η χρυσή 
γέφυρα πυλών είναι μια από τις αναγνωρισμένες γέφυρες στον 
κόσμο. Είναι μοναδικό όχι μόνο λόγω του πορφυρού 
πορτοκαλιού χρώματός του: αυτή η γέφυρα αναστολής χάλυβα,
με 4.200-πόδι-μακριά κεντρική έκταση και δύο πύργους που είναι 
746 πόδια ψηλοί, είναι η μεγαλύτερη που χτίζεται πάντα. 
Οι φωτογραφίες σε αυτήν την ομάδα, που λαμβάνεται μεταξύ 
1933 και 1934, εμφανίζουν διάφορες φάσεις κατασκευής από 
τις διαφορετικές προοπτικές, ανατρέχοντας κάτω, και πέρα από την
έκταση δεδομένου ότι χτιζόταν. Μερικές φωτογραφίες 
εμφανίζουν επίσης τους εργαζομένους που βοήθησαν να χτίσουν 
αυτήν την διάσημη δομή. Η χρυσή γέφυρα πυλών χτίστηκε 
υπό την καθοδήγηση Joseph Baermann Strauss, ένας 
Οχάιο-γεννημένος μηχανικός που έχτισε περισσότερες από 400 
γέφυρες. Το πορτρέτο Strauss εμφανίζει επίσης μερικώς 
χτισμένη γέφυρα στο υπόβαθρο. Η χρυσή γέφυρα πυλών που 
ανοίγουν στα οχήματα και τους πεζούς το 1937. Η κατασκευή
γεφυρών κόλπων άρχισε το 1933, και η έκταση άνοιξε στα 
οχήματα το 1936. Σε 8,25 μίλια, είναι η μακρύτερη 
γέφυρα χάλυβα world?s. Η γέφυρα αποτελείται από τις 
δίδυμες γέφυρες αναστολής. Πολλές από τις φωτογραφίες 
εμφανίζουν εργαζομένους στους στενούς διαδρόμους με τα καλώδια 
και τις τροχαλίες, που χτίζουν τη γέφυρα. Οι αυξανόμενες 
πόλεις δημιούργησαν επίσης τις μεγαλύτερες απαιτήσεις για τα 
στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς, συμπεριλαμβανομένης της ηλεκτρικής 
δύναμης. Η οικοδόμηση των εργοστασίων παραγωγής ηλεκτρικού 
ρεύματος όπως το σπίτι δύναμης ποταμών Pitt και το σπίτι 
δύναμης Las Plumas κοντά σε Oroville, που εμφανίστηκε 
εδώ, βοήθησε να ικανοποιήσει αυτήν την ανάγκη. Νότια 
Καλιφόρνια εβλέίδε επίσης τα μεγάλα προγράμματα 
κατασκευής. Μια εικόνα σε αυτήν την ομάδα εμφανίζει το 
SAN Vicente Dam κάτω από την κατασκευή Λίγες από 
αυτές τις εικόνες λήφθηκαν από Jervie Henry Eastman, το 
οποίο καθιέρωσε το στούντιο Eastman σε 1921, Οι 
φωτογραφίες του μετατράπηκαν συχνά σε κάρτες εικόνων, τέτοιες ως
μια από τις εγκαταστάσεις γεώτρησης πετρελαίου κατά μήκος της 
ωκεάνιας λεωφόρου στην παραλία Huntington, το 1935.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los proyectos grandes del desarrollo de los años
30, diseñados para servir a una población en crecimiento, de la 
dimensión de una variable ayudada California de muchas maneras. 
La mayoría sigue siendo integral hoy. Las fotografías 
muestran el progreso de dos proyectos norteños masivos de California:
el puente de la puerta de oro, que conecta San Francisco y el 
condado de Marin, y el puente de la bahía, que conecta San Francisco 
con Oakland y la bahía del este. El puente de la puerta de oro 
es uno de los puentes reconocidos del mundo. Es único no 
solamente debido a su color anaranjado del vermilion: este 
puente de acero de la suspensión, con un palmo central 
4,200-foot-long y dos torres que sean 746 pies de alto, es el más 
grande construidos siempre. Las fotografías en este grupo, 
tomado entre 1933 y 1934, muestran las varias fases de la 
construcción de diversas perspectivas, mirando abajo, encima, y a 
través del palmo como era construido. Algunas fotos también 
muestran a trabajadores que ayudaron a estructura esta estructura 
famosa. El puente de la puerta de oro fue construido bajo 
dirección de José Baermann Strauss, ingeniero Ohio-llevado que 
construyó más de 400 puentes. El retrato de Strauss también 
muestra el puente parcialmente construido en el fondo. El puente
de la puerta de oro abierto en los vehículos y los peatones en 1937. 
La construcción del puente de la bahía comenzó en 1933, y el 
palmo se abrió en los vehículos en 1936. En 8.25 millas, es el
puente de acero más largo de los world?s. El puente consiste en
los puentes gemelos de la suspensión. Muchas de las fotos 
muestran a trabajadores en pasadizos con los cables y las poleas, 
construyendo el puente. Las ciudades crecientes también crearon
mayores demandas para los recursos, incluyendo corriente eléctrica. 
El edificio de powerhouses tiene gusto de la casa de la potencia
del río de Pitt y de la casa de la potencia de Las Plumas cerca de 
Oroville, mostrado aquí, ayudado para resolver esta necesidad. 
California meridional también vio proyectos de construcción 
grandes. Una imagen en este grupo muestra que la presa del San 
Vicente bajo construction.A pocas de estas imágenes fue tomada por 
Jervie Henry Eastman, que estableció el estudio de Eastman en 1921. 
Sus fotografías fueron dadas vuelta a menudo en las postales 
del cuadro, tales como la que esta' de los aparejos de aceite a lo 
largo del bulevar del océano en Huntington Beach, en 1935.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085250</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105337</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/building-bridges-dams-power-plants</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
