<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107947</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107947</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207004</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Emile Berliner and the Birth of the Recording Industry</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Emile Berliner und die Geburt von der 
Aufnahme-Industrie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Berlinois d'Emile et la naissance de l'industrie 
d'enregistrement</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Emile Berliner e o nascimento da indústria da 
gravação</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Emile Berliner e la nascita dell'industria della 
registrazione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θ*Εμηλε Berliner και η γέννηση της βιομηχανίας 
καταγραφής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Emile Berliner y el nacimiento de la industria de 
la grabación</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">provides a selection of more than 500 letters, lectures, photos, articles, and sound recordings related to the birth of the recording industry. Hear auctioneers, animal calls, musical instruments, and Native American songs, Italian songs, Swedish songs, and more. Berliner (1851-1929), an immigrant and largely self-educated man, was responsible for the development of the microphone and the flat recording disc and gramophone player.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt eine Auswahl von mehr als 500 Zeichen, von 
Vorträgen, von Fotos, von Artikeln und von Tonaufnahmen, die auf der 
Geburt der Aufnahmeindustrie in Verbindung gestanden werden zur 
Verfügung. Hören Sie die Auktionator-, Tieraufrufe, die 
Musikinstrumente und die gebürtigen amerikanischen Liede, die 
italienischen Liede, die schwedischen Liede und mehr. Berliner 
(1851-1929), ein Immigrant und groß ein self-educated Mann, waren 
für die Entwicklung des Mikrophons und des flachen Aufnahmeplatte und
-grammophonspielers verantwortlich.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fournit une sélection de plus de 500 lettres, de 
conférences, de photos, d'articles, et d'enregistrements sonores 
liés à la naissance de l'industrie d'enregistrement. Entendez 
les appels de commissaire-priseur et animaux, les instruments 
musicaux, et les chansons américaines indigènes, les chansons 
italiennes, les chansons suédoises, et plus. Le Berlinois 
(1851-1929), un immigré et en grande partie l'homme de 
art de l'auto-portrait-educated, étaient responsables du développement du 
microphone et du joueur plat de disque et de phonographe 
d'enregistrement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fornece uma seleção de mais de 500 letras, de 
lectures, de fotos, de artigos, e das gravações sadias relacionadas 
ao nascimento da indústria da gravação. Ouça os atendimentos
do auctioneers, os animais, instrumentos musicais, e canções 
americanas nativas, canções italianas, canções suecos, e mais. 
Berliner (1851-1929), um immigrant e um homem pela maior parte 
self-educated, eram responsáveis para o desenvolvimento do microfone 
e do jogador liso do disco e do gramophone da gravação.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fornisce una selezione di più di 500 lettere, 
delle conferenze, delle foto, degli articoli e delle registrazioni del
suono relative alla nascita dell'industria della registrazione. 
Senta le chiamate animali, del auctioneers, gli strumenti 
musicali e le canzoni americane natali, le canzoni italiane, le 
canzoni svedesi e più. Berliner (1851-1929), un immigrante e un
uomo in gran parte self-educated, erano responsabili dello sviluppo 
del microfono e del giocatore piano del disco e del grammofono della 
registrazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρέχει μια επιλογή περισσότερων από 500 
επιστολών, των διαλέξεων, των φωτογραφιών, των άρθρων, και των 
υγιών καταγραφών σχετικών με τη γέννηση της βιομηχανίας 
καταγραφής. Ακούστε τα auctioneers, τις ζωικές κλήσεις, 
τα μουσικά όργανα, και τα εγγενή αμερικανικά τραγούδια, τα 
ιταλικά τραγούδια, τα σουηδικά τραγούδια, και περισσότερων. 
Berliner (1851-1929), ένα που έχουν μεταναστεύσει και 
κατά ένα μεγάλο μέρος αυτοδίδακτο άτομο, ήταν αρμόδιοι για την
ανάπτυξη του μικροφώνου και του επίπεδου δίσκων και gramophone 
καταγραφής φορέα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">proporciona a una selección de más de 500 
cartas, conferencias, fotos, artículos, y grabaciones de sonidos 
relacionadas con el nacimiento de la industria de la grabación. 
Oiga las llamadas del auctioneers, animales, los instrumentos 
musicales, y las canciones americanas nativas, las canciones 
italianas, las canciones suecas, y más. Berliner (1851-1929), 
un inmigrante y un hombre en gran parte autodidacta, eran responsables
del desarrollo del micrófono y del jugador plano del disco y del 
gramófono de la grabación.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207004</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107947</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/emile-berliner-and-the-birth-of-the-recording-industry</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
