<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106946</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106946</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206643</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">National Register Travel Itineraries</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Einwohnermeldeliste-Spielraum-Reisewege</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Itinéraires de Voyage de Registre National</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Itineraries Do Curso Do Registo Nacional</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Itinerari Di Corsa Del Registro Nazionale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εθνικές περιηγήσεις ταξιδιού καταλόγων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Itinerarios Del Recorrido Del Registro Nacional</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">can help families explore historic places in the U.S. Each itinerary describes historic places and their importance, and provides maps, photos, and tourist information. Find itineraries for learning about Civil War battles in Virginia, the Lewis and Clark Expedition, maritime history, women's history, civil rights movement, Florida shipwrecks, the Southwest, Amana Colonies, Ohio and Erie Canal, Detroit, the California coast, Washington, D.C., and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dose helfen Familien, historische Plätze in den 
VEREINIGTEN STAATEN zu erforschen, die jeder Reiseweg historische 
Plätze und ihren Wert beschreibt und liefern Karten, Fotos und 
Touristinformation. Finden Sie Reisewege für das Lernen über 
Bürgerkriegschlachten in Virginia, die Lewis und Clark Expedition, 
Seegeschichte, Geschichte der Frauen, Zivilrechtbewegung, Florida 
Schiffswracks, der Südwest-, Amana Kolonie-, Ohio und Eriekanal, 
Detroit, die Kalifornien Küste, Washington, Gleichstrom und mehr.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">le bidon aident des familles à explorer les 
endroits historiques aux États-Unis. Chaque itinéraire décrit
les endroits historiques et leur importance, et fournit des cartes, 
des photos, et des informations de touristes. Trouvez les 
itinéraires pour se renseigner sur des batailles de guerre civile en 
Virginie, l'expédition de Lewis et de Clark, histoire maritime, 
histoire des femmes, mouvement de droits civiques, naufrages de la 
Floride, le canal de sud-ouest, de colonies d'Amana, de l'Ohio et 
d'Erie, la côte de Detroit, la Californie, Washington, C.C, et plus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">a lata ajuda a famílias explorar lugares historic
nos ESTADOS UNIDOS que cada itinerary descreve lugares historic e sua 
importância, e fornece mapas, fotos, e a informação tourist. 
Encontre itineraries para aprender sobre batalhas da guerra 
civil em Virgínia, a expedição de Lewis e de Clark, history 
marítimo, history das mulheres, movimento das direitas civis, 
shipwrecks de Florida, o canal do sudoeste, das colônias de Amana, do
Ohio e de erie, a costa de Detroit, Califórnia, Washington, C.C., e 
mais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">la latta aiuta le famiglie ad esplorare i posti 
storici negli STATI UNITI che ogni itinerario descrive i posti storici
e la loro importanza e fornisce i programmi, le foto e le informazioni
turistiche. Trovi gli itinerari per imparare circa le battaglie 
di guerra civile nella Virginia, la spedizione del Clark e di Lewis, 
storia marittima, storia delle donne, movimento di diritti civili, 
naufragi della Florida, il canale di sud-ovest, delle colonie di 
Amana, dell'Ohio e di Erie, il litorale de Detroit, la California, 
Washington, DC e più.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">μπορέστε να βοηθήσετε τις οικογένειες να ερευνήσουν τα
ιστορικά μέρη στις ΗΠΑ Κάθε περιήγηση περιγράφει τις 
ιστορικές θέσεις και τη σημασία τους, και παρέχει τους χάρτες, 
τις φωτογραφίες, και τις πληροφορίες τουριστών. Βρείτε τις 
περιηγήσεις για την εκμάθηση για μάχη εμφύλιου πολέμου στη 
Βιρτζίνια, την αποστολή Lewis και clark, τη θαλάσσια 
ιστορία, την ιστορία των γυναικών, τη μετακίνηση αστικών 
δικαιωμάτων, τα ναυάγια της Φλώριδας, το νοτιοδυτικό σημείο, τις 
αποικίες Amana, το κανάλι του Οχάιου και του Erie, το 
Ντητρόιτ, την ακτή Καλιφόρνιας, την Ουάσιγκτον, το ΣΥΝΕΧΈΣ 
ΡΕΎΜΑ, και περισσότεροι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">la lata ayuda a las familias a explorar lugares 
históricos en los ESTADOS UNIDOS que cada itinerario describe lugares
históricos y su importancia, y proporciona a correspondencias, a las 
fotos, y a la información turística. Encuentre los itinerarios
para aprender sobre batallas de la guerra civil en Virginia, la 
expedición de Lewis y de Clark, historia marítimo, la historia de 
las mujeres, movimiento de las derechas civiles, los naufragios de la 
Florida, el canal del sudoeste, de las colonias de Amana, de Ohio y de
Erie, California la costa de Detroit, Washington, C.C., y más.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206643</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106946</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/national-register-travel-itineraries</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
