<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104509</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104509</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206849</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Mount Auburn Cemetery: A New American Landscape</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Montierung Auburn Kirchhof: Eine Neue 
Amerikanische Landschaft</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cimetière Auburn de Support : Un Nouvel 
Horizontal Américain</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Cemetery Auburn Da Montagem: Uma Paisagem 
Americana Nova</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Cimitero Auburn Del Supporto: Un Nuovo 
Paesaggio Americano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επικολλήστε το πυρόξανθο νεκροταφείο: Ένα νέο 
αμερικανικό τοπίο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cementerio Castaño Del Montaje: Un Nuevo 
Paisaje Americano</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">describes the country's first large-scale designed landscape open to the public. The cemetery, established four miles outside Boston in 1831, stood in stark contrast to barren, crowded burial grounds in the city. Providing ample space in a tranquil, natural setting, Mount Auburn attracted not only mourners, but city dwellers wanting to experience nature, as well as tourists and students.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">beschreibt die erste großräumige konzipierte 
Landschaft des Landes, die zur Öffentlichkeit geöffnet ist. 
Der Kirchhof, hergestellt vier Meilen außerhalb Bostons 1831, 
gestanden im steifen Kontrast zu unfruchtbarem, drängte Beerdigung 
Boden in der Stadt. Reichlichen Platz in einem tranquil zur 
Verfügung stellend, hängen natürliche Einstellung, Auburn 
angezogene nicht nur Trauernde, aber die Stadtbewohner, die Natur, 
sowie Touristen und Kursteilnehmer erfahren wünschen ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">décrit le premier horizontal conçu de grande 
puissance du pays ouvert de public. Le cimetière, établi 
quatre milles en dehors de Boston en 1831, tenu dans le contraste 
rigide à stérile, a serré des au sol d'enterrement dans la ville. 
Fournir l'espace suffisant dans une configuration tranquille et
normale, montent non seulement les personnes en deuil attirées 
auburn, mais les habitants de ville voulant éprouver la nature, aussi
bien que des touristes et des étudiants.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">descreve a primeira paisagem projetada em grande 
escala do país aberta ao público. O cemetery, estabelecido 
quatro milhas fora de Boston em 1831, estado no contraste stark a 
estéril, aglomerou terras do enterro na cidade. Fornecendo o 
espaço amplo em um tranquil, o ajuste natural, monta não somente 
mourners atraídos auburn, mas moradores da cidade que querem 
experimentar a natureza, as.well.as turistas e estudantes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">descrive il primo paesaggio progettato su grande 
scala del paese aperto al pubblico. Il cimitero, stabilito 
quattro miglia fuori di Boston in 1831, levato in piedi nel contrasto 
rigido a sterile, ha ammucchiato i motivi di sepoltura nella città. 
Fornendo lo spazio ampio in un tranquil, la regolazione 
naturale, monta non soltanto i mourners attratti auburn, ma gli 
abitanti della città che desiderano avvertire la natura, così come i
turisti e gli allievi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">περιγράφει το πρώτο μεγάλης κλίμακας σχεδιασμένο 
τοπίο της χώρας ανοικτό στο κοινό. Το νεκροταφείο, που 
καθιερώθηκε τέσσερα μίλια έξω από τη Βοστώνη το 1831, 
στάθηκε στην άκαμπτη αντίθεση στους άγονους, συσσωρευμένους 
λόγους ενταφιασμών στην πόλη. Η παροχή του άφθονου 
διαστήματος σε μια ήρεμη, φυσική τιμή τών παραμέτρων, επικολλά 
τους πυρόξανθους γοητευμένους όχι μόνο θρηνητές, αλλά τους 
κατοίκους πόλεων που θέλουν να δοκιμάσει τη φύση, καθώς επίσης 
και τους τουρίστες και τους σπουδαστές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">describe el primer paisaje diseñado en grande del
país abierto al público. El cementerio, establecido cuatro 
millas fuera de Boston en 1831, estado parado en contraste rígido a 
estéril, apretó los argumentos del entierro en la ciudad. 
Proporcionando al espacio suficiente en un tranquil, la 
configuración natural, monta no solamente a mourners atraídos 
castaños, pero a habitantes de la ciudad que desean experimentar la 
naturaleza, así como turistas y estudiantes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206849</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104509</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/mount-auburn-cemetery-a-new-american-landscape</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
