<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106688</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106688</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086682</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Obey Your Air Raid Warden": Big Band as Public Service Announcement</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Befolgen Sie Ihren Luftangriff-Wärter": 
Grosses Band als allgemeiner Service-Ansage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Obéissez Votre Surveillant de Raid aérien" : 
Orchestre en tant qu'annonce de service public</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Obedeça Seu Warden Da Invasão De Ar": 
Faixa grande como o anúncio do serviço público</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Obbedisca Il Vostro Warden Di Incursione Di 
Aria": Fascia grande come annuncio di servizio pubblico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Υπακούστε το φύλακα αεροπορικής επιδρομής σασ": 
Μεγάλη ζώνη ως ανακοίνωση δημόσιων υπηρεσιών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Obedezca A Su Guarda Del Ataque aéreo": 
Venda grande como aviso del servicio público</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the battle for the hearts and minds of the American people during World War II, the U.S. government viewed its popular performers--singers, dancers, and actors--as a crucial weapon. Although a number of stars directly joined the military, those who made movies probably contributed the most to the war effort. Even before Pearl Harbor, Treasury Department officials began making plans to raise money to finance the war by selling bonds to the public, which would be repaid with interest after the war was over. During the war, private citizens and organizations bought $190 billion worth of war bonds at the low interest rate of 1.8 percent. In addition to their work as bond sellers, movie stars also encouraged the populace to follow wartime policies, particularly exhorting them (or joking with them) to observe rationing and save scrap metals. One of the more unusual public service announcements was this 1942 song from Tony Pastor and His Orchestra: "Obey Your Air Raid Warden."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In der Schlacht für die Inneren und den Verstand 
der amerikanischen Leute während des Zweiten Weltkrieges, sah die 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Regierung seine populären Ausführenden -- 
Sänger, Tänzer und Schauspieler -- als entscheidende Waffe an. 
Obgleich eine Anzahl von Sternen direkt das Militär verband, 
trugen die, die Filme bildeten, vermutlich die die meisten zur 
Kriegbemühung bei. Sogar vor Pearl Harbor, fingen 
Fiskus-Abteilung Beamte an, Pläne Geld anheben zu lassen, um den 
Krieg zu finanzieren, indem sie Bindungen zur Öffentlichkeit 
verkauften, die mit Interesse zurückerstattet würde, nachdem der 
Krieg rüber sein. Während des Krieges kauften private Bürger 
und Organisationen $190 Milliarde Wert der Kriegbindungen mit dem 
niedrigen Zinssatz von 1.8 Prozent. Zusätzlich zu ihrer Arbeit 
als Bondverkäufern, regten scherzten Filmstars auch die Bevölkerung 
an, der Kriegpolitik zu folgen, besonders exhorting sie (oder mit 
ihnen) das Rationieren zu beobachten und Schrottmetalle zu sichern. 
Eine der ungewöhnlicheren Ansagen des allgemeinen Services war 
dieses Lied 1942 vom Tony Pastor und von seinem Orchester: 
"Befolgen Sie Ihren Luftangriff-Wärter."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans la bataille pour les coeurs et les esprits 
des  américains pendant la deuxième guerre mondiale, le gouvernement
des ETATS-UNIS a visualisé ses interprètes populaires -- chanteurs, 
danseurs, et acteurs -- comme arme cruciale. Bien qu'un certain 
nombre tienne le premier rôle ait directement joint les militaires, ceux 
qui ont fait des films ait probablement contribué les la plupart à 
l'effort de guerre. Même avant port de perle, les 
fonctionnaires de service de trésor ont commencé à faire des plans 
pour soulever l'argent pour financer la guerre en vendant des 
obligations au public, qui serait remboursé d'intérêt après que 
la guerre plus de. Pendant la guerre, les citoyens privés et 
les organismes ont acheté $190 milliards de valeur des obligations 
de guerre au bas taux d'intérêt d'intérêt de 1.8 pour cent. 
En plus de leur travail comme vendeurs d'obligation, le film 
tient le premier rôle a également encouragé la foule à suivre des 
politiques de temps de guerre, les recommandant instamment en 
particulier (ou plaisantant avec eux) d'observer le rationnement et de
sauvegarder des métaux de chute. Une des annonces plus peu 
communes de service public était cette chanson 1942 de pasteur 
Élégant et de son orchestre : "Obéissez Votre Surveillant 
De Raid aérien."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Na batalha para os corações e as mentes dos 
povos americanos durante a segunda guerra mundial, o governo de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS viu seus performers populares -- singers, dancers, e 
atores -- como uma arma crucial. Embora um número de estrelas 
juntassem diretamente as forças armadas, aquelas que fizeram filmes 
contribuíram provavelmente o a maioria ao esforço da guerra. 
Mesmo antes do porto de pérola, os oficiais do departamento do 
Tesouraria começaram a fazer plantas para levantar o dinheiro para 
financiar a guerra vendendo ligações ao público, que seria 
reembolsado com interesse depois que a guerra sobre. Durante a 
guerra, os cidadãos confidenciais e as organizações compraram $190 
bilhões do valor de ligações de guerra na taxa de interesse baixa 
de 1.8 por cento. Além a seu trabalho como sellers bond, as 
estrelas de filme incentivaram também o populace seguir as políticas
do wartime, exhorting particularmente os (ou gracejando com eles) 
observar racionar e conservar metais de sucata. Um dos anúncios
mais incomuns do serviço público era esta canção 1942 do pastor 
tony e do seu orchestra: "Obedeça Seu Warden Da Invasão De 
Ar."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nella battaglia per i cuori e le menti della gente
americana durante la seconda guerra mondiale, il governo degli STATI 
UNITI ha osservato i relativi esecutori popolari -- cantanti, 
ballerini ed attori -- come arma cruciale. Anche se un certo 
numero di stelle direttamente hanno unito i militari, coloro che ha 
fatto i film probabilmente hanno contribuito il la maggior 
parte allo sforzo di guerra. Anche prima del porto di perla, i 
funzionari di reparto di Ministero del Tesoro hanno cominciato a fare 
i programmi per alzare i soldi per finanziare la guerra vendendo i 
legami al pubblico, che sarebbe rimborsato con interesse dopo che la 
guerra finito. Durante la guerra, i cittadini riservati e le 
organizzazioni hanno comprato $190 miliardo di valore dei legami di 
guerra al tasso di interesse basso di 1.8 per cento. Oltre che 
il loro lavoro come venditori schiavi, le stelle di film 
egualmente hanno consigliato al populace seguire le politiche di 
wartime, exhorting specialmente (o scherzose con loro) osservare il 
razionamento e salvare le ferraglie. Uno degli annunci più 
insoliti di servizio pubblico era questa canzone 1942 dal pastor tony 
e dalla sua orchestra: "Obbedisca Il Vostro Warden Di Incursione
Di Aria."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στη μάχη για τις καρδιές και τα μυαλά των αμερικανικών
ανθρώπων κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ, η 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ κυβέρνηση εμφάνισε τους δημοφιλείς εκτελεστές της -- 
τραγουδιστές, χορευτές, και δράστες -- ως κρίσιμο όπλο. Αν 
και διάφορα αστέρια ένωσαν άμεσα το στρατιωτικό, εκείνοι που 
έκαναν τους κινηματογράφους συνέβαλαν πιθανώς πιό πολύ στην 
πολεμική προσπάθεια. Ακόμη και πριν από το λιμάνι 
μαργαριταριών, οι ανώτεροι υπάλληλοι τμήματος Υπουργείου 
Οικονομικών άρχισαν τα σχέδια για να συγκεντρώσουν τα χρήματα για
να χρηματοδοτήσουν τον πόλεμο με την πώληση των δεσμών στο κοινό,
το οποίο θα ξεπληρωνόταν με το ενδιαφέρον αφότου τελείωσε ο 
πόλεμος. Κατά τη διάρκεια του πολέμου, οι απλοί πολίτες 
και οι οργανώσεις αγόρασαν την αξία $190 δισεκατομμυρίων των 
πολεμικών δεσμών στο χαμηλό επιτόκιο 1,8 τοις εκατό. 
Εκτός από την εργασία τους ως πωλητές δεσμών, τα αστέρια 
κινηματογράφων ενθάρρυναν επίσης το λαό για να ακολουθήσουν τις 
εν καιρώ πολέμου πολιτικές, ιδιαίτερα που προτρέπουν τις (ή που 
αστειεύονται με τις) για να παρατηρήσουν τη διανομή με δελτίο και 
να σώσουν τα μέταλλα απορρίματος. Μια από τις πιό 
ασυνήθιστες ανακοινώσεις δημόσιων υπηρεσιών ήταν αυτό το 
τραγούδι του 1942 από τον πάστορα Tony και την ορχήστρα του:
"Υπακούστε το φύλακα αεροπορικής επιδρομής σας."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En la batalla para los corazones y las mentes de 
la gente americana durante la Segunda Guerra Mundial, el gobierno de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS vio a sus ejecutantes populares -- cantantes, 
bailarines, y agentes -- como arma crucial. Aunque un número de
estrellas ensamblaron directamente a militares, las que hicieron 
películas contribuyeron probablemente el la mayoría al esfuerzo de 
la guerra. Incluso antes de puerto de perla, los funcionarios 
del departamento del Hacienda comenzaron a hacer planes para levantar 
el dinero para financiar la guerra vendiendo enlaces al público, que 
sería compensado con interés después de que la guerra encima. 
Durante la guerra, los ciudadanos privados y las organizaciones 
compraron $190 mil millones del valor de los enlaces de guerra en el 
tipo de interés bajo de 1.8 por ciento. Además de su trabajo 
como vendedores en enlace, las estrellas de cine también animaron al 
populacho siguiera las políticas del tiempo de guerra, suplicándoles
determinado a (o bromeando con ellos) que observen racionar y salven 
los metales de desecho. Uno de los avisos más inusuales del 
servicio público era esta canción 1942 del Pastor tony y de su 
orquesta: "Obedezca A Su Guarda Del Ataque aéreo."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086682</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106688</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/obey-your-air-raid-warden-big-band-as-public-service-announcement</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
