<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/400692516</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>400692516</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203108</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Historical Geology Animations</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Historische Geologie-Animationen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Animations Historiques de Géologie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Animations Históricos Da Geologia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Animazioni Storiche Di Geologia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ιστορικές ζωτικότητες γεωλογίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Animaciones Históricas De la Geología</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site features Flash and Windows Media animations that illustrate various aspects of geologic history. They depict fossil cast formation, the Big Bang and earth through geologic time, the significance of isotopic dating techniques, and views of dinosaurs. These resources are suitable for use in lectures, labs, or other teaching activities.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser Situationsmerkmale Blitz und Windows 
Mediaanimationen, die verschiedene Aspekte der geologischen Geschichte
veranschaulichen. Sie stellen Fossilformanordnung, der grosse 
Knall und die Masse durch geologische Zeit, die Stichhaltigkeit der 
isotopischen datierentechniken und Ansichten der Dinosauriere bildlich
dar. Diese Betriebsmittel sind für Gebrauch in den Vorträgen, 
in den Labors oder in anderen unterrichtenden Aktivitäten verwendbar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ces flash de dispositifs de site et animations de 
medias de Windows qui illustrent de divers aspects de l'histoire 
géologique. Ils dépeignent la formation de fonte de fossile, 
le grande coup et terre par le temps géologique, la signification des
techniques datantes isotopiques, et des vues des dinosaurs. Ces 
ressources conviennent pour l'usage dans les conférences, les 
laboratoires, ou d'autres activités d'enseignement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Estes flash das características de local e 
animations dos media de Windows que ilustram vários aspectos do 
history geologic. Descrevem a formação do molde do fossil, o 
estrondo e a terra grande com o tempo geologic, o significado de 
técnicas datando isotopic, e opiniões os dinosaurs. Estes 
recursos são apropriados para o uso nos lectures, nos laboratórios, 
ou em outras atividades ensinando.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questi flash delle caratteristiche di luogo ed 
animazioni di media di Windows che illustrano le varie funzioni di 
storia geologica. Descrivono la formazione del getto del 
fossile, lo scoppio e la terra grande con tempo geologico, 
l'importanza delle tecniche datanti isotopiche e punti di vista dei 
dinosaurs. Queste risorse sono adatte ad uso nelle conferenze, 
in laboratori, o in altre attività d'istruzione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει τη λάμψη και τις 
ζωτικότητες MEDIA Windows που επεξηγούν τις διάφορες πτυχές 
της γεωλογικής ιστορίας. Απεικονίζουν χυτό τον απολίθωμα 
σχηματισμό, το μεγάλες κτύπημα και τη γη μέσω του γεωλογικού 
χρόνου, η σημασία των ισοτοπικών τεχνικών χρονολόγησης, και των 
όψεων των δεινοσαύρων. Αυτά τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς είναι
κατάλληλα για τη χρήση στις διαλέξεις, τα εργαστήρια, ή άλλες 
δραστηριότητες διδασκαλίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este flash de las características de sitio y 
animaciones de los media de Windows que ilustran varios aspectos de la
historia geológica. Representan la formación del molde del 
fósil, la explosión y la tierra grande con tiempo geológico, la 
significación de técnicas que fechan isotópicas, y las opiniones 
dinosaurios. Estos recursos son convenientes para el uso en 
conferencias, laboratorios, u otras actividades de enseñanza.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203108</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>400692516</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/historical-geology-animations</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
