<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106530</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106530</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086818</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Shall We Gather at the River?": Aimee Semple McPherson on Prohibition</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"sollen Sie wir erfassen am Fluß?": Aimee 
Semple McPherson auf Verbot</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">" nous recueillent au fleuve?" : Aimee 
Semple McPherson sur la prohibition</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"deva nós recolhem no rio?": Aimee Semple 
McPherson na proibição</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Riuniremo al fiume?": Aimee Semple 
McPherson sulla proibizione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Θα συλλέξουμε στον ποταμό;": Aimee Semple 
McPherson στην απαγόρευση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">" nosotros recolectan en el río?": Aimee 
Semple McPherson en la prohibición</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Urban as well as rural Americans flocked to fundamentalist and evangelical churches in the 1920s. Preaching tradition and timeless value, American evangelicals adopted innovative techniques for spreading the word. Aimee Semple McPherson, pastor of the enormous Angelus Temple in the booming city of Los Angeles, preached to a vast radio audience and pioneered the novel technique of faith healing over the airwaves. In this audio clip from a 1924 sermon, McPherson described a loving, kind, and rewarding God instead of the severe, wrathful God of Old Testament tradition. Her youthful persona and cheery good humor helped make her radio presence highly effective. Following a well-publicized scandal involving a mysterious lover, McPherson and other fundamentalists began to lose the prominence they enjoyed in the 1920s.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Städtisch sowie die landwirtschaftlichen 
Amerikaner, die zu den fundamentalistischen und evangelischen Kirchen 
in den zwanziger Jahren predigen Tradition und zeitlosen Wert 
geschart wurden, nahmen amerikanische evangelicals erfinderische 
Techniken für das Verbreiten des Wortes an. Aimee Semple 
McPherson, Pastor des enormen Angelus Bügels in der dröhnenden Stadt
von Los Angeles, predigte zu einem beträchtlichen Radiopublikum und 
ging mit der Romantechnik des Glaubens heilend über den Airwaves 
voran. In diesem Audioclip von einer Predigt 1924, beschrieb 
McPherson ein Lieben, eine Art und einen lohnenden Gott anstelle vom 
strengen, wrathful Gott der Tradition des alten Testaments. Ihre
jugendliche Person und heitre gute Stimmung geholfen, ihre 
Radioanwesenheit in hohem Grade wirkungsvoll zu bilden. Nach 
einem gut-publizierten Skandal, der einen geheimnisvollen Geliebten 
mit einbezieht, fingen McPherson und andere Fundamentalisten an, den 
Vorsprung zu verlieren, den sie in den zwanziger Jahren genossen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Urbain aussi bien que les Américains ruraux 
assemblés aux églises fondamentalistes et évangéliques dans les 
années 20 prêchant la tradition et la valeur intemporelle, les 
evangelicals américains ont adopté des techniques innovatrices pour 
écarter le mot. Aimee Semple McPherson, pasteur de l'énorme 
temple d'Angelus dans la ville éclatante de Los Angeles, a prêché 
à une vaste assistance par radio et a frayé un chemin la technique 
de roman de la foi curatif au-dessus des ondes hertziennes. Dans
ce clip sonore d'un sermon 1924, McPherson a décrit aimer, une sorte,
et un Dieu enrichissant au lieu de Dieu grave et courroucé de la 
tradition de vieux testament. Sa Person jeune et bonne humeur 
gaie aidées pour rendre sa présence par radio fortement pertinente. 
Après un scandale bien-donné de la publicité faisant 
participer un amoureux mystérieux, McPherson et d'autres 
fondamentalistes ont commencé à détruire la proéminence qu'ils ont
appréciée dans les années 20.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Urbano as.well.as os americanos rurais reunidos 
às igrejas fundamentalistas e evangelical nos 1920s. que preaching a 
tradição e o valor timeless, os evangelicals americanos adotaram 
técnicas inovativas para espalhar a palavra. Aimee Semple 
McPherson, pastor do temple enorme de Angelus na cidade crescendo de 
Los Angeles, preached a uma audiência de rádio vasta e abriu caminho
a técnica da novela da fé que healing sobre os airwaves. Neste
grampo audio de um sermon 1924, McPherson descreveu amar, um tipo, e 
um deus recompensando em vez do deus severo, wrathful da tradição do
testament velho. Seus persona jovem e humor bom cheery ajudados 
fazer sua presença de rádio altamente eficaz. Depois de um 
scandal bem-well-publicized que envolve um amante misterioso, 
McPherson e outros fundamentalistas começaram a perder o prominence 
que apreciou nos 1920s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Urbano così come gli Americani rurali affollati 
al fondamentalista ed alle chiese evangelical negli anni 20 che predicano
la tradizione ed il valore timeless, i evangelicals americani hanno 
adottato le tecniche innovarici per la diffusione della parola. 
Aimee Semple McPherson, pastor del tempiale enorme di Angelus 
nella città crescente di Los Angeles, ha predicato ad un pubblico 
radiofonico ampio ed ha aperto la strada alla tecnica del romanzo di 
fede che healing sopra i airwaves. In questa clip audio da un 
sermon 1924, McPherson ha descritto amare, un genere e un dio 
ricompensante anziché il dio severo e adirato di vecchia tradizione 
del Testamento. Il suoi persona youthful e buon umore cheery 
contribuiti per rendere la sua presenza radiofonica altamente 
efficace. A seguito di uno scandalo bene-divulg che fa 
partecipare un amante mysterious, McPherson ed altri 
fondamentalisti hanno cominciato a perdere la protuberanza che hanno 
goduto negli anni 20.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αστικοί καθώς επίσης και αγροτικοί Αμερικανοί 
συγκεντρώθηκαν στις θεμελιωτούσες και εβαγγελικές εκκλησίες στη 
δεκαετία του '20 που κηρύσσει την παράδοση και η άχρονη αξία, 
αμερικανικά evangelicals υιοθέτησε τις καινοτόμες τεχνικές για 
τη λέξη. Το Aimee Semple McPherson, πάστορας του 
τεράστιου ναού Angelus στη να βουίξει πόλη του Λος Αντζελες, 
κήρυξε σε ένα απέραντο ραδιο ακροατήριο και καινοτόμησε τη νέα 
τεχνική θεραπείας πίστης πέρα από τα airwaves. Σε αυτόν
τον ηχητικό συνδετήρα από ένα κήρυγμα του 1924, McPherson 
περιέγραψε μια αγάπη, ένα είδος, και έναν ανταμείβοντας Θεό 
αντί του αυστηρού, οργισμένου Θεού της παλαιάς παράδοσης 
διαθηκών. Το νεανικό persona και το χαρωπό καλό χιούμορ 
της που ενισχύονται να καταστήσει τη ραδιο παρουσία της ιδιαίτερα 
αποτελεσματική. _ μετά από ένας καλά-κοινοποιώ σκάνδαλο 
περι:λαμβάνω ένας μυστήριος εραστής, ΜθΠχερσον και άλλος οπαδός 
αρχίζω να χάνω ο προεξοχή αυτός απολαμβάνω ο δεκαετία του '20.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Urbano así como los americanos rurales reunidos a
las iglesias fundamentalistas y evangélicas en los años 20 que 
predicaban la tradición y el valor intemporal, los evangelicals 
americanos adoptaron las técnicas innovadoras para separar la 
palabra. Aimee Semple McPherson, pastor del templo enorme de
Angelus en la ciudad que crecía de Los Ángeles, predicó a una 
audiencia de radio extensa e inició la técnica de la novela de la fe
curativa sobre los airwaves. En este clip audio de un sermón 
1924, McPherson describió a amar, a una clase, y a dios de recompensa
en vez del dios severo, wrathful de la tradición del viejo 
testamento. Su personaje joven y buen humor cheery ayudados para
hacer su presencia de radio altamente eficaz. Después de un 
escándalo bien-publicado que implicaba a un amante misterioso, 
McPherson y otros fundamentalistas comenzaron a perder la prominencia 
que gozaron en los años 20.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086818</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106530</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/shall-we-gather-at-the-river-aimee-semple-mcpherson-on-prohibition</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
