<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106876</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106876</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086943</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Gravest Question of Our Time": A Senator Lays Out Military Alternatives in the Post-Korean War Atomic Age</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die ernsteste Frage unserer Zeit": Ein 
Senator breitet militärische Alternativen im Pfosten-Koreanischer 
Krieg-Atomalter aus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"la question la plus grave de notre temps" : 
Un sénateur présente des solutions de rechange militaires dans
l'âge atomique de guerre Poteau-Coréenne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"a pergunta a mais grave de nosso tempo": Um
senator Colocar Para fora Militar Alternativa na idade atômica da 
guerra Borne-post-Korean</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la domanda più grave del nostro tempo": Il
senatore presenta le alternative militari nell'età atomica di guerra 
Alberino-Coreana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Το πιό σοβαρό θέμα του χρόνου μασ": Ένας 
γερουσιαστής σχεδιάζει τις στρατιωτικές εναλλακτικές λύσεις στη 
μετα-κορεατική πολεμική ατομική ηλικία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"la cuestión más grave de nuestro tiempo": 
Un senador presenta a alternativas militares en la edad atómica
de la guerra Poste-Coreana</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">For four years after the U.S. dropped atom bombs on Hiroshima and Nagasaki to end World War II, America held a monopoly on the production of atomic weapons. On September 24, 1949, however, news of a Soviet Union nuclear weapons test shocked the nation. The following April, a National Security Council report to President Harry S. Truman advised development of a hydrogen bomb--some 1,000 times more destructive than an atom bomb--and a massive buildup of non-nuclear defenses. The subsequent outbreak of war in Korea in June 1950 justified to many increased defense spending. When fighting reached a stalemate, some in politics and the military--including General Douglas MacArthur, head of the Far East command--advocated the use of atomic weapons against targets in China. Although the Korean War was fought solely with conventional weapons, peace came only after the Eisenhower administration threatened to use nuclear weapons. Following the July 1953 armistice, government and military officials debated the place of nuclear weapons in future defense planning. In this January 1954  Collier's  article, Styles Bridges, chairman of the Senate Appropriations Committee, laid out various proposals and assured citizens of their leaders' dedication "to finding the best solution." Despite a test ban treaty in 1963--sparked in part by the 1962 Cuban Missile Crisis that brought the U.S. and the Soviet Union to the brink of nuclear war--subsequent arms control agreements, and a vigorous nuclear freeze movement, the two superpowers nevertheless pursued an escalating arms race that reached a peak combined total of nearly 60,000 nuclear warheads by the late 1980s.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Für vier Jahre nach den VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
fallengelassenen Atombomben auf Hiroschima und Nagasaki, zum des 
Zweiten Weltkrieges zu beenden, hielt Amerika ein Monopol in die 
Produktion der Atomwaffen an. An September 24, 1949 jedoch 
entsetzten Nachrichten eines Sowjet-Anschlußes, den Kernwaffen 
prüfen, die Nation. Der folgende April, riet ein 
Staatssicherheit Ratreport zum Präsidenten Harry S. Truman 
Entwicklung einer Wasserstoffbombe -- einigen 1.000mal zerstörender 
als eine Atombombe -- und einer massiven Anhäufung der nicht 
nuklearen Verteidigung. Der folgende Ausbruch des Krieges in 
Korea im Juni 1950 schloß zu vielen erhöhte Verteidigungausgabe aus.
Als das Kämpfen einen Stillstand erreichte, befürworteten 
einige in den Politiken und im Militär -- einschließlich General 
Douglas MacArthur, Kopf des Ferner Osten Befehls -- den Gebrauch der 
Atomwaffen gegen Ziele in China. Obgleich der koreanische Krieg 
nur mit herkömmlichen Waffen gekämpft wurde, kam Frieden nur nach 
der Eisenhower Leitung, die bedroht wurde, um Kernwaffen zu benutzen. 
Nach dem Juli 1953 Waffenstillstand debattierten Regierung und 
militärische Beamte den Ort der Kernwaffen in der zukünftigen 
Verteidigungplanung. Im Artikel dieses Januar 1954 Colliers 
britten Art-Brücken, Vorsitzender des Senat-Bewilligungsausschußes, 
verschiedene Anträge aus und versicherten Bürgern von der Widmung 
ihrer Führer "zum Finden der besten Lösung." Trotz eines 
Testverbotvertrags 1963 -- gefunkt im Teil durch die 1962 
Kubaner-Flugkrise, die die VEREINIGTEN STAATEN und den 
Sowjet-Anschluß zum Rand des Kernkrieges holte -- folgende 
Rüstungskontrollevereinbarungen und einer kräftigen 
Kernfrostbewegung übten die zwei Superpowers dennoch einen 
entwickelnden Rüstungswettlauf aus, der eine Spitze kombinierte 
Gesamtmenge von fast 60.000 Kernwarheads durch spätes Jahr erreichte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant quatre années après les bombes atomiques
lâchées par ETATS-UNIS sur Hiroshima et Nagasaki pour terminer la 
deuxième guerre mondiale, l'Amérique a tenu un monopole sur la 
production des armes atomiques. 24 septembre 1949, cependant, 
les nouvelles d'Union Soviétique les armes que nucléaires testent ont 
choqué la nation. Avril suivant, un état du Conseil de 
sécurité nationale au Président Harry S. Truman a informé le 
développement d'une bombe à hydrogène -- environ 1.000 fois plus 
destructive qu'une bombe atomique -- et un habillage massif des 
défenses non-nucléaires. La manifestation ultérieure de 
guerre en Corée en juin 1950 a justifié à beaucoup des dépenses 
pour la défense accrues. Quand le combat a atteint une impasse,
certains dans la politique et les militaires -- comprenant le 
Général Douglas MacArthur, chef de la commande de l'Extrême-Orient 
-- ont préconisé l'utilisation des armes atomiques contre des cibles
en Chine. Bien que la guerre coréenne ait été combattue 
seulement avec les armes conventionnelles, la paix est venue seulement
après que la gestion d'Eisenhower a menacé d'utiliser les armes 
nucléaires. Après l'armistice de juillet 1953, le gouvernement
et les fonctionnaires militaires ont discuté l'endroit des armes 
nucléaires dans le futur plan de défense. En cet article de 
janvier 1954 Collier, les passerelles de modèles, Président du 
Comité de crédits de sénat, ont présenté de diverses propositions
et ont assuré des citoyens de l'attachement de leurs amorces "à 
trouver la meilleure solution." En dépit d'un traité 
d'interdiction d'essai en 1963 -- étincelé en partie par la crise de
missile de 1962 Cubains qui a apporté les ETATS-UNIS et 
l'Union Soviétique au bord de la guerre nucléaire -- accords ultérieurs 
de limitation des armements, et d'un mouvement nucléaire vigoureux de
gel, les deux superpuissances ont néanmoins poursuivi une course aux 
armements d'escalade qui a atteint un total combiné par crête de 
presque 60.000 ogives nucléaires par la fin des années 1980.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Por quatro anos após as bombas de átomo deixadas
cair ESTADOS UNIDOS em Hiroshima e em Nagasaki para terminar a segunda
guerra mundial, América prendeu um monopólio na produção de armas 
atômicas. Setembro em 24, 1949, entretanto, a notícia de uma 
Soviete-união que as armas nucleares testam chocou a nação. O
seguinte abril, um relatório do conselho de segurança nacional ao 
presidente Harry S. Truman recomendou o desenvolvimento de uma bomba 
de hidrogênio -- umas 1.000 vezes mais destrutiva do que uma bomba de
átomo -- e um acúmulo maciço de defesas non-nuclear. O 
outbreak subseqüente da guerra em Coreia em junho 1950 justificou a 
muitos a despesa de defesa aumentada. Quando lutar alcançou um 
empate, algumas na política e nas forças armadas -- including o 
general Douglas MacArthur, cabeça do comando do leste distante -- 
advogaram o uso de armas atômicas de encontro aos alvos em China. 
Embora a guerra korean fosse lutada unicamente com as armas 
convencionais, a paz veio somente após a administração de 
Eisenhower ameaçada usar armas nucleares. Depois do armistice 
de julho 1953, o governo e os oficiais militares debateram o lugar de 
armas nucleares no planeamento de defesa futuro. No artigo deste
collier de janeiro 1954, as pontes dos estilos, presidente do comitê 
de apropriações do senate, colocaram para fora das várias propostas
e asseguraram cidadãos do dedication dos seus líderes "a encontrar a
mais melhor solução." Apesar de um tratado da proibição do 
teste em 1963 -- acendido na parte pela crise do míssil de 1962 
cubanos que trouxe os ESTADOS UNIDOS e a Soviete-união ao brink da 
guerra nuclear -- acordos subseqüentes do controle de braços, e de 
um movimento nuclear vigoroso do freeze, os dois superpowers não 
obstante perseguiram uma raça de braços escalando que alcançasse um
total combinado pico de quase 60.000 warheads nucleares pelos 1980s 
atrasados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Per quattro anni dopo gli STATI UNITI ha caduto le
bombe atomiche su Hiroshima e Nagasaki per concludere la seconda 
guerra mondiale, America ha tenuto un monopolio sulla produzione delle
armi atomiche. Il 24 settembre 1949, tuttavia, le notizie di 
un'Soviet-unione che le armi nucleari esaminano hanno scosso la 
nazione. Seguente aprile, un rapporto del Consiglio di sicurezza
nazionale al presidente Harry S. Truman ha raccomandato lo sviluppo di
una bomba all'idrogeno -- circa 1.000 volta più distruttiva di una 
bomba atomica -- e un'accumulazione voluminosa delle difese non 
nucleari. Lo scoppio successivo di guerra in Corea in giugno 
1950 ha giustificato a molti la spesa aumentata della difesa. 
Quando il combattimento ha raggiunto un impasse, alcuni nelle 
politiche e nei militari -- compreso il General Douglas MacArthur, 
testa del comando dell'Estremo-Oriente -- hanno sostenuto l'uso delle 
armi atomiche contro gli obiettivi in Cina. Anche se la guerra 
coreana è stata combattuta solamente con le armi convenzionali, la 
pace è venuto solo dopo che la gestione di Eisenhower ha minacciato 
di utilizzare le armi nucleari. A seguito del armistice di 
luglio del 1953, il governo ed i funzionari militari hanno dibattuto 
il posto delle armi nucleari nella pianificazione di difesa futura. 
In articolo di questo collier di gennaio del 1954, i ponticelli 
di stili, presidente del comitato di crediti del senato, hanno 
presentato le varie proposte ed hanno assicurato i cittadini 'dedica 
"dei loro capi a trovare la soluzione migliore." Malgrado
un trattato di divieto della prova in 1963 -- scintillato in parte 
dalla crisi del missile dei 1962 cubani che ha portato gli STATI UNITI
e l'Soviet-unione al bordo della guerra nucleare -- armi 
successive gestisce gli accordi e un movimento nucleare vigoroso del 
freeze, i due superpowers tuttavia ha perseguito una corsa crescente 
di armi che ha raggiunto un totale unito picco di quasi 60.000 
warheads nucleari dalla fine degli anni 1980.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Για τέσσερα έτη μετά από τις πεταγμένες οι ΗΠΑ 
βόμβες ατόμων στη Χιροσίμα και το Ναγκασάκι για να τελειώσει τον 
παγκόσμιο πόλεμο ΙΙ, η Αμερική κράτησε ένα μονοπώλιο στην 
παραγωγή των ατομικών όπλων. Στις 24 Σεπτεμβρίου 
..1949, εντούτοις, οι ειδήσεις μιας δοκιμής πυρηνικών όπλων 
Σοβιετικής Ένωσης συγκλόνισαν το έθνος. Ο επόμενος 
Απρίλιος, μια εθνική έκθεση του Συμβουλίου Ασφαλείας στον 
Πρόεδρο Harry S. Truman συμβούλεψε την ανάπτυξη μιας 
βόμβας υδρογόνου -- περίπου 1.000 χρόνοι πιό καταστρεπτικοί 
από μια βόμβα ατόμων -- και μια ογκώδη συγκέντρωση των μη 
πυρηνικών υπερασπίσεων. Το επόμενο ξέσπασμα του πολέμου 
στην Κορέα τον Ιούνιο του 1950 που δικαιολογείται σε πολλά 
αυξανόμενα αμυντικά έξοδα. Όταν η πάλη έφθασε σε ένα 
αδιέξοδο, μερικά στην πολιτική και το στρατιωτικό -- 
συμπεριλαμβανομένου του στρατηγού Douglas MacArthur, κεφάλι 
της εντολής της Απω Ανατολής -- υποστήριξαν τη χρήση των 
ατομικών όπλων ενάντια στους στόχους στην Κίνα. Αν και ο 
κορεατικός πόλεμος διεξήχθη απλώς με τα συμβατικά όπλα, η 
ειρήνη ήρθε μόνο αφού απείλησε να χρησιμοποιήσει η κυβέρνηση 
Eisenhower τα πυρηνικά όπλα. Μετά από την ανακωχή 
Ιουλίου 1953, η κυβέρνηση και οι στρατιωτικοί ανώτεροι 
υπάλληλοι συζήτησαν τη θέση των πυρηνικών όπλων στο μελλοντικό 
αμυντικό προγραμματισμό. Σε αυτό το άρθρο του ανθρακωρύχου 
Ιανουαρίου 1954, οι γέφυρες μορφών, πρόεδρος της Επιτροπής 
πιστώσεων Συγκλήτου, σχεδίασαν τις διάφορες προτάσεις και 
βεβαίωσαν τους πολίτες της αφιέρωσης των ηγετών τους "στην εύρεση
της καλύτερης λύσης." Παρά μια συνθήκη απαγόρευσης δοκιμής
το 1963 -- σπινθηρισμένος εν μέρει από την κρίση βλημάτων του 
1962 κουβανική που έφερε τις ΗΠΑ και τη Σοβιετική Ένωση στο 
χείλο του πυρηνικού πολέμου -- οι επόμενες συμφωνίες ελέγχου 
όπλων, και μια σφριγηλή πυρηνική μετακίνηση παγώματος, οι δύο 
υπερδυνάμεις εντούτοις ακολούθησαν μια κλιμακώνοντας φυλή όπλων 
που έφθασε σε ένα συνδυασμένο αιχμή σύνολο σχεδόν 60.000 
πυρηνικών κεφαλών πυραύλου μέχρι την πρόσφατη δεκαετία του '80.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Por cuatro años después de las bombas atómicas 
caídas ESTADOS UNIDOS en Hiroshima y Nagasaki para terminar la 
Segunda Guerra Mundial, América llevó a cabo un monopolio en la 
producción de armas atómicas. 24 de septiembre de 1949, sin
embargo, las noticias de una Soviet-unio'n que las armas nucleares 
prueban dieron una sacudida eléctrica la nación. El abril 
siguiente, un informe del consejo de la seguridad nacional a 
presidente Harry S. Truman aconsejó el desarrollo de una bomba de 
hidrógeno -- unas 1.000 veces más destructiva que una bomba atómica
-- y una acumulación masiva de defensas no nucleares. El brote 
subsecuente de guerra en Corea en junio 1950 alineó a muchos gastos 
para defensa crecientes. Cuando el luchar alcanzó un 
estancamiento, algo en políticas y los militares -- incluyendo 
general Douglas MacArthur, jefe del comando del este lejano -- abogó 
el uso de armas atómicas contra blancos en China. Aunque la 
guerra coreana fue luchada solamente con las armas convencionales, la 
paz vino solamente después que la administración de Eisenhower 
amenazó utilizar las armas nucleares. Después del armistice de
julio de 1953, el gobierno y los funcionarios militares discutieron el
lugar de armas nucleares en las hojas de operación (planning) de 
defensa futuras. En el artículo de este collier de enero de 
1954, los puentes de los estilos, presidente del comité de 
apropiaciones del senado, presentaron a varias ofertas y aseguraron a 
ciudadanos del esmero de sus arranques de cinta "a encontrar la mejor 
solución." A pesar de un tratado de la interdicción de la 
prueba en 1963 -- chispeado en parte por la crisis del misil de 1962 
cubanos que trajo los ESTADOS UNIDOS y la Soviet-unio'n al borde 
de la guerra nuclear -- acuerdos subsecuentes del control de 
armamentos, y un movimiento nuclear vigoroso de la helada, las dos 
superpotencias sin embargo persiguieron a una carrera de armamentos de
extensión que alcanzó un total combinado pico de casi 60.000 cabezas
nucleares nucleares por el final de los '80.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086943</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106876</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-gravest-question-of-our-time-a-senator-lays-out-military-alternatives-in-the-post-korean-war-atomic-age</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
