<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106401</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106401</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086728</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Photographing Criminals."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">", Verbrecher Fotografierend."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Photographiant des Criminels."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Fotografando Criminosos."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Fotografando I Criminali."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Φωτογραφίζοντας τους εγκληματίες."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Fotografiando A Criminales."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">On May 4, 1886, in Chicago's Haymarket Square, a bomb exploded during a labor demonstration protesting the police shootings of four striking workers. In response, the government and business groups nationwide strengthened the police and the military in an effort to curb labor militancy and public disorder. As part of its coverage of the Haymarket incident, one newspaper displayed this scene from Chicago's police headquarters, showing the construction of a criminal identification system based on photographs. The Rogues' Gallery" served as an archive to identify individual criminals (including political dissenters and labor activists) and to discern</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">An Mai 4, 1886, im Quadrat Haymarket Chicagos, explodierte
eine Bombe während einer Arbeitsdemonstration, welche die Polizei 
shootings von vier auffallenden Arbeitern protestiert. In der 
Antwort, verstärkten die Regierung und Geschäft Gruppen im ganzen 
Land die Polizei und das Militär in einer Bemühung, 
Arbeitsmilitancy- und Öffentlichkeitsstörung zu bändigen. Als
Teil seiner Dichte des Haymarket Ereignisses, zeigte zeigte eine 
Zeitung diese Szene von den PolizeiHauptsitzen Chicagos an und den 
Aufbau eines kriminellen Kennzeichensystems, das auf Fotographien 
basierte. Die Gauner ' Galerie "dienten als Archiv, 
einzelne Verbrecher zu kennzeichnen (einschließlich politische 
dissenters und Arbeitsaktivisten) und zu erkennen</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">4 mai 1886, dans la place de Haymarket de Chicago, une 
panne a éclaté pendant une démonstration de travail protestant les 
shootings de police de quatre ouvriers saisissants. Dans la 
réponse, les groupes de gouvernement et d'affaires dans tout le pays 
ont renforcé la police et les militaires dans un effort de limiter le
désordre de travail de militantisme et de public. En tant 
qu'élément de son assurance de l'incident de Haymarket, un journal a
affiché cette scène des sièges sociaux de la police de Chicago, 
montrant la construction d'un système criminel d'identification basé
sur des photographies. Les Escrocs 'galerie "ont servi 
d'archives pour identifier différents criminels (dissidents 
politiques y compris et activistes de travail) et pour les discerner</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Maio em 4, 1886, no quadrado de Haymarket de Chicago, uma 
bomba explodiu durante uma demonstração labor que protesta os 
shootings das polícias de quatro trabalhadores impressionantes. 
Na resposta, os grupos do governo e do negócio por todo o país
strengthened as polícias e as forças armadas em um esforço curb o 
disorder labor do militancy e do público. Como a parte de sua 
cobertura do incident de Haymarket, um jornal indicou esta cena das 
matrizes das polícias de Chicago, mostrando a construção de um 
sistema criminal da identificação baseado em fotografias. 
Galeria labor a política do Rogues' "serviu como um arquivo 
identificar criminosos individuais (dissenters including e activistas)
e discerni-los</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Maggio su 4, 1886, nel quadrato di Haymarket del Chicago, 
una bomba ha esploso durante la dimostrazione di lavoro che protesta 
gli shootings della polizia di quattro operai notevoli. Nella 
risposta, i gruppi di affari e di governo in tutta la nazione hanno 
rinforzato la polizia ed i militari in uno sforzo porre freno il 
disordine di lavoro del pubblico e della militanza. Come 
componente del relativo riempimento dell'avvenimento di Haymarket, un 
giornale ha visualizzato questa scena dalle sedi della polizia del 
Chicago, mostranti la costruzione di un sistema criminale 
dell'identificazione basato sulle fotografie. Galleria 
di lavoro la politica del Rogues "ha servito da archivio 
identificare i diversi criminali (dissenters compresi e attivisti) 
e discernere</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε Μάιος 4 ..1886, στην πλατεία Haymarket του 
Σικάγου, μια βόμβα που εκρήγνυται κατά τη διάρκεια μιας 
επίδειξης εργασίας που διαμαρτύρεται τους πυροβολισμούς 
αστυνομίας τεσσάρων απεργών εργαζομένων. Στην απάντηση, η 
κυβέρνηση και οι επιχειρησιακές ομάδες σε εθνικό επίπεδο 
ενίσχυσαν την αστυνομία και τους στρατιωτικούς σε μια προσπάθεια 
να συγκρατηθεί η μαχητικότητα εργασίας και η δημόσια αναταραχή. 
Ως τμήμα της κάλυψής της του γεγονότος Haymarket, μια 
εφημερίδα παρουσίασε αυτήν την σκηνή από την έδρα αστυνομίας 
του Σικάγου, που εμφανίζει την κατασκευή ενός ποινικού 
συστήματος προσδιορισμού βασισμένου στις φωτογραφίες. Η 
στοά των απατεώνων "που χρησιμεύεται ως ένα αρχείο για να 
προσδιορίσει τους μεμονωμένους εγκληματίες (συμπεριλαμβανομένων 
των πολιτικών αποστατών και των ενεργών στελεχών εργασίας) και 
για να διακρίνει</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">4 de mayo de 1886, en el cuadrado de Haymarket de 
Chicago, una bomba estalló durante una demostración de trabajo que 
protestaba los shootings del policía de cuatro trabajadores 
llamativos. En respuesta, los grupos del gobierno y del negocio 
por toda la nación consolidaron al policía y a militares en un 
esfuerzo de contener desorden de trabajo de la militancia y del 
público. Como parte de su cobertura del incidente de Haymarket,
un periódico visualizó esta escena de las jefaturas del policía de 
Chicago, mostrando la construcción de un sistema criminal de la 
identificación basado en las fotografías. Los Granujas ' 
galería "sirvieron como archivo para identificar a criminales 
individuales (dissenters políticos incluyendo y los activistas de 
trabajo) y para discernirlos</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086728</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106401</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/photographing-criminals</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
