<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104107</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104107</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209808</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Math / scientific calculator</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathe/wissenschaftlicher Rechner</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Maths/calculatrice scientifique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Math/calculadora científica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Per la matematica/calcolatore scientifico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Math/epjstimonjko's υπολογιστής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas/calculadora científica</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A free web based math / scientific calculator specially designed for the education environment. It operates in a very similar way to the popular school calculators and so does not need re-learning. The calculator can be blown up to full screen size, making it a useful teaching tool in a classroom setting with a projector. Functions: sin, cos, tan, sin-1, cos-1,tan-1 square root, log10, loge, power of ten, squared, ex Constants: pi, e, root 2 This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein freies Web gründete Mathe/wissenschaftlichen 
Rechner, die besonders für die Ausbildung Umgebung bestimmt waren. 
Es funktioniert in einer sehr ähnlichen Methode zu den 
populären Schulerechnern und also braucht nicht wieder zu lernen. 
Der Rechner kann zum vollen Bildumfang gesprengt werden und es 
ein nützliches unterrichtendes Hilfsmittel in einem Klassenzimmer 
bilden, das mit einem Projektor einstellt. Funktionen: 
Sünde, Lattich, Säurenummer, sin-1, cos-1, tan-1 
Quadratwurzel, log10, loge, Energie von 10, quadrierte, ex Konstanten:
PUS, e, verwurzeln 2, die dieses Hilfsmittel ein Bestandteil des
Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an 
http://www.mathopenref.com ist.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un Web libre a basé les maths/calculatrice 
scientifique particulièrement conçues pour l'environnement 
d'éducation. Il fonctionne d'une voie très semblable aux 
calculatrices populaires d'école et ainsi n'a pas besoin 
réapprendre. La calculatrice peut être faite sauter à la 
taille de plein écran, lui faisant un outil d'enseignement utile dans
une salle de classe plaçant avec un projecteur. Fonctions : 
péché, cos, bronzage, sin-1, cos-1, bronzage-1 racine 
carrée, log10, loge, puissance de dix, constantes carrées et ex : 
pi, e, enracinent 2 que cette ressource est un composant du 
projet interactif de manuel de la géométrie de référence ouverte 
de maths à http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um Web livre baseou o math/calculadora científica
projetados especialmente para o ambiente da instrução. 
Opera-se em uma maneira muito similar às calculadoras populares
da escola e assim que não se necessita re-learning. A 
calculadora pode ser fundida até o tamanho de tela cheia, fazendo lhe
uma ferramenta ensinando útil em uma sala de aula que ajusta-se com 
um projetor. Funções: sin, cos, tan, sin-1, cos-1, tan-1
raiz quadrada, log10, loge, potência de dez, constantes esquadradas, 
ex: os pi, e, enraizam 2 que este recurso é um componente do 
projeto interativo do textbook da geometria da referência aberta do 
math em http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un Web libero ha basato il per la 
matematica/calcolatore scientifico progettati specialmente per 
l'ambiente di formazione. Funziona in un modo molto simile ai 
calcolatori popolari della scuola ed in modo da non deve re-learning. 
Il calcolatore può essere scoppiato al formato di schermo 
pieno, rendentegli uno strumento d'istruzione utile in un'aula che si 
regola con un proiettore. Funzioni: sin, cos, tan, sin-1, 
cos-1, tan-1 radice quadrata, log10, loge, un'potenza di dieci, 
costanti quadrati e ex: i pi, e, sradicano 2 che questa risorsa 
è un componente del progetto interattivo del manuale della geometria 
di riferimento aperto di per la matematica a 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένας ελεύθερος Ιστός που βασίζεται 
math/epjstimonjko's υπολογιστής που σχεδιάζεται ειδικά για το 
περιβάλλον εκπαίδευσης. Λειτουργεί με πολύ παρόμοιο τρόπο 
στους δημοφιλείς σχολικούς υπολογιστές και έτσι δεν χρειάζεται 
την επαν-εκμάθηση. Ο υπολογιστής μπορεί να φυσεί μέχρι το 
πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης, που κάνει το ένα χρήσιμο εργαλείο 
διδασκαλίας σε μια τάξη θέτοντας με έναν προβολέα. 
Λειτουργεί: η αμαρτία, μαρούλι, μαύρισμα, αμαρτία-1, 
μαρούλι-1, μαύρισμα-1 τετραγωνική ρίζα, log10, loge, δύναμη
δέκα, τακτοποίησε, πρώην σταθερές: το pi, ε, ρίζα 2 
αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού 
προγράμματος εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού 
σε http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un Web libre basó la matemáticas/la calculadora 
científica diseñadas especialmente para el ambiente de la 
educación. Funciona de una manera muy similar a las 
calculadoras populares de la escuela y así que no necesita volver a 
aprender. La calculadora se puede soplar hasta la talla de la 
pantalla completa, haciéndole una herramienta de enseñanza útil en 
una sala de clase que fija con un proyector. Funciones: 
pecado, lechuga romana, tan, sin-1, cos-1, tan-1 raíz cuadrada,
log10, loge, potencia de diez, constantes ajustadas, exes: los 
pi, e, arraigan 2 que este recurso es un componente del proyecto 
interactivo del libro de textos de la geometría de la referencia 
abierta de la matemáticas en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209808</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104107</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/math-scientific-calculator</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
