<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104160</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104160</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087320</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"A Modern School": Abraham Flexner Outlines Progressive Education</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Eine Moderne Schule": Abraham Flexner 
Umreißt Progressive Ausbildung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Une École Moderne" : Abraham Flexner Trace
les grandes lignes de l'Éducation Progressive</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Uma Escola Moderna": Abraham Flexner 
Esboça A Instrução Progressiva</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Una Scuola Moderna": Abraham Flexner 
Descrive La Formazione Progressiva</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ένα σύγχρονο σχολείο": Θ*Αψραχαμ Flexner 
Outlines Progressive Education</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Una Escuela Moderna": Abraham Flexner 
Contornea La Educación Progresiva</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the early 20th century, an impressive array of intellectuals, social critics, and grassroots activists came together to launch a progressive education movement that sought broad-based change in American educational practice. At the heart of the progressive program lay a pedagogy that emphasized flexibility and critical thinking. This was coupled with the belief that schools should establish organic relationships with their communities, that curricula should confront broad social issues, and that public-school administrators should provide educational opportunities for all children. Thoroughly infused with the reformist sensibilities of Progressive-era politics, progressive education essentially looked to schools for the political and social regeneration of the nation. In this 1916 essay, Abraham Flexner proposed an experimental school based on these ideas. In 1917, he founded the Lincoln School in New York, which embraced many of these disparate elements and prospered for more than three decades, gaining respect and influence.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im frühen 20. Jahrhundert kamen eine 
eindrucksvolle Reihe Intellektuelle, Sozialkritiker und 
Basisaktivisten zusammen, eine progressive Ausbildung Bewegung 
auszustoßen, die broad-based Änderung in der amerikanischen 
pädagogischen Praxis suchte. Am Inneren des progressiven 
Programms legen Sie ein pedagogy, das Flexibilität und das kritische 
Denken hervorhob. Dieses wurde mit dem Glauben verbunden, daß 
Schulen organische Verhältnisse zu ihren Gemeinschaften aufbauen 
sollten, daß Lehrpläne ausgedehnte Sozialausgaben konfrontieren 
sollten und daß Öffentlichkeit-Schule Verwalter pädagogische 
Gelegenheiten für alle Kinder zur Verfügung stellen sollten. 
Gänzlich hineingegossen mit den reformistischen Empfindlichkeiten 
der Progressiv-Ära Politiken, schaute progressive Ausbildung im 
Wesentlichen zu den Schulen nach der politischen und 
Sozialregeneration der Nation. In diesem Versuch 1916 schlug 
Abraham Flexner eine experimentelle Schule vor, die auf diesen Ideen 
basierte. 1917 gründete er die Lincoln Schule in New York, das 
viele dieser unvereinbaren Elemente umfaßte und für mehr als drei 
Dekaden sich erweiterte und Respekt und Einfluß gewann.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En début du 20ème siècle, un alignement 
impressionnant d'intellectuels, les critiques sociaux, et les 
activistes de bases sont venus ensemble pour lancer un mouvement 
progressif d'éducation qui a recherché le changement offrant tout 
l'éventail de produits de la pratique éducative américaine. 
Au coeur du programme progressif étendez une pédagogie qui a 
souligné la flexibilité et la pensée critique. Ceci a été 
couplé à la croyance que les écoles devraient établir des rapports
organiques avec leurs communautés, que les programmes d'études 
devraient confronter de larges issues sociales, et que les 
administrateurs d'école publique devraient présenter des moyens 
éducatifs de tous les enfants. Complètement infusé avec les 
susceptibilités réformistes de la politique de Progressif-ère, 
l'éducation progressive a essentiellement regardé aux écoles pour 
la régénération politique et sociale de la nation. Dans cet 
essai 1916, Abraham Flexner a proposé une école expérimentale 
basée sur ces idées. En 1917, il a fondé l'école de Lincoln 
à New York, qui a embrassé plusieurs de ces éléments disparates et
a prospéré pendant plus de trois décennies, gagnant le respect et 
l'influence.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No 20o século adiantado, uma disposição 
impressive dos intelectuais, os críticos sociais, e as activistas dos
grassroots vieram junto lançar um movimento progressivo da 
instrução que procurasse a mudança broad-based na prática 
educacional americana. No coração do programa progressivo 
coloque um pedagogy que emfatize a flexibilidade e pensar crítico. 
Isto foi acoplado com a opinião que as escolas devem 
estabelecer relacionamentos orgânicos com suas comunidades, que os 
curricula devem confrontar edições sociais largas, e que os 
administradores da público-escola devem fornecer oportunidades 
educacionais para todas as crianças. Infused completamente com 
os sensibilities reformist da política da Progressivo-era, a 
instrução progressiva olhou essencialmente às escolas para a 
regeneração política e social da nação. Neste essay 1916, 
Abraham Flexner propôs uma escola experimental baseada nestas 
idéias. Em 1917, fundou a escola de Lincoln em New York, que 
embraced muitos destes elementos disparate e prospered por mais de 
três décadas, ganhando o respeito e a influência.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nell'inizio del 20esimo secolo, un allineamento 
impressionante degli intellettuali, i critici sociali e gli 
attivisti dei grassroots sono venuto insieme lanciare un movimento 
progressivo di formazione che ha cercato il cambiamento broad-based 
nella pratica educativa americana. Al cuore del programma 
progressivo ponga un pedagogy che ha dato risalto alla flessibilità 
ed a pensare critico. Ciò è stata accoppiata con la credenza 
che le scuole dovrebbero stabilire i rapporti organici con le loro 
Comunità, che i programmi di studi dovrebbero confrontare le vaste 
edizioni sociali e che gli amministratori della pubblico-scuola 
dovrebbero offrire le occasioni educative di tutti i bambini. 
Infuso completamente con le sensibilità riformisti delle 
politiche di Progressivo-era, la formazione progressiva essenzialmente
ha osservato alle scuole per la rigenerazione politica e sociale della
nazione. In questo saggio 1916, Abraham Flexner ha proposto una 
scuola sperimentale basata su queste idee. In 1917, ha fondato 
la scuola de Lincoln a New York, che ha abbracciato molti di questi 
elementi disparati ed ha fatto prosperare per più di tre decadi, 
guadagnando il rispetto e l'influenza.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στις αρχές του 20ού αιώνα, μια εντυπωσιακή σειρά 
διανοούμενων, κοινωνικών κριτικών, και ενεργών στελεχών σε 
επίπεδο βάσης ενώθηκε να προωθήσει μια προοδευτική μετακίνηση 
εκπαίδευσης που επιδίωξε τη σε ευρεία βάση αλλαγή στην 
αμερικανική εκπαιδευτική πρακτική. Στην καρδιά του 
προοδευτικού προγράμματος βάλτε μια παιδαγωγική που υπογράμμισε 
την ευελιξία και την κρίσιμη σκέψη. Αυτό συνδέθηκε με την 
πεποίθηση ότι τα σχολεία πρέπει να καθιερώσουν τις οργανικές 
σχέσεις με τις κοινότητές τους, ότι τα προγράμματα σπουδών 
πρέπει να αντιμετωπίσουν τα ευρέα κοινωνικά ζητήματα, και ότι οι
δημόσιος-σχολικοί διοικητές πρέπει να παρέχουν τις εκπαιδευτικές
ευκαιρίες για όλα τα παιδιά. Λεπτομερώς εμποτισμένη με τις 
μεταρρυθμιστικές ευαισθησίες της πολιτικής προοδευτικός-εποχής, η
προοδευτική εκπαίδευση κοίταξε ουσιαστικά στα σχολεία για την 
πολιτική και κοινωνική αναγέννηση του έθνους. Σε αυτό το 
δοκίμιο του 1916, ο Abraham Flexner πρότεινε ένα 
πειραματικό σχολείο που έδρευσε σε αυτές τις ιδέες. Το 
1917, ίδρυσε το σχολείο του Λίνκολν στη Νέα Υόρκη, η οποία 
αγκαλίασε πολλών από αυτά τα ανόμοια στοιχεία και ευημέρησε για
περισσότερο από τρεις δεκαετίες, κερδίζοντας το σεβασμό και την 
επιρροή.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En el vigésimo siglo temprano, un arsenal 
impresionante de intelectuales, los críticos sociales, y los 
activistas de los pueblos vinieron juntos lanzar un movimiento 
progresivo de la educación que buscó el cambio broad-based en 
práctica educativa americana. En el corazón del programa 
progresivo ponga un pedagogy que acentuó flexibilidad y el 
pensamiento crítico. Esto fue juntada con la creencia que las 
escuelas deben establecer lazos orgánicos con sus comunidades, que 
los planes de estudios deben enfrentar amplias ediciones sociales, y 
que los administradores de la pu'blico-escuela deben proporcionar a 
las oportunidades educativas para todos los niños. Infundido a 
conciencia con las sensibilidades reformistas de las políticas de la 
Progresivo-era, la educación progresiva esencialmente miraba a las 
escuelas para la regeneración política y social de la nación. 
En este ensayo 1916, Abraham Flexner propuso una escuela 
experimental basada en estas ideas. En 1917, él fundó la 
escuela de Lincoln en Nueva York, que abrazó muchos de estos 
elementos dispares y prosperó por más de tres décadas, ganando 
respecto e influencia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087320</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104160</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-modern-school-abraham-flexner-outlines-progressive-education</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
