<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105479</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105479</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206751</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">FEMA for Kids</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">FEMA für Zicklein</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">FEMA pour des gosses</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">FEMA para miúdos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">FEMA per i capretti</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Fema για τα κατσίκια</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">FEMA para los cabritos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">teaches children how to prepare for disasters and how to prevent disasters. Kids can also learn about different types and causes of disasters, share disaster stories, play games, read stories, access research materials, and become a Disaster Action Kid. The site offers disaster prevention resources for parents, teachers, and child care providers.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">bringt Kindern bei, wie man für Unfälle 
vorbereitet und wie man Unfälle verhindert. Zicklein können 
über unterschiedliche Typen und Ursachen der Unfälle, 
Anteilunfallgeschichten, Spielspiele auch erlernen, lesen Geschichten,
greifen auf Forschung Materialien zu und werden ein Unfall-Tätigkeit 
Zicklein. Die Site bietet Unfallverhinderungbetriebsmittel für 
Eltern, Lehrer und Kindobachtversorger an.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">enseigne à des enfants comment se préparer aux 
désastres et comment empêcher des désastres. Les gosses 
peuvent également se renseigner sur différents types et causes de 
désastres, histoires de désastre de part, jeux de jeu, lisent des 
histoires, accèdent à des matériaux de recherches, et deviennent un
gosse d'action de désastre. Le site offre des ressources 
d'empêchement de désastre pour des parents, des professeurs, et des 
fournisseurs d'assistance à l'enfance.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">ensina a crianças como preparar-se para disastres 
e como impedir disastres. Os miúdos podem também aprender 
sobre tipos e causas diferentes dos disastres, histórias do disastre 
da parte, jogos do jogo, lêem histórias, alcançam materiais da 
pesquisa, e transformam-se um miúdo da ação do disastre. O 
local oferece recursos da prevenção do disastre para pais, 
professores, e fornecedores do cuidado de criança.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">insegna a bambini come prepararsi per i disastri e 
come impedire i disastri. I capretti possono anche imparare 
circa i tipi e le cause differenti di disastri, storia di disastro 
della parte, giochi del gioco, leggono le storia, accedono ai 
materiali di ricerca e diventano un capretto di azione di disastro. 
Il luogo offre le risorse di prevenzione di disastro per i 
genitori, gli insegnanti ed i fornitori di cura di bambino.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">διδάσκει τα παιδιά πώς να προετοιμαστεί για τις 
καταστροφές και πώς να αποτρέψει τις καταστροφές. Τα 
κατσίκια μπορούν επίσης να μάθουν για τους διαφορετικούς τύπους 
και τις αιτίες των καταστροφών, ιστορίες καταστροφής μεριδίου, 
παιχνίδια παιχνιδιού, διαβάζουν τις ιστορίες, ερευνητικά υλικά 
πρόσβασης, και γίνονται ένα κατσίκι ενέργειας καταστροφής. 
Η περιοχή προσφέρει τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς πρόληψης 
καταστροφής για τους προμηθευτές δασκάλων, και παιδικής μέριμνας 
γονέων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">enseña a niños cómo prepararse para los 
desastres y cómo prevenir desastres. Los cabritos pueden 
también aprender sobre diversos tipos y causas de los desastres, 
historias del desastre de la parte, juegos del juego, leen historias, 
tienen acceso a los materiales de la investigación, y hacen un 
cabrito de la acción del desastre. El sitio ofrece los recursos
de la prevención del desastre para los padres, los profesores, y los 
abastecedores del cuidado de niño.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206751</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105479</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/fema-for-kids</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
