<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106138</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106138</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203837</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Mass Wasting/Landslide Animations</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Massenwasting/Erdrutsch Animationen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Animations de masse de Wasting/Landslide</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Animations Maciços De Wasting/Landslide</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Animazioni Totali Di Wasting/Landslide</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ζωτικότητες μαζικών σπατάλης/καθιζήσεων εδάφους</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Animaciones Totales De Wasting/Landslide</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site features Flash animations, MPEG simulations, and Real Media video clips that illustrate subsurface processes and consequences of mass wasting and landslide movement. Visualizations of slumps, flows, falls, and translational and rotational slides show bedrock failure and displacement and subsequent building damage and scarp, flowage zone, and toe formation. These resources portray a variety of modeled and real environments and are suitable for use in lectures, labs, or other teaching activities.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Situationsmerkmale blinken Animationen, 
MPEG Simulationen und videoclips der realen Media, die unter der 
Oberfläche liegende Prozesse und die Konsequenzen der Masse 
vergeudend und Erdrutschbewegung veranschaulichen. 
Sichtbarmachungen von Absacken, Flüsse, Fälle und 
translational und Rotationsdiavorführunggrundgesteinausfall und 
Distanzadresse und folgende Gebäude Beschädigung und Scarp, flowage 
Zone und Zeheanordnung. Diese Betriebsmittel schildern eine 
Vielzahl der geformten und realen Umgebungen und sind für Gebrauch in
den Vorträgen, in den Labors oder in anderen unterrichtenden 
Aktivitäten verwendbar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les dispositifs de ce site flashent des 
animations, des simulations de MPEG, et des clips visuels de vrais 
medias qui illustrent des processus à fleur de terre et des 
conséquences de la masse gaspillant et le mouvement d'éboulement. 
Visualisations des récessions, les écoulements, les chutes, et
la panne de roche en place de projection de diapositives et le 
déplacement de translation et de rotation et les dommages et 
l'escarpement ultérieur de bâtiment, la zone de flowage, et la 
formation d'orteil. Ces ressources dépeignent une variété 
d'environnements modelés et vrais et conviennent pour l'usage dans 
les conférences, les laboratoires, ou d'autres activités 
d'enseignement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As características deste local piscam animations,
simulações do MPEG, e os grampos video dos media reais que ilustram 
processos subsuperficiais e as conseqüências da massa que 
desperdiçam e o movimento do landslide. Visualizations dos 
slumps, os fluxos, as quedas, e falha do bedrock da mostra de 
corrediças e deslocamento translational e rotatório e os danos 
subseqüentes e scarp do edifício, zona do flowage, e formação do 
dedo do pé. Estes recursos portray uma variedade de ambientes 
modelados e reais e são apropriados para o uso nos lectures, nos 
laboratórios, ou em outras atividades ensinando.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Caratteristiche di questo luogo espongono a flash 
animazioni, simulazioni del MPEG e clip video di media reali che 
illustrano i processi sotto la superficie e le conseguenze di massa 
che sprecano ed il movimento di landslide. Visualizzazioni dei 
crolli, flussi, cadute e guasto della roccia fresca di proiezione di 
diapositive e spostamento translational e di rotazione e danni 
successivi e scarp della costruzione, zona di flowage e formazione 
della punta. Queste risorse ritraggono una varietà di ambienti 
modellistici e reali e sono adatte ad uso nelle conferenze, in 
laboratori, o in altre attività d'istruzione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει τις ζωτικότητες λάμψης, 
τις προσομοιώσεις MPEG, και τους πραγματικούς τηλεοπτικούς 
συνδετήρες MEDIA που επεξηγούν τις κάτω από την επιφάνεια 
διαδικασίες και τις συνέπειες της μαζικής σπατάλης και της 
μετακίνησης καθιζήσεων εδάφους. Οι απεικονίσεις των 
κατρακυλισμάτων, των ροών, των πτώσεων, και της μεταφραστικής και 
περιστροφικής αποτυχίας στρώματος βράχου επίδειξης φωτογραφικών 
διαφανειών και της μετατόπισης και της επόμενης οικοδόμησης 
βλάπτουν και scarp, ζώνη flowage, και σχηματισμός toe. 
Αυτά τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς απεικονίζουν ποικίλα 
διαμορφωμένα και πραγματικά περιβάλλοντα και είναι κατάλληλα για 
τη χρήση στις διαλέξεις, τα εργαστήρια, ή άλλες δραστηριότητες 
διδασκαλίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las características de este sitio contellean las 
animaciones, las simulaciones del MPEG, y los clips video de los media
verdaderos que ilustran procesos subsuperficies y las consecuencias de
la masa que pierden y el movimiento del derrumbamiento. 
Visualizaciones de depresiones, flujos, caídas, e incidente de 
la roca de fondo de la demostración de diapositivas y dislocación de
translación y rotatoria y daños subsecuente y escarpa del edificio, 
zona del flowage, y formación de la punta. Estos recursos 
retratan una variedad de ambientes modelados y verdaderos y son 
convenientes para el uso en conferencias, laboratorios, u otras 
actividades de enseñanza.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203837</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106138</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/mass-wasting-landslide-animations</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
