<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108030</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108030</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086895</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Bad News From Chicago": Labor Organizer Oscar Ameringer Describes the Effect of the Haymarket Bombing on the Knights of Labor</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Die Falschen Nachrichten Von Chicago": 
Gewerkschaftsorganisator Oscar Ameringer beschreibt den Effekt 
der Haymarket Bombardierung auf den Rittern der Arbeit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Les Mauvaises Nouvelles de Chicago" : 
l'Oscar Ameringer de propagandiste décrit l'effet du 
bombardement de Haymarket sur les chevaliers du travail</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"A Notícia Má De Chicago": O organizer 
labor Oscar Ameringer descreve o efeito do bombardeio de Haymarket nos
knights do trabalho</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Le Notizie Difettose Da Chicago": 
L'organizzatore di lavoro Oscar Ameringer descrive l'effetto 
del bombardamento di Haymarket sui cavalieri del Lavoro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Οι κακές ειδήσεις από το Σικάγο": Διοργανωτής 
Oscar Ameringer Describes εργασίας η επίδραση του 
βομβαρδισμού Haymarket στους ιππότες της εργασίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Las Malas Noticias De Chicago": El 
organizador de trabajo Oscar Ameringer describe el efecto del 
bombardeo de Haymarket en los caballeros del trabajo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Haymarket bombing in 1886 marked a major turning point in the history of nineteenth-century labor. Used by capitalists as an excuse for a crackdown on labor organizations, the bombing also splintered what up had been until then the strongest labor organization in the United States--the Knights of Labor. The anti-labor reaction that followed in the wake of the bombing helped precipitate a rapid decline in membership in the Knights which was eventually supplanted by the American Federation of Labor. In this excerpt from his autobiography, Oscar Ameringer, a Knight himself in 1886, recalled receiving the news about the Haymarket bombing while on strike in Cincinnati.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Haymarket Bombardierung in 1886 kennzeichnete 
einen Hauptdrehpunkt in der Geschichte der 19.-Jahrhundert Arbeit. 
Verwendet durch Kapitalisten als Entschuldigung für ein 
Durchgreifen auf Gewerkschaften, zersplitterte die Bombardierung auch,
was oben bis dann die stärkste Gewerkschaft in den vereinigten 
Zuständen -- die Ritter der Arbeit gewesen war. Anti-bearbeiten
Sie Reaktion, die unmittelbar nach dem Bombardierung geholfenen 
Niederschlag einer schnellen Abnahme in der Mitgliedschaft in den 
Rittern folgte, die schließlich durch die amerikanische Vereinigung 
der Arbeit verdrängt wurde. In diesem Excerpt von seiner 
Autobiographie, Oscar Ameringer, ein Ritter selbst 1886, die, 
Nachrichten über die Haymarket Bombardierung zu empfangen wieder 
aufgerufen während auf Schlag in Cincinnati.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le bombardement de Haymarket dans 1886 a marqué 
un tournant important dans l'histoire du travail de 
dix-neuvième-siècle. Utilisé par des capitalistes comme 
excuse pour un resserrement sur des organismes de travail, le 
bombardement a également brisé ce qui vers le haut avait été 
jusque-là l'organisation de travail la plus forte aux Etats-Unis -- 
les chevaliers du travail. Anti-travaillez la réaction qui a 
suivi à la suite du précipité aidé par bombardement un déclin 
rapide dans l'adhésion dans les chevaliers qui a été par la suite 
supplantée par la fédération américaine du travail. Dans cet
extrait de son autobiographie, Oscar Ameringer, un chevalier 
lui-même en 1886, rappelé recevoir les nouvelles au sujet du 
bombardement de Haymarket tandis qu'en grève à Cincinnati.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O bombardeio de Haymarket em 1886 marcou um ponto 
de giro principal no history do trabalho de décimo-século. 
Usado por capitalistas como uma desculpa para um crackdown em 
organizações labor, o bombardeio lascou-se também o que tinha 
estado acima até então a organização labor a mais forte nos 
estados unidos -- knights do trabalho. Anti-trabalhe a reação 
que seguiu na vigília do precipitate ajudado bombardeio um declínio 
rápido na sociedade nos knights que foi suplantada eventualmente pelo
federation americano do trabalho. Neste excerpt de seu 
autobiography, Oscar Ameringer, um knight ele mesmo em 1886, recordado
receber a notícia sobre o bombardeio de Haymarket quando na batida em
Cincinnati.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il bombardamento di Haymarket in 1886 ha 
contrassegnato una svolta importante nella storia del lavoro di 
diciannovesimo-secolo. Usato dai capitalisti come 
giustificazione per un provvedimento severo sulle organizzazioni 
di lavoro, il bombardamento egualmente si è scheggiato che cosa in 
su era stato fino a che allora l'organizzazione di lavoro più forte
in unito Non dichiarasse -- cavalieri del the del Lavoro. 
La reazione di anti-lavoro che ha seguito come conseguenza 
del precipitato aiutato bombardamento un declino veloce nell'insieme 
dei membri nei cavalieri che finalmente è stato soppiantato dalla 
federazione americana del Lavoro. In questo brano dal suo 
autobiography, Oscar Ameringer, un cavaliere egli stesso in 1886, 
ricordato ricevere le notizie circa il bombardamento di Haymarket 
mentre sul colpo a Cincinnati.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο βομβαρδισμός Haymarket το 1886 χαρακτήρισε μια 
σημαντική κρίσιμη καμπή στην ιστορία της εργασίας 
δέκατος-αιώνα. Χρησιμοποιημένος από τους κεφαλαιοκράτες ως 
δικαιολογία για μια καταστολή στις οργανώσεις εργασίας, ο 
βομβαρδισμός θρυμμάτισε επίσης ποια επάνω ήταν μέχρι τότε η 
ισχυρότερη οργάνωση εργασίας στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες -- ιππότης 
της εργασίας. Η αντίδραση αντι-εργασίας που ακολούθησε 
αμέσως μετά το βομβαρδισμό βοήθησε να κατακρημνίσει μια γρήγορη 
πτώση στην ιδιότητα μέλους στους ιππότες που αντικαταστάθηκε 
τελικά από την αμερικανική ομοσπονδία της εργασίας. Σε 
αυτό το απόσπασμα από την αυτοβιογραφία του, ο Oscar 
Ameringer, ένας ιππότης ο ίδιος το 1886, υπενθύμισε τη λήψη
των ειδήσεων για το Haymarket βομβαρδίζοντας ενώ στην απεργία 
στο Κινκινάτι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El bombardeo de Haymarket en 1886 marcó un 
momento crucial importante en la historia del trabajo del 
diecinueveavo-siglo. Utilizado por los capitalistas como excusa 
para una medida enérgica en organizaciones de trabajo, el bombardeo 
también astilló cuál para arriba había estado hasta entonces la 
organización de trabajo más fuerte de los Estados Unidos -- los 
caballeros del trabajo. Contra-trabaje la reacción que siguió 
en la estela del precipitado ayudado bombardeo una declinación 
rápida en la calidad de miembro en los caballeros que fue suplantada 
eventual por la federación americana del trabajo. En este 
extracto de su autobiografía, Oscar Ameringer, caballero mismo en 
1886, recordado el recibir de las noticias sobre el bombardeo de 
Haymarket mientras que en huelga en Cincinnati.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086895</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108030</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-bad-news-from-chicago-labor-organizer-oscar-ameringer-describes-the-effect-of-the-haymarket-bombing-on-the-knights-of-labor</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
