<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108431</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108431</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212505</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Center for Shark Research</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Mitte für Haifisch-Forschung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le centre pour la recherche de requin</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O centro para a pesquisa do tubarão</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il centro per ricerca dello squalo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το κέντρο για την έρευνα καρχαριών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El centro para la investigación del tiburón</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Mote Marine Laboratory's Center for Shark Research (CSR) is an international center for laboratory and field research, scientific collaboration, consulting, education, and public information on sharks and their relatives, the skates and rays. The CSR research mission includes basic and applied studies of all aspects of shark biology, from anatomy and physiology to ecology and fisheries science. This site includes an array of information about sharks, their general characteristics, distribution and diversity, the shark/cancer connection, shark tagging, attacks and myths. Users can also access information on upcoming shark biology courses. This site provides a thorough overview of sharks.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Mitte des Staubkorn-Marinelabors für 
Haifisch-Forschung (Bauzustands-Übersichtsbericht) ist eine 
internationale Mitte für Labor und fängt Forschung, 
wissenschaftliche Zusammenarbeit, Beraten, Ausbildung und allgemeine 
Informationen über Haifische und ihre Verwandten, die Rochen und 
Strahlen auf. Die Bauzustands-Übersichtsbericht Forschung 
Mission schließt die grundlegenden und angewandten Studien aller 
Aspekte der Haifischbiologie, von Anatomie und Physiologie zu 
Ökologie und Fischereiwissenschaft ein. Diese Site schließt 
eine Reihe Informationen über Haifische, ihre allgemeinen 
Eigenschaften, Verteilung ein und Verschiedenartigkeit, der 
shark/cancer Anschluß, der etikettierende Haifisch, die Angriffe und 
die Mythen Benutzer können auf Informationen über upcoming 
Haifischbiologiekurse auch zugreifen. Diese Site liefert einen 
vollständigen Überblick über Haifische.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le centre du laboratoire marin de grain pour la 
recherche de requin (CSR) est un centre international pour la 
recherche de laboratoire et de zone, la collaboration scientifique, la
consultation, l'éducation, et l'information publique sur des requins 
et leurs parents, les patins et des rayons. La mission de 
recherches de CSR inclut des études de base et appliquées de tous 
les aspects de biologie de requin, de l'anatomie et de la physiologie 
à l'écologie et à la science de pêche. Ce site inclut un 
choix d'informations sur des requins, leurs caractéristiques 
générales, distribution et la diversité, la connexion de 
shark/cancer, le requin étiquetant, les attaques et les utilisateurs 
de mythes peuvent également accéder à l'information sur des cours 
prochains de biologie de requin. Ce site fournit une vue 
d'ensemble complète des requins.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O centro do laboratório marinho do mote para a 
pesquisa do tubarão (CSR) é um centro internacional para a pesquisa 
do laboratório e de campo, a colaboração científica, consultar, a 
instrução, e a informação pública em tubarões e seus parentes, 
os patins e raios. A missão da pesquisa do CSR inclui estudos 
básicos e aplicados de todos os aspectos da biologia do tubarão, do 
anatomy e do physiology ao ecology e à ciência dos fisheries. 
Este local inclui uma disposição da informação sobre 
tubarões, suas características gerais, distribuição e a 
diversidade, a conexão de shark/cancer, o tubarão que etiquetam, os 
ataques e os usuários dos mitos podem também alcançar a 
informação em cursos upcoming da biologia do tubarão. Este 
local fornece uma vista geral completa dos tubarões.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il centro del laboratorio marino del mote per 
ricerca dello squalo (CSR) è un centro internazionale per il 
laboratorio ed indagine in loco, collaborazione scientifica, 
consultarsi, formazione e le informazioni pubbliche sugli squali ed i 
loro parenti, i pattini e raggi. La missione di ricerca del CSR 
include gli studi di base ed applicati su tutte le funzioni di 
biologia dello squalo, dall'anatomia e dalla fisiologia all'ecologia 
ed alla scienza delle industrie della pesca. Questo luogo 
include un allineamento delle informazioni sugli squali, le loro 
caratteristiche generali, distribuzione e la diversità, il 
collegamento di shark/cancer, lo squalo che etichettano, gli attacchi 
e gli utenti di miti possono anche accedere alle informazioni sui 
corsi imminenti di biologia dello squalo. Questo luogo fornisce 
una descrizione completa degli squali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το κέντρο του θαλάσσιου εργαστηρίου κόκων για την 
έρευνα καρχαριών (CSR) είναι διεθνές κέντρο για την έρευνα 
εργαστηρίων και πεδίων, την επιστημονική συνεργασία, τη 
διαβούλευση, την εκπαίδευση, και τις δημόσιες πληροφορίες για τους
καρχαρίες και τους συγγενείς τους, τα σαλάχια και τα σαλάχια. 
Η ερευνητική CSR αποστολή περιλαμβάνει τις βασικές και 
εφαρμοσμένες μελέτες όλων των πτυχών της βιολογίας καρχαριών, 
από την ανατομία και τη φυσιολογία στην οικολογία και την 
επιστήμη αλιείας. Αυτή η περιοχή περιλαμβάνει μια σειρά 
πληροφοριών για τους καρχαρίες, τα γενικά χαρακτηριστικά τους, 
διανομή και η ποικιλομορφία, η σύνδεση καρχαριών/καρκίνου, η 
επικόλληση καρχαριών, οι επιθέσεις και οι χρήστες μύθων μπορούν 
επίσης να έχουν πρόσβαση στις πληροφορίες για τις επερχόμενες 
σειρές μαθημάτων της βιολογίας καρχαριών. Αυτή η περιοχή 
παρέχει μια λεπτομερή επισκόπηση των καρχαριών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El centro del laboratorio marina del mote para la 
investigación del tiburón (CSR) es un centro internacional para la 
investigación del laboratorio y de campo, la colaboración 
científica, consultar, la educación, y la información pública 
sobre tiburones y sus parientes, los patines y los rayos. La 
misión de la investigación del CSR incluye estudios básicos y 
aplicados de todos los aspectos de la biología del tiburón, de la 
anatomía y de la fisiología a la ecología y a la ciencia de las 
industrias pesqueras. Este sitio incluye un arsenal de 
información sobre tiburones, sus características generales, 
distribución y la diversidad, la conexión de shark/cancer, el 
tiburón que marca con etiqueta, los ataques y los utilizadores de los
mitos pueden también tener acceso a la información sobre cursos 
próximos de la biología del tiburón. Este sitio proporciona a
una descripción completa de tiburones.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ROBERT HUETER
FN:ROBERT HUETER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212505</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108431</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-center-for-shark-research</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
