<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/24015</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>24015</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
    <entry>skolverket_7679</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:spindeln.iml.umu.se:skolverket_7679</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
            <entry>skolverket_7679</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">2.011 Introduction to Ocean Science and Engineering, Spring 2006 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">2.011 Einleitung in Ozean-Wissenschaft und 
eine Technik, Frühling 2006 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">2.011 Introduction à la Science d'océan et 
à l'ingénierie, le printemps 2006 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">2.011 Introdução à ciência do oceano e à
engenharia, mola 2006 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">2.011 Introduzione a scienza dell'oceano e ad
ingegneria, primavera 2006 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">2.011 Εισαγωγή στην ωκεάνιες επιστήμη και την 
εφαρμοσμένη μηχανική, άνοιξη του 2006 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">2.011 Introducción a la ciencia y a la 
ingeniería, resorte 2006 (MIT) del océano</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An online course from the MIT OpenCourseWare website (http://ocw.mit.edu) operated by Massachusetts Institute of Technology. This course material is free for anyone to use who accept the terms and conditions of use. The description of this course, published on the MIT OpenCourseWare website, is: "This course is an introduction to the fundamental aspects of science and engineering necessary for exploring, observing, and utilizing the oceans. Hands-on projects focus on instrumentation in the marine environment and the design of ocean observatories for ocean monitoring and exploration. Topics include acoustics, sound speed and refraction, sounds generated by ships and marine animals, sonar systems and their principles of operation, hydrostatic behavior of floating and submerged bodies geared towards ocean vehicle design, stability of ocean vessels, and the application of instrumentation and electronics in the marine environment. Students work with sensor systems and deploy them in the field to gather and analyze real world data."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">turbulence</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">marine</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">submarine</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">sonar</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">ocean acoustics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">marine animal</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">oceanography</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">wave velocity</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">physical oceanography</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">ship</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mechanical Engineering</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">undersea</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">vortex</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">submersible</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">boat</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">surface wave</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">ROV</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">marine science</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">geostrophic flow</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">ocean circulation</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">current</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">propagation phenomena</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Onlinekurs von der MIT OpenCourseWare Web site 
(http://ocw.mit.edu) funktionierte durch Massachusetts Institute of 
Technology. Dieses Kursmaterial ist frei, damit jedermann 
verwendet, wem die Bedingungen des Gebrauches annehmen. Die 
Beschreibung dieses Kurses, veröffentlicht auf der MIT OpenCourseWare
Web site, ist: "dieser Kurs ist eine Einleitung zu den 
grundlegenden Aspekten der Wissenschaft und der Technik, die für das 
Erforschen, das Beobachten und das Verwenden der Ozeane notwendig 
sind. Blindeinschub Projekte konzentrieren auf 
Instrumentenausrüstung in der Marineumgebung und das Design der 
Ozeansternwarten für die Ozeanüberwachung und -erforschung. 
Themen schließen Akustik, stichhaltige Geschwindigkeit und 
Brechung, die Töne, die durch Schiffe festgelegt werden und 
Marinetiere, Sonarsysteme und ihre Grundregeln der Operation ein, 
hydrostatisches Verhalten des Schwimmens und der versenkten Körper 
übersetzt in Richtung zum Ozeanträgerdesign, Stabilität der 
Ozeanbehälter und die Anwendung der Instrumentenausrüstung und der 
Elektronik in der Marineumgebung. Kursteilnehmer arbeiten mit 
Sensor-Systemen und entfalten sie in auffangene, um reale Weltdaten
zu erfassen und zu analysieren."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un cours en ligne du site Web de MIT OpenCourseWare
(http://ocw.mit.edu) a fonctionné par 
massachusetts.institute.of.technology. Ce matériel de cours est
libre pour que n'importe qui utilise qui reçoivent les modalités et 
les conditions de l'utilisation. La description de ce cours, 
éditée sur le site Web de MIT OpenCourseWare, est : "ce cours 
est une introduction aux aspects fondamentaux de la science et de 
l'ingénierie nécessaires pour explorer, observer, et utiliser les 
océans. Les projets à commande manuelle se concentrent sur 
l'instrumentation dans l'environnement marin et la conception des 
observatoires d'océan pour la surveillance et l'exploration d'océan.
Les sujets incluent des acoustiques, vitesse et réfraction 
saine, des bruits produits par bateaux et des animaux marins, des 
systèmes de sonar et leurs principes de fonctionnement, comportement 
hydrostatique de flotter et de corps submergés adaptés vers la 
conception de véhicule d'océan, stabilité des navires d'océan, et 
l'application de l'instrumentation et de l'électronique dans 
l'environnement marin. Les étudiants travaillent avec des 
systèmes de capteur et les déploient dans le domaine pour recueillir
et analyser de vraies données du monde."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um curso em linha do Web site do MIT OpenCourseWare
(http://ocw.mit.edu) operou-se por Instituto de Tecnología de 
Massachusetts. Este material do curso está livre para que 
qualquer um use-se quem aceitam os termos e as condições do uso. 
A descrição deste curso, publicada no Web site do MIT 
OpenCourseWare, é: "este curso é uma introdução aos aspectos
fundamentais da ciência e da engenharia necessárias para explorar, 
observar, e utilizar os oceanos. Os projetos hands-on focalizam 
na instrumentação no ambiente marinho e no projeto de obervatórios 
do oceano para a monitoração e a exploração do oceano. Os 
tópicos incluem acústicas, velocidade e refraction sadio, sons 
gerados por navios e animais marinhos, sistemas do sonar e seus 
princípios de operação, comportamento hydrostatic de flutuar e de 
corpos submersos engrenados para o projeto de veículo do oceano, 
estabilidade de embarcações do oceano, e a aplicação da 
instrumentação e da eletrônica no ambiente marinho. Os 
estudantes trabalham com sistemas do sensor e desdobram-nos no campo 
para recolher e analisar dados reais do mundo."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un corso in linea dal Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) ha funzionato da Massachusetts 
Institute of Technology. Questo materiale di corso è libero 
affinchè chiunque usi chi accettano i termini e le condizioni di uso.
La descrizione di questo corso, pubblicata sul Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare, è: "questo corso è un'introduzione alle 
funzioni fondamentali della scienza e dell'ingegneria necessarie per 
l'esplorazione, l'osservazione e l'utilizzazione degli oceani. I
progetti hands-on mettono a fuoco su strumentazione nell'ambiente 
marino e sul disegno degli osservatori dell'oceano per il controllo e 
l'esplorazione dell'oceano. I soggetti includono l'acustica, 
velocità e la rifrazione sana, suoni generati in navi ed animali 
marini, sistemi del sonar ed i loro principi di funzionamento, 
comportamento idrostatico di galleggiante e dei corpi sommersi 
innestati verso la caratteristica del veicolo dell'oceano, stabilità 
dei vasi dell'oceano e l'applicazione di strumentazione e di 
elettronica nell'ambiente marino. Gli allievi lavorano con i 
sistemi del sensore e li schierano nel campo per riunire ed 
analizzare i dati reali del mondo."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια σε απευθείας σύνδεση σειρά μαθημάτων από τον 
ιστοχώρο MIT OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) που 
χρησιμοποιείται από το ίδρυμα της Μασαχουσέτης τεχνολογίας. 
Αυτό το υλικό σειράς μαθημάτων είναι ελεύθερο για καθένα 
να χρησιμοποιήσει ποιοι αποδέχονται τους όρους και τους όρους 
χρησιμοποίησης. Η περιγραφή αυτής της σειράς μαθημάτων, που
δημοσιεύεται στον ιστοχώρο MIT OpenCourseWare, είναι: 
"Αυτή η σειρά μαθημάτων είναι μια εισαγωγή στις 
θεμελιώδεις πτυχές της επιστήμης και της εφαρμοσμένης μηχανικής 
απαραίτητων για την εξερεύνηση, την παρατήρηση, και τη 
χρησιμοποίηση των ωκεανών. Τα εμπράγματα προγράμματα 
εστιάζουν στην ενοργάνωση στο θαλάσσιο περιβάλλον και το σχέδιο 
των ωκεάνιων παρατηρητήριων για τον ωκεάνιους έλεγχο και την 
εξερεύνηση. Τα θέματα περιλαμβάνουν την ακουστική, την υγιή
ταχύτητα και τη διάθλαση, τους ήχους που παράγονται με τα σκάφη 
και τα θαλάσσια ζώα, sonar τα συστήματα και τις αρχές τους 
λειτουργίας, υδροστατικής συμπεριφοράς να επιπλεύσουν και των 
καταδυμένων οργανισμών που συνδέονται προς το ωκεάνιο σχέδιο 
οχημάτων, σταθερότητας των ωκεάνιων σκαφών, και της εφαρμογής της
ενοργάνωσης και της ηλεκτρονικής στο θαλάσσιο περιβάλλον. Οι
σπουδαστές εργάζονται με τα συστήματα αισθητήρων και τα 
επεκτείνουν στο πεδίο για να συγκεντρώσουν και να αναλύσουν τα 
πραγματικά παγκόσμια στοιχεία."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un curso en línea del Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) funcionó por Instituto de 
Tecnología de Massachusetts. Este material del curso está 
libre para que cualquier persona utilice quiénes validan los 
términos y las condiciones del uso. La descripción de este 
curso, publicada en el Web site del MIT OpenCourseWare, es: 
"este curso es una introducción a los aspectos fundamentales de
la ciencia y de la ingeniería necesarias para explorar, observar, y 
utilizar los océanos. Los proyectos con manos se centran en la 
instrumentación en el ambiente marina y el diseño de los 
observatorios del océano para vigilar y la exploración del océano. 
Los asuntos incluyen acústica, velocidad y refracción sana, 
los sonidos generados por las naves y los animales marinas, los 
sistemas del sonar y su teoría de operación, comportamiento 
hidrostático de la flotación y de cuerpos sumergidos engranados 
hacia diseño de vehículo del océano, estabilidad de los recipientes
del océano, y la aplicación de la instrumentación y de la 
electrónica en el ambiente marina. Los estudiantes trabajan con
los sistemas del sensor y los despliegan en el campo para recopilar y 
para analizar datos verdaderos del mundo."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Turbulenz</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Marine</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Unterseeboot</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sonar</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ozeanakustik</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Marinetier</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ozeanographie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Welle Geschwindigkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">physikalische Ozeanographie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Schiff</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Maschinenbauwesen</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">unterseeisch</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Turbulenz</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">versenkbar</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Boot</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Oberflächenwelle</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ROV</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Marinewissenschaft</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">geostrophic Fluß</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ozeanzirkulation</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">aktuell</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ausbreitungphänomene</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">turbulence</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">marin</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">sous-marin</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">sonar</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">acoustique d'océan</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">animal marin</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">océanographie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">vitesse de vague</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">océanographie physique</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">bateau</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Construction Mécanique</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">sous-marin</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">vortex</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">submersible</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">bateau</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">vague extérieure</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">ROV</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">la science marine</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">écoulement géostrophique</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">circulation d'océan</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">actuel</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">phénomènes de propagation</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">turbulence</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">marinho</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">submarino</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">sonar</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">acústica do oceano</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">animal marinho</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">oceanography</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">velocidade da onda</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">oceanography físico</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">navio</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Engenharia Mecânica</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">sob o mar</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">vortex</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">submergível</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">barco</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">onda de superfície</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">ROV</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">ciência marinha</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fluxo geostrophic</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">circulação do oceano</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">atual</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fenômenos da propagação</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">turbolenza</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">marino</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">sommergibile</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">sonar</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">acustica dell'oceano</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">animale marino</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">oceanografia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">velocità dell'onda</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">oceanografia fisica</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">nave</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ingegneria Meccanica</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">undersea</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">vortice</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">sommergibile</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">barca</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">onda di superficie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">ROV</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">scienza marina</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">flusso geostrophic</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">circolazione dell'oceano</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">corrente</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fenomeni di propagazione</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">αναταραχή</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ναυτικό</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">υποβρύχιο</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">sonar</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ωκεάνια ακουστική</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">θαλάσσιο ζώο</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ωκεανογραφία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ταχύτητα κυμάτων</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">φυσική ωκεανογραφία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">σκάφος</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μηχανική εφαρμοσμένη μηχανική</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">υποθαλάσσιος</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">δίνη</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">υποβρύχιος</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">βάρκα</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">κύμα επιφάνειας</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ROV</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ναυτιλιακές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">geostrophic ροή</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ωκεάνια κυκλοφορία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρών</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">φαινόμενα διάδοσης</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">turbulencia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">marina</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">submarino</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">sonar</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">acústica del océano</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">animal marina</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">oceanografía</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">velocidad de la onda</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">oceanografía física</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">nave</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ingeniería Industrial</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">bajo la superficie del mar</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">vórtice</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">sumergible</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">barco</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">onda superficial</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ROV</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ciencia marina</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">flujo geostrophic</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">circulación del océano</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">actual</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">fenómenos de la propagación</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Taawo;Alma
FN:Alma Taawo
ORG:skolverket
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>course</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>higher education</value>
          </context>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">18-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>795</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">mechanical engineering</string>
                <string language="sv">maskinteknik</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:spindeln.iml.umu.se:skolverket_7679-M</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
            <entry>skolverket_7679-M</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Taawo;Alma
FN:Alma Taawo
ORG:skolverket
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2009-03-15T19:54:33.0Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
N:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
ORG:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T05:58:38.56Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
      <entry>skolverket_7679</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://ocw.mit.edu/OcwWeb/Mechanical-Engineering/2-011Spring-2006/CourseHome/index.htm</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
