<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103547</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103547</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204598</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Does it float? Exploring density</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Schwimmt sie? Erforschende Dichte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Flotte-t-elle ? Densité l'explorant</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Flutua? Densidade explorando</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Galleggia? Densità d'esplorazione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιπλέει; Να ερευνήσει την πυκνότητα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿Flota? Densidad que explora</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Density is a property of matter that requires abstract understanding from your students. This lesson plan is a hands-on lab for exploring the concepts of mass, volume, density, and their relationship. This lab achieves several 8th grade science objectives and incorporates mathematical objectives as well. The lab can easily be used as an introductory lab for the year, thus covering not only the content objectives, but also procedures for completing labs throughout the course of the year.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dichte ist eine Eigenschaft des Stoffes, der 
abstraktes Verständnis von Ihren Kursteilnehmern benötigt. 
Dieser Lektionplan ist ein Blindeinschub Labor für das 
Erforschen der Konzepte der Masse, des Datenträgers, der Dichte und 
ihres Verhältnisses. Dieses Labor erzielt einige 8. 
Gradwissenschaft Lernziele und enthält mathematische Lernziele 
außerdem. Das Labor kann als einleitendes Labor für das Jahr, 
so die Bedeckung nicht nur die zufriedenen Lernziele, aber auch 
Prozeduren für das Durchführen der Labors während des Kurses des 
Jahres leicht benutzt werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La densité est une propriété de la matière qui
exige l'arrangement abstrait de vos étudiants. Ce plan de 
leçon est un laboratoire à commande manuelle pour explorer les 
concepts de la masse, du volume, de la densité, et de leur rapport. 
Ce laboratoire atteint plusieurs 8èmes objectifs de la science 
de catégorie et incorpore des objectifs mathématiques aussi bien. 
Le laboratoire peut facilement être utilisé comme laboratoire 
préliminaire pour l'année, ainsi la bâche non seulement les 
objectifs contents, mais également des procédures pour terminer des 
laboratoires au cours de l'année.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A densidade é uma propriedade da matéria que 
requer a compreensão abstrata de seus estudantes. Esta planta 
da lição é um laboratório hands-on para explorar os conceitos da 
massa, do volume, da densidade, e do seu relacionamento. Este 
laboratório consegue diversos 8os objetivos da ciência da classe e 
incorpora objetivos matemáticos também. O laboratório pode 
fàcilmente ser usado como um laboratório introdutório para o ano, 
assim o covering não somente os objetivos satisfeitos, mas também 
procedimentos terminando laboratórios durante todo o curso do ano.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La densità è una proprietà della materia che 
richiede la comprensione astratta dai vostri allievi. Questo 
programma di lezione è un laboratorio hands-on per l'esplorazione dei
concetti di massa, di volume, di densità e del loro rapporto. 
Questo laboratorio realizza parecchi ottavi obiettivi di scienza
del grado e comprende gli obiettivi matematici pure. Il 
laboratorio può essere usato facilmente come laboratorio introduttivo
per l'anno, così il covering non soltanto gli obiettivi soddisfatti, 
ma anche procedure per completare i laboratori attraverso il corso 
dell'anno.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η πυκνότητα είναι μια ιδιοκτησία του θέματος που 
απαιτεί την περίληψη που καταλαβαίνει από τους σπουδαστές σας. 
Αυτό το σχέδιο μαθήματος είναι ένα εμπράγματο εργαστήριο 
για να ερευνήσει τις έννοιες της μάζας, της έντασης του ήχου, της
πυκνότητας, και της σχέσης τους. Αυτό το εργαστήριο 
επιτυγχάνει διάφορους 8ους στόχους επιστήμης βαθμού και 
ενσωματώνει τους μαθηματικούς στόχους επίσης. Το εργαστήριο
μπορεί εύκολα να χρησιμοποιηθεί ως εισαγωγικό εργαστήριο για το 
έτος, καλύπτοντας κατά συνέπεια όχι μόνο τους ικανοποιημένους 
στόχους, αλλά και τις διαδικασίες για τα εργαστήρια καθ' όλη τη 
διάρκεια του έτους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La densidad es una característica de la materia 
que requiere la comprensión abstracta de sus estudiantes. Este 
plan de la lección es un laboratorio con manos para explorar los 
conceptos de la masa, del volumen, de la densidad, y de su lazo. 
Este laboratorio alcanza varios 8vos objetivos de la ciencia del
grado e incorpora objetivos matemáticos también. El 
laboratorio se puede utilizar fácilmente como laboratorio 
introductorio para el año, así la cubierta no solamente los 
objetivos contentos, pero también los procedimientos para terminar 
laboratorios a través del curso del año.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:TRISH LOUDERMILT
FN:TRISH LOUDERMILT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204598</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103547</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/does-it-float-exploring-density</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
