<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107076</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107076</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213250</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Yosemite in Depth: Geologic Timeline</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Yosemite eingehend: Geologisches Timeline</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Yosemite détaillé : Chronologie 
géologique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Yosemite na profundidade: Timeline Geologic</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Yosemite approfondito: Timeline Geologico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Yosemite σε βάθος: Γεωλογική υπόδειξη ως προς
το χρόνο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Yosemite en profundidad: Timeline 
Geológico</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This interactive geologic timeline is part of the site for Yosemite National park. Users can scroll across the geologic timeline and find out what was happening on Earth at that time. The site also includes a nicely illustrated geologic overview of the park, a virtual hike, quizzes, and a glossary and reference page.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses interaktive geologische timeline ist ein 
Teil der Sites für Yosemite Nationalpark. Benutzer können 
scroll über dem geologischen timeline und herausfinden, was auf Masse
zu dieser Zeit geschah. Die Site schließt auch einen freundlich
erläuterten geologischen Überblick über den Park, eine virtuelle 
Wanderung, Quizen und ein Glossar und eine Bezugsseite ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette chronologie géologique interactive fait 
partie du site pour le parc national de Yosemite. Les 
utilisateurs peuvent faire défiler à travers la chronologie 
géologique et découvrir ce qui se produisait sur terre à ce 
moment-là. Le site inclut également une vue d'ensemble 
géologique bien illustrée du parc, d'une hausse virtuelle, des jeux,
et d'un glossaire et d'une page de référence.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este timeline geologic interativo é parte do 
local para o parque nacional de Yosemite. Os usuários podem 
enrolar-se através do timeline geologic e encontrar para fora o que 
estava acontecendo na terra nesse tempo. O local inclui também 
uma vista geral geologic agradàvel ilustrada do parque, de um hike 
virtual, de quizzes, e de um glossário e de uma página da 
referência.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo timeline geologico interattivo fa parte del
luogo per il parco nazionale di Yosemite. Gli utenti possono 
fare scorrere attraverso il timeline geologico e scoprire che cosa 
stava accadendo su terra a quel tempo. Il luogo egualmente 
include una descrizione geologica piacevolmente illustrata del parco, 
di un aumento virtuale, dei quiz e di un glossario e di una pagina di 
riferimento.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η διαλογική γεωλογική υπόδειξη ως προς το χρόνο 
είναι μέρος της περιοχής για το εθνικό πάρκο Yosemite. 
Οι χρήστες μπορούν να τυλίξουν πέρα από τη γεωλογική 
υπόδειξη ως προς το χρόνο και να ανακαλύψουν τι συνέβαινε στη γη 
εκείνη την περίοδο. Η περιοχή περιλαμβάνει επίσης μια 
ωραία διευκρινισμένη γεωλογική επισκόπηση του πάρκου, ενός 
εικονικού πεζοπορώ, των διαγωνισμοων γνώσεων, και ενός γλωσσαριού
και μιας σελίδας αναφοράς.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este timeline geológico interactivo es parte del 
sitio para el parque nacional de Yosemite. Los utilizadores 
pueden enrollar a través del timeline geológico y descubrir qué 
sucedía en la tierra en aquella 'epoca. El sitio también 
incluye una descripción geológica agradable ilustrada del parque, de
un alza virtual, de concursos, y de un glosario y de una paginación 
de la referencia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213250</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107076</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/yosemite-in-depth-geologic-timeline</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
