<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104299</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104299</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086113</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Eight Hours a Day and Better Conditions": Andrew Pido Explains His Support for the 1919 Steel Strike</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"acht Stunden pro Tag und bessere Bedingungen": 
Andrew Pido erklärt seinen Support für den Stahlschlag 1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"huit heures par jour et meilleures conditions" : 
Andrew Pido explique son soutien de la grève 1919 en acier</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"oito horas um dia e umas circunstâncias 
melhores": Andrew Pido explica sua sustentação para a batida 
1919 de aço</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"otto ore al giorno e circostanze migliori": 
Andrew Pido spiega il suo sostegno il colpo d'acciaio 1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Οκτώ ώρες ημερησίως και καλύτεροι όροι": 
Θ*Ανδρεω Pido Explains His Support για την απεργία 
χάλυβα του 1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"ocho horas un día y condiciones mejores": 
Andrew Pido explica su ayuda para la huelga de acero 1919</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the dramatic 1919 steel strike, 350,000 workers walked off their jobs and crippled the industry. The U.S. Senate Committee on Education and Labor set out to investigate the strike while it was still in progress. In his testimony before the committee, Slavic steelworker Andrew Pido described the discrimination faced by some immigrant workers and how that discrimination - along with long pay and poor conditions--encouraged them to unionize and strike.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im drastischen 1919 Stahlschlag gingen 350.000 
Arbeiter weg von ihren Jobs und verkrüppelten die Industrie. 
Der VEREINIGTE STAATEN Senat-Ausschuß für Ausbildung und 
Arbeit legte dar, um den Schlag nachzuforschen, während er noch in 
Bewegung war. In seinem Zeugnis vor dem Ausschuß, beschrieb 
Slavic Steelworker Andrew Pido die Unterscheidung, die von einigen 
einwandernden Arbeitern gegenübergestellt wurde und wie diese 
Unterscheidung - zusammen mit langer Bezahlung und schlechten 
Bedingungen -- angeregt ihnen unionize und anschlagen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans les 1919 grèves en acier excessive, 350.000 
ouvriers ont marché outre de leurs travaux et ont estropié 
l'industrie. Le comité de sénat des ETATS-UNIS de l'éducation
et du travail s'est mis à étudier la grève tandis qu'elle était 
encore en marche. Dans son témoignage devant le comité, le 
travailleur dans l'industrie sidérurgique slave Andrew Pido a 
décrit la discrimination faite face par quelques ouvriers immigrés 
et comment cette discrimination - avec le long salaire et les 
conditions faibles -- encouragée leur syndiquer et frapper.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nas 1919 batidas de aço dramática, 350.000 
trabalhadores andaram fora de seus trabalhos e aleijaram a indústria.
O comitê do senate de ESTADOS UNIDOS na instrução e no 
trabalho ajustou-se para fora para investigar a batida quando era 
ainda em andamento. Em seu testimony antes do comitê, o 
steelworker Andrew Pido de Slavic descreveu a discriminação 
enfrentada por alguns trabalhadores immigrant e como essa 
discriminação - junto com o pagamento longo e circunstâncias 
deficientes -- incentivada lhes unionize e golpeia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nei 1919 colpi d'acciaio drammatico, 350.000 
operai hanno camminato fuori dei loro lavori ed hanno paralizzato 
l'industria. Il comitato del senato degli STATI UNITI di 
formazione e del Lavoro ha precisato per studiare il colpo mentre
era ancora in progresso. Nella sua testimonianza prima del 
comitato, l'addetto alla lavorazione dell'acciaio Andrew Pido di 
Slavic ha descritto la distinzione affrontata da alcuni operai 
immigrati e come quella distinzione - con paga lunga e le povere 
circostanze -- consigliata a loro unionize e colpisce.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στη δραματική απεργία χάλυβα του 1919, 350.000 
εργαζόμενοι περπάτησαν από τις εργασίες τους και ακρωτηρίασαν τη 
βιομηχανία. Η Επιτροπή ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ Συγκλήτου της 
εκπαίδευσης και η εργασία καθόρισαν να ερευνήσουν την απεργία 
ενώ ήταν ακόμα υπό εξέλιξη. Στην κατάθεσή του ενώπιον 
της επιτροπής, ο σλαβικός σιδηρουργός Andrew Pido περιέγραψε
τη διάκριση που αντιμετωπίστηκε από μερικούς που έχουν 
μεταναστεύσει εργαζομένους και πώς εκείνη η διάκριση - μαζί με 
τη μακροχρόνια αμοιβή και τις κακές συνθήκες -- τους ενθάρρυνε 
για να οργανώσει σε συνδικάτο και να χτυπήσει.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En las 1919 huelgas de acero dramática, 350.000 
trabajadores recorrieron de sus trabajos y lisiaron la industria. 
El comité del senado de ESTADOS UNIDOS sobre la educación y el
trabajo precisó para investigar la huelga mientras que todavía 
estaba en marcha. En su testimonio ante el comité, el 
trabajador siderúrgico Andrew Pido de Slavic describió la 
discriminación hecha frente por algunos trabajadores inmigrantes y 
cómo esa discriminación - junto con paga larga y condiciones pobres 
-- alentador les unionize y pulso.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086113</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104299</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/eight-hours-a-day-and-better-conditions-andrew-pido-explains-his-support-for-the-1919-steel-strike</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
