<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103268</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103268</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207250</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">War and Peace</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Krieg und Frieden</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Guerre et paix</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Guerra e paz</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Guerra e pace</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πόλεμος και ειρήνη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Guerra y paz</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">presents photos, maps, and documents related to America's wars. Features include a Civil War timeline, letters from soldiers, homefront contributions during World War I and II, American women workers during World War II, man-on-the-street interviews after Pearl Harbor, The Stars and Stripes newspaper (for Army troops in France 1918-19), Winston Churchill, the Marshall Plan, Ansel Adam's book on a World War II internment camp, and the Veterans History Project.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt Fotos, Karten und die Dokumente, die auf 
Kriegen Amerikas in Verbindung gestanden werden dar. Merkmale 
enthalten ein Bürgerkrieg timeline, Zeichen von den Soldaten, 
homefront Beiträge während des Ersten Weltkrieges und II, 
amerikanische Frauarbeiter während des Zweiten Weltkrieges, 
Mann-auf-d-Straße Interviews nach Pearl Harbor, die Sternenbanner- 
Zeitung (für Armee troops in Frankreich 1918-19), Winston Churchill, 
das Marschall-Plan-, Anseladam Buch auf einem 
Weltkrieginternierunglager und das Veteran-Geschichte Projekt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">présente des photos, des cartes, et des documents 
liés aux guerres de l'Amérique. Les dispositifs incluent une 
chronologie de guerre civile, des lettres des soldats, des 
contributions de homefront pendant la Première Guerre Mondiale et II,
les ouvrières américaines de femmes pendant la deuxième guerre 
mondiale, entrevues de homme-sur-le-rue après le port de perle, 
Tient le premier rôle et barre le journal (pour l'armée s'assemble en 
France 1918-19), le Winston Churchill, le livre de plan de maréchal, 
d'Ansel Adam sur un camp d'internement de la deuxième guerre 
mondiale, et le projet d'histoire de vétérans.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">apresenta fotos, mapas, e originais relacionados 
às guerras de América. As características incluem um timeline
da guerra civil, letras dos soldados, contribuições do homefront 
durante o world.war.i e o II, trabalhadores americanos das mulheres 
durante a segunda guerra mundial, entrevistas da homem-em-$$$-RUA 
após o porto de pérola, o jornal das estrelas e dos listras (para o 
exército se agrupa em France 1918-19), Winston Churchill, o livro da 
planta do marshall, do Ansel Adam em um acampamento do internamento da
segunda guerra mundial, e o projeto do history dos veterans.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">presenta le foto, i programmi ed i documenti 
relativi alle guerre dell'America. Le caratteristiche includono 
un timeline di guerra civile, lettere dai soldati, contributi del 
homefront durante il world.war.i ed II, operai americani delle donne 
durante la seconda guerra mondiale, interviste della uomo-su-$$$-VIA 
dopo il porto di perla, il giornale delle bande e delle stelle (per 
l'esercito si aduna in Francia 1918-19), Winston Churchill, il libro 
di programma del marshall, di Ansel Adam su un accampamento di 
internamento della seconda guerra mondiale ed il progetto di storia 
dei veterani.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρουσιάζει τις φωτογραφίες, τους χάρτες, και τα 
έγγραφα σχετικά με τους πολέμους της Αμερικής. Τα 
χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα περιλαμβάνουν μια υπόδειξη ως προς το 
χρόνο εμφύλιου πολέμου, τις επιστολές από τους στρατιώτες, 
homefront τις συνεισφορές κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου 
πολέμου Ι και ΙΙ, τους αμερικανικούς εργαζομένους γυναικών κατά 
τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ, τις συνεντεύξεις 
άτομο-$$$-Ο-ΟΔΏΝ μετά από το λιμάνι μαργαριταριών, τα αστέρια 
και την εφημερίδα λωρίδων (για τα στρατεύματα στρατού στη Γαλλία 
1918-19), το Winston Churchill, το Marshall σχέδιο, το 
βιβλίο Ansel Adam σε έναν παγκόσμιο πόλεμο ΙΙ στρατόπεδο 
περιορισμού, και το πρόγραμμα ιστορίας παλαιμάχων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">presenta las fotos, las correspondencias, y los 
documentos relacionados con las guerras de América. Las 
características incluyen un timeline de la guerra civil, las cartas 
de soldados, las contribuciones del homefront durante Primera Guerra 
Mundial e II, los trabajadores americanos de las mujeres durante la 
Segunda Guerra Mundial, las entrevistas de la hombre-en-$$$-CALLE 
después del puerto de perla, el periódico de las estrellas y de las 
rayas (para el ejército marcha en Francia 1918-19), Winston 
Churchill, el libro del plan del ordenar, de Ansel Adán en un campo 
de la internación de la Segunda Guerra Mundial, y el proyecto de la 
historia de los veteranos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207250</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103268</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/war-and-peace</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
