<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103105</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103105</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086065</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Declaration of the Rights of the Negro Peoples of the World": The Principles of the Universal Negro Improvement Association</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Erklärung der Rechte der Schwarze-Völker von 
der Welt": Die Grundregeln der Universalschwarze-Verbesserung 
Verbindung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"déclaration des droites des peuples de nègre du
monde" : Les principes de l'association universelle 
d'amélioration de nègre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"declaração das direitas dos povos do negro do 
mundo": Os princípios da associação universal da melhoria do 
negro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"dichiarazione dei diritti della gente del negro 
del mondo": I principii dell'associazione universale di 
miglioramento del negro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Διακήρυξη των δικαιωμάτων των λαών νέγρων του 
κόσμου": Οι αρχές της καθολικής ένωσης βελτίωσης νέγρων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"declaración de las derechas de la gente del 
negro del mundo": Los principios de la asociación universal de 
la mejora del negro</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">After fighting World War I, ostensibly to defend democracy and the right of self-determination, thousands of African-American soldiers returned home to face intensified discrimination, segregation, and racial violence. Drawing on this frustration, Marcus Garvey attracted thousands of disillusioned black working-class and lower middle-class followers to his Universal Negro Improvement Association (UNIA). The UNIA, committed to notions of racial purity and separatism, insisted that salvation for African Americans meant building an autonomous, black-led nation in Africa. The Black Star Line, an all-black shipping company chartered by the UNIA, was the movement's boldest and most important project, and many African Americans bought shares of stock in the company. A 1920 Black Star Line business meeting in Harlem's Liberty Hall brought together 25,000 UNIA delegates from around the world, and produced an important statement of principles, the "Declaration of Rights of the Negro Peoples of the World."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nachdem sie den Ersten Weltkrieg, um gekämpft 
hatten Demokratie und das Recht von Self-determination anscheinend zu 
verteidigen, kamen Tausenden der Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Soldaten 
nach Hause zu Gesicht verstärkter Unterscheidung, zur Abtrennung und 
zur rassischen Gewalttätigkeit zurück. Zeichnend auf diese 
Frustration, zog Marcus Garvey Tausenden der ernüchterten schwarzen 
Arbeiterklasse und der untereren Mittelklassenachfolger zu seiner 
Universalschwarze-Verbesserung Verbindung an (UNIA). Das UNIA, 
festgelegt an den Begriffen der rassischen Reinheit und des 
Separatismus, beharrte, daß Rettung für afrikanische Amerikaner 
das Aufbauen einer autonomen bedeutete, schwarz-führenden Nation in 
Afrika. Die schwarze Stern-Zeile, eine all-schwarze 
Verschiffenfirma, die durch das UNIA gechartert wurde, war das 
fetteste und wichtigste Projekt der Bewegung, und viele afrikanische 
Amerikaner kauften Kapitalanteile in der Firma. Eine schwarze 
Zeile Geschäftstreffen des Stern-1920 in der Freiheit Hall Harlems 
brachte 25.000 UNIA Delegierte um von der Welt zusammen und 
produzierte eine wichtige Anweisung über Grundregeln, die "Erklärung
der Rechte der Schwarze-Völker von der Welt."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Après le combat de la Première Guerre Mondiale, 
pour défendre en apparence la démocratie et la droite de 
art de l'auto-portrait-determination, les milliers de soldats afro-américains sont 
revenus à la maison à la discrimination intensifiée par visage, à 
la ségrégation, et à la violence raciale. Dessinant sur cet 
anéantissement, Marcus Garvey a attiré des milliers de classe 
ouvrière noire désillusionnée et de sectateurs inférieurs de 
classe moyenne à son association universelle d'amélioration de 
nègre (UNIA). L'UNIA, commis aux notions de la pureté et du 
séparatisme raciaux, a insisté sur le fait que le salut pour les 
Américains africains a signifié établir une nation autonome et 
noir-menée en Afrique. Le noir Tiennent le premier rôle la ligne, une 
compagnie maritime tout-noire privilégiée par l'UNIA, étaient le 
projet le plus gras et le plus important du mouvement, et beaucoup 
d'Américains africains ont acheté des parts des actions à la 
compagnie. Des 1920 que le noir Tiennent le premier rôle la ligne 
réunion d'affaires dans la liberté Hall de Harlem ont 
rassemblé 25.000 délégués d'UNIA de partout dans le monde, et ont 
produit un rapport important des principes, la "déclaration des 
droites des peuples de nègre du monde."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Após ter lutado o world.war.i, para defender 
ostensibly a democracia e a direita do self-determination, os milhares
de soldados Africano-Americanos retornaram para casa à 
discriminação intensified cara, ao segregation, e à violência 
racial. Desenhando nesta frustração, Marcus Garvey atraiu 
milhares do working-class preto disillusioned e de uns seguidores mais
baixos do middle-class a sua associação universal da melhoria do 
negro (UNIA). O UNIA, cometido às noções do purity e do 
separatism raciais, insistiu que o salvation para americanos africanos
significou construir uma nação autônoma, preto-conduzida em 
África. A linha preta da estrela, uma companhia de transporte 
todo-preta fretada pelo UNIA, era o projeto o mais bold(realce) e o 
mais importante do movimento, e muitos americanos africanos compraram 
partes de estoque na companhia. Uma linha preta reunião da 
estrela 1920 de negócio na liberdade Salão de Harlem trouxe junto 
25.000 delegados de UNIA em torno do mundo, e produziu uma indicação
importante dos princípios, a "declaração das direitas dos povos do 
negro do mundo."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dopo il world.war.i di combattimento, difendere 
apparentemente la democrazia e la destra di self-determination, i 
migliaia dei soldati Africano-Americani hanno ritornato a casa a 
distinzione intensificata faccia, alla segregazione ed alla violenza 
razziale. Dissipando su questa frustrazione, Marcus Garvey ha 
attratto i migliaia della classe operaia nera disillusa e dei 
seguicamme più bassi della classe media alla sua associazione 
universale di miglioramento del negro (UNIA). Il UNIA, impegnato
nelle nozioni della purezza e del separatism razziali, ha insistito 
che la salvezza per gli Americani africani ha significato lo 
sviluppo della nazione autonoma e nero-condotta in Africa. La 
riga nera della stella, un'azienda di trasporto tutto-nera istituita 
dal UNIA, era il progetto più GRASSETTO e più importante del 
movimento e molti Americani africani hanno comprato le parti delle 
azione nell'azienda. Una riga nera riunione della stella 1920 di
affari nella libertà Corridoio del Harlem ha riunito 25.000 delegati 
di UNIA intorno al mondo ed ha redatto un'istruzione importante dei 
principii, "la dichiarazione dei diritti della gente del negro del 
mondo."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μετά από να διεξαγάγουν τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι, για 
να υπερασπίσουν φαινομενικά τη δημοκρατία και το δικαίωμα της 
αυτοδιάθεσης, χιλιάδες αφρικανικός-αμερικανικοί στρατιώτες 
επέστρεψαν το σπίτι ενταμένη στην πρόσωπο διάκριση, το 
διαχωρισμό, και τη φυλετική βία. Επισύροντας την προσοχή σε
αυτήν την απογοήτευση, ο Marcus Garvey προσέλκυσε χιλιάδες 
απογοητευμένη μαύρη εργατική τάξη και χαμηλότεροι οπαδοί 
μεσαίων τάξεων στην καθολική ένωση βελτίωσης νέγρων του 
(UNIA). Το UNIA, δεσμευμένο στις έννοιες της φυλετικών 
αγνότητας και του αυτονομισμού, επέμεινε ότι η σωτηρία για 
αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς σήμανε ένα αυτόνομο, μαύρος-οδηγημένο 
έθνος στην Αφρική. Η μαύρη γραμμή αστεριών, μια 
όλος-μαύρη ναυτιλιακή εταιρία που ναυλώθηκε από το UNIA, 
ήταν το pjo' ψολδεστ και σημαντικότερο πρόγραμμα της 
μετακίνησης, και πολλοί αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί αγόρασαν τις 
μετοχές του αποθέματος στην επιχείρηση. Μια επιχειρησιακή 
συνεδρίαση γραμμών αστεριών του 1920 μαύρη στην αίθουσα 
ελευθερίας Harlem συγκέντρωσε 25.000 εκπροσώπους UNIA από
σε όλο τον κόσμο, και παρήγαγε μια σημαντική δήλωση των αρχών, η
"Διακήρυξη των δικαιωμάτων των λαών νέγρων του κόσμου."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Después de luchar Primera Guerra Mundial, 
aparentemente para defender democracia y la derecha de la 
autodeterminación, los millares de soldados Africano-Americanos 
volvieron a casa a la discriminación intensificada cara, a la 
segregación, y a la violencia racial. Trazando en esta 
frustración, Marcus Garvey atrajo a millares de clase obrera negra 
desilusionada y de seguidores más bajos de la clase media a su 
asociación universal de la mejora del negro (UNIA). El UNIA, 
confiado a las nociones de la pureza y del separatism raciales, 
insistió que la salvación para los americanos africanos significó 
la construcción de una nación autónoma, negro-conducida en África.
La línea negra de la estrella, una compañía de envío 
todo-negra cargada por el UNIA, era el proyecto más en negrilla y 
más importante del movimiento, y muchos americanos africanos 
compraron partes de la acción en la compañía. Una línea 
negra reunión de la estrella 1920 de negocio en la libertad Pasillo 
de Harlem reunió a 25.000 delegados de UNIA alrededor del mundo, y 
produjo una declaración importante de principios, el "declaración de
las derechas de la gente del negro del mundo."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086065</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103105</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/declaration-of-the-rights-of-the-negro-peoples-of-the-world-the-principles-of-the-universal-negro-improvement-association</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
