<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106250</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106250</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202819</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Foreshadowing: Quote Identification, Discovery Lesson, and Essay Prompt Analysis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Vorher andeuten: 
Anführungsstrich-Kennzeichen, Entdeckung-Lektion und 
Versuch-sofortige Analyse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Annonce : Identification de guillemet, 
leçon de découverte, et analyse prompte d'essai</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Foreshadowing: Identificação das 
citações, lição da descoberta, e análise alerta do essay</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Foreshadowing: Identificazione di 
virgoletta, lezione di scoperta ed analisi rapida di saggio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Προαναγγελία: Προσδιορισμός αποσπάσματος, μάθημα
ανακαλύψεων, και γρήγορη ανάλυση δοκίμιου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Presagio: Identificación de la cotización,
lección del descubrimiento, y análisis pronto del ensayo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Students identify selected quotes from literary works studied in class. After a brief discussion of what all of the quotes have in common, students will determine that each quote foreshadows an important, upcoming plot development. The class will then examine an essay prompt on foreshadowing, vote on the literary work to be used in planning a response to the prompt, and, as a teacher-led, whole-class activity, come up with a thesis and main point outline for the essay.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kursteilnehmer kennzeichnen ausgewählte 
Anführungsstriche von den literarischen Arbeiten, die in der 
Kategorie studiert werden. Nachdem eine kurze Diskussion über 
was alle Anführungsstriche im Common haben, Kursteilnehmer 
feststellt, daß jeder Anführungsstrich eine wichtige, upcoming 
Plotentwicklung vorher andeutet. Die Kategorie worden 
überprüft dann einen Versuchhinweis auf dem Vorher andeuten, Stimme 
auf der literarischen wenn sie verwendet zu werden Arbeit,, eine 
Antwort zum Hinweis plant, und, wie Lehrer-geführt, 
Vollständigkategorie Aktivität, oben mit einer umreiß der These und
der Hauptsache für den Versuch kommen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les étudiants identifient des guillemet choisis 
des travaux littéraires étudiés dans la classe. Après qu'une
brève discussion de ce que tous les guillemet ont en commun, des 
étudiants détermine que chaque guillemet annoncent un développement
important et prochain de traçage. La classe examinera alors une
demande d'essai sur annoncer, vote sur le travail littéraire à 
utiliser en projetant une réponse à la demande, et, comme 
professeur-mené, activité d'entier-classe, fournissent un contour de
thèse et de point principal pour l'essai.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os estudantes identificam citações selecionadas 
dos trabalhos literários estudados na classe. Depois que uma 
discussão breve de o que todas as citações tenham na terra comum, 
estudantes determinará que cada citações foreshadows um 
desenvolvimento importante, upcoming do lote. A classe 
examinará então um alerta do essay em foreshadowing, voto no 
trabalho literário a ser usado em planear uma resposta ao alerta, e, 
como professor-conduzido, atividade da inteiro-classe, vem acima com 
um esboço do thesis e do ponto principal para o essay.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli allievi identificano le virgolette selezionate
dagli impianti letterari studiati nel codice categoria. Dopo che
una breve discussione su che cosa tutte le virgolette hanno il in 
comune, allievi determini che ogni virgoletta foreshadows uno sviluppo
importante e imminente del diagramma. Il codice categoria allora
esaminerà un richiamo di saggio sul foreshadowing, voto sul lavoro 
letterario da usare nella progettazione della risposta al richiamo e, 
come insegnante-condotto, attività del intero-codice categoria, 
fornisce un profilo del punto principale e di tesi per il saggio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι σπουδαστές προσδιορίζουν τα επιλεγμένα αποσπάσματα 
τα λογοτεχνικά έργα που μελετώνται στην κλάση. Μετά από 
μια συνοπτική συζήτηση αυτού που όλα τα αποσπάσματα έχουν από 
κοινού, οι σπουδαστές θα καθορίσουν ότι κάθε απόσπασμα 
προαναγγέλλει μια σημαντική, επερχόμενη ανάπτυξη πλοκών. Η 
κλάση θα εξετάσει έπειτα μια υπαγόρευση δοκίμιου στην 
προαναγγελία, την ψηφοφορία για το λογοτεχνικό έργο που 
χρησιμοποιείται στον προγραμματισμό μιας απάντησης στην 
υπαγόρευση, και, καθώς δάσκαλος-οδηγημένη, τη δραστηριότητα 
ολόκληρος-κλάσης, βρίσκει ένα περίγραμμα διατριβής και βασικού 
σημείου για το δοκίμιο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los estudiantes identifican cotizaciones 
seleccionadas de los trabajos literarios estudiados en clase. 
Después de que una discusión abreviada de lo que tienen todas 
las cotizaciones en campo común, los estudiantes se determine que 
cada cotización presagia un desarrollo importante, próximo del 
diagrama. La clase entonces examinará una guía del ensayo en 
el presagio, voto en el trabajo literario que se utilizará en planear
una respuesta a la guía, y, como profesor-haber conducido, actividad 
de la entero-clase, viene para arriba con un contorno de la tesis y de
la punta principal para el ensayo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MARTHA OWENS
FN:MARTHA OWENS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202819</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106250</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/foreshadowing-quote-identification-discovery-lesson-and-essay-prompt-analysis</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
