<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108105</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108105</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086289</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Limited My Own Family": Memoir of a 1920s Birth Control Activist</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"I Begrenzte Meine Eigene Familie": 
Abhandlung eines zwanziger Jahre Geburtenkontrolle-Aktivisten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"I A limité Ma Propre Famille" : Mémoire 
d'un activiste de contrôle des naissances des années 20</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"I Limitou Minha Própria Família": Memoir 
de uma activista do controle de nascimento dos 1920s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"La I Ha limitato La Mia Propria Famiglia": 
Memoria di un Attivista di controllo di nascita degli anni 
20</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"περιόρισα την οικογένειά μου": Απομνημονεύματα 
ενός ενεργού στελέχους ελέγχου γέννησης της δεκαετίας του '20</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"I Limitó A Mi Propia Familia": Memoria de 
un activista del control de la natalidad de los años 20</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Born in Forreston, Illinois, in 1868, Sylvie Thygeson taught and worked as a stenographer and typist before her marriage at the age of twenty-three. She and her husband, a lawyer, lived in St. Paul, Minnesota. An activist for women's rights, including suffrage and the legalization of contraception, Thygeson felt that birth control was both a crucial part of egalitarian marriage and a major political commitment. In this interview, conducted in 1972 by her daughter Mary Thygeson Shepardson and historian Sherna Gluck, Thygeson described her and her husband's decision to limit their family, a choice that enabled her to work in the suffrage and birth control movements. Her account offered an intriguing glimpse of how birth control advocates circulated information about contraception at a time when many physicians refused to do so, and when both law and public opinion constrained such practices.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Getragen in Forreston, arbeitete Illinois, 1868, 
Sylvie unterrichtetes Thygeson und als Stenograph und 
Maschinenschreiber vor ihrer Verbindung am Alter von dreiundzwanzig. 
Sie und ihr Ehemann, ein Rechtsanwalt, gelebt in Str. Paul, 
Minnesota. Ein Aktivist für Rechte der Frauen, einschließlich 
Stimmrecht und die Legalisierung der Empfängnisverhütung, Thygeson 
glaubte, daß Geburtenkontrolle ein entscheidendes Teil der 
gleichmacherischen Verbindung und eine politische 
hauptsächlichverpflichtung war. In diesem Interview geleitet 
1972 mit ihrer Tochter Mary Thygeson Shepardson und Historiker Sherna 
Gluck, Thygeson beschrieb Entscheidung ihres und ihres Ehemanns, um 
ihre Familie, eine Wahl zu begrenzen, die sie aktivierte, im 
Stimmrecht und in den Geburtenkontrollebewegungen zu arbeiten. 
Ihr Konto bot einen faszinierenden Blick von an, wie 
Geburtenkontrollefürsprecher Informationen über 
Empfängnisverhütung zu einer Zeit als viele Ärzte verteilten, die 
abgelehnt wurden, um so zu tun, und als Gesetz und öffentliche 
Meinung solche Praxis begrenzten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Soutenu dans Forreston, l'Illinois, en 1868, 
Sylvie Thygeson enseigné et a fonctionné en tant qu'un sténographe 
et dactylo avant son mariage à l'âge de vingt-trois. Elle et 
son mari, un avocat, vécu dans la rue Paul, Minnesota. Un 
activiste pour les droits des femmes, y compris le suffrage et la 
légalisation de la contraception, Thygeson a estimé que le contrôle
des naissances était une partie cruciale de mariage égalitaire et un
engagement politique important. Dans cette entrevue, conduite en
1972 par sa fille Mary Thygeson Shepardson et historien Sherna Gluck, 
Thygeson a décrit la décision de son et son mari pour limiter leur 
famille, un choix qui lui a permis de travailler dans le suffrage et 
les mouvements de contrôle des naissances. Son compte a offert 
un aperçu intrigant de la façon dont les avocats de contrôle des 
naissances ont circulé des informations sur la contraception à un 
moment où beaucoup de médecins refusés pour faire ainsi, et quand 
la loi et l'opinion publique ont contraint de telles pratiques.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Carregado em Forreston, Illinois, em 1868, em 
Sylvie Thygeson ensinado e trabalhou como um stenographer e um 
datilógrafo antes de sua união na idade de vinte e três. Ela 
e seu marido, um advogado, vivido em St. Paul, Minnesota. Uma 
activista para direitas das mulheres, including o suffrage e o 
legalization do contraception, Thygeson sentiu que o controle de 
nascimento era  uma parte crucial da união egalitarian e um 
compromisso político principal. Nesta entrevista, conduzida em 
1972 por sua filha Mary Thygeson Shepardson e historian Sherna Gluck, 
Thygeson descreveu decisão do seu e seu marido para limitar sua 
família, uma escolha que a permitisse de trabalhar nos movimentos do 
controle do suffrage e de nascimento. Seu cliente ofereceu um 
glimpse intrigante de como os advogados do controle de nascimento 
circularam a informação sobre o contraception em uma hora em que 
muitos médicos recusados fazer assim, e em que  a lei e a opinião 
pública confinassem tais práticas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sopportato in Forreston, l'Illinois, in 1868, in 
Sylvie Thygeson insegnato ed ha funzionato come un stenografo e 
dattilografo prima della sua unione all'età di ventitre. Lei ed
il suo marito, un avvocato, vivo in st Paul, Minnesota. Un 
attivista per i diritti delle donne, compreso suffrage e la 
legalizzazione della contraccezione, Thygeson ha ritenuto che il 
controllo di nascita era sia una parte cruciale dell'unione egalitaria
che un impegno politico importante. In questa intervista, 
condotta in 1972 dalla sua figlia Mary Thygeson Shepardson e lo 
storico Sherna Gluck, Thygeson ha descritto decisione del suo e suo 
marito limitare la loro famiglia, una scelta che gli ha permesso di 
lavorare nei movimenti di controllo di nascita e di suffrage. Il
suo cliente ha offerto un glimpse intrigante di come i fautori di 
controllo di nascita hanno fatto circolare le informazioni sulla 
contraccezione in un momento in cui molti medici rifiutati per fare 
così e quando sia la legge che l'opinione pubblica hanno costretto 
tali pratiche.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γεννημένος σε Forreston, Ιλλινόις, το 1868, 
Sylvie Thygeson δίδαξε και εργάστηκε ως στενογράφος και 
δακτυλογράφος πριν από το γάμο της στην ηλικία είκοσι τριών. 
Αυτή και ο σύζυγός της, ένας δικηγόρος, έζησαν στο ST 
Paul, Μινεσότα. Ένα ενεργό στέλεχος για τα δικαιώματα 
των γυναικών, συμπεριλαμβανομένης της ψήφου και της νομιμοποίησης 
της αντισύλληψης, Thygeson θεώρησε ότι ο έλεγχος γέννησης 
ήταν και ένα κρίσιμο μέρος του egalitarian γάμου και μια 
μεγαλύτερη πολιτική δέσμευση. Σε αυτήν την συνέντευξη, που 
πραγματοποιήθηκε το 1972 από την κόρη της Mary Thygeson 
Shepardson και ιστορικός Sherna Gluck, Thygeson 
περιέγραψε της και του συζύγου της την απόφαση να περιορίσουν την 
οικογένειά τους, μια επιλογή που επέτρεψε σε την για να εργαστεί 
στις μετακινήσεις ελέγχου ψήφου και γέννησης. Ο απολογισμός
της πρόσφερε μια ραδιουργώντας αναλαμπή για το πώς κυκλοφορημένες
συνήγοροι πληροφορίες ελέγχου γέννησης για την αντισύλληψη σε 
μία εποχή που αρνήθηκαν να κάνουν έτσι πολλοί παθολόγοι, και 
όταν και περιόρισαν ο νόμος και η κοινή γνώμη τέτοιες 
πρακτικές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Llevado en Forreston, Illinois, en 1868, Sylvie 
Thygeson enseñado y trabajó como un taquígrafo y mecanógrafo antes
de su unión en la edad de veintitrés. Ella y su marido, 
abogado, vivido en St. Paul, Minnesota. Un activista para las 
derechas de las mujeres, incluyendo sufragio y la legalización de la 
contracepción, Thygeson se sentía que el control de la natalidad era
una parte crucial de la unión igualitaria y una consolidación 
política importante. En esta entrevista, conducida en 1972 de 
su hija Maria Thygeson Shepardson e historiador Sherna Gluck, Thygeson
describió la decisión de su y su marido para limitar a su familia, 
una opción que le permitió trabajar en los movimientos del control 
del sufragio y de la natalidad. Su cuenta ofreció una ojeada 
intrigante de cómo los abogados del control de la natalidad 
circularon la información sobre la contracepción en un momento en 
que muchos médicos rechazados para hacer así pues, y cuando la ley y
la opinión pública obligaron tales prácticas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086289</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108105</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-limited-my-own-family-memoir-of-a-1920s-birth-control-activist</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
