<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104942</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104942</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086272</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Am Sorry Not to Be Hung": Oscar Neebe and the Haymarket Affair</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ich bin traurig nicht gehangen zu werden": 
Oscar Neebe und die Haymarket Angelegenheit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"je suis désolé de ne pas être arrêté" : 
Oscar Neebe et l'affaire de Haymarket</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"eu sou pesaroso não ser pendurado": Oscar 
Neebe e o caso de Haymarket</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"sono spiacente non essere appeso": Oscar 
Neebe e l'affare di Haymarket</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"λυπάμαι να μην κρεμαστώ": Θ*Οσθαρ Neebe και η 
υπόθεση Haymarket</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"estoy apesadumbrado de no ser colgado": 
Oscar Neebe y el asunto de Haymarket</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Chicago radicals convicted of the infamous May 4, 1886 Haymarket Square bombing in which one policeman was killed remained openly defiant to the end. Unlike the other seven men convicted of the bombing, Oscar Neebe, a New York-born labor organizer who had been raised in Germany, received not death, but a fifteen-year jail sentence. Although Neebe insisted (accurately) that "there is no evidence"that he had connection with the bombing, he maintained, in this brief address, his solidarity with his comrades. "Your honor," he told the judge, "I am sorry I am not to be hung with the rest of them."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Chicago Radikale, die des unbeliebten Mais 4, 
1886 Haymarket quadratische Bombardierung überführt wurden, in der 
ein Polizist beendet wurde, blieben öffentlich zum Ende defiant. 
Anders als die anderen sieben Männer überführt der 
Bombardierung, Oscar Neebe, ein neuer York-getragener 
Gewerkschaftsorganisator, der in Deutschland, empfangener nicht Tod 
angehoben worden war, aber ein Fünfzehnjahr Gefängnisprogrammsatz. 
Obgleich Neebe (genau) daß "es kein evidence"that gibt, ihn 
hatte Anschluß mit der Bombardierung beharrte, behielt er, in dieser 
kurzen Adresse, seine solidarität mit seinen Kameraden bei. 
"Ihre Ehre," erklärte er dem Richter, "ich ist traurig, daß 
ich nicht mit dem Rest von ihnen gehangen werden soll."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les radicaux de Chicago condamnés mai infâme de 
4, 1886 le bombardement carré de Haymarket dans lequel un policier a 
été détruit sont restés ouvrir provoquants d'extrémité. À
la différence les sept des autres hommes condamnés du bombardement, 
Oscar Neebe, un nouveau propagandiste York-soutenu qui n'avait 
été augmenté en Allemagne, pas la mort reçue, mais une peine de 
quinze-année. Bien que Neebe l'ait exigé (exactement) que "il 
n'y a aucun evidence"that ait eu la connexion avec le bombardement, il
a mis à jour, dans cette brève adresse, sa solidarité avec ses 
camarades. "votre honneur," il a dit le juge, "je suis désolé 
que je ne doive pas être arrêté avec le reste d'eux."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os radicais de Chicago convicted maio infamous do 
4, 1886 o bombardeio quadrado de Haymarket em que um polícia foi 
matado remanesceram abertamente defiant à extremidade. Ao 
contrário de outros sete homens convicted do bombardeio, Oscar Neebe,
um organizer labor York-carregado novo que fosse levantado em Germany,
não morte recebida, mas uma sentença de cadeia de quinze-ano. 
Embora Neebe o insistisse (exatamente) que "não há nenhum 
evidence"that tivesse a conexão com o bombardeio, manteve, neste 
endereço breve, seu solidarity com seus camaradas. "sua honra,"
disse o juiz, "mim é pesaroso que eu não devo ser pendurada com o 
descanso deles."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I radicali del Chicago condannati maggio malfamato
del 4, 1886 bombardamento quadrato di Haymarket in cui un poliziotto 
è stato ucciso sono rimasto apertamente ribelle all'estremità. 
Diverso degli altri sette uomini condannati del bombardamento, 
Oscar Neebe, un nuovo organizzatore di lavoro York-sopportato che era
stato sollevato in Germania, non morte ricevuta, ma una frase di 
prigione di quindici-anno. Anche se Neebe lo ha insistito 
(esattamente) che "non ci è evidence"that ha avuto collegamento con 
il bombardamento, ha effettuato, in questo breve indirizzo, la sua 
solidarietà con i suoi camerati. "il vostro honor," ha detto al
giudice, "io sono spiacente che non dovessi essere appeso con il resto
di loro."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι ριζοσπάστες του Σικάγου που καταδικάζονται του 
κακόφημου Μάιος 4 τετραγωνικός βομβαρδισμός ..1886 
Haymarket σε ποιος ένας αστυνομικός σκοτώθηκε παραμένοντας 
ανοιχτά προκλητικός στο τέλος. Αντίθετα από τα άλλα επτά 
άτομα που καταδικάζονται του βομβαρδισμού, Oscar Neebe, ένας
νέος Υόρκη-γεννημένος διοργανωτής εργασίας που ήταν στη 
Γερμανία, λαμβανόμενος όχι θάνατος, αλλά μια ποινή φυλακίσεων 
δεκαπέντε-έτους. Αν και Neebe επέμεινε (ακριβώς) ότι 
"δεν υπάρχει κανένα evidence"that είχε τη σύνδεση με το 
βομβαρδισμό, διατήρησε, σε αυτήν την συνοπτική διεύθυνση, η 
αλληλεγγύη του με τους συντρόφους του. "Η τιμή σας," είπε 
στο δικαστή, "λυπάμαι ότι δεν πρόκειται να κρεμαστώ με το 
υπόλοιπο τους."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los radicales de Chicago condenados del de mayo 
infame 4 de 1886 el bombardeo cuadrado de Haymarket en el cual mataron
a un policía seguían siendo abiertamente desafiantes al extremo. 
Desemejante de los otros siete hombres condenados por el 
bombardeo, Oscar Neebe, nuevo organizador de trabajo York-llevado que 
había sido levantado en Alemania, no muerte recibida, solamente una 
sentencia de cárcel del quince-año. Aunque Neebe lo insistió 
(exactamente) que "no hay evidence"that tenía conexión con el 
bombardeo, él mantuvo, en este direccionamiento abreviado, su 
solidaridad con sus camaradas. "su honor," él dijo a juez, "yo 
está apesadumbrado que no debo ser colgado con el resto de ellos."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086272</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104942</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-am-sorry-not-to-be-hung-oscar-neebe-and-the-haymarket-affair</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
