<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104832</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104832</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203852</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Math2.org (Formerly "Dave's Math Tables")</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Math2.org (Früher "Mathe-Tabellen Daves")</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Math2.org (Autrefois "Tableaux des Maths de 
Dave")</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Math2.org (Anteriormente De "Tabelas Do Math 
Dave")</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Math2.org (Precedentemente "Tabelle Di Per la 
matematica Del Dave")</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Math2.org (στο παρελθόν "πίνακες Math Dave")</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Math2.org (Antes "Vectores De la Matemáticas De 
Dave")</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This general math site offers reference material on a host of math topics, plus a math message board and links to relevant material online. The tables cover a range of math skills, from basic fraction-decimal conversion to the more advanced calculus and discrete math. The information is presented in notation form, with diagrams, graphs, and tables. The site is available in English, Spanish, and French. This resource is part of the Teaching Quantitative Skills in the Geosciences collection. http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese allgemeine Mathesite bietet Bezugsmaterial 
auf einem Hauptrechner der Mathethemen, plus ein Mathemeldung Brett 
und Links relevantem materiellem Online an. Die Tabellen 
umfassen eine Strecke der Mathefähigkeiten, von der grundlegenden 
Bruch-dezimalen Konvertierung zum hochentwickelteren Kalkül und zu 
getrennten Mathe. Die Informationen werden in der Darstellung 
Form, mit Diagrammen, in den Diagrammen und in den Tabellen 
dargestellt. Die Site ist auf englisches, spanisch und 
französisch vorhanden. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Teil der 
Unterricht quantitativen Fähigkeiten in der Geosciences Ansammlung 
http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site général de maths offre la documentation 
de référence sur une foule de sujets de maths, plus un panneau et 
des liens de message de maths à en ligne matériel approprié. 
Les tables couvrent un intervalle des qualifications de maths, 
de conversion fraction-décimale de base en calcul plus avançé et 
maths discrètes. L'information est présentée dans la forme de
notation, avec des diagrammes, les graphiques, et les tables. Le
site est disponible en anglais, espagnol, et le Français. Cette
ressource fait partie des qualifications quantitatives d'enseignement 
dans la collection http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/ de 
Geosciences</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local geral do math oferece o material de 
referência em um anfitrião de tópicos do math, mais uma placa e as 
ligações da mensagem do math a em linha material relevante. As
tabelas cobrem uma escala de habilidades do math, da conversão 
fração-decimal básica ao cálculo mais avançado e ao math 
discreto. A informação é apresentada no formulário da 
notação, com diagramas, nos gráficos, e nas tabelas. O local 
está disponível em inglês, em espanhol, e o francês. Este 
recurso é parte das habilidades quantitative do ensino na coleção 
http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/ de Geosciences</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo generale di per la matematica offre 
il materiale di riferimento su una miriade di soggetti di per la 
matematica, più un bordo ed i collegamenti del messaggio di per
la matematica ad in linea materiale relativo. Le tabelle coprono
una gamma di abilità di per la matematica, dalla conversione 
frazione-decimale di base al calcolo più avanzato ed al per la 
matematica discreto. Le informazioni sono presentate in forma 
della notazione, con gli schemi, grafici e tabelle. Il luogo è 
disponibile in inglese, spagnolo ed il francese. Questa risorsa 
fa parte delle abilità quantitative di insegnamento 
nell'accumulazione http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/ di 
Geosciences</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η γενική περιοχή math προσφέρει το υλικό 
αναφοράς σε έναν πλήθο των θεμάτων math, συν έναν πίνακα και 
τις συνδέσεις μηνυμάτων math με σχετικό υλικό σε απευθείας 
σύνδεση. Οι πίνακες καλύπτουν μια σειρά των δεξιοτήτων 
math, από τη βασική μέρος-δεκαδική μετατροπή στον πιό 
προηγμένο υπολογισμό και το ιδιαίτερο math. Οι 
πληροφορίες παρουσιάζονται με μορφή σημείωσης, με τα διαγράμματα,
τις γραφικές παραστάσεις, και τους πίνακες. Η περιοχή είναι
διαθέσιμη στα αγγλικά, ισπανικά, και γαλλικά. Αυτό το 
στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς είναι μέρος των ποσοτικών δεξιοτήτων 
διδασκαλίας στη Geosciences συλλογή 
http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio general de la matemáticas ofrece el 
material de referencia en un ordenador principal de los asuntos de la 
matemáticas, más una tarjeta y conexiones del mensaje de la 
matemáticas a en línea material relevante. Los vectores cubren
un rango de las habilidades de la matemáticas, de la conversión 
fraccio'n-decimal básica al cálculo más avanzado y a la 
matemáticas discreta. La información se presenta en forma de 
la notación, con los diagramas, gráficos, y vectores. El sitio
está disponible en inglés, español, y francés. Este recurso 
es parte de las habilidades cuantitativas de la enseñanza en la 
colección http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/ de Geosciences</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:DAVID MANURA
FN:DAVID MANURA
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203852</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104832</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/math2-org-formerly-daves-math-tables</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
