<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107717</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107717</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203501</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Invasive Species: The Nation's Invasive Species Information System</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Angriffssorte: Das SORTE-Informationssystem 
Der Nation Angriffß$ln</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Espèces invahissantes : Le Système 
d'Information Invahissant des Espèces de la Nation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Espécie Invasive: O Sistema De Informação
Invasive Da Espécie Da Nação</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Specie Invasive: Il Sistema d'informazione 
Invasive Di Specie Della Nazione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Της εισβολής είδη: Το της εισβολής σύστημα 
πληροφοριών ειδών του έθνους</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Especie Invasora: El Sistema De Información
Invasor De la Especie De la Nación</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The United States Government's Invasive Species website is the gateway to Federal efforts concerning invasive species. On this site users can learn about the impacts of invasive species and the Federal government's response, as well as read select species profiles and find links to agencies and organizations dealing with invasive species issues. This is also the website for the National Invasive Species Council, which coordinates Federal responses to the problem. Users can access geographically specific information on invasive species, a variety of databases, labs and regulations and the Federal management plan. Invasivespecies.gov provides a wealth of information on domestic invasive species.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die der Vereinigte Staaten
Angriffssorteweb site Regierung ist die Gateway zu den 
Bundesbemühungen hinsichtlich sind der Angriffssorten. Auf 
dieser Site können Benutzer über die Auswirkungen von Angriffssorten
und von Antwort der Bundesregierung, sowie gelesenen auserwählten 
Sorteprofile und Entdeckunglinks zu den Agenturen und die 
Organisationen erlernen, die Angriffssorteausgaben beschäftigen. 
Dieses ist auch die Web site für den nationalen 
Angriffssorte-Rat, der Bundesantworten zum Problem koordiniert. 
Benutzer können geographisch spezifische Informationen über 
Angriffssorte erreichen, eine Vielzahl der Datenbanken, Labors und 
Regelungen und der Bundesmanagementplan. Invasivespecies.gov 
stellt eine Fülle der Informationen auf inländischer Angriffssorte 
zur Verfügung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le site Web invahissant des Espèces du 
gouvernement des Etats-Unis est le Gateway aux efforts fédéraux au 
sujet des espèces invahissantes. Sur ce site les 
utilisateurs peuvent se renseigner sur les impacts des espèces 
invahissantes et de la réponse de gouvernement fédéral, comme des 
profils d'espèces et des liens de trouvaille aux agences et des 
organismes choisis lus traitant les issues invahissantes 
d'espèces. C'est également le site Web pour le Conseil 
invahissant national d'Espèces, qui coordonne des réponses 
fédérales au problème. Les utilisateurs peuvent accéder à 
l'information géographiquement spécifique sur des espèces 
invahissantes, une variété de bases de données, des laboratoires et
des règlements et le plan fédéral de gestion. 
Invasivespecies.gov fournit une richesse d'information sur des 
espèces invahissantes domestiques.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Web site invasive da espécie do governo unido 
dos estados é o Gateway aos esforços federais a respeito das 
espécies invasive. Neste local os usuários podem aprender 
sobre os impactos de espécies invasive e da resposta de governo 
federal, assim como perfis da espécie e as ligações do achado às 
agências e as organizações seletos lidos que tratam das edições 
invasive da espécie. Este é também o Web site para o conselho
invasive nacional da espécie, que coordena respostas federais ao 
problema. Os usuários podem alcançar a informação 
geogràfica específica na espécie invasive, uma variedade das bases 
de dados, laboratórios e regulamentos e a planta federal da 
gerência. Invasivespecies.gov fornece uma riqueza da 
informação na espécie invasive doméstica.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Unito Dichiara il Web site invasive di 
specie del governo è il Gateway agli sforzi federali riguardo alle 
specie invasive. Su questo luogo utenti possono imparare circa 
gli effetti delle specie invasive e della risposta del governo 
federale, come pure i profili di specie ed i collegamenti del 
ritrovamento alle agenzie e le organizzazioni prescelti colti che si 
occupano delle edizioni invasive di specie. Ciò è egualmente 
il Web site per il Consiglio invasive nazionale di specie, che 
coordina le risposte federali al problema. Gli utenti possono 
accedere alle informazioni geograficamente specifiche sulla specie 
invasive, una varietà di basi di dati, laboratori e regolazioni ed il
programma federale della gestione. Invasivespecies.gov fornisce 
una ricchezza delle informazioni sulla specie invasive domestica.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο της εισβολής ιστοχώρος ειδών της Ηνωμένης 
κυβέρνησης είμαι η πύλη στις ομοσπονδιακές προσπάθειες σχετικά 
με τα της εισβολής είδη. Σε αυτήν την περιοχή οι χρήστες 
μπορούν να μάθουν για τις επιδράσεις των της εισβολής ειδών και 
της απάντησης της ομοσπονδιακής κυβέρνησης, καθώς επίσης και να 
διαβάσουν τα επίλεκτα σχεδιαγράμματα ειδών και να βρούν τις 
συνδέσεις με τις αντιπροσωπείες και τις οργανώσεις που εξετάζουν 
τα της εισβολής ζητήματα ειδών. Αυτό είναι επίσης ο 
ιστοχώρος για το εθνικό της εισβολής Συμβούλιο ειδών, το οποίο 
συντονίζει τις ομοσπονδιακές απαντήσεις στο πρόβλημα. Οι 
χρήστες μπορούν να έχουν πρόσβαση γεωγραφικά στις συγκεκριμένες 
πληροφορίες για τα της εισβολής είδη, ποικίλες βάσεις δεδομένων,
τα εργαστήρια και τους κανονισμούς και το ομοσπονδιακό διοικητικό 
σχέδιο. Το Invasivespecies.gov παρέχει έναν πλούτο των 
πληροφοριών για τα εσωτερικά της εισβολής είδη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Web site invasor de la especie del gobierno de 
Estados Unidos es el Gateway a los esfuerzos federales referentes a 
especies invasoras. En este sitio los utilizadores pueden 
aprender sobre los impactos de especies invasoras y de la respuesta 
del gobierno federal, tan bien como perfiles de la especie y 
conexiones del hallazgo a las agencias y las organizaciones selectos 
leídos que se ocupan de las ediciones invasoras de la especie. 
Éste es también el Web site para el consejo invasor nacional 
de la especie, que coordina respuestas federales al problema. 
Los utilizadores pueden tener acceso a la información 
geográficamente específica sobre especie invasora, una variedad de 
bases de datos, los laboratorios y las regulaciones y el plan federal 
de la gerencia. Invasivespecies.gov proporciona a una abundancia
de la información en especie invasora doméstica.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203501</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107717</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/invasive-species-the-nations-invasive-species-information-system</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
