<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108580</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108580</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086948</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Greatest Hebrew Ace": "Levine mit Zayn Flaying Mashin"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Das Größte Hebräische As": "Levine MIT 
Zayn Flaying Mashin"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Le Plus grand As Hébreu" : "MIT Zayn 
Flaying Mashin de Levine"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"O Ace Hebrew O mais grande": de "mit Zayn 
Flaying Mashin Levine"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"L'Asso Ebraico Più grande": "mit Zayn 
Flaying Mashin di Levine"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ο μέγιστος εβραϊκός άσσοσ": "Levine mit 
Zayn Flaying Mashin"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"El As Hebreo Más grande": "mit Zayn 
Flaying Mashin de Levine"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The day after Charles Lindbergh reached Paris in May 1927, the only headline on the front page of the  New York Times  that did not directly concern the young American aviator read "Levine Abandons Bellanca Flight." It chronicled the unsuccessful efforts of Charles Levine of the Columbia Aircraft Company to complete the first transatlantic flight. Later that year the thirty-year-old millionaire did fly to Berlin with Clarence Chamberlin, breaking Lindbergh's record. Yiddish vaudevillian Charles Cohen decided to commemorate the flight in song when President Calvin Coolidge outraged Jews by receiving Chamberlin but not Levine at the White House. The song, sung in Yiddish and English, reflected the ambivalence of American Jews who were still outsiders but also wanted to be part of the mainstream. Like the Americans who greeted Lindbergh's flight by looking forward and backward, Jews were also caught between the past and the future. [English translation follows Yiddish.]</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Tag nach Charles Lindbergh erreichte Paris im 
Mai 1927, die einzige Schlagzeile auf der Vorderseite der New York 
Zeiten, die nicht direkt betrafen den junger amerikanischer Flieger 
gelesenen "Levine Ungezwungenheiten Bellanca Flug." Er zeichnete
die erfolglosen Bemühungen von Charles Levine der Kolumbien 
Flugzeug-Firma auf, den ersten transatlantic Flug durchzuführen. 
Später dieses Jahr flog der dreißig-Jahr-alte Millionaire nach
Berlin mit Clarence Chamberlin und brach Satz Lindberghs. 
Yiddish vaudevillian Charles Cohen entschied, den Flug im Lied 
zu gedenken, als Präsident Calvin Coolidge Juden verletzte, indem er 
Chamberlin aber nicht Levine am Weißen Haus empfing. Das Lied, 
gesungen auf Yiddish und Englisch, reflektierte die ambivalenz der 
amerikanischen Juden, die ruhige Außenseiter waren, aber wollte auch 
ein Teil des Mainstreams sein. Wie die Amerikaner, die Flug 
Lindberghs grüßten, indem sie vorwärts und rückwärts schauten, 
wurden Juden auch zwischen der Vergangenheit und der Zukunft 
abgefangen. [ englische Übersetzung folgt Yiddish. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le jour après Charles Lindbergh a atteint Paris 
en mai 1927, le seul titre sur la page plan des temps de New York qui 
ne sont pas directement concernés américain "le vol de Bellanca 
d'abandons de Levine lu jeune par aviateur." Il a fait la 
chronique des efforts non réussis de Charles Levine du compagnie 
aérien de Colombie de terminer le premier vol transatlantique. 
Plus tard cette année le trente-année-vieux millionnaire a 
volé à Berlin avec Clarence Chamberlin, cassant l'enregistrement de 
Lindbergh. Yiddish Charles vaudevillian Cohen a décidé de 
commémorer le vol dans la chanson quand le Président Calvin Coolidge
a outragé des juifs en recevant Chamberlin mais pas Levine à la 
Maison Blanche . La chanson, chantée dans Yiddish et anglais, a
reflété l'ambivalence des juifs américains qui étaient les 
étrangers immobiles mais a également voulu faire partie du courant 
principal. Comme les Américains qui ont salué le vol de 
Lindbergh en regardant en avant et vers l'arrière, des juifs ont 
été également attrapés entre le passé et le futur. [ la 
traduction en anglais suit Yiddish. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O dia após Charles Lindbergh alcançou Paris em 
maio 1927, o único headline na página dianteira dos tempos de New 
York que não concerniram diretamente aviador americano novo de "o 
vôo lido de Bellanca dos abandonos Levine." Chronicled os 
esforços mal sucedidos de Charles Levine da companhia de avião de 
Colômbia terminar o primeiro vôo transatlantic. Mais tarde 
esse ano o millionaire trinta-ano-velho voou a Berlim com Clarence 
Chamberlin, quebrando o registro de Lindbergh. Yiddish Charles 
vaudevillian Cohen decidiu-se comemorar o vôo na canção quando o 
presidente Calvin Coolidge ultrajou jews recebendo Chamberlin mas não
Levine na casa branca. A canção, cantada em Yiddish e em 
inglês, refletiu o ambivalence dos jews americanos que eram outsiders
imóveis mas qui-lo também ser parte do mainstream. Como os 
americanos que cumprimentaram o vôo de Lindbergh olhando para a 
frente e para trás, os jews foram travados também entre o passado e 
o futuro. [ a tradução inglesa segue Yiddish. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il giorno dopo Charles Lindbergh ha raggiunto 
Parigi nel mese di maggio 1927, l'unico titolo alla pagina anteriore 
dei tempi de New York che direttamente non hanno interessato "il volo 
di Bellanca di abbandoni di Levine colto aviator americano giovane." 
Chronicled gli sforzi infruttuosi di Charles Levine della 
compagnia ærea della Colombia completare il primo volo transatlantico.
Più successivamente quell'anno il trenta-anno-vecchio 
millionaire ha volato a Berlino con Clarence Chamberlin, rompente il 
record del Lindbergh. Yiddish Charles vaudevillian Cohen ha 
deciso commemorare il volo nella canzone quando il presidente Calvin 
Coolidge ha oltraggiato gli ebrei ricevendo Chamberlin ma non Levine 
alla Casa Bianca. La canzone, cantata in Yiddish e nell'inglese,
ha riflesso l'ambivalenza degli ebrei americani che erano stranieri 
tranquilli ma egualmente ha desiderato fare parte della corrente 
principale. Come gli Americani che greeted il volo del Lindbergh
osservando in avanti ed indietro, gli ebrei egualmente sono stati 
interferiti fra l'esperienza ed il futuro. [ la traduzione in 
inglese segue Yiddish. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ημέρα αφότου έφθασε Charles Lindbergh στο 
Παρίσι σε Μάιος το 1927, ο μόνος τίτλος πρώτη σελίδα των 
New York Times που δεν αφορούσαν άμεσα το νέο αμερικανικό
αεροπόρο που διαβάστηκε "Levine εγκαταλείπει την πτήση 
Bellanca." Ηξιστόρησε κατά γράμμα τις ανεπιτυχείς 
προσπάθειες Charles Levine της επιχείρησης αεροσκαφών της 
Κολούμπια για να ολοκληρώσει την πρώτη υπερατλαντική πτήση. 
Αργότερα εκείνο το έτος ο τριάντα-χρονών 
εκατομμυριούχος πέταξε στο Βερολίνο με Clarence Chamberlin, 
που σπάζει το αρχείο Lindbergh. Γίντις vaudevillian 
Charles Cohen αποφάσισε να τιμήσει την μνήμη της πτήσης στο 
τραγούδι όταν πρόσβαλε ο Πρόεδρος Calvin Coolidge τους 
Εβραίους με τη λήψη Chamberlin αλλά όχι Levine στο λευκό 
οίκο. Το τραγούδι, που τραγουδήθηκε σε γίντις και αγγλικά, 
απεικόνισε την αμφιθυμία των αμερικανικών Εβραίων που ήταν ακόμα
ξένοι αλλά και θέλησε να είναι μέρος της επικρατούσας τάσης. 
Όπως τους Αμερικανούς που χαιρέτησαν την πτήση Lindbergh 
με να κοιτάξουν προς τα εμπρός και προς τα πίσω, οι Εβραίοι 
πιάστηκαν επίσης μεταξύ του παρελθόντος και του μέλλοντος. [ Η αγγλική μετάφραση ακολουθεί γίντις. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El día después de Charles Lindbergh alcanzó 
París en mayo de 1927, el único título en la paginación delantera 
de los tiempos de Nueva York que no se refirieron directamente "al 
vuelo leído aviador americano joven de Bellanca de los abandonos de 
Levine." Chronicled los esfuerzos fracasados de Charles Levine 
de la compañía aérea de Colombia de terminar el primer vuelo 
transatlántico. Ese año el treinta-año-viejo millonario voló
más adelante a Berlín con Clarence Chamberlin, rompiendo el 
expediente de Lindbergh. Yiddish Charles vaudevillian Cohen 
decidía a conmemorar el vuelo en la canción cuando presidente Calvin
Coolidge ultrajó a judíos recibiendo Chamberlin pero no Levine en la
casa blanca. La canción, cantada en Yiddish e inglés, reflejó
la ambivalencia de los judíos americanos que eran forasteros 
inmóviles pero también deseó ser parte de la corriente principal. 
Como los americanos que saludaron el vuelo de Lindbergh mirando 
adelante y al revés, cogieron a los judíos también entre el pasado 
y el futuro. [ la traducción inglesa sigue Yiddish. ]</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086948</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108580</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-greatest-hebrew-ace-levine-mit-zayn-flaying-mashin</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
