<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107235</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107235</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204378</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A renaissance of jazz and poetry</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Renaissance von Jazz und von Poesie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une Renaissance du jazz et de la poésie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um renascimento do jazz e da poesia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Una rinascita di jazz e di poesia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια αναγέννηση της τζαζ και της ποίησης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un renacimiento del jazz y de la poesía</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Harlem Renaissance was the birth of a creative plethora in all fields of art for African Americans. The poetry and jazz composed during or inspired by this era naturally complemented each other. Furthermore, many of the themes from the musical and literary worlds are universal and provide a great lesson on how two different works can have a parallel theme.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Allen Harlem Renaissance war die Geburt einer 
kreativen Fülle in auffängt von der kunst für afrikanische
Amerikaner. Die Poesie und der Jazz, die während bestanden oder
bis zum dieser Ära nzten anspornten sich natürlich ergä. 
Ausserdem sind viele der Themen von den musikalischen und 
literarischen Welten allgemeinhin und stellen eine große Lektion auf 
zur Verfügung, wie zwei unterschiedliche Arbeiten ein paralleles 
Thema haben können.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Renaissance de Harlem était la naissance 
d'une pléthore créatrice dans tous les domaines d'art pour les 
Américains africains. La poésie et le jazz composés pendant 
ou inspirés par cette ère se sont naturellement complétés. 
En outre, plusieurs des thèmes des mondes musicaux et 
littéraires sont universels et fournissent une grande leçon sur la 
façon dont deux travaux différents peuvent avoir un thème 
parallèle.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O renascimento de Harlem era o nascimento de um 
plethora creativo em todos os campos da arte para americanos 
africanos. A poesia e o jazz compostos durante ou inspirados por
esta era complementaram-se naturalmente. Além disso, muitos dos
temas dos mundos musicais e literários são universais e fornecem uma
lição grande em como dois trabalhos diferentes podem ter um tema 
paralelo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La rinascita di Harlem era la nascita di una 
pletora creativa in tutti i campi dell'arte per gli Americani 
africani. La poesia ed il jazz composti durante o ispirati entro
questa era si sono complementati naturalmente. Ancora, molti dei
temi dai mondi musicali e letterari sono universali e forniscono una 
lezione grande su come due impianti differenti possono avere un tema 
parallelo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η αναγέννηση Harlem ήταν η γέννηση ενός 
δημιουργικού μεγάλου αριθμού σε όλα τα πεδία της τέχνης για 
αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς. Η ποίηση και η τζαζ που συντέθηκαν
κατά τη διάρκεια ή που εμπνεύστηκαν από αυτήν την εποχή 
συμπλήρωσαν φυσικά η μια την άλλη. Επιπλέον, πολλά από τα 
θέματα από τους μουσικούς και λογοτεχνικούς κόσμους είναι 
καθολικά και παρέχουν ένα μεγάλο μάθημα στον τρόπο με τον οποίο
δύο διαφορετικές εργασίες μπορούν να έχουν ένα παράλληλο θέμα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El renacimiento de Harlem era el nacimiento de una 
plétora creativa en todos los campos del arte para los americanos 
africanos. La poesía y el jazz compuestos durante o inspirados 
por esta era se complementaron naturalmente. Además, muchos de 
los temas de los mundos musicales y literarios son universales y 
proporcionan a una gran lección en cómo dos diversos trabajos pueden
tener un tema paralelo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JANET FORE
FN:JANET FORE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204378</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107235</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/a-renaissance-of-jazz-and-poetry</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
