<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105643</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105643</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974122</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Human Rights Education Handbook: Effective Practices for Learning, Action, and Change</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Menschliche Recht-Ausbildung Handbuch: 
Wirkungsvolle Praxis für das Lernen, Tätigkeit und Änderung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Manuel D'Éducation de Droits de l'homme : 
Pratiques pertinentes pour l'étude, l'action, et le changement</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Manual Da Instrução Das Direitas Humanas: 
Práticas eficazes para a aprendizagem, a ação, e a mudança</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Manuale Di Formazione Di Diritti dell'uomo: 
Pratiche efficaci per imparare, azione e cambiamento</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το εγχειρίδιο εκπαίδευσης των ανθρώπινων δικαιωμάτων: 
Αποτελεσματικές πρακτικές για την εκμάθηση, την ενέργεια, 
και την αλλαγή</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Manual De la Educación De los Derechos 
Humanos: Prácticas eficaces para aprender, la acción, y el 
cambio</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This manual is intended to help people who care about human rights to become effective educators, able to share both their passion and their knowledge. To further human rights education in all its many forms, The Human Rights Education Handbook lays out the basics: why, for whom, what, where, who, and how. It draws on the experience of many educators and organizations, illustrating their effective practices and distilling their accumulated insights.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Handbuch soll helfen, Völker, wem Obacht 
über menschliche Rechte, die wirkungsvollen Erzieher zu werden, 
fähig, ihre Neigung und ihr Wissen zu teilen. Zur weiteren 
Ausbildung der menschlichen Rechte in allen seinen vielen Formen, 
breitet das menschliche Recht-Ausbildung Handbuch die Grundlagen aus: 
warum, für das, was, wo, das und wie. Es zeichnet auf die
Erfahrung vieler Erzieher und Organisationen, veranschaulicht ihre 
wirkungsvolle Praxis und destilliert ihre akkumulierten Einblicke.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce manuel est destiné pour aider à peuple qui 
soin au sujet des droits de l'homme de devenir les éducateurs 
pertinents, capables partager leur passion et leur connaissance. 
À un enseignement plus supérieur de droits de l'homme sous 
toutes ses nombreuses formes, le manuel d'éducation de droits de 
l'homme présente les fondations : pourquoi, pour qui, ce qui, 
où, qui, et comment. Il tirere parti de l'expérience de 
beaucoup d'éducateurs et organismes, illustrant leurs pratiques 
pertinentes et distillant leurs perspicacités accumulées.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este manual é pretendido ajudar povoar quem 
cuidado sobre direitas humanas se transformar educadores eficazes, 
capazes de compartilhar  de sua paixão e de seu conhecimento. A
uma instrução mais adicional das direitas humanas em todos seus 
muitos formulários, o manual da instrução das direitas humanas 
coloca para fora dos princípios: porque, para quem, que, onde, 
que, e como. Desenha na experiência de muitos educadores e 
organizações, ilustrando suas práticas eficazes e destilando suas 
introspecções acumuladas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo manuale è inteso per contribuire a 
popolare chi cura circa i diritti dell'uomo transformarsi in in 
educatori efficaci, in grado di ripartire sia la loro passione che la 
loro conoscenza. A più universitario di diritti dell'uomo in 
tutte le sue numerose forme, il manuale di formazione di diritti 
dell'uomo presenta i principi fondamentali: perchè, per quale, 
che cosa, dove, che e come. Dissipa sull'esperienza in molti 
educatori ed organizzazioni, illustrante le loro pratiche efficaci e 
distillante le loro comprensioni accumulate.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το εγχειρίδιο προορίζεται να βοηθήσει τους 
ανθρώπους που φροντίζουν για τα ανθρώπινα δικαιώματα να γίνουν 
αποτελεσματικοί εκπαιδευτικοί, ικανοί να μοιραστούν και το πάθος 
τους και τη γνώση τους. Για να προαγάγει την εκπαίδευση των 
ανθρώπινων δικαιωμάτων εγχειρίδιο εκπαίδευσης σε όλες τις πολλές
μορφές του, το των ανθρώπινων δικαιωμάτων σχεδιάζει τα βασικά: 
γιατί, για το οποίο, τι, όπου, ο οποίος, και πώς. 
Χρησιμοποιεί την εμπειρία πολλών εκπαιδευτικών και 
οργανώσεων, που επεξηγεί τις αποτελεσματικές πρακτικές τους και 
που αποστάζει τις συσσωρευμένες ιδέες τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este manual se piensa para ayudar a poblar quién 
cuidado sobre derechos humanos de hacer educadores eficaces, capaces 
de compartir su pasión y su conocimiento. A la educación 
adicional de los derechos humanos en todas sus muchas formas, el 
manual de la educación de los derechos humanos presenta a los 
fundamentos: porqué, para que, lo que, donde, que, y cómo. 
Traza en la experiencia de muchos educadores y organizaciones, 
ilustrando sus prácticas eficaces y destilando sus penetraciones 
acumuladas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MARCIA BERNBAUM
FN:MARCIA BERNBAUM
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:NANCY FLOWERS
FN:NANCY FLOWERS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:KRISTI RUDELIUS-PALMER
FN:KRISTI RUDELIUS-PALMER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JOEL TOLMAN
FN:JOEL TOLMAN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974122</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105643</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-human-rights-education-handbook-effective-practices-for-learning-action-and-change</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
