<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108390</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108390</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205968</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Create a Graph</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erstellen Sie ein Diagramm</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Créez un graphique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Críe um gráfico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Crei un grafico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δημιουργήστε μια γραφική παράσταση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cree un gráfico</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Graphs and charts are great because they communicate information visually. For this reason, graphs are often used in newspapers, magazines and businesses around the world.

NCES constantly uses graphs and charts in our publications and on the web. Sometimes, complicated information is difficult to understand and needs an illustration. Graphs or charts can help impress people by getting your point across quickly and visually.

Here you will find five different graphs and charts for you to consider.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diagramme und Diagramme sind groß, weil sie 
Informationen sichtlich mitteilen. Für diesen Grund werden 
Diagramme häufig in den Zeitungen benutzt, benutzt Zeitschriften und 
Geschäfte um das world.NCES ständig Diagramme und Diagramme in 
unseren Publikationen und auf dem Web. Manchmal sind schwierige 
Informationen schwierig zu verstehen und benötigen eine Abbildung. 
Diagramme oder Diagramme können helfen, Leute zu beeindrucken, 
indem sie herüber Ihren Punkt schnell erhalten und visually.Here 
finden Sie fünf unterschiedliche Diagramme und Diagramme, damit Sie 
betrachten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les graphiques et les diagrammes sont grands parce
qu'ils communiquent l'information visuellement. Pour cette 
raison, des graphiques sont souvent utilisés en journaux, les 
magasins et les entreprises autour du world.NCES utilise constamment 
des graphiques et des diagrammes en nos publications et sur le Web. 
Parfois, l'information compliquée est difficile à comprendre 
et a besoin d'une illustration. Les graphiques ou les diagrammes
peuvent aider à impressionner des personnes en obtenant votre point 
à travers rapidement et visually.Here vous trouverez cinq graphiques 
et diagrammes différents pour que vous considériez.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os gráficos e as cartas são grandes porque 
comunicam a informação visualmente. Para esta razão, os 
gráficos são usados frequentemente nos jornais, os compartimentos e 
os negócios em torno do world.NCES usam constantemente gráficos e 
cartas em nossas publicações e no Web. Às vezes, a 
informação complicada é difícil de compreender e necessita uma 
ilustração. Os gráficos ou as cartas podem ajudar imprimir 
povos começando seu ponto transversalmente rapidamente e 
visually.Here você encontrará cinco gráficos e cartas diferentes 
para que você considere.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I grafici e le tabelle sono grandi perché 
comunicano visivamente le informazioni. Per questo motivo, i 
grafici sono usati spesso in giornali, gli scomparti ed i commerci 
intorno al world.NCES usa costantemente i grafici e le tabelle in 
nostre pubblicazioni e sul Web. A volte, le informazioni 
complicate sono difficili da capire e hanno bisogno di 
un'illustrazione. I grafici o le tabelle possono contribuire ad 
impressionare la gente ottenendo il vostro punto attraverso 
rapidamente e visually.Here vi troverete cinque grafici e tabelle 
differenti affinchè consideriate.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι γραφικές παραστάσεις και τα διαγράμματα είναι 
μεγάλες επειδή μεταβιβάζουν τις πληροφορίες οπτικά. Για 
αυτόν τον λόγο, οι γραφικές παραστάσεις χρησιμοποιούνται συχνά 
στις εφημερίδες, τα περιοδικά και οι επιχειρήσεις σε όλο τον 
κόσμο NCES χρησιμοποιούν συνεχώς τις γραφικές παραστάσεις και 
τα διαγράμματα στις δημοσιεύσεις μας και στον Ιστό. Μερικές 
φορές, οι περίπλοκες πληροφορίες είναι δύσκολο να καταλαβευτούν 
και χρειάζονται μια απεικόνιση. Οι γραφικές παραστάσεις ή 
τα διαγράμματα μπορούν να βοηθήσουν να εντυπωσιάσουν τους 
ανθρώπους με να πάρουν το σημείο σας πέρα από γρήγορα και 
οπτικά Εδώ θα βρείτε πέντε διαφορετικά γραφικές 
παραστάσεις και διαγράμματα για σας για να εξετάσετε.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los gráficos y las cartas son grandes porque 
comunican la información visualmente. Por esta razón, los 
gráficos se utilizan a menudo en periódicos, los compartimientos y 
los negocios alrededor del world.NCES utilizan constantemente 
gráficos y cartas en nuestras publicaciones y en el Web. A 
veces, la información complicada es difícil de entender y necesita 
una ilustración. Los gráficos o las cartas pueden ayudar a 
impresionar a gente consiguiendo su punta a través rápidamente y 
visually.Here usted encontrará cinco diversos gráficos y cartas para
que usted considere.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205968</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108390</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/create-a-graph</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
