<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104438</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104438</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086385</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Kissing Rudy Valentino: A High-School Student Describes Movie Going in the 1920s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Küssen Von von Rudy Valentino: Ein High 
School Kursteilnehmer beschreibt den Film, der in den zwanziger Jahren
geht</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Baisers de Rudy Valentino : Un étudiant de 
lycée décrit le film allant dans les années 20</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Beijando Rudy Valentino: Um estudante da 
High School descreve o filme que vai nos 1920s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Baciare Rudy Valentino: Un allievo della 
High School descrive il Film che va negli anni 20</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο φιλώντας Rudy Valentino: Ένας 
υψηλός-σχολικός σπουδαστής περιγράφει τον κινηματογράφο που 
πηγαίνει στη δεκαετία του '20</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Besar Rudy Valentino: Un estudiante de la 
High School secundaria describe la película que va en los años 20</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Fears about the impact of movies on youth led to the Payne Fund research project, which brought together nineteen social scientists and resulted in eleven published reports. One of the most fascinating of the studies was carried out by Herbert Blumer, a young sociologist who would later go on to a distinguished career in the field. For a volume that he called  Movies and Conduct  (1933), Blumer asked more than fifteen hundred college and high school students to write "autobiographies"of their experiences going to the movies. In this motion picture autobiography, a high school "girl" talked about what the movies of the 1920s meant to her.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Furcht über die Auswirkung von Filmen auf Jugend 
führte zu das Payne Kapital Forschung Projekt, das neunzehn 
Sozialwissenschaftler zusammenbrachte und elf erschienene Reports 
ergab. Ein vom faszinierendsten der Studien wurde von Herbert 
Blumer, ein junger Soziologe durchgeführt, der später zu einer 
bemerkenswerten Karriere in auffangene weitergehen würde. 
Für einen Datenträger, daß er Movies anrief und Führung 
(1933), bat Blumer mehr als fünfzehn hundert Hochschul- und High 
Schoolkursteilnehmer, "autobiographies"of ihre Erfahrungen zu 
schreiben, die zu den Filmen gehen. In dieser Bewegung Abbildung
Autobiographie befaßte sich eine High School "Mädchen", mit was die 
Filme der zwanziger Jahre zu ihr bedeuteten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les craintes au sujet de l'impact des films sur la
jeunesse ont mené au projet de recherche de fonds de Payne, qui a 
rassemblé dix-neuf sociologues et a eu comme conséquence onze 
rapports publiés. Un du plus fascinant des études a été 
effectué par Herbert Blumer, un jeune sociologue qui continuerait 
plus tard à une carrière distinguée dans le domaine. Pour un 
volume qu'il a appelé Movies et la conduite (1933), Blumer a demandé
à plus de quinze cent étudiants d'université et de lycée d'écrire
à "autobiographies"of leurs expériences allant au cinéma. En 
cette autobiographie de film cinématographique, un lycée "fille" a 
parlé de ce qu'ont signifié les films des années 20 à elle.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os medos sobre o impacto dos filmes na juventude 
conduziram ao projeto de pesquisa do fundo de Payne, que trouxe junto 
dezenove cientistas sociais e resultou em onze relatórios publicados.
Um do mais fascinante dos estudos foi realizado por Herbert 
Blumer, um sociologist novo que fosse mais tarde sobre a uma distinta 
carreira no campo. Para um volume que chamou Filme e a conduta 
(1933), Blumer pediu que mais de quinze cem estudantes da faculdade e 
da High School escrevessem a "autobiographies"of suas experiências 
que vão aos filmes. Neste autobiography do retrato de 
movimento, uma High School "menina" falou sobre o que os filmes dos 
1920s lhe significaram.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I timori circa l'effetto dei film sulla 
gioventù hanno condotto al progetto di ricerca del fondo monetario di
Payne, che ha riunito diciannove sociologi ed ha dato come risultato 
undici rapporti pubblicati. Uno dell'più affascinante degli 
studi è stato effettuato da Herbert Blumer, un sociologist giovane 
che più successivamente accenderebbe ad una carriera distinta nel 
campo. Per un volume che ha chiamato film e comportamento 
(1933), Blumer ha chiesto a più di quindici cento allievi della High 
School e dell'università di scrivere "a autobiographies"of le loro 
esperienze che vanno ai film. In questo autobiography 
del cinema, una High School "ragazza" ha parlato di che cosa i 
film degli anni 20 hanno significato a lei.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι φόβοι για τον αντίκτυπο των κινηματογράφων στη 
νεολαία οδήγησαν στο ερευνητικό πρόγραμμα Ταμείων Payne, το 
οποίο συγκέντρωσε δεκαεννέα κοινωνικούς επιστήμονες και οδήγησε 
σε ένδεκα δημοσιευμένες εκθέσεις. Ένα από να συναρπάσει 
των μελετών πραγματοποιήθηκε από Herbert Blumer, ένας νέος 
κοινωνιολόγος που θα πήγαινε αργότερα προς μια διακεκριμένη 
σταδιοδρομία στο πεδίο. Για μια ένταση του ήχου ότι κάλεσε
τους κινηματογράφους και συμπεριφορά (1933), Blumer ζήτησε 
από περισσότερων από δεκαπέντε εκατό τους σπουδαστές κολλεγίων 
και γυμνασίου για να γράψει "autobiographies"of την εμπειρία 
τους που πηγαίνει στους κινηματογράφους. Σε αυτήν την 
αυτοβιογραφία ταινιών, ένα γυμνάσιο "κορίτσι" μίλησε για αυτό 
που οι κινηματογράφοι της δεκαετίας του '20 σήμαναν σε την.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los miedos sobre el impacto de películas en la 
juventud condujeron al proyecto de investigación del fondo de Payne, 
que reunió a diecinueve científicos sociales y dio lugar a once 
informes publicados. Uno del más fascinador de los estudios fue
realizado por Herberto Blumer, sociólogo joven que continuaría más 
adelante a una carrera distinguida en el campo. Para un volumen 
que él llamó a Película y la conducta (1933), Blumer pidió que 
más de quince cientos estudiantes de la universidad y de la High 
School secundaria escribieran a "autobiographies"of sus experiencias 
que iban a las películas. En esta autobiografía de la 
película, una High School secundaria "muchacha" habló de lo que 
significaron las películas de los años 20 a ella.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086385</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104438</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/kissing-rudy-valentino-a-high-school-student-describes-movie-going-in-the-1920s</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
