<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108389</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108389</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200940</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Coastal Wave Mechanics</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Küstenwelle Mechaniker</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mécanique Côtière de Vague</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Mecânicos Litorais Da Onda</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Meccanici Litoranei Dell'Onda</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παράκτιοι μηχανικοί κυμάτων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mecánicos Costeros De la Onda</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site features Flash animations and a QuickTime movie that illustrate how waves and water molecules behave along the shore and in deep water settings. Animations depict the orbital motion of water molecules and show cross sections of waves at varying depths. These resources are suitable for use in lectures, labs, or other teaching activities.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Situationsmerkmale blinken Animationen und 
ein QuickTime Film, die veranschaulichen, wie Wellen und 
Wassermoleküle entlang dem Ufer und in den tiefen Wassereinstellungen
sich benehmen. Animationen stellen die Augenhöhlenbewegung der 
Wassermoleküle bildlich dar und zeigen Querschnitte der Wellen an 
unterschiedlichen Tiefen. Diese Betriebsmittel sind für 
Gebrauch in den Vorträgen, in den Labors oder in anderen 
unterrichtenden Aktivitäten verwendbar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les dispositifs de ce site flashent des animations 
et un film de QuickTime qui illustrent comment les vagues et les 
molécules d'eau se comportent le long du rivage et dans les 
configurations profondes de l'eau. Les animations dépeignent le
mouvement orbital des molécules d'eau et montrent les coupes des 
vagues aux profondeurs variables. Ces ressources conviennent 
pour l'usage dans les conférences, les laboratoires, ou d'autres 
activités d'enseignement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As características deste local piscam os 
animations e um filme de QuickTime que ilustram como as ondas e as 
moléculas de água se comportam ao longo da costa e em ajustes 
profundos da água. Os animations descrevem o movimento orbital 
de moléculas de água e mostram seções transversais das ondas em 
profundidades variando. Estes recursos são apropriados para o 
uso nos lectures, nos laboratórios, ou em outras atividades 
ensinando.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Caratteristiche di questo luogo espongono a flash 
animazioni e un film del QuickTime che illustrano come le onde 
e le molecole di acqua si comportano lungo il puntello e nelle 
regolazioni profonde dell'acqua. Le animazioni descrivono il 
movimento orbitale delle molecole di acqua e mostrano le sezioni 
trasversali delle onde alle profondità di variazione. Queste 
risorse sono adatte ad uso nelle conferenze, in laboratori, o in altre
attività d'istruzione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει τις ζωτικότητες λάμψης 
και έναν κινηματογράφο QuickTime που επεξηγούν πώς τα κύματα 
και τα μόρια ύδατος συμπεριφέρονται κατά μήκος της ακτής και 
στις βαθιές τιμές των παραμέτρων ύδατος. Οι ζωτικότητες 
απεικονίζουν την τροχιακή κίνηση των μορίων ύδατος και 
εμφανίζουν διαγώνια τμήματα των κυμάτων στα ποικίλα βάθη. 
Αυτά τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς είναι κατάλληλα για τη χρήση
στις διαλέξεις, τα εργαστήρια, ή άλλες δραστηριότητες 
διδασκαλίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las características de este sitio contellean las 
animaciones y una película de QuickTime que ilustran cómo las ondas 
y las moléculas de agua se comportan a lo largo de la orilla y en 
configuraciones profundas del agua. Las animaciones representan 
el movimiento orbital de las moléculas de agua y muestran secciones 
transversales de ondas en las profundidades que varían. Estos 
recursos son convenientes para el uso en conferencias, laboratorios, u
otras actividades de enseñanza.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200940</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108389</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/coastal-wave-mechanics</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
