<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107718</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107718</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086754</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Politics Is a Pretty Personal Thing with Women": A 1950s Look at the Impact of Women Voters</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Politik ist eine hübsche persönliche Sache mit 
Frauen": Betrachten fünfziger Jahre die Auswirkung der 
Frau-Wähler</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">la "politique est une jolie chose personnelle avec
des femmes" : Les années 50 regardent l'impact des électrices 
de femmes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">a "política é uma coisa pessoal bonita com 
mulheres": Os 1950s olham o impacto de eleitores das mulheres</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la politica è una cosa personale graziosa con le
donne": Gli anni 50 guardano l'effetto degli elettori delle 
donne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η πολιτική είναι ένα αρκετά προσωπικό πράγμα με τις
γυναίκεσ": Η δεκαετία του '50 εξετάζει τον αντίκτυπο των 
ψηφοφόρων γυναικών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">la "política es una cosa personal bonita con las 
mujeres": Los años 50 miran el impacto de los votantes de las 
mujeres</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">When women first voted in national elections following ratification of the 19th Amendment in 1920, participants in the women's movement and others predicted that women voters would be an important factor in a shift toward increased social legislation and anti-corruption in politics. An estimated one-third of the eligible female voters actually voted in 1920, compared to two-thirds of eligible male voters. Women's impact on national elections was not felt to a significant degree until the 1952 election, when the proportion of women voting for Dwight D. Eisenhower was six percent higher than the percentage the candidate pulled among men. Before the 1956 presidential election, the popular magazine  Collier's  sent writer Walter Davenport to bipartisan Marion Country, Indiana, to survey women's attitudes on candidates and issues. Many of the women whose views Davenport included in the resultant article refuted accepted beliefs of seasoned male politicians. Their paraphrased opinions, however, also employed essentialist gender stereotypes of the time--that "women are all house cleaners at heart" and that "a woman lacks the administrative qualities of a man"--to explain perceived voting tendencies. Davenport's findings ignored factors that social scientists have considered to be important in accounting for voting patterns, such as education, income level, age, and race. He did, however, report the opinion of two female teachers that the formation of women's groups during and since World War II--when more women joined the workforce--had resulted in increased political consciousness among women, an opinion that scholars have since found valid. Although by the 1964 election, more women were voting than men, a viable national female voting bloc has not surfaced in the U.S.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Als Frauen zuerst in den nationalen Wahlen nach 
Bestätigung der 19. Änderung 1920 wählten, sagten Teilnehmer an die
Bewegung der Frauen und andere voraus, daß Frauwähler ein wichtiger 
Faktor in einer Schicht in Richtung zu erhöhter Sozialgesetzgebung 
und in der Anti-Korruption in der Politik sein würden. 
Geschätztes Drittel der geeigneten weiblichen Wähler wählte 
wirklich 1920, verglichen bis zweidrittel von geeigneten männlichen 
Wählern. Auswirkung der Frauen auf nationale Wahlen wurde nicht
zu einem bedeutenden Grad bis die Wahl 1952 geglaubt, als der Anteil 
den Frauen, die für Dwight D. Eisenhower wählen, sechs Prozent 
höher war, als der Prozentsatz der Anwärter unter Männern zog. 
Vor der Präsidentenwahl 1956, dem populären Zeitschrift 
Colliers geschickt Verfasser Walter Davenport nach zwei Parteien 
zugehöriges Marion Land, Indiana, Haltung der Frauen auf Anwärtern 
und Ausgaben überblicken. Viele der Frauen deren Ansichten 
Davenport im resultierenden Artikel einschloß, widerlegten geltenden 
Glauben der reifen männlichen Politiker. Ihre paraphrasierten 
Meinungen jedoch setzten auch essentialist Geschlechtstereotypen der 
Zeit -- die "Frauen alle Hausreinigungsmittel am Inneren" sind und die
"eine Frau die administrativen Qualitäten eines Mannes" ermangelt -- 
wahrgenommene wählende Tendenzen zu erklären ein. Entdeckungen
Davenports ignorierten Faktoren, die Sozialwissenschaftler betrachtet 
haben, in der Buchhaltung für wählende Muster, wie Ausbildung, 
Einkommensniveau, Alter und Rennen wichtig zu sein. Er 
berichtete jedoch über die Meinung von zwei weiblichen Lehrern, deren
die Anordnung der Gruppen der Frauen während und seit dem Zweiten 
Weltkrieg -- als mehr Frauen die Mannschaft verbanden -- erhöhtes 
politisches Bewußtsein unter Frauen ergeben hatte, eine Meinung, daß
Gelehrte haben, seit gefunden gültig. Obgleich durch die Wahl 
1964, wählten mehr Frauen, als Männer, ein entwicklungsfähiger 
nationaler weiblicher wählender Block nicht in die US aufgetaucht 
ist.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Quand les femmes ont voté la première fois dans 
des élections nationales après la ratification du 19ème amendement 
en 1920, les participants au mouvement des femmes et d'autres ont 
prévu que les électeurs de femmes seraient un facteur important dans
un décalage vers la législation sociale accrue et l'anti-corruption 
dans la politique. Un un tiers environ des électeurs féminins 
éligibles a voté réellement en 1920, comparé à deux-tiers 
d'électeurs mâles éligibles. L'impact des femmes sur des 
élections nationales n'a pas été senti à un degré significatif 
jusqu'à l'élection 1952, quand la proportion de femmes votant pour 
Dwight D. Eisenhower était six pour cent plus de haut que le 
pourcentage le candidat a tiré parmi les hommes. Avant 
l'élection 1956 présidentielle, le magasin populaire Collier 
envoyé auteur Walter Davenport le pays, en Indiana bipartis de 
Marion, pour examiner les attitudes des femmes sur des candidats et 
des questions. Plusieurs des femmes dont les vues Davenport a 
incluses dans l'article résultant ont réfuté la croyance reçue des
politiciens mâles chevronnés. Leurs avis paraphrasés, 
cependant, ont également utilisé des stéréotypes de genre 
d'essentialist de l'heure -- que les "femmes sont tous les décapants 
de maison au coeur" et que "une femme manque des qualités 
administratives d'un homme" -- d'expliquer des tendances de vote 
perçues. Les résultats de Davenport ont ignoré les facteurs 
que les sociologues ont considérés comme importants dans la 
comptabilité pour les configurations de vote, telles que 
l'éducation, le niveau de revenu, l'âge, et la course. Il, 
cependant, a enregistré l'opinion de deux professeurs féminins 
pendant lesquels la formation des groupes des femmes et depuis la 
deuxième guerre mondiale -- quand plus de femmes ont joint la main 
d'oeuvre -- avait eu comme conséquence la conscience politique accrue
parmi des femmes, une opinion que les disciples ont depuis lors 
trouvé valide. Bien que par l'élection 1964, plus de femmes 
votaient que les hommes, un bloc de vote femelle national viable n'a 
pas apprêté aux États-Unis.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quando as mulheres votaram primeiramente em 
eleições nacionais depois do ratification da 19a emenda em 1920, os 
participants no movimento das mulheres e outros predisseram que os 
eleitores das mulheres seriam um fator importante em uma SHIFT para a 
legislação social aumentada e no anti-anti-corruption na política. 
Uns um terço estimado dos eleitores fêmeas elegíveis votaram 
realmente em 1920, comparado a dois terços de eleitores masculinos 
elegíveis. O impacto das mulheres em eleições nacionais não 
foi sentido a um grau significativo até a eleição 1952, quando a 
proporção das mulheres que votam para Dwight D. Eisenhower era seis 
por cento mais elevada do que a porcentagem o candidato puxou entre 
homens. Antes da eleição 1956 presidencial, do collier popular
do compartimento emitidos escritor Walter Davenport ao país, a 
Indiana bipartisan de Marion, para examinar atitudes das mulheres em 
candidatos e em edições. Muitas das mulheres cujas vistas 
Davenport incluiu no artigo resultante refuted a opinião aceitada de 
políticos masculinos seasoned. Suas opiniões paraphrased, 
entretanto, empregaram também stereotypes do momento -- que as 
"mulheres são todos os líquidos de limpeza da casa no coração" e 
que "do gender do essentialist uma mulher falta as qualidades 
administrativas de um homem" -- de explicar tendências votando 
percebidas. Os findings de Davenport ignoraram os fatores que os
cientistas sociais consideraram ser importantes na contabilidade para 
testes padrões votando, tais como a instrução, o nível de renda, a
idade, e a raça. , entretanto, relatou a opinião de dois 
professores fêmeas que a formação de grupos das mulheres durante e 
desde a segunda guerra mundial -- quando mais mulheres juntaram o 
workforce -- tinha resultado no consciousness político aumentado 
entre mulheres, uma opinião que os scholars têm desde encontrado 
válido. Embora pela eleição 1964, mais mulheres estavam 
votando do que os homens, um bloc votando fêmea nacional viable não 
aplainaram nos E. U..</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Quando le donne in primo luogo hanno votato nelle 
elezioni nazionali dopo la ratifica della diciannovesima correzione in
1920, i partecipanti al movimento delle donne ed altri hanno predetto 
che gli elettori delle donne sarebbero un fattore importante in uno 
spostamento verso legislazione sociale aumentata e nella 
anti-corruzione nella politica. Un un terzo valutato degli 
elettori femminili eleggibili realmente ha votato in 1920, confrontato
a due terzi degli elettori maschii eleggibili. L'effetto delle 
donne sulle elezioni nazionali non è stato ritenuto ad un grado 
significativo fino all'elezione 1952, quando la percentuale di donne 
che votano per Dwight D. Eisenhower era sei per cento superiore a la 
percentuale il candidato ha tirato fra gli uomini. Prima 
dell'elezione presidenziale 1956, del collier popolare dello scomparto
trasmessi a produttore Walter Davenport il paese, in Indiana 
bipartisan di Marion, esaminare gli atteggiamenti delle donne sui 
candidati e sulle edizioni. Molte delle donne di cui le viste 
Davenport ha incluso nell'articolo risultante hanno confutato la 
credenza accettata dei politici maschii seasoned. I loro pareri 
parafrasati, tuttavia, egualmente hanno impiegato gli stereotipi del 
momento -- che "le donne sono tutti i pulitori della casa a cuore" e 
che "di genere di essentialist una donna difetta delle qualità 
amministrative di un uomo" -- di spiegare le tendenze di voto 
percepite. I risultati de Davenport hanno ignorato i fattori che
i sociologi hanno considerato come importanti nella contabilità per i
modelli di voto, quali formazione, il livello di reddito, l'età e la 
corsa. , tuttavia, ha segnalato l'opinione di due insegnanti 
femminili che la formazione dei gruppi delle donne durante e dalla 
seconda guerra mondiale -- quando più donne hanno unito la mano 
d'opera -- aveva provocato la coscienza politica aumentata fra le 
donne, un'opinione che gli eruditi hanno da allora trovato valido. 
Anche se tramite l'elezione 1964, più donne stavano votando che
gli uomini, un blocco di voto femminile nazionale possibile non è 
emerso negli Stati Uniti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Όταν οι γυναίκες ψήφισαν αρχικά στις εθνικές εκλογές
μετά από την επικύρωση της 19$ης τροποποίησης το 1920, οι 
συμμετέχοντες στο κίνημα των γυναικών και άλλοι πρόβλεψαν ότι οι
ψηφοφόροι γυναικών θα ήταν ένας σημαντικός παράγοντας σε μια 
μετατόπιση προς την αυξανόμενη κοινωνική νομοθεσία και 
αντιδιαβρωτικοί στην πολιτική. Ένα κατ' εκτίμηση ένα τρίτο
των επιλέξιμων θηλυκών ψηφοφόρων ψήφισε πραγματικά το 1920, 
έναντι στα δύο τρίτα των επιλέξιμων αρσενικών ψηφοφόρων. Ο
αντίκτυπος των γυναικών στις εθνικές εκλογές δεν έγινε αισθητός 
σε έναν σημαντικό βαθμό μέχρι την εκλογή του 1952, όταν το 
ποσοστό των γυναικών που ψηφίζουν για Dwight Δ. Eisenhower 
ήταν έξι τοις εκατό υψηλότερο από το ποσοστό που ο υποψήφιος 
τράβηξε μεταξύ των ανδρών. Πριν από την προεδρική εκλογή 
του 1956, ο σταλμένος συγγραφέας walter Ντάβενπορτ του 
δημοφιλούς ανθρακωρύχου περιοδικών στη δικομματική Marion 
Country, Ινδιάνα, για να ερευνήσουν τις τοποθετήσεις των 
γυναικών στους υποψηφίους και τα ζητήματα. Πολλές από τις 
γυναίκες οι των οποίων όψεις Ντάβενπορτ περιέλαβαν στο 
επακόλουθο άρθρο αντέκρουσαν τις αποδεκτές πεποιθήσεις των 
καρυκευμένων αρσενικών πολιτικών. Οι παραφρασμένες απόψεις 
τους, εντούτοις, υιοθέτησαν επίσης τα στερεότυπα γένους 
essentialist του χρόνου -- ότι "οι γυναίκες είναι όλοι οι 
καθαριστές σπιτιών στην καρδιά" και ότι "μια γυναίκα στερείται 
τις διοικητικές ιδιότητες ενός άνδρα" -- να εξηγηθούν οι 
αντιληπτές τάσεις ψηφοφορίας. Τα συμπεράσματα του 
Ντάβενπορτ αγνόησαν τους παράγοντες που οι κοινωνικοί επιστήμονες
έχουν θεωρήσει σημαντικούς να αποτελέσουν την ψηφοφορία των 
προτύπων, όπως η εκπαίδευση, το εισοδηματικό επίπεδο, η ηλικία, 
και η φυλή. , Εντούτοις, εξέθεσε την άποψη δύο θηλυκών 
δασκάλων ότι ο σχηματισμός των ομάδων των γυναικών κατά τη 
διάρκεια και από του παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ -- όταν προσχώρησαν 
περισσότερες γυναίκες στο εργατικό δυναμικό -- είχε οδηγήσει 
στην αυξανόμενη πολιτική συνείδηση μεταξύ των γυναικών, μια 
άποψη που οι μελετητές έχουν βρεί από τότε έγκυρη. Αν και
από την εκλογή του 1964, περισσότερες γυναίκες ψήφιζαν από οι
άνδρες, μια βιώσιμη εθνική θηλυκή ομάδα ψηφοφορίας δεν έχουν 
εμφανιστεί στις ΗΠΑ</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cuando las mujeres primero votaron en elecciones 
nacionales después de la ratificación de la diecinueveavo enmienda 
en 1920, los participantes en el movimiento de las mujeres y otros 
predijeron que los votantes de las mujeres serían un factor 
importante en una rotación hacia la legislación social creciente y 
la contra-corrupcio'n en política. Un una mitad estimado de los
votantes femeninos elegibles votó realmente en 1920, comparado a dos 
tercios de votantes masculinos elegibles. El impacto de las 
mujeres en elecciones nacionales no era sentido a un grado 
significativo hasta la elección 1952, cuando la proporción de 
mujeres que votaban por Dwight D. Eisenhower era seis por ciento más 
alta que el porcentaje el candidato tiró entre hombres. Antes 
de la elección presidencial 1956, del collier popular del 
compartimiento enviados programa de escritura Walter Davenport al 
país, a Indiana de dos partidos políticos de Marion, examinar las 
actitudes de las mujeres en candidatos y ediciones. Muchas de 
las mujeres que opiniónes Davenport incluyó en el artículo 
resultante refutaron la creencia validada de políticos masculinos 
chevronnés. Sus opiniones parafraseadas, sin embargo, también 
emplearon los estereotipos de la época -- que las "mujeres son todos 
los productos de limpieza de discos de la casa en el corazón" y que 
"del género del essentialist falta una mujer las calidades 
administrativas de un hombre" -- de explicar tendencias de votación 
percibidas. Los resultados de Davenport no hicieron caso de los 
factores que los científicos sociales han considerado ser importantes
en las estadísticas para el nivel del modelo, por ejemplo la 
educación, de ingresos, la edad, y la raza de votación. Él, 
sin embargo, señaló la opinión de dos profesores femeninos durante 
quienes la formación de los grupos de las mujeres y desde la Segunda 
Guerra Mundial -- cuando más mujeres ensamblaron a mano de obra -- 
había dado lugar al sentido político creciente entre mujeres, una 
opinión que los eruditos tienen desde encontrado válido. 
Aunque por la elección 1964, más mujeres votaban que los 
hombres, un bloque de votación femenino nacional viable no han 
emergido en los E.E.U.U..</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086754</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107718</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/politics-is-a-pretty-personal-thing-with-women-a-1950s-look-at-the-impact-of-women-voters</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
