<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108182</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108182</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202552</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Poetry From Prose: A Different Kind of "Book Report"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Poesie Von der Prosa: Eine andere Art 
"Buch-Report"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Poésie de la Prose : Un genre différent 
d'"état de livre"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Poesia Da Prosa: Um tipo diferente do "do 
relatório livro"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Poesia Da Prosa: Un genere differente "di 
rapporto del libro"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ποίηση από την πεζογραφία: Ένα διαφορετικό 
είδος "έκθεσης βιβλίων"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Poesía De la Prosa: Una diversa clase de 
"informe del libro"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Students use a word-processing program to write a poem that summarizes important themes or events central to the plot of a novel. Once the poem is proofread, students type the poem according to specific directions. They then print their work and illustrate over or around the writing for an illustrated "book report." Students incorporate details from the novel in their writing and in their illustrations of their poems. In this way, students focus on the themes or events in the novel that appeal to them most -- the ones they feel are most important to the novel's meaning.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kursteilnehmer verwenden ein 
Textverarbeitungsprogramm, um ein Gedicht zu schreiben, das die 
wichtige Themen oder Fälle zusammenfaßt, die zum Plot eines Romans 
zentral sind. Sobald Gedichtes gelesen wird, schreiben 
Kursteilnehmer das Gedicht anordnungsgemäß spezifische. Sie 
dann drucken ihre Arbeit und veranschaulichen über oder um dem 
Schreiben für einen erläuterten "Buchreport." Kursteilnehmer 
enthalten Details vom Roman in ihrem Schreiben und in ihren 
Abbildungen ihrer Gedichte. Auf diese Art konzentrieren 
Kursteilnehmer auf die Themen oder die Fälle im Roman, die ihnen am 
meisten gefallen -- die, die sie glauben, sind zur Bedeutung des 
Romans am wichtigsten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les étudiants emploient un programme de 
traitement de texte pour écrire une poésie qui récapitule des 
thèmes ou des événements importants centraux au traçage d'un 
roman. Une fois que la poésie est corrigée, les étudiants 
tapent la poésie selon des directions spécifiques. Ils alors 
impriment leur travail et l'illustrent au-dessus ou autour de 
l'écriture pour un "état illustré de livre." Les étudiants 
incorporent des détails du roman dans leur écriture et dans leurs 
illustrations de leurs poésies. De cette façon, les étudiants
se concentrent sur les thèmes ou les événements dans le roman qui 
font appel à eux plus -- celui qu'elles se sentent est le plus 
important pour la signification du roman.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os estudantes usam um programa de processo de 
texto escrever um poema que sumarie os temas ou os eventos importantes
centrais ao lote de uma novela. Uma vez que o poema é 
corrigido, os estudantes datilografam o poema de acordo com sentidos 
específicos. Então imprimem seu trabalho e ilustram-no sobre 
ou em torno da escrita para do "um relatório ilustrado livro." 
Os estudantes incorporam detalhes da novela em sua escrita e em 
suas ilustrações de seus poemas. Nesta maneira, os estudantes 
focalizam nos temas ou nos eventos na novela que lhes apelam mais -- 
esses que sentem são os mais importantes para o meaning da novela.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli allievi usano un programma elaborato a parole 
per scrivere un poem che ricapitola i temi o gli eventi importanti 
centrali al diagramma di un romanzo. Una volta che il poem è 
corretto le bozze di, gli allievi digitano il poem secondo i sensi 
specifici. Allora stampano il loro lavoro ed illustrano sopra o
intorno alla scrittura per "un rapporto illustrato del libro." 
Gli allievi comprendono i particolari dal romanzo nella loro 
scrittura e nelle loro illustrazioni dei loro poems. In questo 
modo, gli allievi mettono a fuoco sui temi o sugli eventi nel romanzo 
che fanno appello a loro più -- quei che ritengano sono più 
importanti al significato del romanzo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι σπουδαστές χρησιμοποιούν ένα πρόγραμμα 
επεξεργασίας κειμένου για να γράψουν ένα ποίημα που συνοψίζει τα
σημαντικά θέματα ή τα γεγονότα κεντρικά στην πλοκή ενός 
μυθιστορήματος. Μόλις διορθωθεί δοκίμια το ποίημα, οι 
σπουδαστές δακτυλογραφούν το ποίημα σύμφωνα με τις συγκεκριμένες 
κατευθύνσεις. Τυπώνουν έπειτα την εργασία τους και 
επεξηγούν πέρα από ή γύρω από το γράψιμο για μια 
διευκρινισμένη "έκθεση βιβλίων." Οι σπουδαστές ενσωματώνουν
τις λεπτομέρειες από το μυθιστόρημα στο γράψιμό τους και στις 
απεικονίσεις ποιημάτων τους τους. Κατ' αυτό τον τρόπο, οι 
σπουδαστές εστιάζουν στα θέματα ή τα γεγονότα στο μυθιστόρημα 
που απευθύνονται σε τα πιό πολύ -- αυτά αισθάνονται ότι είναι ο
σημαντικότερος στην έννοια του μυθιστορήματος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los estudiantes utilizan un programa de proceso de
la palabra para escribir un poema que resuma los temas o los 
acontecimientos importantes centrales al diagrama de una novela. 
Una vez que se corrija el poema, los estudiantes pulsan el poema
según direcciones específicas. Después imprimen su trabajo y 
lo ilustran sobre o alrededor de la escritura para un "informe 
ilustrado del libro." Los estudiantes incorporan los detalles de
la novela en su escritura y en sus ilustraciones de sus poemas. 
De esta manera, los estudiantes se centran en los temas o los 
acontecimientos en la novela que abrogan a ellos más -- los que se 
sienten son los más importantes para el significado de la novela.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:SALLY WATTS
FN:SALLY WATTS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202552</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108182</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/poetry-from-prose-a-different-kind-of-book-report</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
