<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108385</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108385</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086421</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Love and Companionship Came First": Floyd Dell on Modern Marriage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Liebe und Begleitung kamen zuerst": Floyd 
Dell auf moderner Verbindung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">l'"amour et la compagnie sont venus d'abord" : 
Floyd Dell sur le mariage moderne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">o "amor e o companionship vieram primeiramente": 
Floyd Dell na união moderna</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"l'amore ed il companionship sono venuto in primo 
luogo": Floyd Dell sull'unione moderna</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η αγάπη και η συντροφικότητα ήρθαν πρώτα": 
Κοιλάδα Floyd στο σύγχρονο γάμο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">el "amor y el compañerismo vinieron primero": 
Floyd Dell en la unión moderna</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the 1920s, new sexual ideologies reshaped prescriptions for marriage, incorporating moderate versions of feminism. "Modern Marriage," an excerpt from Floyd Dell's  Outline of Marriage  (1926), set out the ideal of companionship between husband and wife. In this mock dialogue, a savvy young wife instructed a professor in the ways of modern marriage. She frankly endorsed birth control, simplified housekeeping, shared housework, and paid work for childless wives. At the same time, Dell's dialogue affirmed a romantic view of fundamental sexual differences. Generically named "The Young Woman," the female character averred that she chose motherhood as "fulfillment of my nature." Circulated by the American Birth Control League, the tract sought to win support for contraception by portraying its place in respectable, if "modern," marriages.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In den zwanziger Jahren gestalteten neue sexuelle 
Ideologien die Verordnungen für Verbindung um und enthielten 
gemäßigte Versionen von Feminismus. "moderne Verbindung," ein 
Excerpt Floyd Dells von der umreiß von Marriage (1926), legte das 
ideale der Begleitung zwischen Ehemann und Frau dar. In diesem 
mock Dialog wies eine savvy junge Frau einen Professor in den Methoden
der modernen Verbindung an. Sie indossierte aufrichtig 
Geburtenkontrolle, vereinfachte Haushaltung, geteilte Hausarbeit und 
gezahlte Arbeit für kinderlose Frauen. Gleichzeitig bestätigte
Dialog Dells eine romantische Ansicht der grundlegenden sexuellen 
Unterschiede. Generisch benannt "die junge Frau," beteuerte das 
weibliche Zeichen, daß sie wählte Mutterschaft als "Erfüllung 
meiner Natur." Verteilt durch die amerikanische 
Geburtenkontrolle-Liga, suchte die Fläche, Support für 
Empfängnisverhütung zu gewinnen, indem sie seinen Platz in 
beachtlichem schilderte, wenn "modern," Verbindungen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans les années 20, les nouvelles idéologies 
sexuelles ont restructuré des prescriptions pour le mariage, 
incorporant des versions modérées du féminisme. "le mariage 
moderne," un extrait de contour de Floyd Dell de Marriage (1926),
a visé l'idéal de la compagnie entre le mari et l'épouse. 
Dans ce faux dialogue, une jeune épouse savvy a instruit un 
professeur des voies du mariage moderne. Elle a franchement 
approuvé le contrôle des naissances, le ménage simplifié, les 
travaux domestiques partagés, et le travail payé pour les épouses 
sans enfant. En même temps, le dialogue de Dell a affirmé une 
vue romantique des différences sexuelles fondamentales. 
Génériquement nommé "la jeune femme," le caractère femelle a
avéré qu'elle a choisi la maternité en tant que "réalisation de ma
nature." Circulé par la ligue américaine de contrôle des 
naissances, la région a recherché à gagner le soutien de la 
contraception en dépeignant son endroit dans respectable, si 
"moderne," des mariages.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nos 1920s, os ideologies sexual novos reshaped as 
prescrições para a união, incorporando versões moderadas do 
feminismo. "a união moderna," um excerpt do esboço de Floyd 
Dell de União (1926), ajustou-se para fora do ideal do companionship 
entre o marido e a esposa. Neste diálogo mock, uma esposa nova 
savvy instruiu um professor nas maneiras da união moderna. 
Endossou frankly o controle de nascimento, tarefas domésticas 
simplificadas, o housework compartilhado, e o trabalho pago para 
esposas childless. Ao mesmo tempo, o diálogo de Dell afirmou 
uma vista romântica de diferenças sexual fundamentais. Nomeado
genèrica "a mulher nova," o caráter fêmea averred que escolheu o 
motherhood como o "fulfillment de minha natureza." Circulado 
pela liga americana do controle de nascimento, o intervalo procurou 
ganhar a sustentação para o contraception portraying seu lugar em 
respeitável, se "moderno," uniões.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Negli anni 20, le nuove ideologie sessuali hanno 
rimodellato le prescrizioni per l'unione, comprendenti le versioni 
moderate di feminism. "l'unione moderna," un brano dal profilo 
di Floyd Dell di Marriage (1926), ha precisato il ideale di 
companionship fra il marito e la moglie. In questo dialogo 
falso, una moglie giovane savvy ha insegnato ad un professore nei modi
dell'unione moderna. Franco ha firmato il controllo di nascita, 
il governo della casa semplificato, i lavori domestici comuni ed il 
lavoro pagato per le mogli senza figli. Allo stesso tempo, il 
dialogo del Dell ha affermato una vista romantica delle differenze 
sessuali fondamentali. Genericamente chiamato "la donna 
giovane," il carattere femminile averred che ha scelto la maternità 
come "adempimento della mia natura." Circolato dalla lega 
americana di controllo di nascita, il tratto ha cercato di vincere il 
sostegno la contraccezione ritraendo il relativo posto in respectable,
se "moderno," unioni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στη δεκαετία του '20, νέες σεξουαλικές 
αναδιαμορφωμένες ιδεολογίες συνταγές για το γάμο, που ενσωματώνει
τις μέτριες εκδόσεις του φεμινισμού. Ο "σύγχρονος γάμος," 
ένα απόσπασμα από το περίγραμμα της κοιλάδας Floyd του γάμου 
(1926), καθόρισε το ιδανικό της συντροφικότητας μεταξύ του 
συζύγου και της συζύγου. Σε αυτό το πλαστό διαλογικό 
παράθυρο, μια savvy νέα σύζυγος καθοδήγησε έναν καθηγητή με 
τους τρόπους του σύγχρονου γάμου. Επικύρωσε ειλικρινά τον 
έλεγχο γέννησης, απλουστευμένη οικοκυρική, κοινά οικιακά, και 
πλήρωσε την εργασία για τις άτεκνες συζύγους. Συγχρόνως, το
διαλογικό παράθυρο της κοιλάδας βεβαίωσε μια ρομαντική όψη των 
θεμελιωδών σεξουαλικών διαφορών. Γενικά ονόμασε "τη νέα 
γυναίκα," ο θηλυκός χαρακτήρας ότι επέλεξε τη μητρότητα ως 
"εκπλήρωση της φύσης μου." Κυκλοφορημένο από την 
αμερικανική ένωση ελέγχου γέννησης, το κομμάτι επιδίωξε να 
κερδίσει την υποστήριξη για την αντισύλληψη με την απεικόνιση της 
θέσης του σε αξιοσέβαστο, εάν "σύγχρονος," γάμοι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En los años 20, las nuevas ideologías sexuales 
restructuraron las prescripciones para la unión, incorporando 
versiones moderadas del feminismo. la "unión moderna," un 
extracto del contorno de Floyd Dell de Marriage (1926), precisó el 
ideal del compañerismo entre el marido y la esposa. En este 
diálogo falso, una esposa joven lista mandó a un profesor de 
las maneras de la unión moderna. Ella franco endosó control de
la natalidad, operacíones de entretenimiento simplificadas, el 
quehacer doméstico compartido, y el trabajo pagado para las esposas 
sin hijos. En el mismo tiempo, el diálogo de Dell afirmó una 
vista romántica de diferencias sexuales fundamentales. 
Genéricamente nombrado "la mujer joven," el carácter femenino 
averred que ella eligió maternidad como "cumplimiento de mi 
naturaleza." Circulado por la liga americana del control de la 
natalidad, la zona intentó ganar la ayuda para la contracepción 
retratando su lugar en respetable, si "moderno," las uniones.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086421</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108385</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/love-and-companionship-came-first-floyd-dell-on-modern-marriage</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
