<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107215</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107215</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086393</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Lament for "The Lost Pardner"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bejammern Sie für "das verlorene Pardner"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Déplorez "le Pardner perdu"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Lament para "o Pardner perdido"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Deplori "il Pardner perso"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θρηνήστε για "το χαμένο Pardner"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Laméntese para "el Pardner perdido"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Although absent from Hollywood portrayals of the old West, homosexuality was surely a feature of life on the frontier. "The West," observe John D'Emilio and Estelle Freedman in their history of sexuality, "provided extensive opportunities for male-male intimacy. Some men were drawn to the frontier because of their attractions to men." Badger Clark was born in 1883 and grew up in Deadwood, South Dakota. His collection of western poems,  Sun and Saddle Leather , was not published until the second decade of the 20th century. But the following verse about "The Lost Pardner" suggests a continuing--but largely forgotten--gay presence in the American West of the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Obgleich von den Hollywood Schilderungen des alten 
Westens, Homosexualität, sicher war ein Merkmal des Lebens auf der 
Grenze abwesend. "der Westen," beobachtet John D'Emilio und 
Estelle Freedman in ihrer Geschichte der Sexualität, "zur 
Verfügung gestellte umfangreiche Gelegenheiten für 
Mann-Mannintimacy. Einige Männer wurden gezeichnet zur Grenze 
wegen ihrer Anziehungen zu den Männern." Dachs Clark wurde 1883
getragen und aufwuchs im Ballast, South Dakota. Seine Ansammlung
westliches Gedichte, Sonne-und Sattel-Leder, wurde nicht bis die 
zweite Dekade des 20. Jahrhunderts veröffentlicht. Aber der 
folgende Vers über "das verlorene Pardner" schlägt eine 
fortfahrende -- aber groß vergessen -- homosexuelle Anwesenheit im 
Amerikaner westlich von dem späten 19. und früh in den zwanzigsten 
Jahrhunderten vor.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bien qu'absent des représentations de Hollywood 
du vieil ouest, homosexualité était sûrement un dispositif de la 
vie sur la frontière. "l'ouest," observent John d'Emilio et le 
freedman d'Estelle dans leur histoire de sexualité, "des moyens 
étendus présentés d'intimité de mâle-mâle. Quelques hommes
ont été dessinés à la frontière en raison de leurs attractions 
aux hommes." La blaireau Clark a été soutenue en 1883 et a 
grandi en bois mort, Dakota du sud. Sa collection de cuir 
occidental de poésies, de soleil et de selle, n'a pas été éditée 
jusque à la deuxième décennie du 20ème siècle. Mais le vers
suivant au sujet "du Pardner perdu" suggère -- mais en grande partie 
oublié -- une présence gaie continue à l'Américain à l'ouest du 
dix-neuvième en retard et tôt aux vingtième siècles.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Embora ausente dos portrayals de Hollywood do oeste
velho, homosexuality era certamente uma característica da vida na 
fronteira. "o oeste," observa John D'Emilio e freedman de 
Estelle em seu history do sexuality, "oportunidades extensivas 
fornecidas para o intimacy do macho-macho. Alguns homens foram 
desenhados à fronteira por causa de suas atrações aos homens." 
O texugo Clark foi carregado em 1883 e cresceu acima no 
deadwood, Dakota sul. Sua coleção do couro ocidental dos 
poemas, do sol e da sela, não foi publicada até a segunda década do
20o século. Mas o seguinte verso sobre "o Pardner perdido" 
sugere -- mas esquecido pela maior parte -- uma presença gay 
continuando no americano ao oeste do décimo nono atrasado e cedo em 
vigésimos séculos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Anche se assente dalle rappresentazioni di 
Hollywood di vecchio ovest, l'omosessualità era certamente una 
caratteristica di vita sulla frontiera. "l'ovest," osserva John 
D'Emilio ed il freedman di Estelle nella loro storia del sexuality, 
"vaste occasioni offerte di intimacy del maschio-maschio. Alcuni
uomini sono stati dissipati alla frontiera a causa delle loro 
attrazioni agli uomini." Il tasso Clark è stato sopportato in 
1883 e si è sviluppato in su in deadwood, il Dakota del Sud. La
sua accumulazione del cuoio occidentale dei poems, del sole e della 
sella, non è stata pubblicata fino alla seconda decade del ventesimo 
secolo. Ma il seguente verse circa "il Pardner perso" suggerisce
-- ma in gran parte dimenticato -- una presenza continua di gay 
nell'americano ad ovest del diciannovesimo ritardato e presto nei 
ventesimi secoli.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αν και απούσα από τις απεικονίσεις Hollywood της 
παλαιάς δύσης, η ομοφυλοφυλία ήταν σίγουρα ένα χαρακτηριστικό 
γνώρισμα της ζωής στα σύνορα. "Η δύση," παρατηρεί John 
D'Emilio και η Estelle Freedman στην ιστορία 
σεξουαλικότητάς τους, "παρείχε τις εκτενείς ευκαιρίες για την 
αρσενικός-αρσενική οικειότητα. Μερικά άτομα σύρθηκαν στα 
σύνορα λόγω της έλξης τους στα άτομα." Ο ασβός clark 
γεννήθηκε το 1883 και μεγάλωσε σε Deadwood, νότια Ντακότα. 
Η συλλογή του δυτικών ποιημάτων, δέρματος ήλιων και σελών,
δεν δημοσιεύθηκε μέχρι τη δεύτερη δεκαετία του 20ού αιώνα. 
Αλλά ο ακόλουθος στίχος για "το χαμένο Pardner" 
προτείνει μια συνεχιμένος -- αλλά κατά ένα μεγάλο μέρος 
ξεχασμένος -- ομοφυλοφιλική παρουσία στον Αμερικανό δυτικά 
πρόσφατου του δέκατου έννατου και τους εικοστούς νωρίς αιώνες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Aunque esta' ausente de las representaciones de 
Hollywood del viejo oeste, homosexualidad estaba seguramente una 
característica de la vida en la frontera. "el oeste," observa a
Juan D'Emilio y a freedman de Estelle en su historia de la sexualidad,
las "oportunidades extensas proporcionadas para la intimidad del 
varo'n-varo'n. Trazaron a algunos hombres a la frontera debido a
sus atracciones a los hombres." El tejón Clark fue llevado en 
1883 y creció para arriba en el deadwood, Dakota del Sur. Su 
colección de cuero occidental de los poemas, del sol y de la montura,
no fue publicada hasta la segunda década del vigésimo siglo. 
Pero el verso siguiente sobre "el Pardner perdido" sugiere -- 
pero olvidado en gran parte -- una presencia de continuación de 
gay en el americano al oeste del último diecinueveavo y temprano
los vigésimos siglos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086393</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107215</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/lament-for-the-lost-pardner</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
