<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107181</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107181</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202728</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">An Introduction to Stanislavski's Method</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Einleitung in eine Methode Stanislavskis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une introduction à la méthode de Stanislavski</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uma introdução ao método de Stanislavski</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un'introduzione al metodo dello Stanislavski</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια εισαγωγή στη μέθοδο Stanislavski</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una introducción al método de Stanislavski</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This lesson plan provides basic guidelines of the Stanislavski system. Exercises are offered to help the student to think creatively and apply this plan to develop their own acting techniques. This plan can be introduced in one class period and practiced throughout the term. Follow these exercises with improvisation. It will help students focus and begin to think on their feet. This plan deals with concentration.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser Lektionplan liefert grundlegende 
Korrekturlinien des Stanislavski Systems. Übungen werden 
angeboten, um dem Kursteilnehmer zu helfen, kreativ zu denken und 
diesen Plan anzuwenden, um ihre eigenen verantwortlichen Techniken zu 
entwickeln. Dieser Plan kann in einer Kategorie Periode 
eingeführt werden und während der Bezeichnung geübt werden. 
Folgen Sie diesen Übungen mit Improvisation. Sie hilft 
Kursteilnehmern zu fokussieren und anzufangen, auf ihren Füßen zu 
denken. Dieser Plan beschäftigt Konzentration.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce plan de leçon fournit les directives de base du
système de Stanislavski. Des exercices sont offerts pour aider 
l'étudiant à penser créativement et à appliquer ce plan pour 
développer leurs propres techniques temporaires. Ce plan peut 
être présenté dans une période de classe et être pratiqué dans 
toute la limite. Suivez ces exercices avec l'improvisation. 
Elle aide des étudiants à se focaliser et commencer à penser 
sur leurs pieds. Ce plan traite la concentration.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta planta da lição fornece guidelines básicos 
do sistema de Stanislavski. Os exercícios são oferecidos 
ajudar ao estudante pensar creativamente e aplicar esta planta para 
desenvolver suas próprias técnicas ativas. Esta planta pode 
ser introduzida em um período da classe e ser praticada durante todo 
o termo. Siga estes exercícios com o improvisation. Ajuda
a estudantes focalizar e começar a pensar em seus pés. Esta 
planta trata da concentração.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo programma di lezione fornisce la guida di 
riferimento di base del sistema di Stanislavski. Le 
esercitazioni sono offerte per aiutare l'allievo a pensare 
creativamente ed applicare questo programma per sviluppare le loro 
proprie tecniche sostitute. Questo programma può essere 
introdotto in un periodo del codice categoria ed esercitarsi in 
durante il termine. Segua queste esercitazioni con 
improvvisazione. Aiuta gli allievi a mettere a fuoco e 
cominciare a pensare sui loro piedi. Questo programma si occupa 
di concentrazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το σχέδιο μαθήματος παρέχει τις βασικές οδηγίες
του συστήματος Stanislavski. Οι ασκήσεις προσφέρονται για 
να βοηθήσουν το σπουδαστή για να σκεφτούν δημιουργικά και να 
εφαρμόσουν αυτό το σχέδιο για να αναπτύξουν τις να ενεργήσουν 
τους τεχνικές. Αυτό το σχέδιο μπορεί να εισαχθεί σε μια 
περίοδο κλάσης και να ασκηθεί σε όλο τον όρο. Ακολουθήστε 
αυτές τις ασκήσεις με τον αυτοσχεδιασμό. Θα βοηθήσει την 
εστίαση σπουδαστών και θα αρχίσει να σκέφτεται στα πόδια τους. 
Αυτό το σχέδιο εξετάζει τη συγκέντρωση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este plan de la lección proporciona a las guías 
de consulta básicas del sistema de Stanislavski. Los ejercicios
se ofrecen para ayudar al estudiante a pensar creativo y a aplicar 
este plan para desarrollar sus propias técnicas temporarias. 
Este plan se puede introducir en un período de la clase y 
practicar a través del término. Siga estos ejercicios con la 
improvisación. Ayuda a estudiantes a enfocarse y a comenzar a 
pensar en sus pies. Este plan se ocupa de la concentración.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JO ANN TAYLOR
FN:JO ANN TAYLOR
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202728</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107181</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/an-introduction-to-stanislavskis-method</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
