<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105388</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105388</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086420</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Losing the Business: The Donners Recall the Great Depression</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Verlieren des Geschäfts: Der Donners 
Rückruf der große Tiefstand</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Destruction des affaires : Le rappel de 
Donners la grande dépression</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Perdendo o negócio: A recordação de 
Donners o depression grande</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Perdere commercio: Il richiamo di Donners la
depressione grande</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Απώλεια της επιχείρησης: Το Donners 
υπενθυμίζει τη μεγάλη οικονομική κρίση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Perder el negocio: Memoria de Donners la 
gran depresión</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Created in 1935, the Works Progress Administration (WPA) provided hope and employment for millions of unemployed workers and studied the human toll of the depression. One such study--a series of WPA-conducted interviews with Dubuque, Iowa families--found that middle-class Americans particularly felt the sting and shame of unemployment caused by the depression. In this interview, the Donners discussed the closing of their family-owned printing business in Chicago during tough times. Returning to live with Mrs. Donner's family in Dubuque in 1934, Mr. Donner remained unemployed for over a year before landing a job as a timekeeper on a WPA project, earning less than one-third his previous income.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erstellt 1935, stellte die Arbeiten 
Fortschritt-Leitung (WPA) Hoffnung und Beschäftigung für Millionen 
der arbeitslosen Arbeiter zur Verfügung und studierte die menschliche
Abgabe des Tiefstands. Eine solche Studie -- eine Reihe 
WPA-geleitete Interviews mit Dubuque, Iowa Familien -- gefunden, daß 
Mittelklasseamerikaner besonders dem Stich und der Schande 
der Arbeitslosigkeit glaubten, verursachte durch den Tiefstand. 
In diesem Interview behandelte das Donners das Schließen ihres 
Familie besessenen druckengeschäfts in Chicago während der haltbaren
Zeiten. Vor der Landung eines Jobs das Zurückbringen, um mit 
Familie der Mrs Donners in Dubuque 1934, Herr Donner zu leben blieb 
für über ein Jahr, wie ein timekeeper auf einem WPA Projekt 
arbeitslos und weniger als Drittel sein vorhergehendes Einkommen 
erwarb.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Créé en 1935, la gestion d'avancement de travaux
(WPA) a fourni l'espoir et l'emploi pour des millions d'ouvriers sans 
emploi et a étudié le péage humain de la dépression. Une 
telle étude -- une série d'entrevues WPA-conduites avec Dubuque, 
familles de l'Iowa -- constatée que les Américains de classe moyenne
ont en particulier senti la piqûre et la honte du chômage a causé 
par la dépression. Dans cette entrevue, le Donners a discuté 
la fermeture de leurs affaires d'impression possédées par famille 
Chicago pendant des moments difficiles. Le renvoi pour vivre 
avec la famille de Mme Donner's dans Dubuque en 1934, M. Donner est 
resté sans emploi pendant plus d'une année avant de débarquer un 
travail comme un timekeeper sur un projet de WPA, gagnant moins d'un 
tiers de son revenu précédent.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Criado em 1935, a administração do progresso de 
trabalhos (WPA) forneceu a esperança e o emprego para milhões de 
trabalhadores unemployed e estudou o pedágio humano do depression. 
Um tal estudo -- uma série de entrevistas WPA-conduzidas com 
Dubuque, famílias de Iowa -- encontrado que os americanos do 
middle-class sentiram particularmente o sting e o shame do desemprego 
causou pelo depression. Nesta entrevista, o Donners discutiu o 
fechamento de seu negócio imprimindo possuído família em Chicago 
durante épocas resistentes. Retornar para viver com a família 
em Dubuque em 1934, Sr. Donner da Sra. Donner remanesceu unemployed 
por sobre um ano antes de aterrar um trabalho como um timekeeper em um
projeto de WPA, ganhando menos de um terço da sua renda precedente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Creato in 1935, la gestione di progresso degli 
impianti (WPA) ha fornito la speranza e l'occupazione per milioni di 
operai disoccupati ed ha studiato il tributo umano della depressione. 
Uno tale studio -- una serie di interviste WPA-condotte con 
Dubuque, famiglie dello Iowa -- trovato che gli Americani della classe
media hanno ritenuto specialmente lo sting e la vergogna di 
disoccupazione ha causato dalla depressione. In questa 
intervista, il Donners ha discusso la chiusura del loro commercio di 
stampa posseduto famiglia in Chicago durante i periodi duri. Il 
ritorno per vivere con la famiglia in Dubuque in 1934, il sig. Donner 
della sig.ra Donner è rimasto disoccupato per in un anno prima 
dell'atterraggio del lavoro come un timekeeper su un progetto di WPA, 
guadagnando più meno d'un terzo del suo reddito precedente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δημιουργημένη το 1935, η διοίκηση προόδου εργασιών 
(WPA) παρείχε την ελπίδα και την απασχόληση για τα εκατομμύρια 
των άνεργων εργαζομένων και μελέτησε τον ανθρώπινο φόρο της 
κατάθλιψης. Μια τέτοια μελέτη -- μια σειρά ωπα-διευθυνμένων
συνεντεύξεων με Dubuque, οικογένειες του Iowa -- διαπίστωσε 
ότι η μεσαία τάξη Αμερικανοί αισθάνθηκε ιδιαίτερα το τσίμπημα 
και την ντροπή της ανεργίας που προκλήθηκαν από την κατάθλιψη. 
Σε αυτήν την συνέντευξη, το Donners συζήτησε το κλείσιμο 
της οικογένεια-κύριας τυπώνοντας επιχείρησής τους στο Σικάγο 
κατά τη διάρκεια των σκληρών χρόνων. Η επιστροφή για να 
ζήσει με την οικογένεια κας Donner's σε Dubuque το 1934, ο 
κ. Donner παρέμεινε άνεργη για κατά τη διάρκεια ενός έτους 
πρίν προσγειώνεται μια εργασία ως timekeeper σε ένα πρόγραμμα 
WPA, που κερδίζει λιγότερο από το ένα τρίτο το προηγούμενο 
εισόδημά του.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Creado en 1935, la administración del progreso de
trabajos (WPA) proporcionó a esperanza y al empleo para millones de 
trabajadores parados y estudió el peaje humano de la depresión. 
Un tal estudio -- una serie de entrevistas WPA-conducidas con 
Dubuque, familias de Iowa -- encontrado que los americanos de la clase
media sentían determinado la picadura y la vergüenza del desempleo 
causó por la depresión. En esta entrevista, el Donners 
discutió el cierre de su negocio de impresión poseído familia en 
Chicago durante épocas resistentes. El volver para vivir con la
familia en Dubuque en 1934, Sr. Donner de señora Donner seguía 
siendo parado por sobre un año antes de aterrizar un trabajo como un 
timekeeper en un proyecto de WPA, ganando menos de una mitad de su 
renta anterior.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086420</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105388</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/losing-the-business-the-donners-recall-the-great-depression</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
