<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103995</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103995</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206755</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Adventures in the Past</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Abenteuer in der Vergangenheit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Aventures dans le passé</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Aventuras no passado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Avventure nel passato</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Περιπέτειες στο παρελθόν</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Aventuras en el pasado</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">provides lessons, activities, and articles for teaching about history, archeology, and paleontology in North America. Learn about railroads, the Gold Rush, Oregon Trail, evergreen forests, caves, fossils, the Colorado Plateau ecosystem, early explorers, Puebloan (Anasazi) farmers, and more. Discover how archaeologists piece together clues to understand the past. Find out how to build a steam engine.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt Lektionen, Aktivitäten und Artikel für 
das Unterrichten über Geschichte, Archäologie und Paläontologie in 
Nordamerika zur Verfügung. Erlernen Sie über Eisenbahnen, die 
Goldanstürme, die Oregon Spur, die immergrünen Wälder, die Höhlen,
die Fossilien, das Kolorado Hochebeneoekosystem, die frühen Forscher,
Puebloan (Anasazi) die Landwirte und mehr. Entdecken Sie, wie 
Archäologen Anhaltspunkte zusammenstellen, um die Vergangenheit zu 
verstehen. Finden Sie heraus, wie man eine Dampfmaschine 
aufbaut.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fournit des leçons, des activités, et des 
articles pour enseigner au sujet de l'histoire, de l'archéologie, et 
de la paléontologie en Amérique du nord. Renseignez-vous 
sur des chemins de fer, les précipitations d'or, la traînée de 
l'Orégon, les forêts à feuilles persistantes, les cavernes, les 
fossiles, l'écosystème de plateau du Colorado, de premiers 
explorateurs, fermiers de Puebloan (Anasazi), et plus. 
Découvrez comment les archéologues rassemblent des indices 
pour comprendre le passé. Découvrez comment construire un 
moteur de vapeur.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fornece lições, atividades, e artigos ensinando 
sobre o history, o archeology, e o paleontology em America do Norte. 
Aprenda sobre estradas de ferro, as arremetidas do ouro, a fuga 
de Oregon, florestas evergreen, cavernas, fossils, o ecosystem do 
platô de Colorado, exploradores adiantados, fazendeiros de Puebloan 
(Anasazi), e mais. Descubra como os arqueólogos remendam junto 
os indícios para compreender o passado. Encontre para fora como
construir um motor de vapor.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fornisce le lezioni, le attività e gli articoli 
per l'istruzione circa la storia, l'archeologia e la paleontologia in 
America del Nord. Impari circa le ferrovie, gli sbalzi dell'oro,
la traccia dell'Oregon, le foreste evergreen, le caverne, i fossili, 
l'ecosistema del plateau del Colorado, gli esploratori in anticipo, i 
coltivatori di Puebloan (Anasazi) e più. Scopra come gli 
archeologhi radunano gli indizii per capire l'esperienza. Scopra
come costruire un motore a vapore.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρέχει τα μαθήματα, τις δραστηριότητες, και τα άρθρα 
για τη διδασκαλία για την ιστορία, την αρχαιολογία, και την 
παλαιοντολογία στη Βόρεια Αμερική. Μάθετε για τους 
σιδηροδρόμους, τη χρυσή βιασύνη, το ίχνος του Όρεγκον, τα 
αειθαλή δάση, τις σπηλιές, τα απολιθώματα, το οικοσύστημα 
οροπέδιων του Κολοράντο, τους πρώτους εξερευνητές, (Anasazi) 
τους αγρότες Puebloan, και περισσότερους. Ανακαλύψτε πώς 
οι αρχαιολόγοι συναρμολογούν τις ενδείξεις για να καταλάβουν το 
παρελθόν. Ανακαλύψτε πώς να χτίσει μια μηχανή ατμού.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">proporciona a lecciones, a actividades, y a los 
artículos para enseñar sobre historia, arqueología, y 
paleontología en Norteamérica. Aprenda sobre los 
ferrocarriles, las acometidas del oro, el rastro de Oregon, bosques 
imperecederos, cuevas, fósiles, el ecosistema de la meseta de 
Colorado, exploradores tempranos, los granjeros de Puebloan (Anasazi),
y más. Descubra cómo los arqueólogos ensamblan pistas para 
entender el pasado. Descubra cómo construir un motor de vapor.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206755</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103995</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/adventures-in-the-past</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
