<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104193</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104193</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086815</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Seven All Together Went Down": A Family Disappears in the 1927 Mississippi Flood</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Alle Sieben Gingen Zusammen Hinunter": Eine
Familie verschwindet in der Mississippi Flut 1927</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Sept Tous Sont ensemble allés En bas de" : 
Une famille disparaît dans l'inondation 1927 du Mississippi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Sete Todos Foram Junto Abaixo": Uma 
família desaparece na inundação 1927 de Mississippi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Sette Tutti Sono andato Insieme Giù": Una 
famiglia sparisce nell'inondazione 1927 del Mississippi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Επτά όλοι πήγαν μαζί κάτω από": Μια 
οικογένεια εξαφανίζεται στην πλημμύρα του Μισισιπή του 1927</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Siete Todos Juntos Fueron Abajo de": Una 
familia desaparece en la inundación 1927 de Mississippi</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The history of settlement around the Mississippi River is often depicted as a struggle of humankind against Nature. Yet the very richness and fertility of the soil in the Midwest and South is the direct result of the regular flooding of the Mississippi River and its tributaries. In April 1927, after more than a month of rain, the river overflowed its banks in a flood which inundated more than 16 million acres of land in seven states, destroyed 40,000 buildings, washed away over $100 million in crops, and claimed between 250 and 500 lives. For his book about the flood  Deep_n as it Come , historian Pete Daniel interviewed Herman Caillouet, an Army Corps of Engineers employee who used his twenty-two-foot boat to rescue 175 people stranded by the rising waters. Here Caillouet told of his futile attempt to rescue a family of seven.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Geschichte der Regelung um den Mississippi 
Fluß wird häufig als Kampf der Menschheit gegen Natur bildlich 
dargestellt. Dennoch ist der Reichtum und die Ergiebigkeit des 
Bodens im Mittelwesten und im Süden das direkte Resultat der 
regelmäßigen Überschwemmung des Mississippi Flusses und seiner 
Steuerbaren. Im April 1927, nach mehr als ein Monat des Regens, 
lief der Fluß seine Bänke in einer Flut, die mehr als 16 Million 
Morgen Land in sieben Zuständen überflutete über, zerstört 40.000 
Gebäuden, weg gewaschen über $100 Million in den Getreide, und 
zwischen 250 und 500 Lebensdauern behauptet. Für sein Buch 
über die Flut Deep_n, da sie kommt, interviewte Historiker Peter 
Daniel Herman Caillouet, ein Armee-Korps des Ingenieurangestellten, 
das sein Zwanzig-zwei-Fuß Boot benutzte, um 175 Leute zu retten, die 
durch das Steigen angeschwemmt wurden, wässert. Hier erklärte 
Caillouet von seinem vergeblichen Versuch, eine Familie von sieben zu 
retten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'histoire du règlement autour du fleuve du 
Mississippi est souvent dépeinte comme lutte de l'humanité contre la
nature. Pourtant la richesse et la fertilité mêmes du sol dans
le Midwest et les Sud est le résultat direct de 
l'inondation régulière du fleuve du Mississippi et de ses 
tributaires. En avril 1927, après plus qu'un mois de pluie, le 
fleuve a débordé ses banques dans une inondation qui a inondé plus 
de 16 millions d'acres de terre dans sept états, détruite 40.000 
bâtiments, enlevée plus de $100 millions dans les collectes, et 
réclamée entre les 250 et 500 vies. Pour son livre concernant 
l'inondation Deep_n car elle viennent, l'historien Peter Daniel a 
interviewé Herman Caillouet, des corps d'armée d'employé 
d'ingénieurs qui ont utilisé son bateau de vingt-deux-pied pour 
sauver 175 personnes échouées par se lever arrosent. Ici 
Caillouet a raconté sa tentative futile de sauver une famille de 
sept.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O history do estabelecimento em torno do rio de 
Mississippi é descrito frequentemente como um esforço do humankind 
de encontro à natureza. Contudo o richness e a fertilidade very
do solo no Midwest e no sul são o resultado direto do flooding 
regular do rio de Mississippi e de seus tributários. Em abril 
1927, após mais do que um mês da chuva, o rio transbordou seus 
bancos em uma inundação que inundated mais de 16 milhão acres da 
terra em sete estados, destruída 40.000 edifícios, lavada afastado 
sobre $100 milhões nas colheitas, e reivindicada entre 250 e 500 
vidas. Para seu livro sobre a inundação Deep_n porque vem, o 
historian Pete Daniel entrevistou Herman Caillouet, um corpo da armada
do empregado dos coordenadores que usasse seu barco de vinte-dois-pé 
salvar 175 povos encalhados se levantar molhasse. Aqui Caillouet
disse de sua tentativa futile de salvar uma família de sete.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La storia dello stabilimento intorno al fiume del 
Mississippi è descritta spesso come lotta di humankind contro la 
natura. Tuttavia la ricchezza e la fertilità stesse del terreno
nel Midwest e nel sud è il risultato diretto del flooding normale del
fiume del Mississippi e dei relativi tributari. Nel mese di 
aprile del 1927, dopo più di un mese di pioggia, il fiume ha 
traboccato la relativa banca in un inondazione che inundated 
più di 16 milione acri di terra in sette dichiara, 
distrutto 40.000 costruzioni, lavato via oltre $100 milioni nei
raccolti ed esatto fra 250 e 500 vite. Per il suo libro 
sull'inondazione Deep_n poichè viene, lo storico Pete Daniel ha 
intervistato Herman Caillouet, Corpo dell'esercito 
dell'impiegato degli assistenti tecnici che ha utilizzato la sua barca
del venti-due-piede per salvare 175 genti incagliate dall'aumentare 
innaffia. Qui Caillouet ha detto a del suo tentativo inutile di 
salvare una famiglia di sette.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ιστορία της τακτοποίησης γύρω από τον ποταμό του 
Μισισιπή απεικονίζεται συχνά ως προσπάθεια της ανθρωπότητας 
ενάντια στη φύση. Ακόμα η ίδιες οι αφθονία και η 
γονιμότητα του χώματος midwest και το νότο είναι το άμεσο 
αποτέλεσμα της κανονικής πλημμύρας του ποταμού του Μισισιπή και 
των παραπόταμών της. Τον Απρίλιο του 1927, μετά από 
έναν περισσότερο από μήνα της βροχής, ο ποταμός ξεχείλισε τις 
τράπεζές του σε μια πλημμύρα που πλημμύρισε περισσότερα από 
16 εκατομμύριο στρέμματα του εδάφους σε επτά κράτη, που 
καταστράφηκαν 40.000 κτήρια, που πλύθηκαν μακριά πάνω από 
$100 εκατομμύρια στις συγκομιδές, και που απαιτήθηκαν μεταξύ 
250 και 500 ζωών. Για το βιβλίο του για την πλημμύρα 
Deep_n καθώς έρχεται, ο ιστορικός pete Daniel πήρε 
συνέντευξη από το Herman Caillouet, ένας στρατός Σώμα 
του υπαλλήλου μηχανικών που χρησιμοποίησε τη βάρκα 
είκοσι-δύο-ποδιών του για να διασώσει 175 ανθρώπους από τα 
που προσάραξαν ύδατα αύξησης. Εδώ Caillouet που λέεται 
της ανώφελης προσπάθειάς του να διασώσει μια οικογένεια επτά.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La historia del establecimiento alrededor del río
de Mississippi se representa a menudo como lucha del humankind contra 
la naturaleza. Con todo la mismas riqueza y fertilidad del suelo
en el Cercano oeste y el sur es el resultado directo del flooding 
regular del río de Mississippi y de sus tributarios. En abril 
de 1927, después más que un mes de la lluvia, el río desbordó sus 
baterías en una inundación que inundated más de 16 millones de 
acres de pista en siete estados, destruida 40.000 edificios, lavada 
lejos sobre $100 millones en cosechas, y demandada entre 250 y 500 
vidas. Para su libro acerca de la inundación Deep_n como viene,
el historiador Pete Daniel se entrevistó con Herman Caillouet, cuerpo
de ejército del empleado de los ingenieros que utilizó su barco del 
veinte-dos-pie para rescatar a 175 personas trenzadas por el 
levantamiento riega. Aquí Caillouet dijo de su tentativa vana 
de rescatar una familia de siete.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086815</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104193</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/seven-all-together-went-down-a-family-disappears-in-the-1927-mississippi-flood</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
