<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108238</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108238</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086850</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Starving for Women's Suffrage: "I Am Not Strong after These Weeks"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Verhungern für Stimmrecht der Frauen: "ich 
bin nicht nach diesen Wochen stark"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mourir de faim pour le suffrage des femmes : 
"je ne suis pas fort après ces semaines"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Starving para o suffrage das mulheres: "eu 
não sou forte após estas semanas"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Starving per il suffrage delle donne: "non 
sono forte dopo queste settimane"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Να λιμοκτονήσει για την ψήφο των γυναικών: "Δεν 
είμαι ισχυρός μετά από αυτές τις εβδομάδεσ"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El morir de hambre para el sufragio de las 
mujeres: "no soy fuerte después de estas semanas"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Members of the National Woman's Party (NWP) took some of the most militant actions in the struggle for suffrage in the early 20th century. NWP members who had been imprisoned in the Occoquan Workhouse went on a hunger strike to draw international attention to their cause. Prison authorities responded with brutal force feedings. The excerpt included here, from the clandestine prison diary of NWP member Rose Winslow, described the rigors of that experience. Born in Poland, Rose Winslow (her given name was Ruza Wenclawska) started working in a Pennsylvania textile mill at age eleven, quitting eight years later when she developed tuberculosis.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bauteile der nationalen Partei der Frau 
(NWP) ergriffen einige der militantesten Maßnahmen im Kampf für 
Stimmrecht im frühen 20. Jahrhundert. NWP Bauteile, die im 
Occoquan Workhouse eingesperrt worden waren, fuhren einen Hungerstreik
fort, internationale Aufmerksamkeit auf ihre Ursache zu lenken. 
Gefängnisbehörden reagierten mit brutalen Kraftzuführungen. 
Das Excerpt, das hier, vom heimlichen Gefängnistagebuch des NWP
Bauteiles Rose Winslow eingeschlossen war, beschrieb die Härte dieser
Erfahrung. Getragen in Polen, fing Rose Winslow (ihr gegebener 
Name war Ruza Wenclawska) an, in einem Pennsylvania Textiltausendstel 
am Alter elf zu arbeiten und beendete acht Jahre später, als sie 
Tuberkulose entwickelte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les membres de la partie de la femme nationale 
(NWP) ont pris certaines des mesures les plus militantes dans la 
lutte pour le suffrage en début du 20ème siècle. Les membres 
de NWP qui avaient été emprisonnés dans l'Occoquan Workhouse ont 
fait une grève de faim pour appeler l'attention internationale sur 
leur cause. Les autorités de prison ont répondu avec des 
alimentations brutales de force. L'extrait inclus ici, de 
l'agenda clandestin de prison du membre Rose Winslow de NWP, a décrit
les rigueurs de cette expérience. Soutenu en Pologne, Rose 
Winslow (son nom donné était Ruza Wenclawska) a commencé à 
travailler dans un moulin de textile de la Pennsylvanie à l'âge 
onze, quittant huit ans après quand elle a développé la 
tuberculose.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os membros do partido da mulher nacional (NWP) 
fizeram exame de algumas das ações as mais militant no esforço para
o suffrage no 20o século adiantado. Os membros de NWP que 
imprisoned no Occoquan Workhouse foram em uma batida de fome desenhar 
a atenção internacional a sua causa. As autoridades da prisão
responderam com feedings brutais da força. O excerpt incluído 
aqui, do diário clandestine da prisão do membro Rosa Winslow de NWP,
descreveu os rigors dessa experiência. Carregado em Poland, 
Rosa Winslow (seu nome dado era Ruza Wenclawska) começou trabalhar em
um moinho de textile de Pensilvânia na idade onze, parando oito anos 
mais tarde quando desenvolveu o tuberculosis.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I membri del partito della donna nazionale (NWP) 
hanno intrapreso alcune della maggior parte delle azioni del 
militante nella lotta per suffrage nell'inizio del 20esimo secolo. 
I membri di NWP che erano stati incarcerati nel Occoquan 
Workhouse sono andato su un colpo di fame attirare l'attenzione 
internazionale sulla loro causa. Le autorità della prigione 
hanno risposto con le alimentazioni brutali della forza. Il 
brano incluso qui, dal diario clandestino della prigione del membro 
Rosa Winslow di NWP, ha descritto i rigori di quell'esperienza. 
Sopportato in Polonia, Rosa Winslow (il suo dato nome era Ruza 
Wenclawska) ha cominciato lavorare in un laminatoio della tessile 
della Pensilvania all'età undici, rinunciante otto anni più 
successivamente quando ha sviluppato la tubercolosi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα μέλη του συμβαλλόμενου μέρους της εθνικής γυναίκας
(NWP) έλαβαν μερικά από πιό στρατευμένα μέτρα στην 
προσπάθεια για την ψήφο στις αρχές του 20ού αιώνα. Τα μέλη
NWP που ήταν φυλακισμένων στο πτωχοκομείο Occoquan πήγαν σε 
μια απεργία πείνας να επιστήσουν τη διεθνή προσοχή στην αιτία 
τους. Οι αρχές φυλακών αποκρίθηκαν με τις βάναυσες 
τροφοδοτήσεις δύναμης. Το απόσπασμα που περιλήφθηκε εδώ, 
από το μυστικό ημερολόγιο φυλακών του μέλους NWP αυξήθηκε 
Winslow, περιέγραψε τις ακαμψίες εκείνης της εμπειρίας. 
Γεννημένος στην Πολωνία, αυξήθηκε Winslow (το δεδομένο 
όνομά της ήταν Ruza Wenclawska) αρχισμένη εργασία σε έναν 
υφαντικό μύλο της Πενσυλβανίας στην ηλικία ένδεκα, 
εγκαταλείποντας οκτώ έτη αργότερα όταν ανέπτυξε τη φυματίωση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los miembros del partido de la mujer nacional 
(NWP) tomaron algunas de las acciones más militantes de la lucha 
para el sufragio en el vigésimo siglo temprano. Los miembros de
NWP que habían sido encarcelados en el Occoquan Workhouse fueron en 
una huelga de hambre a trazar la atención internacional a su causa. 
Las autoridades de la prisión respondieron con alimentaciones 
brutales de la fuerza. El extracto incluido aquí, del diario 
clandestino de la prisión del miembro Rose Winslow de NWP, describió
los rigores de esa experiencia. Llevado en Polonia, Rose Winslow
(su nombre dado era Ruza Wenclawska) comenzó a trabajar en un molino 
del textil de Pennsylvania en la edad once, saliendo ocho años más 
tarde cuando ella desarrolló tuberculosis.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086850</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108238</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/starving-for-womens-suffrage-i-am-not-strong-after-these-weeks</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
