<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104155</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104155</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201154</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Cyanobacteria Health Page</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Cyanobacteria Gesundheit Seite</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Page de Santé De Cyanobacteria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Página Da Saúde De Cyanobacteria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Pagina Di Salute Di Cyanobacteria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σελίδα υγείας Cyanobacteria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Paginación De la Salud De Cyanobacteria</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) Health Studies page focuses on cyanobacteria, single-celled organisms thought to be the origin of plants. Cyanobacteria live in fresh, brackish, or marine water and are of concern to the CDC and Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) because some can form harmful blooms that deplete the oxygen and block sunlight that other organisms need to live. They can also produce powerful toxins that affect the brain and liver of animals and humans. This website links to an informational page about cyanobacterial harmful algal blooms (including impact to public health), general information, CDC activities, links to relevant websites, publications, and additional CDC topics.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses paginieren Mitten für der 
Krankheit-Steuer-und Verhinderung-(CDC) Gesundheit Studien Foki auf 
cyanobacteria, die einzelnen-celled organismen, die gedacht werden, um
der Ursprung der Betriebe zu sein. Cyanobacteria, das im 
frischen, unreinen oder Marinewasser Phasen ist und sind von Bedeutung
für der CDC und der Behörde für Umweltschutz (EPA) weil einige 
schädliche Blüte bilden können, die den Sauerstoff verbrauchen und 
Tageslicht blocken, das andere organismen benötigen, um zu leben. 
Sie können leistungsfähige Giftstoffe auch produzieren, die 
das Gehirn und die Leber der Tiere und der Menschen beeinflussen. 
Diese Web site bindet mit einer informatorischen Seite über 
cyanobacterial schädliche Algenblüte (einschließlich Auswirkung zum
öffentlichen Gesundheitswesen), allgemeine Informationen, CDC 
Aktivitäten, Links mit relevanten Web site, Publikationen und 
zusätzliche CDC Themen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce les centres pour des études de santé de 
commande et d'empêchement de maladie (CDC) paginent des foyers sur le
cyanobacteria, organizations simples-celled pensées pour être 
l'origine des usines. Cyanobacteria de phase dans l'eau 
fraîche, saumâtre, ou marine et sont une préoccupation de la CDC et
de l'agence de protection de l'environnement (EPA) parce que certains 
peuvent former les fleurs nocives qui épuisent l'oxygène et bloquent
la lumière du soleil dont d'autres organizations ont besoin pour 
vivre. Elles peuvent également produire les toxines puissantes 
qui affectent le cerveau et le foie des animaux et des humains. 
Ce site Web joint à une page informationnelle au sujet des 
fleurs d'algues nocives cyanobacterial (impact y compris à la santé 
publique), des informations générales, des activités de CDC, des 
liens aux sites Web appropriés, des publications, et des sujets 
supplémentaires de CDC.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este os centros para estudos da saúde do controle
e da prevenção de doença (CDC) paginam focos no cyanobacteria, 
únicos-celled organismos pensados para ser a origem das plantas. 
Cyanobacteria vivo na água fresca, brackish, ou marinha e é do
interesse ao CDC e à agência de proteção ambiental (EPA) porque 
alguns podem dar forma às flores prejudiciais que esgotam o oxigênio
e obstruem a luz solar que outros organismos necessitam viver. 
Podem também produzir os toxins poderosos que afetam o cérebro
e o fígado dos animais e dos seres humanos. Este Web site liga 
a uma página informativa sobre flores algal prejudiciais 
cyanobacterial (impacto including à saúde pública), a informação 
geral, as atividades do CDC, as ligações aos Web site relevantes, as
publicações, e tópicos adicionais do CDC.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo i centri per gli studi di salute di 
controllo e di prevenzione di malattia (CDC) paginano i fuochi sul 
cyanobacteria, singoli-celled organismi pensati per essere l'origine 
delle piante. Cyanobacteria in tensione in acqua fresca, 
salmastra, o marina ed è di preoccupazione al CDC ed all'ente per la 
salvaguardia dell'ambiente (EPA) perché alcuni possono formare le 
fioriture nocive che esauriscono l'ossigeno ed ostruiscono la luce 
solare di che altri organismi hanno bisogno per vivere. Possono 
anche produrre le tossine potenti che interessano il cervello ed il 
fegato degli animali e degli esseri umani. Questo Web site si 
collega ad una pagina informativa circa le fioriture d'alghe nocive 
cyanobacterial (effetto compreso a sanità pubblica), le generalità, 
le attività di CDC, i collegamenti ai Web site relativi, le 
pubblicazioni ed i soggetti supplementari di CDC.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό στρέφεται για την εστίαση σελίδων μελετών 
υγείας ελέγχου και πρόληψης ασθενειών (CDC) στο 
cyanobacteria, ενιαίος-κυτταρώδεις οργανισμοί πιθανά η 
προέλευση των εγκαταστάσεων. Το Cyanobacteria ζωντανό στο 
φρέσκο, υφαλμυρό, ή θαλάσσιο ύδωρ και είναι υπόθεση του CDC 
και της αντιπροσωπείας προστασίας του περιβάλλοντος (EPA) 
επειδή μερικοί μπορούν να διαμορφώσουν τις επιβλαβείς ανθίσεις 
που μειώνουν το φως του ήλιου οξυγόνου και ομάδων δεδομένων που 
άλλοι οργανισμοί χρειάζονται για να ζήσουν. Μπορούν επίσης
να παραγάγουν τις ισχυρές τοξίνες που έχουν επιπτώσεις στον 
εγκέφαλο και το συκώτι των ζώων και των ανθρώπων. Αυτός ο 
ιστοχώρος συνδέει με μια ενημερωτική σελίδα για τις 
cyanobacterial επιβλαβείς φυκώδεις ανθίσεις 
(συμπεριλαμβανομένου του αντίκτυπου στη δημόσια υγεία), τις 
γενικές πληροφορίες, τις δραστηριότητες CDC, τις συνδέσεις με 
τους σχετικούς ιστοχώρους, τις δημοσιεύσεις, και τα πρόσθετα 
θέματα CDC.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este los centros para los estudios de la salud del
control y de la prevención de la enfermedad (CDC) paginan los focos 
en cyanobacteria, solos-celled organismos pensados para ser el origen 
de plantas. Cyanobacteria vivo en agua fresca, salobre, o marina
y está de preocupación a la CDC y a la agencia de protección del 
medio ambiente (EPA) porque algunos pueden formar las floraciones 
dañosas que agotan el oxígeno y bloquean la luz del sol que otros 
organismos necesitan para vivir. Pueden también producir las 
toxinas de gran alcance que afectan el cerebro y el hígado de 
animales y de seres humanos. Este Web site conecta a una 
paginación informativa sobre las floraciones algal dañosas 
cyanobacterial (impacto incluyendo a la salud pública), la 
información de carácter general, las actividades de la CDC, las 
conexiones a los Web site relevantes, las publicaciones, y los asuntos
adicionales de la CDC.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:NATIONAL CENTER FOR ENVIRONMENTAL HEALTH
FN:NATIONAL CENTER FOR ENVIRONMENTAL HEALTH
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTERS FOR DISEASE CONTROL AND PREVENTION
FN:CENTERS FOR DISEASE CONTROL AND PREVENTION
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201154</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104155</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/cyanobacteria-health-page</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
