<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104915</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104915</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213076</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Water Quality - Total Dissolved Solids</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wasserqualität - Gesamtmenge Aufgelöste Körper</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Qualité De l'eau - Solides Dissous Par Total</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Qualidade De Água - Sólidos Dissolvidos Total</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Qualità Dell'Acqua - Solidi Dissolti Totale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ποιότητα νερού - διαλυμένα σύνολο στερεά</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Calidad Del Agua - Sólidos Disueltos Total</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this activity, students use a microcomputer connected to a conductivity probe to measure the total dissolved solids in local area water samples. Students then compare their measurements with those of others in their class as well as other standard measurements. On this Starting Point page, users can access information about the exercise's learning goals, context for use, teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment ideas, references and topics covered.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In dieser Aktivität benutzen Kursteilnehmer einen
Mikrocomputer, der an eine Leitfähigkeitprüfspitze angeschlossen 
wird, um die aufgelösten Gesamtkörper in den lokalen Bereich 
Wasserproben zu messen. Kursteilnehmer vergleichen dann ihre 
Messen mit denen von anderen in ihrer Kategorie sowie andere 
Standardmessen. Auf dieser Ausgangspunktseite können Benutzer 
auf Informationen über die erlernenziele der Übung, Kontext für 
Gebrauch-, die Unterrichtenumfaßten anmerkungen und Spitzen, 
Lehrmittel, Einschätzung Ideen, Referenzen und Themen zugreifen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cette activité, les étudiants utilisent un 
micro-ordinateur relié à une sonde de conductivité pour mesurer 
tous les solides dissous dans les échantillons d'eau locaux de zone. 
Les étudiants comparent alors leurs mesures à ceux de d'autres
dans leur classe aussi bien que d'autres mesures standard. À 
cette page de point de départ, les utilisateurs peuvent accéder aux 
informations sur les buts d'étude de l'exercice, contexte pour les 
extrémités d'utilisation, d'enseignement les notes et, le matériel 
didactique, les idées d'évaluation, les références et les sujets 
couverts.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta atividade, os estudantes usam um 
microcomputer conectado a uma ponta de prova do conductivity para 
medir os sólidos dissolvidos totais em amostras de água locais da 
área. Os estudantes comparam então suas medidas com as aquelas
de outras em sua classe as.well.as outras medidas padrão. Nesta
página do ponto começar, os usuários podem alcançar a informação
sobre os objetivos de aprendizagem do exercício, contexto para as 
pontas do uso, ensinar as notas e, os materiais de ensino, as idéias 
da avaliação, as referências e os tópicos cobertos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questa attività, gli allievi utilizzano un 
microcomputer collegato ad una sonda di conducibilità per misurare i 
solidi dissolti totali nei campioni di acqua locali di zona. Gli
allievi allora paragonano le loro misure a quelle di altre nel loro 
codice categoria così come altre misure standard. A questa 
pagina del punto di partenza, gli utenti possono accedere alle 
informazioni sugli obiettivi imparanti dell'esercitazione, contesto 
per le punte di istruzione, di uso note e, i materiali didattici, le 
idee di valutazione, i riferimenti ed i soggetti coperti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτήν την δραστηριότητα, οι σπουδαστές 
χρησιμοποιούν έναν μικροϋπολογιστή που συνδέεται με έναν έλεγχο
αγωγιμότητας για να μετρήσει τα συνολικά διαλυμένα στερεά στις 
τοπικές δειγματοληψίες ύδατος περιοχής. Οι σπουδαστές 
συγκρίνουν έπειτα τις μετρήσεις τους με εκείνους άλλοι στην 
κλάση τους καθώς επίσης και άλλες πρότυπες μετρήσεις. Σε 
αυτήν την σελίδα αφετηρίας, οι χρήστες μπορούν να έχουν 
πρόσβαση στις πληροφορίες για τους στόχους εκμάθησης της άσκησης,
πλαίσιο για τη χρήση, τις σημειώσεις και τις άκρες διδασκαλίας, 
τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, τις ιδέες αξιολόγησης, τις αναφορές και τα
θέματα που καλύπτονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta actividad, los estudiantes utilizan un 
microordenador conectado con una punta de prueba de la conductividad 
para medir los sólidos disueltos totales en muestras de agua locales 
del área. Los estudiantes entonces comparan sus medidas con las
de otras en su clase así como otras medidas estándares. En 
esta paginación del punto de partida, los utilizadores pueden tener 
acceso a la información sobre las metas que aprenden del ejercicio, 
contexto para las extremidades del uso, de la enseñanza las notas y, 
los materiales didácticos, las ideas del gravamen, las referencias y 
los asuntos cubiertos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ROBYN JOHNSON
FN:ROBYN JOHNSON
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:GRETCHEN DEMOSS
FN:GRETCHEN DEMOSS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:RICHARD SORENSEN
FN:RICHARD SORENSEN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213076</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104915</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/water-quality-total-dissolved-solids</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
