<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104075</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104075</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087441</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Black Hawk Remembers Village Life Along the Mississippi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Schwarzer Falke erinnert sich das an Dorf-Leben 
entlang dem Mississippi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le faucon noir se rappelle la vie de village le 
long du Mississippi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O falcão preto recorda a vida da vila ao longo do 
Mississippi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il hawk nero si ricorda della vita del villaggio 
lungo il Mississippi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το μαύρο γεράκι θυμάται την του χωριού ζωή κατά 
μήκος του Μισισιπή</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El halcón negro recuerda vida de la aldea a lo 
largo del Mississippi</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Black Hawk or Ma-ka-tai-me-she-kia-kiak, was born at Saukenuk, a Sauk village at the junction of the Rock and Mississippi Rivers. When the United States took over the area in 1804 after the Louisiana Purchase, several Sauk and other tribal leaders signed a treaty that ceded Indian lands east of the Mississippi River, but allowed the Indians to stay as long as the territory remained the property of the federal government. Fearful of the land hungry Americans, Black Hawk and others joined the British in the War of 1812. Encroaching settlers pushed the Sauks into a confrontation with the American government, and Black Hawk's refusal to abandon his homelands led to the Black Hawk War in 1832. Defeated, the chief was taken East upon orders of President Andrew Jackson. He dictated his life story the following year to a government interpreter. Edited by a local newspaperman, it was the first Indian autobiography published in the United States.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Schwarzer Falke oder MA-Ka-tai-mir-sie-kia-kiak, 
wurden bei Saukenuk, ein Sauk Dorf an der Verzweigung des Felsens und 
der Mississippi Flüsse getragen. Als die Vereinigten Staaten 
den Bereich 1804, nachdem der Louisiana Erwerb, einiger Sauk und 
andere Stammes- Führer unterzeichnete, ein Vertrag, der indische 
Länder östlich des Mississippi Flusses überließ, aber, den Indern,
so lang zu bleiben erlaubte übernahmen, wie die Gegend die 
Eigenschaft der Bundesregierung blieb. Ängstlich von den Land 
hungrigen Amerikanern, vom schwarzen Falken und von den anderen 
verband die Briten im Krieg von 1812. Eingreifende Siedleren 
drückten das Sauks in eine Konfrontation mit der amerikanischen 
Regierung, und die Ablehnung des Schwarz-Falken, zum seiner Heimaten 
zu verlassen, die zu den schwarzen Falken geführt werden, War 1832. 
Besiegt, wurde der Leiter nach Osten nach Ordnungen des 
Präsidenten Andrew Jackson genommen. Er schrieb seine 
Lebengeschichte das folgende Jahr zu einem Regierung Interpreter vor. 
Bearbeitet durch einen lokalen Newspaperman, war es die erste 
indische Autobiographie, die in den Vereinigten Staaten 
veröffentlicht wurde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le faucon ou MA-ka-tai-$$$-ELLE-KIA-KIAK noir, a 
été soutenu chez Saukenuk, un village de Sauk à la jonction de la 
roche et des fleuves du Mississippi. Quand les Etats-Unis ont 
assuré la zone en 1804 après que l'achat de la Louisiane, plusieurs 
Sauk et d'autres amorces tribales ait signé un traité qui a cédé 
les terres indiennes à l'est du fleuve du Mississippi, mais a permis 
aux Indiens de rester aussi longs que le territoire est resté la 
propriété du gouvernement fédéral. Craintif des Américains 
affamés de terre, du faucon noir et des autres a joint les Anglais 
dans la guerre de 1812. Les colons d'empiétement ont poussé le
Sauks dans une confrontation avec le gouvernement américain, et le 
refus du faucon de noir pour abandonner ses patries menées au faucon 
noir font la guerre en 1832. Défait, le chef a été pris à 
l'est sur des commandes du Président Andrew Jackson. Il a 
dicté sa histoire de la vie l'année suivante à un interprète de 
gouvernement. Édité par un journaliste local, c'était la 
première autobiographie indienne éditée aux Etats-Unis.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O falcão ou Miliampère-ka-tai-me--kia-kiak 
preta, foram carregados em Saukenuk, uma vila de Sauk na junção da 
rocha e dos rios de Mississippi. Quando os estados unidos 
fizeram exame sobre da área em 1804 depois que a compra de Louisiana,
diversa Sauk e outros líderes tribais assinou um tratado que ceded 
terras indian leste do rio de Mississippi, mas permitiram que os 
indians permanecessem tão longos como o território remanesceu a 
propriedade do governo federal. Temível dos americanos com fome
da terra, do falcão preto e do outro juntou os Ingleses na guerra de 
1812. Os settlers encroaching introduziram o Sauks em um 
confrontation com o governo americano, e a recusa do falcão do preto 
para abandonar seus homelands conduzidos ao falcão preto guerreia em 
1832. Derrotado, o chefe foi feito exame para o leste em cima 
das ordens do presidente Andrew Jackson. Ditou sua história da 
vida o seguinte ano a um intérprete do governo. Editado por um 
newspaperman local, era o primeiro autobiography indian publicado nos 
estados unidos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il hawk o MA-Ka-tai-me-lei-kia-kiak nero, è stata
sopportata a Saukenuk, un villaggio di Sauk alla giunzione della 
roccia e dei fiumi del Mississippi. Quando unito Dichiara
ha assunto la direzione della zona in 1804 dopo che l'acquisto della 
Luisiana, parecchio Sauk ed altri capi tribali firmasse un 
trattato che ha ceduto le terre indiane ad est del fiume del 
Mississippi, ma che permettesse che gli indiani rimanessero finchè il
territorio è rimasto la proprietà del governo federale. 
Spaventoso degli Americani affamati della terra, del hawk nero e
degli altri ha unito i Britannici nella guerra di 1812. I 
settlers d'invasione hanno spinto il Sauks in un confronto con il 
governo americano ed il rifiuto del hawk di nero per abbandonare le 
sue patrie condotte al hawk nero fa la guerra in 1832. 
Sconfitto, il capo è stato preso verso est sugli ordini del 
presidente Andrew Jackson. Ha dettato la sua storia di vita il 
seguente anno ad un interpretatore di governo. Stampato da un 
newspaperman locale, era il primo autobiography indiano pubblicato in 
unito Dichiara.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαύρο γεράκι ή μΑ-Κα-ταη-εμένα-, γεννήθηκε σε 
Saukenuk, ένα χωριό Sauk στη σύνδεση των ποταμών βράχου και
του Μισισιπή. Όταν οι Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες ανέλαβαν την 
περιοχή το 1804 μετά από την αγορά της Λουιζιάνας, διάφορο 
Sauk και άλλοι φυλετικοί ηγέτες υπέγραψαν μια συνθήκη που 
εξεχώρησε την ινδική ανατολή εδαφών του ποταμού του Μισισιπή, 
αλλά επέτρεψαν στους Ινδούς για να μείνουν εφ' όσον το έδαφος 
παρέμεινε ιδιοκτησία της ομοσπονδιακής κυβέρνησης. Έντρομος
του εδάφους που πεινασμένοι Αμερικανοί, το μαύρο γεράκι και άλλα
ένωσαν τους Βρετανούς στον πόλεμο 1812, αποίκων καταπάτησης 
ώθησε το Sauks σε μια αντιμετώπιση με την αμερικανική 
κυβέρνηση, και η άρνηση του μαύρου γερακιού να εγκαταλειφθούν οι 
πατρίδες του οδήγησε στο μαύρο πόλεμο γερακιών σε 1832, που 
νικήθηκε, προϊστάμενος ήταν ληφθείσα ανατολή επάνω στις κατατάξεις
του Προέδρου Andrew Τζάκσον. Υπαγόρευσε την ιστορία ζωής
του το επόμενο έτος σε έναν κυβερνητικό διερμηνέα. 
Επιμελημένο από έναν τοπικό δημοσιογράφο, ήταν η πρώτη 
ινδική αυτοβιογραφία δημοσιεύω στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Llevaron el halcón o MA-ka-tai-mi'-la -kia-kiak 
negro, en Saukenuk, una aldea de Sauk en la ensambladura de la roca y 
de los ríos de Mississippi. Cuando los Estados Unidos asumieron
el control el área en 1804 después de que la compra de Luisiana, 
varia Sauk y otros arranques de cinta tribales firmara un tratado que 
cedió pistas indias al este del río de Mississippi, pero permitió 
que los indios permanecieran mientras el territorio seguía siendo la 
característica del gobierno federal. Temeroso de los americanos
hambrientos de la pista, del halcón negro y de los otros ensambló a 
Británicos en la guerra de 1812. Los colonos de usurpación 
empujaron el Sauks en una confrontación con el gobierno americano, y 
la denegación del halcón del negro para abandonar sus patrias 
conducidas al halcón negro guerrea en 1832. Derrotado, tomaron 
el jefe al este sobre órdenes de presidente Andrew Jackson. Él
dictó su historia de la vida el año siguiente a un intérprete del 
gobierno. Corregido por un newspaperman local, era la primera 
autobiografía india publicada en los Estados Unidos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087441</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104075</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/black-hawk-remembers-village-life-along-the-mississippi</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
