<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104080</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104080</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203344</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Inquiry Page</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Anfrage-Seite</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Page d'Enquête</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Página Do Inquérito</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Pagina Di Inchiesta</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σελίδα έρευνας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Paginación De la Pregunta</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Inquiry Page is a dynamic virtual community where inquiry-based education can be discussed, resources and experiences shared, and innovative approaches explored in a collaborative environment. The site features a growing database of inquiry units, and you can also build your own inquiry units. The database of exisiting units covers a range of topics from the sciences as well as the humanities. There are pictures of inquiry-based activities and information about other teachers who use inquiry methods. For teachers looking for suport or answers to questions about inquiry-based learning, there is a discussion forum to share ideas. There is also a list of related articles, case studies and evaluations.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Anfrage-Seite ist eine dynamische virtuelle 
Gemeinschaft, in der Anfrage-gegründete Ausbildung behandelt werden 
kann, die Betriebsmittel und Erfahrungen, die geteilt werden, und die 
erfinderischen Annäherungen, die in einer gemeinschaftlichen Umgebung
erforscht werden. Die Situationsmerkmale eine wachsende 
Datenbank der Abfrageeinheiten und Sie können Ihre eigenen 
Abfrageeinheiten auch aufbauen. Die Datenbank der exisiting 
Maßeinheiten umfaßt eine Strecke der Themen von den Wissenschaften 
sowie die Menschlichkeit. Es gibt Abbildungen der 
Anfrage-gegründeten Aktivitäten und der Informationen über andere 
Lehrer, die Anfragemethoden verwenden. Für die Lehrer, die nach
suport oder Antworten zu den Fragen über das Anfrage-gegründete 
Lernen schauen, gibt es ein Diskussion Forum, zum von von Ideen zu 
teilen. Es gibt auch eine Liste der in Verbindung stehenden 
Artikel, der Fallstudien und der Auswertungen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La page d'enquête est une communauté virtuelle 
dynamique où l'éducation enquête-basée peut être discutée, des 
ressources et des expériences partagées, et des approches 
innovatrices explorées dans un environnement de collaboration. 
Les dispositifs de site une base de données croissante des 
unités d'enquête, et vous pouvez également établir vos propres 
unités d'enquête. La base de données des unités exisiting 
couvre un intervalle des sujets des sciences aussi bien que les 
sciences humaines. Il y a des images des activités et des 
informations enquête-basées sur d'autres professeurs qui utilisent 
des méthodes d'enquête. Pour des professeurs recherchant le 
suport ou les réponses aux questions sur l'étude enquête-basée, il
y a un forum de discussion pour partager des idées. Il y a 
également une liste d'articles, d'études de cas et d'évaluations 
relatifs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A página do inquérito é uma comunidade virtual 
dinâmica onde a instrução inquérito-baseada possa ser discutida, 
recursos e experiências compartilhados, e aproximações inovativas 
exploradas em um ambiente collaborative. As características de 
local uma base de dados crescente de unidades de inquérito, e você 
podem também construir suas próprias unidades de inquérito. A
base de dados de unidades exisiting cobre uma escala dos tópicos das 
ciências as.well.as os humanities. Há uns retratos de 
atividades e da informação inquérito-baseadas sobre outros 
professores que usam métodos do inquérito. Para os professores
que procuram o suport ou as respostas às perguntas sobre a 
aprendizagem inquérito-baseada, há um forum da discussão para 
compartilhar de idéias. Há também uma lista de artigos, de 
estudos de caso e de avaliações relacionados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La pagina di inchiesta è una Comunità virtuale 
dinamica in cui la formazione inchiesta-basata può essere discussa, 
risorse ed esperienze compartecipi e metodi innovatori esplorati in un
ambiente di collaborazione. Le caratteristiche di luogo una base
di dati crescente delle unità di inchiesta e voi potete anche 
sviluppare le vostre proprie unità di inchiesta. La base di 
dati delle unità exisiting tratta una gamma di soggetti dalle scienze
così come gli studi umanistici. Ci sono immagini delle 
attività e delle informazioni inchiesta-basate su altri insegnanti 
che usano i metodi di inchiesta. Per gli insegnanti che cercano 
suport o le risposte alle domande circa imparare inchiesta-basato, ci 
è una tribuna di discussione per ripartire le idee. Ci è 
egualmente una lista degli articoli, delle inchieste e delle 
valutazioni relativi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η σελίδα έρευνας είναι δυναμική εικονική κοινότητα 
όπου η έρευνα-βασισμένη στο εκπαίδευση μπορεί να συζητηθεί, τα 
στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς και η εμπειρία κοινός, και οι καινοτόμες 
προσεγγίσεις που εξερευνιούνται σε ένα συνεργάσιμο περιβάλλον. 
Η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει μια βάση δεδομένων ανάπτυξης των 
μονάδων έρευνας, και μπορείτε επίσης να χτίσετε τις μονάδες 
έρευνάς σας. Η βάση δεδομένων οι μονάδες καλύπτει μια 
σειρά των θεμάτων από τις επιστήμες καθώς επίσης και τις 
ανθρωπότητες. Υπάρχουν εικόνες των έρευνα-βασισμένων στο 
δραστηριοτήτων και των πληροφοριών για άλλους δασκάλους που 
χρησιμοποιούν τις μεθόδους έρευνας. Για τους δασκάλους που 
ψάχνουν suport ή τις απαντήσεις στις ερωτήσεις για την 
έρευνα-βασισμένη στην εκμάθηση, υπάρχει ένα φόρουμ συζήτησης 
για να μοιραστεί τις ιδέες. Υπάρχει επίσης ένας κατάλογος 
σχετικών άρθρων, περιπτωσιολογικών μελετών και αξιολογήσεων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La paginación de la pregunta es una comunidad 
virtual dinámica donde la educación pregunta-basada puede ser 
discutida, recursos y experiencias compartidos, y acercamientos 
innovadores explorados en un ambiente de colaboración. Las 
características de sitio una base de datos cada vez mayor de las 
unidades de pregunta, y usted pueden también construir sus propias 
unidades de pregunta. La base de datos de unidades exisiting 
cubre un rango de asuntos de las ciencias así como la humanidad. 
Hay cuadros de actividades y de la información pregunta-basadas
sobre otros profesores que utilicen métodos de la pregunta. 
Para los profesores que buscan el suport o respuestas a las 
preguntas sobre aprender pregunta-basado, hay un foro de la discusión
para compartir ideas. Hay también una lista de artículos, de 
estudios de caso y de evaluaciones relacionados.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203344</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104080</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/inquiry-page</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
