<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104430</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104430</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087005</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The New Housekeeping: Solving the Servant Problem</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Neue Haushaltung: Lösen des 
Bedienstet-Problems</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Nouveau Ménage : Solution du problème 
d'domestique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As Tarefas domésticas Novas: Resolvendo o 
problema do empregado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nuovo Governo della casa: Risolvere il 
problema del servo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η νέα οικοκυρική: Επίλυση του προβλήματος 
υπαλλήλων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las Nuevas Operacíones de entretenimiento: 
Solucionar el problema del criado</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">As immigration dropped sharply during World War I and many native-born women left domestic service for wartime jobs, middle-class women lamented the shortage of domestic workers. This spurred efforts to reorganize housework and a fostered a new breed of home economists who argued for "scientific" housekeeping. By applying the methods and theory of scientific management to the home, these experts argued, housework could be rendered less arduous and time-consuming. The "new housekeeping" often relied solely on the unpaid work of the middle-class wives. A leading proponent of household scientific management, Christine Frederick answered common criticisms of domestic workers by turning a critical eye on their employers. The "servant problem," she argued, was a problem of bad management--middle-class women needed to abandon unsystematic methods and arbitrary supervision for the new principles of scientific management. She expressed unusual empathy for women in domestic service, perhaps because she herself had cleaned houses to help pay her expenses as a college student at Northwestern University.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Da die Immigration, die scharf während des Ersten 
Weltkrieges und vieler gebürtig-getragene Frauen fallengelassen 
wurde, inländischen Service für Kriegjobs ließ, bejammerten 
Mittelklassefrauen den Mangel an inländische Arbeiter. Dieses 
angetriebene Bemühungen, die Hausarbeit und zu reorganisieren 
gefördert einer neuen Brut der Hauptwirtschaftswissenschaftler, die 
für "wissenschaftliche" Haushaltung argumentierten. Indem man 
die Methoden und die Theorie der wissenschaftlichen 
Unternehmensführung am Haus anwendete, konnten diese Experten, die 
argumentiert wurden, Hausarbeit weniger eifrig und zeitraubend gemacht
werden. Die "neue Haushaltung" beruhte häufig nur auf der 
unbezahlten Arbeit der Mittelklassefrauen. Ein führender 
Antragsteller Haushalt der wissenschaftlichen Unternehmensführung, 
Christine Frederick beantwortete geläufige Kritiken der inländischen
Arbeiter, indem er ein kritisches Auge auf ihren Arbeitgebern drehte. 
Das "Bedienstetproblem," argumentierte sie, war ein Problem 
falschem Management -- die Mittelklassefrauen, die benötigt wurden, 
um unsystematische Methoden und willkürliche Überwachung für die 
neuen Grundregeln der wissenschaftlichen Unternehmensführung zu 
verlassen. Sie drückte ungewöhnliches empathy für Frauen im 
inländischen Service, möglicherweise aus, weil sie selbst Häuser 
gesäubert hatte, um zu helfen, ihr Unkosten als Student an der 
nordwestlichen Universität zu zahlen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Car l'immigration abandonnée brusquement pendant 
la Première Guerre Mondiale et les beaucoup les femmes 
indigène-soutenues a laissé le service domestique pour les travaux 
de temps de guerre, les femmes de classe moyen ont déploré le manque
d'ouvriers domestiques. Ce efforts stimulés de réorganiser les
travaux domestiques et stimulés une nouvelle race des économistes à
la maison qui ont plaidé pour le ménage "scientifique". En 
s'appliquant les méthodes et la théorie de gestion scientifique à 
la maison, ces experts discutés, les travaux domestiques pourraient 
être rendus moins laborieux et longs. Le "nouveau ménage" 
souvent s'est fondé seulement sur le travail impayé des épouses de 
classe moyenne. Un principal partisan de gestion scientifique de
ménage, Christine Frederick a répondu à des critiques communes des 
ouvriers domestiques en tournant un oeil critique sur leurs 
employeurs. Le "problème d'domestique," elle a discuté, était
un problème de mauvaise gestion -- femmes de classe moyen requises 
pour abandonner des méthodes non systématiques et la surveillance 
arbitraire pour les nouveaux principes de la gestion scientifique. 
Elle a exprimé l'empathie peu commune pour des femmes en 
service domestique, peut-être parce qu'elle avait nettoyé elle-même
des maisons pour aider à lui payer des dépenses en tant 
qu'étudiante d'université à l'université du nord-ouest.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Porque o immigration deixado cair agudamente 
durante o world.war.i e os muitos mulheres nativo-carregadas deixou o 
serviço doméstico para trabalhos do wartime, as mulheres do 
middle-class lamented a falta de trabalhadores domésticos. Este
esforços spurred reorganize o housework e promovidos uma raça nova 
dos economistas home que discutiram para tarefas domésticas 
"científicas". Aplicando os métodos e a teoria da gerência 
científica à HOME, estes peritos discutidos, housework poderiam ser 
rendidos mais menos arduous e time-consuming. "as tarefas 
domésticas novas" confiaram frequentemente unicamente no trabalho por
pagar das esposas do middle-class. Um proponent principal da 
gerência científica da casa, Christine Frederick respondeu a 
criticisms comuns de trabalhadores domésticos girando um olho 
crítico em seus empregadores. Do "o problema empregado," 
discutiu, foi um problema da gerência má -- mulheres do middle-class
necessitadas abandonar métodos unsystematic e a supervisão 
arbitrária para os princípios novos da gerência científica. 
Expressou empathy incomun para mulheres no serviço doméstico, 
talvez porque ela mesma tinha limpado casas para ajudar lhe pagar 
despesas como um estudante de faculdade na universidade do noroeste.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Poichè l'immigrazione caduta acutamente durante il
world.war.i ed i molti donne natale-sopportate ha lasciato il servizio
domestico per i lavori di wartime, le donne della classe media hanno 
deplorato la scarsità degli operai domestici. Questo sforzi 
stimolati riorganizzare lavori domestici e promossi una nuova razza 
degli economisti domestici che hanno parlato a favore del governo 
della casa "scientifico". Applicando i metodi e la teoria della 
gestione scientifica alla sede, questi esperti discussi, lavori 
domestici potrebbero essere resi meno ardui e che richiede tempo. 
"il nuovo governo della casa" ha contato spesso solamente sul 
lavoro non pagato delle mogli della classe media. Un fautore 
principale della gestione scientifica della famiglia, Christine 
Frederick ha risposto alle critiche comuni degli operai domestici 
girando un occhio critico sui loro datori di lavoro. "il 
problema del servo," ha discusso, era un problema della gestione 
difettosa -- donne della classe media state necessarie per abbandonare
i metodi non sistematici ed il controllo arbitrario per i nuovi 
principii della gestione scientifica. Ha espresso empathy 
insolito per le donne nel servizio domestico, forse perché lei stessa
aveva pulito le case per contribuire a pagarle le spese come allievo 
di università all'università nordoccidentale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σαν μετανάστευση που έπεσαν αισθητά κατά τη διάρκεια 
του παγκόσμιου πολέμου Ι και πολλές εγγενής-γεννημένες γυναίκες 
που αφέθηκαν την εσωτερική υπηρεσία για τις εν καιρώ πολέμου 
εργασίες, οι γυναίκες μεσαίων τάξεων θρήνησαν την έλλειψη των 
εσωτερικών εργαζομένων. Αυτό κέντρισε τις προσπάθειες να 
αναδιοργανωθούν τα οικιακά και ενθαρρυμένη μια νέα φυλή των 
βασικών οικονομολόγων που υποστήριξαν τη "επιστημονική" 
οικοκυρική. Με τη "Εφαρμογή" των μεθόδων και της θεωρίας της
επιστημονικής διαχείρισης στο σπίτι, αυτοί οι εμπειρογνώμονες που
υποστηρίχτηκαν, τα οικιακά θα μπορούσαν να κατασταθούν λιγότερο 
σκληρά και χρονοβόρα. Η "νέα οικοκυρική" συχνά στηρίχθηκε 
απλώς στην απλήρωτη εργασία των συζύγων μεσαίων τάξεων. 
Ένας κύριος υπερασπιστής της οικιακής επιστημονικής 
διαχείρισης, Christine Frederick απάντησε στις κοινές 
κριτικές των εσωτερικών εργαζομένων με τη στροφή ενός κρίσιμου 
ματιού στους εργοδότες τους. Το "πρόβλημα υπαλλήλων," 
υποστήριξε, ήταν ένα πρόβλημα της κακής διαχείρισης -- οι 
γυναίκες μεσαίων τάξεων έπρεπε να εγκαταλείψουν τις 
unsystematic μεθόδους και την αυθαίρετη επίβλεψη για τις νέες 
αρχές της επιστημονικής διαχείρισης. Εξέφρασε το ασυνήθιστο
ενσυναίσθημα για τις γυναίκες στην εσωτερική υπηρεσία, ίσως 
επειδή ο ίδιος είχε καθαρίσει τα σπίτια για να βοηθήσει να 
πληρώσει τις δαπάνες της ως σπουδαστή κολλεγίων στο βορειοδυτικό 
πανεπιστήμιο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Pues la inmigración caída sostenidamente durante 
Primera Guerra Mundial y muchas las mujeres nativo-llevadas dejó el 
servicio doméstico para los trabajos del tiempo de guerra, las 
mujeres de la clase media lamentaron de la escasez de trabajadores 
domésticos. Este esfuerzos estimulados de reorganizar el 
quehacer doméstico y fomentados una nueva casta de los economistas 
caseros que discutieron para las operacíones de entretenimiento 
"científicas". Aplicando los métodos y la teoría de la 
gerencia científica al hogar, estos expertos discutidos, quehacer 
doméstico podrían ser hechos menos arduos y desperdiciadores de 
tiempo. Las "nuevas operacíones de entretenimiento" confiaron a
menudo solamente en el trabajo sin pagar de las esposas de la clase 
media. Un autor principal de la gerencia científica de la casa,
Christine Frederick contestó a críticas comunes de trabajadores 
domésticos dando vuelta a un ojo crítico en sus patrones. El 
"problema del criado," ella discutió, era un problema de la mala 
gerencia -- mujeres de la clase media necesitadas para abandonar 
métodos poco metódicos y la supervisión arbitraria para los nuevos 
principios de la gerencia científica. Ella expresó empathy 
inusual para las mujeres en servicio doméstico, quizás porque ella 
ella misma había limpiado casas para ayudar a pagarle costos como 
estudiante de universidad en la universidad del noroeste.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087005</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104430</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-new-housekeeping-solving-the-servant-problem</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
