<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105884</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105884</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211820</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Radiation Reassessed</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Strahlung Neu abgeschätzt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Rayonnement Réévalué</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Radiação Reassessed</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Radiazione Rivalutata</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ακτινοβολία που επαναξιολογείται</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Radiación Nueva</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">While the scientific community agrees that big doses of ionizing radiation cause serious damage to the human body, the effects of long-term, low-dose radiation are hotly contested. Some believe these minimal doses are dangerous, while others argue they are actually beneficial to human health. So, what's up with radiation? How have disasters at Hiroshima, Nagasaki and Chernobyl aided our scientific understanding of radiation?</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während die wissenschaftliche Gemeinschaft darin 
übereinstimmt, daß grosse Dosen Ursache der ionisierenden Strahlung 
der ernsten Beschädigung des menschlichen Körpers, die Effekte von 
Long-term, Niedrigdosis Strahlung heiß gewetteifert werden. 
Einige glauben, daß diese minimalen Dosen gefährlich sind, 
während andere sie sind wirklich vorteilhaft zur menschlichen 
Gesundheit argumentieren. So ist was oben mit Strahlung? 
Wie haben Unfälle bei Hiroschima, bei Nagasaki und bei 
Chernobyl unser Wissenschaftsverständnis der Strahlung unterstützt?</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Tandis que la communauté scientifique convient 
que les grandes doses de dommages sérieux de cause de radiation 
ionisante au corps humain, les effets du long terme, rayonnement de 
bas-dose sont contestées avec chaleur. Certains croient que ces
doses minimales sont dangereuses, alors que d'autres les discutent 
sont réellement salutaires à la santé humaine. Ainsi, qu'est 
vers le haut avec le rayonnement ? Comment les désastres à 
Hiroshima, à Nagasaki et Chernobyl ont-ils facilité notre 
arrangement scientifique de rayonnement ?</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quando a comunidade científica concordar que os 
doses grandes dos danos sérios da causa da radiação de ionização 
ao corpo humano, os efeitos do prazo, radiação do baixo-low-dose 
estão contestados quente. Alguns acreditam que estes doses 
mínimos são perigosos, quando outros os discutirem são realmente 
benéficos à saúde humana. Assim, que está acima com 
radiação? Como os disastres em Hiroshima, em Nagasaki e em 
Chernobyl ajudaram a nossa compreensão científica da radiação?</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Mentre la Comunità scientifica accosente 
che le dosi grandi di danneggiamento serio di causa di radiazione 
ionizzante del corpo umano, gli effetti del lungo termine, radiazione 
della basso-dose sono contestate caldo. Alcuni credono che 
queste dosi minime siano pericolose, mentre altre le discutono sono 
realmente favorevoli a salute umana. Così, che cosa è in su 
con radiazione? Come i disastri a Hiroshima, Nagasaki e 
Chernobyl hanno aiutato la nostra conoscenza scientifica della 
radiazione?</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ενώ η επιστημονική κοινότητα συμφωνεί ότι οι μεγάλες
δόσεις της ακτινοβολίας ιονισμού προκαλούν τη σοβαρή ζημία στο 
ανθρώπινο σώμα, τα αποτελέσματα του μακροπρόθεσμου, ακτινοβολία 
χαμηλός-δόσεων αμφισβητούνται hotly. Μερικοί θεωρούν 
ότι αυτές οι ελάχιστες δόσεις είναι επικίνδυνες, ενώ άλλοι 
υποστηρίζουν είναι πραγματικά ευεργετικές στην ανθρώπινη υγεία. 
Έτσι, τι επάνω με την ακτινοβολία; Πώς οι καταστροφές
στη Χιροσίμα, το Ναγκασάκι και το Τσέρνομπιλ έχουν βοηθήσει την 
επιστημονική κατανόηση ακτινοβολίας μας;</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mientras que la comunidad científica conviene que
las dosis grandes del daño serio de la causa de la radiación de 
ionización al cuerpo humano, los efectos del largo plazo, radiación 
de la bajo-dosis están disputadas caliente. Algunos creen que 
estas dosis mínimas son peligrosas, mientras que otras los discuten 
son realmente beneficiosas a la salud humana. ¿Así pues, cuál 
está para arriba con la radiación? ¿Cómo los desastres en 
Hiroshima, Nagasaki y Chernobyl han ayudado a nuestra comprensión 
científica de la radiación?</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:DAVID TENENBAUM
FN:DAVID TENENBAUM
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211820</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105884</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/radiation-reassessed</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
