<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103090</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103090</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202562</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Toward computer literacy in the ESL classroom: An introduction To formatting</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In Richtung zum Computerbildungsgrad im ESL 
Klassenzimmer: Eine Einleitung in eine Formatierung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Vers des connaissances en informatique dans la 
salle de classe d'ESL : Une introduction au formatage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Para o literacy de computador na sala de aula de 
ESL: Uma introdução ao formato</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Verso literacy di calcolatore nell'aula di ESL: 
Un'introduzione a formattazione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Προς τη βασική εκπαίδευση υπολογιστών στην τάξη του 
ESL: Μια εισαγωγή στη μορφοποίηση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Hacia conocimiento de informática en la sala de 
clase de ESL: Una introducción al formato</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Word Processing software is used to create and print documents. English as a second language middle school students (with an intermediate level of English proficiency) will be introduced to the advantages of word processing with emphasis on text formatting features in Microsoft Works. Both independent and group work is included in the activities.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Textverarbeitung Software wird benutzt, um 
Dokumente zu erstellen und zu drucken. Englisch als 
Kursteilnehmer einer zweite Sprachenmittleren Schule (mit einer 
Zwischenstufe der englischen Leistungsfähigkeit) wird zu den 
Vorteilen der Textverarbeitung mit Betonung auf Textformatierung 
Merkmalen in den Microsoft Arbeiten eingeführt. ist 
Unabhängiges und Gruppe Arbeit in den Aktivitäten eingeschlossen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le logiciel de traitement de texte est employé 
pour créer et imprimer des documents. l'anglais en tant que 
deuxièmes étudiants d'un collège de langage (avec un niveau 
intermédiaire de compétence anglaise) sera présenté aux avantages 
du traitement de texte avec l'accent sur des dispositifs de formatage 
des textes dans des travaux de Microsoft. Le indépendant et 
le travail de groupe est inclus dans les activités.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O software processar de palavra é usado criar e 
imprimir originais. O inglês como estudantes segundos de uma 
escola média da língua (com um nível intermediário da 
proficiência inglesa) será introduzido às vantagens de processar de
palavra com ênfase em características do formato de texto em 
trabalhos de Microsoft. o independent e o trabalho do grupo 
são incluídos nas atividades.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il software di elaborazione di testi è usato per 
creare e stampare i documenti. L'inglese come allievi secondi 
della scuola centrale di linguaggio (con un livello intermedio di 
competenza inglese) sarà introdotto ai vantaggi di elaborazione di 
testi con l'enfasi sulle caratteristiche di formattazione di testo 
negli impianti del Microsoft. Sia il independent che il lavoro 
de gruppo è incluso nelle attività.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το λογισμικό επεξεργασίας κειμένου χρησιμοποιείται για
να δημιουργήσει και να τυπώσει τα έγγραφα. Τα αγγλικά ως 
σπουδαστές μέσοι σχολείων δεύτερης γλώσσας (με ένα ενδιάμεσο 
επίπεδο αγγλικής ικανότητας) θα εισαχθούν προς όφελος της 
επεξεργασίας κειμένου με έμφαση στα σχηματοποιώντας 
χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα κειμένων στις εργασίες της Microsoft.
Και η εργασία ανεξάρτητων και ομάδας συμπεριλαμβάνεται στις 
δραστηριότητες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El software del tratamiento de textos de textos se
utiliza para crear y para imprimir documentos. El inglés como 
estudiantes segundos de una escuela media del lenguaje (con un nivel 
intermedio de la habilidad inglesa) será introducido a las ventajas 
del tratamiento de textos de textos con énfasis sobre 
características del formato de texto en los trabajos de Microsoft. 
La independiente y el trabajo del grupo se incluye en las 
actividades.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MILENA DOLEZEL
FN:MILENA DOLEZEL
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202562</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103090</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/toward-computer-literacy-in-the-esl-classroom-an-introduction-to-formatting</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
