<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103068</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103068</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086167</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"For the Further Benefit of Our People": George Pullman Answers His Strikers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"für den weiteren Nutzen unserer Leute": 
George Pullman Beantwortet Seine Schlaggeräte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"pour l'avantage supplémentaire de nos personnes"
: Le Pullman de George Répond À Ses Butées</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"para o benefício mais adicional de nossos 
povos": O Pullman De George Responde A Seus Grevistas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"per ulteriore beneficio della nostra gente": 
Il Pullman Di George Risponde Ai Suoi Percussori</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Για το περαιτέρω όφελος των ανθρώπων μασ": 
Θ*Γεοργε Pullman Answers His Strikers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"para la ventaja posterior de nuestra gente": 
El Pullman De George Contesta A Sus Huelguistas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">For workers at the Pullman Palace Car Company in the 1890s, home was the company town of Pullman, Illinois, and rent was deducted from their wages. While owner George Pullman touted it as a model town, the men and women who labored there during the 1893 depression endured starvation wages, deplorable living and working conditions, and, worst of all, Pullman's paternalistic control over all aspects of their lives. Workers appealed to the American Railway Union (ARU), which organized a nationwide strike and boycott against Pullman. In this open letter in the Chicago  Herald  in June 1894, as the strike began, Pullman explained his motives for cutting wages during the economic depression of 1893.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Für Arbeiter an Pullman Palace Car Company im 
1890s, Haus war die Firmastadt von Pullman, Illinois, und Miete wurde 
von ihren Löhnen abgezogen. Während Inhaber George Pullman 
ankündigte, hielt es als vorbildliche Stadt, die Männer und 
Frauen, die dort während des Tiefstands 1893 bearbeiteten, 
Verhungernlöhne, die bedauernswerten lebende und Funktion Bedingungen 
und aus, am falschsten von allen, paternalistische Steuerung des 
Pullmans über allen Aspekten ihrer Lebensdauern. Arbeiter 
gefielen dem amerikanischen Bahnanschluß (ARU), der einen allgemein 
Schlag und einen Boykott gegen Pullman organisierte. In diesem 
geöffneten Zeichen im Chicago Verkünder im Juni 1894, während der 
Schlag anfing, erklärte Pullman seine Motive für Ausschnittlöhne 
während der Wirtschaftskrise von 1893.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pour des ouvriers à Pullman Palace Car Company 
dans le 1890s, maison était la ville de compagnie du pullman, 
l'Illinois, et le loyer a été déduit de leurs salaires. 
Tandis que le pullman de George de propriétaire 
espionnait il en tant qu'une ville modèle, les hommes et 
femmes qui ont travaillé là pendant la dépression 1893 a supporté 
des salaires de misère, des conditions de travail déplorables 
vivantes et, et, plus mauvaises de tous, le contrôle paternaliste du 
pullman's de tous les aspects de leurs vies. Les ouvriers ont 
fait appel à l'union ferroviaire américaine (ARU), qui a organisé 
une grève et un boycott dans tout le pays contre le pullman. 
Dans cette lettre ouverte dans le héraut de Chicago en juin 
1894, pendant que la grève commençait, le pullman a expliqué ses 
motifs pour des salaires de découpage pendant la dépression 
économique de 1893.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Para trabalhadores no Pullman Palácio Carro 
Companhia no 1890s, HOME era a cidade da companhia do Pullman, 
Illinois, e o aluguel foi deduzido de seus salários. Quando o 
Pullman de George do proprietário touted como uma cidade modelo, os 
homens e as mulheres que trabalhassem lá durante o depression 1893 
resistiu salários de starvation, as condições deplorable vivas e do
funcionamento, e, as mais más de tudo, controle paternalistic do 
Pullman sobre todos os aspectos de suas vidas. Os trabalhadores 
apelaram à união railway americana (ARU), que organizou uma batida e
um boycott de âmbito nacional de encontro ao Pullman. Nesta 
letra aberta no herald de Chicago em junho 1894, enquanto a batida 
começou, o Pullman explicou seus motriz para salários do corte 
durante o depression econômico de 1893.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Per gli operai al Pullman Palace Car Company nel 
1890s, sede era la città dell'azienda del pullman, l'Illinois e 
l'affitto è stato dedotto dai loro stipendi. Mentre il pullman 
di George del proprietario touted come una città di modello, gli 
uomini e donne che hanno lavorato là durante la depressione 1893 ha 
resistito agli stipendi di inedia, alle condizioni di lavoro 
deplorable e di vita e, più difettose di tutti, al controllo 
paternalistic del pullman sopra tutte le funzioni delle loro vite. 
Gli operai hanno fatto appello all'unione ferroviaria americana 
(ARU), che ha organizzato un colpo e un boicottaggio nazionali contro 
il pullman. In questa lettera aperta nel herald del Chicago nel 
mese di giugno del 1894, mentre il colpo ha cominciato, il pullman ha 
spiegato i suoi motivi per gli stipendi di taglio durante la 
depressione economica di 1893.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Για τους εργαζομένους στο Pullman Palace Car 
Company στο 1890s, το σπίτι ήταν η πόλη επιχείρησης 
Pullman, Ιλλινόις, και το μίσθωμα αφαιρέθηκε από τις αμοιβές 
τους. Ενώ ο ιδιοκτήτης George Pullman αυτό ως πρότυπη 
πόλη, άνδρες και γυναίκες που εργάστηκαν κατά τη διάρκεια της 
κατάθλιψης 1893 υπόμεινε τις αμοιβές λιμού, τις λυπηρές 
συνθήκες διαβίωσης και εργασίας, και, ο πιό χειρότερα όλες, τον 
paternalistic έλεγχο Pullman σε όλες τις πτυχές των ζωών 
τους. Οι εργαζόμενοι απευθύνθηκαν στην αμερικανική ένωση 
σιδηροδρόμων (ARU), η οποία οργάνωσε μια σε εθνικό επίπεδο 
απεργία και ένα μποϊκοτάρισμα ενάντια σε Pullman. Σε 
αυτήν την ανοικτή επιστολή στο Σικάγο ανακοινώστε τον Ιούνιο του
1894, καθώς η απεργία άρχισε, Pullman εξήγησε τα κίνητρά 
του για τις τέμνουσες αμοιβές κατά τη διάρκεια της οικονομικής 
ύφεσης 1893.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Para los trabajadores en el Pullman Palace Car 
Company en el 1890s, hogar estaba la ciudad de la compañía del 
pullman, Illinois, y el alquiler fue deducido de sus salarios. 
Mientras que el pullman de George del propietario touted como 
una ciudad modelo, los hombres y mujeres que trabajaron allí durante 
la depresión 1893 aguantó salarios de hambre, las condiciones vivas 
y del funcionamiento deplorables, y, peores de todos, control 
paternalistic del pullman sobre todos los aspectos de sus vidas. 
Los trabajadores abrogaron a la unión ferroviaria americana 
(ARU), que ordenó una huelga y un boicoteo a nivel nacional contra el
pullman. En esta carta abierta en el herald de Chicago en junio 
de de 1894, como la huelga comenzó, el pullman explicó sus motivos 
para los salarios del corte durante la depresión económica de 1893.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086167</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103068</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/for-the-further-benefit-of-our-people-george-pullman-answers-his-strikers</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
