<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107786</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107786</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205219</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The How-to's of OER Commons</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wie- zu den OER Common</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Comment-à des terrains communaux d'OER</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Como- das terras comuns de OER</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Come- dei terreni comunali di OER</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πώς- των αστικών τάξεων OER</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Co'mo- de campos comunes de OER</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Become a participant in the OER movement! Learn about open content and open education, licensing of open content, and the benefits of making and using OER. Using real-life examples from OER Commons, you'll learn about adapting and remixing content to meet your needs. By the end of this course, you will be able to locate materials you can use in your teaching and learning as well as share some of your own. The "How Tos" of OER Commons is a set of learning modules evolving out of the development of OER Commons, a teaching and learning network for free-to-use educational materials from around the world, created and licensed by the Institute for the Study of Knowledge Management in Education (ISKME).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Werden ein Teilnehmer an die OER Bewegung! 
Erlernen Sie über geöffneten Inhalt und öffnen Sie 
Ausbildung, Genehmigen des geöffneten Inhalts und den Nutzen des 
Bildens und des Verwendens von von OER. Mit real-life Beispielen
von den OER Common, erlernen Sie über anpassenden und wieder 
mischenden, Inhalt, zum Ihrer Bedürfnisse zu erfüllen. Ende 
dieses Kurses können Sie, Materialien zu lokalisieren, die Sie in 
Ihrem Unterricht und im Lernen sowie Anteil benutzen können einige 
von Ihren Selbst. ", wie Tos" von OER Common ein Set 
erlernenmodule ist, die aus der Entwicklung von OER Common heraus 
entwickeln, ein unterrichtendes und erlernennetz für 
frei-zu-verwenden Sie pädagogische Materialien um von der Welt, 
hergestellt und vom Institut genehmigt für die Studie des Wissen 
Managements in der Ausbildung (ISKME).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Deviennent un participant au mouvement d'OER ! 
Renseignez-vous sur le contenu ouvert et ouvrez l'éducation, 
autorisation du contenu ouvert, et les avantages de faire et 
d'utiliser OER. En utilisant des exemples réels des terrains 
communaux d'OER, vous vous renseignerez sur le contenu s'adaptant et 
de remélange pour satisfaire vos besoins. Vers la fin de ce 
cours, vous pourrez localiser des matériaux que vous pouvez utiliser 
votre enseignement et en apprenant aussi bien que la part certaines de
vos propres. "comment le TOS" des terrains communaux d'OER est 
un ensemble de modules d'étude évoluant hors du développement des 
terrains communaux d'OER, un réseau d'enseignement et d'étude pour 
libre-à-utilisez les matériaux éducatifs de partout dans le monde, 
créé et autorisé par l'institut pour l'étude de la gestion de la 
connaissance dans l'éducation (ISKME).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Torna-se um participant no movimento de OER! 
Aprenda sobre o índice aberto e abra a instrução, licenciar 
do índice aberto, e os benefícios de fazer e de usar OER. 
Usando exemplos real-life das terras comuns de OER, você 
aprenderá sobre o índice adaptando-se e remixing para encontrar-se 
com suas necessidades. Para o fim deste curso, você poderá  
encontrar materiais que você pode se usar em seu ensino e em aprender
as.well.as a parte alguma do seus próprios. "como o Tos" de 
terras comuns de OER é um jogo dos módulos de aprendizagem que 
evoluem fora do desenvolvimento de terras comuns de OER, uma rede 
ensinando e de aprendizagem para livre-à-use materiais educacionais 
em torno do mundo, criado e licenciado pelo instituto para o estudo da
gerência do conhecimento na instrução (ISKME).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Diventa un partecipante al movimento di OER! 
Impari circa il soddisfare aperto ed apra la formazione, 
autorizzare del soddisfare aperto ed i benefici di fare e di usando 
OER. Usando gli esempi in vivo dai terreni comunali di OER, 
imparerete circa il soddisfare adattantesi e di rimescolamento per 
soddisfare le vostre esigenze. Per la fine di questo corso, 
potrete individuare i materiali che potete usare nel vostro 
insegnamento e nell'imparare così come la parte alcuni dei vostri 
propri. "come il TOS" dei terreni comunali di OER è un insieme 
dei moduli imparanti che si evolvono dallo sviluppo dei terreni 
comunali di OER, una rete d'istruzione ed imparante per libero-$$$-USI
i materiali educativi intorno al mondo, creato ed autorizzato 
dall'istituto per lo studio sulla gestione di conoscenza nella 
formazione (ISKME).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γίνετε συμμετέχων στη μετακίνηση OER! Μάθετε 
για την ανοικτή ικανοποιημένη και ανοικτή εκπαίδευση, χορήγηση 
αδειών του ανοικτού περιεχομένου, και τα οφέλη και OER. 
Χρησιμοποιώντας τα πραγματικά παραδείγματα από τις αστικές 
τάξεις OER, θα μάθετε για να προσαρμοστείτε και νέου 
ανακατέματος το περιεχόμενο για να ικανοποιήσετε τις ανάγκες σας. 
Μέχρι το τέλος αυτής της σειράς μαθημάτων, θα είστε σε 
θέση να εντοπίσετε τα υλικά που μπορείτε να χρησιμοποιήσετε στη 
διδασκαλία σας και εκμάθηση καθώς επίσης και να μοιραστείτε 
μερικά από το σας δικοί. "Πώς tos" των αστικών τάξεων 
OER είναι ένα σύνολο ενοτήτων εκμάθησης που εξελίσσονται από
την ανάπτυξη των αστικών τάξεων OER, μια διδασκαλία και ένα 
δίκτυο εκμάθησης για τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά ελεύθερος-$$$-ΧΡΉΣΗΣ 
από σε όλο τον κόσμο, και που χορηγεί άδεια από το ίδρυμα που 
δημιουργείται για τη μελέτη της διαχείρισης γνώσης στην 
εκπαίδευση (ISKME).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Se convierte un participante en el movimiento de 
OER! Aprenda sobre contenido abierto y abra la educación, el 
licenciar del contenido abierto, y las ventajas de hacer y de usar 
OER. Usando ejemplos de la vida real de campos comunes de OER, 
usted aprenderá sobre contenido que se adapta y de remezcla para 
resolver sus necesidades. Para el final de este curso, usted 
podrá localizar los materiales que usted puede utilizar en su 
enseñanza y aprender así como la parte algunos sus el propios. 
"cómo la TOS" de los campos comunes de OER es un conjunto de 
módulos que aprenden que se desarrollan fuera del desarrollo de los 
campos comunes de OER, una red de enseñanza y que aprende para 
libre-a-utilice los materiales educativos alrededor del mundo, creado 
y licenciado por el instituto para el estudio de la gerencia del 
conocimiento en la educación (ISKME).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ISKME
FN:ISKME
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205219</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107786</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-how-tos-of-oer-commons</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
