<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105204</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105204</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205730</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Helping Your Child Become a Reader</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ihrem Kind helfend, werden Sie ein Leser</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En aidant votre enfant devenez un lecteur</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ajudando a sua criança transforme-se um leitor</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Aiutando il vostro bambino transformisi in in un 
lettore</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βοηθώντας το παιδί σας γίνετε αναγνώστης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ayudando a su niño haga un programa de lectura</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">offers dozens of activities families may use to help young children learn the alphabet, play with rhymes, read picture books, act out poems, predict what happens next in stories, create a bookcase, enjoy family stories, write notes and stories, and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">bietet Dutzende Aktivitäten, die Familien 
verwenden können, um jungen Kindern zu helfen, das Alphabet zu 
erlernen, Spiel mit Reimen an, liest Abbildung Bücher, fungiert aus 
Gedichten, sagt voraus, was zunächst in den Geschichten geschieht, 
stellt ein Bücherregal her, genießt Familie Geschichten, schreibt 
Anmerkungen und Geschichten und mehr.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">offre des douzaines d'activités que les familles 
peuvent employer pour aider les enfants en bas âge à apprendre 
l'alphabet, le jeu avec des rimes, lit des livres d'image, agit hors 
des poésies, prévoit ce qui se produit ensuite dans les histoires, 
crée une bibliothèque, apprécie des histoires de famille, écrit 
des notes et des histoires, et plus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">oferece dúzias das atividades que as famílias 
podem se usar ajudar a crianças novas aprender o alfabeto, o jogo com
rimas, lêem livros do retrato, agem para fora dos poemas, predizem o 
que acontece em seguida nas histórias, críam um bookcase, aprecíam 
histórias da família, escrevem notas e histórias, e mais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">offre le dozzine delle attività che le famiglie 
possono usare per aiutare i bambini in giovane età ad imparare 
l'alfabeto, gioco con le rime, leggono i libri dell'immagine, si 
comportano verso l'esterno i poems, predicono che cosa accade dopo 
nelle storia, creano uno scaffale, godono le storia della famiglia, 
scrivono le note e le storia e più.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">προσφέρει τις δωδεκάδες των οικογενειών δραστηριοτήτων
μπορεί να χρησιμοποιήσει για να βοηθήσει τα μικρά παιδιά να 
μάθουν το αλφάβητο, παιχνίδι με τους έμμετρους λόγους, διαβάζει 
τα βιβλία εικόνων, ενεργεί έξω ποιήματα, προβλέπει τι συμβαίνει
έπειτα στις ιστορίες, δημιουργεί μια βιβλιοθήκη, απολαμβάνει τις 
οικογενειακές ιστορίες, γράφει τις σημειώσεις και τις ιστορίες, 
και περισσότερων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece docenas de las actividades que las familias
pueden utilizar para ayudar a niños jóvenes a aprender el alfabeto, 
el juego con rimas, lee los libros del cuadro, actúa fuera de los 
poemas, predice qué sucede después en historias, crea un estante 
para libros, goza de historias de la familia, escribe notas e 
historias, y más.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205730</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105204</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/helping-your-child-become-a-reader</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
