<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107154</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107154</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086944</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Great Awakening Comes to Weathersfield, Connecticut: Nathan Cole's Spiritual Travels</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das große Wecken kommt zu Weathersfield, 
Connecticut: Nathan Coles Angelegenheiten-Spielräume</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le grand réveil vient à Weathersfield, le 
Connecticut : Voyages de Chant religieux de Nathan Cole</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Awakening grande vem a Weathersfield, Connecticut:
Cursos Do Espiritual De Nathan Cole</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il risveglio grande viene a Weathersfield, 
Connecticut: Corse Dello Spiritual Di Nathan Cole</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το μεγάλο ξύπνημα έρχεται σε Weathersfield, 
Κοννέκτικατ: Πνευματικά ταξίδια του λάχανου Nathan</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El gran despertar viene a Weathersfield, 
Connecticut: Recorridos Del Espiritual De Nathan Cole</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the 1730s and 1740s many rural folk rejected the enlightened and rational religion that came from the cosmopolitan pulpits and port cities of British North America. Instead, they were attracted to the evangelical religious movement that became known as the Great Awakening. The English Methodist George Whitefield and other itinerant ministers ignited this popular movement with their speaking tours of the colonies. In this account farmer Nathan Cole described hearing the news of Whitefield's approach to his Connecticut town, as fields emptied and the populace converged: "I saw no man at work in his field, but all seemed to be gone. " Like many others during the Great Awakening, Cole achieved an eventual conversation by focusing not on intellectual issues but on emotional experience. Cole took away an egalitarian message about the spiritual equality of all before God, a message that confronted established authorities.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In den vielen landwirtschaftlichen Völkern 1730s 
und 1740s wies die erleuchtete und rationale Religion zurück, die von
den WeltKanzeln und von den Portstädte von britischem 
Nordamerika kam. Stattdessen wurden sie zur evangelischen 
frommen Bewegung angezogen, die als das große Wecken bekannt wurde. 
Das englische methodistische George Whitefield und andere 
reisende Minister zündete diese populäre Bewegung mit ihren 
sprechenden Touren der Kolonien an. In diesem Kontolandwirt 
Nathan Cole, das die Nachrichten von Annäherung Whitefields zu seiner
Connecticut Stadt hörend, wie, auffängt geleert und die 
beschrieben wurde, Bevölkerung lief zusammen: "ich sah keinen 
Mann an der Arbeit in seinem aufzufangen, aber schien ganz, 
wie viele andere während des großen Weckens, Cole gegangen zu 
werden" erzielte ein etwaiges Gespräch, indem ich nicht auf 
intellektuellen Ausgaben aber auf emotionale Erfahrung konzentrierte. 
Cole nahm eine gleichmacherische Meldung über die geistige 
Gleichheit von allen vor Gott, eine Meldung weg, die hergestellte 
Behörden konfrontierte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans les beaucoup de gens 1730s et 1740s ruraux a 
rejeté la religion éclairée et raisonnable qui est venue des 
pupitres cosmopolites et des villes gauches de l'Amérique 
du nord britannique. Au lieu de cela, ils ont été 
attirés au mouvement religieux évangélique qui est devenu notoire 
en tant que grand réveil. George méthodiste anglais 
Whitefield et d'autres ministres ambulants a mis à feu ce mouvement 
populaire avec leurs excursions parlantes des colonies. Dans ce 
fermier Nathan Cole de compte décrit entendre les nouvelles de
l'approche de Whitefield à sa ville du Connecticut, pendant que les 
zones vidaient et la foule a convergé : "je n'ai vu aucun
homme au travail dans son domaine, mais ai tout semblé être allé" 
comme beaucoup d'autres pendant le grand réveil, Cole ai 
réalisé une conversation certaine en se concentrant pas sur les 
questions intellectuelles mais sur une expérience émotive. 
Cole a emporté un message égalitaire au sujet de 
l'égalité spirituelle de tous avant Dieu, un message qui a 
confronté des autorités établies.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em muitos povos 1730s e 1740s rurais rejeitou a 
religião enlightened e racional que veio dos pulpits cosmopolitan e 
das cidades portuárias de America do Norte britânica. Instead,
foram atraídos ao movimento religioso evangelical que se tornou 
sabido como awakening grande. O George methodist inglês 
Whitefield e outros ministros itinerant inflamou este movimento 
popular com suas excursões faladoras das colônias. Neste 
fazendeiro Nathan Cole do cliente descrito ouvir a notícia da 
aproximação de Whitefield a sua cidade de Connecticut, enquanto os 
campos esvaziaram e o populace convergiu: "eu não vi nenhum 
homem no trabalho em seu campo, mas pareci toda ser ido" como muito 
outro durante awakening grande, Cole consegui uma conversação 
eventual focalizando não em edições intelectuais mas na 
experiência emocional. Cole removeu uma mensagem egalitarian 
sobre a igualdade espiritual de tudo antes do deus, uma mensagem que 
confrontasse autoridades estabelecidas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nella molta gente rurale 1730s e 1740s ha 
rifiutato la religione chiarita e razionale che è venuto dai quadri 
di comando cosmopoliti e dalle città port dell'America del Nord 
britannica. Invece, sono stati attratti al movimento religioso 
evangelical che è stato conosciuto come il risveglio grande. Il
George methodist inglese Whitefield ed altri ministri ambulanti ha 
bruciato questo movimento popolare con i loro giri parlanti delle 
colonie. In questo coltivatore Nathan Cole di cliente descritto 
sentire le notizie del metodo del Whitefield alla sua città del 
Connecticut, mentre i campi si sono svuotati ed il populace ha 
converso: "non ho visto uomo sul lavoro nel suo campo, ma 
interamente ho sembrato essere andato" come molti altri durante il 
risveglio grande, Cole ho realizzato una conversazione finale mettendo
a fuoco non sulle edizioni intellettuali ma sull'esperienza 
impressionabile. Cole ha tolto un messaggio egalitario circa 
l'uguaglianza spiritosa di tutti prima del dio, un messaggio che ha 
confrontato le autorità stabilite.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στο 1730s και το 1740s πολλοί αγροτικός λαός 
απέρριψαν τη διαφωτισμένη και λογική θρησκεία που προήλθε από 
κοσμοπολίτικες pulpits και τις πόλεις λιμένων της βρετανικής 
Βόρειας Αμερικής. Αντ' αυτού, προσελκύστηκαν στην 
εβαγγελική θρησκευτική μετακίνηση που έγινε γνωστή ως μεγάλο 
ξύπνημα. Ο αγγλικός μεθοδιστής George Whitefield και 
άλλοι πλανόδιοι υπουργοί ανάφλεξαν αυτό το δημοφιλές κίνημα με 
τους γύρους ομιλίας τους των αποικιών. Σε αυτόν τον αγρότη 
Nathan απολογισμού το λάχανο περιέγραψε την ακοή των ειδήσεων 
της προσέγγισης Whitefield στην πόλη του Κοννέκτικάτ του, 
καθώς τα πεδία που εκκενώθηκαν και ο λαός σύγκλιναν: "Δεν 
εβλέίδα κανένα άτομο στην εργασία στο πεδίο του, αλλά 
όλοι φάνηκαν να. "Όπως πολλούς άλλους κατά τη διάρκεια 
του μεγάλου ξυπνήματος, το λάχανο επέτυχε μια ενδεχόμενη 
συνομιλία με την εστίαση όχι στα διανοητικά ζητήματα αλλά στη 
συναισθηματική εμπειρία. Το λάχανο πήρε μαζί ένα 
egalitarian μήνυμα για την πνευματική ισότητα όλοι ενώπιον του
Θεού, ένα μήνυμα που αντιμετώπισε τις καθιερωμένες αρχές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En la mucha gente rural 1730s y 1740s rechazó la 
religión aclarada y racional que vino de los púlpitos cosmopolitas y
de las ciudades portuarias de Norteamérica británica. En 
lugar, fueron atraídos al movimiento religioso evangélico que se 
conocía como gran despertar. El George methodist inglés 
Whitefield y otros ministros ambulantes encendió este movimiento 
popular con sus viajes de discurso de las colonias. En este 
granjero Nathan Cole de la cuenta descrito oír las noticias del 
acercamiento de Whitefield a su ciudad de Connecticut, como los campos
vaciaron y el populacho convergió: "no vi a ningún hombre en 
el trabajo en su campo, sino me parecía todo ser ido" como muchos 
otros durante gran despertar, Cole alcancé una conversación eventual
centrándose no en ediciones intelectuales sino en experiencia 
emocional. Cole quitó un mensaje igualitario sobre la igualdad 
espiritual de todos antes de dios, un mensaje que enfrentó 
autoridades establecidas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086944</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107154</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-great-awakening-comes-to-weathersfield-connecticut-nathan-coles-spiritual-travels</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
