<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104720</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104720</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087051</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Solitude of Self": Stanton Appeals for Women's Rights</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die Einsamkeit von Selbst": Stanton 
gefällt für Rechte der Frauen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"la solitude de l'Art de l'auto-portrait" : Stanton 
lance un appel pour les droits des femmes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"o solitude do self": Stanton apela para 
direitas das mulheres</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"il solitude dell'auto": Stanton fa appello 
per i diritti delle donne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η μοναξιά μόνου": Εκκλήσεις Stanton για τα 
δικαιώματα των γυναικών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"la soledad del uno mismo": Stanton abroga 
para las derechas de las mujeres</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The struggle for woman suffrage lasted almost a century. The 1848 Woman's Rights Convention at Seneca Falls, New York, initiated public discussion of votes for women, and serious campaigning began with the founding in 1869 of two original (and competing) suffrage organizations--the National Woman Suffrage Association and the American Woman Suffrage Association. The two groups joined forces in 1890 to form the National American Woman Suffrage Association (NAWSA). NAWSA campaigned diligently for the vote in a variety of ways but did not achieve success until the ratification of the Nineteenth Amendment to the U.S. Constitution in 1920. Elizabeth Cady Stanton served for twenty years as the president of the National Woman Suffrage Association and as the first president of NAWSA. In 1892, she resigned at age 77. Her resignation speech, "The Solitude of Self," eloquently articulated the arguments for the equality of women that she had spent her adult life promoting.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Kampf für Fraustimmrecht dauerte fast ein 
Jahrhundert. Die Recht-Versammlung 1848 der Frau am Seneca 
fällt, New York, initialisierte allgemeine Diskussion über Stimmen 
für Frauen, und die ernste Werbetätigkeit fing mit der Gründung 
1869 von zwei ursprünglichen (und dem Konkurrieren) 
Stimmrechtorganisationen -- die nationale Frau-Stimmrecht-Verbindung 
und die amerikanische Frau-Stimmrecht-Verbindung an. Die zwei 
Gruppen verbanden Kräfte 1890, um die nationale amerikanische 
Frau-Stimmrecht-Verbindung (NAWSA) zu bilden. NAWSA warb, mit 
Sorgfalt für die Stimme in einer Vielzahl von Methoden aber erzielte 
Erfolg bis die Bestätigung der 19.änderung nicht zur VEREINIGTE 
STAATEN Beschaffenheit 1920. Elizabeth Cady Stanton diente für 
Zwanzig Jahre als der Präsident der nationalen 
Frau-Stimmrecht-Verbindung und als der erste Präsident von NAWSA. 
1892 fand sie an Alter 77 ab. Ihre Resignationrede, "die 
Einsamkeit von Selbst," artikulierte redegewandt die Argumente 
für die Gleichheit der Frauen, denen sie ihre 
Erwachsenlebenförderung aufgewendet hatte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La lutte pour le suffrage de femme a duré presque
un siècle. La convention 1848 des droits de la femme chez 
Seneca tombe, New York, débat public lancé des voix pour des 
femmes, et la campagne sérieuse a commencé par la fondation dans 
1869 de deux (et la concurrence) organismes initiaux de suffrage -- 
l'association nationale de suffrage de femme et l'association 
américaine de suffrage de femme. Les deux groupes ont joint des
forces en 1890 pour former l'association américaine nationale de 
suffrage de femme (NAWSA). NAWSA a fait campagne diligemment 
pour la voix par une multitude de moyens mais n'a pas réalisé le 
succès jusqu'à la ratification du dix-neuvième amendement à la 
constitution des ETATS-UNIS en 1920. Elizabeth Cady Stanton a 
servi pendant vingt années en tant que président de l'association 
nationale de suffrage de femme et en tant que premier président de 
NAWSA. En 1892, elle a démissionné à l'âge 77. Son 
discours de démission, "la solitude de l'Art de l'auto-portrait," a par 
éloquence articulé les arguments pour l'égalité des femmes qu'elle
avait dépensé son promotion de la vie d'adulte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O esforço para o suffrage da mulher durou quase 
um século. A convenção 1848 das direitas da mulher no seneca 
cai, New York, discussão pública iniciada dos votos para mulheres, e
fazer campanha sério começou com fundar em 1869 de duas (e competir)
organizações originais do suffrage -- a associação nacional do 
suffrage da mulher e a associação americana do suffrage da mulher. 
Os dois grupos juntaram forças em 1890 para dar forma à 
associação americana nacional do suffrage da mulher (NAWSA). 
NAWSA fêz campanha diligently para o voto em uma variedade das 
maneiras mas não conseguiu o sucesso até o ratification da décima 
nona emenda ao constitution de ESTADOS UNIDOS em 1920. Elizabeth
Cady Stanton serviu por vinte anos como o presidente da associação 
nacional do suffrage da mulher e como o primeiro presidente de NAWSA. 
Em 1892, renunciou na idade 77. Seu discurso da renúncia,
"o solitude do self," articulou eloquently os argumentos para a 
igualdade das mulheres que tinha gastado seu promover da vida do 
adulto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La lotta per suffrage della donna ha durato quasi 
un secolo. La convenzione 1848 di diritti della donna a seneca 
cade, New York, discussione pubblica iniziata sui voti per le donne e 
fare una campagna serio ha cominciato con fondare in 1869 di due (e 
competere) organizzazioni originali di suffrage -- l'associazione 
nazionale di suffrage della donna e l'associazione americana di 
suffrage della donna. I due gruppi hanno unito le forze in 1890 
per formare l'associazione americana nazionale di suffrage della donna
(NAWSA). NAWSA ha fatto una campagna diligente per il voto in 
una varietà di modi ma non ha realizzato il successo fino alla 
ratifica della diciannovesima correzione alla costituzione degli STATI
UNITI in 1920. Elizabeth Cady Stanton ha servito per venti anni 
come il presidente dell'associazione nazionale di suffrage della donna
e come il primo presidente di NAWSA. In 1892, si è dimessa 
all'età 77. Il suo discorso di rassegnazione, "il solitude 
dell'auto," eloquente ha articolato gli argomenti per l'uguaglianza 
delle donne che aveva speso la sua promozione di vita 
dell'adulto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η προσπάθεια για την ψήφο γυναικών διάρκεσε σχεδόν 
έναν αιώνα. Η 1848 Συνθήκη δικαιωμάτων της γυναίκας σε 
Σενέκα Falls, τη Νέα Υόρκη, την αρχισμένη δημόσια συζήτηση 
των ψηφοφοριών για τις γυναίκες, και σοβαρή να κάνει εκστρατεία 
άρχισε με την ίδρυση το 1869 δύο αρχικών (και τον ανταγωνισμό)
οργανώσεων ψήφου -- η εθνική ένωση ψήφου γυναικών και η 
αμερικανική ένωση ψήφου γυναικών. Οι δύο ομάδες ένωσαν 
τις δυνάμεις το 1890 για να διαμορφώσουν την εθνική αμερικανική
ένωση ψήφου γυναικών (NAWSA). NAWSA έκανε εκστρατεία
επιμελώς για την ψηφοφορία με ποικίλους τρόπους αλλά δεν επέτυχε
την επιτυχία έως ότου εχρησίμευσε η επικύρωση της δέκατης 
έννατης τροποποίησης στο ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΌ σύνταγμα σε 1920, 
Elizabeth Cady Stanton για είκοσι έτη ως Πρόεδρος της 
εθνικής ένωσης ψήφου γυναικών και ως ο πρώτος Πρόεδρος NAWSA.
Το 1892, παραιτήθηκε στην ηλικία 77, Η ομιλία 
παραίτησής της, "η μοναξιά μόνου," εύγλωττα άρθρωσε τα ορίσματα
για την ισότητα των γυναικών ότι είχε ξοδεψει την ενήλικη 
προαγωγή ζωής της.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La lucha para el sufragio de la mujer casi duró 
un siglo. La convención 1848 de las derechas de la mujer en el 
seneca se cae, Nueva York, discusión pública iniciada de los votos 
para las mujeres, y el hacer campaña serio comenzó con la fundación
en 1869 de dos (y la competición) organizaciones originales del 
sufragio -- la asociación nacional del sufragio de la mujer y la 
asociación americana del sufragio de la mujer. Los dos grupos 
ensamblaron fuerzas en 1890 para formar la asociación americana 
nacional del sufragio de la mujer (NAWSA). NAWSA hizo campaña 
diligente para el voto en una variedad de maneras pero no alcanzó 
éxito hasta la ratificación de la diecinueveavo enmienda a la 
constitución de ESTADOS UNIDOS en 1920. Elizabeth Cady Stanton 
sirvió por veinte años como el presidente de la asociación nacional
del sufragio de la mujer y como el primer presidente de NAWSA. 
En 1892, ella dimitió en la edad 77. Su discurso de la 
dimisión, "la soledad del uno mismo," elocuente articuló los 
argumentos para la igualdad de las mujeres que ella había pasado su 
promover de la vida del adulto.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087051</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104720</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-solitude-of-self-stanton-appeals-for-womens-rights</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
