<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108761</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108761</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085244</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Early Advertising</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Früh Bekanntmachend</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Tôt Annonçant</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Cedo Anunciando</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Presto Facendo pubblicità</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Νωρίς διαφημιστικός</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Temprano Anunciando</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The modern advertising industry really began in the early 1900s. These early advertising images show how companies approached the business of selling products, places, and ideas in the early 20th century.
Overview

The promotion of products, particularly national brands, began to become more prevalent in the early 1900s. Some categories of advertising shown in this group of images are still with us today: cars, cigarettes, and products aimed at homemakers. In California, car dealers and garages used advertising to promote products and services early on. One photograph shows the Lush Garage in Orange promoting Goodrich Tires as the "Best in the Long Run." In 1936, a photographic postcard for the Chevrolet Garage in Pomona offered 12 lube jobs for $6 in time payments. And as another image illustrates, one still-recognizable brand, Schlitz Beer, got on the advertising bandwagon early at an automobile race in 1908.

Photographs of displays from the Westwood Hardware and Furniture Store in 1936 advertise kitchen stoves and camps stoves from Coleman; and Dr. West's toothbrushes, with bristles that "will not get soggy." A 1929 photo shows a baker and two women in costume advertising Piping Pan Cakery Compound in San Diego.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die moderne Werbebranche fing wirklich in den 
frühen 1900s an. Diese frühen bekanntmachenden Bilder zeigen, 
wie Firmen dem Geschäft des Verkaufens der Produkte, der Plätze und 
der Ideen in der frühen 20. century.OverviewThe Förderung der 
Produkte sich näherten, besonders nationale Marken, anfingen, in den 
frühen 1900s überwiegender zu werden. Einige Kategorien 
Bekanntmachen gezeigt in dieser Gruppe Bildern sind noch mit uns 
heute: Autos, Zigaretten und Produkte strebten 
Hauswirtschaftsleiterinen an. In Kalifornien verwendeten 
Autohändler und -garagen das Bekanntmachen, zum der Produkte und der 
Dienstleistungen früh zu fördern an. Eine Fotographie zeigt 
die üppige Garage in der Orange gut, die langfristig fördert 
Goodrich Gummireifen als "." 1936 bot eine fotographische 
Postkarte für die Chevrolet Garage in Pomona 12 Schmieröljobs für 
$6 in den Zeitzahlungen an. Und wie ein anderes Bild 
veranschaulicht, eine noch-erkennbare Marke, das Schlitz Bier, früh 
eingestiegen in das bekanntmachende Geschäft an einem Autorennen in 
1908.Photographs der Bildschirmanzeigen vom Westwood Hardware-und 
Möbel-Speicher in 1936 machen Sie Kücheöfen bekannt und kampiert 
Öfen von Coleman; und Zahnbürsten des Dr. Wests, mit Borsten, 
die "erhält nicht feucht." Ein Foto 1929 zeigt einen Bäcker 
und zwei Frauen im Kostüm, das friedliches Wanne Cakery Mittel in San
Diego bekanntmacht.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'industrie de publicité moderne a vraiment 
commencé au début des années 1900. Ces images de publicité 
tôt montrent comment les compagnies ont approché les affaires de 
vendre des produits, des endroits, et des idées dans la début du 
20ème promotion de century.OverviewThe des produits, en particulier 
des marques nationales, ont commencé à devenir plus répandues au 
début des années 1900. Quelques catégories de la publicité 
montrées dans ce groupe d'images sont toujours avec nous aujourd'hui 
: les voitures, les cigarettes, et les produits ont visé des 
ménagères. En Californie, les marchands et les garages de 
voiture ont utilisé la publicité pour favoriser des produits et des 
services dès l'abord. Une photographie montre le garage 
abondant dans l'orange favorisant des pneus de Goodrich en tant que 
"mieux à la longue." En 1936, une carte postale photographique 
pour le garage de Chevrolet dans Pomona a offert les 12 travaux de 
lubrifiant pour $6 dans des paiements de temps. Et comme une 
autre image illustre, une marque encore-reconnaissable, bière de 
Schlitz, obtenue dans le mouvement de publicité tôt à une course 
d'automobile dans 1908.Photographs des affichages du magasin de 
meubles de matériel et de Westwood dans 1936 annoncez les fourneaux 
de cuisine et campez des fourneaux de Coleman ; et brosses à 
dents de Dr. West's, avec les brins qui "n'obtiendra pas détrempé." 
Une photo 1929 montre un boulanger et deux femmes dans le 
costume annonçant le composé sifflant de Cakery de casserole à San 
Diego.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A indústria anunciando moderna começou realmente
nos 1900s adiantados. Estas imagens anunciando adiantadas 
mostram como as companhias aproximaram o negócio de vender produtos, 
lugares, e idéias no 20o promotion adiantado de century.OverviewThe 
dos produtos, particularmente tipos nacionais, começaram a tornar-se 
mais prevalent nos 1900s adiantados. Algumas categorias de 
anunciar mostradas neste grupo das imagens são ainda com nós hoje: 
os carros, os cigarros, e os produtos visaram homemakers. 
Em Califórnia, os negociantes e as garagens de carro usaram 
anunciar para promover cedo produtos e serviços sobre. Uma 
fotografia mostra a garagem lush na laranja que promove pneus de 
Goodrich como "melhor a longo prazo." Em 1936, um postcard 
fotográfico para a garagem de Chevrolet em Pomona ofereceu 12 
trabalhos do lubrificante para $6 a tempo pagamentos. E como uma
outra imagem ilustra, um tipo ainda-still-recognizable, cerveja de 
Schlitz, começada no bandwagon anunciando cedo em uma raça de 
automóvel em 1908.Photographs dos indicadores da loja da ferragem e 
de furniture de Westwood em 1936 anuncie fogões da cozinha e acampe 
fogões de Coleman; e toothbrushes do Dr. Oeste, com cerdas que 
"não começará soggy." Uma foto 1929 mostra um padeiro e duas 
mulheres no traje que anuncia composto tranqüilo de Cakery da bandeja
em San Diego.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'industria di pubblicità moderna realmente ha 
cominciato all'inizio degli anni 1900. Queste immagini di 
pubblicità iniziali mostrano come le aziende si sono avvicinate al 
commercio di vendere i prodotti, i posti e le idee nell'inizio del 
20esimo promozione di century.OverviewThe dei prodotti, specialmente 
marche nazionali, hanno cominciato a diventare più prevalenti 
all'inizio degli anni 1900. Alcune categorie di pubblicità 
indicate in questo gruppo delle immagini sono ancora oggi con noi: 
gli automobili, le sigarette ed i prodotti hanno puntato sulle 
casalinghe. Nella California, i commercianti ed i garage di 
automobile hanno usato la pubblicità per promuovere i prodotti ed i 
servizi nella fase iniziale. Una fotografia mostra il garage 
lush in arancio che promuove il più bene a lungo termine le gomme di 
Goodrich come "." In 1936, una cartolina fotografica per il 
garage della Chevrolet in Pomona ha offerto 12 lavori dell'olio 
lubrificante per $6 nei pagamenti di tempo. E come un'altra 
immagine illustra, una marca ancora-riconoscibile, birra di Schlitz, 
ottenuta presto sul carro di pubblicità ad una corsa di automobile in
1908.Photographs delle visualizzazioni dal deposito del hardware e di 
mobilia di Westwood in 1936 faccia pubblicità alle stufe della cucina
e si accampa stufe da Coleman; e toothbrushes del Dott. West, 
con le setole che "non otterrà inzuppato." Una foto 1929 mostra
un panettiere e due donne in costume che fa pubblicità al residuo 
stridente di Cakery della vaschetta a San Diego.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η σύγχρονη διαφημιστική βιομηχανία άρχισε πραγματικά 
στις αρχές των δεκαετιών του 20ου αιώνα. Αυτές οι πρόωρες 
εικόνες διαφήμισης επιδεικνύουν πώς οι επιχειρήσεις πλησίασαν 
την επιχείρηση της πώλησης των προϊόντων, θέσεις, και οι ιδέες 
στην πρόωρη προώθηση του 20ού αιώνα OverviewThe των 
προϊόντων, ιδιαίτερα εθνικά εμπορικά σήματα, άρχισαν να 
γίνονται πιό επικρατούσες στις αρχές των δεκαετιών του 20ου 
αιώνα. Μερικές κατηγορίες διαφήμισης που εμφανίζονται σε 
αυτήν την ομάδα εικόνων είναι ακόμα με μας σήμερα: τα 
αυτοκίνητα, τα τσιγάρα, και τα προϊόντα στόχευσαν στους 
νοικοκύρες. Σε Καλιφόρνια, οι έμποροι και τα γκαράζ 
αυτοκινήτων χρησιμοποίησαν τη διαφήμιση για να προωθήσουν τα 
προϊόντα και τις υπηρεσίες αρχικά. Μια φωτογραφία 
εμφανίζει πολύβλαστο γκαράζ στο πορτοκάλι προάγοντας τις ρόδες 
Goodrich ως "καλύτερο μακροπρόθεσμα." Το 1936, μια 
φωτογραφική κάρτα για το γκαράζ Chevrolet σε Pomona πρόσφερε
12 εργασίες λιπαντικού ελαίου για $6 έγκαιρες πληρωμές. 
Και όπως μια άλλη εικόνα επεξηγεί, ένα ακόμα-αναγνωρίσιμο
εμπορικό σήμα, μπύρα Schlitz, παρμένος στη μόδα διαφήμισης 
νωρίς σε μια αυτοκινητική φυλή σε 1908.Photographs των 
παρουσιάσεων από το υλικό Westwood και επίπλων το κατάστημα το
1936 διαφημίζει τις σόμπες κουζινών και τις σόμπες στρατόπεδων
από Coleman  και οδοντόβουρτσες του Δρ West's, με τις 
σκληρές τρίχες που "δεν θα πάρει soggy." Μια φωτογραφία 
του 1929 εμφανίζει σε αρτοποιό και σε δύο γυναίκες στη 
σωλήνωση διαφήμισης κοστουμιών παν ένωση Cakery στο Σαν 
Ντιέγκο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La industria de publicidad moderna realmente 
comenzó en los 1900s tempranos. Estas imágenes de publicidad 
tempranas muestran cómo las compañías acercaron al negocio de 
vender productos, lugares, e ideas en la vigésima promoción temprana
de century.OverviewThe de productos, determinado las marcas de 
fábrica nacionales, comenzaron a llegar a ser más frecuentes en los 
1900s tempranos. Algunas categorías de la publicidad mostradas 
en este grupo de imágenes todavía están con nosotros hoy: los
coches, los cigarrillos, y los productos tuvieron como objetivo a 
caseros. En California, los distribuidores y los garages de 
coche utilizaron la publicidad para promover productos y servicios 
temprano encendido. Una fotografía muestra el garage lush en la
naranja que promueve los neumáticos de Goodrich como "lo más mejor 
posible en el funcionamiento largo." En 1936, una postal 
fotográfica para el garage de Chevrolet en Pomona ofreció 12 
trabajos del lubricante para $6 en pagos del tiempo. Y como otra
imagen ilustra, una marca de fábrica au'n-reconocible, cerveza de 
Schlitz, conseguida en el carro de la banda de música de publicidad 
temprano en una raza de automóvil en 1908.Photographs de 
visualizaciones del almacén de la dotación física y de muebles de 
Westwood en 1936 anuncie las estufas de la cocina y acampa las estufas
de Coleman; y cepillos de dientes del Dr. West's, con las cerdas
que "no conseguirá empapado." Una foto 1929 muestra a un 
panadero y a dos mujeres en el traje que anuncia el compuesto 
aflautado de Cakery de la cacerola en San Diego.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085244</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108761</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/early-advertising</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
