<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108694</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108694</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205711</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Around the World in 1896</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Um die Welt 1896</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Autour du monde en 1896</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em torno do mundo em 1896</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Intorno al mondo in 1896</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε όλο τον κόσμο το 1896</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Alrededor del mundo en 1896</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a lesson in which students take a trip around the world in 1896 using an online collection of 900 images. The collection includes photos of railroads, elephants, camels, horses, sleds and sleighs, sedan chairs, rickshaws, and other types of transportation, as well as city views, street and harbor scenes, landscapes, and people in North Africa, Asia, Australia, and Oceania.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist eine Lektion, in der Kursteilnehmer eine Reise
um die Welt 1896 mit einer Onlineansammlung von 900 Bildern nehmen. 
Die Ansammlung enthält Fotos der Eisenbahnen, der Elefanten, 
der Kamele, der Pferde, der Schlitten und der sleighs, der sedan 
Stühle, der rickshaws und anderer Typen Transport, sowie 
Stadtansichten, Straße und Hafenszenen, Landschaften und Leute in 
Nordafrika, in Asien, in Australien und in Ozeanien.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est une leçon dans laquelle les étudiants 
prennent un voyage autour du monde en 1896 en utilisant une collection
en ligne de 900 images. La collection inclut des photos des 
chemins de fer, les éléphants, les chameaux, les chevaux, les 
traîneaux et les traîneaux, les chaises de berline, les 
pousse-pousse, et d'autres types de transport, comme des vues de ville, 
des scènes de rue et de port, des horizontaux, et les gens en Afrique
du nord, en Asie, en Australie, et Océanie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é uma lição em que os estudantes fazem exame de
um desengate em torno do mundo em 1896 usando uma coleção em linha 
de 900 imagens. A coleção inclui fotos das estradas de ferro, 
os elefantes, os camelos, os cavalos, os trenós e os sleighs, 
cadeiras sedan, rickshaws, e outros tipos de transporte, assim como 
vistas da cidade, cenas da rua e do porto, paisagens, e povos em 
África norte, em Ásia, em Austrália, e em Oceania.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è una lezione in cui gli allievi prendono un 
viaggio intorno al mondo in 1896 usando una collezione in linea di 900
immagini. L'accumulazione include le foto delle ferrovie, 
elefanti, cammelli, cavalli, slitte e sleighs, sedie sedan, rickshaws 
ed altri tipi di trasporti, come pure le viste della città, scene del
porto e della via, paesaggi e la gente in Africa del nord, in Asia, in
Australia ed Oceania.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι ένα μάθημα στο οποίο οι σπουδαστές παίρνουν 
ένα ταξίδι σε όλο τον κόσμο το 1896 χρησιμοποιώντας μια σε 
απευθείας σύνδεση συλλογή 900 εικόνων. Η συλλογή 
περιλαμβάνει τις φωτογραφίες των σιδηροδρόμων, των ελεφάντων, των 
καμηλών, των αλόγων, των ελκήθρων και των ελκήθρων, των καρεκλών 
φορείων, των δίτροχων χειραμαξών, και άλλων τύπων μεταφοράς, 
καθώς επίσης και όψεων πόλεων, σκηνών οδών και λιμανιών, 
τοπίων, και ανθρώπων στη βόρεια Αφρική, την Ασία, την Αυστραλία,
και την Ωκεανία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es una lección en la cual los estudiantes toman 
un viaje alrededor del mundo en 1896 usando una colección en línea 
de 900 imágenes. La colección incluye las fotos de 
ferrocarriles, los elefantes, los camellos, los caballos, los trineos 
y los sleighs, las sillas del sedán, los rickshaws, y otros tipos
de transporte, tan bien como opiniones de la ciudad, las escenas de la
calle y del puerto, los paisajes, y gente en África del norte, Asia, 
Australia, y Oceanía.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205711</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108694</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/around-the-world-in-1896</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
