<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106032</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106032</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086254</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">How Many Socialists Does It Take To Screw in a Light Bulb?: Finding Humor and Pathos in Class Struggle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wieviele Sozialisten es zur Schraube in einer 
Glühlampe? nimmt: Finden von von Stimmung und von von Pathose 
im Kategorie Kampf</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Combien de socialistes il prend à la vis dans une
ampoule ? : Conclusion de l'humeur et du pathétique dans la 
lutte de classe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quantos socialists ele fazem exame ao parafuso em 
um bulbo claro?: Encontrando o humor e o pathos na luta de 
classes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Quanti socialisti esso prende alla vite in una 
lampadina?: Individuazione umore e del pathos nella lotta di 
codice categoria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πόσοι σοσιαλιστές αυτό παίρνουν για να βιδώσουν μέσα
έναν ελαφρύ βολβό;: Εύρεση του χιούμορ και του πάθου στην 
προσπάθεια κλάσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cuántos socialistas él llevan el tornillo en una
bombilla?: Encontrar humor y pathos en lucha de clase</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The  Appeal to Reason  was the most popular radical publication in American history. This socialist newspaper, whose founding in 1895 predated the creation of the Socialist Party in 1901, reached a paid circulation of more than three-quarters of a million people by 1913. During political campaigns and crises, it often sold more than four million individual copies. From its headquarters in Girard, Kansas, the  Appeal  published an eclectic mix of news (particularly of strikes and political campaigns), essays, poetry, fiction, humor, and cartoons. During and after World War I, the paper declined in circulation because of the deaths and departures of key editorial figures, the declining fortunes of the Socialist Party, and the repression of U.S. radicalism. It ceased publishication in November 1922. These snippets of working-class humor and human drama were compiled for the December 23, 1911, issue.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Anklang an Grund war die populärste radikale 
Publikation in der amerikanischen Geschichte. Diese 
sozialistische Zeitung, deren die Gründung in 1895 die Kreation der 
sozialistischen Partei 1901 zurückdatierte, erreichte eine 
zahlende Zirkulation von mehr als Dreiviertel von Million Leuten bis 
zum 1913. Während der politischen Kampagnen und der Krisen 
verkaufte sie häufig mehr als vier Million einzelne Exemplare. 
Von seinen Hauptsitzen in Girard, veröffentlichte Kansas, 
der Anklang eine eklektische Mischung der Nachrichten (besonders von 
Schlägen und von politischen Kampagnen), der Versuche, der Poesie, 
der Erfindung, der Stimmung und der Karikaturen. Während und 
nach des Ersten Weltkrieges sank das Papier in der Zirkulation wegen 
der Todesfälle und der Abfahrt der redaktionellen 
Schlüsselabbildungen, der abfallenden Vermögen der sozialistischen 
Partei und der Unterdrückung der VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Radikalismus. Es hörte publishication im November 1922 auf. 
Diese snippets der Arbeiterklassestimmung und des menschlichen 
Dramas wurden für den Dezember 23, 1911, Ausgabe kompiliert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'appel à la raison était la plus populaire 
publication radicale dans l'histoire américaine. Ce journal 
socialiste, dont la fondation dans 1895 a antidaté la création du 
parti socialiste en 1901, a atteint une circulation payée plus de de 
trois quarts de million de personnes d'ici 1913. Pendant des 
campagnes et des crises politiques, il a souvent vendu plus de quatre 
millions de différentes copies. De ses sièges sociaux dans 
Girard, le Kansas, l'appel a édité un mélange éclectique des 
nouvelles (en particulier des grèves et des campagnes politiques), 
des essais, de la poésie, de la fiction, de l'humeur, et des dessins 
animés. Pendant et après la Première Guerre Mondiale, le 
papier a diminué dans la circulation en raison des décès et des 
départs des figures éditoriales principales, des fortunes en baisse 
du parti socialiste, et de la répression du radicalisme des 
ETATS-UNIS. Il a cessé le publishication en novembre 1922. 
Ces extraits d'humeur de classe ouvrier et de drame humain 
ont été compilés pour 23 décembre 1911, issue.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A apelação à razão era a publicação radical 
a mais popular no history americano. Este jornal socialist, cuja
fundar em 1895 predated a criação do partido socialist em 1901, 
alcançou uma circulação paga mais de de três quartos de povos de 
milhão por 1913. Durante campanhas e crises políticas, vendeu 
frequentemente mais de quatro milhão cópias individuais. De 
suas matrizes em Girard, Kansas, a apelação publicou uma mistura 
eclectic da notícia (particularmente das batidas e de campanhas 
políticas), dos essays, da poesia, do fiction, do humor, e dos 
cartoons. Durante e após o world.war.i, o papel declinou na 
circulação por causa das mortes e das partidas das figuras editorial
chaves, das fortunas declinando do partido socialist, e do repression 
do radicalism de ESTADOS UNIDOS. Cessou o publishication em 
novembro 1922. Estes snippets do humor do working-class e do 
drama humano foram compilados para dezembro o 23, 1911, edição.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'appello a motivo era la pubblicazione radicale 
più popolare nella storia americana. Questo giornale 
socialista, di cui fondare in 1895 predated la creazione del partito 
socialista in 1901, ha raggiunto una circolazione paid più di di tre 
quarti di di milioni di persone entro 1913. Durante le campagne 
e le crisi politiche, ha venduto spesso più di quattro milione 
diverse copie. Dalle relative sedi in Girard, Kansas, l'appello 
ha pubblicato una miscela eclettica delle notizie (specialmente dei 
colpi e delle campagne politiche), dei saggi, della poesia, del 
romanzo, dell'umore e dei fumetti. Durante e dopo il 
world.war.i, la carta ha declinato nella circolazione a causa delle 
morti e delle partenze delle figure editoriali chiave, delle fortune 
declinanti del partito socialista e della repressione del radicalism 
degli STATI UNITI. Ha cessato il publishication nel mese di 
novembre del 1922. Questi snippets di umore della classe operaia
e del dramma umano sono stati compilati per 23 dicembre 1911, 
edizione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η έκκληση στο λόγο ήταν η δημοφιλέστερη ριζική 
δημοσίευση στην αμερικανική ιστορία. Αυτή η σοσιαλιστική 
εφημερίδα, της οποίας η ίδρυση το 1895 προηγήθηκε χρονικώς τη 
δημιουργία του Σοσιαλιστικού Κόμματος το 1901, έφθασε σε μια 
πληρωμένη κυκλοφορία περισσότερο από των τριών τετάρτων 
εκατομμύριο ανθρώπων από 1913, Κατά τη διάρκεια των 
πολιτικών εκστρατειών και των κρίσεων, πώλησε συχνά περισσότερα 
από τέσσερα εκατομμύριο μεμονωμένα αντίγραφα. Από την 
έδρα της στο Girard, Κάνσας, η έκκληση δημοσίευσε ένα 
εκλεκτικό μίγμα των ειδήσεων (ιδιαίτερα των απεργιών και των 
πολιτικών εκστρατειών), των δοκίμιων, της ποίησης, της 
μυθιστοριογραφίας, του χιούμορ, και των κινούμενων σχεδίων. 
Κατά τη διάρκεια και μετά από του παγκόσμιου πολέμου Ι, το
έγγραφο μειώθηκε στην κυκλοφορία λόγω των θανάτων και των 
αναχωρήσεων των βασικών εκδοτικών αριθμών, τις μειωμένος τύχες 
του Σοσιαλιστικού Κόμματος, και την καταστολή της ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ 
ριζοσπαστισμού. Έπαψε το publishication τον Νοέμβριο του 
1922. Αυτά τα αποκόματα του χιούμορ εργατικών τάξεων και
του ανθρώπινου δράματος μεταγλωττίστηκαν για τις 23 Δεκεμβρίου 
..1911, ζήτημα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La súplica a la razón era la publicación 
radical más popular de la historia americana. Este periódico 
socialista, que la fundación en 1895 predated la creación del 
partido socialista en 1901, alcanzó una circulación pagada de más 
de tres cuartos millones de personas antes de 1913. Durante 
campañas y crisis políticas, vendió a menudo más de cuatro 
millones de copias individuales. De sus jefaturas en Girard, 
Kansas, la súplica publicó una mezcla ecléctica de las noticias 
(determinado de huelgas y de campañas políticas), de los ensayos, de
la poesía, de la ficción, del humor, y de historietas. Durante
y después de Primera Guerra Mundial, el papel declinó en la 
circulación debido a las muertes y las salidas de las figuras 
editoriales dominantes, de las fortunas que declinaban del partido 
socialista, y de la represión del radicalismo de ESTADOS UNIDOS. 
Cesó el publishication en noviembre de 1922. Estos 
snippets del humor de la clase obrera y del drama humano fueron 
compilados para 23 de diciembre de 1911, edición.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086254</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106032</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/how-many-socialists-does-it-take-to-screw-in-a-light-bulb-finding-humor-and-pathos-in-class-struggle</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
