<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107406</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107406</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212715</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Seasons and the Earth's Orbit - Milankovitch Cycles</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Jahreszeiten und die Bahn der Masse - 
Milankovitch Schleifen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les saisons et l'orbite de la terre - cycles de 
Milankovitch</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As estações e a órbita da terra - ciclos de 
Milankovitch</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le stagioni e l'orbita della terra - cicli di 
Milankovitch</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι εποχές και η γήινη τροχιά - κύκλοι Milankovitch</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las estaciones y la órbita de la tierra - ciclos 
de Milankovitch</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Astronomical Applications Department (AAD) of the U.S. Naval Observatory computes, from fundamental astronomical reference data, the position, brightness, and other observable characteristics of celestial bodies, as well as the circumstances of astronomical phenomena. This page describes the Earth's orbit, seasons and their relation to Milankovitch cycles. Users can also follow links to the AAD's publications, data services, software, FAQ and research.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die astronomische Anwendungen Abteilung (AAD) der 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Marinesternwarte berechnet, von den grundlegenden 
astronomischen Bezugsdaten, die Position, Helligkeit und andere 
wahrnehmbare Eigenschaften der Himmelskörper, sowie die Umstände der
astronomischen Phänomene. Diese Seite beschreibt die Bahn der 
Masse, die Jahreszeiten und ihre Relation zu den Milankovitch 
Schleifen. Benutzer können Links zu des den Publikationen AADs,
zu den Datendienstleistungen, zur Software, zum FAQ und zur Forschung 
auch folgen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le service astronomique d'applications (AAD) de 
l'observatoire naval des ETATS-UNIS calcule, des données 
astronomiques fondamentales de référence, la position, l'éclat, et 
d'autres caractéristiques observables des corps célestes, aussi bien
que les circonstances des phénomènes astronomiques. Cette page
décrit l'orbite de la terre, des saisons et leur relation aux cycles 
de Milankovitch. Les utilisateurs peuvent également suivre des 
liens aux publications de l'AAD, aux services de données, au 
logiciel, au FAQ et à la recherche.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O departamento astronômico das aplicações (AAD)
do obervatório naval de ESTADOS UNIDOS computa, dos dados 
astronômicos fundamentais da referência, a posição, o brilho, e 
outras características observable de corpos celestiais, as.well.as as
circunstâncias de fenômenos astronômicos. Esta página 
descreve a órbita da terra, estações e sua relação aos ciclos de 
Milankovitch. Os usuários podem também seguir as ligações 
às publicações do AAD, aos serviços dos dados, ao software, ao FAQ
e à pesquisa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il reparto astronomico di applicazioni (AAD) 
dell'osservatorio navale degli STATI UNITI computa, dai dati 
astronomici fondamentali di riferimento, la posizione, la luminosità 
ed altre caratteristiche osservabili dei corpi celesti, così come le 
circostanze dei fenomeni astronomici. Questa pagina descrive 
l'orbita della terra, le stagioni ed il loro rapporto con cicli di 
Milankovitch. Gli utenti possono anche seguire i collegamenti 
alle pubblicazioni del AAD, ai servizi di dati, al software, al FAQ ed
alla ricerca.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το αστρονομικό τμήμα εφαρμογών (aad) του 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΎ ναυτικού παρατηρητήριου υπολογίζει, από τα 
θεμελιώδη αστρονομικά στοιχεία αναφοράς, τη θέση, τη 
φωτεινότητα, και άλλα αισθητά χαρακτηριστικά των ουράνιων 
οργανισμών, καθώς επίσης και τις περιστάσεις των αστρονομικών 
φαινομένων. Αυτή η σελίδα περιγράφει τη γήινη τροχιά, τις 
εποχές και τη σχέση τους με τους κύκλους Milankovitch. Οι 
χρήστες μπορούν επίσης να ακολουθήσουν τις συνδέσεις με τις 
aad δημοσιεύσεις, τις υπηρεσίες στοιχείων, το λογισμικό, το 
FAQ και την έρευνα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El departamento astronómico de las aplicaciones 
(AAD) del observatorio naval de ESTADOS UNIDOS computa, de datos 
astronómicos fundamentales de la referencia, la posición, el brillo,
y otras características observables de cuerpos celestes, así como 
las circunstancias de fenómenos astronómicos. Esta paginación
describe la órbita de la tierra, estaciones y su relación a los 
ciclos de Milankovitch. Los utilizadores pueden también seguir 
conexiones a las publicaciones del AAD, a los servicios de los datos, 
al software, al FAQ y a la investigación.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212715</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107406</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-seasons-and-the-earths-orbit-milankovitch-cycles</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
