<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103432</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103432</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1221201388</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Module Four: Money Management</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Modul Vier: Gelddisposition</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Module Quatre : Gestion de fortunes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Módulo Quatro: Gerência De Dinheiro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Modulo Quattro: Gestione Di Soldi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ενότητα τέσσερα: Διαχείριση χρημάτων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Módulo Cuatro: Gerencia De Dinero</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Money Management may be defined as the process of managing money, including investments, budgeting, banking, and taxes. Managing your money is an essential life skill. When you know what you're doing, it really isn't so difficult. Once you've left home, the only person responsible for your financial health is you, so it's good to know the essentials. Managing your money can help reduce the stress levels that you experience throughout your life. It can help you to plan for unexpected events and expenses. A budget is a plan for spending and savings. It is a financial plan of income and expenditure which assists you in managing your finances. Subsequently we will learn about appropriate budgeting principles. Some learners make the choice and become entrepreneurs even while they are formally studying: they provide services such as barbering and manicures for a small financial return from their friends. This module will consider the qualities and the main tools of an entrepreneur.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gelddisposition kann als der Prozeß des 
Handhabens des Geldes, einschließlich Investitionen, das Planen, das 
Bankkontos Haben Bankkontos Haben und die Steuern definiert werden. 
Ihr Geld zu handhaben ist eine wesentliche Lebenfähigkeit. 
Wenn Sie wissen, was Sie tun, ist es wirklich nicht so 
schwierig. Sobald Sie linkes Haus haben, ist die einzige Person,
die für Ihre finanzielle Gesundheit verantwortlich ist, Sie, also ist
es gut, die Wesensmerkmale zu kennen. Das Handhaben Ihres Geldes
kann helfen, die Druckstufen zu verringern, die Sie während Ihrer 
Lebensdauer erfahren. Es kann Ihnen helfen, für unerwartete 
Fälle und Unkosten zu planen. Ein Etat ist ein Plan für 
Ausgabe und Sparungen. Es ist ein finanzieller Plan des 
Einkommens und der Aufwendung, der Vorlagen Sie, wenn Ihre Finanzen 
gehandhabt werden. Nachher erlernen wir über passende 
Budgetierungsgrundsätze. Einige Anfänger treffen die Wahl und 
werden Unternehmer, sogar während sie formal studieren: sie 
stellen Services wie Barbering und Maniküren für eine kleine 
finanzielle Rückkehr von ihren Freunden zur Verfügung. Dieses 
Modul betrachtet die Qualitäten und die Haupthilfsmittel eines 
Unternehmers.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La gestion de fortunes peut être définie comme 
processus de contrôler l'argent, y compris des investissements, 
économiser, banques, et des impôts. La gestion de votre argent
est une compétence essentielle de la vie. Quand vous savez ce 
que vous faites, il n'est pas vraiment aussi difficile. Une fois
que vous avez la maison gauche, la seule personne chargée de votre 
santé financière est vous, ainsi il est bon de connaître les bases.
La gestion de votre argent peut aider à réduire les niveaux 
d'effort que vous éprouvez durant toute votre vie. Elle peut 
vous aider à projeter pour des événements et des dépenses 
inattendus. Un budget est un plan pour la dépense et 
l'épargne. C'est un plan financier du revenu et de la dépense 
qui des aides vous en contrôlant vos finances. Ultérieurement 
nous nous renseignerons sur des principes économisants appropriés. 
Quelques étudiants font le choix et deviennent des 
entrepreneurs même tandis qu'ils étudient formellement : ils 
fournissent des services tels que barbering et manucures pour un petit
retour financier de leurs amis. Ce module considérera les 
qualités et les outils principaux d'un entrepreneur.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A gerência de dinheiro pode ser definida como o 
processo de controlar o dinheiro, including investimentos, incluir no 
orçamento, depositar, e impostos. Controlar seu dinheiro é uma
habilidade essencial da vida. Quando você sabe o que você 
está fazendo, não é realmente assim difícil. Uma vez que 
você tem a HOME esquerda, a única pessoa responsável para sua 
saúde financeira é você, assim que é bom saber os fundamentos. 
Controlar seu dinheiro pode ajudar reduzir os níveis do stress 
que você experimenta durante todo sua vida. Pode ajudar-lhe 
planear para eventos e despesas inesperados. Um orçamento é 
uma planta para a despesa e as economias. É uma planta 
financeira da renda e da despesa que assistências você em controlar 
suas finanças. Subseqüentemente nós aprenderemos sobre 
princípios incluindo no orçamento apropriados. Alguns learners
fazem a escolha e transformam-se empreendedores mesmo quando estudarem
formalmente: fornecem serviços tais como barbering e manicures 
para um retorno financeiro pequeno de seus amigos. Este módulo 
considerará as qualidades e as ferramentas principais de um 
empreendedor.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La gestione di soldi può essere definita come il 
processo di gestione dei soldi, compreso gli investimenti, stanziare, 
contare e le tasse. La gestione dei vostri soldi è un'abilità 
essenziale di vita. Quando conoscete che cosa state facendo, 
realmente non è così difficile. Una volta che avete sede di 
sinistra, l'unica persona responsabile della vostra salute finanziaria
è voi, in modo da è buono da conoscere il necessario. La 
gestione dei vostri soldi può contribuire a ridurre i livelli di 
sforzo che avvertite durante la vostra vita. Può aiutarla a 
progettare per gli eventi e le spese inattesi. Un preventivo è 
un programma per spendere ed il risparmio. È un 
programma finanziario di reddito e di dispendio che aiuti voi nella 
gestione delle vostre finanze. Successivamente impareremo circa 
i principii stanzianti adatti. Alcuni principianti fanno la 
scelta e diventano imprenditori persino mentre stanno studiando 
formalmente: forniscono i servizi quali barbering ed i manicures
per un piccolo ritorno finanziario dai loro amici. Questo modulo
considererà le qualità e gli strumenti principali di un 
imprenditore.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η διαχείριση χρημάτων μπορεί να οριστεί ως η 
διαδικασία τα χρήματα, συμπεριλαμβανομένων των επενδύσεων, της 
σύνταξης προϋπολογισμού, της κατάθεσης, και των φόρων. Η 
διαχείριση των χρημάτων σας είναι μια ουσιαστική ικανότητα ζωής.
Όταν ξέρετε τι κάνετε, δεν είναι πραγματικά τόσο δύσκολο.
Μόλις αφήσετε το σπίτι, μόνο αρμόδιος για την οικονομική 
υγεία σας είναι εσύ, έτσι είναι καλό να είναι γνωστά τα 
προϊόντα πρώτης ανάγκης. Η διαχείριση των χρημάτων σας 
μπορεί να βοηθήσει να μειώσει τα επίπεδα πίεσης που δοκιμάζετε 
καθ' όλη τη διάρκεια της ζωής σας. Μπορεί να σας βοηθήσει 
για να προγραμματίσει για τα απροσδόκητες γεγονότα και τις 
δαπάνες. Ένας προϋπολογισμός είναι ένα σχέδιο για τα 
έξοδα και την αποταμίευση. Είναι ένα οικονομικό σχέδιο του
εισοδήματος και των δαπανών που σας βοηθά στη διαχείριση των 
πόρων χρηματοδότησής σας. Στη συνέχεια θα μάθουμε για τις 
κατάλληλες αρχές σύνταξης προϋπολογισμού. Μερικοί 
αρχάριοι κάνουν την επιλογή και γίνονται επιχειρηματίες ακόμη 
και ενώ μελετούν τυπικά: παρέχουν τις υπηρεσίες όπως και 
τα μανικιούρ για μια μικρή οικονομική επιστροφή από τους φίλους 
τους. Αυτή η ενότητα θα εξετάσει τις ιδιότητες και τα 
βασικά εργαλεία ενός επιχειρηματία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La gerencia de dinero se puede definir como el 
proceso de manejar el dinero, incluyendo inversiones, el presupuesto, 
depositar, e impuestos. El manejo de su dinero es una habilidad 
esencial de la vida. Cuando usted sabe lo que usted está 
haciendo, realmente no es tan difícil. Una vez que usted tenga 
hogar izquierdo, la única persona responsable de su salud financiera 
es usted, así que es bueno saber el esencial. El manejo de su 
dinero puede ayudar a reducir los niveles de la tensión que usted 
experimenta a través de su vida. Puede ayudarle a planear para 
los acontecimientos y los costos inesperados. Un presupuesto es 
un plan para el gasto y los ahorros. Es un plan financiero de la
renta y del gasto que las ayudas usted en el manejo de sus finanzas. 
Aprenderemos posteriormente sobre principios de presupuesto 
apropiados. Algunos principiantes hacen la opción y hacen 
empresarios incluso mientras que están estudiando formalmente: 
proporcionan a servicios tales como barbering y manicures para 
una vuelta financiera pequeña de sus amigos. Este módulo 
considerará las calidades y las herramientas principales de un 
empresario.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1221201388</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103432</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/module-four-money-management</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
