<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105943</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105943</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206329</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Glorieta and Raton Passes: Gateways to the Southwest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Glorieta und Raton Durchläufe: Gateways zum
Südwesten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Passages de Glorieta et de Raton : Gateways 
au sud-ouest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Passagens de Glorieta e de Raton: Gateways 
ao sudoeste</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Passaggi di Raton e di Glorieta: Gateway al 
sud-ovest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Glorieta και περάσματα Raton: Πύλη στο 
νοτιοδυτικό σημείο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Pasos de Glorieta y de Raton: Gateways al 
sudoeste</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">examines the role of these two passes in ensuring that the Southwest would become and remain part of the U.S. Learn about traders and armies that depended on the passes, which were part of the Santa Fe Trail, as the best way to get through the Sangre de Cristo Mountains. The Santa Fe Trail was a key trade route until the railroad reached Santa Fe in 1880. Like the trail, the railroad and later highways ran through the two passes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">überprüft die Rolle dieser zwei Durchläufe, 
wenn, sicherstellend, daß der Südwesten werden würde und Teil der 
VEREINIGTEN STAATEN zu bleiben über Händler und Armeen, die von den 
Durchläufen abhingen, die ein Teil der Santa Fe Spur waren, als die 
beste Methode, durch Sangre de Cristo Mountains zu erhalten erlernen 
Sie. Die Santa Fe Spur war ein Schlüsselgeschäftsweg, bis die 
Eisenbahn Santa Fe 1880 erreichte. Wie die Spur liefen die 
Eisenbahn und die neueren Datenbahnen durch die zwei Durchläufe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">examine le rôle de ces deux passages en 
s'assurant que le sud-ouest deviendrait et rester région des 
ETATS-UNIS renseignez-vous sur les commerçants et les armées qui ont
dépendu des passages, qui faisaient partie de la traînée de 
technicien de Santa, comme meilleure voie d'obtenir par Sangre de 
Cristo Mountains. La traînée de technicien de Santa était un 
itinéraire commercial principal jusqu'à ce que le chemin de fer ait 
atteint le technicien de Santa en 1880. Comme la traînée, le 
chemin de fer et les omnibus postérieurs ont fonctionné par les deux
passages.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">examina o papel destas duas passagens em 
assegurar-se de que o sudoeste se torne e para remanescer parte dos 
ESTADOS UNIDOS aprenda sobre os comerciantes e os exércitos que 
dependeram das passagens, que eram parte da fuga de Fe de Santa, como 
a mais melhor maneira começar através do Sangre de Cristo Montanha. 
A fuga de Fe de Santa foi uma rota de comércio chave até que a
estrada de ferro alcançou o Fe de Santa em 1880. Como a fuga, a
estrada de ferro e as estradas mais atrasadas funcionaram através das
duas passagens.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esamina il ruolo di questi due passaggi 
nell'accertarsi che il sud-ovest sia diventato e rimanere zona degli 
STATI UNITI impari circa i commercianti e gli eserciti che dipendevano
dai passaggi, che facevano parte della traccia di tecnico di 
assistenza di Santa, come il modo migliore ottenere attraverso il 
Sangre de Cristo Mountains. La traccia di tecnico di assistenza 
di Santa era un itinerario commerciale chiave fino a che la ferrovia 
non raggiungesse il tecnico di assistenza di Santa in 1880. Come
la traccia, la ferrovia e le strade principali successive hanno 
funzionato attraverso i due passaggi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει το ρόλο αυτών των δύο περασμάτων στην 
εξασφάλιση ότι το νοτιοδυτικό σημείο θα γινόταν και θα παρέμενε 
μέρος των ΗΠΑ μαθαίνει για τους εμπόρους και τους στρατούς που 
εξαρτήθηκαν από τα περάσματα, τα οποία ήταν μέρος του ίχνους Φε
Santa, ως καλύτερος τρόπος παίρνω μέσω Sangre de 
Cristo Mountains. Το ίχνος Φε Santa ήταν ένας 
βασικός εμπορικός δρόμος έως ότου έφθασε ο σιδηρόδρομος στο Φε 
Santa το 1880. Όπως το ίχνος, ο σιδηρόδρομος και οι 
πιό πρόσφατες εθνικές οδοί έτρεξαν μέσω των δύο περασμάτων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">examina el papel de estos dos pasos en asegurarse 
de que se convirtió el sudoeste y seguir siendo parte de los ESTADOS 
UNIDOS aprenda sobre los comerciantes y los ejércitos que dependieron
de los pasos, que eran parte del rastro de FE de santa, como la mejor 
manera de conseguir a través del Sangre de Cristo Mountains. El
rastro de FE de santa era una ruta comercial dominante hasta que el 
ferrocarril alcanzó el FE de santa en 1880. Como el rastro, el 
ferrocarril y las carreteras más últimas se ejecutaron a través de 
los dos pasos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206329</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105943</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/glorieta-and-raton-passes-gateways-to-the-southwest</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
