<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106940</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106940</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087290</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"A Date Which Will Live in Infamy": FDR Asks for a Declaration of War</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ein Datum, das in der Niedertracht" lebt: 
FDR bittet um eine Erklärung des Krieges</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"une date qui vivra dans l'infamie" : Le FDR
demande une déclaration de guerre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"uma data que viva no infamy": O FDR pede 
uma declaração da guerra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"una data che vivrà nel infamy": Il FDR 
chiede una dichiarazione della guerra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Μια ημερομηνία που θα ζήσει σε Infamy": FDR ζητά μια Διακήρυξη του πολέμου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"una fecha que vivirá en infamy": El FDR 
pide un declaración de la guerra</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Japanese attack on Pearl Harbor, Hawaii, on December 7, 1941, stunned virtually everyone in the United States military. Japan's carrier-launched bombers found Pearl Harbor totally unprepared. President Franklin Roosevelt quickly addressed Congress to ask for a declaration of war as illustrated in this audio excerpt. Although he never mentioned Europe or the fact that Germany had by then declared war on the United States, the Pearl Harbor attack allowed him to begin the larger intervention in the European war he had long wanted.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der japanische Angriff auf Pearl Harbor, Hawaii, 
an Dezember 7, 1941, betäubt praktisch jeder im Vereinigte Staaten 
Militär. Japans Fördermaschine-ausgestoßene Bomber fanden 
Pearl Harbor total unvorbereitet. Präsident Franklin Roosevelt 
sprach schnell zu Kongreß, um um eine Erklärung des Krieges zu 
bitten, wie in diesem Audioexcerpt veranschaulicht. Obgleich er 
nie Europa oder die Tatsache erwähnte, daß Deutschland bis dahin 
Krieg auf den Vereinigten Staaten erklärt hatte, erlaubte der Pearl 
Harborangriff ihm, die größere Intervention im europäischen Krieg 
anzufangen, den er lang gewünscht hatte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'attaque japonaise sur le port de perle, Hawaï, 
7 décembre 1941, assommé pratiquement chacun dans les militaires 
des Etats-Unis. Les bombardiers porteur-lancés du Japon ont 
trouvé le port de perle totalement non préparé. Le Président
Franklin Roosevelt s'est rapidement adressé au congrès pour demander
une déclaration de guerre comme illustrée dans cet extrait sonore. 
Bien qu'il n'ait jamais mentionné l'Europe ou le fait que 
l'Allemagne d'ici là avait déclaré la guerre sur les Etats-Unis, 
l'attaque de port de perle lui a permise de commencer l'intervention 
plus grande dans la guerre européenne qu'il avait longtemps voulue.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O ataque japonês no porto de pérola, Havaí, 
dezembro em 7, 1941, stunned virtualmente todos nos estados unidos 
militares. Os bombardeiros portador-lançados de Japão 
encontraram o porto de pérola totalmente unprepared. O 
presidente Franklin Roosevelt dirigiu-se rapidamente ao congress para 
pedir uma declaração da guerra como ilustrada neste excerpt audio. 
Embora nunca mencionasse Europa ou o fato que Germany teve pela 
guerra então declarada nos estados unidos, o ataque do porto de 
pérola permitiu que começasse a intervenção maior na guerra que 
européia tinha querido por muito tempo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'attacco giapponese al porto di perla, Hawai, il 
7 dicembre 1941, stordito virtualmente tutto in unito Dichiara 
i militari. I bombardieri elemento-lanciati del Giappone hanno 
trovato il porto di perla completamente non preparato. Il 
presidente Franklin Roosevelt ha parlato rapidamente al congresso per 
chiedere una dichiarazione della guerra come illustrata in questo 
brano audio. Anche se non ha accennato mai Europa o il fatto che
la Germania per allora aveva dichiarato la guerra con unito 
Dichiara, l'attacco del porto di perla ha permesso che lui 
cominciasse il più grande intervento nella guerra europea lungamente 
aveva desiderato.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ιαπωνική επίθεση στο λιμάνι μαργαριταριών, Χαβάη, 
στις 7 Δεκεμβρίου ..1941, ζάλισε ουσιαστικά ο στις Ηνωμένες 
Πολιτείες στρατιωτικές. Τα μεταφορέας-προωθημένα 
βομβαρδιστικά αεροπλάνα της Ιαπωνίας βρήκαν το λιμάνι 
μαργαριταριών συνολικά απροετοίμαστο. Ο Πρόεδρος Franklin
Roosevelt εξέτασε γρήγορα το συνέδριο που ρωτά για μια δήλωση 
του πολέμου όπως διευκρινίζεται σε αυτό το ηχητικό απόσπασμα. 
Αν και δεν ανέφερε ποτέ την Ευρώπη ή το γεγονός ότι η 
Γερμανία είχε κηρύξει έως τότε τον πόλεμο στις Ηνωμένες 
Πολιτείες, η λιμενική επίθεση μαργαριταριών επέτρεψε σε τον για 
να αρχίσει μεγαλύτερη επέμβαση στον ευρωπαϊκό πόλεμο που είχε 
θελήσει από καιρό.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El ataque japonés contra el puerto de perla, 
Hawaii, 7 de diciembre de 1941, atontado virtualmente cada uno en 
los militares de Estados Unidos. Los bombarderos 
portador-lanzados de Japón encontraron el puerto de perla totalmente 
sin preparación. Presidente Franklin Roosevelt se dirigió 
rápidamente al congreso para pedir un declaración de la guerra 
según lo ilustrado en este extracto audio. Aunque él nunca 
mencionó Europa o el hecho de que Alemania para entonces había 
declarado guerra en los Estados Unidos, el ataque del puerto de perla 
permitió que él comenzara la intervención más grande en la guerra 
europea que él había deseado de largo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087290</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106940</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-date-which-will-live-in-infamy-fdr-asks-for-a-declaration-of-war</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
