<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105730</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105730</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206583</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Asia and Pacific Islands: Peace Corps</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Asien und pazifische Inseln: Friedenskorps</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">l'Asie et les îles Pacifiques : Corps de 
Paix</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ásia e consoles pacíficos: Corpo De Paz</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'Asia ed isole pacifiche: Corpo di 
pace</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ασία και ειρηνικά νησιά: Ειρήνη Σώμα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Asia e islas pacíficas: Cuerpo De Paz</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Over two dozen lessons address stories, letters, and folk tales that focus on Peace Corps Volunteer experiences in Asia and the Pacific islands. Topics include arranged marriages, learning a new language and culture, different cultural perspectives, rural Mongolian nomadic culture, cultural and economic complexities in China, learning to speak Chinese, what constitutes a good job, resolving contrasting values between cultures (Sri Lanka and Papua New Guinea).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Über zwei Dutzend Lektionadresse Geschichten 
erfährt Zeichen und Volksgeschichten, die auf 
Friedenskorps-Freiwilliger konzentrieren, in Asien und in den 
pazifischen Inseln. Themen schließen die geordneten 
Verbindungen ein und erlernen eine neue Sprache und Kultur, 
unterschiedliche kulturelle Perspektiven, landwirtschaftliche 
mongolische nomadische Kultur-, kulturelle und 
ökonomischekompliziertheiten in China, erlernend, den Chinesen, was 
zu sprechen einen guten Job festsetzt, das Kontrastieren behebend 
bewertet zwischen Kulturen (Sri Lanka und Papua-new.guinea).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Plus de deux histoires de douzaine adresses de 
leçons, les lettres, et les contes folkloriques qui se concentrent 
sur le volontaire de corps de paix éprouve en Asie et les îles 
Pacifiques. Les sujets incluent des mariages disposés, 
apprenant un nouveau langage et la culture, les différentes 
perspectives culturelles, les complexités de culture, culturelles et 
économiques nomades mongoles rurales en Chine, apprenant à parler 
chinois, ce qui constitue un bon travail, résolvant contraster 
évalue entre les cultures (le Sri Lanka et le Papua-new.guinea).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Sobre duas histórias de dúzia endereços das 
lições, as letras, e os tales populares que focalizam no voluntário
do corpo de paz experimentam em Ásia e nos consoles pacíficos. 
Os tópicos incluem as uniões arranjadas, aprendendo uma 
língua nova e a cultura, os perspectives cultural diferentes, as 
complexidades nomadic mongolian rurais da cultura, as cultural e as 
econômicas em China, aprendendo falar o chinês, o que constitui um 
trabalho bom, resolvendo contrastar avaliam entre culturas (Sri Lanka 
e Papua Nova Guiné).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Oltre due storia di dozzina indirizzi di lezioni, 
le lettere ed i racconti pieghi che mettono a fuoco sulle esperienze 
volontarie di Corpo di pace in Asia ed isole pacifiche. I 
soggetti includono le unioni organizzate, imparanti un nuovo 
linguaggio e la coltura, le prospettive culturali differenti, le 
complessità culturali ed economiche nomadi mongole rurali della 
coltura, in Cina, imparante parlare cinese, che cosa costituisce 
un buon lavoro, risolvente la contrapposizione stima fra le colture 
(la Sri Lanka e Papua-new.guinea).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πάνω από δύο δωδεκάα μαθήματα εξετάζουν τις 
ιστορίες, τις επιστολές, και τις λαϊκές ιστορίες ότι η εστίαση 
στην ειρήνη προσφέρεται εθελοντικά Σώμα την εμπειρία στην 
Ασία και τα ειρηνικά νησιά. Τα θέματα περιλαμβάνουν τους 
τακτοποιημένους γάμους, μαθαίνοντας μια νέο γλώσσα και έναν 
πολιτισμό, τις διαφορετικές πολιτιστικές προοπτικές, τον αγροτικό
μογγολικό νομαδικό πολιτισμό, τις πολιτιστικές και οικονομικές 
περιπλοκές στην Κίνα, που μαθαίνει να μιλούν τα κινέζικα, τι 
αποτελεί μια καλή εργασία, που επιλύει τις αντιπαραβαλλόμενες 
τιμές μεταξύ των πολιτισμών (Σρι Λάνκα και Νέα 
Παπούα-Γουϊνέα).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sobre dos historias de docena direccionamientos de
las lecciones, las cartas, y los cuentos populares que se centran en 
voluntario del cuerpo de paz experimentan en Asia y las islas 
pacíficas. Los asuntos incluyen las uniones dispuestas, 
aprendiendo un nuevo lenguaje y la cultura, diversas perspectivas 
culturales, las complejidades nómadas mongoles rurales de la cultura,
culturales y económicas en China, aprendiendo hablar chino, qué 
constituye un buen trabajo, resolviendo poner en contraste valora 
entre las culturas (Sri Lanka y Papua-new.guinea).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206583</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105730</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/asia-and-pacific-islands-peace-corps</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
