<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105707</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105707</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207066</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Fill up the Canvas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Füllen Sie oben das Segeltuch</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Remplissez la toile</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Encha acima a lona</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Riempia in su la tela di canapa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γεμίστε επάνω τον καμβά</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Llene para arriba la lona</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features journal entries from 20 points in the journey of Lewis and Clark: mission preparations, winter in St. Louis, first council with Indians, death of Sergeant Floyd, first killing of a buffalo, Sioux camps, near run-in with Teton Sioux, Rocky Mountains, Nez Perce, falls of the Columbia River, and others. The site also provides letters from Thomas Jefferson to Lewis and Clark; images of people, places, plants, and animals; and maps.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Merkmale Journaleinträge von 20 Punkten in der 
Reise von Lewis und von Clark: Mission Vorbereitungen, Winter in
St. Louis, erster Rat mit Indern, Tod des Sergeants Floyd, erste 
Tötung eines Büffels, Sioux kampiert, nahe Run-in mit Teton Sioux, 
felsige Berge, Nez Perce, Fällen des Kolumbien Flusses und anderen. 
Die Site stellt auch Zeichen von Thomas Jefferson zu Lewis und 
zu Clark zur Verfügung; Bilder der Leute, der Plätze, der 
Betriebe und der Tiere; und Karten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">écritures comptables de dispositifs de 20 points 
dans le voyage de Lewis et de Clark : les préparations de 
mission, hiver à St Louis, le premier conseil avec des Indiens, la 
mort du Sergent Floyd, le premier massacre d'un buffle, Sioux 
campe, près du rodage avec Teton Sioux, les montagnes rocheuses, Nez 
Perce, chutes du fleuve de Colombie, et d'autres. Le site 
fournit également des lettres de Thomas Jefferson à Lewis et à 
Clark ; images des personnes, des endroits, des usines, et des 
animaux ; et cartes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">entradas de jornal das características de 20 
pontos na viagem de Lewis e de Clark: as preparações da 
missão, inverno em St. Louis, primeiro conselho com indians, morte do
sergeant Floyd, primeira matança de um búfalo, Sioux acampam, perto 
do run-in com Teton Sioux, montanhas rochosas, Nez Perce, quedas do 
rio de Colômbia, e outras. O local fornece também letras de 
Thomas Jefferson a Lewis e a Clark; imagens dos povos, dos 
lugares, das plantas, e dos animais; e mapas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">entrate di giornale delle caratteristiche da 20 
punti nel viaggio di Lewis e di Clark: le preparazioni di 
missione, inverno a St. Louis, il primo consiglio con gli indiani, 
morte del sergeant Floyd, la prima uccisione di un bufalo, Sioux si 
accampa, vicino al run-in con Teton Sioux, montagne rocciose, Nez 
Perce, le cadute del fiume della Colombia ed altre. Il luogo 
egualmente fornisce le lettere da Thomas Jefferson a Lewis ed a Clark;
immagini della gente, dei posti, delle piante e degli animali; 
e programmi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χαρακτηρίζει τις καταχωρήσεις περιοδικών από 20 
σημεία στο ταξίδι Lewis και clark: οι προετοιμασίες 
αποστολής, χειμώνας στο ST Louis, το πρώτο συμβούλιο με 
Ινδούς, θάνατος του λοχία Floyd, πρώτα να σκοτώσουν ενός 
βούβαλου, Σιού στρατοπεδεύουν, κοντά ρονταμένος με τα σιού, 
δύσκολο βουνά Teton, Nez Perce, τις πτώσεις του ποταμού 
της Κολούμπια, και άλλα. Η περιοχή παρέχει επίσης τις 
επιστολές από τον Thomas Jefferson σε Lewis και clark  
εικόνες των ανθρώπων, των θέσεων, των φυτών, και των ζώων  
και χάρτες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">entradas de diario de las características a 
partir de 20 puntas en el viaje de Lewis y de Clark: las 
preparaciones de la misión, invierno en St. Louis, primer consejo con
los indios, muerte de sargento Floyd, primera matanza de un búfalo, 
Sioux acampan, cerca de riña con Teton Sioux, las montañas rocosas, 
Nez Perce, las caídas del río de Colombia, y otras. El sitio 
también proporciona a cartas de Thomas Jefferson a Lewis y a Clark; 
imágenes de la gente, de lugares, de plantas, y de animales; 
y correspondencias.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207066</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105707</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/fill-up-the-canvas</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
