<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104368</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104368</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086933</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Facts Must Be Faced": Intelligence Is Destiny</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Die Tatsachen Müssen Gegenübergestellt werden":
Intelligenz Ist Schicksal</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Les Faits Doivent Être faits face" : 
l'Intelligence Est Destin</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Os Fatos Devem Ser enfrentados": A 
Inteligência É Destiny</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"I Fatti Devono Essere affrontati": 
L'Intelligenza È Destino</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Τα γεγονότα πρέπει να αντιμετωπιστούν": Η 
νοημοσύνη είναι πεπρωμένο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Los Hechos Se deben Hacer frente": La 
Inteligencia Es Destino</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">"There is nothing about an individual as important as his IQ," declared psychologist Lewis M. Terman in 1922. To the extent that this is true, it is in large measure because of Terman himself and the opportunity that World War I afforded for the first widespread use of intelligence testing. The army's use of intelligence tests lent new credibility to the emerging profession of psychology, even as it sparked public debate about the validity of the tests and their implications for American democracy. Psychologist Henry Herbert Goddard suggested that intelligence testing proved that socialist ideas were "absurd" and Americans too democratic. In  Human Efficiency and Levels of Intelligence  (1922), Goddard argued that social and economic inequality were good and necessary because some people were smarter than others. He furthermore concluded that people were happiest in their proper social and economic places, as decreed by their differing mental endowments.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"es gibt nichts über eine Einzelperson, die," 
erklärter Psychologe Lewis M. Terman 1922 so wichtig ist wie sein IQ.
Soweit daß dieses zutreffend ist, ist es in großem Umfang 
wegen Terman selbst und der Gelegenheit, die der Erste Weltkrieg für 
den ersten weitverbreiteten Gebrauch von Intelligenzprüfung sich 
leistete. Der Gebrauch der Armee von Intelligenz prüft 
verliehene neue Glaubwürdigkeit zum auftauchenden Beruf von 
Psychologie, selbst als er allgemeine Debatte über die Gültigkeit 
der Tests und ihrer Implikationen für amerikanische Demokratie 
funkte. Psychologe-Henry Herbert Goddard schlug daß die 
Intelligenzprüfung vor, die nachgewiesen wurde, daß sozialistische 
Ideen "absurd" und die demokratischen Amerikaner zu waren. In 
der menschlichen Leistungsfähigkeit und in den Stufen von 
Intelligence (1922), argumentierte Goddard, daß Sozial- und 
ökonomische Verschiedenheit gut und notwendig waren, weil einige 
Leute intelligenter als andere waren. Er feststellte ausserdem, 
daß Leute in ihren korrekten Sozial- und ökonomischen Plätzen am 
glücklichsten waren, wie durch ihre unterscheidenen 
Geistesausstattungen verordnet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"il n'y a rien au sujet d'un individu aussi 
important que son Q.I.," psychologue avoué Lewis M. Terman en 1922. 
Dans la mesure où c'est vrai, il est dans une large mesure en 
raison de Terman lui-même et de l'occasion que la Première Guerre 
Mondiale a eus les moyens pour le premier usage répandu du test 
d'intelligence. L'utilisation de l'armée de l'intelligence 
teste la nouvelle crédibilité prêtée à la profession naissante de
la psychologie, même pendant qu'elle étincelait discussion publique 
au sujet de la validité des essais et de leurs implications pour la 
démocratie américaine. Henry Herbert Goddard de psychologue a 
suggéré que test d'intelligence montré que les idées socialistes 
étaient "absurdes" et des Américains trop démocratiques. Dans
l'efficacité et les niveaux humains d'Intelligence (1922), Goddard a 
argué du fait que l'inégalité sociale et économique étaient bonne
et nécessaire parce que quelques personnes étaient plus futées que 
d'autres. Il a en outre conclu que les gens étaient les plus 
heureux dans leurs endroits sociaux et économiques appropriés, comme
décrété par leurs dotations mentales différentes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"não há nada sobre um indivíduo tão importante
quanto seu IQ," psicólogo declarado Lewis M. Terman em 1922. 
Até ao ponto em que isto é verdadeiro, está na medida grande 
por causa de Terman ele mesmo e na oportunidade que o world.war.i teve
recursos para para o primeiro uso difundido de testar da 
inteligência. O uso do exército da inteligência testa o 
credibility novo emprestado à profissão emergente do psychology, 
mesmo como ele acendeu debate público sobre a validez dos testes e de
suas implicações para a democracia americana. O Henry Herbert 
Goddard do psicólogo sugeriu que testar da inteligência provado que 
as idéias socialist eram "absurd" e americanos demasiado 
democráticos. Na eficiência e em níveis humanos de 
Inteligência (1922), Goddard discutiu que o desigualdade social e 
econômico era bom e necessário porque alguns povos eram mais 
espertos do que outros. Além disso concliu que os povos eram os
mais felizes em seus lugares sociais e econômicos apropriados, como 
decreed por seus endowments mentais diferindo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"ci è niente circa un individuo importante quanto
il suo quoziente d'intelligenza," psicologo dichiarato Lewis M. Terman
in 1922. Anche se questo è allineare, è in una larga misura a 
causa di Terman egli stesso e dell'occasione che il world.war.i si è 
permesso per il primo uso molto diffuso di prova di intelligenza. 
L'uso dell'esercito di intelligenza verifica la nuova 
credibilità prestata alla professione d'emersione della psicologia, 
proprio mentre ha scintillato dibattito pubblico circa la validità 
delle prove e delle loro implicazioni per la democrazia americana. 
Il henry Herbert Goddard dello psicologo ha suggerito che prova 
di intelligenza provata che le idee socialiste erano "irragionevoli" 
ed Americani troppo democratici. Nel risparmio di temi e nei 
livelli umani di Intelligence (1922), Goddard ha sostenuto che la 
diseguaglianza sociale ed economica era necessaria buona e perché 
qualche gente era più astuta di altre. Ancora ha concluso che 
la gente era più felice nei loro posti sociali ed economici adeguati,
come decretato tramite le loro dotazioni mentali differenti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Δεν υπάρχει τίποτα για ένα άτομο τόσο σημαντικό 
όπως ο ΔΕΙΚΤΗΣ ΝΟΗΜΟΣΎΝΗΣ του," δηλωμένος ψυχολόγος Lewis Μ. 
Terman σε 1922, μέχρι το σημείο που αυτό ισχύει, αυτό 
είναι σε μεγάλο βαθμό λόγω Terman ο ίδιος και της ευκαιρίας 
που ο παγκόσμιος πόλεμος εγώ παρείχε για την πρώτη διαδεδομένη 
χρήση της δοκιμής νοημοσύνης. Η χρήση του στρατού των 
δοκιμών νοημοσύνης δάνεισε τη νέα αξιοπιστία στο αναδυόμενο 
επάγγελμα της ψυχολογίας, ακόμη και δεδομένου ότι προκάλεσε τη 
δημόσια συζήτηση για την ισχύ των δοκιμών και των επιπτώσεών 
τους στην αμερικανική δημοκρατία. Ο ψυχολόγος Henry 
Herbert Goddard πρότεινε ότι η δοκιμή νοημοσύνης απέδειξε 
ότι οι σοσιαλιστικές ιδέες ήταν "παράλογεσ" και Αμερικανοί πάρα
πολύ δημοκρατικοί. Στην ανθρώπινα αποδοτικότητα και τα 
επίπεδα νοημοσύνης (1922), Goddard υποστήριξε ότι η 
κοινωνική και οικονομική ανισότητα ήταν καλή και απαραίτητη 
επειδή μερικοί άνθρωποι ήταν εξυπνώτεροι από άλλοι. 
Επιπλέον κατέληξε στο συμπέρασμα ότι οι άνθρωποι ήταν οι 
ευτυχέστεροι στις κατάλληλες κοινωνικές και οικονομικές θέσεις 
τους, όπως θεσπίζεται από τις διαφορετικές διανοητικές 
χρηματοδοτήσεις τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"no hay nada sobre un individuo tan importante 
como su índice de inteligencia," psicólogo declarado Lewis M. Terman
en 1922. Hasta el punto de esto sea verdad, está en la medida 
grande debido a Terman misma y la oportunidad que la Primera Guerra 
Mundial produjo para el primer uso extenso de la prueba de la 
inteligencia. El uso del ejército de la inteligencia prueba 
nueva credibilidad prestada a la profesión que emerge de la 
psicología, incluso como él chispeó discusión público sobre la 
validez de las pruebas y de sus implicaciones para la democracia 
americana. El Henrio Herberto Goddard del psicólogo sugirió 
que prueba de la inteligencia probada que las ideas socialistas eran 
"absurdas" y americanos demasiado democráticos. En eficacia y 
niveles humanos de Intelligence (1922), Goddard discutió que la 
desigualdad social y económica fuera buena y necesaria porque alguna 
gente era más elegante que otras. Él además concluyó que la 
gente era la más feliz de sus lugares sociales y económicos 
apropiados, según lo decretado por sus dotaciones mentales que 
diferenciaban.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086933</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104368</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-facts-must-be-faced-intelligence-is-destiny</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
