<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104683</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104683</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086126</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Equal Rights Are Not Special": Advocates Call for an End to Anti-Gay Employment Discrimination</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Gleiche Rechte Sind Nicht" Speziell: 
Fürsprecher verlangen ein Ende zur Anti-Homosexuellen 
Diskriminierung bei der Anstellung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"L'Égalité des droits N'est pas Spéciale" : 
Les avocats nécessitent une extrémité à la discrimination à
l'embauche Anti-Gaie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"As Direitas Iguais Não são Especiais": Os
advogados chamam-se para uma extremidade à discriminação de emprego
Anti-anti-Gay</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"I Diritti Uguali Non sono Speciali": I 
fautori richiedono un'estremità a distinzione di occupazione di 
Anti-gay</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα "ίσα δικαιώματα δεν είναι ειδικά": Κλήση 
συνηγόρων για ένα τέλος στην αντι-εύθυμη διάκριση απασχόλησης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las "Derechas Iguales No son Especiales": 
Los abogados llaman para un extremo a la discriminación de 
empleo de Anti-gay</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Although Title VII of the landmark Civil Rights Act of 1964 prohibited employment discrimination based on race, color, religion, national origin, and sex, as of 2002, no Federal law prevents an employer from discrimination based on sexual orientation. With the advent of the gay liberation movement in 1969, grassroots and national groups fought for legal protection for gay men and lesbians in the workplace, educational institutions, and housing. In 1972, East Lansing, Michigan, became the first city to forbid discrimination in local government hiring based on sexual orientation. While more than 175 localities and 13 states have passed similar antidiscrimination legislation, opponents have successfully campaigned to stop or repeal such laws by arguing that they conferred "special rights" on gay men and lesbians. Colorado voters in a 1992 referendum adopted an amendment to their State Constitution to prohibit protection of persons based on their "homosexual, lesbian or bisexual orientation, conduct, practices or relationships." Although the U.S. Supreme Court ruled in 1996 that the Colorado amendment violated the equal protection clause of the 14th Amendment, and President Bill Clinton issued an Executive Order in 1998 that explicitly prohibited discrimination based on sexual orientation for Executive Branch civilian employment, gay and lesbian employees remain unprotected from discriminatory practices in many areas of the country. In the following testimony to a House subcommittee in 1994, five advocates for federal legislation presented arguments and personal accounts to demonstrate the need to establish, in the words of one of the witnesses, "the equal right to work in the U.S."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Obgleich Titel VII der Grenzstein Zivilrecht-Tat 
von 1964 die Diskriminierung bei der Anstellung verbot, die auf 
Rennen, Farbe, Religion, nationalem Ursprung und Geschlecht basierte, 
wie von 2002, verhindert kein Bundesgesetz einen Arbeitgeber an der 
Unterscheidung, die auf sexueller Lagebestimmung basiert. Mit 
dem Aufkommen der homosexuellen Befreiungbewegung 1969, der 
Basis und der nationalen Gruppen gekämpft für Rechtsschutz 
für homosexuelle Männer und Lesbier an dem Arbeitsplatz, der 
pädagogischen Anstalten und des Gehäuses. 1972 wurde 
Ostlansing, Michigan, die erste Stadt, zum von von Unterscheidung bei 
der lokale Regierung Einstellung zu verbieten, die auf sexueller 
Lagebestimmung basierte. Während mehr als 175 Stellen und 13 
Zustände ähnliche antidiscrimination Gesetzgebung geführt haben, 
haben Konkurrenten erfolgreich geworben, um solche Gesetze zu stoppen 
oder zu widerrufen, indem sie argumentierten, daß sie "spezielle 
Rechte" auf homosexuellen Männern und Lesbiern konferierten. 
Kolorado Wähler in einem Referendum 1992 nahmen eine Änderung 
zu ihrer Zustand-Beschaffenheit an, um Schutz der Personen zu 
verbieten, die basierten auf ihrem "Homosexual, lesbische oder 
bisexual Lagebestimmung, Führung, Praxis oder Verhältnisse." 
Obgleich das VEREINIGTE STAATEN Höchste Gericht 1996 anordnete,
daß die Kolorado Änderung die gleiche Schutzklausel der 14. 
Änderung verletzte und Präsident Bill Clinton eine 
Ausführungsverordnung 1998 herausgab, das ausdrücklich die 
Unterscheidung verbot, die auf sexueller Lagebestimmung für 
Exekutivezivilbeschäftigung basierte, bleiben Homosexuell- und 
Lesbierangestellte von der diskriminierenden Praxis in vielen 
Bereichen des Landes ungeschützt. Im folgenden Zeugnis zu einer
Hausunterausschuß 1994, fünf Fürsprecher für die 
Bundesgesetzgebung die Argumente und persönliche Konten dargestellt, 
zum der Notwendigkeit zu demonstrieren, in den Wörtern von einem der 
Zeugen herzustellen, "das Gleichgestelltrecht, in den US zu arbeiten."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bien que le titre VII de l'acte de droits civiques
de borne limite de 1964 ait interdit la discrimination à l'embauche 
basée sur la course, la couleur, la religion, l'origine nationale, et
le sexe, en date de 2002, aucune loi fédérale empêche un employeur 
de la discrimination basée sur l'orientation sexuelle. Avec 
l'arrivée du mouvement gai de libération en 1969, bases et groupes 
nationaux combattus pour la protection légale pour les hommes et les 
lesbiennes gais dans le lieu de travail, établissements éducatifs, 
et logement. En 1972, Lansing est, Michigan, est devenu la 
première ville pour interdire la discrimination dans la location de 
gouvernement local basée sur l'orientation sexuelle. Tandis que
plus de 175 localités et 13 états ont passé la législation 
semblable d'antidiscrimination, les adversaires ont avec succès fait 
campagne pour arrêter ou abroger de telles lois en arguant du fait 
qu'ils ont conféré "des droites spéciales" sur les hommes et les 
lesbiennes gais. Les électeurs du Colorado dans un référendum
1992 ont adopté un amendement à leur constitution d'état pour 
interdire la protection des personnes basées sur leur "homosexuel, 
orientation lesbienne ou bisexuelle, conduite, pratiques ou 
rapports." Bien que la cour suprême des ETATS-UNIS ait régné 
en 1996 que l'amendement du Colorado a violé la clause égale de 
protection du 14ème amendement, et le Président Bill Clinton a 
émis une commande exécutive en 1998 qui a explicitement interdit la 
discrimination basée sur l'orientation sexuelle pour l'emploi civil 
de branchement exécutif, les employés de gay et de lesbienne restent
non protégés des pratiques discriminatoires dans beaucoup de zones 
du pays. Dans le témoignage suivant à un sous-comité de 
Chambre en 1994, cinq avocats pour la législation fédérale 
présentée des arguments et des comptes personnels pour démontrer la
nécessité d'établir, dans les mots d'un des témoins, "la droite 
d'égale de travailler aux États-Unis."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Embora o título VII do ato das direitas civis do 
marco de 1964 proíba a discriminação de emprego baseada na raça, 
na cor, na religião, na origem nacional, e no sexo, como de 2002, 
nenhuma lei federal impede um empregador da discriminação baseada na
orientação sexual. Com o advent do movimento gay do liberation
em 1969, grassroots e grupos nacionais lutados pela proteção legal 
para homens e lesbians gay no workplace, instituições educacionais, 
e carcaça. Em 1972, Lansing do leste, Michigan, transformou-se 
a primeira cidade para proibir a discriminação em empregar do 
governo local baseado na orientação sexual. Quando mais de 175
localities e 13 estados passarem a legislação similar do 
antidiscrimination, os oponentes fizeram campanha com sucesso para 
parar ou repeal tais leis discutindo que conferenciaram "direitas 
especiais" em homens e em lesbians gay. Os eleitores de Colorado
em um referendum 1992 adotaram uma emenda a seu constitution do estado
para proibir a proteção das pessoas baseadas em seus "homosexual, 
orientação lesbian ou bisexual, conduta, práticas ou 
relacionamentos." Embora a corte suprema de ESTADOS UNIDOS 
governe em 1996 que a emenda de Colorado violated a cláusula igual da
proteção da 1â emenda, e o presidente Bill Clinton emitiu uma ordem
executiva em 1998 que proibiu explicitamente a discriminação baseada
na orientação sexual para o emprego civil da filial executiva, os 
empregados do gay e do lesbian remanescem desprotegidos das práticas 
discriminatory em muitas áreas do país. No seguinte testimony 
a uma subcomissão da casa em 1994, cinco advogados para a 
legislação federal apresentada os argumentos e os clientes pessoais 
para demonstrar a necessidade estabelecer, nas palavras de uma das 
testemunhas, "a direita do igual trabalhar nos E. U.."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Anche se il titolo VII della Legge di diritti 
civili del limite di 1964 ha proibito la distinzione di occupazione 
basata sulla razza, sul colore, sulla religione, sull'origine 
nazionale e sul sesso, a partire da 2002, nessuna legge federale evita
un datore di lavoro distinzione basata sull'orientamento sessuale. 
Con l'avvenimento del movimento di liberazione di gay 
in 1969, grassroots e gruppi nazionali combattuti per protezione 
legale per gli uomini e lesbiche di gay nel posto di lavoro, 
istituti scolastici ed alloggiamento. In 1972, Lansing 
orientale, Michigan, si è transformata in nella prima città per 
proibire alla distinzione nell'assumere di ente pubblico territoriale 
basato sull'orientamento sessuale. Mentre più di 175 località 
e 13 dichiara hanno passato la legislazione simile di 
antidiscrimination, gli avversari hanno fatto una campagna con 
successo per arrestare o abrogare tali leggi sostenendo che hanno 
conferito "diritti speciali" sugli uomini e sulle lesbiche di 
gay. Gli elettori del Colorado in un referendum 1992 
hanno adottato una correzione al loro Dichiarano la costituzione
per proibire la protezione delle persone basate sul loro "omosessuale,
orientamento lesbico o bisexual, comportamento, pratiche o rapporti." 
Anche se la Corte suprema degli STATI UNITI ha regolato in 1996 
che la correzione del Colorado ha violato la clausola uguale di 
protezione della quattordicesima correzione ed il presidente Bill 
Clinton ha pubblicato un ordine esecutivo in 1998 che ha proibito 
esplicitamente la distinzione basata sull'orientamento sessuale per 
occupazione civile del ramo esecutivo, gli impiegati della lesbica e 
di gay rimangono non protetti dalle pratiche discriminatorie 
in molte zone del paese. Nella seguente testimonianza ad un 
sottocomitato della Camera in 1994, cinque fautori per legislazione 
federale presentata gli argomenti ed i clienti personali per 
dimostrare la necessità di stabilire, nelle parole di uno dei 
testimoni, "la destra del uguale funzionare negli Stati Uniti."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αν και ο τίτλος VII του νόμου αστικών δικαιωμάτων 
ορόσημων του 1964 απαγόρευσε τη διάκριση απασχόλησης βασισμένη
στη φυλή, το χρώμα, η θρησκεία, η εθνική προέλευση, και το φύλο,
από το 2002, κανένας ομοσπονδιακός νόμος αποτρέπουν έναν 
εργοδότη από τη διάκριση βασισμένη στο σεξουαλικό 
προσανατολισμό. Με την εμφάνιση της ομοφυλοφιλικής 
μετακίνησης απελευθέρωσης το 1969, το σε επίπεδο βάσης και οι 
εθνικές ομάδες πάλεψαν για τη νομική προστασία για τα 
ομοφυλοφιλικές άτομα και τις λεσβίες στον εργασιακό χώρο, τα 
εκπαιδευτικά όργανα, και την κατοικία. Το 1972, το
ανατολικό Λάνσινγκ, Μίτσιγκαν, έγινε η πρώτη πόλη για να 
απαγορεύσει τη διάκριση στη μίσθωση τοπικής κυβέρνησης βασισμένη
στο σεξουαλικό προσανατολισμό. Ενώ περισσότερες από 175 
τοποθεσίες και 13 κράτη έχουν περάσει την παρόμοια νομοθεσία 
antidiscrimination, οι αντίπαλοι έχουν κάνει εκστρατεία 
επιτυχώς να σταματήσουν ή να ακυρώσουν τέτοιους νόμους με να 
υποστηρίξουν ότι παρείχαν τα "ειδικά δικαιώματα" στα 
ομοφυλοφιλικές άτομα και τις λεσβίες. Οι ψηφοφόροι του 
Κολοράντο σε ένα δημοψήφισμα του 1992 υιοθέτησαν μια 
τροποποίηση στο κρατικό σύνταγμά τους για να απαγορεύσουν την 
προστασία των προσώπων βασισμένη στο "ομοφυλοφιλικές, λεσβιακές 
ή αμφίφυλες προσανατολισμό, τη συμπεριφορά, τις πρακτικές ή τις 
σχέσεις τους." Αν και το ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ ανώτατο δικαστήριο 
διέταξε το 1996 ότι η τροποποίηση του Κολοράντο παραβίασε την 
ίση πρόταση προστασίας της 14$ης τροποποίησης, και ο Πρόεδρος 
Bill Clinton εξέδωσε μια εκτελεστική εντολή το 1998 που 
απαγόρευσε ρητά τη διάκριση βασισμένη στο σεξουαλικό 
προσανατολισμό για την εκτελεστική πολιτική απασχόληση κλάδων, οι
ομοφυλοφιλικοί και λεσβιακοί υπάλληλοι παραμένουν μη 
προστατευμένί από τις μεροληπτικές πρακτικές σε πολλές περιοχές
της χώρας. Στην ακόλουθη κατάθεση σε μια υποεπιτροπή 
σπιτιών το 1994, πέντε συνήγοροι για την ομοσπονδιακή 
νομοθεσία παρουσίασαν τα ορίσματα και τους προσωπικούς 
απολογισμούς για να καταδείξουν την ανάγκη να καθιερώσουν, στις 
λέξεις ένας από τους μάρτυρες, "το ίσο δικαίωμα να εργαστούν 
U.S."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Aunque el título VII del acto de las derechas 
civiles de la señal de 1964 prohibió la discriminación de empleo 
basada en la raza, el color, la religión, el origen nacional, y el 
sexo, en fecha 2002, ninguna ley federal previene a patrón de la 
discriminación basada en la orientación sexual. Con el 
advenimiento del movimiento gay de la liberación en 1969, 
pueblos y grupos nacionales de combate para la protección legal para 
los hombres gays y lesbianas en el lugar de trabajo, 
instituciones educativas, y cubierta. En 1972, Lansing del este,
Michigan, se convirtió en la primera ciudad para prohibir la 
discriminación en emplear del gobierno local basado en la 
orientación sexual. Mientras que más de 175 lugares y 13 
estados han aprobado la legislación similar del antidiscrimination, 
los opositores han hecho campaña con éxito para parar o para abrogar
tales leyes discutiendo que consultaron las "derechas especiales" a 
hombres gays y a lesbianas. Los votantes de Colorado en 
un referéndum 1992 adoptaron una enmienda a su constitución del 
estado para prohibir la protección de las personas basadas en su 
"homosexual, orientación lesbiana o bisexual, conducta, prácticas o 
lazos." Aunque el Tribunal Supremo de ESTADOS UNIDOS gobernó en
1996 que la enmienda de Colorado violó la cláusula igual de la 
protección de la 14ta enmienda, y presidente Bill Clinton publicó 
una orden ejecutiva en 1998 que prohibió explícitamente la 
discriminación basada en la orientación sexual para el empleo civil 
de la ramificación ejecutiva, los empleados del gay y de la 
lesbiana siguen siendo desprotegidos de prácticas discriminatorias en
muchas áreas del país. En el testimonio siguiente a un 
subcomité de la casa en 1994, cinco abogados para la legislación 
federal presentada los argumentos y las cuentas personales para 
demostrar la necesidad de establecer, en las palabras de uno de los 
testigos, "la derecha del igual de trabajar en los E.E.U.U.."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086126</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104683</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/equal-rights-are-not-special-advocates-call-for-an-end-to-anti-gay-employment-discrimination</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
