<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107634</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107634</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086466</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Math Tools</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathe-Hilfsmittel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Outils de Maths</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ferramentas Do Math</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Strumenti Di Per la matematica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εργαλεία Math</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Herramientas De la Matemáticas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Math Tools is a project of The Math Forum @ Drexel, funded in part by the National Science Foundation. The goal is to create a community digital library that supports the use and development of software for mathematics education. We began work in September of 2002 and through the help of many people there is already an active and rich resource center. You are the key. The point is to enable users to help each other use technology effectively in the math classroom. By sharing our experiences, activities, comments, and needs, we can help each other find tools that are known to work well and learn how to use them and improve them. Teachers, students, researchers, publishers, and software developers are all working together in Math Tools.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathe-Hilfsmittel ist ein Projekt des Mathe-Forums
@ Drexel, finanziert im Teil durch das National Science Foundation. 
Das Ziel ist, eine Gemeinschaftsdigitale Bibliothek 
herzustellen, die den Gebrauch und die Entwicklung von Software für 
Mathematikausbildung unterstützt. Wir fingen Arbeit im 
September von 2002 an und durch die Hilfe vieler Leute gibt es bereits
eine aktive und reiche Hilfsmittelmitte. Sie sind die Taste. 
Der Punkt soll Benutzer aktivieren, sich zu helfen, Technologie 
im Matheklassenzimmer effektiv zu verwenden. Indem sie unsere 
Erfahrungen teilen, kommentiert Aktivitäten, und Notwendigkeiten, 
können wir uns helfen, Hilfsmittel zu finden, die bekannt, um zu 
arbeiten hervorquellen und erlernen, wie man sie benutzt und sie 
verbessert. Lehrer, Kursteilnehmer, Forscher, Verleger und 
Software-Entwickler sind alle Funktion zusammen in den 
Mathe-Hilfsmitteln.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les outils de maths est un projet du forum @ 
Drexel de maths, placé en partie par le National Science Foundation. 
Le but est de créer une bibliothèque digitale de la 
communauté qui supporte l'utilisation et le développement du 
logiciel pour l'éducation de mathématiques. Nous avons 
commencé le travail en septembre de 2002 et par l'aide de beaucoup de
gens il y a déjà un centre actif et riche de ressource. Vous 
êtes la clé. Le point doit permettre à des utilisateurs de 
s'aider à utiliser la technologie pertinemment dans la salle de 
classe de maths. En partageant nos expériences, les activités,
commente, et les besoins, nous pouvons nous aider à trouver les 
outils qui sont connus pour fonctionner jaillissent et apprennent 
comment les utiliser et les améliorer. Les professeurs, les 
étudiants, les chercheurs, les éditeurs, et les lotisseurs de 
logiciel sont tout le fonctionnement ensemble dans des outils de 
maths.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As ferramentas do math são um projeto do forum @ 
Drexel do math, financiado na parte pelo National Science Foundation. 
O objetivo é criar uma biblioteca digital da comunidade que 
suporte o uso e o desenvolvimento do software para a instrução da 
matemática. Nós começamos o trabalho em setembro de 2002 e 
com a ajuda de muitos povos há já um centro ativo e rico do recurso.
Você é a chave. O ponto deve permitir usuários de 
ajudar-se a usar eficazmente a tecnologia na sala de aula do math. 
Compartilhando de nossas experiências, as atividades, comentam,
e necessidades, nós podemos ajudar-se a encontrar as ferramentas que 
são sabidas para trabalhar jorram e aprendem como as usar e as 
melhorar. Os professores, os estudantes, os investigadores, os 
publishers, e os colaboradores do software são todo o funcionamento 
junto em ferramentas do math.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli strumenti di per la matematica è un progetto 
della tribuna @ Drexel di per la matematica, costituito un fondo per 
in parte dal National Science Foundation. L'obiettivo è di 
creare una libreria digitale della Comunità che sostiene l'uso e lo 
sviluppo di software per formazione di matematica. Abbiamo 
cominciato il lavoro in settembre di 2002 e con l'aiuto di molta gente
ci è già un centro attivo e ricco delle risorse. Siete il 
tasto. Il punto deve permettere agli utenti di aiutarsi ad usare
efficacemente la tecnologia nell'aula di per la matematica. 
Ripartendo le nostre esperienze, le attività, commenta e 
bisogni, possiamo aiutarsi a trovare gli strumenti che sono conosciuti
per funzionare scaturiscono ed imparano come usarli e migliorarli. 
Gli insegnanti, gli allievi, i ricercatori, gli editori e gli 
sviluppatori del software sono insieme tutto il funzionamento in 
strumenti di per la matematica.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα εργαλεία Math είναι ένα πρόγραμμα του Math 
φόρουμ @ Drexel, που χρηματοδοτείται εν μέρει από το εθνικό 
ίδρυμα επιστήμης. Ο στόχος είναι να δημιουργηθεί μια 
κοινοτική ψηφιακή βιβλιοθήκη που υποστηρίζει τη χρήση και την 
ανάπτυξη του λογισμικού για την εκπαίδευση μαθηματικών. 
Αρχίσαμε την εργασία το Σεπτέμβριο του 2002 και μέσω των 
οδηγιών πολλών ανθρώπων υπάρχει ήδη ένα ενεργό και πλούσιο 
κέντρο των στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς. Είστε το πλήκτρο. 
Το σημείο είναι να επιτραπούν οι χρήστες για να βοηθήσει ο 
ένας τον άλλον να χρησιμοποιήσει την τεχνολογία αποτελεσματικά 
στην τάξη math. Με τη διανομή της εμπειρίας, των 
δραστηριοτήτων, των σχολίων, και των αναγκών μας, μπορούμε να 
βοηθήσουμε ο ένας τον άλλον να βρεί τα εργαλεία που είναι 
γνωστά για να απασχολούνται καλά και να μαθαίνουν σπώς να τους 
χρησιμοποιήσουν και να τους βελτιώσουν. Οι δάσκαλοι, οι 
σπουδαστές, οι ερευνητές, οι εκδότες, και οι υπεύθυνοι για την 
ανάπτυξη όλοι λογισμικού λειτουργούν μαζί στα εργαλεία Math.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las herramientas de la matemáticas son un 
proyecto del foro @ Drexel de la matemáticas, financiado en parte por
el National Science Foundation. La meta es crear una biblioteca 
digital de la comunidad que utilice el uso y el desarrollo del 
software para la educación de las matemáticas. Comenzamos el 
trabajo en septiembre de 2002 y con la ayuda de mucha gente hay ya un 
centro activo y rico del recurso. Usted es el clave. La 
punta es permitir a utilizadores ayudarse a utilizar tecnología con 
eficacia en la sala de clase de la matemáticas. Compartiendo 
nuestras experiencias, las actividades, comentan, y las necesidades, 
podemos ayudarnos a encontrar las herramientas que se saben para 
trabajar manan y aprenden cómo utilizarlas y mejorarlas. Los 
profesores, los estudiantes, los investigadores, los editores, y los 
reveladores del software son todo el funcionamiento juntos en 
herramientas de la matemáticas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086466</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107634</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/math-tools</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
