<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103341</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103341</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203943</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">MicrobeWorld</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">MicrobeWorld</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">MicrobeWorld</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">MicrobeWorld</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">MicrobeWorld</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">MicrobeWorld</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">MicrobeWorld</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Hosted by the American Society for Microbiologists (ASM), this site explores the world of microbes with vivid images and descriptions. It contains information about microbiology, what microbiologists do, and how they do it. The site features MicrobeWorld Radio, an in-depth focus on topics in microbiology, a weekly digest of what's new in microbiology, information about the TV series and companion book "Intimate Strangers: Unseen Life on Earth," and links to other ASM sites.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bewirtet durch die amerikanische Gesellschaft für
Biologen (ASM), erforscht diese Site die Welt der Mikroben mit klaren 
Bildern und Beschreibungen. Sie enthält Informationen über 
Mikrobiologie, welche Biologen tun und wie sie sie tun. Der 
Situationsmerkmale MicrobeWorld Radio, ein eingehender Fokus auf 
Themen in der Mikrobiologie, eine wöchentliche Auswahl von, was in 
der Mikrobiologie, in den Informationen über die Fernsehapparat Serie
und Begleiterbuch "in den vertrauten Fremden neu ist: Unseen 
Lebensdauer auf Masse, "und Links zu anderen ASM Sites.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Accueilli par la société américaine pour les 
microbiologistes (ASM), ce site explore le monde des microbes avec des
images et des descriptions vives. Il contient des informations 
sur la microbiologie, quels microbiologistes font, et comment ils la 
font. La radio de MicrobeWorld de dispositifs de site, un foyer 
détaillé sur des sujets en microbiologie, un sommaire hebdomadaire 
de ce qu'il y a de neuf dans la microbiologie, les informations sur la
série de TV et les étrangers intimes de livre de compagnon ": 
La vie invisible sur terre, "et liens à d'autres sites d'ASM.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Hospedado pela sociedade americana para os 
microbiologists (ASM), este local explora o mundo dos micróbios com 
imagens e descrições vívidas. Contem a informação sobre o 
microbiology, que microbiologists fazem, e como o fazem. O 
rádio de MicrobeWorld das características de local, um foco in-depth
em tópicos no microbiology, um sumário semanal de o que é novo no 
microbiology, na informação sobre a série da tevê e em 
desconhecido intimate do livro do companheiro ": Vida 
despercebida na terra, "e ligações a outros locais do ASM.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ospitato dalla società americana per i 
microbiologi (ASM), questo luogo esplora il mondo dei microbi con le 
immagini e le descrizioni chiare. Contiene le informazioni su 
microbiologia, che microbiologi fanno e come la fanno. La radio 
di MicrobeWorld delle caratteristiche di luogo, un fuoco approfondito 
sui soggetti in microbiologia, una raccolta settimanale di che cosa è
nuovo nella microbiologia, nelle informazioni sulla serie della TV e 
negli sconosciuti intimi del libro del compagno ": Vita unseen 
su terra, "e collegamenti ad altri luoghi dell'ASM.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Φιλοξενημένη από την αμερικανική κοινωνία για τους 
μικροβιολόγους (ASM), αυτή η περιοχή εξερευνά τον κόσμο των 
μικροβίων με τις ζωηρές εικόνες και τις περιγραφές. 
Περιέχει τις πληροφορίες για τη μικροβιολογία, ποιοι 
μικροβιολόγοι, και πώς το κάνουν. Η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει 
MicrobeWorld το ραδιόφωνο, μια σε βάθος εστίαση στα θέματα στη 
μικροβιολογία, μια εβδομαδιαία αφομοίωση ποιου νέου στη 
μικροβιολογία, οι πληροφορίες για τη σειρά TV και ο σύντροφος 
κρατούν τους "οικείους ξένους: Απαρατήρητη ζωή στη γη, "και
συνδέσεις με άλλες περιοχές ASM.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Recibido por la sociedad americana para los 
microbiólogos (ASM), este sitio explora el mundo de microbios con 
imágenes y descripciones vivas. Contiene la información sobre 
la microbiología, qué microbiólogos hacen, y cómo la hacen. 
La radio de MicrobeWorld de las características de sitio, un 
foco profundizado en asuntos en microbiología, un resumen semanal de 
cuál es nuevo en microbiología, la información sobre la serie de la
TV y extranjeros Íntimos del libro del compañero ": Vida 
no vista en la tierra, "y conexiones a otros sitios del ASM.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:AMERICAN SOCIETY FOR MICROBIOLOGY
FN:AMERICAN SOCIETY FOR MICROBIOLOGY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203943</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103341</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/microbeworld</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
