<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108006</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108006</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200412</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">American Scientist</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Amerikanischer Wissenschaftler</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Scientifique Américain</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Cientista Americano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienziato Americano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αμερικανικός επιστήμονας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Científico Americano</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Web site is designed to provide a sample of the content the magazine, and to encourage exploration and discussion of themes treated in the magazine. American Scientist is an illustrated bimonthly magazine about science and technology and covers work in fields that range from molecular biology to computer engineering. Readers also enjoy The Scientists' Bookshelf, a comprehensive book-review section and a number of regular columns that cover topics in computing, engineering, public and professional issues and reflections on the history and practice of science. Once a year, the editors enlist children to help review books, software and other products for young scientists. This site includes a very useful search tool that allows the user to locate articles using key words or phrases. This resource is part of the Biocomplexity collection. http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Web site ist, um eine Probe des Inhalts zur 
Verfügung zu stellen die Zeitschrift, konzipiert und Erforschung und 
Diskussion über die Themen anzuregen, die in der Zeitschrift 
behandelt werden. Amerikanischer Wissenschaftler ist eine 
erläuterte zweimonatliche Zeitschrift über Wissenschaft und 
Technologie und Abdeckungen arbeiten auffängt innen diese 
Strecke von der molekularen Biologie zur Computertechnik. Leser 
genießen auch das Bücherregal der Wissenschaftler, ein komplettes 
Buch-Zusammenfassung Kapitel und eine Anzahl von regelmäßigen 
Spalten, die Themen im Rechnen, in der Technik, in der Öffentlichkeit
und in den Fachmannausgaben und -reflexionen auf der Geschichte und 
der Praxis der Wissenschaft umfassen. Einmal jährlich tragen 
die Herausgeber Kinder ein, um Zusammenfassungbüchern, Software und 
anderen Produkten für junge Wissenschaftler zu helfen. Diese 
Site enthält ein sehr nützliches Suchhilfsmittel, das dem Benutzer 
erlaubt, Artikel mit Schlüsselwörtern oder Phrasen zu lokalisieren. 
Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Teil der Biocomplexity Ansammlung 
http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site de Web est conçu pour fournir un 
échantillon du contenu le magasin, et pour encourager l'exploration 
et la discussion des thèmes traités dans le magasin. Le 
scientifique américain est un magasin bimensuel illustré au sujet de
la science et la technologie et les couvertures fonctionnent dans les 
domaines qui s'étendent de la biologie moléculaire au génie 
informatique. Les lecteurs apprécient également l'étagère 
des scientifiques, une section complète de livre-revue et un certain 
nombre de colonnes régulières qui couvrent des sujets en calculant, 
en machinant, le public et les issues et les réflexions de 
professionnel sur l'histoire et la pratique de la science. Une 
fois par an, les éditeurs enrôlent des enfants pour aider les livres
de revue, le logiciel et d'autres produits pour de jeunes 
scientifiques. Ce site inclut un outil très utile de recherche 
qui permet à l'utilisateur de localiser des articles en utilisant les
mots clés ou des expressions. Cette ressource fait partie de la
collection http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/ de Biocomplexity</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Web site é projetado fornecer uma amostra do
índice o compartimento, e incentivar a exploração e a discussão 
dos temas tratados no compartimento. O cientista americano é um
compartimento bimonthly ilustrado sobre a ciência e a tecnologia e as
tampas trabalham nos campos que variam da biologia molecular à 
engenharia de computador. Os leitores aprecíam também o 
bookshelf dos cientistas, uma seção detalhada da livro-revisão e um
número de colunas regulares que cobrem tópicos em computar, em 
projetar, em público e em edições e em reflexões do profissional 
no history e na prática da ciência. Uma vez um ano, os 
editores alistam crianças para ajudar a livros da revisão, a 
software e a outros produtos para cientistas novos. Este local 
inclui uma ferramenta muito útil da busca que permita que o usuário 
encontre artigos usando as palavras chaves ou as frases. Este 
recurso é parte da coleção http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/ 
de Biocomplexity</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Web site è destinato per fornire un 
campione del soddisfare lo scomparto e per consigliare 
all'esplorazione ed alla discussione sui temi trattati nello 
scomparto. Lo scienziato americano è uno scomparto bimestrale 
illustrato circa la scienza e la tecnologia e le coperture funzionano 
nei campi che variano da biologia molecolare ad ingegneria di 
calcolatore. I lettori egualmente godono il bookshelf degli 
scienziati, una sezione completa di libro-revisione ed un certo numero
di colonne normali che riguardano i soggetti nella computazione, 
nell'ingegneria, in pubblico e nelle edizioni e nelle riflessioni del 
professionista sulla storia e sulla pratica della scienza. Una 
volta all'anno, gli editori arruolano i bambini per aiutare i libri di
revisione, il software ed altri prodotti per gli scienziati giovani. 
Questo luogo include uno strumento molto utile di ricerca che 
permette che l'utente individui gli articoli usando le parole o le 
frasi chiave. Questa risorsa fa parte dell'accumulazione 
http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/ di Biocomplexity</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος σχεδιάζεται για να παρέχει ένα 
δείγμα του περιεχομένου το περιοδικό, και για να ενθαρρύνει την 
εξερεύνηση και τη συζήτηση των θεμάτων που αντιμετωπίζονται στο 
περιοδικό. Ο αμερικανικός επιστήμονας είναι ένα 
διευκρινισμένο διμηνιαίο περιοδικό για την επιστήμη και την 
τεχνολογία και καλύπτει την εργασία στα πεδία που κυμαίνονται 
από τη μοριακή βιολογία ως την εφαρμοσμένη μηχανική υπολογιστών.
Οι αναγνώστες απολαμβάνουν επίσης το ράφι των επιστημόνων, 
ένα περιεκτικό τμήμα βιβλίο-αναθεώρησης και διάφορες κανονικές 
στήλες που καλύπτουν τα θέματα στον υπολογισμό, την εφαρμοσμένη 
μηχανική, τα δημόσιες και επαγγελματικές ζητήματα και τις 
αντανακλάσεις στην ιστορία και την πρακτική της επιστήμης. 
Μία φορά το χρόνο, οι επεξεργαστές στρατολογούν τα παιδιά 
για να βοηθήσουν τα βιβλία αναθεώρησης, το λογισμικό και άλλα 
προϊόντα για τους νέους επιστήμονες. Αυτή η περιοχή 
περιλαμβάνει ένα πολύ χρήσιμο εργαλείο αναζήτησης που επιτρέπει
στο χρήστη για να εντοπίσει τα άρθρα χρησιμοποιώντας τις βασικές 
λέξεις ή τις φράσεις. Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς είναι
μέρος της Biocomplexity συλλογής 
http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio del Web se diseña para 
proporcionar a una muestra del contenido el compartimiento, y para 
animar la exploración y la discusión de los temas tratados en el 
compartimiento. El científico americano es un compartimiento 
bimensual ilustrado sobre ciencia y la tecnología y las cubiertas 
trabajan en los campos que se extienden de biología molecular a la 
ingeniería de ordenador. Los programas de lectura también 
gozan del estante de los científicos, una sección comprensiva de la 
libro-revisio'n y un número de columnas regulares que cubren asuntos 
en computar, dirigir, público y ediciones y reflexiones del 
profesional en la historia y la práctica de la ciencia. Una vez
al año, los editores alistan a niños para ayudar a los libros de la 
revisión, a software y a otros productos para los científicos 
jóvenes. Este sitio incluye una herramienta muy útil de la 
búsqueda que permita que el utilizador localice los artículos usando
las palabras claves o las frases. Este recurso es parte de la 
colección http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/ de Biocomplexity</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200412</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108006</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/american-scientist</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
