<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108102</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108102</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211179</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Basic Filmmaking for High School Drama Departments</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Grundlegendes Filmmaking für High School 
Drama-Abteilungen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Filmmaking de base pour des services de drame de 
lycée</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Filmmaking básico para departamentos do drama da 
High School</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Filmmaking di base per i reparti di dramma della 
High School</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βασικό Filmmaking για τα τμήματα δράματος γυμνασίου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Filmmaking básico para los departamentos del 
drama de la High School secundaria</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This is a course in Narrative Film Production which shows how drama departments can create short motion pictures as part of a drama class. Currently, we have only one lesson. But eventually, there will be more. And with each lesson, you will participate in the making of a movie based on your own story.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses ist ein Kurs in der erzählenden 
Film-Produktion, die zeigt, wie Dramaabteilungen kurze Bewegung 
Abbildungen als Teil einer Dramakategorie erstellen können. 
Aktuell haben wir nur eine Lektion. Aber schließlich, 
gibt es mehr. Und mit jeder Lektion, nehmen Sie am Bilden eines 
Films teil, der auf Ihrer eigenen Geschichte basiert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">C'est un cours de la production narrative de film 
qui montre comment les services de drame peuvent créer les films 
cinématographiques courts en tant qu'élément d'une classe de drame.
Actuel, nous avons seulement une leçon. Mais par la 
suite, il y aura plus. Et avec chaque leçon, vous participerez 
à la fabrication d'un film basé sur votre propre histoire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este é um curso na produção narrativa da 
película que mostra como os departamentos do drama podem criar 
retratos de movimento curtos como a parte de uma classe do drama. 
Atualmente, nós temos somente uma lição. Mas 
eventualmente, haverá mais. E com cada lição, você 
participará em fazer de um filme baseado em sua própria história.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ciò è un corso nella produzione narrativa della 
pellicola che mostra come i reparti di dramma possono creare il cinema
corto come componente di un codice categoria di dramma. 
Attualmente, abbiamo soltanto una lezione. Ma finalmente, 
ci saranno più. E con ogni lezione, parteciperete a fare di un 
film basato sulla vostra propria storia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό είναι μια σειρά μαθημάτων στην αφηγηματική 
παραγωγή ταινιών που επιδεικνύει πώς τα τμήματα δράματος 
μπορούν να δημιουργήσουν τις σύντομες ταινίες ως τμήμα μιας 
κλάσης δράματος. Αυτήν την περίοδο, έχουμε μόνο ένα 
μάθημα. Αλλά τελικά, θα υπάρξουν περισσότεροι. Και με
κάθε μάθημα, θα συμμετάσχετε στην παραγωγή ενός κινηματογράφου 
βασισμένου στην ιστορία σας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esto es un curso en la producción narrativa de la
película que muestra cómo los departamentos del drama pueden crear 
películas cortas como parte de una clase del drama. 
Actualmente, tenemos solamente una lección. Pero 
eventual, habrá más. Y con cada lección, usted participará 
en la fabricación de una película basada en su propia historia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211179</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">GNU Free Documentation License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108102</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/basic-filmmaking</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
