<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107165</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107165</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206336</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Brown v. Board: Five Communities That Changed America</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Braunes v. Brett: Fünf Gemeinschaften, Die 
Amerika Änderten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Panneau brun de v. : Les Cinq Communautés 
Qui Ont changé l'Amérique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Placa marrom do v.: Cinco Comunidades Que 
Mudaram América</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Bordo marrone del v.: Cinque Comunità
Che Hanno cambiato L'America</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Brown V. Board: Πέντε Κοινότητες που 
άλλαξαν την Αμερική</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Tarjeta marrón del v.: Cinco Comunidades 
Que Cambiaron América</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">describes five cases the Supreme Court agreed to hear in 1952 under one title: Brown v. Board of Education. The cases originated in Delaware, Kansas, South Carolina, Virginia, and Washington, D.C. Each contested the separate but equal doctrine of the Court's 1896 Plessy v. Ferguson decision, which by the 1950s had resulted in 17 states requiring racial segregation in public schools and 4 states allowing it.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">beschreibt fünf Fälle das Höchste Gericht, das 
vereinbart wird, um in 1952 unter einem Namen zu hören: Braunes
v. Brett der Ausbildung. Die Fälle entstanden in Delaware, 
Kansas, Südcarolina, Virginia, und Washington, D.C. Each wetteiferte 
die unterschiedliche aber gleiche Lehre der Plessy V. Ferguson des 
Gerichtes Entscheidung 1896, die bis zum den fünfziger Jahren 17 
Zustände ergeben hatte, die rassische Abtrennung in den allgemeinen 
Schulen benötigen und 4 Zustände, sie erlaubend.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">décrit cinq cas la cour suprême acceptée pour 
entendre dans 1952 au-dessous de un titre : Panneau brun de v. 
d'éducation. Les caisses ont provenu du Delaware, le Kansas, 
Caroline du sud, la Virginie, et Washington, D.C. Each a 
contesté la doctrine séparée mais égale de la décision 1896 de 
Plessy v. Ferguson de la cour, qui par les années 50 avait eu comme 
conséquence 17 états exigeant la ségrégation raciale dans des 
écoles d'Etat et 4 états la permettant.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">descreve cinco casos a corte suprema concordada 
ouvir-se em 1952 sob um título: Placa marrom do v. da 
instrução. Os casos originaram em Delaware, Kansas, carolina 
sul, Virgínia, e Washington, C.C. Cada contestou a doutrina separada 
mas igual da decisão 1896 de Plessy v. Ferguson da corte, que pelos 
1950s tinha resultado em 17 estados que requerem o segregation racial 
em escolas públicas e em 4 estados permitindo o.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">descrive cinque casi la Corte suprema 
accosentita per sentirsi in 1952 sotto un titolo: 
Bordo marrone del v. di formazione. I casi 
provenuti nel Delaware, Kansas, Carolina del Sud, la Virginia e 
Washington, D.C. Each hanno contestato il separato ma la dottrina 
uguale della decisione 1896 di Plessy v. Ferguson della corte, che 
entro gli anni 50 aveva provocato 17 dichiara richiedere la 
segregazione razziale in "public school" ed in 4 dichiara 
permetterla.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">περιγράφει πέντε υποθέσεις που το ανώτατο δικαστήριο 
συμφώνησε να εξετάσει το 1952 υπό έναν τίτλο: Brown 
V. Board της εκπαίδευσης. Οι περιπτώσεις που 
δημιουργούνται στο Delaware, το Κάνσας, τη νότια Καρολίνα, τη 
Βιρτζίνια, και την Ουάσιγκτον, ΣΥΝΕΧΈΣ ΡΕΎΜΑ Κάθε ένας 
αμφισβήτησε το χωριστό αλλά ίσο δόγμα της 1896 Plessy V.
Ferguson του δικαστηρίου απόφασης, η οποία μέχρι τη δεκαετία 
του '50 είχε οδηγήσει σε 17 κράτη που απαιτούν το φυλετικό 
διαχωρισμό στα δημόσια σχολεία και 4 κράτη που επιτρέπουν το.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">describe cinco casos el Tribunal Supremo acordado 
para oír en 1952 bajo un título: Tarjeta marrón del v. de la 
educación. Los casos originaron en Delaware, Kansas, Carolina 
del Sur, Virginia, y Washington, D.C. Each disputó la doctrina 
separada pero igual de la decisión 1896 de Plessy v. Ferguson de la 
corte, que por los años 50 había dado lugar a 17 estados que 
requerían la segregación racial en escuelas públicas y a 4 estados 
permitiéndola.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206336</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107165</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/brown-v-board-five-communities-that-changed-america</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
