<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104877</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104877</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213008</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Virtual Courseware for Earth and Environmental Sciences</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Virtuelles Unterrichtsprogramm für Masse und 
Klimawissenschaften</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Courseware virtuel pour la terre et les sciences 
environnementales</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Courseware virtual para a terra e ciências 
ambientais</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Courseware virtuale per terra e scienze 
ambientali</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εικονικό διδακτικό υλικό για τη γη και τις 
περιβαλλοντικές επιστήμες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Courseware virtual para la tierra y las ciencias 
ambientales</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site is a collection of interactive, inquiry-based learning exercises for variety of science topics. Activities are grouped by category and include earthquakes and seismicity, global warming, absolute dating, hydrology, and biology. Earth science tutorials and online laboratory activities feature photographs, maps, diagrams, interactive graphs, and helpful illustrations and animations that make the activities user-friendly and engaging. Exercises teach as they go by requiring students to answer questions correctly before they can proceed to the next section. Assessment tools such as quizzes and exams are available for instructors. The site also provides a link to Biology Labs On-Line, a comprehensive site of biology simulations and exercises available for a fee.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site ist eine Ansammlung interaktives, 
Anfrage-gegründetes Lernen trainiert für Vielzahl der Wissenschaft 
Themen. Aktivitäten werden durch Kategorie gruppiert und 
Erdbeben und Seismicity, globales Wärmen, absolute Datierung, 
Hydrologie und Biologie einschließen. Geowissenschaft Tutorials
und Laboronline-Dienst kennzeichnen Fotographien, Karten, Diagramme, 
interaktive Diagramme und nützliche Abbildungen und Animationen, die 
die Aktivitäten benutzerfreundlich und das Engagieren bilden. 
Übungen unterrichten, während sie gehen, indem sie 
Kursteilnehmer benötigen, Fragen richtig zu beantworten, bevor sie 
zum folgenden Kapitel fortfahren können. Einschätzung 
Hilfsmittel wie Quizen und Prüfungen sind für Ausbilder vorhanden. 
Die Site stellt auch ein Link zu den Biologie-Labors online, zu 
einer kompletten Site der Biologiesimulationen und zu den Übungen, 
die für eine Gebühr vorhanden sind zur Verfügung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site est une collection d'exercices d'étude 
interactifs et enquête-basés pour la variété de sujets de la 
science. Des activités sont groupées par catégorie et 
incluent des tremblements de terre et séismicité, chauffage global, 
dater absolu, hydrologie, et biologie. Les cours d'instruction 
de science de la terre et les activités en ligne de laboratoire 
comportent des photographies, des cartes, des diagrammes, des 
graphiques interactifs, et des illustrations et des animations utiles 
qui rendent les activités convivial et s'engager. Les exercices
enseignent pendant qu'ils vont en exigeant des étudiants de répondre
à des questions correctement avant qu'ils puissent procéder à la 
prochaine section. Les outils d'évaluation tels que des jeux et
des examens sont disponibles pour des instructeurs. Le site 
fournit également un lien aux laboratoires de biologie en ligne, à 
un site complet des simulations de biologie et aux exercices 
disponibles pour des honoraires.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local é uma coleção de exercícios de 
aprendizagem interativos, inquérito-baseados para a variedade de 
tópicos da ciência. As atividades são agrupadas pela 
categoria e incluem terremotos e seismicity, aquecer-se global, datar 
absoluto, hydrology, e biologia. Os tutorials da ciência de 
terra e as atividades em linha do laboratório caracterizam 
fotografias, mapas, diagramas, gráficos interativos, e as 
ilustrações e os animations úteis que fazem as atividades 
user-friendly e acoplar. Os exercícios ensinam enquanto vão 
requerendo estudantes responder corretamente a perguntas antes que 
possam proseguir à seção seguinte. As ferramentas da 
avaliação tais como quizzes e exams estão disponíveis para 
instrutores. O local fornece também uma ligação aos 
laboratórios de biologia em linha, a um local detalhado de 
simulações da biologia e aos exercícios disponíveis para uma taxa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo è una collezione di esercitazioni 
imparanti interattive e inchiesta-basate per varietà di soggetti di 
scienza. Le attività sono raggruppate per la categoria ed 
includono i terremoti e la sismicità, riscaldamento globale, datare 
assoluto, l'idrologia e biologia. Le lezioni private di scienze 
della terra e le attività in linea del laboratorio caratterizzano le 
fotografie, programmi, schemi, grafici interattivi ed illustrazioni ed
animazioni utili che rendono le attività facile da usare e 
l'aggancio. Le esercitazioni insegnano mentre vanno richiedendo 
agli allievi di rispondere correttamente alle domande prima che 
possano continuare alla sezione seguente. Gli strumenti di 
valutazione quali i quiz ed i exams sono disponibili per gli 
istruttori. Il luogo egualmente fornisce un collegamento ai 
laboratori di biologia in linea, ad un luogo completo delle 
simulazioni di biologia ed alle esercitazioni disponibili per una 
tassa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή είναι μια συλλογή των διαλογικών, 
έρευνα-βασισμένων στον ασκήσεων εκμάθησης για την ποικιλία των 
θεμάτων επιστήμης. Οι δραστηριότητες ομαδοποιούνται ανά 
κατηγορία και περιλαμβάνουν τους σεισμούς και seismicity, την 
παγκόσμια αύξηση της θερμοκρασίας λόγω του φαινομένου του 
θερμοκηπίου, την απόλυτη χρονολόγηση, την υδρολογία, και τη 
βιολογία. Τα σεμινάρια γήινης επιστήμης και οι σε απευθείας
σύνδεση εργαστηριακές δραστηριότητες χαρακτηρίζουν τις 
φωτογραφίες, τους χάρτες, τα διαγράμματα, τις διαλογικές γραφικές
παραστάσεις, και τις χρήσιμες απεικονίσεις και τις ζωτικότητες που
κάνουν τις δραστηριότητες φιλικές προς το χρήστη και δεσμεύοντας.
Οι ασκήσεις διδάσκουν καθώς πηγαίνουν με την απαίτηση των 
σπουδαστών για να απαντηθούν οι ερωτήσεις σωστά προτού να 
μπορέσουν να προχωρήσουν στο επόμενο τμήμα. Τα εργαλεία 
αξιολόγησης όπως οι διαγωνισμοοι γνώσεων και οι διαγωνισμοί είναι
διαθέσιμα για τους εκπαιδευτικούς. Η περιοχή παρέχει επίσης
μια σύνδεση με τα εργαστήρια της βιολογίας on-line, μια 
περιεκτική περιοχή των προσομοιώσεων και των ασκήσεων της 
βιολογίας διαθέσιμων έναντι αμοιβής.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio es una colección de los ejercicios que
aprenden interactivos, pregunta-basados para la variedad de asuntos de
la ciencia. Las actividades son agrupadas por categoría e 
incluyen terremotos y sismicidad, el calentarse global, el fechar 
absoluto, hidrología, y biología. Las guías de la geología y
las actividades en línea del laboratorio ofrecen las fotografías, 
las correspondencias, los diagramas, los gráficos interactivos, y las
ilustraciones y las animaciones provechosas que hacen las actividades 
convivial y el acoplamiento. Los ejercicios enseñan mientras 
que van requiriendo a estudiantes contestar a preguntas correctamente 
antes de que puedan proceder a la sección siguiente. Las 
herramientas del gravamen tales como concursos y exámenes están 
disponibles para los instructores. El sitio también proporciona
a una conexión a laboratorios de biología en línea, a un sitio 
comprensivo de las simulaciones de la biología y a los ejercicios 
disponibles para un honorario.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:DAVID MAYO
FN:DAVID MAYO
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213008</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104877</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/virtual-courseware-for-earth-and-environmental-sciences</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
