<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104980</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104980</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086241</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"His Car Is His Pride": Ode to a World War I Ambulance</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Sein Auto Ist Sein Stolz": Ode zu einem 
Weltkrieg-Krankenwagen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Sa Voiture Est Sa Fierté" : Ode à une 
ambulance de Première Guerre Mondiale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Seu Carro É Seu Orgulho": Ode a uma 
ambulância do world.war.i</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Il Suo Automobile È Il Suo Orgoglio": Ode 
ad un'ambulanza di world.war.i</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Το αυτοκίνητό του είναι η υπερηφάνειά του": 
Ωδή σε έναν παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι ασθενοφόρο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Su Coche Es Su Orgullo": Oda a una 
ambulancia de la Primera Guerra Mundial</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Even before the United States entered World War I, some young men signed up with the volunteer ambulance corps, which recruited college students and recent graduates to serve on the French and Italian fronts. Among them were such later famous writers as e. e. cummings, Dashiell Hammett, John Dos Passos, and Ernest Hemingway. Not surprisingly, many of these former ambulance drivers later wrote about their experiences in memoirs and novels. In this passage, from a book-length memoir, Robert Whitney Imbrie wrote in a humorous vein of the bond of affection and loyalty between an ambulance driver and his car.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sogar bevor die Vereinigten Staaten den Ersten 
Weltkrieg eintrugen, unterzeichneten einige junge Männer oben mit dem
freiwilligen Krankenwagenkorps, das Studenten und neue Absolvent 
einzog, um auf den französischen und italienischen Frontseiten zu 
dienen. Unter ihnen waren solche neuere berühmte Verfasser wie 
e. e. cummings, Dashiell Hammett, John DOS Passos und Ernest 
Hemingway. Nicht überraschend, schrieben viele dieser 
ehemaligen Krankenwagentreiber später über ihre Erfahrungen in 
Abhandlungen und in Romane. In diesem Durchgang von einer 
Buch-Länge Abhandlung, schrieb Robert Whitney Imbrie in eine 
humorvolle Ader der Bindung der Neigung und der Loyalität zwischen 
einem Krankenwagentreiber und seinem Auto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Même avant que les Etats-Unis ont écrit la 
Première Guerre Mondiale, quelques jeunes hommes se sont 
engagés avec les corps volontaires d'ambulance, qui ont 
recruté des étudiants d'université et des diplômés récents pour 
servir sur les avants français et italiens. Parmi eux étaient 
de plus défunts auteurs célèbres tels que des cummings de e. de e.,
Dashiell Hammett, DOS Passos de John, et Ernest Hemingway. Pas 
étonnamment, plusieurs de ces anciens gestionnaires d'ambulance plus 
tard ont écrit au sujet de leurs expériences en mémoires et romans.
Dans ce passage, d'un mémoire de livre-longueur, Robert Whitney
Imbrie a écrit dans une veine pleine d'humour de l'obligation de 
l'affection et de la fidélité entre un gestionnaire d'ambulance et 
sa voiture.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Mesmo antes que os estados unidos incorporaram o 
world.war.i, alguns homens novos assinaram acima com o corpo 
voluntário da ambulância, que recrutou estudantes de faculdade e 
graduados recentes para servir nas partes dianteiras francesas e 
italianas. Entre eles eram escritores famosos mais atrasados 
como cummings do e. do e., Dashiell Hammett, Dos Passos de John, e 
Ernest Hemingway. Não surprisingly, muitos destes excitadores 
anteriores da ambulância escreveram mais tarde sobre suas 
experiências nos memoirs e nas novelas. Nesta passagem, de um 
memoir do livro-comprimento, Robert Whitney Imbrie escreveu em uma 
veia humorous da ligação da afeição e da lealdade entre um 
excitador da ambulância e seu carro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Anche prima che unito Dichiari il 
world.war.i inserito, alcuni giovani hanno firmato in su con il 
corpo volontario dell'ambulanza, che hanno reclutato gli 
allievi di università ed i neo-laureati per servire sulle parti 
anteriori francesi ed italiane. Fra loro erano tali produttori 
famosi successivi come i cummings del e. del e., Dashiell Hammett, il 
DOS Passos del John ed Ernest Hemingway. Non sorprendentemente, 
molti di questi driver precedenti dell'ambulanza più successivamente 
hanno scritto circa le loro esperienze in memorie e romanzi. In 
questo passaggio, da una memoria di libro-lunghezza, Robert Whitney 
Imbrie ha scritto in una vena divertente del legame di affetto e di 
lealtà fra un driver dell'ambulanza ed il suo automobile.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ακόμη και πριν από τον εισαγμένο οι Ηνωμένες 
Πολιτείες παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι, μερικοί νεαροί άνδρες υπέγραψαν 
επάνω με το εθελοντικό ασθενοφόρο σώμα, το οποίο 
στρατολόγησε τους σπουδαστές κολλεγίων και τους πρόσφατους 
πτυχιούχους εξυπηρετώ στα γαλλικά και ιταλικά μέτωπα. 
Μεταξύ τους ήταν τέτοιοι πιό πρώην διάσημοι συγγραφείς 
όπως τα cummings ε. ε., Dashiell Hammett, John Dos 
Passos, και Ernest Hemingway. Όπως ήταν αναμενόμενο,
πολλοί από αυτούς τους προηγούμενους οδηγούς ασθενοφόρων 
έγραψαν αργότερα για την εμπειρία τους στα απομνημονεύματα και τα 
μυθιστορήματα. Σε αυτήν την μετάβαση, από απομνημονεύματα 
βιβλίο-μήκους, Robert Whitney Imbrie έγραψε σε μια 
χιουμοριστική φλέβα του δεσμού της αγάπης και της πίστης μεταξύ 
ενός οδηγού ασθενοφόρων και του αυτοκινήτου του.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Incluso antes de que los Estados Unidos 
incorporaron Primera Guerra Mundial, algunos hombres jóvenes firmaron
para arriba con el cuerpo voluntario de la ambulancia, que reclutó a 
estudiantes de universidad y a graduados recientes para servir en los 
frentes franceses e italianos. Entre ellos estaban los programas
de escritura famosos más últimos tales como cummings del e. del e., 
Dashiell Hammett, DOS Passos de Juan, y Ernest Hemingway. No 
asombrosamente, muchos de estos programas pilotos anteriores de la 
ambulancia escribieron más adelante sobre sus experiencias en 
memorias y novelas. En este paso, de una memoria de la 
libro-longitud, Roberto Whitney Imbrie escribió en una vena chistosa 
del enlace del afecto y de la lealtad entre un programa piloto de la 
ambulancia y su coche.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086241</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104980</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/his-car-is-his-pride-ode-to-a-world-war-i-ambulance</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
