<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107144</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107144</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086392</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Lament for Lives Lost: Rose Schneiderman and the Triangle Fire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bejammern Sie für die verlorenen Leben: Rose
Schneiderman und das Dreieck-Feuer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Déplorez pendant les vies détruites : Rose 
Schneiderman et le feu de triangle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Lament por as vidas perdidas: Rosa 
Schneiderman e o fogo do triângulo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Deplori le vite perse: Rosa Schneiderman ed 
il fuoco del triangolo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θρηνήστε τις ζωές που χάνονται για: Αυξήθηκε 
Schneiderman και το πυρ τριγώνων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Laméntese por las vidas perdidas: Rose 
Schneiderman y el fuego del triángulo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">One of the greatest industrial tragedies in U.S. history occurred on March 25, 1911, when 146 workers, mostly young immigrant women, died in a fire at the Triangle Shirtwaist company in New York City. The victims had been trapped by blocked exit doors and faulty fire escapes. The aftermath of the catastrophe brought grief and recriminations. Protest rallies and memorial meetings were held throughout the city. During one meeting at the Metropolitan Opera House, tension broke out between the working-class Lower East Siders who filled the galleries (and saw class solidarity as the ultimate solution to the problems of industrial safety) and the middle- and upper-class women in the boxes who sought reforms like creation of a bureau of fire prevention. The meeting would have broken up in disorder if not for a stirring speech by Rose Schneiderman, a Polish-born former hat worker who had once led a strike at the Triangle factory. Although she barely spoke above a whisper, Schneiderman held the audience spellbound.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine der größten industriellen Tragödien in der
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Geschichte trat an März 25, 1911, als 146 
Arbeiter, meistens die jungen einwandernden Frauen auf, gestorben in 
einem Feuer bei der Dreieck Shirtwaist Firma in New York City. 
Die Opfer waren durch geblockte Ausgang Türen eingeschlossen 
worden und fehlerhaftes Feuer entgeht. Die Nachmahd der 
Katastrophe holte Leid und Recriminations. Protest sammelt und 
Erinnerungssitzungen fanden in der Stadt statt. Während eines, 
das am Metropolitanoper Haus trifft, brach Spannkraft zwischen der 
Arbeiterklasse niedrigeres Ostsiders aus, die die Galerien (und 
Sägekategorie solidarität als die entscheidende Lösung zu den 
Problemen industrieller Sicherheit) und die mittleren und der 
Oberklasse Frauen in den Kästen füllte, die Verbesserungen wie 
Kreation eines Büros der Feuerverhütung suchten. Die Sitzung 
würde oben Störung eingelaufen haben, wenn nicht für eine rührende
Rede durch Rose Schneiderman, ein Polieren-getragener ehemaliger 
Hutarbeiter, der hatte, einmal einen Schlag an der Dreieckfabrik 
führte. Obgleich sie kaum über einem Flüstern sprach, 
hielt Schneiderman die Publikum spellbound an.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une des plus grandes tragédies industrielles dans
l'histoire des ETATS-UNIS s'est produite 25 mars 1911, quand 146 
ouvriers, la plupart du temps jeunes femmes immigrées, mortes dans un
feu à la compagnie de Chemisier de triangle à New York City. 
Les victimes avaient été emprisonnées par les portes 
bloquées de sortie et le feu défectueux s'échappe. Le 
lendemain de la catastrophe a apporté la peine et les 
récriminations. La protestation se rassemble et des réunions 
commémoratives ont été tenues dans toute la ville. Pendant 
l'on se réunissant au théatre de l'$opéra métropolitain, la 
tension a éclaté entre le classe ouvrier Siders est inférieur qui a
rempli galeries (et solidarité de classe de scie comme solution 
finale aux problèmes de la sécurité du travail) et femmes moyen- et
de la bourgeoisie dans les cadres qui ont recherché des réformes 
comme la création d'un bureau de protection contre l'incendie. 
La réunion aurait enfoncé vers le haut le désordre si pas 
pour un discours d'agitation par Rose Schneiderman, un ancien ouvrier 
Polir-soutenu de chapeau qui a eu menait par le passé une grève à 
l'usine de triangle. Bien qu'elle ait à peine parlé au-dessus 
d'un chuchotement, Schneiderman a jugé les assistances 
fascinées.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uma das tragédias industriais as mais grandes no 
history de ESTADOS UNIDOS ocorreu março em 25, 1911, quando 146 
trabalhadores, na maior parte mulheres immigrant novas, morridas em um
fogo na companhia de Shirtwaist do triângulo em New York City. 
As vítimas tinham sido prendidas por portas obstruídas da 
saída e o fogo defeituoso escapa-se. O aftermath do catastrophe
trouxe o grief e os recriminations. O protesto rallies e as 
reuniões memorial foram realizadas durante todo a cidade. 
Durante um que encontra-se com na casa de ópera metropolitana, 
a tensão quebrou para fora entre o working-class um Siders do leste 
mais baixo que encheu as galerias (e o solidarity da classe da serra 
como a solução final aos problemas da segurança industrial) e as 
mulheres médias e upper-class nas caixas que procuraram reformas como
a criação de um departamento da prevenção de fogo. A 
reunião quebraria acima no disorder if.not para um discurso agitando 
por Rosa Schneiderman, um trabalhador anterior Lustr-carregado do 
chapéu que tivesse conduzisse uma vez a uma batida na fábrica do 
triângulo. Embora falasse mal acima de um sussurro, 
Schneiderman manteve as audiências spellbound.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Una delle tragedie industriali più grandi nella 
storia degli STATI UNITI si è presentata il 25 marzo 1911, quando 146
operai, principalmente donne immigrate giovani, morte in un fuoco 
all'azienda di Shirtwaist del triangolo a New York City. Le 
vittime erano state bloccate dai portelli ostruiti dell'uscita ed il 
fuoco difettoso fuoriesce. Il guaime della catastrofe ha portato
il dolore ed i recriminations. La protesta si raduna e le 
riunioni commemorative sono state tenute durante la città. 
Durante l'uno che viene a contatto alla Camera di opera 
metropolitana, il tensionamento ha scoppiato fra la classe operaia 
Siders orientale più basso che ha riempito le gallerie (e 
solidarietà del codice categoria della sega come l'ultima soluzione 
ai problemi di sicurezza sul lavoro) e le donne centrali e d'alto ceto
nelle caselle che hanno cercato le riforme come la creazione di un 
ufficio della protezione contro l'incendio. La riunione si 
sarebbe rotta in su nel disordine se non per un discorso di 
mescolatura da Rosa Schneiderman, un ex operaio Lucid-sopportato del 
cappello che ha avuto una volta ha condotto un colpo alla fabbrica del
triangolo. Anche se ha parlato a mala pena sopra un bisbiglio, 
Schneiderman ha giudicato i pubblici spellbound.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια από τις μέγιστες βιομηχανικές τραγωδίες στην 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ ιστορία εμφανίστηκε στις 25 Μαρτίου ..1911, όταν
πέθαναν 146 εργαζόμενοι, συνήθως νέες που έχουν μεταναστεύσει
γυναίκες, σε μια πυρκαγιά στην επιχείρηση μπλουζών τριγώνων στην 
πόλη της Νέας Υόρκης. Τα θύματα είχαν παγιδευτεί από τις 
παρεμποδισμένες πόρτες εξόδων και τις ελαττωματικές εξόδους 
κινδύνου. Η συνέπεια της καταστροφής έφερε τη θλίψη και τα 
recriminations. Οι συναθροίσεις διαμαρτυρίας και οι 
αναμνηστικές συνεδριάσεις πραγματοποιήθηκαν σε όλη την πόλη. 
Κατά τη διάρκεια μιας συνεδρίασης στο μητροπολιτικό σπίτι 
οπερών, η ένταση ξέσπησε μεταξύ της χαμηλότερης ανατολής 
Siders εργατικών τάξεων που γέμισε τις στοές (και 
εβλέίδε την αλληλεγγύη κλάσης ως τελευταία λύση στα 
προβλήματα της βιομηχανικής ασφάλειας) και τη μέση - και 
αριστοκρατικές γυναίκες στα πεδία που επιδίωξαν τις 
μεταρρυθμίσεις όπως τη δημιουργία ενός γραφείου της πρόληψης 
πυρκαγιάς. Η συνεδρίαση θα είχε σπάσει επάνω στην 
αναταραχή εάν όχι για μια ανακατώνοντας ομιλία από ροδαλό 
Schneiderman, ένας πολωνικός-γεννημένος προηγούμενος 
εργαζόμενος καπέλων που είχε οδηγήσει μιά φορά μια απεργία στο 
εργοστάσιο τριγώνων. Αν και μίλησε μόλις επάνω από έναν 
ψίθυρο, Schneiderman κράτησε το ακροατήριο συναρπασμένο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una de las tragedias industriales más grandes de 
la historia de ESTADOS UNIDOS ocurrió de marcha la 25 de 1911, cuando
146 trabajadores, sobre todo mujeres inmigrantes jóvenes, muertas en 
un fuego en la compañía de Shirtwaist del triángulo en New York 
City. Las puertas bloqueadas de la salida habían atrapado a las
víctimas y el fuego defectuoso se escapa. Las consecuencias de 
la catástrofe trajeron pena y recriminaciones. La protesta se 
reúne y las reuniones conmemorativas fueron celebradas a través de 
la ciudad. Durante uno que satisfacía en la casa de ópera 
metropolitana, la tensión explotó entre la clase obrera un Siders 
del este más bajo que llenó a las galerías (y a solidaridad de la 
clase de la sierra como la última solución a los problemas de la 
seguridad en el trabajo) y a mujeres medias y de la clase alta en los 
rectángulos que buscaron reformas como la creación de una oficina de
la prevención contra los incendios. La reunión habría 
adaptado para arriba desorden si no para un discurso de revolvimiento 
por Rose Schneiderman, trabajador anterior Pulir-llevado del sombrero 
que tenía condujo una vez una huelga en la fábrica del triángulo. 
Aunque ella habló descubierto sobre un susurro, Schneiderman 
sostuvo a audiencias hechizadas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086392</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107144</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/lament-for-lives-lost-rose-schneiderman-and-the-triangle-fire</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
