<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106520</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106520</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207266</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Kids Next Door</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zicklein-Folgende Tür</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Prochaine Porte de Gosses</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Porta Seguinte Dos Miúdos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Portello Seguente Dei Capretti</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επόμενη πόρτα κατσικιών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Puerta Siguiente De los Cabritos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">lets kids know how they can help the homeless, presents personal stories on what young people are doing to help their communities, and provides a place for kids to submit their own stories. Children can also take a virtual field trip to the library, learn how to go on a scavenger hunt, and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">informiert Zicklein, wie sie dem Homeless helfen 
können, darstellt persönliche Geschichten auf was junge Leute tun, 
um ihren Gemeinschaften zu helfen, und zur Verfügung stellt einen 
Platz, damit Zicklein ihre eigenen Geschichten eingeben. Kinder 
können ein virtuelles auch nehmen auffangen Reise zur 
Bibliothek, erlernen, wie man auf einer Reinigerjagd und mehr geht.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fait des gosses savoir ils peuvent aider le 
sans-abri, présente les histoires personnelles sur ce que les jeunes 
font pour aider leurs communautés, et fournit un endroit pour que les
gosses soumettent leurs propres histoires. Les enfants peuvent 
également prendre un voyage de zone virtuel à la bibliothèque, 
apprennent comment aller sur une chasse à Scavenger, et davantage.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">deixa miúdos saber podem ajudar ao desabrigado, 
apresenta as histórias pessoais em o que os povos novos estão 
fazendo para ajudar a suas comunidades, e fornece um lugar para que os
miúdos submetam suas próprias histórias. As crianças podem 
também fazer exame de um desengate de campo virtual à biblioteca, 
aprendem como ir em uma caça do SCAVENGER, e mais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">lascia i capretti sapere possono aiutare il 
nomade, presenta le storia personali su che cosa i giovani stanno 
facendo per aiutare le loro Comunità e fornisce un posto affinchè i 
capretti presentino le loro proprie storia. I bambini possono 
anche prendere un viaggio di campo virtuale alla libreria, imparano 
come andare su un pulitore cercano e più.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ενημερώνει τα κατσίκια πώς μπορούν να βοηθήσουν τους 
αστέγους, παρουσιάζει τις προσωπικές ιστορίες σχετικά με ποιους 
νέους κάνει για να βοηθήσει τις κοινότητές τους, και παρέχει μια
θέση για τα κατσίκια για να υποβάλει τις ιστορίες τους. Τα 
παιδιά μπορούν επίσης να πάρουν ένα εικονικό ταξίδι πεδίων στη
βιβλιοθήκη, να μάθει πώς να πάνε σε ένα κυνήγι οδοκαθαριστών, 
και περισσότερο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">deja a cabritos saber pueden ayudar al nómada, 
presenta las historias personales en lo que está haciendo la gente 
joven para ayudar a sus comunidades, y proporciona a un lugar para que
los cabritos sometan sus propias historias. Los niños pueden 
también llevar un disparo al campo virtual la biblioteca, aprenden 
cómo ir en una caza del limpiador, y más.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207266</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106520</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/kids-next-door</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
