<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106500</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106500</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206950</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Effigy Mounds National Monument Teacher's Guide</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Anleitung Bildnis-Damm-Des Nationalen 
Denkmal-Lehrers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Guide du Professeur National de Monument de 
Monticules d'Effigie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Do Professor Nacional Do Monumento Dos Montes Do 
Effigy Guia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Guida Dell'Insegnante Nazionale Del Monumento Dei 
Monticelli Del Effigy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Effigy οδηγός του εθνικού δασκάλου μνημείων 
αναχωμάτων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Guía Del Profesor Nacional Del Monumento De los 
Montones Del Effigy</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">provides more than 40 lesson ideas developed by teachers to help students learn about Eastern Woodland Native Americans who lived in the upper Mississippi River valley (southwestern Wisconsin and northeast Iowa) from about 500 BC to 1300 AD and who built effigies -- ceremonial burial mounds shaped to represent bears, eagles, falcons, bison, deer, turtles, lizards, and other creatures.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt mehr zur Verfügung, als 40 Lektionideen, 
die von den Lehrern zu den Hilfe Kursteilnehmern entwickelt werden, 
über östliches Waldgebürtige Amerikaner erlernen, die im oberen 
Mississippi River Valley (südwestliches Wisconsin und Nordostiowa) 
von ungefähr 500 BC zu ANZEIGE 1300 wohnten und die Bildnisse -- die 
zeremoniellen Grabhügel aufbauten, die geformt wurden, um Bären, 
Adler, Falken, Bison, Rotwild, Schildkröten, Eidechsen und andere 
Geschöpfe darzustellen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fournit plus de 40 idées de leçon développées 
par des professeurs aux étudiants d'aide se renseignent sur les 
Américains indigènes de régfion boisée orientale qui ont habité 
au Mississippi supérieur River Valley (le Wisconsin du sud-ouest et 
Iowa du nord-est) environ de 500 BC à l'ANNONCE 1300 et qui ont 
construit des effigies -- monticules d'enterrement cérémonieux 
formés pour représenter des ours, des aigles, des faucons, le bison,
des cerfs communs, des tortues, des lézards, et d'autres créatures.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fornece mais de 40 idéias da lição 
desenvolvidas por professores aos estudantes da ajuda aprendem sobre 
os americanos nativos da floresta oriental que viveram no Mississippi 
superior River Valley (Wisconsin do sudoeste e Iowa do nordeste) de 
aproximadamente 500 BC ao ANÚNCIO 1300 e que construíram effigies --
montes de enterro ceremonial dados forma para representar ursos, 
águias, falcões, bisonte, cervos, tartarugas, lagartos, e outras 
criaturas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fornisce più di 40 idee di lezione sviluppate 
dagli insegnanti agli allievi di aiuto imparano circa gli Americani 
natali del terreno boscoso orientale che hanno vissuto BC nel 
Mississippi superiore River Valley (Wisconsin del sud-ovest ed Iowa di
nordest) da circa 500 all'ANNUNCIO 1300 e che hanno costruito i 
effigies -- monticelli di sepoltura ceremonial a forma di per 
rappresentare gli orsi, le aquile, i falchi, il bisonte, i cervi, le 
tartarughe, le lucertole ed altre creature.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρέχει περισσότερες από 40 ιδέες μαθήματος που 
αναπτύσσονται από τους δασκάλους για να βοηθήσουν τους σπουδαστές
να μάθουν για ανατολικούς δασόβιους εγγενείς Αμερικανούς που 
έζησαν στην ανώτερη κοιλάδα ποταμών του Μισισιπή (νοτιοδυτικά 
Wisconsin και βορειοανατολικό Iowa) από περίπου 500 Π.Χ. 
στην ΑΓΓΕΛΙΑ 1300 και που έχτισαν effigies -- εθιμοτυπικά 
αναχώματα ενταφιασμών που διαμορφώθηκαν για να αντιπροσωπεύσουν 
τις αρκούδες, τους αετούς, τα γεράκια, το βίσωνα, τα ελάφια, τις 
χελώνες, τις σαύρες, και άλλα πλάσματα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">proporciona más de 40 ideas de la lección 
desarrolladas por los profesores a los estudiantes de la ayuda 
aprenden sobre los americanos nativos del arbolado del este que 
vivieron en el Mississippi superior River Valley (Wisconsin al 
sudoeste e Iowa nordestal) de cerca de 500 A.C. al ANUNCIO 1300 y que 
construyeron los effigies -- montones de entierro ceremoniales 
formados para representar a osos, a águilas, a halcones, al bisonte, 
a ciervos, a tortugas, a lagartos, y a otras criaturas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206950</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106500</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/effigy-mounds-national-monument-teachers-guide</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
