<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103092</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103092</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086144</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Factories are talked about as schools of vice": Elias Nason Considers Careers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"mit Fabriken werden als Schulen des Lasters" 
befaßt: Elias Nason Betrachtet Karrieren</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">des "usines sont parlées comme écoles de vice" :
Elias Nason Considère des Carrières</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">as "fábricas são faladas aproximadamente como 
escolas do vice": Elias Nason Considera Carreiras</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"le fabbriche sono parlate di come scuole di 
vizio": Elias Nason Considera Le Carriere</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Τα εργοστάσια μιλιούνται για ως σχολεία της κακίασ": 
Θ*Εληας Nason Considers Careers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">las "fábricas se hablan como escuelas del vicio":
Elias Nason Considera Carreras</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Many young men and women coming of age in the early-nineteenth century began to think about possibilities beyond the farm economy. The founding of new institutions of higher education and the expansion of older ones in New England beyond the handful of colonial colleges provided opportunities to farm boys from a wider range of social backgrounds. One such man was Elias Nason, born into a large family and poor. He wrote to his parents about the prospects for his brothers and sisters in this 1835 letter, the year that he was graduated from Brown University in Providence, Rhode Island. Like many, he was going to school intermittently at the same time that he was teaching school to stay afloat. Nason expressed a common prejudice of the time against work in the mills or factory labor when he warned: "Factories are talked about as schools of vice in all circles here."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Kommen vieler junger Männer und der Frauen 
des Alters im früh-19.jahrhundert fing an, an Möglichkeiten über 
dem landwirtschaftlichen hinaus zu denken. Die Gründung der 
neuen Anstalten von höherer Ausbildung und die Expansion der älterer
in Neu-England über der Handvoll der Kolonialhochschulen hinaus 
stellten Gelegenheiten zu den Landarbeitern von einer breiteren 
Strecke der Sozialhintergründe zur Verfügung. Ein solcher Mann
war Elias Nason, getragen in eine große Familie und in Armen. 
Er schrieb seinen Eltern über die Aussichten für seine Brüder
und Schwestern in dieses 1835 Zeichen, das Jahr, daß er von der 
braunen Universität in der Vorsehung abgestuft war, Rhode-Insel. 
Wie viele ging er zur Schule stoßweise, zur gleichen Zeit als 
er Schule unterrichtete, um flott zu bleiben. Nason drückte ein
geläufiges Vorurteil der Zeit gegen Arbeit in den Tausendsteln oder 
in der Fabrikarbeit aus, als er warnte: "mit Fabriken werden 
befaßt als Schulen des Lasters in allen Kreisen hier."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Venir de beaucoup de jeunes hommes et de femmes de
l'âge au tôt-dix-neuvième siècle a commencé à penser aux 
possibilités au delà de l'économie de ferme. La fondation de 
nouveaux établissements d'une éducation plus élevée et l'expansion
de les plus anciens en Nouvelle Angleterre au delà de la poignée 
d'universités coloniales ont fourni des occasions aux garçons de 
ferme d'un éventail de milieux sociaux. Un tel homme était 
Elias Nason, soutenu dans une famille nombreuse et des pauvres. 
Il a écrit à ses parents au sujet des perspectives pour ses 
frères et soeurs dans cette 1835 lettre, l'année qu'il était 
gradué de l'université brune dans la providence, île de Rhode. 
Comme beaucoup, il allait à l'école par intermittence pendant 
qu'il enseignait l'école pour rester à flot. Nason a exprimé 
un préjudice commun du temps contre le travail en moulins ou travail 
d'usine quand il a averti : des "usines sont parlées comme 
écoles de vice en tous les cercles ici."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A vinda de muitos homens novos e de mulheres de 
idade no cedo-décimo nono século começou a pensar sobre 
possibilidades além da economia de fazenda. Fundar de 
instituições novas de uma instrução mais elevada e a expansão das
mais velhas em Nova Inglaterra além do punhado de faculdades 
coloniais forneceram oportunidades aos meninos de fazenda de uma 
escala mais larga de fundos sociais. Um tal homem era Elias 
Nason, carregado em uma família grande e em pobres. Escreveu a 
seus pais sobre os prospetos para seus irmãos e irmãs nesta 1835 
letra, o ano que era graduado da universidade marrom no providence, 
console de Rhode. Como muitos, estava indo à escola 
intermitentemente ao mesmo tempo que ensinava a escola para permanecer
afloat. Nason expressou um preconceito comum do tempo de 
encontro ao trabalho nos moinhos ou no trabalho da fábrica quando 
advertiu: as "fábricas são faladas aproximadamente como 
escolas do vice em todos os círculos aqui."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il raggiungimento della maturità delle donne e di
molti giovani nel presto-diciannovesimo secolo ha cominciato a pensare
alle possibilità oltre l'economia dell'azienda agricola. 
Fondare di nuove istituzioni di istruzione superiore e 
l'espansione di quelle più vecchie in Nuova Inghilterra oltre la 
manciata di università coloniali hanno fornito le occasioni ai 
ragazzi dell'azienda agricola da una vasta gamma degli ambienti 
sociali. Un tale uomo era Elias Nason, sopportato in una grande 
famiglia ed in un povero. Ha scritto ai suoi genitori circa
i prospetti per i suoi fratelli e sorelle in questa 1835 lettera, 
l'anno che era graduato dall'università marrone nel providence, 
Rhode-isola. Come molti, stava andando intermittentemente alla 
scuola nello stesso momento in cui stava insegnando la scuola per 
rimanere a galla. Nason ha espresso un pregiudizio comune del 
tempo contro lavoro nel lavoro della fabbrica o dei laminatoi 
quando ha avvertito: "le fabbriche sono parlate di come scuole 
di vizio in tutti i cerchi qui."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ενηλικίωση πολλών νεαρών άνδρων και γυναικών στον 
πρόωρος-δέκατο έννατο αιώνα άρχισε να σκέφτεται για τις 
δυνατότητες πέρα από την αγροτική οικονομία. Η ίδρυση των 
νέων οργάνων της τριτοβάθμιας εκπαίδευσης και η επέκταση 
παλαιότερων στη Νέα Αγγλία πέρα από τη χούφτα των αποικιακών 
κολλεγίων παρείχαν τις ευκαιρίες να καλλιεργηθούν τα αγόρια από 
ένα ευρύτερο φάσμα των κοινωνικών υποβάθρων. Ένα τέτοιο 
άτομο ήταν Elias Nason, γεννημένο σε μια μεγάλη οικογένεια 
και τους φτωχούς. Έγραψε στους γονείς του για τις προοπτικές
για τους αδελφούς και τις αδελφές του σε αυτήν την 1835 
επιστολή, το έτος ότι ήταν κλιμακωτός από το καφετί 
πανεπιστήμιο στην πρόνοια, Ρόδος. Όπως πολλούς, πήγαινε 
στο σχολείο περιοδικά συγχρόνως ότι δίδασκε το σχολείο για να 
μείνει επιπλέον. Το Nason εξέφρασε μια κοινή προκατάληψη
του χρόνου ενάντια στην εργασία στους μύλους ή την εργασία 
εργοστασίων όταν προειδοποίησε: "Τα εργοστάσια μιλιούνται 
για ως σχολεία της κακίας σε όλους τους κύκλους εδώ."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El venir de muchos hombres jóvenes y de las 
mujeres de la edad en el temprano-diecinueveavo siglo comenzó a 
pensar de posibilidades más allá de la economía de granja. La
fundación de nuevas instituciones de una educación más alta y la 
extensión las más viejas en Nueva Inglaterra más allá del puñado 
de universidades coloniales proporcionaron a oportunidades a los 
muchachos de granja de una gama más amplia de fondos sociales. 
Un tal hombre era Elias Nason, nacido en una familia grande y 
pobres. Él escribió a sus padres sobre las perspectivas para 
sus hermanos y hermanas en esta 1835 carta, el año que él era 
graduado de universidad marrón en providence, Rhode-isla. Como 
muchos, él iba a la escuela intermitentemente a la vez que él 
enseñaba la escuela para permanecer a flote. Nason expresó un 
prejudicar común del tiempo contra trabajo en los molinos o el 
trabajo de la fábrica cuando él advirtió: las "fábricas se 
hablan como escuelas del vicio en todos los círculos aquí."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086144</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103092</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/factories-are-talked-about-as-schoolsof-vice-elias-nason-considers-careers</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
