<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108679</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108679</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206076</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">ABC's of Nuclear Science and Technology</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ABC der Kernwissenschaft und der Technologie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">ABC de la Science et de technologie nucléaires</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">ABC da ciência e da tecnologia nucleares</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">ABC di scienza e di tecnologia nucleari</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ABC της πυρηνικών επιστήμης και της τεχνολογίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ABC de la ciencia y de la tecnología nucleares</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Introduces the object that contains almost all of the mass in the universe, the atomic nucleus. Antimatter, beta rays, fission and fusion, the structure of the atomic nucleus, how elements on the earth were produced, how we use the nucleus in every day life, and the effects of radiation in the environment are among the topics. The site includes nearly a dozen experiments that can be done in chemistry and physics classes, along with A Teacher's Guide to the Nuclear Science and Technology Wall Chart.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Stellt die Nachricht, die fast die ganze Masse im 
Universum enthält, den Atomkern vor. Antimaterie, Betastrahlen,
Spaltung und Schmelzverfahren, die Struktur des Atomkernes, wie 
Elemente auf der Masse produziert wurden, wie wir den Kern in jeden 
Tageslebensdauer benutzen und die Effekte der Strahlung in der 
Umgebung zu den Themen gehören. Die Site schließt fast 
Experimente Dutzend ein, die in den Chemie- und Physikkategorien, 
zusammen mit der Anleitung eines Lehrers zur Kernwissenschaft und zum 
Technologie-Wand-Diagramm erfolgt werden können.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Présente l'objet qui contient presque toute la 
masse dans l'univers, le noyau atomique. Antimatière, bêtas 
rayons, fission et fusion, la structure du noyau atomique, comment des
éléments sur la terre ont été produits, comment nous utilisons le 
noyau dans chaque vie de jour, et les effets du rayonnement dans 
l'environnement sont parmi les sujets. Le site inclut presque 
les expériences une douzaine qui peuvent être faites dans des 
classes de chimie et de physique, avec le guide d'un professeur de la 
Science et du diagramme nucléaires de mur de technologie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Introduz o objeto que contem quase toda a massa no
universo, o núcleo atômico. Antimatter, raios beta, fission e 
fusão, a estrutura do núcleo atômico, como os elementos na terra 
foram produzidos, como nós usamos o núcleo em cada vida do dia, e os
efeitos da radiação no ambiente são entre os tópicos. O 
local inclui quase as experiências uma dúzia que podem ser feitas em
classes do chemistry e da física, junto com a guia de um professor à
ciência e à carta nucleares da parede da tecnologia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Introduce l'oggetto che contiene quasi tutta la 
massa nell'universo, il nucleo atomico. Antimatter, raggi beta, 
fissione e fusione, la struttura del nucleo atomico, come gli elementi
sulla terra sono stati prodotti, come usiamo il nucleo in ogni vita di
giorno e gli effetti di radiazione nell'ambiente sono fra i soggetti. 
Il luogo include quasi gli esperimenti un dozzina che possono 
essere fatti nei codici categoria di fisica e di chimica, con la guida
dell'insegnante alla scienza ed alla tabella nucleari della parete di 
tecnologia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εισάγει το αντικείμενο που περιέχει σχεδόν όλη την 
μάζα στον κόσμο, ο ατομικός πυρήνας. Antimatter, οι 
βήτα ακτίνες, η διάσπαση και η τήξη, η δομή του ατομικού 
πυρήνα, πώς τα στοιχεία στη γη παρήχθησαν, πώς χρησιμοποιούμε 
τον πυρήνα σε κάθε ζωή ημέρας, και τα αποτελέσματα της 
ακτινοβολίας στο περιβάλλον είναι μεταξύ των θεμάτων. Η 
περιοχή περιλαμβάνει σχεδόν δωδεκάα πειράματα που μπορούν να 
γίνουν στις κλάσεις χημείας και φυσικής, μαζί με τον οδηγό ενός
δασκάλου για το πυρηνικό διάγραμμα τοίχων επιστήμης και 
τεχνολογίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Introduce el objeto que contiene casi toda la masa
en el universo, el núcleo atómico. Antimatter, rayos beta, 
fisión y fusión, la estructura del núcleo atómico, cómo los 
elementos en la tierra fueron producidos, cómo utilizamos el núcleo 
en cada vida del día, y los efectos de la radiación en el ambiente 
están entre los asuntos. El sitio incluye casi los experimentos
una docena que se pueden hacer en clases de la química y de la 
física, junto con la guía de un profesor a la ciencia y a la carta 
nucleares de la pared de la tecnología.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206076</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108679</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/abcs-of-nuclear-science-and-technology</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
