<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104004</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104004</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086407</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Let Us Reason Together": W. E. B. Du Bois Defends Black Resistance</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Lassen Sie Uns Zusammen Folgern": W. E. B. 
Du Bois Defends Schwarzer Widerstand</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Raisonnons Ensemble" : Résistance Noire De
W. E. B. Du Bois Defends</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Deixe-nos Raciocinar Junto": Resistência 
Preta De W. E. B. Du Bois Defender</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Ragioniamo Insieme": Resistenza Nera Del W.
E. B. Du Bois Defends</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Διαλογιστείτε μαζί": Μαύρη αντίσταση Θ*Ω. Ε. Β.
du Bois Defends</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Razonemos Junto": Resistencia Negra De W. 
E. B. Du Bois Defends</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the years immediately following World War I, tens of thousands of southern blacks and returning black soldiers flocked to the nation's Northern cities looking for good jobs and a measure of respect and security. Many white Americans, fearful of competition for scarce jobs and housing, responded by attacking black citizens in a spate of urban race riots. In urban African-American enclaves, the 1920s were marked by a flowering of cultural expressions and a proliferation of black self-help organizations that accompanied the era of the "New Negro." Debates raged over the best political and organizational path for black Americans, and the  Crisis , the national magazine of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP), offered one of the earliest and most powerful endorsements of the "New Negro." In an editorial immediately following the Chicago race riot of 1919,  Crisis  editor W. E. B. Du Bois argued in favor of acts of self-defense and armed resistance, despite the editorial's conciliatory title, "Let Us Reason Together."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In den Jahren direkt nach dem Ersten Weltkrieg, in
den 10 Tausenden der südlichen Schwarzer und in den zurückkommenden 
schwarzen Soldaten geschart zu den Nordstädte der Nation, die guten 
Jobs und einem Maß nach Respekt und Sicherheit suchen. Viele 
weiße Amerikaner, ängstlich von der Konkurrenz für knappe Jobs und 
Gehäuse, reagiert durch das Angreifen der schwarzen Bürger in einer 
Überflutung der städtischen Rennenaufstände. In den 
städtischen Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Enklaven wurden die zwanziger 
Jahre durch ein Blühen der kulturellen Ausdrücke und eine starke 
Verbreitung der schwarzen Self-helporganisationen gekennzeichnet, die 
begleiteten die Ära des "neuen Schwarzen." Debatten rasten 
über dem besten politischen und organisatorischen Pfad für schwarze 
Amerikaner und die Krise, die nationale Zeitschrift der nationalen 
Verbindung für die Zuführung der Farbiger (NAACP), eine der 
frühesten und leistungsfähigsten Aufschriften des "neuen Schwarzen 
angeboten." In einem Leitartikel direkt nach dem Chicago 
Rennenaufstand von 1919, argumentierte Krise Herausgeber W. E. B. Du 
Bois zugunsten der Taten von Self-defense und bewaffnete Widerstand, 
trotz des versöhnlichen Namens des Leitartikels, "lassen Sie uns 
zusammen folgern."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant les années juste après la Première 
Guerre Mondiale, des dizaines de milliers de noirs méridionaux et des
soldats noirs de renvoi assemblés aux villes nordiques de la nation 
recherchant les bons travaux et une mesure de respect et de 
sécurité. Beaucoup d'Américains blancs, craintifs de la 
concurrence pour les travaux rares et le logement, répondue en 
attaquant les citoyens noirs dans un flux des émeutes urbaines de 
course. Dans les enclaves afro-américaines urbaines, les années 
20 ont été marquées par une fleuraison des expressions culturelles 
et une prolifération des organismes noirs de art de l'auto-portrait-help qui ont 
accompagné l'ère du "nouveau nègre." Les discussions ont fait
rage au-dessus de la meilleure voie d'accès politique et 
d'organisation pour les Américains noirs, et la crise, le magasin 
national de l'association nationale pour l'avancement des personnes de
couleur (NAACP), offert une des approbations les plus tôt et les plus
puissantes du "nouveau nègre." Dans un éditorial juste après 
l'émeute de course de Chicago de 1919, l'éditeur W. E. B. Du Bois de
crise plaidé en faveur des actes de art de l'auto-portrait-defense et de 
résistance armée, en dépit du titre conciliant de l'éditorial, 
"nous a laissés raisonner ensemble."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nos anos imediatamente depois do world.war.i, em 
dez dos milhares de pretos do sul e nos soldados pretos de retorno 
reunidos às cidades do norte da nação que procuram trabalhos bons e
uma medida do respeito e da segurança. Muitos americanos 
brancos, temíveis da competição para trabalhos escassos e carcaça,
respondida atacando cidadãos pretos em um spate de motins urbanos da 
raça. Em enclaves Africano-Americanos urbanos, os 1920s foram 
marcados flowering de expressões cultural e por um proliferation das 
organizações pretas do self-help que acompanharam a era "do negro 
novo." Os debates raged sobre o mais melhor trajeto político e 
organizational para americanos pretos, e a crise, o compartimento 
nacional da associação nacional para o avanço dos povos coloridos 
(NAACP), oferecido um dos endossos os mais adiantados e os mais 
poderosos "do negro novo." Em um editorial imediatamente depois 
do motim da raça de Chicago de 1919, o editor W. E. B. Du Bois da 
crise discutiu no favor dos atos do self-defense e armou a 
resistência, apesar do título conciliatory do editorial, "deixe-nos 
raciocinar junto."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fra anni subito dopo del world.war.i, i dieci 
delle migliaia dei neri del sud e soldati neri di ritorno affollati 
alle città nordiche della nazione che cercano i buoni lavori e una 
misura di rispetto e di sicurezza. Molti Americani bianchi, 
spaventosi di concorrenza per i lavori limitati e l'alloggiamento, 
risposta attacando i cittadini neri in un flusso dei tumulti urbani 
della corsa. In zone franche Africano-Americane urbane, gli anni
20 sono stati contrassegnati tramite una fioritura delle espressioni 
culturali e una proliferazione delle organizzazioni nere di self-help 
che hanno accompagnato l'era "di nuovo negro." I dibattiti si 
sono infuriati sopra il percorso politico ed organizzativo migliore 
per gli Americani neri e la crisi, lo scomparto nazionale 
dell'associazione nazionale per l'avanzamento della gente colorata 
(NAACP), offerto una delle approvazioni più iniziali e più potenti 
"di nuovo negro." In un editoriale subito dopo del tumulto della
corsa del Chicago di 1919, l'editore W. E. B. Du Bois di crisi 
perorato per gli atti di self-defense e di resistenza munita, malgrado
il titolo conciliativo dell'editoriale, "li ha lasciati ragionare 
insieme."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στα έτη αμέσως μετά από τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι, οι 
δεκάδες χιλιάδων νότιοι Μαύροι και επιστρέφοντας μαύροι 
στρατιώτες συγκεντρώθηκαν στις βόρειες πόλεις του έθνους που 
αναζητούν τις καλές θέσεις εργασίας και ένα μέτρο του σεβασμού 
και της ασφάλειας. Πολλοί λευκοί Αμερικανοί, έντρομοι του 
ανταγωνισμού για τις λιγοστές εργασίες και την κατοικία, που 
αποκρίνεται με να επιτεθεί στους μαύρους πολίτες στο α χείμαρρος 
των αστικών φυλετικών ταραχών. Στα αστικά 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικά περίκλειστα εδάφη, η δεκαετία του '20 
χαρακτηρίστηκε από ένα άνθισμα των πολιτιστικών εκφράσεων και 
έναν πολλαπλασιασμό των μαύρων οργανώσεων αυτοβοήθειας που 
συνόδευσαν την εποχή του "νέου νέγρου." Οι συζητήσεις 
οργίστηκαν πέρα από το καλύτερο πολιτικό και οργανωτικό 
μονοπάτι για μαύρους Αμερικανούς, και η κρίση, το εθνικό 
περιοδικό της εθνικής ένωσης για την πρόοδο των έγχρωμων 
ανθρώπων (NAACP), πρόσφερε μιας από τις πιό πρόωρες και 
ισχυρότερες επικυρώσεις του "νέου νέγρου." Σε ένα κύριο 
άρθρο αμέσως μετά από τη φυλετική ταραχή του Σικάγου του 
1919, ο επεξεργαστής Θ*Ω. Ε. Β. du Bois κρίσης υποστήριξε 
υπέρ των πράξεων της μόνος-υπεράσπισης και η οπλισμένη 
αντίσταση, παρά τον κατευναστικό τίτλο του κύριου άρθρου, 
"διαλογιστείτε από κοινού."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En los años inmediatamente después de la Primera
Guerra Mundial, los diez de millares de negros meridionales y los 
soldados negros que vuelven reunidos a las ciudades norteñas de la 
nación que buscan buenos trabajos y una medida de respecto y de 
seguridad. Muchos americanos blancos, temerosos de la 
competición para los trabajos escasos y la cubierta, respondida 
atacando a ciudadanos negros en una crecida de los alborotos urbanos 
de la raza. En enclaves Africano-Americanos urbanos, los años 
20 fueron marcados por un florecimiento de expresiones culturales y 
una proliferación de las organizaciones negras del esfuerzo personal 
que acompañaron la era del "nuevo negro." Los discusiones 
rabiaron sobre el mejor camino político y de organización para los 
americanos negros, y la crisis, el compartimiento nacional de la 
asociación nacional para el adelanto de la gente coloreada (NAACP), 
ofrecido uno de los endosos más tempranos y más de gran alcance del 
"nuevo negro." En un editorial inmediatamente después del 
alboroto de la raza de Chicago de 1919, el editor W. E. B. Du Bois de 
la crisis discutido en el favor de actos de la autodefensa y de la 
resistencia armada, a pesar de el título conciliatorio del editorial,
"nos dejó razonar junto."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086407</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104004</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/let-us-reason-together-w-e-b-du-bois-defends-black-resistance</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
