<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108731</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108731</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087170</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">War Is "a Blessing, Not a Curse": The Case for Why We Must Fight</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Krieg ist "ein Segen, nicht ein Fluch": Das 
Argument für, warum wir kämpfen müssen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La guerre est "une bénédiction, pas une 
malédiction" : Le point de droit pour pourquoi nous devons 
combattre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A guerra é "um blessing, não um curse": O 
argumento para porque nós devemos lutar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La guerra è "un blessing, non un curse": 
L'argomento per perchè dobbiamo combattere</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο πόλεμος είναι "μια ευλογία, όχι μια πληγή": Η
περίπτωση για γιατί πρέπει να παλεψουμε</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La guerra es "una bendición, no una maldición": 
El caso para porqué debemos luchar</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1917, voices were raised outside Congress on both sides of the issue of American involvement in the European war. Shortly before President Woodrow Wilson's call for war on April 2, 1917, the editors of a conservative magazine, the  North American Review , laid out the basic arguments for U.S. participation. Fundamentally, they saw the war as a struggle between democracy and barbarism. Similar statements and speeches--as well as more coercive measures--gradually captured the public discourse. Fairly quickly, those who rejected the rationales for United States participation in the war found themselves increasingly isolated. Liberals, intellectuals, and even many socialists soon lined up behind American intervention.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1917 wurden Stimmen außerhalb des Kongresses auf 
beiden Seiten der Ausgabe der amerikanischen Miteinbeziehung im 
europäischen Krieg angehoben. Kurz, bevor Präsident Woodrow 
Wilson Aufruf für Krieg an April 2, 1917, die Herausgeber einer 
konservativen Zeitschrift, die nordamerikanische Zusammenfassung, die 
grundlegenden Argumente für VEREINIGTE STAATEN Teilnahme ausbritt. 
Grundlegend sahen sie den Krieg als Kampf zwischen Demokratie 
und Barbarism. Ähnliche Anweisungen und Reden -- sowie 
zwingendere Masse -- erfaßten stufenweise die allgemeine Darlegung. 
Ziemlich schnell, fanden sich die, die die rationales für 
Vereinigte Staaten Teilnahme am Krieg zurückwiesen, in zunehmendem 
Maße lokalisiert. Liberale, Intellektuelle und sogar viele 
Sozialisten richteten bald hinter amerikanischer Intervention aus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1917, des voix ont été élevées en dehors du
congrès des deux côtés de la question de la participation 
américaine dans la guerre européenne. Peu avant l'appel du 
Président Woodrow Wilson pour la guerre 2 avril 1917, les éditeurs 
d'un magasin conservateur, la revue américaine du nord, a 
présenté les arguments de base pour la participation des ETATS-UNIS.
Fondamentalement, ils ont vu la guerre comme lutte entre la 
démocratie et la barbarie. Les rapports et les discours 
semblables -- aussi bien que des mesures plus coercitives -- ont 
graduellement capturé le discours public. Assez rapidement, 
ceux qui ont rejeté les rationales pour la participation des 
Etats-Unis à la guerre se sont trouvés de plus en plus d'isolement. 
Les libéraux, les intellectuels, et même beaucoup de 
socialistes ont bientôt aligné derrière l'intervention américaine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1917, as vozes foram levantadas fora do 
congress em ambos os lados da introdução da participação americana
na guerra européia. Logo antes que atendimento do presidente 
Woodrow Wilson para a guerra abril em 2, 1917, os editores de um 
compartimento conservador, a revisão norte-americana, colocada para 
fora dos argumentos básicos para a participação de ESTADOS UNIDOS. 
Fundamental, viram a guerra como um esforço entre a democracia 
e o barbarism. As indicações e os discursos similares -- 
as.well.as medidas mais coercive -- capturaram gradualmente o discurso
público. Razoavelmente rapidamente, aqueles que rejeitaram os 
rationales para a participação unida dos estados na guerra 
encontraram-se isolados cada vez mais. Os liberais, os 
intelectuais, e mesmo muitos socialists alinharam logo acima atrás da
intervenção americana.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1917, le voci sono state alzate fuori del 
congresso da entrambi i lati dell'emissione della partecipazione 
americana alla guerra europea. Poco prima la richiesta del 
presidente Woodrow Wilson per la guerra il 2 aprile 1917, gli editori 
di uno scomparto conservatore, la revisione nordamericana, ha presentato
gli argomenti di base per partecipazione degli STATI UNITI. 
Fondamentalmente, hanno visto la guerra come lotta fra la 
democrazia ed il barbarism. Le istruzione ed i discorsi simili 
-- così come le misure più coercive -- hanno bloccato gradualmente 
il discorso pubblico. Ragionevolmente rapidamente, coloro che ha
rifiutato i rationales per unito Dichiarano la partecipazione 
alla guerra si sono trovati sempre più isolati. I liberali, gli
intellettuali e perfino molti socialisti presto hanno allineato dietro
intervento americano.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1917, οι φωνές αυξήθηκαν έξω από το συνέδριο 
και στις δύο πλευρές του ζητήματος της αμερικανικής συμμετοχής 
στον ευρωπαϊκό πόλεμο. Λίγο πριν η κλήση Προέδρου 
Woodrow Wilson's για τον πόλεμο στις 2 Απριλίου ..1917, οι 
επεξεργαστές ενός συντηρητικού περιοδικού, η βορειοαμερικανική 
αναθεώρηση, σχεδίασε τα βασικά ορίσματα για την ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ 
συμμετοχή. Πλήρως, εβλέίδαν τον πόλεμο ως προσπάθεια
μεταξύ της δημοκρατίας και της βαρβαρότητας. Οι παρόμοιες 
δηλώσεις και οι ομιλίες -- τόσο καλά όσο περισσότερα 
καταναγκαστικά μέτρα -- βαθμιαία συνέλαβαν τη δημόσια ομιλία. 
Αρκετά γρήγορα, εκείνοι που απέρριψαν τις λογικές για 
Ηνωμένη συμμετοχή στον πόλεμο βρέθηκαν όλο και περισσότερο 
απομονωμένου. Οι φιλελεύθεροι, οι διανοούμενοι, και ακόμη 
και πολλοί σοσιαλιστές παράταξαν σύντομα πίσω από την 
αμερικανική επέμβαση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1917, las voces fueron levantadas fuera de 
congreso sobre ambas caras de la aplicación la implicación americana
en la guerra europea. Poco antes la llamada de presidente 
Woodrow Wilson para la guerra 2 de abril de 1917, los editores de 
un compartimiento conservador, la revisión norteamericana, presentó 
a los argumentos básicos para la participación de ESTADOS UNIDOS. 
Fundamental, vieron la guerra como lucha entre la democracia y 
el barbarismo. Las declaraciones y los discursos similares -- 
así como medidas más coactivas -- capturaron gradualmente el 
discurso público. Bastante rápidamente, los que rechazaron los
rationales para la participación de Estados Unidos en la guerra se 
encontraron aislados cada vez más. Los liberales, los 
intelectuales, e incluso muchos socialistas pronto se alinearon 
detrás de la intervención americana.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087170</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108731</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/war-is-a-blessing-not-a-curse-the-case-for-why-we-must-fight</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
