<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/1760599335</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>1760599335</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206136</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">NASA Earth Observatory</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die NASA Masse Sternwarte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Observatoire de la Terre de la NASA</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Obervatório Da Terra da NASA</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Osservatorio Della Terra della NASA</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γήινο παρατηρητήριο της NASA</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Observatorio De la Tierra de la NASA</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">provides new satellite imagery and scientific information about Earth's climate and environmental change. It features stories about the atmosphere, oceans, land, life, heat and energy, and remote sensing. Visitors may build and view animations showing changes in population, vegetation, precipitation, and other phenomena.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt neue Satellitenbilder und Fachinformation 
über Klima und Klimaänderung der Masse zur Verfügung. Sie 
kennzeichnet Geschichten über die Atmosphäre, die Ozeane, das Land, 
die Lebensdauer, die Hitze und die Energie und die Fernabfragung. 
Besucher können die Animationen aufbauen und ansehen, die 
Änderungen in der Bevölkerung, in der Vegetation, im Niederschlag 
und in anderen Phänomenen zeigen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fournit le nouveau langage figuré satellite et 
l'information scientifique au sujet du climat et du changement 
environnemental de la terre. Elle comporte des histoires au 
sujet de l'atmosphère, les océans, la terre, la vie, la chaleur et 
l'énergie, et la télédétection. Les visiteurs peuvent 
établir et visualiser des animations montrant des changements de 
population, de végétation, de précipitation, et d'autres 
phénomènes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fornece o imagery satellite novo e a informação 
científica sobre o clima e a mudança ambiental da terra. 
Caracteriza histórias sobre a atmosfera, os oceanos, a terra, a
vida, o calor e a energia, e detetar remoto. Os visitantes podem
construir e ver os animations que mostram mudanças na população, na
vegetação, na precipitação, e nos outros fenômenos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fornisce le nuove immagini proveniente dal 
satellite e l'informazione scientifica sul clima e sul cambiamento 
ambientale della terra. Caratterizza le storia circa 
l'atmosfera, gli oceani, la terra, la vita, il calore e l'energia ed 
il telerilevamento. Gli ospiti possono sviluppare ed osservare 
le animazioni che mostrano i cambiamenti in popolazione, nella 
vegetazione, in precipitazione ed in altri fenomeni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρέχει τα νέα δορυφορικά καλολογικά στοιχεία και τις
επιστημονικές πληροφορίες για το γήινες κλίμα και την 
περιβαλλοντική αλλαγή. Χαρακτηρίζει τις ιστορίες για την 
ατμόσφαιρα, τους ωκεανούς, το έδαφος, τη ζωή, τη θερμότητα και 
την ενέργεια, και την τηλεπισκόπηση. Οι επισκέπτες μπορούν 
να χτίσουν και να εμφανίσουν τις ζωτικότητες που εμφανίζουν 
αλλαγές στον πληθυσμό, τη βλάστηση, την πτώση, και άλλα 
φαινόμενα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">proporciona a nuevas imágenes basadas en los 
satélites y a la información científica sobre el clima y el cambio 
ambiental de la tierra. Ofrece historias sobre la atmósfera, 
los océanos, la pista, la vida, el calor y la energía, y la 
detección alejada. Los visitantes pueden construir y visión 
las animaciones que muestran cambios en la población, la vegetación,
la precipitación, y otros fenómenos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206136</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>1760599335</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/nasa-earth-observatory</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
