<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105528</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105528</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207043</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Going-to-the-Sun Road: A Model of Landscape Engineering</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gehen-zu-d-Sonne Straße: Ein Modell der 
Landschaftstechnik</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Route du l'Aller-à-le-Soleil : Un modèle 
de l'ingénierie d'horizontal</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Estrada Do V-à-$$$-Sol: Um modelo da 
engenharia da paisagem</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Strada Del And-$$$-$$$-Sole: Un modello di 
ingegneria di paesaggio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πηγαίνω-$$$-Ο-ΉΛΙΟΣ δρόμος: Ένα μοντέλο της 
εφαρμοσμένης μηχανικής τοπίων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Camino Del Ir-a-$$$-Sol: Un modelo de la 
ingeniería del paisaje</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">was the first highway by which visitors could see the lakes, glaciers, alpine peaks, and meadows of Glacier National Park. Work on the 50-mile route, which connected the east and west sides of the park and crossed the Continental Divide at Logan Pass, began in 1921. The high technical standards of the Bureau of Public Roads (later the Federal Highway Administration) needed to be balanced with the commitment of the National Park Service to minimize damage to the landscape.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">war die erste Datenbahn, durch die Besucher die 
Seen, die Gletscher, die alpinen Spitzen und die Wiesen des 
Gletscher-Nationalparks sehen konnten. Arbeit über den Weg 
50-mile, der die Ost- und Westseiten des Parks anschloß und 
Wasserscheide am Logan Durchlauf kreuzte, fing 1921 an. Die 
hohen technischen Standards des Büros der allgemeinen Straßen 
(später die Bundesdatenbahn-Leitung) mußten mit der Verpflichtung 
des Nationalpark-Services ausgeglichen werden, um Beschädigung der 
Landschaft herabzusetzen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">était le premier omnibus par lequel les visiteurs
pourraient voir les lacs, les glaciers, les crêtes alpestres, et les 
prés du parc national de glacier. Le travail sur l'itinéraire 
50-mile, qui a relié les côtés est et occidentaux du parc et a 
croisé le continental se divise au passage de Logan, a commencé en 
1921. Les niveaux techniques élevés du bureau des routes 
publiques (plus tard la gestion fédérale d'omnibus) ont dû être 
équilibrés avec l'engagement du service de parc national pour 
réduire au minimum des dommages à l'horizontal.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">era a primeira estrada por que os visitantes 
poderiam ver os lagos, as geleiras, os picos alpine, e os prados do 
parque nacional da geleira. O trabalho na rota 50-mile, que 
conectou os lados do leste e ocidentais do parque e cruzou o 
continental se divide na passagem de Logan, começou em 1921. Os
padrões técnicos elevados do departamento de estradas públicas 
(mais tarde a administração federal da estrada) necessitaram ser 
balançados com o compromisso do serviço do parque nacional para 
minimizar os danos à paisagem.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">era la prima strada principale da cui gli ospiti 
potrebbero vedere i laghi, i ghiacciai, i picchi alpini ed i prati del
parco nazionale del ghiacciaio. Il lavoro sull'itinerario 
50-mile, che ha collegato i lati orientali ed ad ovest del parco ed ha
attraversato il continentale si divide al passaggio di Logan, ha 
cominciato in 1921. Le alte norme tecniche dell'ufficio delle 
strade pubbliche (più successivamente la gestione federale della 
strada principale) hanno dovuto essere equilibrate con l'impegno del 
servizio del parco nazionale per minimizzare il danneggiamento del 
paesaggio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ήταν η πρώτη εθνική οδός από την οποία οι 
επισκέπτες θα μπορούσαν να δουν τις λίμνες, τους 
παγετώνες, τις αλπικές αιχμές, και τα λιβάδια του εθνικού πάρκου
παγετώνων. Η εργασία για τη διαδρομή 50-μιλίου, που σύνδεσε
τις πλευρές ανατολής και δύσης του πάρκου και διέσχισε την 
ηπειρωτική διαίρεση στο πέρασμα Logan, άρχισε το 1921. 
Τα υψηλά τεχνικά πρότυπα του γραφείου των δημόσιων δρόμων 
(αργότερα η ομοσπονδιακή διοίκηση εθνικών οδών) έπρεπε να 
ισορροπηθούν με την υποχρέωση της εθνικής υπηρεσίας πάρκων να 
ελαχιστοποιήσει τη ζημία στο τοπίο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">era la primera carretera por la cual los 
visitantes podrían ver los lagos, los glaciares, los picos alpestres,
y los prados del parque nacional del glaciar. El trabajo sobre 
la ruta 50-mile, que conectó las caras del este y del oeste del 
parque y cruzó el continental se divide en el paso de Logan, comenzó
en 1921. Los altos estándares técnicos de la oficina de los 
caminos públicos (más adelante la administración federal de la 
carretera) necesitaron ser balanceados con la consolidación del 
servicio del parque nacional para reducir al mínimo daño al paisaje.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207043</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105528</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/going-to-the-sun-road-a-model-of-landscape-engineering</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
