<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104761</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104761</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086405</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Leon Sverdlove On the Taft-Hartley Act</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Leon Sverdlove auf der Taft-Hartley Tat</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Leon Sverdlove sur la Loi de Taft-Hartley</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Leon Sverdlove no ato de Taft-Hartley</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Leon Sverdlove sulla Legge di Taft-Hartley</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Leon Sverdlove στο νόμο ταφτ- Hartley</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Leon Sverdlove en el acto de Taft-Hartley</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Taft-Hartley Act, passed in 1947, symbolized the anti-labor climate of postwar America. The act expanded the power of employers and the government to prevent union organizing and strikes, and made it difficult for unions to take industrial action. The most difficult aspect of the bill for many unions to swallow required labor leaders to declare themselves to be non-Communist if they wanted to participate in NLRB elections. While many union members, like Leon Sverdlove of the Jewelry Workers union in New York, resented having to divulge their political views, they accepted the act's requirement in order to protect what union rights they had left. As Sverdlove found, however, even accepting the act's dictates did not protect unions and their members from accusations of communism, and many unions and workers suspected as communist sympathizers were forced out of organized labor.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Taft-Hartley Tat, geführt 1947, symbolisierte
Anti-bearbeiten Klima von Nachkriegsamerika. Die Tat erweiterte 
die Energie der Arbeitgeber und der Regierung, das 
Anschlußorganisieren und -schläge zu verhindern, und gebildet es 
schwierig, damit Anschlüße gewerkschaftliche Kampfmassnahme nehmen. 
Der schwierigste Aspekt der Rechnung, damit viele Anschlüße 
benötigten Gewerkschaftsführer, sich zu erklären, um nicht 
kommunistisch zu sein schlucken, wenn sie an den NLRB Wahlen 
teilnehmen wollten. Während viele Anschlußbauteile, wie Leon 
Sverdlove des Schmucksache-Arbeiteranschlußes in New York, ihre 
politischen Ansichten verbreiten übelgenommenes Müssen, sie annahmen
die Anforderung der Tat, um zu schützen, welche Anschlußrechte sie 
gelassen hatten. Da gefundenes Sverdlove die Vorschriften der 
Tat jedoch sogar annehmen Anschlüße und ihre Bauteile nicht vor 
Anklagen des Kommunismus schützte, und viele Anschlüße und 
Arbeiter, die als kommunistische Gleichgesinnte vermutet wurden, aus 
organisierter Arbeit heraus vorverlegt waren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'acte de Taft-Hartley, passé en 1947, a 
symbolisé anti-travaillent le climat de l'Amérique d'après-guerre. 
L'acte a augmenté la puissance des employeurs et du 
gouvernement d'empêcher l'organisation et les grèves des syndicats, 
et fait lui difficile pour que les syndicats prennent l'action 
industrielle. L'aspect le plus difficile de la facture pour que 
beaucoup de syndicats avalent a exigé des dirigeants syndicaux de se 
déclarer pour être non communistes s'ils voulaient participer aux 
élections de NLRB. Tandis que beaucoup de travailleurs 
syndiqués, comme Leon Sverdlove du syndicat de bijoux à New York, 
devoir offensé par divulguer leurs vues politiques, ils recevaient la
condition de l'acte afin de protéger quelles droites des syndicats 
ils avaient laissées. Car Sverdlove trouvé, cependant, 
recevoir même les préceptes de l'acte n'a pas protégé des 
syndicats et leurs membres contre des accusations du communisme, et 
beaucoup de syndicats et ouvriers suspectés en tant que sympathisants
communistes étaient obligatoires hors du travail organisé.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O ato de Taft-Hartley, passado em 1947, symbolized
anti-trabalha o clima de América postwar. O ato expandiu a 
potência dos empregadores e do governo impedir organizar e batidas da
união, e feito lhe difícil para que as uniões façam exame da 
ação industrial. O aspecto o mais difícil da conta para que 
muitas uniões engulam requereu líderes labor declarar-se para ser 
non-Communist se quisessem participar em eleições de NLRB. 
Quando muitos membros de união, como Leon Sverdlove da união 
de trabalhadores da jóia em New York, ter que ressentido divulge suas
vistas políticas, eles aceitaram a exigência do ato a fim proteger 
que direitas da união tinham deixado. Porque Sverdlove 
encontrado, entretanto, mesmo aceitar as ordens do ato não protegeu 
uniões e seus membros dos accusations do communism, e muitos uniões 
e trabalhadores suspeitados como sympathizers comunistas eram forçado
fora do trabalho organizado.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Legge di Taft-Hartley, passata in 1947, ha 
simbolizzato il clima di anti-lavoro dell'America dopoguerra. 
L'atto ha espanso l'potenza dei datori di lavoro e del governo 
impedire l'organizzazione ed i colpi del sindacato e reso esso 
difficile affinchè i sindacati intraprenda l'azione industriale. 
La funzione più difficile della fattura affinchè molti 
sindacati swallow ha richiesto ai capi di lavoro di 
dichiararsi per essere non comunisti se desiderassero partecipare alle
elezioni di NLRB. Mentre molti membri del sindacato, come Leon 
Sverdlove dell'unione di operai dei monili a New York, dovere 
risentito di divulgare i loro punti di vista politici, hanno accettato
il requisito dell'atto per proteggere che diritti del sindacato 
avevano lasciato. Poichè Sverdlove trovato, tuttavia, neppure 
accettare i dettami dell'atto non ha protetto i sindacati ed i loro 
membri dalle accuse di comunismo e molti sindacati ed operai 
ritenuti sospetto come simpatizzanti comunisti erano forzato dal 
lavoro organizzato.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το νόμο ταφτ- Hartley, που πέρασαν το 1947, 
συμβόλισε το κλίμα αντι-εργασίας της μεταπολεμικής Αμερικής. 
Η πράξη επέκτεινε τη δύναμη των εργοδοτών και της 
κυβέρνησης για να αποτρέψει την οργάνωση και τις απεργίες ένωσης,
και το κατέστησε δύσκολο για τις ενώσεις να λάβουν βιομηχανικά 
μέτρα. Η δυσκολότερη πτυχή του λογαριασμού για πολλές 
ενώσεις για να καταπιούν απαίτησε τους ηγέτες εργασίας για να 
δηλωθεί για να είναι μη κομουνιστής εάν θέλησαν να συμμετέχουν 
στις εκλογές NLRB. Ενώ πολλά μέλη ένωσης, όπως Leon 
Sverdlove του σωματείου εργαζομένων κοσμήματος στη Νέα Υόρκη, 
ηγανάκτησαν να πρέπει να αποκαλύψουν τις πολιτικές όψεις τους, 
αποδέχθηκαν την απαίτηση της πράξης προκειμένου να προστατευθεί 
ποιος δικαιώματα ένωσης είχαν αφήσει. Όπως Sverdlove 
βρήκε, εντούτοις, ακόμη και να αποδεχθεί τις προσταγές της 
πράξης δεν προστάτευσε τις ενώσεις και τα μέλη τους από τις 
κατηγορίες του κομμουνισμού, και πολλοί ενώσεις και εργαζόμενοι 
που υποψιάστηκαν ως κομμουνιστικοί υποστηρικτές αναγκάστηκαν από 
την οργανωμένη εργασία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El acto de Taft-Hartley, pasado en 1947, 
simbolizó contra-trabaja clima de América de la posguerra. El 
acto amplió la potencia de patrones y del gobierno de prevenir la 
ordenación y huelgas de la unión, y hecho le difícil para que las 
uniones tomen la acción industrial. El aspecto más difícil de
la cuenta para que muchas uniones traguen requirió a arranques de 
cinta de trabajo declararse para ser no comunistas si desearon 
participar en elecciones de NLRB. Mientras que muchos miembros 
de unión, como Leon Sverdlove de la unión de trabajadores de la 
joyería en Nueva York, el tener que resentido divulgar sus opiniones 
políticas, ellos validaron el requisito del acto para proteger las 
qué derechas de la unión habían dejado. Pues Sverdlove 
encontrado, sin embargo, incluso validar los dictados del acto no 
protegió a uniones y a sus miembros contra acusaciones del comunismo,
y muchas uniones y trabajadores sospechados como simpatizantes 
comunistas eran forzado fuera de trabajo ordenado.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086405</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104761</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/leon-sverdlove-on-the-taft-hartley-act</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
