<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107200</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107200</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086304</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Wasn't Interested In Living In The United States If I Wasn't Going To Be In The Movement:" Jack O'Dell on Civil Rights Organizing</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Ich War Nicht Interessiert, An, In den Vereinigten
Staaten Zu wohnen, Wenn Ich Nicht Im BegriffWAR, In der Bewegung Zu 
sein:" Jack O'Dell auf dem Zivilrecht-Organisieren</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Je N'étais pas Intéressé À Habiter Aux 
Etats-Unis Si Je N'allais pas Être Dans Le Mouvement :" Jack 
o'Dell sur l'organisation de droits civiques</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Eu Não estava Interessado Em Viver Nos Estados 
Unidos Se Eu Não fosse Estar No Movimento:" Jack O'Dell em 
organizar das direitas civis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Non ero Interessato Nel Vivere Nel Unito 
Dichiaro Se Non sterà andando Essere Nel Movimento:" 
Jack O'Dell sull'organizzazione di diritti civili</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Δεν ενδιαφέρθηκα για τη διαβίωση στις Ηνωμένες 
Πολιτείες εάν δεν επρόκειτο είμαι στη μετακίνηση:" Γρύλος 
O'Dell στην οργάνωση αστικών δικαιωμάτων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"No estaba Interesado En Vivir En Los Estados 
Unidos Si No iba A estar En El Movimiento:" Gato O'Dell en la 
ordenación de las derechas civiles</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Jack O'Dell was one of many young black servicemen who returned from World War II determined to change conditions for African Americans at home. Along with veterans, African Americans who had participated in wartime industries and union organizing, and who had experienced improvements in pay and education, became more assertive in their demands for equality. As a member of the National Maritime Union, O'Dell participated in union organizing and challenging racial discrimination. Later, he used his job as an insurance agent to speak with African Americans in their homes, encouraging them to register to vote. These activities formed a basis for his participation in the Civil Rights Movement, during which he directed the New York office of the Southern Christian Leadership Conference (SCLC).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Jack O'Dell war einer vieler junger schwarzer 
Soldaten, die vom Zweiten Weltkrieg zurückkamen, der 
festgestellt wurde, um Bedingungen für afrikanische Amerikaner zu 
Hause zu ändern. Zusammen mit Veteranen wurden afrikanische 
Amerikaner, die an den Kriegindustrien und -anschluß teilgenommen 
hatten, die organisieren und die Gehaltsaufbesserungen und Ausbildung 
erfahren hatten, in ihren Nachfragen nach Gleichheit assertive. 
Als Bauteil des nationalen Seeanschlußes, nahm O'Dell am 
Anschlußorganisieren und an schwieriger rassischer Unterscheidung 
teil. Später verwendete er seinen Job als Versicherungsagent, 
mit afrikanischen Amerikanern in ihren Häusern zu sprechen und regte 
sie mit Register mit Stimme an. Diese Aktivitäten bildeten eine
Grundlage für seine Teilnahme an der Zivilrecht-Bewegung, während 
deren er das New York Büro der südlichen christlichen 
Führung-Konferenz (SCLC) verwies.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jack o'Dell était l'un de beaucoup de jeunes 
soldats noirs qui sont retournés de la deuxième guerre mondiale 
déterminée pour changer des conditions pour les Américains 
africains à la maison. Avec des vétérans, les Américains 
africains qui avaient participé aux industries et à l'union de temps
de guerre organisant, et qui avaient éprouvé des augmentations de 
salaire et l'éducation, sont devenus plus autoritaires dans leurs 
demandes d'égalité. En tant que membre de l'union maritime 
nationale, o'Dell a participé à l'organisation des syndicats et à 
la discrimination raciale provocante. Plus tard, il a utilisé 
son travail comme agent d'assurance de parler avec les Américains 
africains dans leurs maisons, les encourageant au registre à la voix.
Ces activités ont formé une base pour sa participation au 
mouvement de droits civiques, pendant lequel il a dirigé le bureau de
New York de la conférence chrétienne méridionale de conduite 
(SCLC).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jack O'Dell era um de muitos recrutas pretos novos 
que retornaram da segunda guerra mundial determinada mudar condições
para americanos africanos na HOME. Junto com veterans, os 
americanos africanos que tinham participado nas indústrias e na 
união do wartime que organizam, e que tinham experimentado melhorias 
no pagamento e na instrução, tornaram-se mais assertive em suas 
demandas para a igualdade. Como um membro da união marítima 
nacional, O'Dell participou em organizar da união e em 
discriminação racial challenging. Mais tarde, usou seu 
trabalho como um agente de seguro falar com os americanos africanos em
suas HOME, incentivando as ao registo ao voto. Estas atividades 
deram forma a uma base para sua participação no movimento das 
direitas civis, durante que dirigiu o escritório de New York da 
conferência christian do sul da liderança (SCLC).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Jack O'Dell era uno di molti tecnici di 
manutenzione neri giovani che hanno ritornato dalla seconda guerra 
mondiale determinata per cambiare i termini per gli Americani africani
nel paese. Con i veterani, gli Americani africani che avevano 
partecipato alle industrie ed all'unione di wartime che organizzano e 
che avevano avvertito i miglioramenti nella paga e nella formazione, 
sono diventato più assertive nelle loro richieste di uguaglianza. 
Come membro dell'unione marittima nazionale, O'Dell ha 
partecipato all'organizzazione del sindacato ed alla distinzione 
razziale challenging. Più successivamente, ha usato il suo 
lavoro come agente di assicurazione parlare con gli Americani africani
nelle loro sedi, consiglianti loro al registro al voto. Queste 
attività hanno formato una base per la sua partecipazione al 
movimento di diritti civili, durante cui ha diretto l'ufficio de New 
York del congresso cristiano del sud di direzione (SCLC).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο Jack O'Dell ήταν ένα από πολλά νέα μαύρα 
servicemen που επέστρεψαν από τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο ΙΙ που 
καθορίστηκε για να αλλάξει τους όρους για αφρικανικούς 
Αμερικανούς στο σπίτι. Μαζί με τους παλαιμάχους, 
αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί που είχαν συμμετάσχει στις εν καιρώ 
πολέμου βιομηχανίες και την οργάνωση ένωσης, και που είχαν 
δοκιμάσει τις βελτιώσεις στην αμοιβή και την εκπαίδευση, έγιναν 
πιό κατηγορηματικοί στις απαιτήσεις τους για την ισότητα. 
Σαν μέλος της εθνικής θαλάσσιας ένωσης, O'Dell 
συμμετείχε στην ένωση που οργανώνει και που προκαλεί τη φυλετική 
διάκριση. Αργότερα, χρησιμοποίησε την εργασία του ως 
ασφαλιστικό πράκτορα για να μιλήσει με αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς 
στα σπίτια τους, που ενθαρρύνουν τα για να καταχωρήσει για να 
ψηφίσει. Αυτές οι δραστηριότητες αποτέλεσαν μια βάση για τη
συμμετοχή του στο Κίνημα αστικών δικαιωμάτων, κατά τη διάρκεια 
του οποίου κατεύθυνε το γραφείο της Νέας Υόρκης της νότιας 
χριστιανικής διάσκεψης ηγεσίας (SCLC).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Gato O'Dell era uno de muchos mecánicos negros 
jóvenes que volvieron de la Segunda Guerra Mundial determinada para 
cambiar las condiciones para los americanos africanos en el país. 
Junto con veteranos, los americanos africanos que habían 
participado en las industrias y la unión del tiempo de guerra que 
ordenaban, y que habían experimentado mejoras en paga y la 
educación, hicieron más asertivos en sus demandas para la igualdad. 
Como miembro de la unión marítimo nacional, O'Dell participó 
en la ordenación de la unión y la discriminación racial 
desafiadora. Más adelante, él utilizó su trabajo como agente 
de seguro de hablar con los americanos africanos en sus hogares, 
animándolos al registro al voto. Estas actividades formaron una
base para su participación en el movimiento de las derechas civiles, 
durante el cual él dirigió la oficina de Nueva York de la 
conferencia cristiana meridional de la dirección (SCLC).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086304</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107200</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-wasnt-interested-in-living-in-the-united-states-if-i-wasnt-going-to-be-in-the-movement-jack-odell-on-civil-rights-organizing</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
