<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108119</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108119</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086924</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Corn Parade .</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Mais-Parade.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Défilé De Maïs.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A Parada Do Milho.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Parata Del Cereale.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η παρέλαση καλαμποκιού.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Desfile Del Maíz.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">During the Great Depression, New Deal programs provided work for a range of unemployed Americans, including creative artists. Visual artists working for the Federal Art Project created murals for the walls of federal and state buildings and established community art centers in remote areas. The murals often depicted ordinary Americans, at work or in struggle, rendered in heroic, larger than life style. Few of the post office murals commissioned by the Treasury Department Section of Fine Art displayed the humor of Orr C. Fisher's paean to corn. But the Iowa-born Fisher's work suggests the kind of regional boosterism and pride of place that characterized many murals painted by local artists.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während des großen Tiefstands stellten Programme des 
neuen Abkommens Arbeit für eine Strecke der arbeitslosen Amerikaner, 
einschließlich kreative Künstler zur Verfügung. 
Sichtkünstler, die für die Bundeserstellten Wandbilder der 
kunst Projekt für die Wände der Bundes- und Zustandgebäude und der 
hergestellten Gemeinschaftskunstmitten in den Remotebereichen 
arbeiten. Die Wandbilder stellten häufig gewöhnliche 
Amerikaner, an der Arbeit oder im Kampf bildlich dar, übertragen in 
heroischem, größer als Lebensstil. Wenige der 
Postamtwandbilder, die durch das Fiskus-Abteilung Kapitel der feinen 
kunst beauftragen wurden, zeigten die Stimmung Orr C. Fishers der 
Lobrede zum Mais an. Aber die Iowa-getragenen Arbeit des 
Fischers schlägt die Art des regionalen boosterism und Stolz des 
Platzes vor, der viele Wandbilder kennzeichnete, die von den lokalen 
Künstlern gemalt wurden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant la grande dépression, les programmes de nouvelle 
affaire ont fourni le travail pour un intervalle des Américains sans 
emploi, y compris les artistes créateurs. Artistes visuels 
travaillant pour les muraux créés par projet fédéral d'art pour 
les murs des bâtiments fédéraux et d'état et des centres établis 
d'art de la communauté dans des régions éloignées. Les 
muraux ont souvent dépeint les Américains ordinaires, au travail ou 
dans la lutte, rendue dans héroïque, plus grande que le style de 
vie. Peu des muraux de poste commissionnés par la section de 
service de trésor de l'art fin ont affiché l'humeur du péan d'Orr 
C. Fisher's au maïs. Mais le travail de Fisher Iowa-soutenu 
suggère le genre de boosterism régional et la fierté de l'endroit 
qui a caractérisé beaucoup de muraux peints par les artistes locaux.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Durante o depression grande, os programas do negócio novo
forneceram o trabalho para uma escala de americanos unemployed, 
including artistas creativos. Artistas visuais que trabalham 
para os murals criados da arte projeto federal para as paredes de 
edifícios federais e do estado e de centros estabelecidos da arte da 
comunidade em áreas remotas. Os murals descreveram 
frequentemente americanos ordinários, no trabalho ou no esforço, 
rendido em heroic, maior do que o estilo de vida. Poucos dos 
murals do escritório de borne comissão pela seção do departamento 
do Tesouraria da arte fina indicaram o humor do paean de Orr C. Fisher
ao milho. Mas o trabalho do fisher Iowa-carregado sugere o tipo 
do boosterism regional e o orgulho do lugar que caracterizou muitos 
murals pintados por artistas locais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Durante la depressione grande, i programmi di nuovo affare
hanno fornito il lavoro per una gamma di Americani disoccupati, 
compreso gli artisti creativi. Gli artisti visivi che lavorano 
per i murals creati il progetto federale di arte per le pareti di 
federale e dichiarano le costruzioni ed i centri stabiliti di 
arte della Comunità nelle zone a distanza. I murals hanno 
descritto spesso gli Americani ordinari, sul lavoro o nella lotta, 
resa in eroico, più grande dello stile di vita. Pochi dei 
murals dell'ufficio postale incaricati dalla sezione di reparto di 
Ministero del Tesoro dell'arte fine hanno visualizzato l'umore del 
paean di Orr C. Fisher a cereale. Ma il lavoro del pescatore 
Iowa-sopportato suggerisce il genere di boosterism regionale e 
l'orgoglio del posto che ha caratterizzato molti murals verniciati 
dagli artisti locali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατά τη διάρκεια της μεγάλης οικονομικής κρίσης, νέα
παρεχόμενη προγράμματα εργασία διαπραγμάτευσης για μια σειρά 
άνεργων Αμερικανών, συμπεριλαμβανομένων των δημιουργικών 
καλλιτεχνών. Οι εικαστηκοί καλλιτέχνες που εργάζονται για το
ομοσπονδιακό πρόγραμμα τέχνης δημιούργησαν τις τοιχογραφίες για 
τους τοίχους των ομοσπονδιακών και κρατικών κτηρίων και ίδρυσαν 
τα κοινοτικά κέντρα τέχνης στις απομακρυσμένες περιοχές. Οι
τοιχογραφίες απεικόνισαν συχνά συνηθισμένους Αμερικανούς, στην 
εργασία ή στην προσπάθεια, έδωσαν σε ηρωικό, μεγαλύτερος από 
τον τρόπο ζωής. Λίγες από τις τοιχογραφίες ταχυδρομείων 
που ανατέθηκαν από το τμήμα τμήματος Υπουργείου Οικονομικών της 
λεπτής τέχνης παρουσίασαν το χιούμορ Orr Γ. Fisher's του 
παιάνα στο καλαμπόκι. Αλλά η εργασία του Iowa-gennime'noy
ψαρά προτείνει το είδος περιφερειακού boosterism και την 
υπερηφάνεια της θέσης που χαρακτήρισαν πολλές τοιχογραφίες που 
χρωματίστηκαν από τους τοπικούς καλλιτέχνες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Durante la gran depresión, los programas del nuevo 
reparto proporcionaron al trabajo para un rango de americanos parados,
incluyendo artistas creativos. Artistas visuales que trabajan 
para los murals creados proyecto federal del arte para las paredes de 
los edificios federales y del estado y de los centros establecidos del
arte de la comunidad en áreas alejadas. Los murals 
representaron a menudo a americanos ordinarios, en el trabajo o en la 
lucha, rendida en heroico, más grande que estilo de vida. Pocos
de los murals del correos comisionados por la sección del 
departamento del Hacienda del arte fino visualizaron el humor del 
paean de Orr C. Fisher's al maíz. Pero el trabajo del pescador 
Iowa-llevado sugiere la clase de boosterism regional y el orgullo del 
lugar que caracterizó muchos murals pintados por los artistas 
locales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086924</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108119</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-corn-parade</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
