<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106342</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106342</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206327</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Office of Science and Technology Education</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Büro der Wissenschaft und der 
Technologie-Ausbildung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le bureau de la Science et de l'éducation de 
technologie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O escritório da ciência e da instrução da 
tecnologia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'ufficio di scienza e di educazione di 
tecnologia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το γραφείο της εκπαίδευσης επιστήμης και τεχνολογίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La oficina de la ciencia y de la educación de la 
tecnología</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features free educational materials and outreach programs at the NIH, a video and slide program of speakers discussing Hollywood movies that have a medical science theme, original stories about medical research in the news, profiles of people in a variety of science-related careers, and articles that explain how various achievements in science happened.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Merkmale geben pädagogische Materialien frei und 
übertreffen Programme am NIH, an einem Bildschirm und am 
Plättchenprogramm der Sprecher, die Hollywood Filme behandeln, die 
ein medizinisches Wissenschaft Thema, ursprüngliche Geschichten über
medizinische Forschung in den Nachrichten, Profile der Leute in einer 
Vielzahl der Wissenschaft-in Verbindung stehenden Karrieren und 
Artikel haben, die beschreiben, wie verschiedene Ausführungen in der 
Wissenschaft geschahen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les dispositifs libèrent les matériaux 
éducatifs et dépassent des programmes au NIH, à un vidéo et au 
programme de glissière des orateurs discutant les films de 
Hollywood qui ont un thème médical de la science, des histoires 
initiales au sujet de recherche médicale dans les nouvelles, des 
profils des personnes dans une variété de carrières 
science-connexes, et des articles qui expliquent comment les divers 
accomplissements en science se sont produits.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">as características livram materiais educacionais 
e excedem programas no NIH, em um vídeo e no programa da corrediça 
dos altofalantes que discutem os filmes de Hollywood que têm um tema 
médico da ciência, umas histórias originais sobre a pesquisa 
médica na notícia, uns perfis dos povos em uma variedade de 
carreiras ciência-relacionadas, e uns artigos que expliquem como as 
várias realizações na ciência aconteceram.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">le caratteristiche liberano i materiali educativi 
e superano i programmi al NIH, ad un video ed al programma dello 
scorrevole degli altoparlanti che discutono i film di 
Hollywood che hanno un tema medico di scienza, lle storia originali 
circa ricerca medica nelle notizie, i profili della gente in una 
varietà di carriere scienza-relative e gli articoli che spiegano come
i vari successi nella scienza sono accaduto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">τα ελεύθερα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά χαρακτηριστικών 
γνωρισμάτων και ξεπερνούν τα προγράμματα στο NIH, ένα βίντεο 
και ένα πρόγραμμα φωτογραφικών διαφανειών των ομιλητών που 
συζητούν τους κινηματογράφους Hollywood που έχουν ένα ιατρικό 
θέμα επιστήμης, αρχικές ιστορίες για την ιατρική έρευνα στις 
ειδήσεις, τα σχεδιαγράμματα των ανθρώπων σε ποικίλες 
επιστήμη-σχετικές με το σταδιοδρομίες, και τα άρθρα που εξηγούν 
πώς τα διάφορα επιτεύγματα στην επιστήμη συνέβησαν.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">las características liberan los materiales 
educativos y exceden programas en el NIH, un vídeo y el programa de 
la diapositiva de los locutores que discuten las películas de 
Hollywood que tienen un tema médico de la ciencia, historias 
originales sobre la investigación médica en las noticias, perfiles 
de la gente en una variedad de carreras ciencia-relacionadas, y los 
artículos que explican cómo sucedieron los varios logros en ciencia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206327</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106342</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-office-of-science-and-technology-education</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
