<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108386</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108386</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205464</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Refugee: The Power of Language</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Flüchtling: Die Energie der Sprache</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Réfugié : La puissance du langage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Refugee: A potência da língua</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Rifugiato: L'potenza del linguaggio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πρόσφυγας: Η δύναμη της γλώσσας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Refugiado: La potencia del lenguaje</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The film "Refugee" follows three young Cambodian American men on their journey to Cambodia to find family members. Some of the characters' experiences are easier than others because of their ability to speak Cambodian. In this lesson plan, students compare and contrast the characters' experiences with a focus on language. Students will also interview family members to trace their family's language roots.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Film "Flüchtling" folgt drei jungen 
kambodschanischen amerikanischen Männern auf ihrer Reise nach 
Kambodscha, um Familie Bauteile zu finden. Einige der 
Erfahrungen der Zeichen sind einfacher als andere wegen ihrer 
Fähigkeit, Kambodschaner zu sprechen. In diesem Lektionplan 
vergleichen Kursteilnehmer und kontrastieren die Erfahrungen der 
Zeichen mit einem Fokus auf Sprache. Kursteilnehmer interviewen 
auch Familie Bauteile, um Wurzeln Sprache ihrer Familie zu verfolgen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le film "réfugié" suit trois jeunes hommes 
américains cambodgiens sur leur voyage au Cambodge pour trouver des 
membres de famille. Certaines des expériences des caractères 
sont plus faciles que d'autres en raison de leur capacité de parler 
cambodgien. Dans ce plan de leçon, les étudiants comparent et 
contrastent les expériences des caractères avec un foyer sur le 
langage. Les étudiants intervieweront également des membres de
famille pour tracer les racines du langage de leur famille.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A película "refugee" segue três homens 
americanos cambodian novos em sua viagem a Cambodia para encontrar 
membros da família. Algumas das experiências dos caráteres 
são mais fáceis do que outras por causa de sua abilidade de falar o 
cambodian. Nesta planta da lição, os estudantes comparam e 
contrastam as experiências dos caráteres com um foco na língua. 
Os estudantes entrevistarão também membros da família para 
seguir raizes da língua da sua família.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La pellicola "rifugiato" segue tre uomini 
americani cambogiani giovani sul loro viaggio in Cambogia per trovare
i membri della famiglia. Alcune delle esperienze dei caratteri 
sono più facili di altre a causa della loro capacità di parlare 
cambogiano. In questo programma di lezione, gli allievi 
confrontano e contrappongono le esperienze dei caratteri con un fuoco 
sul linguaggio. Gli allievi egualmente intervisteranno i membri 
della famiglia per seguire le radici di linguaggio della loro 
famiglia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ταινία "πρόσφυγασ" ακολουθεί τρία νέα καμποτζιανά 
αμερικανικά άτομα στο ταξίδι τους στην Καμπότζη για να βρεί τα 
οικογενειακά μέλη. Μερικές από την εμπειρία των χαρακτήρων
είναι ευκολότερες από άλλες λόγω της δυνατότητάς τους να 
μιλήσουν Καμποτζηανό. Σε αυτό το σχέδιο μαθήματος, οι 
σπουδαστές συγκρίνουν και αντιπαραβάλλουν την εμπειρία των 
χαρακτήρων με μια εστίαση στη γλώσσα. Οι σπουδαστές θα 
πάρουν συνέντευξη από επίσης τα οικογενειακά μέλη για να 
επισημάνουν τις γλωσσικές ρίζες της οικογένειάς τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La película "refugiado" sigue a tres hombres 
americanos camboyanos jóvenes en su viaje a Camboya para encontrar a 
miembros de la familia. Algunas de las experiencias de los 
caracteres son más fáciles que otras debido a su capacidad de hablar
camboyano. En este plan de la lección, los estudiantes comparan
y ponen en contraste las experiencias de los caracteres con un foco en
lenguaje. Los estudiantes también se entrevistarán con a 
miembros de la familia para rastrear las raíces del lenguaje de su 
familia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205464</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108386</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/refugee-the-power-of-language</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
