<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104604</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104604</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212672</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Northwest Fisheries Science Center (NFSC) Harmful Algal Blooms Program</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Nordwestschädliche Algenblüte Programm Der 
FISCHEREI-Wissenschaft Mitte-(NFSC)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Programme D'algues Nocif du nord-ouest de 
Fleurs du Centre de la Science de Pêche (NFSC)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Programa Algal Prejudicial Noroeste Das Flores 
Do Centro Da Ciência Dos Fisheries (NFSC)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Programma D'alghe Nocivo Di nord-ovest Delle 
Fioriture Del Centro Di Scienza Delle Industrie della pesca (NFSC)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το πρόγραμμα κεντρικών (NFSC) επιβλαβές φυκώδες 
ανθίσεων επιστήμης βορειοδυτικής αλιείας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Programa Algal Dañoso Del noroeste De las 
Floraciones Del Centro De la Ciencia De las Industrias pesqueras 
(NFSC)</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This website features the NFSC Harmful Algal Blooms (HAB) Program, which works cooperatively with other NOAA agencies and provides information concerning HABs and marine biotoxins to the public, state and federal agencies, tribes, university, and others in the Eastern Pacific region. The website provides an overview of HABs and biotoxins, NWFSC research and research partnerships, outreach information (including Red Tides and ORHAB newsletters), and links to related websites.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Web site kennzeichnet das NFSC schädliche 
Algenblüte (HAB) Programm, das kooperativ mit anderen NOAA Agenturen 
arbeitet und die Informationen hinsichtlich sind HABs und der 
Marinebiotoxins zur Öffentlichkeit, Zustand und Bundesämter, 
Stämme, Universität zur Verfügung stellt, und andere in der 
östlichen pazifischen Region. Die Web site liefert einen 
Überblick über HABs und biotoxins, NWFSC Forschung und Forschung 
Teilhaberschaften, übertreffen Informationen (einschließlich rote 
Gezeiten und ORHAB Rundschreiben) und Links zu in Verbindung 
stehenden Web site.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site Web comporte le programme d'algues nocif 
des fleurs de NFSC (HAB), qui fonctionne coopérativement avec 
d'autres agences de NOAA et fournit l'information au sujet de HABs et 
de biotoxins marins au public, l'état et les agences fédérales, 
tribus, université, et d'autres dans Pacifique oriental. Le 
site Web fournit une vue d'ensemble de HABs et les biotoxins, 
recherche de NWFSC et associations de recherches, dépassent 
l'information (marées rouges y compris et bulletins d'ORHAB), et des 
liens aux sites Web relatifs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Web site caracteriza o programa algal 
prejudicial das flores de NFSC (HAB), que trabalha cooperativa com 
outras agências de NOAA e fornece a informação a respeito de HABs e
dos biotoxins marinhos ao público, o estado e agências federais, 
tribes, universidade, e outro na região pacífica oriental. O 
Web site fornece uma vista geral de HABs e os biotoxins, pesquisa de 
NWFSC e parcerias da pesquisa, excedem a informação (marés 
vermelhas including e boletins de notícias de ORHAB), e as ligações
aos Web site relacionados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Web site caratterizza le fioriture d'alghe 
nocive di NFSC (HAB) che il programma, che funziona in cooperazione 
con altre agenzie di NOAA e fornisce le informazioni riguardo a HABs 
ed i biotoxins marini al pubblico, dichiara ed enti federali, 
le tribù, l'università ed altre nella regione pacifica orientale. 
Il Web site fornisce una descrizione di HABs ed i biotoxins, 
ricerca di NWFSC ed associazioni di ricerca, superano le informazioni 
(maree rosse comprese e bollettini di ORHAB) ed i collegamenti ai Web 
site relativi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος χαρακτηρίζει το επιβλαβές φυκώδες 
πρόγραμμα ανθίσεων NFSC (HAB), το οποίο λειτουργεί 
συνεταιριστικά με άλλες αντιπροσωπείες NOAA και παρέχει τις 
πληροφορίες σχετικά με HABs και τις θαλάσσιες βιοτοξίνες στο 
κοινό, το κράτος και τις ομοσπονδιακές αντιπροσωπείες, τις φυλές,
το πανεπιστήμιο, και άλλα στην ανατολική ειρηνική περιοχή. 
Ο ιστοχώρος παρέχει μια επισκόπηση HABs και οι 
βιοτοξίνες, η έρευνα NWFSC και οι ερευνητικές συνεργασίες, 
ξεπερνούν τις πληροφορίες (συμπεριλαμβανομένων των κόκκινων 
παλιρροιών και των ενημερωτικών δελτίων ORHAB), και τις 
συνδέσεις με τους σχετικούς ιστοχώρους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este Web site ofrece el programa algal dañoso de 
las floraciones de NFSC (HAB), que trabaja cooperativo con otras 
agencias de NOAA y proporciona a la información referente HABs y a 
biotoxins marinas al público, al estado y a las agencias federales, 
tribus, universidad, y otros en la región pacífica del este. 
El Web site proporciona a una descripción de HABs y los 
biotoxins, investigación de NWFSC y sociedades de la investigación, 
exceden la información (mareas rojas incluyendo y los boletines de 
noticias de ORHAB), y conexiones a los Web site relacionados.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:THE NORTHWEST FISHERIES SCIENCE CENTER, NATIONAL OCEANIC AND ATMOSPHERIC ADMINISTRATION
FN:THE NORTHWEST FISHERIES SCIENCE CENTER, NATIONAL OCEANIC AND ATMOSPHERIC ADMINISTRATION
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212672</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104604</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-northwest-fisheries-science-center-nfsc-harmful-algal-blooms-program</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
