<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105651</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105651</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206206</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Global Warming Facts and Our Future</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Globale wärmende Tatsachen und unsere Zukunft</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Faits de chauffage globaux et notre futur</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fatos aquecendo-se globais e nosso futuro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fatti di riscaldamento globali ed il nostro 
futuro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σφαιρικά γεγονότα θέρμανσης και το μέλλον μας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Hechos que se calientan globales y nuestro futuro</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">explores the latest scientific information from the National Academy of Science and Technologys. Is our climate warming? Are humans causing it? What might be the effects? What can be done? Learn about the greenhouse effect, the carbon cycle, past changes in our climate, and predicted changes and how they could affect sea levels, agriculture, and ecosystems. See options for reducing CO2 emissions.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erforscht die neueste Fachinformation von der 
National Academy of Sciences und Technologys. Wärmt sich unser 
Klima? Verursachen Menschen es? Was konnte die Effekte 
sein? Was kann getan werden? Erlernen Sie über den 
Gewächshauseffekt, die Carbonschleife, hinter Änderungen in unserem 
Klima und vorausgesagten Änderungen und wie sie Meeresspiegel, 
Landwirtschaft und Oekosysteme beeinflussen konnten. Sehen Sie 
Optionen für das Verringern der CO2-Emissionen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">explore la dernière information scientifique de 
la National Academy of Sciences et Technologys. Notre climat 
chauffe-t-il ? Les humains le causent-ils ? Que pourrait 
être les effets ? Que peut être fait ? Renseignez-vous 
sur l'effet de serre chaude, le cycle de carbone, après des 
changements de notre climat, et des changements prévus et comment ils
pourraient affecter des niveaux de mer, l'agriculture, et des 
écosystèmes. Voir les options pour réduire des émissions de 
CO2.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">explora a informação científica a mais atrasada
da National Academy of Sciences e Technologys. Nosso clima está
aquecendo-se? Os seres humanos estão causando-o? Que 
pôde ser os efeitos? Que pode ser feito? Aprenda sobre o 
efeito da estufa, o ciclo de carbono, após mudanças em nosso clima, 
e mudanças preditas e como poderiam afetar níveis de mar, 
agricultura, e ecosystems. Veja opções reduzindo emissões do 
CO2.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esplora l'ultima informazione scientifica 
dall'Accademia nazionale della scienza e di Technologys. Il 
nostro clima sta scaldando? Gli esseri umani stanno causandolo? 
Che cosa ha potuto essere gli effetti? Che cosa può 
essere fatto? Impari circa l'effetto della serra, il ciclo di 
carbonio, oltre i cambiamenti nel nostro clima ed i cambiamenti 
previsti e come potrebbero interessare i livelli di mare, 
l'agricoltura e gli ecosistemi. Veda le opzioni per la riduzione
delle emissioni del CO2.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ερευνά τις πιό πρόσφατες επιστημονικές πληροφορίες 
από την εθνική ακαδημία της επιστήμης και Technologys. Το
κλίμα μας θερμαίνει; Οι άνθρωποι τον προκαλούν; Τι να 
είναι τα αποτελέσματα; Τι μπορεί να γίνει; Μάθετε για
το φαινόμενο του θερμοκηπίου, τον κύκλο άνθρακα, τις προηγούμενες
αλλαγές στο κλίμα μας, και τις προβλεφθείσες αλλαγές και πώς θα 
μπορούσαν να έχουν επιπτώσεις στις στάθμες θάλασσας, τη γεωργία,
και τα οικοσυστήματα. Δείτε τις προαιρετικές 
δυνατότητες για τις εκπομπές του CO2.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">explora la información científica más última 
de la National Academy of Sciences y Technologys. ¿Nuestro clima
se está calentando? ¿Los seres humanos lo están causando? 
¿Qué pudo ser los efectos? ¿Qué puede ser hecha? 
Aprenda sobre el efecto del invernadero, el ciclo de carbón, 
más allá de cambios en nuestro clima, y de cambios predichos y cómo
podrían afectar niveles de mar, agricultura, y ecosistemas. Vea
las opciones para reducir emisiones del CO2.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206206</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105651</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/global-warming-facts-and-our-future</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
