<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106906</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106906</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205607</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">And justice for all: the Trail of Tears, Mexican deportation, and Japanese internment</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Und Gerechtigkeit für alle: die Spur der 
Risse, der mexikanischen Zwangsverschickung und der japanischen 
Internierung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Et justice pour tous : la traînée des 
larmes, de la déportation mexicaine, et de l'internement japonais</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">E justiça para tudo: a fuga dos rasgos, da 
deporta16cao mexicana, e do internamento japonês</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">E giustizia per tutti: la traccia delle 
rotture, della deportazione messicana e dell'internamento giapponese</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Και δικαιοσύνη για όλους: το ίχνος των δακρύων, 
της μεξικάνικης εκτόπισης, και του ιαπωνικού περιορισμού</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Y justicia para todos: el rastro de 
rasgones, de la deportación mexicana, y de la internación japonesa</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Many textbooks mention the Trail of Tears, but fail to mention that this early displacement of an ethnic minority is only the one of many legally-sanctioned forced relocations. This lesson will address the displacement of American Indians through the Trail of Tears, the forced deportation of Mexican Americans during the Great Depression, and the internment of Japanese American citizens during WWII.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Viele Lehrbücher erwähnen die Spur der Risse, 
aber können erwähnen, daß nicht diese frühe Distanzadresse einer 
ethnischen Minorität die nur eine vieler zugelassen-sanktionierter 
vorverlegter Verschiebungen ist. Diese Lektion adressiert die 
Distanzadresse der Indianer durch die Spur der Risse, der vorverlegten
Zwangsverschickung der mexikanischen Amerikaner während des großen 
Tiefstands und der Internierung der japanischen amerikanischen Bürger
während WWII.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Beaucoup de manuels mentionnent la traînée des 
larmes, mais ne mentionnent pas que ce déplacement tôt d'une 
minorité ethnique est seulement un de beaucoup de réadressages 
obligatoires légal-sanctionnés. Cette leçon adressera le 
déplacement des Indiens d'Amerique par la traînée des larmes, de la
déportation obligatoire des Américains mexicains pendant la grande 
dépression, et de l'internement des citoyens américains japonais 
pendant le WWII.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Muitos textbooks mencionam a fuga dos rasgos, mas 
não mencionam que este deslocamento adiantado de um minority étnico 
é o somente o um de muitos relocations forçados 
legal-legally-sanctioned. Esta lição dirigir-se-á ao 
deslocamento de indians americanos através da fuga dos rasgos, da 
deporta16cao forçada de americanos mexicanos durante o depression 
grande, e do internamento de cidadãos americanos japoneses durante 
WWII.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Molti manuali accennano la traccia delle rotture, 
ma non riescono ad accennare che questo spostamento iniziale di una 
minoranza etnica è il soltanto uno di molte rilocazioni forzate 
legale-legally-sanctioned. Questa lezione richiamerà lo 
spostamento degli indiani americani attraverso la traccia delle 
rotture, della deportazione forzata degli Americani messicani durante
la depressione grande e dell'internamento dei cittadini americani 
giapponesi durante il WWII.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πολλά εγχειρίδια αναφέρουν το ίχνος των δακρύων, 
αλλά αποτυγχάνουν να αναφέρουν ότι αυτή η πρόωρη μετατόπιση 
μιας εθνικής μειονότητας είναι μόνο μια από πολλές 
νόμιμα-εγκριμένες αναγκασμένες επαναμεταθέσεις. Αυτό το 
μάθημα θα εξετάσει τη μετατόπιση αμερικανικών Ινδών μέσω του 
ίχνους των δακρύων, της αναγκασμένης εκτόπισης μεξικάνικων 
Αμερικανών κατά τη διάρκεια της μεγάλης οικονομικής κρίσης, και 
του περιορισμού των ιαπωνικών αμερικανικών πολιτών κατά τη 
διάρκεια WWII.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Muchos libros de textos mencionan el rastro de 
rasgones, pero no pueden mencionar que esta dislocación temprana de 
una minoría étnica es solamente el una de muchas realocaciones 
forzadas legal-sancionadas. Esta lección tratará la 
dislocación de indios americanos a través del rastro de rasgones, de
la deportación forzada de americanos mexicanos durante la gran 
depresión, y de la internación de ciudadanos americanos japoneses 
durante WWII.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PATRICIA CAMP
FN:PATRICIA CAMP
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205607</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106906</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/and-justice-for-all-the-trail-of-tears-mexican-deportation-and-japanese-internment</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
