<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107671</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107671</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087259</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"You Couldn't Escape the Anti- Communism:" Jack O'Dell Recalls Red-Baiting in the Civil Rights Movement</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Sie konnten nicht dem Kommunismus Anti- 
entgehen:" Jack O'Dell Rückrufe, die in der Zivilrecht-Bewegung
Rot-Anlocken</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"vous ne pourriez pas échapper anti au communisme
:" Rappels de Jack o'Dell Rouge-Amorçant dans le mouvement de 
droits civiques</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"você não poderia escapar anti- do communism:" 
Recordações de Jack O'Dell quered-Baiting no movimento das 
direitas civis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"non potreste fuoriuscire anti il comunismo:" 
Richiami del Jack O'Dell cheAdescano nel movimento di diritti 
civili</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Δεν θα μπορούσατε να δραπετεύσετε τον αντι - 
κομμουνισμός:" Ανακλήσεις γρύλων O'Dell κόκκινος-που 
δελεάζουν στο Κίνημα αστικών δικαιωμάτων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"usted no podría escapar contra el comunismo:" 
Memorias de Gato O'Dell Rojo-Que hostigan en el movimiento de 
las derechas civiles</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Anti-communism still had tremendous political weight during the early 1960's, when opponents of Civil Rights used it to undermine support for the African-American movement. Like many other black leaders, Jack O'Dell, who was the director of the Southern Christian Leadership Conference (SCLC) office in New York in 1963, became the target of an FBI operation. The bureau leaked unsubstantiated charges against him in an attempt to smear the SCLC as communist influenced. O'Dell remembered that President Kennedy pressured Martin Luther King, Jr. to sever ties with O'Dell, who Kennedy described as a notorious communist, in order to win support for the Civil Rights Act.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Anti-Kommunismus hatte noch enormes politisches 
Gewicht während der frühen sechziger Jahre, als Konkurrenten von 
Zivilrechten es benutzten, um Support für die 
Afrikanisch-Amerikanische Bewegung zu untergraben. Wie viele 
andere schwarze Führer wurde Jack O'Dell, der der Direktor des 
südlichen christlichen Büros der Führung-Konferenz (SCLC) in New 
York 1963 war, das Ziel einer FBI Operation. Das Büro, das 
ausgelaufen wurde, unsubstantiated Ladungen gegen ihn, um das SCLC als
beeinflußter Kommunist zu schmieren. O'Dell erinnerte, daß 
Präsident Kennedy Martin Luther König drueckte, jr. daran, um 
Gleichheit mit O'Dell zu trennen, das Kennedy als notorischer 
Kommunist beschrieb, um Support für die Zivilrechte zu gewinnen 
fungieren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">l'Anti-communisme avait toujours le poids 
politique énorme pendant le début des années soixante, quand les 
adversaires des droits civiques l'avaient l'habitude pour miner le 
soutien du mouvement afro-américain. Comme beaucoup d'autres 
amorces noires, Jack o'Dell, qui était le directeur du bureau 
chrétien méridional de la conférence de conduite (SCLC) à New York
en 1963, est devenu la cible d'une exécution de FBI. Le 
bureau a fui les frais non fondés contre lui afin d'essayer d'enduire
le SCLC en tant que communiste influencé. o'Dell s'est rappelé
que président Kennedy a pressurisé le roi de Martin Luther, Jr. 
pour diviser des cravates avec o'Dell, que Kennedy a décrit en 
tant que communiste notoire, dans la commande pour gagner le soutien 
des droits civiques agissent.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">o Anti-anti-communism teve ainda o peso político 
tremendo durante os 1960's adiantados, quando os oponentes de direitas
civis o usaram undermine a sustentação para o movimento 
Africano-Americano. Como muitos outros líderes pretos, Jack 
O'Dell, que era o diretor do escritório christian do sul da 
conferência da liderança (SCLC) em New York em 1963, transformou-se 
o alvo de uma operação de FBI. O departamento escapado 
unsubstantiated cargas de encontro a ele em uma tentativa de manchar o
SCLC como o comunista influenciado. O'Dell recordou que o 
presidente Kennedy exerceu pressão sobre o rei de Martin Luther, Jr. 
sever laços com O'Dell, que Kennedy descreveu como um comunista 
notorious, a fim ganhar a sustentação para as direitas civis age.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">il Anti-comunismo ancora ha avuto peso politico 
tremendo durante l'inizio degli anni 60, quando gli avversari dei 
diritti civili lo hanno usato per insidiare il sostegno il movimento 
Africano-Americano. Come molti altri capi neri, Jack 
O'Dell, che era il direttore dell'ufficio cristiano del sud di 
congresso di direzione (SCLC) a New York in 1963, si è transformato 
in nell'obiettivo di un funzionamento di FBI. L'ufficio 
fuoriuscito unsubstantiated le spese contro di lui nel tentativo di 
spalmare lo SCLC come comunista influenzato. O'Dell si è 
ricordato di che il presidente Kennedy pressured il re del Martin 
Luther, Jr. per dividere i legami con O'Dell, che Kennedy ha descritto
come comunista rinomato, per vincere il sostegno i diritti civili si 
comporta.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο αντι-κομμουνισμός είχε ακόμα το τεράστιο πολιτικό 
βάρος κατά τη διάρκεια της πρόωρης δεκαετίας του '60, όταν το 
χρησιμοποίησαν οι αντίπαλοι των αστικών δικαιωμάτων για να 
υπονομεύσουν την υποστήριξη για την αφρικανικός-αμερικανική 
μετακίνηση. Όπως πολλούς άλλους μαύρους ηγέτες, Jack 
O'Dell, που ήταν ο σκηνοθέτης του νότιου χριστιανικού γραφείου
διασκέψεων ηγεσίας (SCLC) στη Νέα Υόρκη το 1963, έγινε ο 
στόχος μιας λειτουργίας FBI. Το γραφείο διέρρευσε τις 
αβάσιμες δαπάνες ενάντια σε τον σε μία προσπάθεια να λερωθεί το 
SCLC όπως κομμουνιστή που επηρεάστηκε. Τα O'Dell 
θυμήθηκαν ότι ο Πρόεδρος Kennedy πίεσε το βασιλιά Martin 
Luther, νεώτερος για να χωρίσει τους δεσμούς με O'Dell, το 
οποίο Kennedy περιέγραψε ως πασίγνωστο κομμουνιστή, 
προκειμένου να κερδηθεί η υποστήριξη για το νόμο αστικών 
δικαιωμάτων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">el Contra-comunismo todavía tenía enorme peso 
político durante los años 60 tempranos, cuando los opositores de las
derechas civiles lo utilizaron para minar la ayuda para el movimiento 
Africano-Americano. Como muchos otros arranques de cinta negros,
Gato O'Dell, que era el director de la oficina cristiana meridional de
la conferencia de la dirección (SCLC) en Nueva York en 1963, hizo la 
blanco de una operación de FBI. La oficina escapada 
unsubstantiated cargas contra él en una tentativa de manchar el SCLC 
como comunista influenciado. O'Dell recordó que presidente 
Kennedy ejerció presión sobre a rey de Martin Luther, Jr. para 
separar lazos con O'Dell, que Kennedy describió como comunista 
notorio, para ganar la ayuda para las derechas civiles actúa.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087259</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107671</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/you-couldnt-escape-the-anti-communism-jack-odell-recalls-red-baiting-in-the-civil-rights-movement</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
