<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104466</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104466</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086849</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Starting for Lowell."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">", abfahrend nach Lowell."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"partant pour Lowell."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"partindo para Lowell."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"partendo per Lowell."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Αρχικός για το Lowell."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"saliendo para Lowell."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">During the 1820s, large scale production of fabric centered in New England. Perhaps the best known of such cotton mill towns was Lowell, Massachusetts. The Lowell mills mechanized each stage of cloth production, and most mill workers were young, single women from rural New England families struggling to make ends meet. This illustration from T. S. Arthur's reform tract  Illustrated Temperance Tales  (1850) presented a young woman leaving her farm family to work in a cotton mill. This picture was accurate in showing that New England farm families often had to rely on income from factory labor. But reformers blamed economic hardship on personal weaknesses--in the case of Arthur's story, the father's alcoholism.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während des 1820s zentrierte Produktion der großen Skala
des Gewebes in Neu-England. Möglicherweise war gut bekannt von 
solchen Baumwollspinnereistädten Lowell, Massachusetts. Die 
Lowell Tausendstel mechanisierten jedes Stadium der Tuchproduktion, 
und die meisten Tausendstelarbeiter waren junge, einzelne Frauen von 
den landwirtschaftlichen Neu-England Familien, die kämpfen, um Enden 
treffen zu lassen. Diese Abbildung T. S. Arthur von der 
Verbesserungfläche veranschaulichte Temperance Geschichten (1850) 
darstellte eine junge Frau, die ihre Bauernhoffamilie Arbeit in einer 
Baumwollspinnerei läßt. Diese Abbildung war genau, wenn sie 
zeigte, daß Neu-England Bauernhoffamilien auf Einkommen von der 
Fabrikarbeit häufig bauen mußten. Aber Reformer tadelten
ökonomische Härte auf persönlichen Schwächen -- im Fall von der 
Geschichte Arthurs, der Alkoholismus des Vaters.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant le 1820s, la production à grande échelle du 
tissu a centré en Nouvelle Angleterre. Peut-être mieux connu 
de telles villes de filature de coton était Lowell, le Massachusetts.
Les moulins de Lowell ont mécanisé chaque étape de production
de tissu, et la plupart des ouvrières de moulin étaient de jeunes, 
célibataires femmes des familles rurales de la Nouvelle Angleterre 
luttant pour faire des extrémités se réunir. Cette 
illustration de région de réforme de T. S. Arthur a illustré les 
contes de Modération (1850) a présenté une jeune femme laissant sa 
famille de ferme au travail dans une filature de coton. Cette 
image était précise en prouvant que les familles de ferme de la 
Nouvelle Angleterre souvent ont dû compter sur le revenu du travail 
d'usine. Mais les réformateurs ont blâmé des difficultés 
économiques sur des faiblesses personnelles -- dans le cas de 
l'histoire de Arthur, l'alcoolisme du père.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Durante o 1820s, a produção da escala grande da tela 
centrou-se em Nova Inglaterra. Talvez sabido melhor de tais 
cidades do moinho de algodão era Lowell, Massachusetts. Os 
moinhos de Lowell mechanized cada estágio da produção de pano, e a 
maioria de trabalhadores do moinho eram mulheres novas, únicas das 
famílias rurais de Nova Inglaterra que esforçam-se para fazer 
extremidades encontrar-se com. Esta ilustração do intervalo da
reforma de T. S. Arthur ilustrou os tales de Temperance (1850) 
apresentou uma mulher nova que deixa sua família da fazenda ao 
trabalho em um moinho de algodão. Este retrato era exato em 
mostrar que as famílias da fazenda de Nova Inglaterra frequentemente 
tiveram que confiar na renda do trabalho da fábrica. Mas os 
reformers responsabilizaram o hardship econômico em fraquezas 
pessoais -- no exemplo da história de Arthur, o alcoholism do pai.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Durante il 1820s, la produzione della grande scala di 
tessuto ha concentrato in Nuova Inghilterra. Forse conosciuto il
più bene di tali città del cotonificio era Lowell, Massachusetts. 
I laminatoi de Lowell hanno meccanizzato ogni fase di produzione
del panno e la maggior parte dei operai del laminatoio erano donne 
giovani e non-sposate dalle famiglie rurali della Nuova Inghilterra 
che lottano per fare le estremità venire a contatto di. Questa 
illustrazione dal tratto di riforma del T. S. Arthur ha illustrato i 
racconti di Temperance (1850) ha presentato una donna giovane che 
lascia la sua famiglia dell'azienda agricola a lavoro in un 
cotonificio. Questa immagine era esatta nell'indicare che le 
famiglie dell'azienda agricola della Nuova Inghilterra hanno dovuto 
contare spesso su reddito dal lavoro della fabbrica. Ma i 
reformers hanno incolpato delle difficoltà economiche sulle debolezze
personali -- nel caso della storia del Arthur, l'alcolismo del padre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατά τη διάρκεια του 1820s, παραγωγή μεγάλης 
κλίμακας του υφάσματος που κεντροθετείται στη Νέα Αγγλία. 
Ίσως το καλύτερο που ήταν γνωστό για τέτοιες πόλεις μύλων
βαμβακιού ήταν Lowell, Μασαχουσέτη. Οι μύλοι του 
Lowell μηχανοποίησαν κάθε στάδιο της παραγωγής υφασμάτων, και 
οι περισσότεροι εργαζόμενοι μύλων ήταν νέες, ανύπαντρες από τις
αγροτικές οικογένειες της Νέας Αγγλίας που αγωνίζονται να κάνουν
τις άκρες να συναντηθούν. Αυτή η απεικόνιση από το κομμάτι
μεταρρύθμισης Τ. Θ*ς. αρθούρου επεξήγησε οι ιστορίες ότι 
μετριοπάθειας (1850) παρουσίασαν μια νέα γυναίκα που αφήνει 
την αγροτική οικογένειά της για να εργαστούν σε έναν μύλο 
βαμβακιού. Αυτή η εικόνα ήταν ακριβής να δείξει ότι οι 
αγροτικές οικογένειες της Νέας Αγγλίας έπρεπε συχνά να 
στηριχθούν στο εισόδημα από την εργασία εργοστασίων. Αλλά 
οι μεταρρυθμιστές κατηγόρησαν την οικονομική δυσκολία στις 
προσωπικές αδυναμίες -- στην περίπτωση της ιστορίας αρθούρου, ο 
αλκοολισμός του πατέρα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Durante el 1820s, la producción de la escala grande de la
tela se centró en Nueva Inglaterra. Quizás sabido lo más 
mejor posible de tales ciudades de la fábrica de algodón era Lowell,
Massachusetts. Los molinos de Lowell mecanizaron cada etapa de 
la producción del paño, y la mayoría de los trabajadores del molino
eran mujeres jóvenes, solas de las familias rurales de Nueva 
Inglaterra que luchaban para hacer que los extremos satisfacen. 
Esta ilustración de la zona de la reforma de T. S. Arturo 
ilustró los cuentos de Temperance (1850) presentó a mujer joven que 
dejaba su familia de la granja al trabajo en una fábrica de algodón.
Este cuadro era exacto en mostrar que las familias de la granja 
de Nueva Inglaterra tuvieron que confiar a menudo en renta del trabajo
de la fábrica. Pero los reformadores culparon dificultad 
económica en debilidades personales -- en el caso de la historia de 
Arturo, el alcoholismo del padre.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086849</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104466</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/starting-for-lowell</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
