<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104527</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104527</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209957</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Online Science-athon: The Chocolate Melt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Onlinewissenschaft-athon: Die Schokolade 
Schmelze</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science-athon En ligne : La Fonte de 
Chocolat</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência-athon Em linha: O Derretimento Do 
Chocolate</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza-athon In linea: La Fusione Del 
Cioccolato</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε απευθείας σύνδεση επιστήμη -επιστήμη-ατχον: 
Το λειωμένο μέταλλο σοκολάτας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia-athon En línea: El Derretimiento 
Del Chocolate</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Online Science-athon offers elementary and middle-grade students opportunities to discover the science in their daily lives. Presented as challenges, the Science-athon asks students to investigate their world in ways that are engaging and fun, easy for teachers to incorporate into their teaching, and instructive. Students doing the Chocolate Melt decide on a container-tin can, cardboard box, plastic bucket, paper bag, or similar object-to use as a solar cooker. Then they consider how to melt a refrigerated standard-size milk chocolate chip that has been placed on the end of a toothpick inside the cooker in as short a time as possible. This includes figuring out how to reshape the container so that the heat from the sun is concentrated on the chocolate chip, deciding what colors and textures to use for lining inside surfaces and insulating the cooker, examining where to put the chocolate chip, and identifying how to point the cooker at the sun. Reviewing scientific information helps students improve the effectiveness of their cooker designs and make predictions about the ones they think will cook the most rapidly. On Chocolate Melting Day, students collect and record data to share with other students doing the challenge. </string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Onlinewissenschaft-athon bietet die 
grundlegende und Mittlergrad Kursteilnehmer Gelegenheiten, die 
Wissenschaft in ihren täglichen Lebensdauern zu entdecken an. 
Dargestellt als Herausforderungen, bittet die Wissenschaft-athon
Kursteilnehmer, ihre Welt in den Methoden, die und sich engagieren, im
Spaß nachzuforschen, einfach, damit Lehrer in ihren Unterricht 
verbinden, und lehrreich. Die Kursteilnehmer, welche die 
Schokolade Schmelze tun, entscheiden auf einer Behälter-Zinn Dose, 
Sammelpack, Plastikwanne, Papierbeutel, oder ähnlich Nachricht- zum 
Gebrauch als Solarkocher. Dann betrachten sie, wie man ein 
gekühltes Standard-Größe Milchschokoladechip schmilzt, das am Ende 
eines toothpick innerhalb des Kochers in so kurz eine Zeit plaziert 
worden ist, wie möglich. Dieses schließt das Berechnen aus 
ein, wie man den Behälter umgestaltet, damit die Hitze von der Sonne 
auf das Schokolade Chip konzentriert wird und entscheidet, welche für
Innenflächen des Futters und das Isolieren des Kochers, das 
Überprüfen, wo man das Schokolade Chip und das Kennzeichnen zu 
verwenden Farben und Beschaffenheiten, setzt, wie man den Kocher auf 
die Sonne zeigt. Fachinformation Hilfen Kursteilnehmer 
wiederholend, verbessern Sie die Wirksamkeit ihrer Kocherdesigns und 
bilden Sie Vorhersagen über die, die sie kochen schnell denken. 
An Schokolade schmelzendem Tag sammeln Kursteilnehmer und 
speichern Daten, um mit anderen Kursteilnehmern zu teilen, welche die 
Herausforderung tun.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science-athon en ligne offre les étudiants 
élémentaires et de moyen-catégorie des occasions de découvrir la 
science dans leurs vies quotidiennes. Présenté en tant que 
défis, la Science-athon demande à des étudiants d'étudier leur 
monde des voies qui s'engagent et de l'amusement, facile pour des 
professeurs d'incorporer à leur enseignement, et instructif. 
Les étudiants faisant la fonte de chocolat décident d'un bidon
de récipient-étain, cadre de carton, position en plastique, le sac, 
ou semblable de papier objet- à l'utilisation comme cuiseur solaire. 
Alors ils considèrent comment fondre une puce frigorifiée de 
chocolat du lait de standard-taille qui a été placée sur 
l'extrémité d'un toothpick à l'intérieur du cuiseur dans aussi 
sous peu un moment comme possible. Ceci inclut figurer hors de 
la façon restructurer le récipient de sorte que la chaleur du soleil
soit concentrée sur la puce de chocolat, décidant quelles couleurs 
et textures à utiliser pour les surfaces intérieures de doublure et 
isoler le cuiseur, examiner où mettre la puce de chocolat, et 
identifier comment diriger le cuiseur au soleil. En passant en 
revue des étudiants d'aides d'information scientifique améliorez 
l'efficacité de leurs conceptions de cuiseur et faites les 
prévisions au sujet de celles qu'ils pensent feront cuire le plus 
rapidement. Le jour de fonte de chocolat, les étudiants 
rassemblent et enregistrent des données pour partager avec d'autres 
étudiants faisant le défi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A Ciência-athon em linha oferece estudantes 
elementares e da médio-classe oportunidades de descobrir a ciência 
em suas vidas diárias. Apresentado como desafios, a 
Ciência-athon pede que os estudantes investiguem seu mundo nas 
maneiras que estão acoplando e no divertimento, fácil para que os 
professores incorporem em seu ensino, e instructive. Os 
estudantes que fazem o derretimento do chocolate decidem-se em uma 
lata da recipiente-lata, caixa de cartão, cubeta plástica, o saco, 
ou similar de papel objeto- ao uso como um fogão solar. Então 
consideram como derreter uma microplaqueta refrigerated do chocolate 
de leite do padrão-tamanho que seja colocada na extremidade de um 
toothpick dentro do fogão tão brevemente em um momento como 
possível. Isto inclui figurar para fora de como reshape o 
recipiente de modo que o calor do sol seja concentrado na 
microplaqueta do chocolate, decidindo-se que cores e texturas a se 
usar para superfícies interiores do forro e isolar o fogão, examinar
onde pôr a microplaqueta do chocolate, e identificar como apontar o 
fogão no sol. Revendo estudantes das ajudas da informação 
científica melhore a eficácia de seus projetos do fogão e faça 
predições sobre essas que pensam cozinharão o mais ràpidamente. 
No dia de derretimento do chocolate, os estudantes coletam e 
gravam dados para compartilhar com outros estudantes que fazem o 
desafio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Scienza-athon in linea offre gli allievi del 
centrale-grado ed elementari occasioni scoprire la scienza nelle loro 
vite quotidiane. Presentato come sfide, la Scienza-athon chiede 
agli allievi di studiare il loro mondo nei modi che stanno 
agganciandosi e nel divertimento, facile affinchè gli insegnanti 
incorpori nel loro insegnamento ed istruttivo. Gli allievi che 
fanno la fusione del cioccolato decidono di una latta della 
contenitore-latta, contenitore di cartone, benna di plastica, sacco di
carta, o simile oggetto- ad uso come fornello solare. Allora 
considerano come fondere un circuito integrato refrigerato del 
cioccolato al latte di standard-formato che è stato disposto 
sull'estremità di un toothpick all'interno del fornello bruscamente 
in un momento come possibile. Ciò include calcolare verso 
l'esterno come rimodellare il contenitore in moda da concentrare il 
calore dal sole sul circuito integrato del cioccolato, decidente che 
colori e strutture da usare per le superfici interne del rivestimento 
ed isolare il fornello, esaminare dove mettere il circuito integrato 
del cioccolato ed identificare come indicare il fornello al sole. 
Rivedendo gli allievi di aiuti di informazione scientifica 
migliori l'efficacia dei loro disegni del fornello e faccia le 
previsioni circa quelle che pensino cucinino il più velocemente. 
Il giorno di fusione del cioccolato, gli allievi raccolgono e 
registrano i dati per ripartirsi con altri allievi che fanno la sfida.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η σε απευθείας σύνδεση επιστήμη -επιστήμη-ατχον 
προσφέρει τις στοιχειώδεις και μέσες ευκαιρίες σπουδαστών να 
ανακαλύψουν την επιστήμη στις καθημερινές ζωές τους. 
Παρουσιασμένη ως προκλήσεις, η επιστήμη -επιστήμη-ατχον 
ζητά από τους σπουδαστές για να ερευνήσει τον κόσμο τους στους 
τρόπους που δεσμεύουν και διασκέδαση, εύκολη για τους δασκάλους 
να ενσωματώσουν στη διδασκαλία τους, και διδακτική. Οι 
σπουδαστές που κάνουν το λειωμένο μέταλλο σοκολάτας αποφασίζουν 
ότι σε έναν εμπορευματοκιβώτιο-κασσίτερο μπορέστε, κιβώτιο 
χαρτονιού, πλαστικός κάδος, τσάντα εγγράφου, ή παρόμοιος 
αντικείμενο- στη χρήση ως ηλιακή κουζίνα. Κατόπιν 
εξετάζουν πώς να λειώσουν ένα κατεψυγμένο τσιπ σοκολάτας 
γάλακτος πρότυπος-μεγέθους που έχει τοποθετηθεί στο τέλος ενός 
toothpick μέσα στην κουζίνα σε όσο το δυνατόν πιό σύντομο 
χρονικό διάστημα. Αυτό περιλαμβάνει τον υπολογισμό πώς να 
αναδιαμορφώσει το εμπορευματοκιβώτιο έτσι ώστε η θερμότητα από 
τον ήλιο συγκεντρώνεται στο τσιπ σοκολάτας, αποφασίζοντας τί 
χρώματα και συστάσεις στη χρήση για τις εσωτερικές επιφάνειες 
ευθυγράμμισης και η μόνωση της κουζίνας, η εξέταση πού να τεθεί 
το τσιπ σοκολάτας, και ο προσδιορισμός πώς να δείξουν την κουζίνα
στον ήλιο που αναθεωρεί τις επιστημονικές πληροφορίες βοηθούν 
τους σπουδαστές να βελτιώσουν την αποτελεσματικότητα των σχεδίων 
κουζινών τους και να κάνουν τις προβλέψεις για αυτές που 
σκέφτονται θα μαγειρεψουν ο πιό πάρα πολύ γρήγορα. την 
ημέρα τήξης σοκολάτας, οι σπουδαστές συλλέγουν και τα στοιχεία 
αρχείων που μοιράζονται με άλλους σπουδαστές που κάνουν την 
πρόκληση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Ciencia-athon en línea ofrece a estudiantes 
elementales y del medio-grado las oportunidades de descubrir la 
ciencia en sus vidas diarias. Presentado como desafíos, la 
Ciencia-athon pide que los estudiantes investiguen su mundo de las 
maneras que están enganchando y de la diversión, fácil para que los
profesores incorporen en su enseñanza, e instructivo. Los 
estudiantes que hacen el derretimiento del chocolate deciden sobre una
lata de la envase-lata, una caja de cartón, un compartimiento 
plástico, una bolsa de papel, o un similar objeto- a uso como cocina 
solar. Entonces consideran cómo derretir una viruta refrigerada
del chocolate con leche de la esta'ndar-talla que se ha colocado en el
extremo de un toothpick dentro de la cocina en tan brevemente una 
época como sea posible. Esto incluye calcular fuera de cómo 
restructurar el envase para concentrar el calor del sol en la viruta 
del chocolate, decidiendo a qué colores y texturas a utilizar para 
las superficies interiores de la guarnición y aislar la cocina, 
examinar donde poner la viruta del chocolate, e identificar cómo 
señalar la cocina en el sol. Repasando a estudiantes de las 
ayudas de la información científica mejore la eficacia de sus 
diseños de la cocina y haga las predicciones sobre las que piensan 
cocinarán lo más rápidamente posible. En día que derrite del
chocolate, los estudiantes recogen y registran datos para compartir 
con otros estudiantes que hacen el desafío.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209957</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104527</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/chocolate-melt</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
