<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108360</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108360</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973913</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Immune Attack</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Immuner Angriff</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Attaque Immunisée</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ataque Imune</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Attacco Immune</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανοση επίθεση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ataque Inmune</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Immune Attacks content is geared for senior level high school biology and first year university biology. To play the game, users control a microscopic robot and navigate through a first-person 3D body, completing a series of stepwise missions to detect a bacterial infection and activate the appropriate defensive immune cells. These stepwise missions follow the actual biological process that occurs during an infection and how immune cells are stimulated to kill the bacteria.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Immuner Angriffe Inhalt wird für ältere 
waagerecht ausgerichtete High School Biologie und erste 
Jahruniversitätsbiologie übersetzt. Um das Spiel zu spielen, 
steuern Benutzer einen mikroskopischen Roboter und steuern durch einen
Erstperson 3D Körper und führen eine Reihe schrittweise Missionen 
durch um eine bakterielle Infektion zu entdecken und die passenden 
defensiven immunen Zellen zu aktivieren. Diese schrittweisen 
Missionen folgen dem tatsächlichen biologischen Prozeß, der während
einer Infektion auftritt und wie immune Zellen angeregt werden, um das
Bakterium zu beenden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le contenu immunisé d'attaques est adapté pour 
la biologie de niveau aînée de lycée et la première biologie 
d'université d'année. Pour jouer le jeu, les utilisateurs 
contrôlent un robot microscopique et dirigent par un corps de la 
premier-personne 3D, terminant une série de missions par étapes pour
détecter une infection bactérienne et pour lancer les cellules 
immunisées défensives appropriées. Ces missions par étapes 
suivent le processus biologique réel qui se produit pendant une 
infection et comment des cellules immunisées sont stimulées pour 
détruire les bactéries.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O índice imune dos ataques é engrenado para a 
biologia nivelada sênior da High School e a primeira biologia da 
universidade do ano. Para jogar o jogo, os usuários controlam 
um robô microscópico e navigate através de um corpo da 
primeiro-pessoa 3D, terminando uma série de missões stepwise para 
detectar uma infecção bacteriana e para ativar as pilhas imunes 
defensivas apropriadas. Estas missões stepwise seguem o 
processo biológico real que ocorre durante uma infecção e como as 
pilhas imunes são estimuladas para matar as bactérias.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il soddisfare immune di attacchi è innestato per 
biologia livellata maggiore della High School e prima biologia 
dell'università di anno. Per giocare il gioco, gli utenti 
gestiscono un robot microscopico e traversano attraverso un corpo 
della primo-persona 3D, completante una serie di missioni graduali per
rilevare un'infezione batterica e per attivare le cellule immuni 
difensive adatte. Queste missioni graduali seguono il processo 
biologico reale che si presenta durante l'infezione e come le cellule 
immuni sono stimolate per uccidere i batteri.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το άνοσο περιεχόμενο επιθέσεων συνδέεται για την 
ανώτερη βιολογία γυμνασίου επιπέδων και την πανεπιστημιακή 
βιολογία του πρώτου έτους. Για να παίξουν το παιχνίδι, οι 
χρήστες ελέγχουν ένα μικροσκοπικό ρομπότ και να πλοηγήσουν μέσω
ενός τρισδιάστατου σώματος πρώτος-προσώπων, που ολοκληρώνει μια 
σειρά σταδιακών αποστολών για να ανιχνεύσουν μια βακτηριακή 
μόλυνση και να ενεργοποιήσουν τα κατάλληλα αμυντικά άνοσα 
κύτταρα. Αυτές οι σταδιακές αποστολές ακολουθούν την 
πραγματική βιολογική διαδικασία που εμφανίζεται κατά τη διάρκεια
μιας μόλυνσης και πώς τα άνοσα κύτταρα υποκινούνται για να 
σκοτώσουν τα βακτηρίδια.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El contenido inmune de los ataques se engrana para
la biología llana mayor de la High School secundaria y la primera 
biología de la universidad del año. Para jugar el juego, los 
utilizadores controlan una robusteza microscópica y navegan a través
de un cuerpo de la primero-persona 3D, terminando una serie de 
misiones stepwise para detectar una infección bacteriana y para 
activar las células inmunes defensivas apropiadas. Estas 
misiones stepwise siguen el proceso biológico real que ocurre durante
una infección y cómo las células inmunes se estimulan para matar a 
las bacterias.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973913</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108360</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/immune-attack</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
