<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106818</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106818</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087494</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Colored Rule in the Reconstructed (?) State."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"farbige Richtlinie im wieder aufgebauten (?) 
Zustand."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"règle colorée dans (?) l'état reconstruit."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"régua colorida (?) no estado reconstructed."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la regola colorata in ricostruita (?) 
Dichiara."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Χρωματισμένος κανόνας στο αναδημιουργημένο) κράτος 
(?."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"regla coloreada en (?) el estado reconstruido."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Although Thomas Nast was an ardent supporter of equal rights, he often resorted to racial and ethnic stereotypes in his  Harper's Weekly  cartoons. Questioning the actions of some southern black Republican legislators, in the cartoon on the left Nast drew the figure of "Columbia," symbol of the nation, chiding: "You are aping the lowest whites. If you disgrace your race in this way you had better take back seats." Nast got a taste of his own medicine in this answering cartoon (right) on the cover of the  New York Daily Graphic , entitled "I Wonder How  Harper's  Artist Likes To Be Offensively Caricatured Himself?" Such consciousness in the press about offensive imagery would not last long. By the 1880s, with the end of a national commitment to black equality, racist stereotypes characterized most published cartoons and illustrations.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Obgleich Thomas Nast ein leidenschaftlicher Verfechter der
gleichen Rechte war, griff er häufig auf die rassischen und 
ethnischen Stereotypen seines Harpers in den wöchentlichen 
Karikaturen zurück. Das Ausfragen der Tätigkeiten einiger 
südlicher schwarzer republikanischer Gesetzgeber, in der Karikatur 
auf dem linken Nast zeichnete die Abbildung von "Kolumbien," das 
Symbol der Nation und schalt: "Sie äffen das niedrigste Weiß 
nach. Wenn Sie Ihr Rennen auf diese Art entehren, hatten Sie 
besseres, Sitze zurückzunehmen." Nast erhielt einen Geschmack 
seiner eigenen Medizin in dieser antwortenden Karikatur (recht) auf 
der Abdeckung der New York täglich Graphik, erlaubt "ich sich 
wundern, wie Künstler Harpers Offensively Caricatured selbst sein 
mag?" Solches Bewußtsein in der Presse über beleidigende 
Bilder würde nicht lang dauern. Durch das 1880s mit dem Ende 
einer nationalen Verpflichtung, zum von von Gleichheit zu schwärzen, 
kennzeichneten rassistische Stereotypen die meisten erschienenen 
Karikaturen und die Abbildungen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bien que Thomas Nast ait été un défenseur ardent 
d'égalité des droits, il a souvent recouru aux stéréotypes raciaux
et ethniques dans les dessins animés hebdomadaires de son Harper. 
La remise en cause des actions de quelques législateurs 
républicains noirs méridionaux, dans le dessin animé sur le Nast 
gauche a dessiné la figure de "Colombie," symbole de la nation, 
réprimandant : "vous imitez les plus bas blancs. Si vous 
déshonorez votre course de cette façon vous avez eu meilleur de 
prendre des banquettes arrières." Nast a obtenu un goût de sa propre 
médecine dans ce dessin animé de réponse (droit) sur la couverture 
de New York du graphique quotidiennement, intitulée "je se demandent 
comment l'artiste de Harper aime être Offensivement Caricatured 
lui-même?" Une telle conscience dans la presse au sujet du 
langage figuré blessant ne durerait pas longtemps. Par le 
1880s, avec la fin d'un engagement national pour noircir l'égalité, 
les stéréotypes racistes ont caractérisé la plupart des dessins 
animés et illustrations édités.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Embora Thomas Nast fosse um supporter ardent de direitas 
iguais, recorreu frequentemente aos stereotypes raciais e étnicos em 
cartoons semanais do seu Harper. Questionar as ações de alguns
legislators republicanos pretos do sul, no cartoon no Nast esquerdo 
desenhou a figura de "Colômbia," símbolo da nação, chiding: 
"você aping os brancos os mais baixos. Se você 
desonrasse sua raça nesta maneira você teve melhor fazer exame para 
trás de assentos." Nast começou um gosto de sua própria 
medicina neste cartoon respondendo (direito) na tampa de New York do 
gráfico diariamente, intitulada "mim quer saber como o artista de 
Harper gosta de ser Offensively Caricatured ele mesmo?" Tal 
consciousness na imprensa sobre o imagery ofensivo não duraria por 
muito tempo. Pelo 1880s, com o fim de um compromisso nacional 
para enegrecer a igualdade, os stereotypes racist caracterizaram a 
maioria cartoons e de ilustrações publicados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Anche se Thomas Nast era un sostenitore ardent dei diritti
uguali, ha ricorso spesso agli stereotipi razziali ed etnici nei 
fumetti settimanali del suo Harper. Mettere in discussione le 
azioni di alcuni legislatori Repubblicani neri del sud, nel fumetto sul 
Nast di sinistra ha dissipato la figura "di Colombia," simbolo della 
nazione, rimproverante: "state imitarando i bianchi più bassi. 
Se disgrace la vostra corsa in questo modo avete avuti migliore 
prendere indietro le sedi." Nast ha ottenuto un gusto della sua 
propria medicina in questo fumetto di risposta (di destra) sulla 
copertura de New York del grafico giornalmente, intitolata "io si 
domanda come l'artista del Harper gradisce essere In modo offensivo 
Caricatured egli stesso?" Tale coscienza nella pressa circa il 
linguaggio figurato offensivo non durerebbe lungamente. Dal 
1880s, con la conclusione di un impegno nazionale per annerire 
l'uguaglianza, gli stereotipi razzisti hanno caratterizzato la maggior
parte di fumetto e delle illustrazioni pubblicati.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αν και ο Thomas Nast ήταν διακαής υποστηρικτής 
των ίσων δικαιωμάτων, προσέφυγε συχνά στα φυλετικά και εθνικά 
στερεότυπα στα εβδομαδιαία κινούμενα σχέδια του Harper του. 
Η επερώτηση των ενεργειών μερικών νότιων μαύρων 
δημοκρατικών νομοθετών, στα κινούμενα σχέδια στο αριστερό Nast
έσυρε τον αριθμό "της Κολούμπια," σύμβολο του έθνους, που 
επιπλήττει: "Πιθηκίζετε τα χαμηλότερα λευκά. Εάν 
ντροπιάζετε τη φυλή σας κατ' αυτό τον τρόπο έπρεπε να πάρετε 
καλύτερα τα πίσω καθίσματα." Το Nast πήρε μια προτίμηση 
της ιατρικής του σε αυτά τα κινούμενα σχέδια απάντησης (δεξιά) 
στην κάλυψη της Νέας Υόρκης καθημερινά γραφικής, τιτλοφορημένος 
"αναρωτιέμαι πώς ο καλλιτέχνης Harper επιθυμεί να είναι 
προσβλητικά Caricatured ο ίδιος;" Τέτοια συνείδηση στον 
Τύπο για τα δυσάρεστα καλολογικά στοιχεία δεν θα διαρκούσε πολύ.
Από το 1880s, με το τέλος μιας εθνικής δέσμευσης για τη 
μαύρη ισότητα, ρατσιστικά στερεότυπα που χαρακτηρίζονται τις 
περισσότερες δημοσιευμένες κινούμενα σχέδια και απεικονίσεις.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Aunque Thomas Nast era un partidario ardiente de las 
derechas iguales, él recurrió a menudo a los estereotipos raciales y
étnicos en las historietas semanales de su Harper. Preguntar 
las acciones de algunos legisladores republicanos negros meridionales,
en la historieta en el Nast izquierdo trazó la figura de "Colombia," 
símbolo de la nación, regañando: "usted está imitando los 
blancos más bajos. Si usted deshonra su raza de esta manera 
usted tenía mejor tomar detrás asientos." Nast consiguió un 
gusto de su propia medicina en esta historieta que contestaba 
(derecha) en la cubierta de Nueva York del gráfico diariamente, 
titulada "yo se pregunta cómo el artista de Harper tiene gusto de ser
Offensively Caricatured mismo?" Tal sentido en la prensa sobre 
imágenes ofensivas no duraría de largo. Por el 1880s, con el 
final de una consolidación nacional para ennegrecer igualdad, los 
estereotipos racist caracterizaron la mayoría de las historietas y de
las ilustraciones publicadas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087494</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106818</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/colored-rule-in-the-reconstructed-state</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
