<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103519</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103519</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087085</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Yeast which Makes the Bread Rise": Hallie Flanagan on Drama as Politics</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die Hefe, die das Brot steigen läßt": 
Hallie Flanagan auf Drama als Politik</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"la levure qui fait le pain se lever" : 
Hallie Flanagan sur le drame comme politique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"o fermento que faz o pão se levantar": 
Hallie Flanagan no drama como a política</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"il lievito che fa il pane aumentare": 
Hallie Flanagan sul dramma come politica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η ζύμη που κάνει το ψωμί να αυξηθεί": Hallie Flanagan στο δράμα ως πολιτική</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"la levadura que hace que se levanta el pan": 
Hallie Flanagan en drama como política</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">"The theater must grow up," declared Hallie Flanagan, director of the New Deal-era Federal Theatre Project (FTP), which provided employment for actors, directors, and technicians during the Depression. By the 1930s, theater was rapidly losing its audiences to movies, and Flanagan sought to win audiences back by revitalizing drama with the excitement and conflict of contemporary life and politics. Her energy and sense of urgency came through in this talk on theater as social action, entitled "First Federal Summer Theatre: A Report." She borrowed the rhetoric of the militant labor movement as she summarized the work of a 1937 summer project that gathered FTP workers from around the country.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"das Theater muß aufwachsen," erklärtes Hallie 
Flanagan, Direktor des neue Behandeln-Ära Bundestheater-Projektes 
(ftp), das Beschäftigung für Schauspieler, Direktoren und Techniker 
während des Tiefstands zur Verfügung stellte. Bis zum den 
dreißiger Jahren verlor Theater schnell seine Publikum zu den Filmen 
und Flanagan, das gesucht wurde, um Publikum zurück zu gewinnen durch
Wiederbelebendrama mit der Aufregung und der $überschneidung der 
zeitgenössischen Lebensdauer und der Politik. Ihre Energie und 
Richtung der Dringlichkeit kamen durch in dieses Gespräch auf Theater
als Sozialtätigkeit, erlaubt "erstes Bundessommer-Theater: Ein 
Report." Sie borgte die Rhetorik der militanten 
Arbeiterbewegung, während sie die Arbeit eines 1937-Sommer-Projektes 
zusammenfaßte, das ftp Arbeiter aus um dem Land erfaßte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"le théâtre doit grandir," Hallie avoué 
Flanagan, directeur du projet fédéral de théâtre de nouvelle 
Occuper-ère (ftp), qui a fourni l'emploi pour des acteurs, des 
directeurs, et des techniciens pendant la dépression. Par les 
années 30, le théâtre détruisait rapidement ses assistances aux 
films, et Flanagan recherché pour gagner des assistances en arrière 
par drame de revitalisation avec l'excitation et le conflit de la vie 
et de la politique contemporaines. Son énergie et sens 
d'urgence sont venus à travers dans cet entretien sur le théâtre en
tant qu'action sociale, intitulée le "premier théâtre fédéral 
d'été : Un État." Elle a emprunté la rhétorique du 
mouvement de travail militant pendant qu'elle récapitulait le 
travail d'un projet de 1937 étés qui a recueilli des ouvriers de ftp
de dans le pays.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"o teatro deve crescer acima," Hallie declarado 
Flanagan, diretor do projeto federal do theatre da Negoci-era nova 
(ftp), que forneceu o emprego para atores, diretores, e técnicos 
durante o depression. Pelos 1930s, o teatro perdia ràpidamente 
suas audiências aos filmes, e Flanagan procurado ganhar para trás 
audiências pelo drama revitalizing com o excitamento e o conflito da 
vida e da política contemporary. Seus energia e sentido do 
urgency vieram completamente nesta conversa no teatro como a ação 
social, intitulada "primeiro theatre federal do verão: Um 
Relatório." Pediu o rhetoric do movimento labor militant 
enquanto sumariou o trabalho de um projeto de 1937 verões que 
recolhesse trabalhadores do ftp em torno do país.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"il teatro deve svilupparsi in su," Hallie 
dichiarato Flanagan, direttore del progetto federale del teatro di 
nuova Tratt-era (ftp), che ha fornito l'occupazione per gli attori, i 
direttori ed i tecnici durante la depressione. Entro i 1930s, il
teatro stava perdendo velocemente i relativi pubblici ai film e
Flanagan cercato per vincere i pubblici indietro dal dramma di 
ravvivamento con l'eccitamento ed il conflitto di vita e di politica 
contemporanee. La suoi energia e senso di urgenza sono venuto 
attraverso in questo colloquio sul teatro come azione sociale, 
intitolata "primo teatro federale di estate: Un Rapporto." 
Ha preso in prestito la retorica del movimento di lavoro del 
militante mentre ha ricapitolato il lavoro di un progetto di 1937 
estati che ha riunito gli operai del ftp intorno al paese.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Το θέατρο πρέπει να μεγαλώσει," δηλωμένο Hallie 
Flanagan, σκηνοθέτης του νέου προγράμματος θεάτρων 
διαπραγμάτευση-εποχής ομοσπονδιακού (FTP), το οποίο παρείχε 
την απασχόληση για τους δράστες, τους σκηνοθέτες, και τους 
τεχνικούς κατά τη διάρκεια της κατάθλιψης. Μέχρι τη 
δεκαετία του '30, το θέατρο έχανε γρήγορα τα ακροατήριά του 
στους κινηματογράφους, και Flanagan επιδίωξε να κερδίσει τα 
ακροατήρια πίσω με την αναζωογοηση του δράματος με τον ενθουσιασμό
και τη σύγκρουση της σύγχρονων ζωής και της πολιτικής. Η 
ενέργεια και η αίσθηση επείγουσας ανάγκης της ήρθαν κατευθείαν 
σε αυτήν την συζήτηση στο θέατρο ως κοινωνική ενέργεια, που 
τιτλοφορήθηκε "πρώτο ομοσπονδιακό θερινό θέατρο: Μια 
έκθεση." Δανείστηκε τη ρητορική της στρατευμένης 
μετακίνησης εργασίας δεδομένου ότι συνόψισε την εργασία ενός 
θερινού προγράμματος του 1937 που σύλλεξε τους εργαζομένους 
FTP από γύρω από τη χώρα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"el teatro debe crecer para arriba," Hallie 
declarado Flanagan, director del proyecto federal del teatro de la 
nueva Repartir-era (ftp), que proporcionó al empleo para los agentes,
los directores, y los técnicos durante la depresión. Por los 
años 30, el teatro perdía rápidamente sus audiencias a las 
películas, y Flanagan intentado para ganar a audiencias detrás por 
drama de la revitalización con el entusiasmo y el conflicto de la 
vida y de la política contemporáneas. Su energía y sentido de
la urgencia vinieron a través en esta charla sobre teatro como 
acción social, dada derecho "primer teatro federal del verano: 
Un Informe." Ella pidió prestado el retórico del 
movimiento de trabajo militante mientras que ella resumió el trabajo
de un proyecto de 1937 veranos que recolectó a trabajadores del ftp 
alrededor del país.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087085</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103519</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-yeast-which-makes-the-bread-rise-hallie-flanagan-on-drama-as-politics</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
