<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107817</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107817</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206949</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">President's Day: United in Service</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Day Des Präsidenten: Vereinigt worden im 
Service</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Day du Président : Uni en service</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Dia Do Presidente: Unido no serviço</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Day Del Presidente: Unito in servizio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ημέρα Προέδρου: Ενωμένος στην υπηρεσία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Day De Presidente: Unido en servicio</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">includes web-exclusive videos, presidential biographies developed with the help of area 5th-graders, coloring pages by a White House artist, and resources on volunteer service, history and civics for students, parents and teachers. In web videos, Lord of the Rings actor Sean Astin, Arizona Diamondback Luis Gonzalez, and former Washington Redskin Darrell Green discuss the importance of volunteer service.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">enthält Web-exklusive videos, die 
Präsidentenbiographien, die mit Hilfe des Bereiches 5th-graders 
entwickelt werden und färbt Seiten von einem Hauskünstler und 
Betriebsmittel auf freiwilligem Service, Geschichte und 
Gemeinschaftskunde für Kursteilnehmer, Eltern und Lehrer. In 
den Web videos behandeln Lord des Ringschauspielers Sean Astin, 
Arizona-Diamantmarkierung Luis Gonzalez und ehemaliges Washington 
Redskin Darrell Grün den Wert des freiwilligen Services.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">inclut des videos Web-exclusifs, biographies 
présidentielles développées avec l'aide de la zone 5th-graders, 
colorant des pages par un artiste  de la Maison Blanche, et des 
ressources au service, à l'histoire et à l'éducation civique 
volontaires pour des étudiants, des parents et des professeurs. 
Dans des videos de Web, le seigneur de l'acteur Sean Astin de 
boucles, le dos en forme de losange Luis Gonzalez de l'Arizona, 
et l'ancien vert de Darrell de Peau Rouge de Washington discutent 
l'importance du service volontaire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">inclui videos Web-exclusivos, biografias 
presidenciais desenvolvidas com a ajuda da área 5th-graders, 
colorindo páginas por um artista branco da casa, e recursos no 
serviço, no history e no civics voluntários para estudantes, pais e 
professores. Em videos do Web, o senhor do ator Sean Astin dos 
anéis, o diamondback Luis Gonzalez do arizona, e o verde anterior de 
Darrell do redskin de Washington discutem a importância do serviço 
voluntário.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">include i videos Web-esclusivi, biografie 
presidenziali sviluppate con l'aiuto di zona 5th-graders, colorante le
pagine da un artista della Casa Bianca e le risorse su servizio, su 
storia e su civics volontari per gli allievi, i genitori e gli 
insegnanti. In videos di Web, il signore dell'attore Sean Astin 
degli anelli, il diamondback Luis Gonzalez dell'Arizona ed il verde 
precedente di Darrell del redskin de Washington discutono l'importanza
di servizio volontario.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">περιλαμβάνει τα Ιστός-αποκλειστικά βίντεο, προεδρικές
βιογραφίες που αναπτύσσονται με τη βοήθεια των 5$ος-γκρέιντερ 
περιοχής, που χρωματίζουν τις σελίδες από έναν καλλιτέχνη 
λευκών οίκων, και τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς στην εθελοντικά 
υπηρεσία, την ιστορία και το civics για τους σπουδαστές, τους 
γονείς και τους δασκάλους. Στα βίντεο Ιστού, ο Λόρδος του 
δράστη δαχτυλιδιών Σων Astin, Αριζόνα Diamondback Luis 
Gonzalez, και πρώην ερυθρόδερμος Darrell της Ουάσιγκτον 
πράσινο συζητά τη σημασία της εθελοντικής υπηρεσίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">incluye los videos Web-exclusivos, biografías 
presidenciales desarrolladas con la ayuda del área 5th-graders, 
coloreando las paginaciones por un artista blanco de la casa, y los 
recursos en el servicio, la historia y el civics voluntarios para los 
estudiantes, los padres y los profesores. En videos del Web, el 
señor del agente Sean Astin de los anillos, el diamondback Luis 
Gonzalez del Arizona, y el verde anterior de Darrell del piel roja de 
Washington discuten la importancia del servicio voluntario.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206949</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107817</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/presidents-day-united-in-service</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
