<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105125</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105125</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205598</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Fugitive Slave Law Simulation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Flüchtling-Sklavengesetz-Simulation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Simulation Slave de Loi de Fugitif</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Simulação Slave Da Lei Do Fugitive</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Simulazione Slave Di Legge Del Fuggitivo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Προσομοίωση νόμου σκλάβων προσφύγων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Simulación Auxiliar De la Ley Del Fugitivo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Students face the crisis issue of the Fugitive Slave Bill which gave southerners the right to regain their runaway slaves and return them to bondage. It is also considered by many to have contributed to growing sectionalism in the U.S. and eventually the Civil War. In order to take on the roles of historical actors, students will examine primary source documents from the Documenting the American South collection and critique arguments in favor and opposed to the Bill.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kursteilnehmer stellen die Krise Ausgabe der 
Flüchtling-Sklave Rechnung gegenüber, die southerners das Recht gab,
ihre Durchgehensklaven wiederzugewinnen und sie zur Knechtschaft 
zurückzubringen. Sie wird auch durch viele betrachtet, zu 
wachsendem sectionalism in den VEREINIGTEN STAATEN und schließlich im
Bürgerkrieg beigetragen zu haben. Um auf den Rollen der 
historischen Schauspieler zu nehmen, überprüfen Kursteilnehmer 
Primärquelldokumente vom Dokumentieren der amerikanischen 
Südansammlung und Kritikargumente in der Bevorzugung und der Rechnung
entgegengesetzt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les étudiants font face à la question de crise 
de la facture Slave de fugitif qui a donné à des habitants du sud
le droit de regagner leurs esclaves d'emballement et de les renvoyer 
au servage. Elle est également considérée comme par beaucoup 
avoir contribuée au sectionalism croissant aux ETATS-UNIS et par la 
suite à la guerre civile. Afin de prendre les rôles des 
acteurs historiques, les étudiants examineront les documents de 
source primaires de documenter les arguments du sud américains 
de collection et de critique en faveur et opposés à la facture.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os estudantes enfrentam a introdução da crise da
conta do escravo do fugitive que deu a southerners a direita regain 
seus escravos do runaway e os retornar ao bondage. É 
considerada também por muitos ter contribuído ao sectionalism 
crescente nos ESTADOS UNIDOS e eventualmente na guerra civil. A 
fim fazer exame nos papéis de atores históricos, os estudantes 
examinarão originais de fonte preliminares de documentar os 
argumentos sul americanos da coleção e da crítica no favor e 
opostos à conta.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli allievi affrontano l'emissione di crisi della 
fattura dello schiavo del fuggitivo che ha dato a southerners la 
destra riguadagnare i loro schiavi di instabilità e restituirli a 
bondage. Egualmente è considerata da molti contribuire al 
sectionalism crescente negli STATI UNITI e finalmente la guerra 
civile. Per intraprendere i ruoli degli attori storici, gli 
allievi esamineranno i documenti di origine primari dalla 
documentazione degli argomenti del sud americani della valutazione e 
dell'accumulazione nel favore ed opposti alla fattura.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι σπουδαστές αντιμετωπίζουν το ζήτημα κρίσης του 
σκλάβου Bill προσφύγων που έδωσε στους νοτίους το δικαίωμα να 
επανακτήσει τους σκλάβους δραπέτη τους και να τους επιστρέψει στη 
δουλεία. Θεωρείται επίσης από πολλούς για να έχει 
συμβάλει στην ανάπτυξη του τοπικισμού στις ΗΠΑ και τελικά τον 
εμφύλιο πόλεμο. Προκειμένου να παρθούν οι ρόλοι των 
ιστορικών δραστών, οι σπουδαστές θα εξετάσουν τα αρχικά έγγραφα 
πηγής από την τεκμηρίωση τα αμερικανικά ορίσματα νότιων 
συλλογής και κριτικής υπέρ και που αντιτάσσονται στο Bill.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los estudiantes hacen frente a la aplicación de 
la crisis la cuenta del esclavo del fugitivo que dio a southerners la 
derecha de recuperar sus esclavos del fugitivo y de volverlos al 
bondage. También es considerada por muchos haber contribuido al
sectionalism creciente en los ESTADOS UNIDOS y eventual la guerra 
civil. Para adquirir el papeles de agentes históricos, los 
estudiantes examinarán documentos de fuente primarios de documentar 
los argumentos del sur americanos de la colección y de la crítica en
favor y opuestos a la cuenta.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MEGHAN MCGLINN
FN:MEGHAN MCGLINN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205598</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105125</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/fugitive-slave-law-simulation</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
