<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104132</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104132</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086986</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Massacre at New Orleans .</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Blutbad in New-Orleans.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Massacre à la Nouvelle-Orléans.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O massacre em Nova Orleães.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il massacre a New Orleans.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η σφαγή στη Νέα Ορλεάνη.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Masacre en New Orleans.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The state governments that came to power in the South in 1865 and 1866 passed harsh laws regulating the movement and conditions of work for newly freed slaves. Known as Black Codes, these laws sought to recreate slavery in all but name by preventing blacks from working outside of agriculture and domestic service, limiting their movement, and subjecting those without a contract for employment to arrest and forced labor. Local officials also gave tacit or overt support to intense racist violence. Rioting whites in Memphis killed forty-six African-Americans in May 1866. Two months later, thirty-four blacks and three white supporters were murdered by a white mob in New Orleans. In this picture, Thomas Nast gave his view of Andrew Johnson's role in the July 1866 New Orleans riot.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Zustandregierungen, die kamen, im Süden 1865 und 1866
verabschiedete rauhe Gesetze anzuschalten, welche die Bewegung und die
Zustände der Arbeit für eben freigegebene Sklaven regeln. 
Bekannt als schwarze Codes, suchten diese Gesetze, Sklaverei in 
allen als Namen, indem sie Schwarze am Arbeiten außerhalb von 
Landwirtschaft und des inländischen Services, am Begrenzen ihrer 
Bewegung und am Unterwerfen die ohne einen Vertrag, neu zu erstellen 
verhinderten damit Beschäftigung festhält und erzwangen Arbeit. 
Lokale Beamte gaben auch stillschweigenden oder offenkundigen 
Support zur intensiven rassistischen Gewalttätigkeit. 
Randalierendes Weiß in Memphis beendete forty-six 
Afrikanisch-Amerikaner im Mai 1866. Zwei Monate später, wurden 
thirty-four Schwarze und drei weiße Verfechter von einem weißen 
Pöbel in New-Orleans ermordet. In dieser Abbildung gab Thomas 
Nast seine Ansicht Andrew Johnsons der Rolle im Juli 1866 New-Orleans 
Aufstand.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les gouvernements d'état qui sont venus pour actionner 
dans les Sud en 1865 et 1866 lois dures passées réglant le 
mouvement et les conditions du travail pour les esclaves nouvellement 
libérés. Connu en tant que codes noirs, ces lois ont 
recherché à recréer l'esclavage en tout sauf le nom en empêchant 
des noirs de travailler en dehors de l'agriculture et du service 
domestique, de limiter leur mouvement, et de soumettre ceux sans 
contrat pour que l'emploi arrête et ont forcé le travail. Les 
fonctionnaires locaux ont également donné le support tacite ou 
manifeste à la violence raciste intense. Les blancs s'ameutants
à Memphis ont détruit des Afro-Américains de forty-six en mai 1866. 
Deux mois plus tard, des noirs de thirty-four et trois 
défenseurs blancs ont été assassinés par une foule blanche à la 
Nouvelle-Orléans. Dans cette image, Thomas Nast a donné son 
avis de rôle d'Andrew Johnson dans l'émeute de juillet 1866 la 
Nouvelle-Orléans.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os governos do estado que vieram power no sul em 1865 e 
1866 leis ásperas passadas que regulam o movimento e as condições 
do trabalho para escravos recentemente livrados. Sabido como 
códigos pretos, estas leis procuraram recrear o slavery em tudo com 
exceção do nome impedindo que os pretos trabalhem fora da 
agricultura e do serviço doméstico, limitem seu movimento, e 
sujeitem aqueles sem um contrato para que o emprego prenda e forçaram
o trabalho. Os oficiais locais deram também a sustentação 
tacit ou overt à violência racist intensa. Os brancos 
amotinando-se em Memphis mataram Africano-Americanos do forty-six em 
maio 1866. Dois meses mais tarde, os pretos do thirty-four e 
três supporters brancos foram assassinados por um mob branco em Nova 
Orleães. Neste retrato, Thomas Nast deu sua vista do papel de 
Andrew Johnson no motim de julho 1866 Nova Orleães.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I governi di dichiarare che sono venuto alimentare nel sud
in 1865 e 1866 leggi dure approvate che regolano il movimento e gli 
stati di lavoro per gli schiavi recentemente liberati. 
Conosciuto come codici neri, queste leggi hanno cercato di 
ricreare lo slavery in tutto solo il nome impedendo i neri il 
funzionamento fuori dell'agricoltura e del servizio domestico, 
limitare il loro movimento ed il soggetto dei quelli senza un 
contratto affinchè l'occupazione arrestassero ed hanno forzato il 
lavoro. I funzionari locali egualmente hanno dato il 
supporto tacito o evidente alla violenza razzista intensa. I 
bianchi sollevantesi a Memphis hanno ucciso gli Africano-Americani del
forty-six nel mese di maggio 1866. Due mesi più 
successivamente, i neri del thirty-four e tre sostenitori bianchi sono
stati assassinati da un mob bianco a New Orleans. In questa 
immagine, Thomas Nast ha dato il suo parere del ruolo del Andrew 
Johnson nel tumulto luglio 1866 di New Orleans.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι κρατικές κυβερνήσεις που ήρθαν στην εξουσία στο 
νότο το 1865 και το 1866 πέρασαν τους σκληρούς νόμους που 
ρυθμίζουν τη μετακίνηση και τους όρους της εργασίας για τους 
πρόσφατα ελευθερωμένους σκλάβους. Γνωστοί ως μαύροι 
κώδικες, αυτοί οι νόμοι επιδίωξαν να αναδημιουργήσουν τη σκλαβιά
στο όλο εκτός από το όνομα με την παρεμπόδιση των Μαύρων από 
την εργασία έξω από τη γεωργία και την εσωτερική υπηρεσία, τον 
περιορισμό της μετακίνησής τους, και την υποβολή εκείνων χωρίς 
μια σύμβαση για την απασχόληση στη σύλληψη και την καταναγκαστική 
εργασία. Οι τοπικοί ανώτεροι υπάλληλοι έδωσαν επίσης τη 
σιωπηρή ή προφανή υποστήριξη στην έντονη ρατσιστική βία. 
Τα λευκά στάσης στη Μέμφιδα σκότωσαν σαράντα έξι 
αφρικανικός-Αμερικανούς σε Μάιος 1866, Δύο μήνες 
αργότερα, τριάντα τέσσερις Μαύροι και τρεις λευκοί υποστηρικτές 
δολοφονήθηκαν από έναν λευκό όχλο στη Νέα Ορλεάνη. Σε 
αυτήν την εικόνα, ο Thomas Nast έδωσε την όψη του ρόλου του
Andrew Johnson's στην ταραχή της Νέας Ορλεάνης Ιουλίου 
1866.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los gobiernos del estado que vinieron accionar en el sur 
en 1865 y 1866 leyes ásperos aprobados que regulaban el movimiento y 
las condiciones del trabajo para los esclavos nuevamente liberados. 
Conocido como códigos negros, estos leyes intentaron 
reconstruir esclavitud en todos sino nombre evitando que los negros el
trabajo fuera de agricultura y de servicio doméstico, la limitación 
de su movimiento, y sujeten ésos sin un contrato para que el empleo 
arreste y forzaron el trabajo. Los funcionarios locales también
dieron la ayuda tácita o abierta a la violencia racist intensa. 
Los blancos que se desenfrenaban en Memphis mataron a 
Africano-Americanos del forty-six en mayo de 1866. Dos meses 
más adelante, los negros del thirty-four y tres partidarios blancos 
fueron asesinados por una multitud blanca en New Orleans. En 
este cuadro, Thomas Nast dio su opinión del papel de Andrew Johnson 
en el alboroto de julio 1866 de New Orleans.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086986</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104132</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-massacre-at-new-orleans</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
