<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108753</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108753</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202668</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Reading Guides</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Leseanleitungen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Guides de Lecture</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Guias Da Leitura</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Guide Della Lettura</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οδηγοί ανάγνωσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Guías De la Lectura</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Groups will develop a Reading Guide for each non-fiction resource book for units in science, Social Sciences, and other curriculum areas. Students will identify useful features each book and where the important information will be found. Reviewing non-fiction features of print resources will familiarize the class with material on reserve for the unit. Overviewing and identifying text features will help students determine how to approach the various formats of text relevant to the topic.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gruppen entwickeln eine Leseanleitung für jedes 
Nichterfindung Hilfsmittelbuch für Maßeinheiten in der Wissenschaft,
in den Sozialwissenschaften und in anderen Lehrplanbereichen. 
Kursteilnehmer kennzeichnen nützliche Merkmale jedes Buch und 
wo die wichtigen Informationen gefunden werden. Das Wiederholen 
der Nichterfindung Merkmale der Druckbetriebsmittel macht die 
Kategorie mit Material auf Reserve für die Maßeinheit vertraut. 
Overviewing und das Kennzeichnen der Textmerkmale willen helfen 
Kursteilnehmern, festzustellen, wie man den verschiedenen Formaten des
Textes relevant zum Thema nähert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les groupes développeront un guide de lecture 
pour chaque livre de ressource de non-fiction pour des unités en 
science, sciences sociales, et d'autres zones de programme d'études. 
Les étudiants identifieront les dispositifs utiles chaque livre
et où l'information importante sera trouvée. Passer en revue 
des dispositifs de non-fiction des ressources d'impression 
familiarisera la classe avec le matériel sur la réserve pour 
l'unité. Overviewing et l'identification des dispositifs des 
textes veulent aident des étudiants à déterminer comment approcher 
les divers formats du texte concernant le sujet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os grupos desenvolverão uma guia da leitura para 
cada livro do recurso do non-non-fiction para unidades na ciência, em
ciências sociais, e em outras áreas do curriculum. Os 
estudantes identificarão características úteis cada livro e onde a 
informação importante será encontrada. Rever características
do non-non-fiction de recursos da cópia familiarizará a classe com o
material na reserva para a unidade. Overviewing e identificar 
características do texto querem ajudam a estudantes determinar como 
aproximar os vários formatos do texto relevantes ao tópico.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I gruppi svilupperanno una guida della lettura per
ogni libro delle risorse di non-romanzo per le unità nella scienza, 
nelle scienze sociali ed in altre zone di programma di studi. 
Gli allievi identificheranno le caratteristiche utili ogni libro
e dove le informazioni importanti saranno trovate. La 
riesaminazione delle caratteristiche di non-romanzo delle risorse 
della stampa renderà familiare il codice categoria a materiale sulla 
riserva per l'unità. Overviewing ed identificare le 
caratteristiche del testo vogliono aiutano gli allievi a determinare 
come avvicinarsi ai vari formati di testo relativi al soggetto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι ομάδες θα αναπτύξουν έναν οδηγό ανάγνωσης για 
κάθε non-fiction βιβλίο των στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς για τις 
μονάδες στην επιστήμη, τις κοινωνικές επιστήμες, και άλλες 
περιοχές προγράμματος σπουδών. Οι σπουδαστές θα 
προσδιορίσουν τα χρήσιμα χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα κάθε βιβλίο 
και όπου οι σημαντικές πληροφορίες θα βρεθούν. Non-fiction αναθεώρησης τα χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα των 
έντυπων πηγών θα εξοικειώσουν την κλάση με το υλικό στην 
επιφύλαξη για τη μονάδα. Η επισκόπηση και ο προσδιορισμός 
των χαρακτηριστικών γνωρισμάτων κειμένων θα βοηθήσουν τους 
σπουδαστές να καθορίσουν πώς να πλησιάσουν τις διάφορες μορφές 
του κειμένου σχετικές με το θέμα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los grupos desarrollarán una guía de la lectura 
para cada libro del recurso de la no-ficcio'n para las unidades en 
ciencia, ciencias sociales, y otras áreas del plan de estudios. 
Los estudiantes identificarán características útiles cada 
libro y donde la información importante será encontrada. El 
repaso de características de la no-ficcio'n de los recursos de la 
impresión familiarizará la clase con el material en la reserva para 
la unidad. Overviewing e identificar características del texto 
quieren ayudan a estudiantes a determinarse cómo acercar a los varios
formatos del texto relevantes al asunto.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ELIZABETH HUBBE
FN:ELIZABETH HUBBE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202668</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108753</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/reading-guides</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
