<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107901</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107901</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206428</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Today in History</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Heute in der Geschichte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Aujourd'hui dans l'histoire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Hoje no history</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Oggi nella storia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σήμερα στην ιστορία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Hoy en historia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features a different person or event in history each day. Past features include Frederick Douglass, Woodrow Wilson, George Washington, Abraham Lincoln, Benjamin Banneker, Rosa Parks, Samuel Slater, Louisa May Alcott, Radio City Arts Hall, the Wright brothers' first flight, the Bill of Rights, the Gadsden Purchase, the Federal Reserve System, the Wounded Knee massacre, Pearl Harbor, the first controlled nuclear fission chain reaction, and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">kennzeichnet eine andere Person oder einen Fall in
der Geschichte jeden Tag. Hinter Merkmalen enthalten Sie 
Frederick Douglass, Woodrow Wilson, George Washington, Abraham 
Lincoln, Benjamin Banneker, Rosa Parks, Samuel Slater, Louisa mag 
Alcott, Radiostadt-künste Hall, der Erstflug der Wright Brüder, die 
Verfassung, der Gadsden Erwerb, das Bundesreserve-System, das 
verletzte Knieblutbad, Pearl Harbor, die erste gesteuerte 
Kernspaltungkettenreaktion und mehr.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">comporte une personne ou un événement 
différente dans l'histoire chaque jour. Après des dispositifs 
incluez Frederick Douglass, Woodrow Wilson, George Washington, 
Abraham Lincoln, Benjamin Banneker, parcs de Rosa, couvreur de Samuel,
Louisa peut Alcott, arts par radio Hall, vol des frères de Wright le 
premier, la déclaration des droits, l'achat de Gadsden, le système 
de réserve fédérale, le massacre blessé de genou, port de 
perle, la première réaction en chaîne contrôlée de ville de 
fission nucléaire, et plus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">caracteriza uma pessoa ou um evento diferente no 
history cada dia. Após características inclua Frederick 
Douglass, Woodrow Wilson, George Washington, Abraham Lincoln, Benjamin
Banneker, parques de Rosa, telhador de Samuel, Louisa pode Alcott, 
artes de rádio Salão da cidade, o primeiro vôo dos irmãos de 
Wright, a conta de direitas, a compra de Gadsden, o sistema de reserva
federal, o massacre ferido do joelho, porto de pérola, a primeira 
reação chain controlada de fission nuclear, e mais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">caratterizza una persona o un evento differente 
nella storia ogni giorno. Oltre le caratteristiche includa 
Frederick Douglass, Woodrow Wilson, George Washington, Abraham 
Lincoln, Benjamin Banneker, i parchi del Rosa, lo slater di Samuel, 
Louisa può Alcott, le arti radiofoniche Corridoio, il primo volo dei 
fratelli di Wright, la fattura dei diritti, l'acquisto de Gadsden, il 
sistema di riserva federale, il massacre ferrito del ginocchio, il 
porto di perla, la prima reazione a catena gestita della città di 
fissione nucleare e più.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χαρακτηρίζει ένα διαφορετικό πρόσωπο ή ένα γεγονός 
στην ιστορία κάθε ημέρα. Τα προηγούμενα χαρακτηριστικά 
γνωρίσματα περιλαμβάνουν Frederick Douglass, Woodrow 
Wilson, George Ουάσιγκτον, Abraham Λίνκολν, Benjamin 
Banneker, πάρκα Rosa, Samuel Slater, Louisa Μάιος
Alcott, ραδιο αίθουσα τεχνών πόλεων, η πρώτη πτήση των 
αδελφών Wright, ο Bill των δικαιωμάτων, η αγορά του 
Γκάτσντεν, το σύστημα ομοσπονδιακής επιφύλαξης, η πληγωμένη 
σφαγή γονάτων, λιμάνι μαργαριταριών, η πρώτη μάρτυραη αλυσιδωτή
αντίδραση πυρηνικής διάσπασης, και περισσότερο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece una diversa persona o acontecimiento en 
historia cada día. Más allá de características incluya 
Frederick Douglass, Woodrow Wilson, George Washington, Abraham 
Lincoln, Benjamin Banneker, parques de Rosa, pizarrero de Samuel, 
Louisa puede Alcott, artes de radio Pasillo, el primer vuelo de los 
hermanos de Wright, la cuenta de las derechas, la compra de Gadsden, 
el sistema de reserva federal, la masacre herida de la rodilla, 
puerto de perla, la primera reacción en de la ciudad cadena 
controlada de la fisión nuclear, y más.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206428</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107901</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/today-in-history</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
