<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104760</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104760</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973947</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Physics Games: Liquid Crystals</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Physik-Spiele: Flüssige Kristalle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jeux de Physique : Cristaux Liquides</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogos Da Física: Cristais Líquidos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giochi Di Fisica: Cristalli Liquidi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παιχνίδια φυσικής: Υγρά κρύσταλλα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Juegos De la Física: Cristales Líquidos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Play a game and find out about a Nobel Prize awarded discovery or work! A liquid crystal is a substance that flows like a liquid but maintains some of the ordered structure characteristic of crystals. In the 1960s, a French theoretical physicist, Pierre-Gilles de Gennes turned his interest to liquid crystals and soon found fascinating analogies between liquid crystals and superconductors as well as magnetic materials. His work would later be rewarded with the Nobel Prize in Physics 1991. Today, liquid crystals are found in every home, for example in thermometers and computer screens.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spielen Sie ein Spiel und finden Sie über eine 
zugesprochene Entdeckung oder eine Arbeit des Nobelpreises heraus! 
Ein flüssiger Kristall ist eine Substanz, der Flüsse wie eine 
Flüssigkeit aber etwas von der bestellten Struktur beibehält, die 
von den Kristallen charakteristisch ist. In den sechziger Jahren
drehte ein französischer theoretischer Physiker, Pierre-Gilles de 
Gennes sein Interesse zu den flüssigen Kristallen und fand bald 
faszinierende Analogien zwischen flüssigen Kristallen und 
superconductors sowie magnetische Materialien. Seine Arbeit 
würde später mit dem Nobelpreise in Physik 1991 belohnt. Heute
werden flüssige Kristalle in jedem Haus, z.B. in den Thermometern und
in den Bildschirmen gefunden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jouez un jeu et découvrez au sujet d'une 
découverte ou d'un travail attribuée de prix Nobel ! Un 
cristal liquide est une substance que les écoulements comme un 
liquide mais met à jour une partie de la structure commandée 
caractéristique des cristaux. Dans les années 60, un physicien
théorique français, Pierre-gilles de Gennes a tourné son 
intérêt aux cristaux liquides et a bientôt trouvé des analogies 
fascinantes entre les cristaux et les supraconducteurs liquides aussi bien
que les matériaux magnétiques. Son travail plus tard serait 
récompensé avec le prix Nobel dans la physique 1991. 
Aujourd'hui, des cristaux liquides sont trouvés dans chaque 
maison, par exemple dans les thermomètres et des écrans 
d'ordinateur.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogue um jogo e encontre-o para fora sobre uma 
descoberta ou um trabalho concedido do prêmio de nobel! Um 
cristal líquido é uma substância que os fluxos como um líquido mas
mantenham alguma da estrutura requisitada característica dos 
cristais. Nos 1960s, um físico teórico francês, Pierre-Gilles
de Gennes girou seu interesse para cristais líquidos e encontrou logo
analogias fascinantes entre cristais e superconductors líquidos 
as.well.as materiais magnéticos. Seu trabalho seria 
recompensado mais tarde com o prêmio de nobel na física 1991. 
Hoje, os cristais líquidos são encontrados em cada HOME, para 
o exemplo nos termômetros e nas telas de computador.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gioc un gioco e scopra circa una scoperta o un 
lavoro ricevuta del premio Nobel! Un a cristallo liquido è una 
sostanza che i flussi come un liquido ma effettua alcuna della 
struttura ordinata caratteristica dei cristalli. Negli anni 60, 
un fisico teorico francese, Pierre-Gilles de Gennes ha girato il suo 
interesse verso i cristalli liquidi e presto ha trovato le analogie 
affascinanti fra i cristalli ed i superconductors liquidi così come i
materiali magnetici. Il suo lavoro più successivamente sarebbe 
ricompensato con il premio Nobel nella fisica 1991. Oggi, gli a 
cristallo liquidi sono trovati in ogni sede, per esempio in termometri
e schermi di calcolatore.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παίξτε ένα παιχνίδι και ανακαλύψτε για μια 
απονεμημένη βραβείο ανακάλυψη ή μια εργασία Νόμπελ! Ένα 
υγρό κρύσταλλο είναι μια ουσία που ρέει όπως ένα υγρό αλλά 
διατηρεί μερικών από τη διαταγμένη δομή χαρακτηριστική των 
κρυστάλλων. Στη δεκαετία του '60, ένας γαλλικός θεωρητικός 
φυσικός, Pierre-Gilles de Gennes γύρισε το ενδιαφέρον του 
στα υγρά κρύσταλλα και βρήκε σύντομα τις συναρπαστικές αναλογίες
μεταξύ των υγρών κρυστάλλων και των υπεραγωγών καθώς επίσης και 
των μαγνητικών υλικών. Η εργασία του θα ανταμειβόταν 
αργότερα με το βραβείο Νόμπελ στη φυσική 1991, Σήμερα, 
τα υγρά κρύσταλλα βρίσκονται σε κάθε σπίτι, παραδείγματος χάριν
στα θερμόμετρα και τις οθόνες υπολογιστών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Juegue un juego y descubra sobre un 
descubrimiento o un trabajo concedido del premio Nobel! Un 
cristal líquido es una sustancia que los flujos como un líquido pero
mantienen algo de la estructura pedida característica de cristales. 
En los años 60, un físico teórico francés, Pierre-Gilles de 
Gennes dio vuelta a su interés a los cristales líquidos y pronto 
encontró analogías fascinadoras entre los cristales y los 
superconductors líquidos así como los materiales magnéticos. 
Su trabajo sería recompensado más adelante con el premio Nobel
en la física 1991. Hoy, los cristales líquidos se encuentran 
en cada hogar, por ejemplo en termómetros y pantallas de ordenador.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973947</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104760</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/physics-games-liquid-crystals</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
