<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106701</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106701</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087496</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Come, brothers, you have grown so big you cannot afford to quarrel."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"gekommen, Brüder, sind Sie gewachsen, also groß 
können Sie nicht sich leisten zu streiten."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"venu, des frères, vous vous êtes développé si 
grand vous ne pouvez pas vous permettre de vous disputer."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"vindo, irmãos, você cresceu assim que grande 
você não pode ter recursos para discutir."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"venuto, i fratelli, vi siete sviluppati così 
grande non potete permettersi di quarrel."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ελάτε, αδελφοί, έχετε αυξηθεί τόσο μεγάλο εσείς 
δεν μπορείτε να αντέξετε οικονομικά να μαλώσετε."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"venido, los hermanos, usted ha crecido así que 
grande usted no puede permitirse pelear."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">William A. Rogers depicts Capital and Labor as evenly matchedwith Commerce a beleaguered refereeon a 1901 cover of  Harper's Weekly . Variations on this theme frequently appeared in the Progressive Era's mainstream press. Commerce alternated with other allegorical figures like the nation" or the "public</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">William A. Rogers stellt Haupt- und Arbeits als 
gleichmäßig matchedwith Handel ein belagertes refereeon eine 
Abdeckung 1901 von Wochenzeitung Harpers bildlich dar. Varianten
auf diesem Thema erschienen häufig in der progressiven 
Hauptströmungspresse der Ära. Handel wechselte mit anderen 
allegorischen Abbildungen wie der Nation "oder der" Öffentlichkeit</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">William A. Rogers dépeint capital et de travail en tant 
qu'également commerce de matchedwith un refereeon cerné une 
couverture 1901 de l'hebdomadaire de Harper. Les variations sur 
ce thème sont fréquemment apparues dans la presse traditionnelle de 
l'ère progressive. Le commerce a alterné avec d'autres figures
allégoriques comme la nation "ou" le public</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">William A. Rogers descreve importante e labor como 
uniformente o comércio do matchedwith um refereeon beleaguered uma 
tampa 1901 do semanário de Harper. As variações neste tema 
apareceram freqüentemente na imprensa mainstream da era progressiva. 
O comércio alternou com outras figuras allegorical como a 
nação "ou" o público</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">William A. Rogers descrive uniformemente capitale ed il 
Lavoro come commercio del matchedwith un refereeon assillato una 
copertura 1901 del settimanale del Harper. Le variazioni su 
questo tema sono comparso frequentemente nella pressa tradizionale 
dell'era progressiva. Il commercio si è alternato con altre 
figure allegoriche come la nazione "o" il pubblico</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θ*Ωηλληαμ A. Rogers απεικονίζει το κεφάλαιο και 
την εργασία ως matchedwith ομοιόμορφα εμπόριο ένα 
πολιορκούμενο refereeon μια κάλυψη του 1901 της εβδομαδιαίας 
έκδοσης Harper. Οι παραλλαγές σε αυτό το θέμα συχνά 
εμφανίζομαι στον επικρατόντα Τύπο της προοδευτικής εποχής. 
Το εμπόριο εναλλάχτηκε με άλλους αλληγορικούς αριθμούς 
όπως το έθνος "ή το" κοινό</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Guillermo A. Rogers representa capital y de trabajo como 
uniformemente comercio del matchedwith un refereeon cercado una 
cubierta 1901 del semanario de Harper. Las variaciones en este 
tema aparecieron con frecuencia en la prensa de corriente de la era 
progresiva. El comercio se alternó con otras figuras 
alegóricas como la nación "o" el público</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087496</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106701</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/come-brothers-you-have-grown-so-big-you-cannot-afford-to-quarrel</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
