<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108274</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108274</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086679</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Not Rum but Righteousness": Billy Sunday Attacks Booze</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"nicht Rum aber Righteousness": Billy Sonntag
Nimmt Schnäpse In Angriff</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"pas rhum mais Droiture" : Billy 
Dimanche Attaque des Boissons alcoolisées</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"não rum mas Righteousness": O Billy 
Domingo Ataca Bebidas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"non rum ma Righteousness": Il Billy 
Domenica Attaca Le Bevande</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Όχι ρούμι αλλά ευθύτητα": Θ*Ψηλλυ Sunday 
Attacks Booze</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"no ron sino Righteousness": El Billy 
Domingo Ataca Los Licores</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Urban as well as rural Americans flocked to fundamentalist and evangelical churches in the 1920s. Preaching tradition and timeless value, American evangelicals adopted innovative techniques for spreading their message. Billy Sunday, the most famous preacher of the early 20th century, began his career as a professional baseball player. He emphasized a rugged, swaggering, masculine Christianity spoken in plain, slangy English. Widely regarded as the model for novelist Sinclair Lewis's  Elmer Gantry,  he combined the modern and the traditional in attacks on liquor, like this excerpt from one of Sunday's sermons. Sunday denounced the government's attempt to regulate and tax liquor as immoral. In his famously forceful and slangy style, he insisted that America needed God, not liquor.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Städtisch sowie landwirtschaftliche Amerikaner 
scharte sich zu fundamentalistischem und evangelische Kirchen in den 
zwanziger Jahren, die Tradition und zeitlosen Wert, amerikanische 
evangelicals predigen, nahmen erfinderische Techniken für das 
Verbreiten ihrer Meldung an. Billy Sonntag, der berühmteste 
Prediger des frühen 20. Jahrhunderts, fing seine Karriere als 
professioneller Baseballspieler an. Er hob ein schroffes hervor,
swaggering, das männliche Christentum, das in der Ebene, slangy 
Englisch gesprochen wurde. Weit betrachtet als das Modell für 
Novelist Sinclair Lewiss Elmer Bock, kombinierte er das moderne und 
das traditionelle in den Angriffen auf Alkohol, wie diesem Excerpt von
einer von Predigten Sonntags. Sonntag kündigte den Versuch der 
Regierung, Alkohol zu regeln und zu besteuern, wie unmoralisch. 
In seiner berühmt starken und slangy Art beharrte er dieses 
Amerika benötigter Gott, nicht Alkohol.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Urbain aussi bien que les Américains ruraux s'est
assemblé à fondamentaliste et les églises évangéliques dans les 
années 20 prêchant la tradition et la valeur intemporelle, des 
evangelicals américains ont adopté des techniques innovatrices pour 
écarter leur message. Billy dimanche, le prédicateur le 
plus célèbre du début du 20ème siècle, a commencé sa carrière 
en tant que joueur professionnel de base-ball. Il a souligné un
raboteux, se vantant, christianisme masculin parlé en plaine, 
l'anglais en jargon. Largement considéré comme modèle pour
le portique d'Elmer de Sinclair Lewis de romancier, il a combiné le 
moderne et le traditionnel dans les attaques sur la boisson 
alcoolisée, comme cet extrait d'un des sermons de dimanche. 
Dimanche a dénoncé la tentative du gouvernement de régler et 
imposer la boisson alcoolisée comme immorale. Dans son modèle 
célèbre puissant et en jargon, il a exigé la cette Amérique 
Dieu nécessaire, pas boisson alcoolisée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Urbano as.well.as americanos rurais reuniu-se a 
fundamentalista e as igrejas evangelical nos 1920s. que preaching a 
tradição e o valor timeless, evangelicals americanos adotaram 
técnicas inovativas para espalhar sua mensagem. O billy 
domingo, preacher o mais famoso do 20o século adiantado, começou sua
carreira como um jogador profissional do baseball. Emfatizou um 
áspero, swaggering, christianity masculine falado na planície, 
inglês slangy. Considerado extensamente como o modelo para o 
gantry de Elmer de Sinclair Lewis do novelist, combinou o moderno e o 
tradicional nos ataques no licor, como este excerpt de um de sermons 
de domingo. Domingo denounced a tentativa do governo de regular 
e tax o licor como immoral. Em seu estilo famosa forceful e 
slangy, insistiu essa América deus necessitado, não licor.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Urbano così come gli Americani rurali si è 
affollato al fondamentalista e le chiese evangelical negli anni 20 che 
predicano la tradizione ed il valore timeless, evangelicals americani 
hanno adottato le tecniche innovarici per la diffusione del loro 
messaggio. Il billy domenica, il preacher più famoso di inizio 
del 20esimo secolo, ha cominciato la sua carriera come giocatore 
professionale di baseball. Ha dato risalto ad un robusto, 
swaggering, christianity maschile parlato in pianura, inglese slangy. 
Ampiamente considerato il modello per la cavalletto di Elmer di 
Sinclair Lewis del romanziere, ha unito il moderno ed il tradizionale
negli attacchi a liquore, come questo brano da uno dei sermons della 
domenica. Domenica ha denunciato il tentativo del governo di 
regolare e tassare il liquore come immorale. Nel suo stile 
famoso valido e slangy, ha insistito la quell'America dio stato 
necessario, non liquore.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αστικοί καθώς επίσης και αγροτικοί Αμερικανοί 
συγκεντρώθηκαν στις θεμελιωτούσες και εβαγγελικές εκκλησίες στη 
δεκαετία του '20 που κηρύσσει την παράδοση και η άχρονη αξία, 
αμερικανικά evangelicals υιοθέτησε τις καινοτόμες τεχνικές για 
το μήνυμά τους. Ο Billy Sunday, ο διασημότερος 
ιεροκήρυκας του πρόωρου 20ού αιώνα, άρχισε τη σταδιοδρομία του 
ως επαγγελματικό φορέα μπέιζ-μπώλ. Υπογράμμισε έναν 
τραχύ, καυχησιάρη, αρσενικό χριστιανισμό προφορικό στα σαφή, 
slangy αγγλικά. Ευρέως θεωρημένος ως μοντέλο για τον 
ατσάλινο σκελετό Elmer Sinclair Lewis μυθιστοριογράφων, 
συνδύασε σύγχρονο και τον παραδοσιακό στις επιθέσεις στο ποτό, 
όπως αυτό το απόσπασμα από ένα από τα κηρύγματα της Κυριακής. 
Η Κυριακή κατήγγειλε την κυβερνητική προσπάθεια να ρυθμίσει
και το φορολογικό ποτό όπως ανήθικο. Στο περίφημα ισχυρό 
και slangy ύφος του, επέμεινε ότι η Αμερική χρειάστηκε το 
Θεό, όχι ποτό.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Urbano así como americanos rurales se reunió a 
fundamentalista y las iglesias evangélicas en los años 20 que 
predicaban la tradición y el valor intemporal, los evangelicals 
americanos adoptaron las técnicas innovadoras para separar su 
mensaje. El billy domingo, el predicador más famoso del 
vigésimo siglo temprano, comenzó su carrera como jugador profesional
del béisbol. Él acentuó un rugoso, swaggering, cristianismo 
masculino hablado en llano, inglés slangy. Mirado extensamente 
como el modelo para el pórtico de Elmer de Sinclair Lewis del 
novelista, él combinó el moderno y el tradicional en ataques contra 
el licor, como este extracto a partir del uno de los sermones de 
domingo. Domingo denunci la tentativa del gobierno de regular y 
de gravar el licor como inmoral. En su estilo famoso poderoso y 
slangy, él insistió esa América dios necesitado, no licor.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086679</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108274</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/not-rum-but-righteousness-billy-sunday-attacks-booze</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
