<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104689</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104689</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203139</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Hot Colors- Windows into Hidden Worlds</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Heiße Farben Windows in versteckte Welten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Couleurs chaudes Windows aux mondes cachés</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Cores quentes Windows em mundos escondidos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Colori caldi Windows nei mondi nascosti</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Καυτά χρώματα - Windows στους κρυμμένους κόσμους</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Colores calientes Windows en los mundos ocultados</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This website contains an electronic field trip based on Yellowstone National Park's hot springs and the microorganisms living in them. The site includes a link for teachers providing an introduction, overview of concepts explored in the trip, lesson plans, and additional web links. The electronic field trip may be viewed in a low bandwidth version without downloading. For a high bandwith version of the field trip, Macromedia Flash Player is required and can be downloaded on site. Further information on system requirements and field trip procedures are outlined on the website as well.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Web site enthält ein elektronisches 
auffangen die Reise, die auf Yellowstone Nationalpark heißen
Frühlingen und den Mikroorganismen leben in ihnen basiert. Die 
Site schließt ein Link für die Lehrer ein, die eine Einleitung, 
Überblick über die Konzepte zur Verfügung stellen, die in der Reise
erforscht werden, Lektionpläne und zusätzliche Web-Links. Die 
elektronischen fangen Reise können in einer niedrigen 
Bandweiteversion angesehen werden auf, ohne zu downloaden. Für 
eine hohe bandwith Version der auffangenreise, Macromedia wird 
greller Spieler benoetigt und kann auf Site downloadet werden. 
Weitere Informationen über System Anforderungen und 
fangen Reiseprozeduren werden umrissen auf der Web site 
außerdem auf.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site Web contient un voyage de zone 
électronique basé sur les ressorts chauds et les micro-organismes de
parc national de Yellowstone vivant dans eux. Le site inclut un 
lien pour des professeurs fournissant une introduction, la vue 
d'ensemble des concepts explorés dans le voyage, les plans de leçon,
et les liens supplémentaires de Web. Le voyage de zone 
électronique peut être visualisé dans une basse version de largeur 
de bande sans téléchargement. Pour une version élevée de 
bandwith du voyage de zone, le joueur instantané de Macromedia est 
prié et peut être téléchargé sur le site. Davantage 
d'information sur des conditions de système et des procédures de 
voyage de zone sont aussi bien tracées les grandes lignes sur le site
Web.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Web site contem um desengate de campo 
eletrônico baseado nas molas quentes e nos microorganisms de parque 
nacional de Yellowstone que vivem neles. O local inclui uma 
ligação para os professores que fornecem uma introdução, a vista 
geral dos conceitos explorados no desengate, as plantas da lição, e 
as ligações adicionais do Web. O desengate de campo 
eletrônico pode ser visto em uma versão baixa da largura de faixa 
sem downloading. Para uma versão elevada do bandwith do 
desengate de campo, o jogador flash de Macromedia é requerido e pode 
downloaded no local. Uma informação mais adicional em 
exigências do sistema e os procedimentos do desengate de campo são 
esboçados no Web site também.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Web site contiene un viaggio di campo 
elettronico basato sulle molle calde e sui microorganismi del parco 
nazionale di Yellowstone che vivono in loro. Il luogo include un
collegamento per gli insegnanti che forniscono un'introduzione, la 
descrizione dei concetti esplorati nel viaggio, i programmi di lezione
ed i collegamenti supplementari di Web. Il viaggio di campo 
elettronico può essere osservato in una versione bassa di larghezza 
di banda senza trasferire. Per un'alta versione del bandwith del
viaggio di campo, il giocatore istantaneo di Macromedia è richiesto e
può essere trasferito sul luogo. Ulteriori informazioni sui 
requisiti del sistema e le procedure di viaggio di campo sono 
descritte sul Web site pure.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος περιέχει ένα ηλεκτρονικό ταξίδι 
πεδίων βασισμένο στα καυτά ελατήρια του εθνικού πάρκου 
Yellowstone και τους μικροοργανισμούς ζωντανός σε τους. Η 
περιοχή περιλαμβάνει μια σύνδεση για τους δασκάλους που παρέχουν 
μια εισαγωγή, την επισκόπηση των εννοιών που εξερευνιούνται στο 
ταξίδι, τα σχέδια μαθήματος, και τις πρόσθετες συνδέσεις Ιστού. 
Το ηλεκτρονικό ταξίδι πεδίων μπορεί να εμφανιστεί σε μια 
χαμηλή έκδοση εύρους ζώνης χωρίς μεταφόρτωση. Για μια 
υψηλή έκδοση bandwith του ταξιδιού πεδίων, ο φορέας λάμψης 
Macromedia απαιτείται και μπορεί να μεταφορτωθεί στην περιοχή. 
Οι συμπληρωματικές πληροφορίες για τις απαιτήσεις συστημάτων
και οι διαδικασίες ταξιδιού πεδίων περιγράφονται στον ιστοχώρο 
επίσης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este Web site contiene un disparo al campo 
electrónico basado en los resortes calientes y los microorganismos 
del parque nacional de Yellowstone que viven en ellos. El sitio 
incluye una conexión para los profesores que proporcionan a una 
introducción, a la descripción de los conceptos explorados en el 
viaje, a planes de la lección, y a conexiones adicionales del Web. 
El disparo al campo electrónico se puede ver en una versión 
baja de la anchura de banda sin descargar. Para una alta 
versión del bandwith del disparo al campo, requieren y puede ser 
descargado al jugador de destello de Macromedia en sitio. La 
información adicional sobre requisitos del sistema y los 
procedimientos del disparo al campo se contornean en el Web site 
también.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:THERMAL BIOLOGY INSTITUTE NATIONAL SCIENCE FOUNDATION
FN:THERMAL BIOLOGY INSTITUTE NATIONAL SCIENCE FOUNDATION
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:YELLOWSTONE PARK FOUNDATION
FN:YELLOWSTONE PARK FOUNDATION
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203139</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104689</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/hot-colors-windows-into-hidden-worlds</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
