<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104465</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104465</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207081</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The People... Native Americans</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Leute... Gebürtige Amerikaner</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Peuple... Américains Indigènes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os Povos... Americanos Nativos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Gente... Americani Natali</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι άνθρωποι... Εγγενείς Αμερικανοί</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Gente... Americanos Nativos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">offers more than 30 collections of photos, essays, and other resources for learning about American Indians. Topics include daily life for Native American women in the late 1800s, the Wounded Knee Massacre, Custer's Last Stand, and Pocahontas. Resources include a tribe locator, recordings of Native American music, and an exhibit of flutes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">bietet mehr als 30 Ansammlungen Fotos, Versuche und
andere Betriebsmittel für das Lernen über Indianer an. Themen 
schließen tägliche Lebensdauer für gebürtige amerikanische Frauen 
im späten 1800s, im verletzten Knie-Blutbad, Custers im letzten 
Standplatz und in Pocahontas ein. Betriebsmittel schließen ein 
Stammverzeichnis, Aufnahmen der gebürtigen amerikanischen Musik und 
eine Ausstellung der Flöten ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">offre plus de 30 collections de photos, d'essais, 
et d'autres ressources pour se renseigner sur des Indiens d'Amerique. 
Les sujets incluent la vie quotidienne pour les femmes 
américaines indigènes vers la fin de 1800s, du Massacre blessé 
de genou, stand de Custer du dernier, et du Pocahontas. Les 
ressources incluent un repère de tribu, des enregistrements de la 
musique américaine indigène, et un objet exposé des cannelures.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">oferece mais de 30 coleções das fotos, dos 
essays, e dos outros recursos para aprender sobre indians americanos. 
Os tópicos incluem a vida diária para mulheres americanas 
nativas no 1800s atrasado, no massacre ferido do joelho, carrinho de 
Custer no último, e no Pocahontas. Os recursos incluem um 
localizador do tribe, gravações da música americana nativa, e uma 
exibição das flautas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">offre più di 30 collezioni di foto, di saggi e di
altre risorse per imparare circa gli indiani americani. I 
soggetti includono la vita quotidiana per le donne americane natali 
verso la fine di 1800s, del massacre ferrito del ginocchio, basamento 
del Custer di ultimo e di Pocahontas. Le risorse includono un 
indicatore di posizione della tribù, le registrazioni di musica 
americana natale e un'esposizione delle scanalature.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">προσφέρει περισσότερες από 30 συλλογές των 
φωτογραφιών, των δοκίμιων, και άλλων στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς για 
την εκμάθηση για αμερικανικούς Ινδούς. Τα θέματα 
περιλαμβάνουν την καθημερινή ζωή για τις εγγενείς αμερικανικές 
γυναίκες προς το τέλος 1800s, της πληγωμένης σφαγής γονάτων, 
της τελευταίας στάσης Custer, και του Pocahontas. Τα 
στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς περιλαμβάνουν έναν εντοπιστή φυλών, τις 
καταγραφές της εγγενούς αμερικανικής μουσικής, και ένα έκθεμα 
των φλαούτων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece más de 30 colecciones de fotos, de 
ensayos, y de otros recursos para aprender sobre indios americanos. 
Los asuntos incluyen la vida de cada día para las mujeres 
americanas nativas en el último 1800s, la Masacre herida de la 
rodilla, el soporte pasado de Custer, y Pocahontas. Los recursos
incluyen un localizador de la tribu, grabaciones de la música 
americana nativa, y un objeto expuesto de flautas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207081</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104465</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-people-native-americans</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
