<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108768</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108768</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213221</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Worldwatch Institute Homepage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Worldwatch Institut-Homepage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Homepage d'Institut de Worldwatch</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Homepage Do Instituto De Worldwatch</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Homepage Dell'Istituto Di Worldwatch</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αρχική σελίδα ιδρύματος Worldwatch</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Homepage Del Instituto De Worldwatch</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Worldwatch Institute offers a unique blend of interdisciplinary research, global focus, and accessible writing making it a good source of information on the interactions among key environmental, social, and economic trends. Worldwatch's work revolves around the transition to an environmentally sustainable and socially just society - and how to achieve it. From their homepage, users can follow links to publications, a resource center, Worldwatch Live, a press room and research information.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Worldwatch Institut bietet eine eindeutige 
Mischung der interdisziplinären Forschung, des globalen Fokus und des
zugänglichen Schreibens, das es eine gute Quelle von den 
Informationen auf den Interaktionen unter Schlüsselklima-, Sozial- 
und ökonomischen Tendenzen bildet an. Arbeit Worldwatchs 
rotiert um den Übergang zu einer umweltsmäßig stützbaren und 
sozial gerechten Gesellschaft - und wie man sie erzielt. Von 
ihrem homepage können Benutzer Links zu den Publikationen, zu einer 
Hilfsmittelmitte, zu Phasen Worldwatch, zu einem Presseraum und zu 
Forschung Informationen folgen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'institut de Worldwatch offre un seul mélange de
recherche interdisciplinaire, de foyer global, et d'écriture 
accessible lui faisant une bonne source de l'information sur les 
interactions parmi les tendances environnementales, sociales, et 
économiques principales. Le travail de Worldwatch tourne autour
de la transition à une société dans l'environnement soutenable et 
socialement juste - et comment la réaliser. De leur homepage, 
les utilisateurs peuvent suivre des liens aux publications, à un 
centre de ressource, à Worldwatch de phase, à une salle de presse et
à une information de recherches.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O instituto de Worldwatch oferece uma mistura 
original da pesquisa interdisciplinary, do foco global, e da escrita 
acessível que faz lhe uma fonte boa da informação nas interações 
entre as tendências ambientais, sociais, e econômicas chaves. 
O trabalho de Worldwatch revolve em torno da transição a uma 
sociedade ambiental sustainable e social justa - e como consegui-la. 
De seu homepage, os usuários podem seguir as ligações às 
publicações, a um centro do recurso, a Worldwatch vivo, a um quarto 
da imprensa e a uma informação da pesquisa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'istituto di Worldwatch offre una miscela unica 
di ricerca interdisciplinare, del fuoco globale e della scrittura 
accessibile gli che rende una buona sorgente delle informazioni sulle 
interazioni fra le congiunture ambientali, sociali e chiave. Il 
lavoro del Worldwatch gira intorno alla transizione ad una società in
condizioni ambientali sostenibile e socialmente giusta - e come 
realizzarla. Dal loro homepage, gli utenti possono seguire i 
collegamenti alle pubblicazioni, ad un centro delle risorse, a 
Worldwatch in tensione, ad una stanza della pressa ed alle 
informazioni di ricerca.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το ίδρυμα Worldwatch προσφέρει ένα μοναδικό μίγμα 
της διεπιστημονικής έρευνας, της σφαιρικής εστίασης, και του 
προσιτού γραψίματος κάνοντας το μια καλή πηγή πληροφοριών για 
τις αλληλεπιδράσεις μεταξύ των βασικών περιβαλλοντικών, 
κοινωνικών, και οικονομικών τάσεων. Η εργασία του 
Worldwatch περιστρέφεται γύρω από τη μετάβαση περιβαλλοντικά 
σε έναν βιώσιμο και κοινωνικά ακριβώς μια κοινωνία - και πώς να 
τον επιτύχει. Από την αρχική σελίδα τους, οι χρήστες 
μπορούν να ακολουθήσουν τις συνδέσεις με τις δημοσιεύσεις, ένα 
κέντρο των στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς, Worldwatch ζωντανά, ένα 
δωμάτιο Τύπου και ερευνητικές πληροφορίες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El instituto de Worldwatch ofrece una mezcla 
única de la investigación interdisciplinaria, del foco global, y de 
la escritura accesible que le hace una buena fuente de la información
en las interacciones entre las tendencias ambientales, sociales, y 
económicas dominantes. El trabajo de Worldwatch gira alrededor 
de la transición a una sociedad ambientalmente sostenible y social 
justa - y cómo alcanzarla. De su homepage, los utilizadores 
pueden seguir conexiones a publicaciones, a un centro del recurso, a 
Worldwatch vivo, a un cuarto de la prensa y a una información de la 
investigación.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213221</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108768</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/worldwatch-institute-homepage</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
