<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106416</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106416</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086829</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Shying Away: Labor Leaders Steer Clear of the Farmers' Alliance</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Shying Weg: Gewerkschaftsführer steuern 
klar vom Bündnis der Landwirte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Lancement Loin : Les dirigeants syndicaux 
orientent clairement de l'alliance des fermiers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Recuar Afastado: Os líderes labor dirigem 
claramente do alliance dos fazendeiros</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lancio Via: I Capi di lavoro 
dirigono chiaramente dell'alleanza dei coltivatori</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Να ρίξει μακριά: Οι ηγέτες εργασίας οδηγούν 
σαφή της συμμαχίας των αγροτών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Arrojar Lejos: Los arranques de cinta de 
trabajo dirigen claramente de la alianza de los granjeros</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1892 the possibility of a Labor-Populist alliance circulated. Populist orators like Mary Lease sought to build ties between the Farmer's Alliance and the labor movement by mobilizing farmers to send wheat and corn to striking workers at Carnegie's Homestead mill. Top labor leaders like Samuel Gompers did not respond to Lease's and other Populist leaders' overtures. Gompers's opposition to labor support for Populism was part of his broader reluctance to entangle the labor movement in any political alliance or in political action at all. Despite Gompers's opposition, the 1892 AFL convention did endorse the Populist calls for initiative, referendum, and government ownership of the telephone and telegraph system as well as a campaign to increase trade unions' political activities. In 1896 there was renewed pressure for the AFL to endorse the combined Democratic-Populist ticket headed by William Jennings Bryan. Gompers sought to meet that pressure with this circular to "affiliated unions," which argued against allying with the Populist Party.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In 1892 verteilte die Möglichkeit eines 
BearbeitenVolksbündnisses. Volksredner wie Mary Miete suchten, 
Gleichheit zwischen dem Bündnis des Landwirts und der 
Arbeiterbewegung durch mobilisierende Landwirte aufzubauen, um Weizen 
und Mais am Gehöfttausendstel Carnegies zu schicken auffallenden 
Arbeitern. Obere Gewerkschaftsführer wie Samuel Gompers 
reagierten nicht auf Annäherungsversuche der Miete und anderer 
Volksführer. Die Opposition Gomperss, zum des Supports für 
Populismus zu bearbeiten war ein Teil seiner ausgedehnteren 
Abneigung, zum der Arbeiterbewegung in jedem politischen Bündnis oder
in der politischen Tätigkeit an allen zu verwickeln. Trotz der 
Opposition Gomperss indossierte die 1892 AFL Versammlung die 
Volksaufrufe für Initiative, Referendum und Regierung Besitz des 
Telefon- und Fernschreibersystems sowie eine Kampagne, um politische 
Aktivitäten der Gewerkschaften zu erhöhen. 1896 gab es 
erneuerten Druck, damit das AFL die kombinierte DemokratischVolkskarte
indossiert, die von William Jennings Bryan vorangegangen wird. 
Gompers suchte, diesen Druck mit diesem Rundschreiben 
"angeschlossene Anschlüße zu treffen,", das gegen das Verbinden mit 
der VolksPartei argumentierte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans 1892 la possibilité d'une alliance 
Travailler-Populiste a circulé. Les orateurs populistes comme 
le bail de Mary ont recherché à construire des cravates entre 
l'alliance du fermier et le mouvement de travail par les fermiers de 
mobilisation pour envoyer le blé et le maïs aux ouvriers saisissants
au moulin de la ferme de Carnegie's. Les dirigeants syndicaux 
supérieurs comme Samuel Gompers n'ont pas répondu aux ouverture du 
bail et d'autres amorces populistes. L'opposition de Gompers 
pour travailler le soutien du Populisme faisait partie de sa plus 
large hésitation pour empêtrer le mouvement de travail dans 
n'importe quelle alliance politique ou dans l'action politique du 
tout. En dépit de l'opposition de Gompers, la convention de 
1892 AFL a approuvé les appels populistes pour l'initiative, le 
référendum, et la propriété de gouvernement du système de 
téléphone et de télégraphe aussi bien qu'une campagne pour 
augmenter les activités politiques des syndicats. En 1896 il y 
avait pression remplacée pour que l'AFL approuve le billet 
Démocratique-Populiste combiné dirigé par William Jennings Bryan. 
Gompers a recherché à rencontrer cette pression avec cette 
circulaire "syndicats filiales," qui a discuté contre s'allier avec 
la partie populiste.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1892 a possibilidade de um alliance 
Trabalh-labor-Populist circulou. Os orators populist como o 
aluguer de Mary procuraram construir laços entre o alliance do 
fazendeiro e o movimento labor por fazendeiros mobilizing para emitir 
o trigo e o milho aos trabalhadores impressionantes no moinho do 
homestead de Carnegie. Os líderes labor superiores como Samuel 
Gompers não responderam às insinuação do aluguer e de outros 
líderes populist. A oposição de Gompers para trabalhar a 
sustentação para Populism era parte de sua relutância mais larga 
para entangle o movimento labor em todo o alliance político ou na 
ação política em tudo. Apesar da oposição de Gompers, a 
convenção de 1892 AFL endossou os atendimentos populist para a 
iniciativa, o referendum, e a posse do governo do sistema do telefone 
e do telégrafo as.well.as uma campanha para aumentar atividades 
políticas de uniões de comércio. Em 1896 havia uma pressão 
renovada para que o AFL endosse o bilhete 
Democrático-democratic-Populist combinado dirigido por William 
Jennings Bryan. Gompers procurou encontrar-se com essa pressão 
com esta circular "uniões affiliated," que discutiu de encontro a se 
aliar com o partido populist.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1892 la possibilità di alleanza di 
lavoro-populist ha circolato. I orators populistici come il 
contratto d'affitto della Mary hanno cercato di costruire i legami fra
l'alleanza del coltivatore ed il movimento di lavoro dai coltivatori 
di mobilitazione per trasmettere il frumento ed il cereale agli operai
notevoli al laminatoio della fattoria del Carnegie. I 
capi di lavoro superiori come Samuel Gompers non hanno 
risposto ai overtures capi populistici di altri e del 
contratto d'affitto '. L'opposizione del Gompers a sostegno 
di lavoro Populism faceva parte della sua più vasta riluttanza per 
impigliare il movimento di lavoro in tutta l'alleanza politica o 
nell'azione politica affatto. Malgrado opposizione del Gompers, 
la convenzione di 1892 AFL ha firmato le richieste populistiche per 
iniziativa, il referendum e la proprietà di governo del sistema del 
telegrafo e del telefono così come una campagna per aumentare le 
attività politiche dei sindacati. In 1896 ci era pressione 
rinnovata affinchè il AFL firmi il biglietto Democratico-Populistico 
unito diretto da William Jennings Bryan. Gompers ha cercato di 
venire a contatto di quella pressione con questa circonvallazione 
"sindacati affiliated," che ha parlato contro allearsi con il partito 
populistico.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1892 η δυνατότητα μιας εργασία-λαϊκιστικής 
συμμαχίας που κυκλοφορούν. Οι λαϊκιστικοί ομιλητές όπως 
Mary Lease επιδίωξαν να χτίσουν τους δεσμούς μεταξύ της 
συμμαχίας του αγρότη και η μετακίνηση εργασίας με να 
κινητοποιήσει τους αγρότες για να στείλει το σίτο και το 
καλαμπόκι στους απεργούς εργαζομένους στους κορυφαίους ηγέτες 
εργασίας εκατομμυρίου αγροτικών σπιτιών Carnegie όπως το 
Samuel Gompers δεν αποκρίθηκε στα overtures της μίσθωσης 
και άλλων λαϊκιστικών ηγετών. Η αντίθεση του Gompers 
στην υποστήριξη εργασίας για το λαϊκισμό ήταν μέρος της 
ευρύτερης απροθυμίας του να μπλέξει τη μετακίνηση εργασίας σε 
οποιαδήποτε πολιτική συμμαχία ή στην πολιτική ενέργεια καθόλου 
όλες. Παρά την αντίθεση Gompers, η σύμβαση 1892 AFL
επικύρωσε τις λαϊκιστικές κλήσεις για την πρωτοβουλία, το 
δημοψήφισμα, και την κυβερνητική ιδιοκτησία του συστήματος 
τηλεφώνων και τηλέγραφων καθώς επίσης και μια εκστρατεία για να 
αυξήσει τις πολιτικές δραστηριότητες των συνδικάτων. Το 
1896 υπήρξε ανανεωμένη πίεση για το AFL να επικυρωθεί το 
συνδυασμένο δημοκρατικός-λαϊκιστικό εισιτήριο που διευθύνθηκε 
από William Jennings Bryan. Το Gompers επιδίωξε να
συναντηθεί ότι πίεση με αυτήν την εγκύκλιο στις "συμβεβλημένες 
ενώσεις," που μίλησαν ενάντια στη σύνδεση με το λαϊκιστικό 
συμβαλλόμενο μέρος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1892 la posibilidad de una alianza 
Trabajar-Populista circuló. Los oradores populistas como el 
arriendo de Maria intentaron construir lazos entre la alianza del 
granjero y el movimiento de trabajo por los granjeros de movilización
para enviar trigo y maíz a los trabajadores llamativos en el molino 
de la granja de Carnegie. Los arranques de cinta de trabajo 
superiores como Samuel Gompers no respondieron a las insinuaciónes 
del arriendo y de otros arranques de cinta populistas. La 
oposición de Gompers para trabajar la ayuda para el Populismo era 
parte de su repugnancia más amplia para enredar el movimiento de 
trabajo en cualquier alianza política o en la acción política en 
todos. A pesar de la oposición de Gompers, la convención de 
1892 AFL endosó las llamadas populistas para la iniciativa, el 
referéndum, y la propiedad del gobierno del sistema del teléfono y 
del telégrafo así como una campaña para aumentar las actividades 
políticas de los sindicatos. En 1896 había presión renovada 
para que el AFL endose el boleto Democra'tico-Populista combinado 
dirigido por Guillermo Jennings Bryan. Gompers intentó resolver
esa presión con esta circular "uniones afiliadas," que discutió 
contra aliarse con el partido populista.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086829</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106416</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/shying-away-labor-leaders-steer-clear-of-the-farmers-alliance</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
