<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107247</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107247</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206783</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Attu: North American Battleground of World War II</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Attu: Nordamerikanisches Schlachtfeld des 
Zweiten Weltkrieges</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Attu : Champs de bataille américain 
du nord de la deuxième guerre mondiale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Attu: Battleground norte-americano da 
segunda guerra mundial</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Attu: Battleground nordamericano della 
seconda guerra mondiale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Attu: Βορειοαμερικανικό πεδίο μάχης του 
παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Attu: Campo de batalla norteamericano de la 
Segunda Guerra Mundial</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is the site of the only land battle on the North American continent during World War II. In June 1942, Japanese forces invaded Attu and other Aleautian islands. Americans feared the islands would be used as a staging area to attack the mainland. The U.S. had to regain the Aleutians at all costs.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist die Site der einzigen Landschlacht auf dem 
nordamerikanischen Kontinent während des Zweiten Weltkrieges. 
Im Juni 1942, japanische Kräfte eingedrungenes Attu und andere 
Aleautian Inseln. Amerikaner fürchteten sich, daß die Inseln 
als Inszenierung Bereich benutzt würden, um das Festland in Angriff 
zu nehmen. Die VEREINIGTEN STAATEN mußten die Aleute um jeden 
Preis wiedergewinnen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est le site de la seule bataille de terre sur le 
continent américain du nord pendant la deuxième guerre mondiale. 
En juin 1942, forces japonaises Attu envahi et d'autres îles 
d'Aleautian. Les Américains ont craint que les îles soient 
employées comme zone mettante en scène pour attaquer le continent. 
Les ETATS-UNIS ont dû regagner les Aléoutes à tout prix.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é o local da única batalha da terra no 
continente norte-americano durante a segunda guerra mundial. Em 
junho 1942, em forças japonesas Attu invadido e em outros consoles de
Aleautian. Os americanos temeram que os consoles estariam usados
como uma área de estágio atacar o mainland. Os ESTADOS UNIDOS 
tiveram que regain os aleutians em todos os custos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è il luogo di unica battaglia della terra sul 
continente nordamericano durante la seconda guerra mondiale. In 
giugno del 1942, nelle forze giapponesi Attu invaso ed in altre isole 
di Aleautian. Gli Americani hanno temuto che le isole sarebbero 
usate come zona di organizzazione per attacare il continente. 
Gli STATI UNITI hanno dovuto riguadagnare i aleutians a tutti i 
costi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι η περιοχή της μόνης μάχης εδάφους στη 
βορειοαμερικανική ήπειρο κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου
ΙΙ. Τον Ιούνιο του 1942, οι ιαπωνικές δυνάμεις εισέβαλαν 
σε Attu και άλλα νησιά Aleautian. Αμερικανοί 
φοβισμένοι τα νησιά θα χρησιμοποιούνταν ως περιοχή οργάνωσης 
για να επιτεθούν στην ηπειρωτική χώρα. Οι ΗΠΑ έπρεπε να 
επανακτήσουν το Aleutians οπωσδήποτε.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es el sitio de la única batalla de la pista en el
continente norteamericano durante la Segunda Guerra Mundial. En 
junio de de 1942, fuerzas japonesas Attu invadido y otras islas de 
Aleautian. Los americanos temieron que las islas fueran 
utilizadas como área que efectúa para atacar el continente. 
Los ESTADOS UNIDOS tuvieron que recuperar a los aleutians a toda
costa.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206783</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107247</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/attu-north-american-battleground-of-world-war-ii</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
