<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107293</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107293</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206419</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Lewis and Clark: Mapping the West</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lewis und Clark: Diagramm des Westens</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Lewis et Clark : Tracer l'ouest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Lewis e Clark: Traçando o oeste</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lewis e Clark: Tracciato dell'ovest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Lewis και clark: Χαρτογράφηση της δύσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Lewis y Clark: Asociar el oeste</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features maps of the famous expedition. The Corps of Discovery collected 30 maps from Indians, trappers, and traders, and prepared 140 maps -- most of them drawn or compiled by Clark. The website shows the King map (created for the expedition) and the first map displaying their geographical discoveries. Descriptions of expedition members, life on the trail, and help provided by Indian tribes are included.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">kennzeichnet Karten der berühmten Expedition. 
Das Korps der Entdeckung sammelte 30 Karten von den Indern, von 
den Trappers und von den Händlern, und die meisten vorbereitet 140 
Karten -- ihnen gezogen oder durch Clark kompiliert. Die Web 
site zeigt die Königkarte (hergestellt für die Expedition) und die 
erste Karte, die ihre geographischen Entdeckungen anzeigt. 
Beschreibungen der Expeditionbauteile, das Leben auf der Spur 
und die Hilfe, die von den Indian Stämmen bereitgestellt wird, sind 
enthalten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">comporte des cartes en expédition célèbre. 
Les corps de la découverte ont rassemblé 30 cartes des 
Indiens, des trappeurs, et des commerçants, et préparé 140 cartes 
-- plus d'eux tirés ou compilé par Clark. Le site Web montre 
la carte de roi (créée pour l'expédition) et la première carte 
affichant leurs découvertes géographiques. Les descriptions 
des membres d'expédition, la vie sur la traînée, et l'aide fournie 
par des tribus d'Indian sont incluses.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">caracteriza mapas da expedição famosa. O 
corpo da descoberta coletou 30 mapas dos indians, dos caçadores, e 
dos comerciantes, e preparado 140 mapas -- mais deles drawn ou 
compilado por Clark. O Web site mostra o mapa do rei (criado 
para a expedição) e o primeiro mapa que indica suas descobertas 
geográficas. As descrições de membros da expedição, a vida 
na fuga, e a ajuda fornecida por tribes de Indian são incluídas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">caratterizza i programmi della spedizione famosa. 
Il Corpo della scoperta ha raccolto 30 programmi dagli 
indiani, dai cacciatori di pelli e dai commercianti e preparato 140 
programmi -- la maggior parte di loro tirati o compilato da Clark. 
Il Web site mostra il programma del re (creato per la 
spedizione) ed il primo programma che visualizza le loro scoperte 
geografiche. Le descrizioni dei membri di spedizione, la vita 
sulla traccia e l'aiuto fornito dalle tribù dell'Indian sono inclusi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χάρτες χαρακτηριστικών γνωρισμάτων της διάσημης 
αποστολής. Σώμα της ανακάλυψης συνέλεξε 30 χάρτες 
από Ινδούς, τα trappers, και τους εμπόρους, και προετοίμασε 
140 χάρτες -- οι περισσότεροι από τους που σύρθηκαν ή που 
μεταγλωττίστηκαν από clark. Ο ιστοχώρος εμφανίζει το 
χάρτη βασιλιάδων (που δημιουργούνται για την αποστολή) και πρώτο 
χάρτη που παρουσιάζει τις γεωγραφικές ανακαλύψεις τους. Οι 
περιγραφές των μελών αποστολής, της ζωής στο ίχνος, και των 
οδηγιών που παρέχονται από τις ινδικές φυλές συμπεριλαμβάνονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece correspondencias de la expedición famosa. 
El cuerpo del descubrimiento recogió 30 correspondencias de 
indios, de tramperos, y de comerciantes, y preparado 140 
correspondencias -- más de ellos exhaustos o compilado por Clark. 
El Web site muestra la correspondencia del rey (creada para la 
expedición) y la primera correspondencia que visualiza sus 
descubrimientos geográficos. Las descripciones de los miembros 
de la expedición, la vida en el rastro, y la ayuda proporcionada por 
las tribus indian son incluidas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206419</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107293</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/lewis-and-clark-mapping-the-west</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
