<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107980</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107980</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087380</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">American Memory from the Library of Congress</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Amerikanischer Speicher von der Bibliothek des 
Kongresses</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mémoire américaine de la bibliothèque du 
congrès</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Memória americana da biblioteca do congress</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Memoria americana dalla libreria del congresso</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αμερικανική μνήμη από τη βιβλιοθήκη του συνεδρίου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Memoria americana de la biblioteca del congreso</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">American Memory provides free and open access through the Internet to written and spoken words, sound recordings, still and moving images, prints, maps, and sheet music that document the American experience. It is a digital record of American history and creativity. These materials, from the collections of the Library of Congress and other institutions, chronicle historical events, people, places, and ideas that continue to shape America, serving the public as a resource for education and lifelong learning.</string>
          </description>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Amerikanischer Speicher stellt frei und 
geöffneter Zugriff durch das Internet zu geschriebenen und 
gesprochenen Wörtern, zu den Tonaufnahmen, zu den ruhigen und 
beweglichen Bildern, zu den Drucken, zu den Karten und zur Blattmusik 
zur Verfügung, die die amerikanische Erfahrung dokumentieren. 
Es ist ein digitaler Satz der amerikanischen Geschichte und der 
Kreativität. Diese Materialien, von den Ansammlungen der 
Bibliothek des Kongresses und anderer Anstalten, zeichnen historische 
Fälle, Leute, Plätze und Ideen auf, die fortfahren, Amerika zu 
formen und die Öffentlichkeit als Hilfsmittel für Ausbildung und das
lebenslängliche Lernen dienen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La mémoire américaine fournit librement et 
accès ouvert par l'Internet aux mots écrits et parlés, aux 
enregistrements sonores, aux images immobiles et mobiles, aux copies, 
aux cartes, et à la musique de feuille qui documentent l'expérience 
américaine. C'est un enregistrement digital de l'histoire et de
la créativité américaines. Ces matériaux, des collections de
la bibliothèque du congrès et d'autres établissements, font la 
chronique des événements historiques, des personnes, des endroits, 
et des idées qui continuent à former l'Amérique, servant le public 
de ressource pour l'éducation et l'étude perpétuelle.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A memória americana fornece livre e acesso aberto
através do Internet às palavras escritas e faladas, às gravações 
sadias, às imagens imóveis e moventes, às cópias, aos mapas, e à 
música da folha que documentam a experiência americana. É um 
registro digital do history e da creatividade americanos. Estes 
materiais, das coleções da biblioteca do congress e das outras 
instituições, chronicle eventos históricos, povos, lugares, e 
idéias que continuam a dar forma a América, servindo ao público 
como um recurso para a instrução e a aprendizagem lifelong.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La memoria americana fornisce liberamente ed 
accesso aperto attraverso il Internet alle parola scritte e, alle 
registrazioni del suono, alle immagini tranquille e commoventi, alle 
stampe, ai programmi ed alla musica del foglio che documentano 
l'esperienza americana. È un record digitale di storia e di 
creatività americane. Questi materiali, dalle collezioni della 
libreria del congresso e di altre istituzioni, chronicle gli eventi 
storici, la gente, i posti e le idee che continuano a modellare 
l'America, servente il pubblico da risorsa per formazione ed imparare 
lifelong.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η αμερικανική μνήμη παρέχει την ελεύθερη και ανοικτή 
πρόσβαση μέσω του Διαδικτύου στις γραπτές και προφορικές λέξεις,
τις υγιείς καταγραφές, ακόμα και τις κινούμενες εικόνες, τις 
τυπωμένες ύλες, τους χάρτες, και τη μουσική φύλλων που 
τεκμηριώνουν την αμερικανική εμπειρία. Είναι ένα ψηφιακό 
αρχείο της αμερικανικών ιστορίας και της δημιουργικότητας. 
Αυτά τα υλικά, από τις συλλογές της βιβλιοθήκης του 
συνεδρίου και άλλων οργάνων, εξιστορούν κατά γράμμα τα 
ιστορικούς γεγονότα, τους ανθρώπους, τις θέσεις, και τις ιδέες 
που συνεχίζουν να διαμορφώνουν την Αμερική, που χρησιμεύει κοινό 
ως ένα στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς για την εκπαίδευση και δια βίου που.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La memoria americana proporciona libremente y 
acceso abierto a través del Internet a las palabras escritas y 
habladas, a las grabaciones de sonidos, a las imágenes inmóviles y 
móviles, a las impresiones, a las correspondencias, y a la música de
la hoja que documentan la experiencia americana. Es un 
expediente digital de la historia y de la creatividad americanas. 
Estos materiales, de las colecciones de la biblioteca del 
congreso y de otras instituciones, chronicle acontecimientos 
históricos, la gente, lugares, y las ideas que continúan formando 
América, sirviendo al público como recurso para la educación y 
aprender de por vida.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087380</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107980</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/american-memory-from-the-library-of-congress</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
