<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106111</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106111</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087479</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Chicago and Its Eight Reasons": Walter White Considers the Causes of the 1919 Chicago Race Riot</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Chicago und seine acht Gründe": Walter 
Weiß betrachtet die Ursachen des Chicago Rennen-Aufstands 1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Chicago et ses huit raisons" : Le blanc de 
Walter considère les causes de l'émeute 1919 de course de Chicago</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Chicago e suas oito razões": O branco de 
Walter considera as causas do motim 1919 da raça de Chicago</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Chicago ed i relativi otto motivi": Il 
bianco di Walter considera le cause del tumulto 1919 della corsa del 
Chicago</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Σικάγο και οκτώ λόγοι του": Walter White 
Considers οι αιτίες της φυλετικής ταραχής του Σικάγου του 
1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Chicago y sus ocho razones": El blanco de 
Walter considera las causas del alboroto 1919 de la raza de Chicago</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">As U.S. soldiers returned from Europe in the aftermath of World War I, scarce housing and jobs heightened racial and class antagonisms across urban America. African-American soldiers, in particular, came home from the war expecting to enjoy the full rights of citizenship that they had fought to defend overseas. In the spring and summer of 1919, murderous race riots erupted in 22 American cities and towns. Chicago experienced the most severe of these riots. The  Crisis , published by the NAACP, responded to the Chicago race riot with a major article in October 1919, "Chicago and Its Eight Reasons." Author Walter White, then assistant executive secretary of the NAACP, described eight causes of the riot and concluded that tensions had increased in the city partially in response to the influx of African Americans. Though sympathetic to the new migrants' plight, White's article criticized both African-American newcomers to Chicago and the city's black politicians. White also concluded, approvingly, that some black citizens, with a newfound spirit of independence, chose to retaliate against the pervasive attacks by white Chicagoans rather than remain passive victims.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während VEREINIGTE STAATEN Soldaten von Europa in
der Nachmahd des Ersten Weltkrieges zurückkamen, erhöhten knappes 
Gehäuse und Jobs die rassische und Kategorie Antagonismen über 
städtischem Amerika. Die Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Soldaten 
kamen insbesondere nach Hause vom Krieg erwartend, die vollen Rechte 
der Staatsbürgerschaft zu genießen, die sie gekämpft hatten, um 
übersee zu verteidigen. Im Frühling und im Sommer von 1919, 
brachen mörderische Rennenaufstände in 22 amerikanischen Städte und
in Städten aus. Chicago erfuhr das strengste dieser Aufstände.
Die Krise, veröffentlicht durch das NAACP, reagierte auf den 
Chicago Rennenaufstand mit einem Hauptartikel im Oktober 1919, 
"Chicago und seine acht Gründe." Schreiben Sie Walter Weiß, 
dann den behilflichen Geschäftsführer vom NAACP, beschrieben acht 
Ursachen des Aufstands und festgestellt, daß Spannkräfte sich der 
Stadt teilweise in Erwiderung auf den Zufluß der afrikanischen 
Amerikaner erhöht hatten. Zwar sympatisch zur neuen Lage der 
Wanderer, Artikel des Weiß kritisierte beide 
Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Neulinge zu Chicago und die schwarzen 
Politiker der Stadt. Weiß folgerte auch anerkennend daß einige
schwarze Bürger, mit einem neuentdeckten Geist von Unabhängigkeit, 
beschlossen, sich gegen die durchdringenden Angriffe durch weißes 
Chicagoans zu revanchieren anstatt passive Opfer bleiben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant que les soldats des ETATS-UNIS 
retournaient de l'Europe dans le lendemain de la Première Guerre 
Mondiale, le logement rare et les travaux ont intensifié des 
antagonismes raciaux et de classe à travers l'Amérique urbaine. 
Les soldats afro-américains, en particulier, sont venus à la 
maison de la guerre comptant apprécier les pleines droites de la 
citoyenneté qu'ils avaient combattu pour défendre outre-mer. 
Au printemps et l'été de 1919, les émeutes meurtrières de 
course ont éclaté dans 22 villes et villes américaines. 
Chicago a éprouvé le plus grave de ces émeutes. La 
crise, éditée par le NAACP, a répondu à l'émeute de course de 
Chicago avec un article important en octobre 1919, "Chicago et ses 
huit raisons." Écrivez le blanc de Walter, puis secrétaire de 
direction auxiliaire du NAACP, décrit huit causes de l'émeute et 
conclu que les tensions avaient augmenté dans la ville partiellement 
en réponse à l'afflux des Américains africains. Cependant 
sympathique des nouveaux à la situation difficile migrants, l'article
du blanc a critiqué les nouveaux venus afro-américains à Chicago et les
politiciens noirs de la ville. Le blanc a également conclu, 
avec approbation, que quelques citoyens noirs, avec un esprit 
récemment découvert de l'indépendance, ont choisi de exercer des 
représailles contre les attaques dominantes par Chicagoans blanc 
plutôt que restent les victimes passives.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Enquanto os soldados de ESTADOS UNIDOS retornaram 
de Europa no aftermath do world.war.i, a carcaça escassa e os 
trabalhos heightened antagonisms raciais e da classe através de 
América urbana. Os soldados Africano-Americanos, no detalhe, 
vieram para casa da guerra esperando apreciar as direitas cheias do 
citizenship que tinham lutado para defender no ultramar. Na mola
e no verão de 1919, os motins murderous da raça erupted em 22 
cidades e cidades americanas. Chicago experimentou o mais severo
destes motins. A crise, publicada pelo NAACP, respondeu ao motim
da raça de Chicago com um artigo principal em outubro 1919, "Chicago 
e suas oito razões." Seja o autor do branco de Walter, então 
secretária executiva assistente do NAACP, descrita oito causas do 
motim e conclída que as tensões tinham aumentado na cidade 
parcialmente em resposta ao influx de americanos africanos. 
Though sympathetic ao plight dos emigrantes novos, artigo do 
branco criticou ambos os newcomers Africano-Americanos a Chicago e os 
políticos pretos da cidade. O branco concliu também, 
approvingly, que alguns cidadãos pretos, com um espírito newfound da
independência, escolheram retaliate de encontro aos ataques pervasive
por Chicagoans branco melhor que remanescem vítimas passivas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Mentre i soldati degli STATI UNITI hanno ritornato
da Europa nel guaime del world.war.i, l'alloggiamento limitato ed i 
lavori hanno intensificato gli antagonismi del codice categoria e 
razziali attraverso l'America urbana. I soldati 
Africano-Americani, in particolare, sono venuto a casa dalla guerra 
pensanti godere i diritti completi della cittadinanza che avevano 
combattuto per difendere oltremare. Nella molla e nell'estate di
1919, i tumulti murderous della corsa hanno scoppiato in 22 
città e città americane. Chicago ha sperimentato il più 
severo di questi tumulti. La crisi, pubblicata dal NAACP, ha 
risposto al tumulto della corsa del Chicago con un articolo importante
nel mese di ottobre del 1919, "Chicago ed i relativi otto motivi." 
Crei il bianco di Walter, allora segretaria esecutiva di aiuto 
del NAACP, descritta otto cause del tumulto e conclusiva che i 
tensionamenti erano aumentato di città parzialmente in risposta 
all'afflusso degli Americani africani. Comunque simpatico alla 
situazione difficile dei nuovi migranti, articolo del bianco ha 
criticato entrambi i nuovi venuti Africano-Americani a Chicago ed i 
politici neri della città. Il bianco egualmente ha concluso, 
approvingly, che alcuni cittadini neri, con uno spirito newfound di 
indipendenza, hanno scelto retaliate contro gli attacchi dominanti da 
Chicagoans bianco piuttosto che rimangono vittime passive.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δεδομένου ότι οι ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΙ στρατιώτες επέστρεψαν 
από την Ευρώπη στη συνέπεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου Ι, η λιγοστή 
κατοικία και οι εργασίες ύψωσαν τους φυλετικούς και ανταγωνισμούς
κλάσης σε ολόκληρη την αστική Αμερική. 
Αφρικανικός-αμερικανικά οι στρατιώτες, ειδικότερα, προήλθαν
κατ' οίκον από τον πόλεμο αναμένοντας να απολαύσουν των πλήρων 
δικαιωμάτων της υπηκοότητας που είχαν παλεψει για να υπερασπίσουν 
στο εξωτερικό. Την άνοιξη και το καλοκαίρι του 1919, οι 
δολοφονικές φυλετικές ταραχές ξέσπασαν σε 22 αμερικανικές 
πόλεις και κωμοπόλεις. Το Σικάγο δοκίμασε τον αυστηρότερο 
αυτών των ταραχών. Η κρίση, που δημοσιεύθηκε από το 
NAACP, αποκρίθηκε στη φυλετική ταραχή του Σικάγου με ένα 
σημαντικό άρθρο τον Οκτώβριο του 1919, "Σικάγο και οκτώ λόγοι
της." Ο συντάκτης walter White, έπειτα βοηθητικός 
εκτελεστικός γραμματέας του NAACP, περιέγραψε οκτώ αιτίες της 
ταραχής και κατέληξε στο συμπέρασμα ότι οι εντάσεις είχαν 
αυξηθεί στην πόλη μερικώς σε απάντηση στην εισροή αφρικανικών 
Αμερικανών. Εν τούτοις συμπονετική των νέων μεταναστών η 
δύσκολη θέση, άρθρο του λευκού επέκρινε και τους 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικούς νεοφερμένους στο Σικάγο και τους 
μαύρους πολιτικούς της πόλης. Το λευκό ολοκλήρωσε επίσης, 
επιδοκιμαστικά, ότι μερικοί μαύροι πολίτες, με ένα προσφάτως 
ανευρεθέν πνεύμα της ανεξαρτησίας, επέλεξαν να εκδικηθούν τις 
κυρίαρχες επιθέσεις από άσπρο Chicagoans παρά να παραμείνουν 
παθητικά θύματα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mientras que los soldados de ESTADOS UNIDOS 
volvieron de Europa en las consecuencias de la Primera Guerra Mundial,
la cubierta escasa y los trabajos aumentaron antagonismos raciales y 
de la clase a través de América urbana. Los soldados 
Africano-Americanos, en detalle, vinieron a casa de la guerra 
esperando gozar de las derechas completas de la ciudadanía que 
habían luchado para defender en ultramar. En el resorte y el 
verano de 1919, los alborotos murderous de la raza entraron en 
erupción en 22 ciudades y ciudades americanas. Chicago 
experimentó el más severo de estos alborotos. La crisis, 
publicada por el NAACP, respondió al alboroto de la raza de Chicago 
con un artículo importante en octubre de 1919, "Chicago y sus ocho 
razones." Sea autor del blanco de Walter, entonces secretaria 
ejecutiva auxiliar del NAACP, descrita ocho causas del alboroto y 
concluida que las tensiones habían aumentado de la ciudad 
parcialmente en respuesta a la afluencia de americanos africanos. 
Sin embargo comprensivo al apuro de los nuevos nómadas, 
artículo del blanco criticó a ambos recién llegado 
Africano-Americanos a Chicago y a políticos negros de la ciudad. 
El blanco también concluyó, approvingly, que algunos 
ciudadanos negros, con un alcohol newfound de la independencia, 
eligieron tomar represalias contra los ataques penetrantes por 
Chicagoans blanco más bien que siguen siendo víctimas pasivas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087479</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106111</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/chicago-and-its-eight-reasons-walter-white-considers-the-causes-of-the-1919-chicago-race-riot</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
