<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108627</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108627</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206655</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Genetic Basics</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Genetische Grundlagen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Fondations Génétiques</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Princípios Genetic</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Principi fondamentali Genetici</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γενετικά βασικά</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fundamentos Genéticos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">looks at how genes work, exceptions to Mendel's rules, how DNA gets replicated, genes and disease, current research and recent discoveries, and how applications of genetic research (biotechnology) are being used in agriculture, health, and pharmacogenetics (medicine) to change our world for the better.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">betrachtet, wie Gene arbeiten, Ausnahmen zu den 
Richtlinien Mendels, wie DNA wiederholt erhält, Gene und Krankheit, 
aktuelle Forschung und Neuentdeckungen und wie Anwendungen der 
genetischen Forschung (Biotechnologie) in der Landwirtschaft, in der 
Gesundheit und in den Pharmacogenetics (Medizin) verwendet werden um 
unsere Welt für das bessere zu ändern.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">regarde la façon dont les gènes fonctionnent, 
des exceptions aux règles de Mendel, comment l'ADN obtient repliée, 
des gènes et la maladie, la recherche actuelle et les découvertes 
récentes, et comment des applications de la recherche génétique 
(biotechnologie) sont employées en agriculture, santé, et 
pharmacognénétique (médecine) pour changer notre monde pour le 
meilleur.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">olha como os genes trabalham, exceções às 
réguas de Mendel, como o DNA começam replicated, genes e a doença, 
a pesquisa atual e as descobertas recentes, e como as aplicações da 
pesquisa genetic (biotechnology) estão sendo usadas na agricultura, 
na saúde, e nos pharmacogenetics (medicina) mudar nosso mundo para o 
melhor.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">guarda come i geni funzionano, eccezioni alle 
regole del Mendel, come il DNA ottiene ripiegato, geni e la malattia, 
la ricerca corrente e le scoperte recenti e come le applicazioni di 
ricerca genetica (biotecnologia) stanno usande in agricoltura, salute 
e pharmacogenetics (medicina) per cambiare il nostro mondo per il 
migliore.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει το πώς τα γονίδια λειτουργούν, εξαιρέσεις 
στους κανόνες του Mendel, το πώς το DNA παίρνει 
ξαναδιπλωμένο, γονίδια και ασθένεια, παρούσα έρευνα και 
πρόσφατες ανακαλύψεις, και πώς οι εφαρμογές της γενετικής 
έρευνας (βιοτεχνολογία) χρησιμοποιούνται στη γεωργία, την υγεία, 
και τις φαρμακογενετικές (ιατρική) για να αλλάξουν τον κόσμο μας 
προς το καλύτερο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">mira cómo los genes trabajan, las anomalías a 
las reglas de Mendel, cómo la DNA consigue replegada, los genes y la 
enfermedad, la investigación actual y los descubrimientos recientes, 
y cómo las aplicaciones de la investigación genética 
(biotecnología) se están utilizando en agricultura, salud, y 
pharmacogenetics (medicina) para cambiar nuestro mundo para el mejor.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206655</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108627</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/genetic-basics</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
