<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108494</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108494</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086284</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Had Visions of Being Rounded Up:" Emira Habiby-Browne Describes the Impact of the September 11, 2001 Attacks on Arab Americans</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ich hatte Anblicke von herauf aufgerundet 
werden:" Emira Habiby-Browne beschreibt die Auswirkung des 
Septembers 11, 2001 Angriffe auf arabischen Amerikanern</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"j'ai eu des visions de l'arrondissage vers le 
haut de :" Emira Habiby-Browne décrit l'impact septembre de 11,
2001 attaques sur les Américains arabes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"eu tive visões de ser arredondado acima de:" 
Emira Habiby-Browne descreve o impacto setembro do 11, 2001 
ataques em americanos árabes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"ho avuto visioni di arrotondamento su:" 
Emira Habiby-Browne descrive l'effetto del 11 settembre, 2001 
attacco agli Americani arabi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Είχα τα οράματα να στρογγυλευτώ επάνω:" Το 
Emira χαψηψυ- Browne περιγράφει τον αντίκτυπο της 11ης 
Σεπτεμβρίου ..2001 επιτίθεται σε αραβικούς Αμερικανούς</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"tenía visiones del redondeo encima de:" 
Emira Habiby-Browne describe el impacto del de septiembre 11, 
2001 ataques contra americanos árabes</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">For Arab and Muslim Americans, especially those living in New York, the terrorist attacks of September 11, 2001 were particularly painful; they not only had to confront the sorrow of the attacks, but they also faced a tide of discrimination, harassment, and in some cases violence aimed at Arabs and Muslims. Emira Habiby-Browne, the director of the Arab-American Family Support Center in Brooklyn, spoke about the hostility many community members faced on the job, and the fear that spread as hundreds of Arab and Middle Eastern men were detained in secret by the federal government. Like other groups whose loyalty was questioned during wartime due to their ethnic background, Arab and Muslim Americans identify themselves closely with their country and were deeply saddened and frustrated by the suspicion targeted at them.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Für die arabischen und moslemischen Amerikaner 
besonders die wohnend in New York, waren die Terroristangriffe von 
September 11, 2001 besonders schmerzlich; sie mußten die sorge 
der Angriffe nicht nur konfrontieren, aber sie stellten auch 
Gezeiten der Unterscheidung, der Belästigung und in einigen 
Fällen der Gewalttätigkeit angestrebten Araber und der Moslems 
gegenüber. Emira Habiby-Browne, der Direktor der 
Araber-Amerikanischen Familie Unterstützungsmitte in Brooklyn, 
Speiche über die Feindseligkeit viele Gemeinschaftsbauteile 
gegenübergestellt auf dem Job und der Furcht, die verbritt, während 
Hunderte Araber und mittlere östliche Männer im Geheimnis durch die 
Bundesregierung zurückgehalten wurden. Wie andere Gruppen deren
Loyalität während des Krieges wegen ihrer ethnischen Hintergrund, 
Araber-und Moslem-Amerikaner gefragt wurde, kennzeichnen Sie sich nah 
mit ihrem Land und wurden tief durch das Misstrauen betrübt und 
frustriert, das an ihnen gezielt wird.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pour les Américains arabes et musulmans, 
particulièrement ceux habitant à New York, les attaques de 
terroriste septembre de 11, 2001 étaient particulièrement 
douloureuses ; ils non seulement ont dû confronter la douleur 
des attaques, mais ils ont également fait face à une marée de 
discrimination, de harcèlement, et dans certains cas d'Arabes et de 
musulmans visés par violence. Emira Habiby-Browne, directeur du
centre d'assistance Arabe-Américain de famille à Brooklyn, rai au 
sujet de l'hostilité beaucoup de membre de la Communauté faits face 
sur le travail, et la crainte qui a écarté pendant que des centaines
d'Arabe et hommes orientaux moyens étaient détenues dans le secret 
par le gouvernement fédéral. Comme d'autres groupes dont la 
fidélité a été remise en cause pendant le temps de guerre dû à 
leurs Américains ethniques de fond, d'Arabe et de musulmans 
identifiez-vous étroitement avec leur pays et avez été 
profondément attristé et frustré par le soupçon visé à eux.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Para os americanos árabes e muçulmanos, especial
aqueles vivendo em New York, os ataques do terrorista setembro de 11, 
2001 eram particularmente dolorosos; são tidos que não somente
confrontá-los o sorrow dos ataques, mas enfrentaram também uma maré
da discriminação, harassment, e em árabes visados violência e em 
muçulmanos de alguns casos. Emira Habiby-Browne, diretor do 
centro de sustentação Árabe-Americano da família em Brooklyn, raio
sobre a hostilidade muitos membros de comunidade enfrentados no 
trabalho, e no medo que espalhou enquanto as centenas do árabe e de 
homens orientais médios foram detidas no segredo pelo governo 
federal. Como outros grupos cuja a lealdade foi questionada 
durante o wartime  devido a seus americanos étnicos do fundo, do 
árabe e dos muçulmanos identifique-se pròxima com seu país e 
profundamente foram entristecidos e frustrados pela suspeita alvejada 
neles.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Per gli Americani arabi e musulmani, 
particolarmente quelli viventi a New York, gli attacchi del terrorista
del 11 settembre, 2001 erano particolarmente dolorosi; dovuti 
non soltanto per confrontarli il dispiacere degli attacchi, ma 
egualmente hanno affrontato una marea di distinzione, del harassment 
ed in alcuni casi degli arabi e dei musulmani puntati su 
violenza. Emira Habiby-Browne, il direttore del centro di 
sostegno della famiglia di arabo-american a Brooklyn, spoke circa 
l'ostilità molti membri di Comunità affrontati sul lavoro e sul 
timore che si è sparso mentre i centinaia dell'arabo e degli 
uomini orientali centrali sono stati ritenuti nel segreto dal governo 
federale. Come altri gruppi di cui la lealtà è stata messa in 
discussione durante il wartime dovuto i loro Americani etnici della 
priorità bassa, dell'arabo e dei musulmani identifichisi molto
attentamente con il loro paese e profondamente sono stati rattristati 
e frustrato stati dal sospetto designato loro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Για αραβικούς και μουσουλμανικούς Αμερικανούς, ειδικά 
εκείνοι που ζουν στη Νέα Υόρκη, οι τρομοκρατικές επιθέσεις της 
11ης Σεπτεμβρίου ..2001 ήταν ιδιαίτερα επίπονες  όχι 
μόνο έπρεπε να αντιμετωπίσουν τη θλίψη των επιθέσεων, αλλά 
αντιμετώπισαν επίσης μια παλίρροια της διάκρισης, της 
παρενόχλησης, και σε μερικές περιπτώσεις της βίας που στόχευσε 
στους Αραβες και μουσουλμάνους. Το Emira χαψηψυ- Browne,
ο σκηνοθέτης του αραβικός-αμερικανικού κέντρου οικογενειακής 
υποστήριξης στο Μπρούκλιν, μίλησε για την εχθρότητα πολλά 
κοινοτικά μέλη που αντιμετωπίστηκαν στην εργασία, και ο φόβος που
διέδωσε ως εκατοντάδες των αραβικών και μέσων ανατολικών ατόμων 
τέθηκε υπό κράτηση στο μυστικό από την ομοσπονδιακή κυβέρνηση. 
Όπως άλλες ομάδες η των οποίων πίστη εξετάστηκε κατά τη 
διάρκεια της εμπόλεμης περιόδου λόγω στο εθνικό υπόβαθρό τους, 
αραβικοί και μουσουλμανικοί Αμερικανοί προσδιορίζονται πολύ με τη
χώρα τους και λυπήθηκαν βαθειά και ματαιώθηκαν από την υποψία 
που στοχεύει σε τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Para los americanos árabes y musulmanes, 
especialmente ésos viviendo en Nueva York, los ataques del terrorista
del de septiembre 11, 2001 eran determinado dolorosos; los 
tenidos que no solamente para enfrentar el dolor de los ataques, pero 
los también hicieron frente a una marea de la discriminación, 
hostigamiento, y en árabes dirigidos violencia y musulmanes de 
algunos casos. Emira Habiby-Browne, el director del centro de 
ayuda A'rabe-Americano de la familia en Brooklyn, rayo sobre la 
hostilidad muchos miembros de la Comunidad hechos frente en el 
trabajo, y el miedo que se separó mientras que el gobierno federal 
detuvieron a los centenares de árabe y de hombres del este medios en 
secreto. Como otros grupos que lealtad fue preguntada durante el
tiempo de guerra  debido a sus americanos étnicos del fondo, del 
árabe y de los musulmanes identifiqúese de cerca con su país y 
profundamente eran entristecidos y frustrados por la suspicacia 
apuntada en ellos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086284</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108494</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-had-visions-of-being-rounded-up-emira-habiby-browne-describes-the-impact-of-the-september-11-2001-attacks-on-arab-americans</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
