<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107365</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107365</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206147</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">nanoHUB.org</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">nanoHUB.org</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">nanoHUB.org</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">nanoHUB.org</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">nanoHUB.org</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">nanoHUB.org</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">nanoHUB.org</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">provides online simulations, learning modules, and interactive tools for learning about nanotechnology -- the design and production of structures, devices, and systems one atom or one molecule at a time. Analyze the electronic properties of different nano materials and the optical properties of nanoparticles. Explore molecular conduction, nanofluids, and nanowires. Create simulations of nanoelectronic and nanoelectromechanical systems. Registration required.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt Online-Simulation, Lernenmodule und 
interaktive Hilfsmittel für über nanotechnology hintereinander 
erlernen -- das Design und die Produktion der Strukturen, der 
Einheiten und der Systeme ein Atom oder ein Molekül zur Verfügung. 
Analysieren Sie die elektronischen Eigenschaften der 
unterschiedlichen nano Materialien und die optischen Eigenschaften von
nanoparticles. Erforschen Sie molekulare Übertragung, 
nanofluids und nanowires. Erstellen Sie Simulationen der 
nanoelectronic und nanoelectromechanical Systeme. Registrierung 
benötigt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fournit des modules de simulations en direct, 
d'étude, et des outils interactifs pour se renseigner sur le 
nanotechnology -- la conception et la production des structures, des 
dispositifs, et des systèmes un atome ou une molécule à la fois. 
Analysez les propriétés électroniques de différents 
matériaux de nano et les propriétés optiques des 
nanoparticles. Explorez la conduction, les nanofluids, et les 
nanowires moléculaires. Créez les simulations des systèmes 
nanoelectronic et nanoelectromechanical. Enregistrement requis.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fornece os módulos das simulações em linha, da 
aprendizagem, e ferramentas interativas para aprender sobre o 
nanotechnology -- o projeto e a produção das estruturas, dos 
dispositivos, e dos sistemas um átomo ou uma molécula de cada vez. 
Analise as propriedades eletrônicas de materiais diferentes do 
nano e as propriedades óticas dos nanoparticles. Explore a 
condução, nanofluids, e nanowires molecular. Críe 
simulações de sistemas nanoelectronic e nanoelectromechanical. 
Registo requerido.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fornisce i moduli imparare, di simulazioni in 
linea e gli strumenti interattivi per imparare circa il nanotechnology
-- il disegno e la produzione delle strutture, dei dispositivi e dei 
sistemi un atomo o una molecola alla volta. Analizzi le 
proprietà elettroniche dei materiali differenti di nano e le 
proprietà ottiche dei nanoparticles. Esplori la conduzione, i 
nanofluids ed i nanowires molecolari. Crei le simulazioni dei 
sistemi nanoelectronic e nanoelectromechanical. Registro 
richiesto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρέχει τις σε απευθείας σύνδεση προσομοιώσεις, τις 
ενότητες εκμάθησης, και τα διαλογικά εργαλεία για για τη 
νανοτεχνολογία -- το σχέδιο και η παραγωγή των δομών, των 
συσκευών, και των συστημάτων ένα άτομο ή ένα μόριο τη φορά. 
Αναλύστε τις ηλεκτρονικές ιδιότητες των διαφορετικών νανο 
υλικών και τις οπτικές ιδιότητες των nanoparticles. 
Ερευνήστε τη μοριακή διεξαγωγή, nanofluids, και 
nanowires. Δημιουργήστε τις προσομοιώσεις των 
nanoelectronic και nanoelectromechanical συστημάτων. 
Εγγραφή που απαιτείται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">proporciona a los módulos de las simulaciones en 
línea, el aprender, y a las herramientas interactivas para aprender 
sobre nanotechnology -- el diseño y la producción de estructuras, de
dispositivos, y de sistemas un átomo o una molécula al mismo tiempo.
Analice las características electrónicas de diversos 
materiales del nano y las características ópticas de nanoparticles. 
Explore la conducción, los nanofluids, y los nanowires 
moleculares. Cree las simulaciones de sistemas nanoelectronic y 
nanoelectromechanical. Registro requerido.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206147</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107365</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/nanohub.org</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
