<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103273</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103273</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086751</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Poet William Carlos Williams Describes the Crowd at the Ballpark</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dichter William Carlos Williams beschreibt die 
Masse am Baseballstadion</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le poèt William Carlos Williams décrit la foule 
chez le Ballpark</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O poeta William Carlos Williams descreve a 
multidão no Ballpark</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il poet William Carlos Williams descrive la folla 
al Ballpark</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ποιητής William Carlos Williams Describes το 
πλήθος στην Εξέδρα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El poeta Guillermo Carlos Williams describe a 
muchedumbre en el Estadio de béisbol</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Baseball's growing popularity in the 1920s can be measured by structural and cultural changes that helped transform the game, including the building of commodious new ballparks; the emergence of sports pages in daily urban newspapers; and the enormous popularity of radio broadcasts of baseball games.Baseball commentators and critics expended much ink during the 1920s discussing the exact nature and composition of this new and expanding fan population. Some derided the influx of new fans to urban ballparks, in part because of the growing visibility in the bleachers of the sons and daughters of working-class Italian, Polish, and Jewish immigrants, and in part because the game seemed to be straying from its origins in traditional rural and small-town America. Poet William Carlos Williams evoked the growing diversity of baseball's fans and their impact on the game in "The Crowd at the Ball Park," published in the  Dial  in 1923.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wachsende Popularität des Baseballs in den 
zwanziger Jahren kann durch die strukturellen und kulturellen 
Änderungen, die das halfen, Spiel umzuwandeln, einschließlich das 
Gebäude der commodious neuen Baseballstadion gemessen werden; 
das Hervortreten der Sportseiten in den täglichen städtischen 
Zeitungen; und die enorme Popularität der Radiosendungen der 
Kommentatoren und der Kritiker des Baseballs games.Baseball 
verbrauchte viel Tinte während der zwanziger Jahre die genaue Natur 
und den Aufbau dieser neuen und erweiternventilatorbevölkerung 
behandelnd. Einige derided den Zufluß der neuen Ventilatoren zu
den städtischen Baseballstadion, im Teil wegen der wachsenden Sicht in
den Zuschauertribünen der Söhne und der Töchter des Arbeiterklasse 
Italieners, des Poliermittels und der jüdischen Immigranten und im 
Teil, weil das Spiel schien, von seinen Ursprung in traditionellem 
landwirtschaftlichem und in der Kleinstadt Amerika wegzulaufen. 
Dichter William Carlos Williams erwähnte die wachsende 
Verschiedenartigkeit der Ventilatoren des Baseballs und ihre 
Auswirkung auf das Spiel "in der Masse am Baseballstadion," 
veröffentlichte im Vorwahlknopf 1923.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La popularité croissante du base-ball dans les 
années 20 peut être mesurée par les changements structuraux et 
culturels qui ont aidé à transformer le jeu, y compris le bâtiment 
de nouveaux ballparks spacieux ; l'apparition des pages de 
sports en journaux urbains quotidiens ; et l'énorme popularité
des émissions par radio des commentateurs et des critiques du 
base-ball games.Baseball a dépensé beaucoup d'encre pendant les 
années 20 discutant la nature et la composition exactes de cette 
nouvelle et augmentante population de ventilateur. Certains 
derided l'afflux de nouveaux ventilateurs aux ballparks urbains, en 
partie en raison de la visibilité croissante dans les grandins des
fils et des filles de l'Italien de classe ouvrière, du poli, et des 
immigrés juifs, et en partie parce que le jeu a semblé vaguer de ses
origines dans rural traditionnel et la petit-ville Amérique. Le
poèt William Carlos Williams a évoqué la diversité croissante des 
ventilateurs du base-ball et leur impact sur le jeu dans "la foule au 
parc de boule," a édité dans le cadran en 1923.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A popularidade crescente do baseball nos 1920s 
pode ser medida pelas mudanças estruturais e cultural que ajudaram 
transformar o jogo, including o edifício de ballparks novos 
commodious; o emergence de páginas dos esportes em jornais 
urbanos diários; e a popularidade enorme das transmissões de 
rádio dos comentadores e dos críticos do baseball games.Baseball 
expended muita tinta durante os 1920s que discutem a natureza e a 
composição exatas desta população nova e expandindo do ventilador.
Alguns derided o influx de ventiladores novos aos ballparks 
urbanos, na parte por causa da visibilidade crescente nos bleachers 
dos filhos e das filhas do italiano do working-class, do lustrador, e 
de immigrants jewish, e na parte porque o jogo pareceu vaguear de suas
origens em rural tradicional e na pequeno-cidade América. O 
poeta William Carlos Williams evoked a diversidade crescente de 
ventiladores do baseball e seu impacto no jogo "na multidão no parque
da esfera," publicou no seletor em 1923.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La popolarità crescente del baseball negli anni 
20 può essere misurata dai cambiamenti strutturali e culturali che 
hanno contribuito a trasformare il gioco, compreso la costruzione di 
nuovi ballparks commodious; l'emersione delle pagine di sport in
giornali urbani quotidiani; e la popolarità enorme delle 
radiodiffusioni radiofoniche dei commentatori e dei critici di 
baseball games.Baseball ha consumato molto inchiostro durante gli anni
20 che discutono la natura e la composizione esatte di questa nuova e 
popolazione d'espansione del ventilatore. Alcuni derided 
l'afflusso di nuovi ventilatori ai ballparks urbani, in parte a causa 
della visibilità crescente nei bleachers dei figli e delle figlie 
dell'italiano della classe operaia, dello smalto e degli immigranti 
ebrei ed in parte perché il gioco ha sembrato smarrirsi dalle 
relative origini in rurale tradizionale ed in piccolo-città America. 
Il poet William Carlos Williams ha evocato la diversità 
crescente dei ventilatori del baseball ed il loro effetto sul gioco 
"nella folla al parco della sfera," ha pubblicato nella manopola in 
1923.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η αυξανόμενη δημοτικότητα του μπέιζ-μπώλ στη δεκαετία
του '20 μπορεί να μετρηθεί από τις δομικές και πολιτιστικές 
αλλαγές που βοήθησαν να μετασχηματίσουν το παιχνίδι, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένης της οικοδόμησης των ευρύχωρων νέων 
εξεδρών  η εμφάνιση των αθλητικών σελίδων στις 
καθημερινές αστικές εφημερίδες  και η τεράστια δημοτικότητα
των ραδιο ραδιοφωνικών μεταδόσεων των σχολιαστών και των κριτικών 
μπέιζ-μπώλ παιχνιδιών μπέιζ-μπώλ χρησιμοποίησε πολύ μελάνι 
κατά τη διάρκεια της δεκαετίας του '20 συζητώντας την ακριβείς 
φύση και τη σύνθεση αυτού του νέου και επεκτειμένος πληθυσμού 
ανεμιστήρων. Μερικοί η εισροή των νέων ανεμιστήρων στις 
αστικές εξέδρες, εν μέρει λόγω της αυξανόμενης διαφάνειας
στους λευκαντές των γιων και των κορών των ιταλικών, πολωνικών, 
και εβραϊκών μεταναστών εργατικών τάξεων, και εν μέρει επειδή 
το παιχνίδι φάνηκε από την προέλευσή του στην παραδοσιακή 
αγροτική και μικρού χωριού Αμερική. Ο ποιητής William 
Carlos Williams προκάλεσε την αυξανόμενη ποικιλομορφία των 
ανεμιστήρων του μπέιζ-μπώλ και του αντίκτυπού τους στο παιχνίδι 
"στο πλήθος στην Εξέδρα," δημοσιευμένος στον πίνακα το 
1923.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El renombre cada vez mayor del béisbol en los 
años 20 se puede medir por los cambios estructurales y culturales que
ayudaron a transformar el juego, incluyendo el edificio de estadios de béisbol
nuevos commodious; la aparición de las paginaciones de los 
deportes en periódicos urbanos diarios; y el renombre enorme de
las difusiones de radio de los comentaristas y de los críticos del 
béisbol games.Baseball expendió mucha tinta durante los años 20 que
discutían la naturaleza y la composición exactas de esta población 
nueva y que se ampliaba del ventilador. Algunos derided la 
afluencia de ventiladores nuevos a los estadios de béisbol urbanos, en parte 
debido a la visibilidad cada vez mayor en los blanqueadores de los 
hijos y de las hijas del italiano de la clase obrera, del pulimento, y
de los inmigrantes judíos, y en parte porque el juego se parecía 
perderse de sus orígenes en rural tradicional y la pequeño-ciudad 
América. El poeta Guillermo Carlos Williams evocó la 
diversidad cada vez mayor de los ventiladores del béisbol y su 
impacto en el juego en "la muchedumbre en el Estadio de béisbol," publicó en 
el dial en 1923.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086751</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103273</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/poet-william-carlos-williams-describes-the-crowd-at-the-ballpark</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
