<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107633</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107633</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202741</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Cask of Amontillado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Tonne von Amontillado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le tonneau d'Amontillado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O barril de Amontillado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il barile di Amontillado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το βαρέλι Amontillado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El barril de Amontillado</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The short story "The Cask of Amontillado," by Edgar Allan Poe is an effective venue for teaching English I literary terms. The following lesson plan is designed to engage the reader in a deeper than superficial reading of the text. It is also designed to elicit discussion and written critical-thinking responses. This lesson assumes that the literary terms have already been introduced. However, if they have not, the teacher may use this lesson to introduce these terms in the context of the literature.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die kurze Geschichte "die Tonne von Amontillado," 
durch Edgar Allan Poe ist ein wirkungsvoller Schauplatz für 
unterrichtendes Englisch I literarische Bezeichnungen. Der 
folgende Lektionplan ist konzipiert, um sich den Leser in einem tiefer
als oberflächlichen Messwert des Textes zu engagieren. Er ist 
auch konzipiert, um Diskussion und geschriebene kritisch-denkende 
Antworten herauszubekommen. Diese Lektion nimmt an, daß die 
literarischen Bezeichnungen bereits eingeführt worden sind. 
Jedoch wenn sie nicht haben, kann der Lehrer diese Lektion 
verwenden, um diese Bezeichnungen im Kontext der Literatur 
vorzustellen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'histoire courte "le tonneau d'Amontillado," par 
Edgar Allan Poe est un rendez-vous pertinent pour l'anglais 
d'enseignement I des limites littéraires. Le plan suivant de 
leçon est conçu pour engager le lecteur dans une lecture plus 
profondément que superficielle du texte. Il est également 
conçu pour obtenir la discussion et les réponses depensée écrites.
Cette leçon suppose que les limites littéraires ont été 
déjà présentées. Cependant, si elles démuni, le 
professeur peuvent employer cette leçon pour présenter ces limites 
dans le contexte de la littérature.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A história curta "o barril de Amontillado," por 
Edgar Allan Poe é um venue eficaz para o inglês ensinando I termos 
literários. A seguinte planta da lição é projetada acoplar o
leitor em uma leitura mais profundamente do que superficial do texto. 
É projetada também eliciar a discussão e respostas 
crítico-pensando escritas. Esta lição supõe que os termos 
literários têm sido introduzidos já. Entretanto, se não 
tiverem, o professor pode usar esta lição introduzir estes termos no
contexto da literatura.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La storia corta "il barile di Amontillado," da 
Edgar Allan Poe è una sede della riunione efficace per l'inglese 
d'istruzione I termini letterari. Il seguente programma di 
lezione è destinato per agganciare il lettore in una lettura più 
profondamente superficiale del testo. Egualmente è destinato 
per trarre la discussione e le risposte fuori critico-pensanti 
scritte. Questa lezione suppone che i termini letterari già 
sono stati introdotti. Tuttavia, se non hanno, l'insegnante può
usare questa lezione per introdurre questi termini nel contesto della 
letteratura.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η σύντομη ιστορία "το βαρέλι Amontillado," από τον 
Edgar Allan Poe είναι ένας αποτελεσματικός τόπος 
συναντήσεως για τους αγγλικούς ι λογοτεχνικούς όρους διδασκαλίας.
Το ακόλουθο σχέδιο μαθήματος σχεδιάζεται για να συμμετέχει 
τον αναγνώστη σε έναν βαθύτερο από την επιφανειακή ανάγνωση του 
κειμένου. Έχει ως σκοπό επίσης να αποσπάσει τη συζήτηση 
και τις γραπτές απαντήσεις κρίσιμος-σκέψης. Αυτό το μάθημα
υποθέτει ότι οι λογοτεχνικοί όροι έχουν εισαχθεί ήδη. 
Εντούτοις, εάν δεν έχουν, ο δάσκαλος μπορεί να 
χρησιμοποιήσει αυτό το μάθημα για να εισαγάγει αυτούς τους όρους
στα πλαίσια της λογοτεχνίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La historia corta "el barril de Amontillado," por 
Edgar Allan Poe es un lugar eficaz para el inglés de enseñanza I los
términos literarios. El plan siguiente de la lección se 
diseña para contratar al programa de lectura a una lectura más 
profundamente que superficial del texto. También se diseña 
para sacar la discusión y respuestas de cri'tico-pensamiento 
escritas. Esta lección asume que los términos literarios se 
han introducido ya. Sin embargo, si no tienen, el profesor puede
utilizar esta lección para introducir estos términos en el contexto 
de la literatura.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:GUY HILL
FN:GUY HILL
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CRYSTAL BROWN
FN:CRYSTAL BROWN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202741</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107633</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-cask-of-amontillado</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
