<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106936</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106936</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209802</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Arc Peripheral Angle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bogen-Peripheriegerät-Winkel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Angle de Périphérique d'Arc</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ângulo Do Peripheral Do Arco</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Angolo Dell'Unità periferica Dell'Arco</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Απομακρυσμένη γωνία τόξων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ángulo El Periférico Del Arco</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate the concept of the peripheral angle (inscribed angle) of an arc. This is the angle subtended at the circle circumference of an arc. The applet shows an arc with draggable end points and the angle it subtends at the circumference. It is seen that this angle is constant for a constant arc length. It shows also what happens when the vertex is inside the arc that subtends it The web page has links to other arc properties and a formula for the subtended angle for a given arc length. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die das Konzept des Zusatzwinkels (inscribed Winkel) eines 
Bogens zeigen. Dieses ist der Winkel subtended am Kreisumkreis 
eines Bogens. Der applet zeigt einen Bogen mit draggable Ende 
Punkten und dem Winkel es subtends am Umkreis. Es wird gesehen, 
daß dieser Winkel für eine konstante Bogenlänge konstant ist. 
Es zeigt auch, was geschieht, wenn der Gipfel innerhalb des 
Bogens ist, daß subtends es die Webseite Links zu anderen 
Bogeneigenschaften hat und eine Formel für Winkel für eine gegebene 
Bogenlänge subtended. Applet kann zum vollen Bildumfang für 
Gebrauch mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. 
Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von 
jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den 
benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein 
Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven 
Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent le concept de l'angle périphérique (angle 
inscrit) d'un arc. C'est l'angle subtended à la 
circonférence de cercle d'un arc. L'applet montre un arc avec 
les points finals draggable et l'angle il des subtends à la 
circonférence. On le voit que cet angle est constant pour une 
longueur constante d'arc. Il montre également ce qui se produit
quand le sommet est à l'intérieur de l'arc que les subtends il la 
page Web a des liens à d'autres propriétés d'arc et une formule 
pour subtended l'angle pour une longueur donnée d'arc. L'applet
peut être agrandi à la taille de plein écran pour l'usage avec un 
projecteur de salle de classe. Le après utilisation dans la 
salle de classe, étudiant peut lui accéder encore de n'importe quel 
navigateur de Web à la maison ou dans la bibliothèque sans la 
procédure de connexion exigée. Cette ressource est un 
composant du projet interactif de manuel de la géométrie de 
référence ouverte de maths à http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem o conceito do ângulo periférico (ângulo inscrito) de um 
arco. Este é o ângulo subtended na circunferência do círculo
de um arco. O applet mostra um arco com pontos de extremidade 
draggable e o ângulo ele subtends na circunferência. Vê-se 
que este ângulo é constante para um comprimento constante do arco. 
Mostra também o que acontece quando o vertex é dentro do arco 
que os subtends ele o Web page têm as ligações a outras 
propriedades do arco e uma fórmula para subtended o ângulo para um 
comprimento dado do arco. O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho 
de tela cheia para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. O 
depois de uso na sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez 
de todo o web browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de 
uma sessão requerido. Este recurso é um componente do projeto 
interativo do textbook da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano il concetto dell'angolo periferico (angolo inscribed) di un
arco. Ciò è l'angolo subtended alla circonferenza del cerchio 
di un arco. Il applet mostra un arco con i punti finali 
draggable e l'angolo esso subtends alla circonferenza. È visto 
che questo angolo è costante per una lunghezza costante dell'arco. 
Mostra egualmente che cosa accade quando il vertice è 
all'interno dell'arco che i subtends esso il Web page ha collegamenti 
ad altre proprietà dell'arco e una formula per subtended l'angolo per
una data lunghezza dell'arco. Il applet può essere ingrandito 
al formato di schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore dell'aula. 
La post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può accederle ancora 
da tutto il web browser nel paese o nella libreria senza l'inizio 
attività richiesto. Questa risorsa è un componente del 
progetto interattivo del manuale della geometria di riferimento aperto
di per la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν την έννοια της απομακρυσμένης γωνίας (εγγραμμένη 
γωνία) ενός τόξου. Αυτό είναι η γωνία που υποτείνεται 
στην περιφέρεια κύκλων ενός τόξου. Το applet εμφανίζει 
ένα τόξο με τα draggable σημεία τελών και τη γωνία που 
υποτείνει στην περιφέρεια. Βλέπει ότι αυτή η γωνία
είναι σταθερή για ένα σταθερό μήκος τόξων. Εμφανίζει 
επίσης τι συμβαίνει πότε vertex είναι μέσα στο τόξο που τον 
υποτείνει ιστοσελίδας έχει τις συνδέσεις με άλλες ιδιότητες 
τόξων και έναν τύπο για την υποτειμένη γωνία για ένα δεδομένο 
μήκος τόξων. Το Applet μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες 
μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με έναν προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά
από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε
τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη 
βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το
στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού 
προγράμματος εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού 
σε http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran el concepto del ángulo periférico (ángulo inscrito) de 
un arco. Éste es el ángulo subtended en la circunferencia del 
círculo de un arco. El applet muestra un arco con los puntos 
finales draggable y el ángulo él los subtends en la circunferencia. 
Se ve que este ángulo es constante para una longitud constante 
del arco. Muestra también qué sucede cuando la cima es dentro 
del arco que los subtends él el Web page tienen conexiones a otras 
características del arco y un fórmula para subtended el ángulo para
una longitud dada del arco. El applet se puede agrandar a la 
talla de la pantalla completa para el uso con un proyector de la sala 
de clase. El uso posterior en la sala de clase, estudiante puede
tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier web browser en el país o en la 
biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. Este recurso es un 
componente del proyecto interactivo del libro de textos de la 
geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas en 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209802</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106936</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/arc-peripheral-angle</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
