<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104040</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104040</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206902</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">To Know Ourselves</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sich Kennen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pour Se connaître</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Para conhecer-se</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Per conoscersi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Για να είναι γνωστός</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Para conocerse</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">tells about the Human Genome Project and provides general information about and links to the coordinated effort to determine the complete sequence of the DNA in the human genome. It surveys the project's goals, the tools being used to map genetic code, the spin-off technologies generated by the project, and the ethical, legal, and social implications of knowing our genetic blueprint.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erklärt über das menschliche Genom-Projekt und 
stellt allgemeine Informationen über und Links zur koordinierten 
Bemühung, die komplette Reihenfolge der DNA im menschlichen Genom 
festzustellen zur Verfügung. Es überblickt die Ziele des 
Projektes, die Hilfsmittel, die verwendet werden, genetischen Code 
abzubilden, die Zweittechnologien, die durch das Projekt und die 
ethischen, zugelassenen festgelegt werden, und Sozialimplikationen des
Kennens unserer genetischen Lichtpause.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dit au sujet du projet humain de génome et 
fournit des informations générales au sujet de et des liens à 
l'effort coordonné de déterminer l'ordre complet de l'ADN dans le 
génome humain. Il examine les buts du projet, les outils étant
utilisés pour tracer le code génétique, les technologies 
secondaires produites par le projet, et les implications morales, 
légales, et sociales de connaître notre modèle génétique.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">diz sobre o projeto humano do genome e fornece a 
informação geral sobre e as ligações ao esforço coordenado 
determinar a seqüência completa do DNA no genome humano. 
Examina os objetivos do projeto, as ferramentas que estão sendo
usadas traçar o código genetic, as tecnologias spin-off geradas pelo
projeto, e as implicações éticas, legais, e sociais de saber nosso 
blueprint genetic.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">dice a circa il progetto umano del genome e 
fornisce le generalità su ed i collegamenti allo sforzo coordinato 
determinare la sequenza completa del DNA nel genome umano. 
Esamina gli obiettivi del progetto, gli strumenti che usando 
tracciare il codice genetico, le tecnologie secondarie generate dal 
progetto e le implicazioni etiche, legali e sociali di conoscere il 
nostro modello genetico.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">λέει για το ανθρώπινο πρόγραμμα γονιδιώματος και 
παρέχει τις γενικές πληροφορίες για και τις συνδέσεις με τη 
συντονισμένη προσπάθεια να καθοριστεί η πλήρης ακολουθία του 
DNA στο ανθρώπινο γονιδίωμα. Ερευνά τους στόχους του 
προγράμματος, τα εργαλεία που χρησιμοποιούνται για να 
χαρτογραφήσουν το γενετικό κώδικα, οι τεχνολογίες υποπροϊόντος 
που παράγονται από το πρόγραμμα, και οι ηθικές, νομικές, και 
κοινωνικές επιπτώσεις της γνώσης του γενετικού σχεδιαγράμματός 
μας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">habla del proyecto humano del Genoma y 
proporciona a la información de carácter general sobre y a 
conexiones al esfuerzo coordinado de determinar la secuencia completa 
de la DNA en el genoma humano. Examina las metas del 
proyecto, las herramientas que son utilizadas asociar código 
genético, las tecnologías spin-off generadas por el proyecto, y las 
implicaciones éticas, legales, y sociales de saber nuestro modelo 
genético.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206902</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104040</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/to-know-ourselves</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
