<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/1851512614</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>1851512614</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206050</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Exploring the Moon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erforschen des Mondes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Explorer la lune</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Explorando a lua</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Esplorazione della luna</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εξερεύνηση του φεγγαριού</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Explorar la luna</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a teacher's guide for learning about lunar geology and regolith (loose material on the moon's surface), distance to the moon, Apollo landing sites, and life support systems. Lessons focus on calculating the distance between scale models of earth and the moon, designing a spacecraft for travel to and from the moon, the locations and geology of the six Apollo landing sites, and calculating the diameter of the moon using proportions.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist die Anleitung eines Lehrers für das Lernen 
über Mondgeologie und Regolith (loses Material auf der Oberfläche 
des Mondes), Abstand zu den Mond-, Apollo Landungsites und zu den 
Lebenserhaltungssystemen. Lektionen konzentrieren auf die 
Berechnung des Abstandes zwischen den Skalamodellen von Masse und dem 
Mond, konzipieren ein Raumfahrzeug für Spielraum nach und von dem 
Mond, den Standorten und Geologie der sechs Apollo Landungsites, und 
errechnen den Durchmesser des Mondes mit Anteilen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est le guide d'un professeur pour se renseigner 
sur la géologie lunaire et le régolithe (matière non fixée sur la 
surface de la lune), la distance aux sites de lune, d'atterrissage 
d'Apollo, et aux appareils respiratoires. Les leçons se 
concentrent sur calculer la distance entre les modèles d'échelle de 
la terre et la lune, concevant un vaisseau spatial pour le voyage à 
et de la lune, des emplacements et de la géologie des six sites 
d'atterrissage d'Apollo, et calculant le diamètre de la lune en 
utilisant des proportions.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é a guia de um professor para a aprendizagem 
sobre a geologia lunar e o regolith (material frouxo na superfície da
lua), a distância aos locais da lua, da aterragem de Apollo, e aos 
sistemas de sustentação de vida. As lições focalizam em 
calcular a distância entre os modelos da escala da terra e a lua, 
projetando uma nave espacial para o curso a e da lua, das posições e
da geologia dos seis locais da aterragem de Apollo, e calculando o 
diâmetro da lua usando proporções.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è la guida dell'insegnante per imparare circa la 
geologia lunare e la regolite (materiale sfuso sulla superficie della 
luna), la distanza ai luoghi di atterraggio dell'Apollo, della luna ed
ai sustemi di sopravvivenza. Le lezioni mettono a fuoco sulla 
calcolazione della distanza fra i modelli della scala di terra e la 
luna, progettanti una nave spaziale per la corsa a e da la luna, le 
posizioni e la geologia dei sei luoghi di atterraggio dell'Apollo e 
calcolatori il diametro della luna usando le proporzioni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι ο οδηγός ενός δασκάλου για την εκμάθηση για τη 
σεληνιακή γεωλογία και regolith (χαλαρό υλικό στην επιφάνεια 
του φεγγαριού), την απόσταση στο φεγγάρι, τις προσγειωμένος 
περιοχές απόλλωνα, και τα συστήματα υποστήριξης ζωής. Τα 
μαθήματα εστιάζουν στον υπολογισμό της απόστασης μεταξύ των 
μοντέλων κλίμακας της γης και του φεγγαριού, που σχεδιάζουν ένα 
διαστημικό σκάφος για το ταξίδι σε και από το φεγγάρι, τις 
θέσεις και τη γεωλογία των έξι προσγειωμένος περιοχών απόλλωνα, 
και που υπολογίζουν τη διάμετρο του φεγγαριού χρησιμοποιώντας τις 
αναλογίες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es la guía de un profesor para aprender sobre la 
geología lunar y el regolith (material flojo en la superficie de la 
luna), la distancia a los sitios de la luna, del aterrizaje de Apolo, 
y a los sistemas de ayuda de vida. Las lecciones se centran en 
calcular la distancia entre los modelos de la escala de la tierra y la
luna, diseñando una nave espacial para el recorrido a y desde la 
luna, las localizaciones y la geología de los seis sitios del 
aterrizaje de Apolo, y calculando el diámetro de la luna usando 
proporciones.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206050</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>1851512614</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/exploring-the-moon</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
