<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103209</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103209</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086980</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Los Angeles Dressmakers Strike of 1933: Anita Andrade Castro Becomes a Union Activist</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Los Angeles Damenschneiderin-Schlag von 1933: 
Anita Andrade Castro steht einem Anschluß-Aktivisten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La grève de couturières de Los Angeles de 1933 : 
Anita Andrade Castro va bien à un activiste des syndicats</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A batida das costureiras de Los Angeles de 1933: 
Anita Andrade Castro assenta bem em uma activista da união</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il colpo dei sarti da donna de Los Angeles di 1933:
Anita Andrade Castro sta bene ad un Attivista del sindacato</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η απεργία μοδιστρών του Λος Αντζελες του 1933: 
Ανητα Andrade Castro Becomes ένα ενεργό στέλεχος 
ένωσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La huelga de las modistas de Los Ángeles de 1933: 
Anita Andrade Castro siente bien a un activista de la unión</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In October 1933 Chicana dressmakers in Los Angeles launched a citywide strike against the sweatshop conditions under which they toiled. An interview with Anita Andrade Castro, a young dressmaker who went on to become a longtime union activist, provided glimpses of the experience of the rank-and-file strikers. In two excerpts from a long interview done in 1972 by historian Sherna Gluck for the Feminist History Research Project, Castro described, first, her initiation into the union and, second, her arrest as a striker, her anxieties about the impact on her desire to become a citizen, and her encounter with a prostitute.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im Oktober 1933 Chicana stießen 
Damenschneiderinnen in Los Angeles einen in der ganzen Stadt Schlag 
gegen die Fabrik mit schlechten Arbeitsbedingungenzustände aus, unter
denen sie abplagten. Ein Interview mit Anita Andrade 
Castro, eine junge Damenschneiderin, die fortfuhr, ein langfristiger 
Anschlußaktivist zu werden, vorausgesetzt Blicke der Erfahrung der 
Ordnen-unddatei Schlaggeräte. In zwei Excerpts von einem langen
Interview erfolgt 1972 mit Historiker Sherna Gluck für das 
feministische Geschichte Forschung Projekt, Castro beschrieben, 
erstes, ihre Inbetriebnahme in den Anschluß und, Sekunde, ihr 
Anhalten als Schlaggerät, ihre Ängste um die Auswirkung auf ihren 
Wunsch, ein Bürger zu werden und ihr Treffen mit einem 
Prostituierteen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En octobre 1933 Chicana les couturières à Los 
Angeles ont lancé une grève partout dans la ville contre les 
conditions de bagne dans lesquels elles travaillent fort. Une 
entrevue avec Anita Andrade Castro, une jeune couturière qui a 
continué pour devenir un activiste à long terme des syndicats, si 
aperçus de l'expérience des butées de ranger-et-fichier. Dans
deux extraits d'une longue entrevue faite en 1972 par l'historien 
Sherna Gluck pour le projet de recherche féministe d'histoire, 
Castro décrit, le premier, son déclenchement dans l'union et, 
seconde, son arrestation comme butée, ses inquiétudes au sujet de 
l'impact sur son désir de devenir un citoyen, et sa rencontre avec 
une prostituée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em outubro 1933 Chicana as costureiras em Los 
Angeles lançaram uma batida citywide de encontro às condições do 
sweatshop sob que labutam. Uma entrevista com Anita Andrade 
Castro, uma costureira nova que fosse sobre se transformar uma 
activista longtime da união, desde que glimpses da experiência dos 
grevistas da espesso-e-lima. Em dois excerpts de uma entrevista 
longa feita em 1972 pelo historian Sherna Gluck para o projeto de 
pesquisa feminista do history, Castro descrito, primeiro, sua 
iniciação na união e, segundo, sua apreensão como um grevista, 
suas ansiedades sobre o impacto em seu desejo transformar-se um 
cidadão, e seu encontro com um prostitute.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nel mese di ottobre 1933 Chicana i sarti da donna a
Los Angeles hanno lanciato un colpo citywide contro gli stati 
dell'azienda che sfrutta la manodopera in cui lavorano duramente. 
Un'intervista con Anita Andrade Castro, un sarto da donna 
giovane che ha continuato a diventare un attivista da molto tempo del 
sindacato, se glimpses dell'esperienza nei percussori 
dell'alline-e-archivio. In due brani da un'intervista lunga 
fatta in 1972 dallo storico Sherna Gluck per il progetto di ricerca 
femminista di storia, Castro descritto, il primo, il suo inizio 
nell'unione e, il secondo, il suo arresto come percussore, le sue 
ansie circa l'effetto sul suo desiderio transformarsi in in un 
cittadino ed il suo incontro con un prostitute.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τον Οκτώβριο του 1933 οι μοδίστρες Chicana στο Λος
Αντζελες προώθησαν μια αστικού επιπέδού απεργία ενάντια στους 
όρους σκλαβοπάζαρο κάτω από τους οποίους κοπίασαν. Μια 
συνέντευξη με Ανητα Andrade Castro, μια νέα μοδίστρα που 
πήγε για να γίνει μακροπρόθεσμο ενεργό στέλεχος ένωσης, υπό τον
όρο ότι αναλαμπές της εμπειρίας των απεργών πυκνός-και-αρχείων.
Σε δύο αποσπάσματα από μια μακροχρόνια συνέντευξη που 
γίνεται το 1972 από τον ιστορικό Sherna Gluck για το 
φεμινιστικό ερευνητικό πρόγραμμα ιστορίας, Castro που 
περιγράφεται, πρώτα, η έναρξή της στην ένωση και, δευτερόλεπτο, 
τη σύλληψή της ως απεργό, οι ανησυχίες της για τον αντίκτυπο στην
επιθυμία της να γίνει πολίτης, και η σύγκρουσή της με μια πόρνη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En octubre 1933 de Chicana las modistas en Los 
Ángeles lanzaron una huelga citywide contra las condiciones de la 
fábrica de explotación bajo las cuales trabajan. Una 
entrevista con Anita Andrade Castro, modista joven que continuó hacer
un activista de largo plazo de la unión, con tal que ojeadas de la 
experiencia de los huelguistas del alinear-y-fichero. En dos 
extractos de una entrevista larga hecha en 1972 del historiador Sherna
Gluck para el proyecto de investigación feminista de la historia, 
Castro descrito, el primer, su lanzamiento en la unión y, el segundo,
su detención como huelguista, sus ansiedades sobre el impacto en su 
deseo de hacer un ciudadano, y su encuentro con una prostitute.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086980</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103209</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-los-angeles-dressmakers-strike-of-1933-anita-andrade-castro-becomes-a-union-activist</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
