<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108404</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108404</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086674</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Nobody Would Eat Kraut": Lola Gamble Clyde on Anti-German Sentiment in Idaho During World War I</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Niemand Würde Kraut" Essen: Lola 
Glücksspiel Clyde auf Anti-Deutschem Gefühl in Idaho während des 
Ersten Weltkrieges</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Personne Ne mangerait Kraut" : Jeu Clyde de
Lola sur le sentiment Anti-Allemand en Idaho pendant la Première 
Guerre Mondiale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Ninguém Comeria Kraut": Gamble Clyde de 
Lola no sentiment Anti-Alemão em Idaho durante o world.war.i</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Nessuno Mangerebbe Kraut": Gioco Clyde di 
Lola sul sentimento Anti-Tedesco nell'Idaho durante il world.war.i</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Κανένας δεν θα έτρωγε Kraut": Τυχερό 
παιχνίδι Clyde Lola στο αντι-γερμανικό συναίσθημα στο 
Idaho κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου Ι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Nadie Comería Kraut": Juego Clyde de Lola 
en el sentimiento Contra-Alema'n en Idaho durante Primera Guerra 
Mundial</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">When the United States went to war against Germany in 1917, German Americans faced vicious and unfair attacks on their loyalty. Many anti-German incidents were not recorded, but they lived on powerfully in people's memories. In this 1976 interview, Lola Gamble Clyde, the daughter of an Irish-born Presbyterian minister and a teenager during World War I, described the "hysteria" that faced German Americans in rural Latah County, Idaho.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Als die Vereinigten Staaten war gegen Deutschland 
1917 gingen, stellten deutsche Amerikaner die schändlichen und 
unfairen Angriffe auf ihrer Loyalität gegenüber. Viele 
Anti-Deutsche Ereignisse wurden nicht gespeichert, aber sie lebten an 
leistungsfähig in den Speichern der Leute. In diesem Interview 
1976 beschrieben Lola Glücksspiel Clyde, die Tochter eines 
Irisch-getragenen presbyterianischen Ministers und des Jugendlichen 
während des Ersten Weltkrieges, die "Hysterie", die deutsche 
Amerikaner in der landwirtschaftlichen Latah Grafschaft 
gegenüberstellte, Idaho.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Quand les Etats-Unis sont allés faire la guerre 
contre l'Allemagne en 1917, les Américains allemands ont fait face à
des attaques méchantes et injustes sur leur fidélité. 
Beaucoup d'incidents anti-Allemands n'ont pas été 
enregistrés, mais ils ont vécu en fonction puissant dans les 
mémoires des personnes. Dans cette entrevue 1976, le jeu Clyde 
de Lola, la fille d'un ministre presbytérien Irlandais-soutenu et 
d'un adolescent pendant la Première Guerre Mondiale, ont décrit 
l'"hystérie" qui s'est posée aux Américains allemands dans le 
comté rural de Latah, l'Idaho.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quando os estados unidos foram guerrear de 
encontro a Germany em 1917, os americanos alemães enfrentaram ataques
vicious e unfair em sua lealdade. Muitos incidents anti-Alemães
não foram gravados, mas viveram sobre poderosa em memórias do 
pessoa. Nesta entrevista 1976, o gamble Clyde de Lola, a filha 
de um ministro presbyterian Irish-carregado e de um teenager durante o
world.war.i, descreveram o "hysteria" que enfrentou americanos 
alemães no condado rural de Latah, Idaho.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Quando unito Dichiara è andato fare la 
guerra contro la Germania in 1917, gli Americani tedeschi hanno 
affrontato gli attacchi viziosi ed ingiusti alla loro lealtà. 
Molti avvenimenti anti-Tedeschi non sono stati registrati, ma 
hanno vissuto sopra potente nelle memorie della gente. In questa
intervista 1976, il gioco Clyde di Lola, la figlia di un ministro 
presbyterian Irlandese-sopportato e di un adolescente durante il 
world.war.i, hanno descritto "il hysteria" che ha posto agli Americani
tedeschi nella contea rurale di Latah, l'Idaho.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Όταν οι Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες πήγαν στον πόλεμο ενάντια
στη Γερμανία το 1917, γερμανικοί Αμερικανοί αντιμετώπισαν 
κακοήθεις και άδικες επίθεση στην πίστη τους. Πολλά 
αντι-γερμανικά γεγονότα δεν καταγράφηκαν, αλλά έζησαν επάνω με 
δύναμη στις μνήμες των ανθρώπων. Σε αυτήν την συνέντευξη 
του 1976, Lola το τυχερό παιχνίδι Clyde, η κόρη ενός 
ιρλανδικός-γεννημένου Πρεσβυτεριανού υπουργού και ενός εφήβου 
κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου Ι, περιέγραψαν τη 
"υστερία" που αντιμετώπισε γερμανικούς Αμερικανούς στον αγροτικό 
Latah νομό, Idaho.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cuando los Estados Unidos fueron a guerrear contra
Alemania en 1917, los americanos alemanes hicieron frente a ataques 
viciosos e injustos contra su lealtad. Muchos incidentes 
contra-Alemanes no fueron registrados, sino que vivieron encendido de 
gran alcance en las memorias de la gente. En esta entrevista 
1976, el juego Clyde de Lola, la hija de un ministro presbyterian 
Irlande's-llevado y de un adolescente durante Primera Guerra Mundial, 
describieron la "histeria" que hizo frente a americanos alemanes en el
condado rural de Latah, Idaho.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086674</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108404</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/nobody-would-eat-kraut-lola-gamble-clyde-on-anti-german-sentiment-in-idaho-during-world-war-i</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
