<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104725</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104725</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206031</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">National Energy Technology Laboratory's Cool Science and Technology</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kühle Wissenschaft und Technologie des nationales
Energie-Technologie-Labors</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science fraîche et la technologie d'énergie 
du laboratoire national de technologie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência fresca e tecnologia do laboratório 
nacional da tecnologia da energia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza fredda e tecnologia di energia del 
laboratorio nazionale di tecnologia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δροσερές επιστήμη και τεχνολογία του εθνικού 
ενεργειακού εργαστηρίου τεχνολογίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia fresca y tecnología de la energía del 
laboratorio nacional de la tecnología</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">provides lessons and experiments -- created by teachers, scientists, and engineers -- on a range of energy-related topics: acid water from coal mines, biomass size reduction, clean air research, carbon dioxide sequestration, co-burning biomass and coal, fluidized bed combustion, fuel cell technology, gas vortices, landfill management, parallel computing, passive acid mine drainage, and phytoremediation (using plants to clean up the environment).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt die Lektionen und Experimente -- erstellt 
von den Lehrern, von den Wissenschaftlern und von den Ingenieuren -- 
auf einer Strecke der energiebezogenen Themen zur Verfügung: 
saures Wasser von den Kohlengruben, Lebendmassezerkleinern, 
saubere Luftforschung, Kohlendioxydabsonderung, Co-brennende 
Lebendmasse und Kohle, Flüssigbettverbrennung, Kraftstoffzelle 
Technologie, Gasturbulenzen, Aufschüttungmanagement, paralleles 
Rechnen, passive saure Grube Entwässerung und phytoremediation 
(Betriebe verwendend, um herauf die Umgebung zu säubern).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fournit des leçons et des expériences -- 
créées par des professeurs, des scientifiques, et des ingénieurs --
sur un intervalle des sujets énergétiques : l'eau acide des 
mines de houille, réduction de la taille de biomasse, recherche 
propre d'air, séquestration d'anhydride carbonique, biomasse et 
charbon debrûlure, combustion à lit fluidisé, technologie de 
cellules de carburant, des vortexes de gaz, gestion de remblai, 
calcul parallèle, drainage acide passif de mine, et phytoremediation 
(employant des usines pour nettoyer l'environnement).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fornece as lições e as experiências -- criadas 
por professores, por cientistas, e por coordenadores -- em uma escala 
de tópicos energy-related: a água ácida das minas de carvão,
da redução de tamanho do biomass, pesquisa limpa do ar, 
sequestration do dióxido de carbono, biomass dequeimadura e carvão, 
fluidized a combustão da cama, a tecnologia da célula combustível, 
os vortices do gás, a gerência do landfill, a paralela que computam,
a drenagem ácida passiva da mina, e o phytoremediation (que usa 
plantas limpar acima do ambiente).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fornisce le lezioni e gli esperimenti -- creati 
dagli insegnanti, dagli scienziati e dagli assistenti tecnici -- su 
una gamma di soggetti energetici: acqua acida dalle miniere di 
carbone, riduzione di misura della biomassa, ricerca pulita dell'aria,
sequestro dell'anidride carbonica, biomassa e carbone co-bruciantesi, 
combustione a letto fluidizzato, tecnologia delle cellule di 
combustibile, vortici del gas, gestione del materiale di riporto, 
computazione parallela, drenaggio acido passivo della miniera e 
phytoremediation (che usando le piante per pulire l'ambiente).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρέχει τα μαθήματα και τα πειράματα -- που 
δημιουργούνται από τους δασκάλους, τους επιστήμονες, και τους 
μηχανικούς -- σε μια σειρά των σχετικών με την ενέργεια θεμάτων: 
το όξινο ύδωρ από τα ορυχεία άνθρακα, τη μείωση μεγέθους 
βιομαζών, την καθαρή έρευνα αέρα, την απομάκρυνση διοξειδίου του
άνθρακα, την ομο-καίγοντας βιομάζα και τον άνθρακα, ρευστοποίησε 
την καύση κρεβατιών, την τεχνολογία κυττάρων καυσίμων, αέριο
τις δίνες, τη διαχείριση υλικών οδόστρωσης, τον παράλληλο 
υπολογίζοντας, την παθητική όξινη αποξήρανση ορυχείων, και τη 
φυτοθεραπεία (που χρησιμοποιεί τις εγκαταστάσεις για να καθαρίσει 
επάνω το περιβάλλον).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">proporciona a las lecciones y a los experimentos 
-- creados por los profesores, los científicos, y los ingenieros -- 
en un rango de asuntos energéticos: agua ácida de minas de 
carbón, reducción de talla de la biomasa, investigación limpia del 
aire, secuestro del bióxido de carbono, biomasa y carbón co-que se 
quema, combustión de estrato fluidificado, tecnología de la célula 
de combustible, vórtices del gas, gerencia del terraplén, el 
computar paralelo, drenaje ácido pasivo de la mina, y 
phytoremediation (que usa las plantas para limpiar encima del 
ambiente).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206031</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104725</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/national-energy-technology-laboratorys-cool-science-and-technology</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
