<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106073</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106073</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1651176673</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">AP Physics C</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">AP Physik C</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Physique C de AP</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Física C do Ap</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fisica C di Ap</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Φυσική γ AP</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Física C del Ap</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This curriculum covers all of the material outlined by the College Board as necessary to prepare students to pass the AP Physics C exam. This course is designed to acquaint you with topics in mechanics and classical electricity and magnetism. The course covers two semesters. The first semester is devoted to Newtonian mechanics including: kinematics, laws of motion, work and energy, systems of particles, momentum, circular motion, oscillations, and gravitation. The second semester discusses the topics of electricity and magnetism. The course emphasizes problem solving including calculus, and there are numerous interactive examples throughout. You will also gain laboratory experience through interactive lab simulations and wet labs.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser Lehrplan umfaßt die ganze Material, das 
durch das Hochschulgremium wie benötigt, Kursteilnehmer 
vorzubereiten, die Prüfung der AP Physik zu führen C umrissen wird. 
Dieser Kurs ist konzipiert, um Sie mit Themen in den Mechanikern
und klassische Elektrizität und Magnetismus mitzuteilen. Der 
Kurs umfaßt zwei Semester. Das erste Semester wird newtonischen
Mechanikern einschließlich gewidmet: Kinematik, Gesetze der 
Bewegung, Arbeit und Energie, Systeme der Partikel, Momentum, 
kreisförmige Bewegung, Pendelbewegungen und Gravitation. Das 
zweite Semester behandelt die Themen von Elektrizität und von 
Magnetismus. Der Kurs hebt das Lösen von Problemen 
einschließlich Kalkül hervor, und es gibt zahlreiche interaktive 
Beispiele gänzlich. Sie gewinnen auch Laborerfahrung durch 
interaktive Laborsimulationen und nasse Labors.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce programme d'études couvre tout le matériel 
tracé les grandes lignes par le conseil d'université selon les 
besoins pour préparer des étudiants passer l'examen de la physique C
de AP. Ce cours est conçu pour vous mettre au courant des 
sujets en mécanique et électricité et magnétisme classiques. 
Le cours couvre deux semestres. Le premier semestre est 
consacré à la mécanique newtonienne comprenant : 
cinématique, lois de mouvement, travail et énergie, systèmes 
des particules, élan, mouvement circulaire, oscillations, et 
attraction universelle. Le deuxième semestre discute les sujets
de l'électricité et du magnétisme. Le cours souligne la 
résolution des problèmes comprenant le calcul, et il y a de nombreux
exemples interactifs partout. Vous acquerrez également 
l'expérience de laboratoire par des simulations interactives de 
laboratoire et des laboratoires humides.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este curriculum cobre todo o material esboçado 
pela placa de faculdade como necessário preparar estudantes para 
passar o exam da física C do AP. Este curso é projetado 
familiarizá-lo com os tópicos nos mecânicos e eletricidade e 
magnetismo classical. O curso cobre dois semesters. O 
primeiro semester é devotado aos mecânicos newtonian including: 
kinematics, leis do movimento, trabalho e energia, sistemas das 
partículas, momentum, movimento circular, oscilações, e 
gravitação. O segundo semester discute os tópicos da 
eletricidade e do magnetismo. O curso emfatiza resolver de 
problema including o cálculo, e há uns exemplos interativos 
numerosos throughout. Você ganhará também a experiência do 
laboratório através das simulações interativas do laboratório e 
dos laboratórios molhados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo programma di studi tratta tutto il 
materiale descritto dal Bordo dell'università come necessario 
preparare gli allievi per passare il exam di fisica C di AP. 
Questo corso è destinato per informarlo dei soggetti in 
meccanici ed elettricità e magnetismo classici. Il corso 
riguarda due semestri. Il primo semestre è dedicato ai 
meccanici newtoniani compreso: cinematica, leggi di movimento, 
lavoro ed energia, sistemi delle particelle, quantità di moto, 
movimento circolare, oscillazioni e gravitazione. Il secondo 
semestre discute i soggetti di elettricità e di magnetismo. Il 
corso dà risalto alla soluzione dei problemi compreso il calcolo e ci
sono esempi interattivi numerosi dappertutto. Egualmente 
guadagnerete l'esperienza del laboratorio attraverso le simulazioni 
interattive del laboratorio ed i laboratori bagnati.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το πρόγραμμα σπουδών καλύπτει όλο το υλικό που 
περιγράφεται από τον πίνακα κολλεγίου για να προετοιμάσει 
ανάλογα με τις ανάγκες τους σπουδαστές για να περάσει το 
διαγωνισμό φυσικής γ AP. Αυτή η σειρά μαθημάτων 
σχεδιάζεται για να σας εξοικειώσει με τα θέματα στους μηχανικούς 
και την κλασσικούς ηλεκτρική ενέργεια και το μαγνητισμό. Η 
σειρά μαθημάτων καλύπτει δύο εξάμηνα. Το πρώτο εξάμηνο 
αφιερώνεται στους νευτώνειους μηχανικούς συμπεριλαμβανομένου: 
kinematics, νόμοι της κίνησης, της εργασίας και της 
ενέργειας, των συστημάτων των μορίων, της ορμής, της κυκλικής 
κίνησης, των ταλαντώσεων, και της βαρύτητας. Το δεύτερο 
εξάμηνο συζητά τα θέματα της ηλεκτρικής ενέργειας και του 
μαγνητισμού. Η σειρά μαθημάτων υπογραμμίζει την επίλυση 
προβλήματος συμπεριλαμβανομένου του υπολογισμού, και υπάρχουν 
πολυάριθμα διαλογικά παραδείγματα. Θα αποκτήσετε επίσης την
εργαστηριακή εμπειρία μέσω των διαλογικών προσομοιώσεων 
εργαστηρίων και των υγρών εργαστηρίων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este plan de estudios cubre todo el material 
contorneado por la tarjeta de universidad como necesaria para preparar
a estudiantes para aprobar el examen de la física C del AP. 
Este curso se diseña para conocerle de asuntos en mecánicos y 
electricidad y magnetismo clásicos. El curso cubre dos 
semestres. El primer semestre se dedica a los mecánicos 
neutonianos incluyendo: cinemática, leyes del movimiento, 
trabajo y energía, sistemas de partículas, ímpetu, movimiento 
circular, oscilaciones, y gravitación. El segundo semestre 
discute los asuntos de la electricidad y del magnetismo. El 
curso acentúa solucionar de problema incluyendo cálculo, y hay 
ejemplos interactivos numerosos en todas partes. Usted también 
ganará experiencia del laboratorio a través de simulaciones 
interactivas del laboratorio y de laboratorios mojados.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:UNKNOWN
FN:UNKNOWN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1651176673</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106073</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/ap-physics-c</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
