<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105041</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105041</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205626</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Plan for a panel discussion regarding the validity of the Lincoln Administration</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Plan für eine Paneldiskussion betreffend ist die 
Gültigkeit der Lincoln Leitung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Plan pour une discussion de panneau concernant la 
validité de la gestion de Lincoln</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Planta para uma discussão do painel a respeito da 
validez da administração de Lincoln</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Programma per una discussione del pannello per 
quanto riguarda la validità della gestione de Lincoln</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σχέδιο για μια συζήτηση επιτροπής σχετικά με την ισχύ
της κυβέρνησης του Λίνκολν</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Plan para una discusión del panel con respecto a 
la validez de la administración de Lincoln</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Many of the events surrounding the American Civil War era have become national myths rather than accurate historical facts. This paradigm can be rationalized as a need for national healing. This lesson encourages students to investigate all sides of the issues within the context of the Civil War era. This will contribute to an understanding of the actual events that were catalysts for Lincoln's executive decisions. Students will become "experts" on the Lincoln administration and accept the responsibility of sharing their expertise with their classmates through oral communication in a panel discussion. They will also be responsible for turning in the written work produced as a result of their research, as well as developing a handout and perhaps a visual aid, as they see fit.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Viele der Fälle, welche die amerikanische 
Bürgerkriegära umgeben, haben gewordene nationale Mythen anstatt 
genaue historische Tatsachen. Dieses Paradigma kann als 
Notwendigkeit am nationalen Heilend rationalisiert werden. Diese
Lektion regt Kursteilnehmer an, alle Seiten der Ausgaben innerhalb des
Kontextes der Bürgerkriegära nachzuforschen. Dieses trägt zu 
einem Verständnis der tatsächlichen Fälle bei, die Katalysatoren 
für Lincolns Executiventscheidungen waren. Kursteilnehmer 
werden "Experten" auf der Lincoln Leitung und nehmen die 
Verantwortlichkeit des Teilens ihrer Sachkenntnis mit ihren 
Mitschülern durch Mundkommunikation in einer Paneldiskussion an. 
Sie sind auch für das Drehen in die schriftliche Arbeit 
verantwortlich, die resultierend aus ihrer Forschung, sowie das 
Entwickeln eines Mitteilungsblattes und möglicherweise des 
Sichthilfsmittels produziert wird, wie sie Sitz sehen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Plusieurs des événements entourant l'ère 
américaine de guerre civile ont des mythes nationaux devenus plutôt 
que des faits historiques précis. Ce paradigme peut être 
rationalisé comme besoin de curatif national. Cette leçon 
encourage des étudiants à étudier tous les côtés des issues dans 
le contexte de l'ère de guerre civile. Ceci contribuera à un 
arrangement des événements réels qui étaient des catalyseurs pour 
les décisions exécutives de Lincoln. Les étudiants 
deviendront des "experts" en gestion de Lincoln et recevront la 
responsabilité de partager leur expertise avec leurs camarades de 
classe par la transmission orale dans une discussion de panneau. 
Ils seront également responsables de la rotation dans le 
travail écrit produit en raison de leur recherche, aussi bien que 
développer une aumône et peut-être une aide visuelle, comme ils 
voient l'ajustement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Muitos dos eventos que cercam a era americana da 
guerra civil têm mitos nacionais tornados melhor que fatos 
históricos exatos. Este paradigm pode rationalized como uma 
necessidade para healing nacional. Esta lição incentiva 
estudantes investigar todos os lados das edições dentro do contexto 
da era da guerra civil. Isto contribuirá a uma compreensão dos
eventos reais que eram catalizadores para as decisões executivas de 
Lincoln. Os estudantes transformar-se-ão "peritos" na 
administração de Lincoln e aceitar-se-ão a responsabilidade de 
compartilhar de sua perícia com seus classmates com uma comunicação
oral em uma discussão do painel. Serão também responsáveis 
para girar no trabalho escrito produzido em conseqüência de sua 
pesquisa, as.well.as desenvolver um handout e talvez um dae 
(dispositivo automático de entrada) visual, como vêem o ajuste.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Molti degli eventi che circondano l'era americana 
di guerra civile hanno i miti nazionali diventati piuttosto che fatti 
storici esatti. Questo paradigma può essere razionalizzato come
esigenza del healing nazionale. Questa lezione consiglia agli 
allievi studiare tutti i lati delle edizioni all'interno del contesto 
dell'era di guerra civile. Ciò contribuirà ad una comprensione
degli eventi reali che erano catalizzatori per le decisioni esecutive 
de Lincoln. Gli allievi diventeranno "esperti" sulla gestione de
Lincoln ed accetteranno la responsabilità di compartecipazione della 
loro perizia con i loro classmates con la comunicazione orale in una 
discussione del pannello. Egualmente saranno responsabili della 
rotazione nel lavoro scritto prodotto come conseguenza della loro 
ricerca, così come sviluppare una dispensa e forse un sussidio 
visivo, come vedono la misura.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πολλά από τα γεγονότα που περιβάλλουν την αμερικανική
εποχή εμφύλιου πολέμου έχουν γίνει εθνικοί μύθοι παρά τα 
ακριβή ιστορικά γεγονότα. Αυτό το παράδειγμα μπορεί να 
οργανωθεί ορθολογικά ως ανάγκη για την εθνική θεραπεία. 
Αυτό το μάθημα ενθαρρύνει τους σπουδαστές για να ερευνήσει 
όλες τις πλευρές των ζητημάτων μέσα στο πλαίσιο της εποχής 
εμφύλιου πολέμου. Αυτό θα συμβάλει σε μια κατανόηση των 
πραγματικών γεγονότων που ήταν καταλύτες για τις εκτελεστικές 
αποφάσεις του Λίνκολν. Οι σπουδαστές θα γίνουν 
"εμπειρογνώμονεσ" στην κυβέρνηση του Λίνκολν και θα αποδεχθούν την
ευθύνη την εξοικείωσή τους με τους συμμαθητές τους μέσω της 
προφορικής επικοινωνίας σε μια συζήτηση επιτροπής. Θα είναι
επίσης αρμόδιοι για τη στροφή στη γραπτή εργασία που παράγεται 
ως αποτέλεσμα της έρευνάς τους, καθώς επίσης και την ανάπτυξη 
ενός φυλλάδιου και ίσως ένα οπτικό βοήθημα, δεδομένου ότι 
βλέπουνε την τακτοποίηση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Muchos de los acontecimientos que rodean la era 
americana de la guerra civil tienen mitos nacionales convertidos más 
bien que hechos históricos exactos. Este paradigma se puede 
racionalizar como necesidad de curativo nacional. Esta lección 
anima a estudiantes que investiguen todas las caras de las ediciones 
dentro del contexto de la era de la guerra civil. Esto 
contribuirá a una comprensión de los acontecimientos reales que eran
catalizadores para las decisiones ejecutivas de Lincoln. Los 
estudiantes harán "expertos" en la administración de Lincoln y 
validarán la responsabilidad de compartir su maestría con sus 
classmates con la comunicación oral en una discusión del panel. 
También serán responsable de dar vuelta en el trabajo escrito 
producido como resultado de su investigación, así como desarrollar 
un folleto y quizás una ayuda visual, como ven ajuste.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JAMIE HULSE
FN:JAMIE HULSE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205626</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105041</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/plan-for-a-panel-discussion-regarding-the-validity-of-the-lincoln-administration</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
