<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108665</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108665</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206880</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Establishing Borders: The Expansion of the United States, 1846-48</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Herstellen Der Ränder: Die Expansion der 
Vereinigten Staaten, 1846-48</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Établissement des Cadres : L'expansion des 
Etats-Unis, 1846-48</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Estabelecendo Beiras: A expansão dos estados
unidos, 1846-48</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Stabilizzazione Dei Bordi: L'espansione del 
unito Dichiara, 1846-48</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Καθιέρωση των συνόρων: Επέκταση των Ηνωμένων 
Πολιτειών, 1846-48</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Establecer Las Fronteras: La extensión de 
los Estados Unidos, 1846-48</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">offers geography and history activities showing how two years in history had an indelible impact on American politics and culture. Students interpret historical maps, identify territories acquired by the U.S., identify states later formed from these territories, examine the territorial status of Texas, and identify political, social, and economic issues related to the expansion of the U.S. in the 1840s.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Angebote Geographie und Geschichte Aktivitäten, 
die zeigen, wie zwei Jahre in der Geschichte eine unauslöschbare 
Auswirkung auf amerikanische Politik und Kultur hatten. 
Kursteilnehmer deuten historische Karten, kennzeichnen die 
Gegenden, die durch die VEREINIGTEN STAATEN erworben werden, 
kennzeichnen die Zustände, die später von diesen Gegenden gebildet 
werden, überprüfen den territorialen Status von Texas und 
kennzeichnen die politischen, Sozial- und ökonomischen Ausgaben, die 
auf der Expansion der VEREINIGTEN STAATEN im 1840s in Verbindung 
gestanden werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">offres géographie et activités d'histoire 
montrant comment deux ans dans l'histoire ont eu un impact 
indélébile sur la politique et la culture américaines. Les 
étudiants interprètent les cartes historiques, identifient des 
territoires saisis par les ETATS-UNIS, identifient des états plus 
tard formés de ces territoires, examinent le mode territorial du 
Texas, et identifient les issues politiques, sociales, et économiques
liées à l'expansion des ETATS-UNIS dans le 1840s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">ofertas geografia e atividades do history que 
mostram como dois anos no history tiveram um impacto indelible na 
política e na cultura americanas. Os estudantes interpretam 
mapas históricos, identificam os territórios adquiridos pelos 
ESTADOS UNIDOS, identificam os estados dados forma mais tarde destes 
territórios, examinam o status territorial de Texas, e identificam as
edições políticas, sociais, e econômicas relacionadas à expansão
dos ESTADOS UNIDOS no 1840s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">offerte geografia ed attività di storia che 
mostrano come due anni nella storia hanno avuti un effetto indelebile 
sulla politica e sulla coltura americane. Gli allievi 
interpretano i programmi storici, identificano i territori acquistati 
dagli STATI UNITI, identificano dichiara più successivamente 
formato da questi territori, esaminano la condizione territoriale del 
Texas ed identificano le edizioni politiche, sociali ed economiche 
relative all'espansione degli STATI UNITI nel 1840s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">προσφέρει τις δραστηριότητες γεωγραφίας και ιστορίας 
που επιδεικνύουν πώς δύο έτη στην ιστορία άσκησαν ανεξίτηλη 
επίδραση στην αμερικανικούς πολιτική και τον πολιτισμό. Οι 
σπουδαστές ερμηνεύουν τους ιστορικούς χάρτες, προσδιορίζουν τα 
εδάφη που αποκτιούνται από τις ΗΠΑ, προσδιορίζουν τα κράτη που 
διαμορφώνονται αργότερα από αυτά τα εδάφη, εξετάζουν την 
εδαφική θέση του Τέξας, και προσδιορίζουν τα πολιτικά, 
κοινωνικά, και οικονομικά ζητήματα σχετικά με την επέκταση των 
ΗΠΑ στο 1840s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofertas geografía y actividades de la historia que
muestran cómo dos años en historia tenían un impacto indeleble en 
política y cultura americanas. Los estudiantes interpretan 
correspondencias históricas, identifican los territorios adquiridos 
por los ESTADOS UNIDOS, identifican los estados formados más adelante
de estos territorios, examinan el estatus territorial de Tejas, e 
identifican las ediciones políticas, sociales, y económicas 
relacionadas con la extensión de los ESTADOS UNIDOS en el 1840s.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206880</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108665</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/establishing-borders-the-expansion-of-the-united-states-1846-48</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
