<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104384</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104384</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087273</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"80 Rounds in Our Pants Pockets": Orville Quick Remembers Pearl Harbor</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"80 Umläufe in unseren Hosen steckt" ein: 
Orville Erinnert Schnell Sich an Pearl Harbor</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"80 séries dans notre pantalon empoche" : 
Orville Se rappelle Vite Le Port de Perle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"80 círculos em nossas calças pockets": 
Orville Recorda Rapidamente O Porto De Pérola</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"80 tondi in nostri pantaloni intasca": 
Orville Rapidamente Si ricorda Del Porto Di Perla</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"80 κύκλοι στις τσέπες εσωρούχων μασ": Το 
Orville θυμάται γρήγορα το λιμάνι μαργαριταριών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"80 redondos en nuestros pantalones embolsan": 
Orville Aprisa Recuerda El Puerto De Perla</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Japanese attack on Pearl Harbor, Hawaii, stunned virtually everyone in the U.S. military: Japan's carrier-launched bombers found Pearl Harbor totally unprepared. In this 1991 interview, conducted by John Terreo for the Montana Historical Society, serviceman Orville Quick, who was assigned to build airfields and was very near Pearl Harbor on December 6, 1941, remembers the attack. He also provided a vivid, and humorous, account of the chaos from a soldier's point of view.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der japanische Angriff auf Pearl Harbor, Hawaii, 
betäubt praktisch jeder im VEREINIGTE STAATEN Militär: Japans 
Fördermaschine-ausgestoßene Bomber fanden Pearl Harbor total 
unvorbereitet. In diesem Interview 1991 schnell geleitet mit 
John Terreo für die Montana historische Gesellschaft, erinnert sich 
Soldat Orville, der Bauflugplätzen zugewiesen wurde und sehr 
nahe Pearl Harbor an Dezember 6 war, 1941, an den Angriff. Er 
stellte auch ein klares zur Verfügung, und ein humorvoll, Konto des 
Chaos vom Gesichtspunkt eines Soldaten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'attaque japonaise sur le port de perle, Hawaï, 
assommée pratiquement chacun dans les militaires des ETATS-UNIS : 
Les bombardiers porteur-lancés du Japon ont trouvé le port de 
perle totalement non préparé. Dans cette entrevue 1991, 
conduite par John Terreo pour la société historique du Montana, le 
soldat Orville vite, qui a été affecté aux terrains d'aviation de 
construction et était très près de port de perle 6 décembre 1941,
se rappelle l'attaque. Il a également fourni un vif, et plein 
d'humour, compte du chaos du point de vue d'un soldat.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O ataque japonês no porto de pérola, Havaí, 
stunned virtualmente todos nas forças armadas de ESTADOS UNIDOS: 
Os bombardeiros portador-lançados de Japão encontraram o porto
de pérola totalmente unprepared. Nesta entrevista 1991, 
conduzida por John Terreo para a sociedade histórica de Montana, o 
recruta Orville rapidamente, que foi atribuído aos aeródromos da 
configuração e estava muito perto do porto de pérola dezembro em 6,
1941, recorda o ataque. Forneceu também um vívido, e humorous,
cliente do caos do ponto de um soldado da vista.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'attacco giapponese al porto di perla, Hawai, 
stordita virtualmente tutto nei militari degli STATI UNITI: I 
bombardieri elemento-lanciati del Giappone hanno trovato il porto di 
perla completamente non preparato. In questa intervista 1991, 
condotta da John Terreo per la società storica del Montana, il 
tecnico di manutenzione Orville rapidamente, che è stato assegnato 
agli aerodromi di configurazione ed era molto vicino al porto di perla
il 6 dicembre 1941, si ricorda dell'attacco. Egualmente ha 
fornito un chiaro e divertente, cliente del caos dal punto di vista 
del soldato.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ιαπωνική επίθεση στο λιμάνι μαργαριταριών, Χαβάη, 
που ζαλίζεται ουσιαστικά η καθεμία στις ΗΠΑ στρατιωτικές: 
Μεταφορέας-προωθημένο βομβαρδιστικά αεροπλάνα λιμάνι 
μαργαριταριών της Ιαπωνίας συνολικά απροετοίμαστο. Σε αυτήν
την συνέντευξη του 1991, που πραγματοποιείται από John 
Terreo για την ιστορική κοινωνία της Μοντάνα, serviceman 
Orville γρήγορα, που διορίστηκε για να χτίσει τα αεροδρόμια και
ήταν πολύ κοντά στο λιμάνι μαργαριταριών στις 6 Δεκεμβρίου 
..1941, θυμάται την επίθεση. Παρείχε επίσης μια ζωηρή, 
και χιουμοριστική, περιγραφή του χάους από την άποψη ενός 
στρατιώτη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El ataque japonés contra el puerto de perla, 
Hawaii, atontada virtualmente cada uno en los militares de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS: Los bombarderos portador-lanzados de Japón encontraron 
el puerto de perla totalmente sin preparación. En esta 
entrevista 1991, conducida por Juan Terreo para la sociedad histórica
de Montana, el mecánico Orville aprisa, que fue asignado a los campos
de aviación de la estructura y estaba muy cerca de puerto de perla de
diciembre el 6 de 1941, recuerda el ataque. Él también 
proporcionó a vivo, y chistoso, cuenta del caos desde el punto de 
vista de un soldado.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087273</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104384</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/80-rounds-in-our-pants-pockets-orville-quick-remembers-pearl-harbor</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
