<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104540</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104540</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207244</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">These Honored Dead: The Battle of Rivers Bridge and Civil War Combat Casualties</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Geehrten Toten: Die Schlacht 
Fluss-Brücke und Bürgerkrieg-der Kampf-Unfall</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ces Morts Honorés : La bataille des 
accidents de combat de passerelle de fleuves et de guerre civile</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Estes Mortos Honrados: A batalha de víctimas
do combate da ponte dos rios e da guerra civil</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questi Morti Honored: La battaglia degli 
incidenti di combattimento del ponticello dei fiumi e di guerra 
civile</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτοί οι τιμημένοι νεκροί: Η μάχη των θυμάτων 
αγώνα γεφυρών ποταμών και εμφύλιου πολέμου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Estos Muertos Honrados: La batalla de las 
muertes del combate del puente de los ríos y de la guerra civil</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">recounts a battle in a cold, rainy swamp in South Carolina during the last year of the war. In contrast to major campaigns and battles, this small battle presents the war on a human scale. Through maps, illustrations, photos, and descriptions, one can comprehend the entire battlefield and tactics used there. Excerpts from letters help students see the war and its effects from the perspective of individual commanders and soldiers.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">zählt eine Schlacht in einem kalten, regnerischen 
Sumpf in Südcarolina während des letzten Jahres des Krieges nach. 
Im Gegensatz zu Hauptkampagnen und Schlachten stellt diese 
kleine Schlacht den Krieg auf einer menschlichen Skala dar. 
Durch Karten, Abbildungen, Fotos und Beschreibungen kann man das
gesamte Schlachtfeld und die Taktiken begreifen, die dort verwendet 
werden. Excerpts von den Zeichenhilfe Kursteilnehmern sehen den 
Krieg und seine Effekte von der Perspektive der einzelnen Kommandanten
und der Soldaten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">raconte une bataille dans un marais froid et 
pluvieux en Caroline du sud pendant la dernière année de la 
guerre. Contrairement aux campagnes et aux batailles 
principales, cette petite bataille présente la guerre sur une 
échelle humaine. Par des cartes, des illustrations, des photos,
et des descriptions, on peut comprendre le champ de bataille et la 
tactique entiers utilisés là. Les extraits des étudiants 
d'aide de lettres voient la guerre et ses effets de la perspective de 
différents commandants et soldats.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">recounts uma batalha em um swamp frio, chuvoso em 
carolina sul durante o ano passado da guerra. No contraste às 
campanhas e às batalhas principais, esta batalha pequena apresenta a 
guerra em uma escala humana. Com os mapas, as ilustrações, as 
fotos, e as descrições, se pode compreender o campo de batalha e as 
táticas inteiros usados lá. Os excerpts dos estudantes da 
ajuda das letras vêem a guerra e seus efeitos do perspective de 
comandantes e de soldados individuais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">racconta una battaglia in una palude fredda e 
piovosa in Carolina del Sud durante l'anno scorso della guerra. 
Contrariamente alle campagne ed alle battaglie importanti, 
questa piccola battaglia presenta la guerra con scala umana. Con
i programmi, le illustrazioni, le foto e le descrizioni, si può 
comprendere l'interi campo di battaglia e tattiche usati là. I 
brani dagli allievi di aiuto delle lettere vedono la guerra ed i 
relativi effetti dalla prospettiva di diversi comandanti e soldati.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξιστορεί μια μάχη σε ένα κρύο, βροχερό έλος στη 
νότια Καρολίνα κατά τη διάρκεια του περασμένου χρόνου του 
πολέμου. Σε αντίθεση με σημαντικές εκστρατείες και μάχες, 
αυτή η μικρή μάχη παρουσιάζει τον πόλεμο σε μια ανθρώπινη 
κλίμακα. Μέσω των χαρτών, των απεικονίσεων, των 
φωτογραφιών, και των περιγραφών, κάποια μπορεί να κατανοήσει το 
ολόκληρες πεδίο μάχη και την τακτική χρησιμοποιούμενα εκεί. 
Τα αποσπάσματα από τους σπουδαστές οδηγιών επιστολών 
βλέπουνε τον πόλεμο και τα αποτελέσματά του από την 
προοπτική των μεμονωμένων διοικητών και των στρατιωτών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">contó de nuevo una batalla en un pantano frío, 
lluvioso en Carolina del Sur durante el año pasado de la guerra. 
En contraste con las campañas y las batallas importantes, esta 
batalla pequeña presenta la guerra en una escala humana. Con 
correspondencias, ilustraciones, fotos, y descripciones, uno puede 
comprender el campo de batalla y las táctica enteros usados allí. 
Los extractos de estudiantes de la ayuda de las cartas 
consideran la guerra y sus efectos de la perspectiva de comandantes y 
de soldados individuales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207244</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104540</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/these-honored-dead-the-battle-of-rivers-bridge-and-civil-war-combat-casualties</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
