<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103693</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103693</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203777</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Map Projection Animations</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Karte Projektion Animationen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Animations de Projection de Carte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Animations Da Projeção Do Mapa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Animazioni Della Proiezione Del Programma</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ζωτικότητες προβολής χαρτών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Animaciones De la Proyección De la 
Correspondencia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site features QuickTime and Flash animations that address issues cartographers face as they try to fit a three-dimensional surface on a flat planar surface while making maps. Characteristics and distortions of cylindrical, conical, planar, and Goode's projections are discussed. These resources are suitable for use in lectures, labs, or other teaching activities.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Situationsmerkmale QuickTime und grelle 
Animationen, die Ausgaben Kartenzeichnergesicht adressieren, während 
sie versuchen, eine dreidimensionale Oberfläche auf einer flachen 
planaren Oberfläche zu passen während bildend, bildet ab. 
Eigenschaften und Verzerrungen der zylinderförmigen, konischen,
planaren und Goodes Projektionen werden behandelt. Diese 
Betriebsmittel sind für Gebrauch in den Vorträgen, in den Labors 
oder in anderen unterrichtenden Aktivitäten verwendbar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les dispositifs de ce site QuickTime et les 
animations instantanées qui adressent le visage de cartographes 
d'issues pendant qu'ils essayent d'adapter une surface 
tridimensionnelle sur une surface planaire plate tandis que faisant 
trace. Des caractéristiques et les déformations des 
projections cylindrique, coniques, planaires, et de Goode sont 
discutées. Ces ressources conviennent pour l'usage dans les 
conférences, les laboratoires, ou d'autres activités d'enseignement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As características deste local QuickTime e os 
animations flash que se dirigem à cara dos cartographers das 
edições enquanto tentarem caber uma superfície tridimensional em 
uma superfície planar plana quando fazendo traçam. As 
características e as distorções de projeções cilíndricas, 
cónicas, planar, e de Goode são discutidas. Estes recursos 
são apropriados para o uso nos lectures, nos laboratórios, ou em 
outras atividades ensinando.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Caratteristiche di questo luogo QuickTime e le 
animazioni istantanee che richiamano la faccia dei cartographers delle
edizioni mentre provano a misura una superficie tridimensionale su una
superficie planare piana mentre facendo traccia. Le 
caratteristiche e le distorsioni delle proiezioni cilindriche, 
conical, planari e del Goode sono discusse. Queste risorse sono 
adatte ad uso nelle conferenze, in laboratori, o in altre attività 
d'istruzione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει τις ζωτικότητες 
QuickTime και λάμψης που εξετάζουν το πρόσωπο χαρτογράφων 
ζητημάτων δεδομένου ότι προσπαθούν να εγκαταστήσουν μια 
τρισδιάστατη επιφάνεια σε μια επίπεδη επίπεδη επιφάνεια κάνοντας
τους χάρτες. Τα χαρακτηριστικά και οι διαστρεβλώσεις 
κυλινδρικών, κωνικών, των επίπεδων, και προβολών Goode 
συζητούνται. Αυτά τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς είναι κατάλληλα
για τη χρήση στις διαλέξεις, τα εργαστήρια, ή άλλες 
δραστηριότητες διδασκαλίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las características de este sitio QuickTime y las
animaciones de destello que tratan la cara de los cartógrafos de las 
ediciones mientras que intentan caber una superficie tridimensional en
una superficie planar plana mientras que hacen asocian. Las 
características y las distorsiones de las proyecciones cilíndricas, 
cónicas, planar, y de Goode se discuten. Estos recursos son 
convenientes para el uso en conferencias, laboratorios, u otras 
actividades de enseñanza.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203777</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103693</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/map-projection-animations</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
