<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105010</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105010</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086302</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Was Not Wanted Any Longer": A Retail Worker Joins the Union in 1914 and Gets Fired</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Ich Wurde Nicht Irgendwie Länger" Gewünscht: 
Ein Kleinarbeiter verbindet den Anschluß 1914 und erhält 
abgefeuert</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Je N'ai pas été voulu  Plus longtemps" : 
Un ouvrier au détail joint l'union en 1914 et obtient mis le 
feu</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Eu Não fui querido  Mais por muito tempo": 
Um trabalhador de varejo junta a união em 1914 e começa-a 
ateado fogo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Non sono stato desiderato Affatto Più 
lungamente": Un operaio al minuto unisce l'unione in 1914 ed 
ottiene infornato</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"δεν ήμουν επιθυμητός άλλο": Ένας λιανικός 
εργαζόμενος ενώνει την ένωση το 1914 και παίρνει βαλμένος 
φωτιά</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Me No desearon Más de largo": Un 
trabajador al por menor ensambla la unión en 1914 y consigue 
encendido</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Employers had many ways to retaliate against their workers who tried to organize, ranging from allies in state and local police forces to detective agencies that used secret operatives to disrupt unions and supplied thugs to protect strikebreakers during strikes. But the simplest expedient available was to simply fire employees who were perceived as potential troublemakers. In 1914, a former department store worker named Sylvia Schulman testified before the U. S. Commission on Industrial Relations. In the excerpt included here she described how she was fired simply for joining the retail clerk's union.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Arbeitgeber hatten viele Methoden, sich gegen ihre
Arbeiter zu revanchieren, die versuchten zu organisieren und reichten 
von den Verbündeten im Zustand und von den lokalen Polizeikräften 
bis zu Detektivbüros, die geheime Arbeiter verwendeten, um 
Anschlüße und angegebene Schurkeen zu stören, um Streikbrecher 
während der Schläge zu schützen. Aber das einfachste 
vorhandene Hilfsmittel sollte Angestellte einfach feuern, die als 
mögliche troublemakers wahrgenommen wurden. 1914 benannte ein 
ehemaliger Abteilung Speicherarbeiter Sylvia Schulman, der vor der 
USKOMMISSION auf industriellen Beziehungen zwischen den Sozialpartnern
bezeugt wurde. Im Excerpt, das hier beschrieb sie eingeschlossen
war, wie sie einfach für Anschluß der verbindenen den 
Kleinsekretärin gefeuert wurde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les employeurs ont eu beaucoup de voies de exercer
des représailles contre leurs ouvriers qui ont essayé d'organiser, 
s'étendant des alliés dans l'état et des forces locales de police 
aux agences de détectives qui ont utilisé les employés secrets pour
perturber des syndicats et des gangsters fournis pour protéger des 
briseurs de grève pendant les grèves. Mais l'expédient le 
plus simple disponible devait mettre le feu simplement aux employés 
qui ont été perçus en tant que fauteurs de troubles potentiels. En 
1914, un ancien ouvrier de grand magasin a nommé Sylvia Schulman 
témoigné devant la Commission des États-Unis sur des relations 
industrielles. Dans l'extrait inclus ici elle a décrit comment 
elle a été mise le feu simplement pour l'union du vendeur au détail
se joignant.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os empregadores tiveram muitas maneiras retaliate 
de encontro a seus trabalhadores que tentaram organizar, variando dos 
aliados no estado e das forças locais das polícias às agências 
detective que usaram operatives secretos disrupt uniões e thugs 
fornecidos para proteger strikebreakers durante batidas. Mas o 
expediente o mais simples disponível devia atear fogo simplesmente 
aos empregados que foram percebidos como troublemakers potenciais. 
Em 1914, um trabalhador anterior da loja de departamento nomeou 
Sylvia Schulman testified antes do commission dos E. U. em relações 
industriais. No excerpt incluído aqui descreveu como foi ateada
fogo simplesmente para a união de caixeiro de varejo juntando.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I datori di lavoro hanno avuti molti modi 
retaliate contro i loro operai che hanno provato ad organizzare, 
variando dagli alleati dentro dichiarano e forze locali della 
polizia alle agenzie detective che hanno usato gli operatori segreti 
per interrompere i sindacati ed i thugs forniti per proteggere i 
crumiri durante i colpi. Ma l'espediente più semplice 
disponibile doveva infornare semplicemente gli impiegati che sono 
stati percepiti come troublemakers potenziali. In 1914, un ex 
operaio del grande magazzino ha chiamato Sylvia Schulman testimoniato 
prima della Commissione degli Stati Uniti sulle relazione industriali.
Nel brano incluso qui ha descritto come è stata infornata 
semplicemente per l'unione dell'impiegato al minuto unentesi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι εργοδότες είχαν πολλούς τρόπους να εκδικηθούν τους
εργαζομένους τους που προσπάθησαν να οργανώσουν, κυμαινόμενος από
τους συμμάχους στο κράτος και τις τοπικές αστυνομικές δυνάμεις ως
τις αντιπροσωπείες ιδιωτικών αστυνομικών που χρησιμοποίησαν τους 
μυστικούς χειριστές για να αναστατώσουν τις ενώσεις και παρείχαν 
τους κακοποιούς για να προστατεύσουν strikebreakers κατά τη 
διάρκεια των απεργιών. Αλλά το απλούστερο μέσο διαθέσιμο 
ήταν να απολυθούν απλά οι υπάλληλοι που θεωρήθηκαν ως πιθανοί 
ταραχοποιοί. Το 1914, ένας προηγούμενος εργαζόμενος 
καταστημάτων τμημάτων ονόμασε τη Σύλβια Schulman που 
πιστοποιήθηκε πριν από το Θ*u. Θ*ς. η Επιτροπή στις εργασιακές 
σχέσεις. Στο απόσπασμα συμπεριλαμβανόμενο εδώ περιέγραψε 
πώς απολύθηκε απλά για την ένωση της ένωσης του λιανικού 
υπαλλήλου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los patrones tenían muchas maneras de tomar 
represalias contra sus trabajadores que intentaron ordenar, 
extendiéndose de aliados en estado y de fuerzas locales del policía 
a las agencias detectives que utilizaron a operarios secretos para 
interrumpir uniones y a gamberros provistos para proteger a 
rompehuelgas durante huelgas. Pero el expediente más simple 
disponible era encender simplemente a los empleados que fueron 
percibidos como troublemakers potenciales. En 1914, un 
trabajador anterior del almacén grande nombró a Sylvia Schulman 
atestiguado ante la Comisión de los E.E.U.U. en relaciones laborales.
En el extracto incluido aquí ella describió cómo la 
encendieron simplemente para la unión del vendedor al por menor que 
ensamblaba.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086302</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105010</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-was-not-wanted-any-longer-a-retail-worker-joins-the-union-in-1914-and-gets-fired</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
