<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105953</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105953</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086419</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Lorraine Thiebaud on Safety Issues for Healthcare Workers in the Age of AIDS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lothringen Thiebaud auf Sicherheit Ausgaben für 
Healthcare Arbeiter im Alter von AIDS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Lorraine Thiebaud sur des questions de sûreté 
pour des Membres du personnel soignant dans l'âge du SIDA</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Lorena Thiebaud em edições de segurança para 
trabalhadores de Healthcare na idade do AIDS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Lorraine Thiebaud sui problemi di sicurezza per 
gli operai di Healthcare nell'età del AIDS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Λωρραίνη Thiebaud στα ζητήματα ασφάλειας για τους 
εργαζομένους υγειονομικής περίθαλψης στην ηλικία του AIDS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Lorena Thiebaud en las ediciones de seguridad para 
los trabajadores de Healthcare en la edad del SIDA</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">AIDS emerged as a health crisis in the 1980's and early 1990's. While many Americans initially associated the disease with gay men, ignorance about AIDS contributed to its rapid spread, first to intravenous drug users and then to heterosexuals. The lack of information available to people at risk particularly affected health workers like Lorraine Theibaud, a registered nurse at San Francisco General Hospital. Theibaud and her colleagues, fearful about contracting or spreading the disease, were not given adequate information or training on how to protect themselves or their patients. When she discovered safety methods and technology that were not available at her hospital, Theibaud organized health workers to demand access to new safety techniques. Her campaign worked, winning workers new safety training and a permanent monitoring committee.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">AIDS tauchte als Gesundheit Krise in den achtziger 
Jahren und in den frühen neunziger Jahren auf. Während viele 
Amerikaner zuerst die Krankheit mit homosexuellen Männern verbanden, 
trug Unwissenheit über AIDS zu seiner schnellen Verbreitung, zuerst 
zu den intravenösen Drogenbenutzern und dann zu den Heterosexuellen 
bei. Der Mangel an Informationen vorhanden für Leute an der 
Gefahr beeinflußte besonders Gesundheit Arbeiter wie Lothringen 
Theibaud, eine eingetragene Krankenschwester San Francisco am 
allgemeinen Krankenhaus. Theibaud und ihren Kollegen, die über 
das Vertrages Abschließen Vertrages Abschließen oder das Verbreiten 
der Krankheit ängstlich sind, wurden nicht ausreichende Informationen
oder die Ausbildung gegeben auf, wie man oder ihre Patienten schützt.
Als sie Sicherheit Methoden und Technologie entdeckte, die nicht
an ihrem Krankenhaus vorhanden waren, organisierte Theibaud Gesundheit
Arbeiter, um Zugriff zu den neuen Sicherheit Techniken zu verlangen. 
Ihre Kampagne arbeitete und gewann neues Training Sicherheit der
Arbeiter und einen permanenten überwachenausschuß.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le SIDA a émergé comme crise de santé dans les 
années 80 et le début des années 90. Tandis que beaucoup 
d'Américains associaient au commencement la maladie aux hommes gais, 
l'ignorance au sujet du SIDA a contribué à sa diffusion rapide, 
d'abord aux utilisateurs de drogue intraveineux et puis aux 
hétérosexuels. Le manque d'information disponible aux gens en 
danger a en particulier affecté le personnel sanitaire comme la 
Lorraine Theibaud, une infirmière enregistrée à l'hôpital 
général de San Francisco. Theibaud et ses collègues, 
craintifs au sujet de contracter ou d'écarter la maladie, n'ont pas 
été donnés l'information adéquate ou la formation sur la façon 
dont se protéger ou leurs patients. Quand elle a découvert les
méthodes et la technologie de sûreté qui n'étaient pas disponibles
à son hôpital, Theibaud a organisé le personnel sanitaire pour 
exiger l'accès à de nouvelles techniques de sûreté. Sa 
campagne a fonctionné, gagnant la nouvelle formation à la sécurité
d'ouvriers et un comité de surveillance permanent.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O AIDS emergiu como uma crise de saúde nos 1980's 
e nos 1990's adiantados. Quando muitos americanos associaram 
inicialmente a doença com os homens gay, o ignorance sobre o AIDS 
contribuiu a sua propagação rápida, primeiramente aos usuários de 
droga intravenous e então aos heterosexuals. A falta da 
informação disponível aos povos no risco afetou particularmente 
trabalhadores de saúde como Lorena Theibaud, uma enfermeira registada
no hospital geral do San Francisco. Theibaud e seus colegas, 
temíveis sobre contrair ou espalhar a doença, não foram dados a 
informação adequada ou treinar em como proteger-se ou seus 
pacientes. Quando descobriu os métodos e a tecnologia de 
segurança que não estavam disponíveis em seu hospital, Theibaud 
organizou trabalhadores de saúde para exijir o acesso às técnicas 
novas de segurança. Sua campanha trabalhou, ganhando o 
treinamento de segurança novo dos trabalhadores e um comitê de 
monitoração permanente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il AIDS è emerso come crisi di salute negli anni 
80 e nell'inizio degli anni 90. Mentre molti Americani 
inizialmente hanno associato la malattia con gli uomini di 
gay, l'ignoranza circa il AIDS ha contribuito alla relativa 
diffusione veloce, in primo luogo agli utenti di droga endovenosi ed 
allora ai heterosexuals. La mancanza di informazioni disponibile
alla gente al rischio ha interessato specialmente gli operai di salute
come il Lorraine Theibaud, un'infermiera registrata all'ospedale 
generale de San Francisco. Theibaud ed i suoi colleghe, 
spaventosi circa contrarre o la diffusione della malattia, non sono 
stati dati le informazioni sufficienti o l'addestramento su come 
proteggersi o i loro pazienti. Quando ha scoperto i metodi e la 
tecnologia di sicurezza che non erano disponibili al suo ospedale, 
Theibaud ha organizzato gli operai di salute per richiedere l'accesso 
alle nuove tecniche di sicurezza. La sua campagna ha funzionato,
vincendo la nuova formazione in materia di sicurezza degli operai e un
comitato di controllo permanente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το AIDS προέκυψε ως κρίση υγείας στη δεκαετία του 
'80 και την πρόωρη δεκαετία του '90. Ενώ πολλοί Αμερικανοί 
σύνδεσαν αρχικά την ασθένεια με τα ομοφυλοφιλικά άτομα, η άγνοια
για το AIDS συνέβαλε στη γρήγορη διάδοσή της, πρώτα στους 
ενδοφλέβιους χρήστες φαρμάκων και έπειτα στους ετεροφυλόφιλους. 
Η έλλειψη πληροφοριών διαθέσιμη στους ανθρώπους σε κίνδυνο 
είχε επιπτώσεις ιδιαίτερα στους εργαζομένους στον ιατρικό κλάδο 
όπως τη Λωρραίνη Theibaud, μια εγγραμμένη νοσοκόμα στο γενικό 
νοσοκομείο του Σαν Φρανσίσκο. Στο Theibaud και σοι 
συνάδελφοί της, έντρομοι για την εργολαβία ή τη διάδοση της 
ασθένειας, δεν παρέχηκαν τις επαρκείς πληροφορίες ή την 
κατάρτιση στο πώς να προστατευθούν ή τους ασθενείς τους. 
Όταν ανακάλυψε τις μεθόδους και την τεχνολογία ασφάλειας 
που δεν ήταν διαθέσιμες στο νοσοκομείο της, Theibaud οργάνωσε 
τους εργαζομένους στον ιατρικό κλάδο για να απαιτήσει την 
πρόσβαση στις νέες τεχνικές ασφάλειας. Η εκστρατεία της 
ελειτούργησε, κερδίζοντας τη νέα κατάρτιση ασφάλειας εργαζομένων
και μια μόνιμη ελεγκτική επιτροπή.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El SIDA emergió como crisis de salud en los años 
80 y los años 90 tempranos. Mientras que muchos americanos 
asociaron inicialmente la enfermedad a los hombres gays, la 
ignorancia sobre SIDA contribuyó a su extensión rápida, primero a 
los utilizadores de droga intravenosos y entonces a los heterosexuals.
La carencia de la información disponible para la gente en el 
riesgo afectó determinado a ayudantes de sanidad como Lorena 
Theibaud, enfermera registrada en el hospital general de San 
Francisco. No dieron Theibaud y sus colegas, temerosos sobre 
contraer o separar la enfermedad, la información adecuada o el 
entrenamiento en cómo protegerse o a sus pacientes. Cuando ella
descubrió los métodos y la tecnología de seguridad que no estaban 
disponibles en su hospital, Theibaud ordenó a ayudantes de sanidad 
para exigir el acceso a las nuevas técnicas de seguridad. Su 
campaña trabajó, ganando al nuevo entrenamiento de seguridad de los 
trabajadores y a un comité que vigilaba permanente.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086419</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105953</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/lorraine-thiebaud-on-safety-issues-for-healthcare-workers-in-the-age-of-aids</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
