<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103361</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103361</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206044</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Conservation Movement at a Crossroads: the Hetch Hetchy Controversy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Erhaltung Bewegung an einer Querstraße: 
die Hetch Hetchy Kontroverse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le mouvement d'économie à un carrefour : 
la polémique de Hetch Hetchy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O movimento do conservation em um crossroads: 
a controvérsia de Hetch Hetchy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il movimento di conservazione ad una strada 
trasversale: la polemica di Hetch Hetchy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Κίνημα συντήρησης σταυροδρόμια: η διαμάχη 
Hetch Hetchy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El movimiento de la conservación en una 
encrucijada: la controversia de Hetch Hetchy</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a two-part teaching unit about the controversy among conservationists over a proposal to turn part of Yosemite National Park into a dam to furnish water to San Francisco. The first part explores the history of the conservation movement in general, while the second links to primary records, such as Congressional debates, of Hetch Hetchy itself.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">eine zweiteilige ist das Unterrichten Maßeinheit 
über die Kontroverse unter Naturschützern über einem Antrag, zum 
des Teils von Yosemite Nationalpark zu eine Verdammung zu machen, um 
Wasser nach San Francisco zu versorgen. Das erste Teil erforscht
die Geschichte der Erhaltung Bewegung im allgemeinen, während das 
zweite mit Primärsätzen, wie Kongreßdebatten, von Hetch Hetchy 
selbst bindet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est une unité l'enseignement en deux parties au 
sujet de la polémique parmi des protecteurs de la nature au-dessus 
d'une proposition pour transformer une partie de parc national de 
Yosemite en barrage pour fournir l'eau à San Francisco. La 
première partie explore l'histoire du mouvement d'économie en 
général, alors que la deuxième joint aux enregistrements primaires,
tels que des discussions congressionnelles, de Hetch Hetchy lui-même.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é uma unidade ensinar two-part sobre a 
controvérsia entre conservationists sobre uma proposta para girar a 
parte do parque nacional de Yosemite em uma represa para equipar a 
água a San Francisco. A primeira parte explora o history do 
movimento do conservation no general, quando a segunda ligar aos 
registros preliminares, tais como debates congressionais, de Hetch 
Hetchy próprio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è un'unità insegnare in due parti circa la 
polemica fra i conservationists sopra una proposta per trasformare 
nella parte del parco nazionale di Yosemite una diga per fornire 
l'acqua a San Francisco. La prima parte esplora la storia del 
movimento di conservazione in generale, mentre la seconda si collega 
ai record primari, quali i dibattiti congressuali, di Hetch Hetchy in 
se.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι μια διμερής μονάδα διδασκαλίας για τη διαμάχη 
μεταξύ των μαχομένων για τη διατήρηση του φυσικού περιβάλλοντος 
πέρα από μια πρόταση να μετατραπεί μέρος του εθνικού πάρκου 
Yosemite σε φράγμα για να εφοδιάσει το ύδωρ στο Σαν Φρανσίσκο. 
Το πρώτο μέρος ερευνά την ιστορία της μετακίνησης 
συντήρησης γενικά, ενώ το δεύτερο συνδέει με τα αρχικά αρχεία, 
όπως οι του Κογκρέσου συζητήσεις, Hetch Hetchy το ίδιο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es una unidad la enseñanza bipartita sobre la 
controversia entre conservationists sobre una oferta para dar vuelta a
la parte del parque nacional de Yosemite en una presa para equipar el 
agua a San Francisco. La primera parte explora la historia del 
movimiento de la conservación en general, mientras que la segunda 
conecta a los registros principales, tales como discusiones del 
congreso, de Hetch Hetchy sí mismo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206044</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103361</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-conservation-movement-at-a-crossroads-the-hetch-hetchy-controversy</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
