<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107602</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107602</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087261</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Younger and More Vigorous Blood": FDR on the Judiciary</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"jüngeres und kräftigeres Blut": FDR auf 
der Justizgewalt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">un "plus jeune et plus vigoureux sang" : FDR
sur l'ordre judiciaire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"sangue mais novo e mais vigoroso": Fdr no 
judiciary</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"anima più giovane e più vigorosa": Fdr 
sull'ordinamento giudiziario</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Νεώτερο και σφριγηλότερο αίμα": FDR στο 
δικαστικό</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"una sangre más joven y más vigorosa": Fdr
en la judicatura</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Frustrated by the elimination of the NRA and other programs, like the Agricultural Adjustment Act ( United States v. Butler,  1936) through the courts, and overconfident after his big win in the 1936 elections, Roosevelt proposed a novel but not entirely unprecedented solution in 1937. He would add one new judge to the federal judicial system for every active judge over the age of seventy. The result would create fifty new judgeships, including up to six new Supreme Court justices. Having established these new positions, the president could then appoint new judges friendly to his administration and tip the balance in his favor. Roosevelt posed the measure as a plan to streamline the Court system and ease its caseload, as he explained in this fireside chat on March 9, 1937. Roosevelt argued that the Court expansion bill would merely restore the balance of power intended by the Constitution's framers, a balance that had been lost to a reactionary, backward-looking, shortsighted group of old men.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Frustriert durch die Beseitigung des NRA und 
anderer Programme, wie der landwirtschaftlichen Justage-Tat 
(Vereinigter Staaten V. Butler, 1936) durch die Gerichte und 
overconfident, nachdem sein grosser Gewinn in den 1936 Wahlen, 
Roosevelt einen Roman aber nicht völlig beispiellose Lösung 1937 
vorschlug. Er würde einen neuen Richter dem 
Bundesgerichtssystem für jeden aktiven Richter über dem Alter von 
siebzig hinzufügen. Das Resultat würde fünfzig neue 
Richterämter erstellen und schließen würde bis sechs neue 
Gerichtgerechtigkeit ein. , diese neuen Positionen herstellend, 
könnte der Präsident die neuen Richter dann ernennen, die zu seiner 
Leitung freundlich sind und die Balance zu seinen Gunsten spitzen. 
Roosevelt warf das Maß als Plan auf, die Gerichtsverfassung zu 
glätten und seine Kistenladung zu erleichtern, wie er in diesem 
Kaminschwätzchen an März 9 erklärte, 1937. Roosevelt 
argumentierte, daß die Gerichtexpansion Rechnung bloß die Balance 
der Energie beabsichtigt von den Verfassern der Beschaffenheit 
wiederherstellen würde, eine Balance, die zu einem Reaktionär 
verloren worden war und rückwärts-schaute, shortsighted Gruppe alte 
Männer.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Frustré par l'élimination du NRA et d'autres 
programmes, comme la Loi agricole de réglage (Etats-Unis v. Butler, 
1936) par les cours, et présomptueux après que sa grande victoire 
dans les 1936 élections, Roosevelt ait proposé un roman mais la 
solution pas entièrement sans précédent en 1937. Il 
ajouterait un nouveau juge au système juridique fédéral pour chaque
juge actif au-dessus de l'âge de soixante-dix. Le résultat 
créerait cinquante nouvelles fonctions de juge, incluant jusqu'à six
nouvelles justices de cour suprême. Après avoir établi ces 
nouvelles positions, le président pourrait alors nommer de nouveaux 
juges amicaux à sa gestion et incliner l'équilibre en sa faveur. 
Roosevelt a posé la mesure comme plan d'améliorer le système 
de cour et de soulager son chargement de caisse, comme il a expliqué 
dans cette causerie de coin du feu 9 mars 1937. Roosevelt a 
argué du fait que la facture d'expansion de cour restaurerait 
simplement l'equilibre des forces destiné par les auteurs de la 
constitution, un équilibre qui avait été détruit à un 
réactionnaire, vers l'arrière-regardant, shortsighted le groupe de 
vieux hommes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Frustrado pelo elimination do NRA e de outros 
programas, como o ato agricultural do ajuste (estados unidos v. 
Mordomo, 1936) através das cortes, e overconfident depois que sua 
vitória grande nas 1936 eleições, Roosevelt propôs uma novela mas 
solução não inteiramente unprecedented em 1937. Adicionaria 
um juiz novo ao sistema judicial federal para cada juiz ativo sobre a 
idade de setenta. O resultado criaria cinqüênta judgeships 
novos, incluindo até seis justiças novas da corte suprema. 
Estabelecendo estas posições novas, o presidente poderia 
então apontar os juizes novos amigáveis para sua administração e 
derrubar o contrapeso em seu favor. Roosevelt posed a medida 
como uma planta aerodinamizar o sistema de corte e facilitar seu 
caseload, como explicou neste bate-papo do fireside março em 9, 1937.
Roosevelt discutiu que a conta da expansão da corte restauraria
meramente o contrapeso de potência pretendido pelos framers do 
constitution, um contrapeso que fosse perdido a um reactionary, para 
trás-olhando, shortsighted o grupo de homens velhos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Frustrato dall'eliminazione del NRA e di altri 
programmi, come la Legge agricola di registrazione (unita 
Dichiara il v. Butler, 1936) attraverso le corti ed 
overconfident dopo che la sua vittoria grande nelle 1936 elezioni, 
Roosevelt proponga un romanzo ma la soluzione non interamente senza 
precedente in 1937. Aggiungerebbe un nuovo giudice al sistema 
giudiziario federale per ogni giudice attivo sopra l'età di settanta.
Il risultato creerebbe cinquanta nuovi judgeships, includenti 
fino a sei nuove giustizie della Corte suprema. Stabilendo 
queste nuove posizioni, il presidente potrebbe allora nominare i nuovi
giudici amichevoli alla sua gestione e capovolgere l'equilibrio nel 
suo favore. Roosevelt ha proposto la misura come programma 
migliorare il sistema di corte e facilitare il relativo caseload, ha 
spiegato in questa chiacchierata del focolare il 9 marzo 1937. 
Roosevelt ha sostenuto che la fattura di espansione della corte 
soltanto ristabilirebbe l'equilibrio di forze progettato dai framers 
della costituzione, un equilibrio che era stato perso ad un 
reactionary, indietro-osservante, shortsighted il gruppo degli uomini 
anziani.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ματαιωμένο από την αποβολή της ΕΚΑ και άλλων 
προγραμμάτων, όπως το γεωργικό νόμο ρύθμισης (Ηνωμένες 
Πολιτείες V. οικονόμος, 1936) μέσω των δικαστηρίων, και 
overconfident αφότου κερδίζω μεγάλος του στις εκλογές του 
1936, Roosevelt πρότεινε ένα μυθιστόρημα αλλά όχι εξ 
ολοκλήρου την πρωτοφανή λύση το 1937. Θα πρόσθετε έναν 
νέο δικαστή στο ομοσπονδιακό δικαστικό σύστημα για κάθε ενεργό 
δικαστή μετά την ηλικία εβδομήντα. Το αποτέλεσμα θα 
δημιουργούσε πενήντα νέα judgeships, που περιλαμβάνουν μέχρι 
έξι νέα justices ανώτατου δικαστηρίου. Καθιερώνοντας 
αυτές τις νέες θέσεις, ο Πρόεδρος θα μπορούσε έπειτα να 
διορίσει τους νέους δικαστές φιλικούς στη διοίκησή του και να 
τοποθετήσει αιχμή στην ισορροπία στην εύνοιά του. Το 
Roosevelt έθεσε το μέτρο ως σχέδιο για να βελτιώσει το σύστημα
δικαστηρίου και να διευκολύνει ο αριθμός των εγγράφων του, όπως 
εξήγησε σε αυτήν την συνομιλία εστιών στις 9 Μαρτίου, 1937, 
Roosevelt υποστήριξε ότι ο λογαριασμός επέκτασης δικαστηρίου 
θα αποκαθιστούσε μόνο την ισορροπία της δύναμης που προορίζεται 
από τα framers του συντάγματος, μια ισορροπία που ήταν χαμένη 
σε ένα αντιδραστικό, προς τα πίσω-κοίταγμα, μυωπική ομάδα 
ηληκιωμένων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Frustrado por la eliminación del NRA y de otros 
programas, como el acto agrícola del ajuste (Estados Unidos v. 
Butler, 1936) a través de las cortes, y presumido después de que su 
triunfo grande en las 1936 elecciones, Roosevelt propusiera una novela
pero la solución no enteramente sin precedente en 1937. Él 
agregaría a un nuevo juez al sistema judicial federal para cada juez 
activo sobre la edad de setenta. El resultado crearía cincuenta
nuevos judgeships, incluyendo hasta seis nuevas justicias del Tribunal
Supremo. Estableciendo estas nuevas posiciones, el presidente 
podría después designar a nuevos jueces cómodos a su 
administración e inclinar el equilibrio en su favor. Roosevelt 
planteó la medida como plan de aerodinamizar el sistema judicial y de
facilitar su caseload, como él explicó en esta charla del hogar de 
marcha la 9 de 1937. Roosevelt discutió que la cuenta de la 
extensión de la corte restableciera simplemente el equilibrio de la 
potencia previsto por los framers de la constitución, un equilibrio 
que había sido perdido a un reaccionario, al reve's-mirando, 
shortsighted a grupo de viejos hombres.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087261</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107602</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/younger-and-more-vigorous-blood-fdr-on-the-judiciary</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
