<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108757</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108757</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087180</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">We are Told that the Americans have 13 Councils Compos'd of Chiefs and Warriors: The Chickasaws Send a Message of Conciliation to Congress, 1783</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wir werden erklärt, daß die Amerikaner 13 Räte 
Compos'd der Leiter und der Krieger haben: Die Chickasaws
schicken Kongreß, 1783 eine Meldung der Versöhnung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Nous sommes dits que les Américains ont les 13 
Conseils Compos'd des chefs et des guerriers : Les Chickasaws 
envoient un message de la conciliation au congrès, 1783</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nós somos ditos que os americanos têm 13 
conselhos Compos'd dos chefes e dos guerreiros: Os chickasaws 
emitem uma mensagem do conciliation ao congress, 1783</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ci diciamo a che gli Americani abbiano 13 Consigli
Compos'd dei capi e dei guerrieri: I chickasaws trasmettono un 
messaggio della conciliazione al congresso, 1783</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Έχουμε την υποχρέωση ότι οι Αμερικανοί έχουν 13 
Συμβούλια Compos'd των προ!ισταμένων και των πολεμιστών: 
Το Chickasaws στέλνει ένα μήνυμα του συμβιβασμού στο 
συνέδριο, 1783</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Nos dicen que los americanos tienen 13 consejos 
Compos'd de jefes y de guerreros: Los chickasaws envían un 
mensaje de la conciliación al congreso, 1783</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Chickasaw Indians occupied a key region of northern Mississippi. They held in check the French and Choctaws with their allies and trading partners the British. The American Revolution ended that balance of power. The Chickasaws sought neutrality but also felt allegiance to the British due to their long-held ties. In 1779, the Virginians sent threatening messages warning them of dire consequences if they did not make peace. The Chickasaw chiefs replied in a bold manner. The Mississippi River valley changed signifcantly when the Spanish replaced the British in West Florida. The Chickasaws found themselves without allies and caught in a competitive crossfire between Spain, the new United States government, and the various new states. The once defiant Chickasaw leaders sought to inaugurate a new relationship with the new United States by sending this message to Congress in the spring of 1783. They desired a halt to encroachments on their land and regular access to supplies in order to appease their belligerent young warriors.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Chickasaw-Inder besetzten eine 
Schlüsselregion von Nordmississippi. Sie hielten in der 
Überprüfung die Franzosen und die Choctaws mit ihren Verbündeten 
und Handelspartnern die Briten an. Die amerikanische Umdrehung 
beendete diese Balance der Energie. Die Chickasaws suchten, 
Neutralität aber glaubten auch Untertanentreue zu den Briten wegen 
ihrer langgehaltenen Gleichheit. 1779 sendete das Virginians die
bedrohenden Meldungen, die sie der entsetzlichen Konsequenzen warnen, 
wenn sie nicht Frieden bildeten. Die Chickasawleiter antworteten
in einer fetten Weise. Das Mississippi River Valley änderte 
signifcantly, als das Spanisch die Briten in Westflorida ersetzte. 
Die Chickasaws fanden sich ohne Verbündete und fingen in einem 
konkurrierenden Kreuzfeuer zwischen Spanien, der neuen Vereinigte 
Staaten Regierung und den verschiedenen neuen Zuständen ab. , 
sobald defiant Chickasawführer suchten, ein neues Verhältnis zu den 
neuen Vereinigten Staaten zu eröffnen, indem sie dem Kongreß im 
Früjahr von 1783 diese Meldung schickten. Sie wünschten einen 
Halt zu den Eingriffen auf ihrem Land und zum regelmäßigen Zugriff 
zum Zubehör, um ihre kriegführenden jungen Krieger zu 
beschwichtigen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Indiens de chickasaw ont occupé une région 
principale du Mississippi nordique. Ils ont tenu en test les 
Français et les Choctaws avec leurs alliés et partenaires 
commerciaux les Anglais. La révolution américaine a terminé 
cet equilibre des forces. Les Chickasaws ont recherché la 
neutralité mais ont également senti l'allégeance aux Anglais dus à
leurs cravates de longue date. En 1779, le Virginians a envoyé 
les messages menaçants les avertissant de grandes conséquences s'ils
ne faisaient pas la paix. Les chefs de chickasaw ont répondu 
d'une façon grasse. Le Mississippi River Valley a changé 
signifcantly quand l'Espagnol a substitué les Anglais en Floride 
occidentale. Les Chickasaws se sont trouvés sans alliés et ont
attrapé dans un courant perturbateur concurrentiel entre l'Espagne, 
le nouveau gouvernement des Etats-Unis, et les divers nouveaux états.
Une fois que les amorces provoquantes de chickasaw recherchaient
à inaugurer un nouveau rapport avec les nouveaux Etats-Unis en 
envoyant ce message au congrès au printemps de 1783. Elles ont 
désiré un arrêt aux empiétements sur leur terre et à l'accès 
régulier aux approvisionnements afin d'apaiser leurs jeunes guerriers
belligérants.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os indians do chickasaw ocuparam uma região chave
de Mississippi do norte. Prenderam na verificação os franceses
e os choctaws com seus aliados e sócios negociando os Ingleses. 
A volta americana terminou esse contrapeso de potência. 
Os chickasaws procuraram o neutrality mas sentiram também o 
allegiance aos Ingleses  devido a seus laços long-held. Em 
1779, o Virginians emitiu as mensagens ameaçando que advertem as de 
conseqüências dire se não fizessem a paz. Os chefes do 
chickasaw responderam em uma maneira bold(realce). O Mississippi
River Valley mudou signifcantly quando o espanhol substituiu os 
Ingleses em Florida ocidental. Os chickasaws encontraram-se sem 
aliados e travaram-se em um fogo cruzado do competidor entre Spain, o 
governo unido novo dos estados, e os vários estados novos. Uma 
vez que os líderes defiant do chickasaw procuraram inaugurate um 
relacionamento novo com os estados unidos novos emitindo esta mensagem
ao congress na mola de 1783. Desejaram uma parada aos 
encroachments em sua terra e ao acesso regular às fontes a fim 
appease seus guerreiros novos beligerantes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli indiani del chickasaw hanno occupato una 
regione chiave del Mississippi del Nord. Hanno tenuto nel 
controllo i francesi ed i choctaws con i loro alleati e partner 
commerciali i Britannici. La rivoluzione americana ha concluso 
quell'equilibrio di forze. I chickasaws hanno cercato la 
neutralità ma egualmente hanno ritenuto il allegiance ai Britannici 
dovuto i loro legami di lunga data. In 1779, il Virginians ha 
trasmesso i messaggi minacciosi che li avvertono delle conseguenze 
dire se non facessero la pace. I capi del chickasaw hanno 
risposto in un modo GRASSETTO. Il Mississippi River Valley è 
cambiato signifcantly quando lo Spagnolo ha sostituito i Britannici in
Florida ad ovest. I chickasaws si sono trovati senza alleati ed 
hanno interferito in un crossfire competitivo fra la Spagna, il nuovo 
unito Dichiara il governo ed il vario nuovo dichiara. 
Una volta ribelle i capi del chickasaw cercati per 
inaugurare un nuovo rapporto con il nuovo unito Dichiara 
trasmettendo questo messaggio al congresso nella primavera di 1783. 
Hanno voluto una fermata ai encroachments sulla loro terra ed 
all'accesso normale ai rifornimenti per calmare i loro guerrieri 
giovani bellicosi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Chickasaw Ινδοί κατέλαβε μια βασική περιοχή του 
βόρειου Μισισιπή. Κράτησαν στον έλεγχο τους Γάλλους και το 
Choctaws με τους συμμάχους και τους εμπορικούς εταίρους τους οι 
Βρετανοί. Η αμερικανική επανάσταση τελείωσε εκείνη την 
ισορροπία της δύναμης. Το Chickasaws επιδίωξε την 
ουδετερότητα αλλά και αισθάνθηκε την υποταγή στους Βρετανούς 
λόγω στους long-held δεσμούς τους. Το 1779, το 
Virginians έστειλε να απειλήσει τα μηνύματα που προειδοποιούν 
τα για τις τρομερές συνέπειες εάν δεν έκαναν την ειρήνη. Οι
προ!ιστάμενοι Chickasaw απάντησαν κατά τρόπο έντονο. Η 
κοιλάδα ποταμών του Μισισιπή άλλαξε signifcantly όταν 
αντικατέστησε ο Ισπανός τους Βρετανούς στη δυτική Φλώριδα. 
Το Chickasaws βρέθηκε χωρίς συμμάχους και πιάνω σε 
ανταγωνιστικά διασταυρούμενα πυρά μεταξύ της Ισπανίας, της νέας 
Ηνωμένης κυβέρνησης, και των διάφορων νέων κρατών. Οι μιά 
φορά προκλητικοί ηγέτες Chickasaw επιδίωξαν να εγκαινιάσουν 
μια νέα σχέση με τις νέες Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες με την αποστολή 
αυτού του μηνύματος στο συνέδριο άνοιξη 1783. Επιθύμησαν
μια στάση στις καταπατήσεις στο έδαφός τους και την κανονική 
πρόσβαση στις προμήθειες προκειμένου να κατευναστούν οι εμπόλεμοι
νέοι πολεμιστές τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los indios del chickasaw ocuparon una región 
dominante de Mississippi norteño. Sostuvieron en cheque a los 
franceses y a choctaws con sus aliados y socios que negociaban los 
Británicos. La revolución americana terminó ese equilibrio de
la potencia. Los chickasaws buscaron neutralidad pero también 
sentían lealtad a los Británicos  debido a sus lazos desde hace 
mucho tiempo. En 1779, el Virginians envió los mensajes 
amenazadores que los advertían de consecuencias calamitosas si no 
hicieron las paces. Los jefes del chickasaw contestaron de una 
manera en negrilla. El Mississippi River Valley cambió 
signifcantly cuando el español substituyó a Británicos en la 
Florida del oeste. Los chickasaws se encontraron sin los aliados
y cogieron en un tiroteo competitivo entre España, el nuevo gobierno 
de Estados Unidos, y los varios nuevos estados. Una vez que los 
arranques de cinta desafiantes del chickasaw intentaran inaugurar un 
nuevo lazo con los Estados Unidos nuevos enviando este mensaje al 
congreso en el resorte de 1783. Desearon un alto a las 
usurpaciones en su pista y al acceso regular a las fuentes para 
apaciguir a sus guerreros jóvenes beligerantes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087180</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108757</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/we-are-told-that-the-americans-have-13-councils-composd-of-chiefs-and-warriors-the-chickasaws-send-a-message-of-conciliation-to-congress-1783</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
