<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105952</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105952</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086347</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"It Has No Popular Support": Robert M. La Follette Votes Against a Declaration of War</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Es Hat Keinen Populären Support": Robert 
M. La Follette Stimmen gegen eine Erklärung des Krieges</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Il N'a Aucun Support Populaire" : Voix de 
Robert M. La Follette contre une déclaration de guerre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Não tem Nenhuma Sustentação Popular": 
Votos de Robert M. La Follette de encontro a uma declaração da
guerra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Non ha Supporto Popolare": Voti del Robert 
M. La Follette contro una dichiarazione della guerra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Δεν έχει καμία λαϊκή υποστήριξη": Ψηφοφορίες 
Robert M. La Follette ενάντια σε μια Διακήρυξη του 
πολέμου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"No tiene Ninguna Ayuda Popular": Votos de 
Roberto M. La Follette contra un declaración de la guerra</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The events of the first few months of 1917, from the resumption of unrestricted submarine attacks to the Zimmerman telegram, broke the back of the antiwar movement and substantially increased enthusiasm for American intervention. But some dissident voices remained. Among the firmest congressional opponents was the progressive Wisconsin senator Robert M. La Follette. On April 4, 1917, two days after President Woodrow Wilson's call for war, La Follette argued in this speech before Congress that the United States had not been even-handed in its treatment of British and German violations of American neutrality. A Republican senator from a state with a large agricultural and German-American population, La Follette worried that the war would divert attention from domestic reform efforts. But even in Wisconsin La Follette met opposition; the state legislature censured him, as did some of his longtime progressive allies. One of them said that he was "of more help to the Kaiser than a quarter of a million troops."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Fälle der ersten Monate von 1917, von der 
Zurücknahme der uneingeschränkten Unterwasserangriffe zum Zimmerman 
Telegramm, brachen die Rückseite der Antikriegsbewegung und erhöhten
im wesentlichen Begeisterung für amerikanische Intervention. 
Aber einige Dissidentstimmen blieben. Unter den festesten
Kongreßkonkurrenten war der progressive Wisconsin Senator Robert M. 
La Follette. An April 4, 1917, zwei Tage nachdem Präsident 
Woodrow Wilson Aufruf für Krieg, La Follette in dieser Rede vor 
Kongreß argumentierte, daß die Vereinigten Staaten nicht in seiner 
Behandlung der britischen und deutschen Verletzungen der 
amerikanischen Neutralität even-handed gewesen waren. Ein 
republikanischer Senator von einem Zustand mit einer großen 
landwirtschaftlichen und Deutsch-Amerikanischen Bevölkerung, La 
Follette sorgte sich, daß der Krieg Aufmerksamkeit von den 
inländischen Verbesserungbemühungen umleiten würde. Aber 
glätten Sie in getroffener Opposition des Wisconsin La Follette; 
die Zustandgesetzgebung kritisierte ihn, wie einige seiner 
langfristigen progressiven Verbündeten. Einer von ihnen sagte, 
daß er war "von mehr Hilfe zum Kaiser als ein Viertel von Million 
Truppen."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les événements des mois premiers de 1917, de la 
reprise des attaques submersibles sans restriction au télégramme de 
Zimmerman, ont cassé le dos du mouvement pacifiste et ont 
sensiblement augmenté l'enthousiasme pour l'intervention américaine. 
Mais quelques voix dissidentes sont demeurées. Parmi les 
adversaires congressionnels les plus fermes était le sénateur 
progressif Robert M. La Follette du Wisconsin. 4 avril 1917, 
pendant deux jours après que l'appel du Président Woodrow Wilson 
pour la guerre, La Follette a argué du fait dans ce discours devant 
le congrès que les Etats-Unis n'avaient pas été équitables dans 
son traitement des violations britanniques et allemandes de 
neutralité américaine. Un sénateur républicain d'un état 
avec une grande population agricole et Allemand-Américaine, La 
Follette s'est inquiété que la guerre détourne l'attention des 
efforts domestiques de réforme. Mais même dans l'opposition 
rencontrée par Follette de La du Wisconsin ; la législature 
d'état l'a censuré, de même que  certains de ses alliés 
progressifs à long terme. L'un d'entre eux a indiqué qu'il 
était "de plus d'aide au Kaiser qu'un quart d'million de troupes."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os eventos do primeiros poucos meses de 1917, da 
ressunção de ataques submarinos irrestritos ao telegrama de 
Zimmerman, quebraram a parte traseira do movimento antiwar e 
aumentaram substancialmente o entusiasmo para a intervenção 
americana. Mas algumas vozes dissident remanesceram. Entre
os oponentes congressionais os mais firmes era o senator progressivo 
Robert M. La Follette de Wisconsin. Abril em 4, 1917, dois dias 
depois que o atendimento do presidente Woodrow Wilson para a guerra, 
la Follette discutiu neste discurso antes do congress que os estados 
unidos não tinham sido even-handed em seu tratamento de violações 
britânicas e alemãs do neutrality americano. Um senator 
republicano de um estado com uma população agricultural e 
Alemão-Americana grande, la Follette preocupou-se que a guerra 
desviaria a atenção dos esforços domésticos da reforma. Mas 
nivele na oposição encontrada com Follette do la de Wisconsin; 
a legislatura de estado censured o, como  alguns de seus aliados
progressivos longtime. Um deles disse que era "de mais ajuda ao 
Kaiser do que um quarto de milhão tropas."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli eventi dei mesi primissimi di 1917, dalla 
ripresa degli attacchi sottomarini senza restrizione al telegramma di 
Zimmerman, hanno rotto la parte posteriore del movimento pacifista e 
sostanzialmente hanno aumentato l'entusiasmo per intervento americano.
Ma alcune voci del dissidente sono rimasto. Fra gli 
avversari congressuali più costanti era il senatore progressivo 
Robert M. La Follette del Wisconsin. Il 4 aprile 1917, due 
giorni dopo che la richiesta del presidente Woodrow Wilson per la 
guerra, la La Follette discutesse in questo discorso prima che il 
congresso che unito Dichiara non era stato even-handed nel 
relativo trattamento delle violazioni britanniche e tedesche di 
neutralità americana. Un senatore Repubblicano da un dichiarare
con una grande popolazione agricola e Tedesco-Americana, la La 
Follette si è preoccupato che la guerra devierebbe l'attenzione dagli
sforzi domestici di riforma. Ma anche nell'opposizione venuta a 
contatto di Follette della La del Wisconsin; la legislatura di 
dichiarare lo ha censurato, come alcuni dei suoi alleati progressivi 
da molto tempo. Un di loro ha detto che era "di più aiuto al 
Kaiser che un quarto di milione truppe."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα γεγονότα των πρώτων-πρώτων μηνών του 1917, από 
την επανάληψη των απεριόριστων υποβρύχιων επιθέσεων στο 
τηλεγράφημα Zimmerman, έσπασαν το πίσω μέρος της αντιπολεμικής
μετακίνησης και αύξησαν αισθητά τον ενθουσιασμό για την 
αμερικανική επέμβαση. Αλλά μερικές διαφωνούσες φωνές 
παρέμειναν. Μεταξύ των σταθερότερων του Κογκρέσου αντιπάλων
ήταν το προοδευτικό Wisconsin γερουσιαστής Robert M. La
Follette. Στις 4 Απριλίου ..1917, δύο ημέρες μετά από
την κλήση Προέδρου Woodrow Wilson's για τον πόλεμο, το Λα 
Follette υποστήριξε σε αυτήν την ομιλία πριν από το συνέδριο 
ότι οι Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες δεν ήταν ισομοιρασμένες στην 
επεξεργασία βρετανικές και γερμανικές παραβίασή της της 
αμερικανικής ουδετερότητας. Ένας δημοκρατικός γερουσιαστής 
από ένα κράτος με έναν μεγάλο γεωργικό και 
γερμανικός-αμερικανικό πληθυσμό, Λα Follette ανησύχησε ότι ο 
πόλεμος θα εξέτρεπε την προσοχή από τις εσωτερικές προσπάθειες 
μεταρρύθμισης. Αλλά ακόμη και στο Λα του Wisconsin 
Follette συνάντησε την αντίθεση  το κρατικό νομοθετικό 
σώμα τον επέκρινε, όπως μερικοί από τους μακροπρόθεσμους 
προοδευτικούς συμμάχους του. Ένας από τους είπε ότι 
βοήθησε "περισσότερες στο Kaiser από ένα τέταρτο εκατομμύριο 
στρατευμάτων."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los acontecimientos de los meses primeros de 1917,
de la reasunción de ataques submarinos sin restricción al telegrama 
de Zimmerman, rompieron la parte posteriora del movimiento pacifista y
aumentaron substancialmente el entusiasmo para la intervención 
americana. Pero seguía habiendo algunas voces disidentes. 
Entre los opositores del congreso más firmes estaba el senador 
progresivo Roberto M. La Follette de Wisconsin. 4 de abril de
1917, dos días después de que la llamada de presidente Woodrow 
Wilson para la guerra, la Follette discutió en este discurso antes de
congreso que los Estados Unidos no hubieran sido even-handed en su 
tratamiento de violaciones británicas y alemanas de la neutralidad 
americana. Un senador republicano de un estado con una 
población agrícola y Alema'n-Americana grande, la Follette se 
preocupó que la guerra desviaría la atención de esfuerzos 
domésticos de la reforma. Pero iguale en la oposición resuelta
Follette del la de Wisconsin; la legislatura de estado lo 
censuró, al igual que algunos de sus aliados progresivos de largo 
plazo. Una de ellos dijo que él estaba "de más ayuda al Kaiser
que un cuarto de millón de tropas."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086347</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105952</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/it-has-no-popular-support-robert-m-la-follette-votes-against-a-declaration-of-war</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
