<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105407</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105407</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086714</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Over a Hundred Different People Used This Needle:" Michael Yantsos Describes Drug Use and AIDS in Prison</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"über hundert unterschiedlichen Leuten benutzte 
diese Nadel:" Michael Yantsos beschreibt Droge Gebrauch und AIDS
im Gefängnis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"au-dessus d'cent personnes différentes a utilisé
cette aiguille :" Michael Yantsos décrit l'utilisation et le 
SIDA de drogue en prison</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"sobre cem povos diferentes usou esta agulha:" 
Michael Yantsos descreve o uso e o AIDS da droga na prisão</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"sopra cento genti differenti ha usato questo ago:"
Michael Yantsos descrive l'uso ed il AIDS della droga in 
prigione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Πέρα από εκατό διαφορετικούς ανθρώπους 
χρησιμοποιούμενους αυτή η βελόνα:" Michael Yantsos 
Describes Drug Use και AIDS στη φυλακή</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"sobre cientos diversas personas utilizó esta 
aguja:" Michael Yantsos describe uso y el SIDA de la droga en la
prisión</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Michael Yantsos contracted AIDS through intravenous drug use while in prison in 1983. Yantsos was one of thousands who became infected before information about the disease or adequate treatment was available. As a result, Yantsos, like most Americans, knew next to nothing about the disease when AIDS struck during the early 1980's. Many associated the disease with gay men, who were its first victims, but the epidemic soon spread to other populations _ first to intravenous drug users, and then to heterosexuals. Reagan era cuts in drug treatment programs and the "war" on drugs that pushed thousands of addicts into prison also contributed to the disease's spread.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Michael Yantsos schloß Vertrag AIDS durch 
intravenösen Drogegebrauch während im Gefängnis 1983 ab. 
Yantsos war eins von Tausenden, die angesteckt wurden, bevor 
Informationen über die Krankheit oder die ausreichende Behandlung 
vorhanden waren. Infolgedessen wußte Yantsos, wie die meisten 
Amerikaner, nahe bei nichts über die Krankheit, als AIDS während der
frühen achtziger Jahre anschlug, die viele die Krankheit mit 
homosexuellen Männern verbanden, die seine ersten Opfer waren, aber 
die Epidemie verbritt bald zu anderen Bevölkerungen _ zuerst zu den 
intravenösen Drogenbenutzern und dann zu den Heterosexuellen. 
Reagan Ära schneidet Drogebehandlungprogramme und den "Krieg" 
auf Drogen ein, die Tausenden Süchtige in das Gefängnis drückten, 
das auch zur Verbreitung der Krankheit beigetragen wurde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Michael Yantsos a contracté le SIDA par 
l'utilisation intraveineuse de drogue tandis qu'en prison en 1983. 
Yantsos était l'un de milliers qui sont devenus infectés avant
que les informations sur la maladie ou le traitement adéquat aient 
été disponibles. En conséquence, Yantsos, comme la plupart 
des Américains, a su à côté de rien au sujet de la maladie quand 
le SIDA a heurté pendant le début des années 80. Beaucoup ont
associé la maladie aux hommes gais, qui étaient ses premières 
victimes, mais l'épidémie bientôt s'est écartée à d'autres 
populations _ d'abord aux utilisateurs de drogue intraveineux, et puis
aux hétérosexuels. L'ère de Reagan coupe dedans des 
programmes de traitement de drogue et la "guerre" sur les drogues qui 
ont poussé des milliers de mordus dans la prison également 
contribuée à la propagation de maladie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Michael Yantsos contraiu o AIDS com o uso 
intravenous da droga quando na prisão em 1983. Yantsos foi um 
dos milhares que se tornaram infected antes que a informação sobre a
doença ou o tratamento adequado estêve disponível. Em 
conseqüência, Yantsos, como a maioria de americanos, soube ao lado 
de nada sobre a doença quando o AIDS golpeou durante os 1980's. onde 
adiantados muitos associaram a doença com os homens gay, que eram 
suas primeiras vítimas, mas a epidemia espalhou logo a outras 
populações _ primeiramente aos usuários de droga intravenous, e 
então aos heterosexuals. A era de Reagan corta dentro programas
do tratamento da droga e a "guerra" nas drogas que introduziram 
milhares dos viciados na prisão contribuída também à propagação 
da doença.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Michael Yantsos ha contratto il AIDS con uso 
endovenoso della droga mentre in prigione in 1983. Yantsos era 
una delle migliaia che sono stato infettate prima che le informazioni 
sulla malattia o sul trattamento sufficiente fossero disponibili. 
Di conseguenza, Yantsos, come la maggior parte dei Americani, ha
saputo vicino a niente circa la malattia quando il AIDS ha colpito 
durante l'inizio degli anni 80 che molti hanno associato la malattia 
con gli uomini di gay, che erano le relative prime vittime, ma
l'epidemia presto si è sparsa ad altre popolazioni _ in primo luogo 
agli utenti di droga endovenosi ed allora ai heterosexuals. 
L'era del Reagan taglia dentro i programmi di trattamento della 
droga e "la guerra" con droghe che hanno spinto i migliaia delle 
persone dedite nella prigione anche contribuita alla diffusione della 
malattia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Michael Yantsos συμβλήθηκε το AIDS μέσω της 
ενδοφλέβιας χρήσης φαρμάκων ενώ στη φυλακή σε 1983, Yantsos
ήταν μια από τις χιλιάδες που έγιναν μολυσμένες προτού οι 
πληροφορίες για την ασθένεια ή την επαρκή θεραπεία ήταν 
διαθέσιμες. Κατά συνέπεια, Yantsos, όπως τους 
περισσότερους Αμερικανούς, ήξερε δίπλα σε τίποτα για την 
ασθένεια όταν χτύπησε το AIDS κατά τη διάρκεια της πρόωρης 
δεκαετίας του '80 Πολλοί σύνδεσαν την ασθένεια με τα 
ομοφυλοφιλικά άτομα, τα οποία ήταν τα πρώτα θύματά του, αλλά η
επιδημία εξαπλώθηκε σύντομα σε άλλους πληθυσμούς _ πρώτα στους 
ενδοφλέβιους χρήστες φαρμάκων, και έπειτα στους ετεροφυλόφιλους. 
Η εποχή Reagan κόβει στα προγράμματα επεξεργασίας 
φαρμάκων και ο "πόλεμοσ" στα φάρμακα που ώθησαν χιλιάδες 
εξαρτημένοι στη φυλακή συνέβαλε επίσης της ασθένειας που 
διαδόθηκε.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Michael Yantsos contrajo el SIDA con uso 
intravenoso de la droga mientras que en la prisión en 1983. 
Yantsos era uno de los millares que se infectaron antes de que 
la información sobre la enfermedad o el tratamiento adecuado 
estuviera disponible. Consecuentemente, Yantsos, como la 
mayoría de los americanos, sabía al lado nada sobre la enfermedad 
cuando el SIDA pulso durante los años 80 tempranos que muchos 
asociaron la enfermedad a los hombres gays, que eran sus 
primeras víctimas, pero la epidemia pronto se separó a otras 
poblaciones _ primero a los utilizadores de droga intravenosos, y 
entonces a los heterosexuals. La era de Reagan corta adentro 
programas del tratamiento de la droga y la "guerra" en las drogas que 
empujaron a millares de adicto en la prisión también contribuida a 
la extensión de la enfermedad.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086714</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105407</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/over-a-hundred-different-people-used-this-needle-michael-yantsos-describes-drug-use-and-aids-in-prison</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
