<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107432</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107432</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200722</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Breaking Up is Hard to Do</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Oben brechen ist hart zu tun</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Rupture il est difficile de faire vers le haut</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quebrar acima é duro de fazer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Rompersi in su è duro da fare</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο χωρισμός είναι δύσκολο να καθεί</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El romperse para arriba es duro de hacer</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The collapse of the Soviet State in 1991 was followed by Chechen President Dzhokhar Dudayev's declaration of the Chechen Republic's independence from Moscow. Concerned over the loss of its territorial integrity, Russian troops invaded the breakaway republic and a civil war ensued. In l996, Chechen rebels regained control of the capital, Grozny, from Russian forces, almost destroying the city in the process. Fighting in Chechnya continues to this day, although on a relatively smaller scale. The WIDE ANGLE video 'Greetings From Grozny' (2002) examines the conflict from the perspectives of Russian soldiers, Chechen separatist militants, radical Chechen Islamists, and civilians living in Grozny.In this lesson, students will explore the multiple perspectives surrounding the conflict, examine the conflict's regional and international implications, and understand the mindsets of Chechens who have managed to maintain their identity and self-esteem in the face of untold human suffering. This lesson can be used during or after a lesson on the breakup of the Soviet Union and the formation of the Russian Federation (1991- present). A basic knowledge of post- Soviet history and basic geographical facts of Eurasia are required for the successful completion of the lesson.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Einsturz des sowjetischen Zustandes 1991 wurde
Chechen Präsident Dzhokhar Dudayevs von der Erklärung der 
Unabhängigkeit der Chechen-Republik von Moskau gefolgt. 
Betroffen über dem Verlust seiner territorialen 
Vollständigkeit, drangen russische Truppen die abgespaltene Republik 
ein und ein Bürgerkrieg folgte. In l996 gewannen 
Chechenaufrührer Steuerung des Kapitals, Grozny, von den russischen 
Kräften wieder und fast zerstörten die Stadt im Prozeß. Das 
Kämpfen in Chechnya fährt zu diesem Tag, obgleich auf einem 
verhältnismäßig Klein fort. Die video ' Weitwinkelgrüße von
Grozny ' (2002) überprüft die $überschneidung von den Perspektiven 
der russischen Soldaten, ChechenSeparatist militants, des 
radikalen Chechen Islamists und der Zivilisten, die in Grozny.In diese
Lektion leben, Kursteilnehmer erforschen die mehrfachen Perspektiven, 
welche die $überschneidung umgeben, überprüfen die regionalen und 
internationalen Implikationen der $überschneidung und verstehen die 
Denkrichtungen von Chechens, die gehandhabt haben, ihre Identität und
Self-esteem angesichts untold des menschlichen Suffering 
beizubehalten. Diese Lektion kann während oder nach einer 
Lektion auf dem Auseinanderbrechen des Sowjet-Anschlußes und der 
Anordnung der russischen Vereinigung (Geschenk 1991-) verwendet 
werden. Ein grundlegendes Wissen der sowjetischen Geschichte des
Pfostens und grundlegende geographische Tatsachen von Eurasia werden 
für die erfolgreiche Beendigung der Lektion benoetigt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'effondrement de l'état soviétique en 1991 a 
été suivi de la déclaration de Tchétchène le Président Dzhokhar 
Dudayev de l'indépendance Tchétchène de la République de Moscou. 
Préoccupé par la perte de sa intégrité territoriale, les 
troupes russes ont envahi la république détachée et une guerre 
civile s'est ensuivie. Dans l996, les rebelles de Tchétchène 
ont regagné la commande du capital, Grozni, des forces russes, 
détruisant presque la ville dans le processus. Le combat dans 
Chechenie continue à ce jour, bien que sur une échelle 
relativement plus petite. Les 'salutations visuelles 
GRANDES-ANGULAIRES de Grozni '(2002) examine le conflit des 
perspectives des soldats russes, des militants séparatistes 
Tchétchènes, des Islamiste Tchétchènes radicaux, et des civils 
vivant dans Grozny.In cette leçon, étudiants exploreront les 
perspectives multiples entourant le conflit, examineront les 
implications régionales et internationales du conflit, et 
comprendront les mentalités des Tchétchènes qui sont parvenus à 
mettre à jour leur identité et art de l'auto-portrait-esteem face à la douleur 
humaine incalculable. Cette leçon peut être utilisée pendant
ou après une leçon sur la dissolution d'Union Soviétique et la formation
de la fédération russe (présent 1991-). Une connaissance de 
base de l'histoire soviétique de poteau et des faits géographiques 
de base d'Eurasia sont exigés pour l'accomplissement réussi de la 
leçon.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O colapso do estado soviético em 1991 foi seguido
pela declaração de Chechen Presidente Dzhokhar Dudayev da 
independência da república do chechen de Moscow. Concernido 
sobre a perda de sua integridade territorial, as tropas russian 
invadiram a república breakaway e uma guerra civil seguiu. Em 
l996, os rebels do chechen regained o controle do capital, Grozny, das
forças russian, destruindo quase a cidade no processo. Lutar em
Chechnya continua a este dia, embora em uma escala relativamente 
menor. O ÂNGULO que LARGO ' os cumprimentos video de Grozny ' 
(2002) examinam o conflito dos perspectives dos militants russian dos 
soldados, do separatist do chechen, do chechen radical Islamists, e 
dos civis que vivem em Grozny.In esta lição, estudantes explorará 
os perspectives múltiplos que cercam o conflito, examinará as 
implicações regionais e internacionais do conflito, e compreenderá 
os mindsets dos chechens que controlaram manter seus identidade e 
self-esteem na cara do sofrimento humano do untold. Esta lição
pode ser usada durante ou após uma lição no breakup da 
Soviete-união e na formação do federation russian (presente 1991-).
Um conhecimento básico do history soviético do borne e os 
fatos geográficos básicos de Eurasia são requeridos para a 
conclusão bem sucedida da lição.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il crollo del Soviet Dichiara in 1991 è 
stato seguito dalla dichiarazione del Chechen Presidente Dzhokhar 
Dudayev dell'indipendenza della Repubblica del chechen da Mosca. 
Interessato sopra la perdita della relativa integrità 
territoriale, le truppe russe hanno invaso la repubblica staccata e 
una guerra civile ha seguito. In l996, i ribelli del chechen
hanno riguadagnato il controllo del capitale, Groznyi, dalle forze 
russe, quasi distruggere la città nel processo. Il 
combattimento in Chechnya continua a questo giorno, anche se su un a 
scala ridotta relativamente. I video 'saluti GRANDANGOLARI da 
Groznyi '(2002) esamina il conflitto dalle prospettive dei militanti
russi del separatista del chechen, dei soldati, delle islamite 
radicali del chechen e dei civili che vivono in Grozny.In questa 
lezione, allievi esploreranno le prospettive multiple che circondano 
il conflitto, esamineranno le implicazioni regionali ed internazionali
del conflitto e capiranno i mindsets dei chechens che sono riuscito ad
effettuare la loro identità e self-esteem di fronte a suffering umano
del untold. Questa lezione può essere usata durante o dopo la 
lezione sul disfacimento dell'Soviet-unione e sulla formazione della 
federazione russa (presente 1991-). Una conoscenza di base di 
storia sovietica dell'alberino ed i fatti geografici di base di 
Eurasia sono richiesti per il completamento riuscito della lezione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η κατάρρευση του σοβιετικού κράτους το 1991 
ακολουθήθηκε από την τσετσένια δήλωση Προέδρου Dzhokhar 
Dudayev's της ανεξαρτησίας της τσετσένιας Δημοκρατίας από τη 
Μόσχα. Σχετικά με την απώλεια εδαφικής ακεραιότητάς του, 
τα ρωσικά στρατεύματα εισέβαλαν στην αποσπασθείσα δημοκρατία και 
ένας εμφύλιος πόλεμος ακολούθησε. L996, οι τσετσένιοι 
επαναστάτες επανάκτησαν τον έλεγχο του κεφαλαίου, Γκρόζνυ, από 
τις ρωσικές δυνάμεις, καταστρέφοντας σχεδόν την πόλη στη 
διαδικασία. Η πάλη σε Τσετσενία συνεχίζεται σε αυτήν την 
ημέρα, αν και σε μια σχετικά μικρότερη κλίμακα. Οι 
τηλεοπτικοί "χαιρετισμοί WIDE.ANGLE από το Γκρόζνυ" (2002) 
εξετάζουν τη σύγκρουση από τις προοπτικές των ρωσικών 
στρατιωτών, των τσετσένιων μαχητών αυτονομιστής, ριζικού 
τσετσένιου Islamists, και των πολιτών που ζουν στο Γκρόζνυ 
Σε αυτό το μάθημα, οι σπουδαστές θα ερευνήσουν τις 
πολλαπλάσιες προοπτικές που περιβάλλουν τη σύγκρουση, θα 
εξετάσουν τις περιφερειακές και διεθνείς επιπτώσεις της 
σύγκρουσης, και θα καταλάβουν τις νοοτροπίες chechens που έχουν
κατορθώσει να διατηρήσουν την ταυτότητα και τον αυτοσεβασμό τους 
παρά το ανεξιστόρητο ανθρώπινο βάσανο. Αυτό το μάθημα 
μπορεί να χρησιμοποιηθεί κατά τη διάρκεια ή μετά από ενός 
μαθήματος στην αποσύνθεση της Σοβιετικής Ένωσης και του 
σχηματισμού της ρωσικής ομοσπονδίας (παρόν 1991-). Μια 
βασική γνώση θέσης - η σοβιετική ιστορία και τα βασικά 
γεωγραφικά γεγονότα της Ευρασίας απαιτούνται για την επιτυχή 
ολοκλήρωση του μαθήματος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El derrumbamiento del estado soviético en 1991 
fue seguido por el declaración de chechen Presidente Dzhokhar Dudayev
de la independencia de la república del chechen de Moscú. 
Tratado sobre la pérdida de su integridad territorial, las 
tropas rusas invadieron la república disidente y una guerra civil 
sobrevino. En l996, los rebeldes del chechen recuperaron el 
control del capital, Grozny, de las fuerzas rusas, casi destruyendo la
ciudad en el proceso. El luchar en Chechnya continúa a este 
día, aunque en una escala relativamente más pequeña. Los ' 
saludos video GRANANGULARES de Grozny ' (2002) examinan el conflicto 
de las perspectivas de los soldados rusos, de los militantes 
separatistas del chechen, del chechen radical Islamists, y de los 
civiles que viven en Grozny.In esta lección, estudiantes explorarán 
las perspectivas múltiples que rodean el conflicto, examinarán las 
implicaciones regionales e internacionales del conflicto, y 
entenderán los mindsets de los chechens que han manejado mantener su 
identidad y autoestima en la cara del sufrimiento humano del untold. 
Esta lección se puede utilizar durante o después de una 
lección en la desintegración de la Soviet-unio'n y la formación de 
la federación rusa (presente 1991-). Un conocimiento básico de
la historia soviética del poste y los hechos geográficos básicos de
Eurasia se requieren para la terminación acertada de la lección.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MELVIN MASKIN
FN:MELVIN MASKIN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200722</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107432</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/breaking-up-is-hard-to-do</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
