<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103727</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103727</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086892</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Ancient Days Have Not Departed": Calvin Coolidge on the Spirituality of Commerce</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Die Alten Tage Sind Nicht" Abgereist: 
Calvin Coolidge auf dem Spirituality des Handels</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Le Démuni Antique de Jours Est parti" : 
Calvin Coolidge sur le spirituality du commerce</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Os Dias Antigos Não partiram": Calvin 
Coolidge na espiritualidade do comércio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"I Giorni Antichi Non hanno partito": Calvin
Coolidge sullo spirituality del commercio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Οι αρχαίες ημέρες δεν έχουν αναχωρήσει": Calvin Coolidge στην πνευματικότητα του εμπορίου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Los Días Antiguos No han salido": Calvin 
Coolidge en la espiritualidad del comercio</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">With his famously laconic style, President Calvin Coolidge captured the spirit of the 1920s when he announced in a speech before the Society of American Newspaper Editors that "the chief business of the American people is business." Coolidge's aphorism revealed the centrality of commerce to the nation and its culture in the 1920s, even while it concealed some of the wrenching cultural changes that were required to accommodate a commercial civilization. Coolidge, as a son of rural Vermont and small-town Massachusetts, played a key role in reassuring people that the new business order was compatible with traditional American values. In this 1925 address to the New York State Chamber of Commerce, Coolidge mixed new prescriptions for a pro-business government with traditional homilies about the contributions of American business "to the spiritual restoration of the world." He insisted that "traditional" values could fit comfortably into a business civilization.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mit seiner berühmt laconic Art erfaßte 
Präsident Calvin Coolidge den Geist der zwanziger Jahre, als er in 
einer Rede vor der Gesellschaft der amerikanischen Zeitungsverleger 
verkündete, die "das Hauptgeschäft der amerikanischen Leute ist 
Geschäft." Aphorismus Coolidges deckte die zentrale Lage des 
Handels zur Nation und seiner Kultur in den zwanziger Jahren auf, 
sogar während er einige der entreißenden kulturellen Änderungen 
verbarg, die benoetigt wurden, um eine kommerzielle Zivilisation 
anzupassen. Coolidge, als Sohn von landwirtschaftlichem Vermont 
und von Kleinstadt Massachusetts, spielte eine Schlüsselrolle in 
versicherenden Leuten, daß die neue Bestellung mit traditionellen 
amerikanischen Werten kompatibel war. In dieser Adresse 1925 zur
Staat- New-Yorkhandelskammer, mischte Coolidge neue Verordnungen für 
eine Pro-Geschäft Regierung mit traditionellen Homilies über die 
Beiträge des amerikanischen Geschäfts "zur geistigen 
Wiederherstellung der Welt." Er beharrte, daß "traditionelle" 
Werte in eine Geschäft Zivilisation bequem passen konnten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Avec son modèle célèbre laconique, le 
Président Calvin Coolidge a capturé l'esprit des années 20 où il a
annoncé dans un discours devant la société des éditeurs de journal
américains que "les affaires en chef des  américains sont des 
affaires." L'aphorisme de Coolidge a indiqué la centralité du 
commerce à la nation et de sa culture dans les années 20, même 
tandis qu'il cachait certains des changements culturels arrachants qui
ont été exigés pour faciliter une civilisation commerciale. 
Coolidge, en tant que fils du Vermontn et de petit-ville ruraux 
le Massachusetts, a joué un rôle principal dans les personnes 
rassurantes que la nouvelle commande d'affaires était compatible avec
des valeurs américaines traditionnelles. Dans cette adresse 
1925 à la chambre de commerce de l'état de New-York, Coolidge a 
mélangé de nouvelles prescriptions pour un gouvernement de 
pro-affaires aux homilies traditionnels au sujet des contributions des
affaires américaines "à la restauration spirituelle du monde." 
Il a insisté sur le fait que les valeurs "traditionnelles" 
pourraient s'adapter confortablement dans une civilisation d'affaires.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Com seu estilo famosa laconic, o presidente Calvin
Coolidge capturou o espírito dos 1920s em que anunciou em um discurso
antes da sociedade dos editores de jornal americanos que "o negócio 
principal dos povos americanos é negócio." O aphorism de 
Coolidge revelou o centrality do comércio à nação e da sua cultura
nos 1920s, mesmo quando escondeu algumas das mudanças cultural 
wrenching que foram requeridas para acomodar uma civilização 
comercial. Coolidge, como um filho de Vermont e da 
pequeno-cidade rurais Massachusetts, jogou um papel chave em povos 
tranquilizando que a ordem de negócio nova era compatível com 
valores americanos tradicionais. Neste endereço 1925 à câmara
de estado de New York de comércio, Coolidge misturou prescrições 
novas para um governo do pro-negócio com os homilies tradicionais 
sobre as contribuições do negócio americano "à restauração 
espiritual do mundo." Insistiu que os valores "tradicionais" 
poderiam caber confortavelmente em uma civilização do negócio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Con il suo stile famoso laconic, il presidente 
Calvin Coolidge ha bloccato lo spirito degli anni 20 in cui ha 
annunciato in un discorso prima della società degli editori di 
giornale americani che "il commercio principale della gente americana 
è il commercio." Il aphorism del Coolidge ha rivelato il 
centrality del commercio alla nazione e della relativa coltura negli 
anni 20, persino mentre ha celato alcuni dei cambiamenti culturali 
wrenching che sono stati richiesti per accomodare una civilizzazione 
commerciale. Coolidge, come figlio del Vermont e della 
piccolo-città rurali Massachusetts, ha svolto un ruolo chiave in 
gente di riassicurazione che il nuovo ordine di affari era compatibile
con i valori americani tradizionali. In questo indirizzo 1925 a 
New York Dichiari la camera di commercio, nuove prescrizioni 
mescolate Coolidge per un governo di pro-commercio con i homilies 
tradizionali circa i contributi del commercio americano "al ripristino
spiritoso del mondo." Ha insistito che i valori "tradizionali" 
potrebbero inserire confortevolmente in una civilizzazione di affari.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Με το περίφημα λακωνικό ύφος του, ο Πρόεδρος Calvin
Coolidge συνέλαβε το πνεύμα της δεκαετίας του '20 όταν 
ανήγγειλε σε μια ομιλία ενώπιον της κοινωνίας των αμερικανικών 
επεξεργαστών εφημερίδων ότι "η προϊστάμενος επιχείρηση των 
αμερικανικών ανθρώπων είναι επιχείρηση." Ο αφορισμός του 
Coolidge αποκάλυψε την κεντρικότητα του εμπορίου στο έθνος και 
του πολιτισμού του στη δεκαετία του '20, ακόμη και ενώ έκρυψε 
μερικών από τις να στρέψει πολιτιστικές αλλαγές που απαιτήθηκαν 
για να προσαρμόσουν έναν εμπορικό πολιτισμό. Το Coolidge,
ως γιος του αγροτικού Βερμόντ και της μικρού χωριού Μασαχουσέτης,
διαδραμάτισε έναν βασικό ρόλο στον καθησυχασμό των ανθρώπων ότι
η νέα επιχειρησιακή κατάταξη ήταν συμβατή με τις παραδοσιακές 
αμερικανικές αξίες. Σε αυτήν την διεύθυνση του 1925 στο 
κρατικό εμπορικό επιμελητήριο της Νέας Υόρκης, Coolidge 
ανάμιξε τις νέες συνταγές για μια pro-business κυβέρνηση με τα 
παραδοσιακά homilies για τις συνεισφορές της αμερικανικής 
επιχείρησης "στην πνευματική αποκατάσταση του κόσμου." 
Επέμεινε ότι οι "παραδοσιακέσ" αξίες θα μπορούσαν να 
αρμόσουν άνετα σε έναν επιχειρησιακό πολιτισμό.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Con su estilo famoso lacónico, presidente Calvin 
Coolidge capturó el alcohol de los años 20 en que él anunció en un
discurso antes de la sociedad de los redactores americanos que "el 
principal negocio de la gente americana es negocio." El aphorism
de Coolidge reveló el centrality del comercio a la nación y de su 
cultura en los años 20, incluso mientras que encubrió algunos de los
cambios culturales wrenching que fueron requeridos para acomodar una 
civilización comercial. Coolidge, como hijo de Vermont y de la 
pequeño-ciudad rurales Massachusetts, desempeñó un papel dominante 
en la gente que tranquilizaba que la nueva orden de negocio era 
compatible con valores americanos tradicionales. En este 
direccionamiento 1925 a la Cámara de estado de Nueva York de 
Comercio, Coolidge mezcló las nuevas prescripciones para un gobierno 
del favorable-negocio con homilies tradicionales sobre las 
contribuciones del negocio americano "a la restauración espiritual 
del mundo." Él insistió que los valores "tradicionales" 
podrían caber comfortablemente en una civilización del negocio.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086892</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103727</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-ancient-days-have-not-departed-calvin-coolidge-on-the-spirituality-of-commerce</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
