<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103528</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103528</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205337</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">You Decide: Is the Bush Administration's "No Child Left Behind" policy of high-stakes testing good for America's students?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sie Entscheiden: Ist das kein Kind der Bush 
Leitung "nach links hinter" Politik von hoch-anbindet die Prüfung auf
Kursteilnehmer Amerikas gut?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Vous Décidez : Enfant de gestion de Bush 
aucun l'"à gauche derrière" la politique de haut-jalonne-t-il 
déterminer n'est-il bon les étudiants de l'Amérique ?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Você Decide-se: É criança de 
administração de Bush nenhuma "à esquerda atrás" da política de 
elevado-estaca testar boa para estudantes de América?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Decidete: Non c'è bambino della gestione di 
Bush il nessun "a sinistra dietro" la politica di alto-picchetta la 
prova buono ad allievi dell'America?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αποφασίζετε: Είναι ο θάμνος κανένα παιδί της 
διοίκησης "που αφήνεται" την πολιτική της δοκιμής 
υψηλός-πασσάλων καλός για τους σπουδαστές της Αμερικής;</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Usted Decide: ¿El niño de la administración
de Bush "no hay a la izquierda detrás" de la política de alto-estaca
la prueba bueno para los estudiantes de América?</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This educational guide focuses on high-stakes testing in public education and the related social, legal, personal, political, national and local implications surrounding the issue. Students are invited to examine arguments from both sides of the debate, developing critical thinking skills as they work through the activities and learn how to support their arguments with evidence and reason. It is expected that students will effectively determine where they stand on this controversial issue and be able to articulate their reasons at the end of this guide.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese pädagogische Anleitung konzentriert auf 
hoch-anbindet die Prüfung im Unterrichtswesen und die in Verbindung 
stehenden Sozial-, zugelassenen, persönlichen, politischen, 
nationalen und lokalen Implikationen, welche die Ausgabe umgeben. 
Kursteilnehmer werden eingeladen, Argumente von beiden Seiten 
der Debatte zu überprüfen und entwickeln kritische denkende 
Fähigkeiten, während sie durch die Aktivitäten arbeiten und wie man
ihre Argumente mit Beweis und Grund erlernen, unterstützt. Es 
wird erwartet, daß Kursteilnehmer effektiv feststellen, wo sie zu 
diesem umstrittenen Punkt stehen und können, ihre Gründe am Ende 
dieser Anleitung zu artikulieren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce guide éducatif se concentre sur haut-jalonne le test 
dans l'éducation publique et les implications sociales, légales, 
personnelles, politiques, nationales et locales relatives entourant 
l'issue. Des étudiants sont invités à examiner des arguments 
des deux côtés de la discussion, développant des qualifications de 
pensée critiques pendant qu'ils travaillent par les activités et 
apprennent comment supporter leurs arguments avec l'évidence et la 
raison. On s'attend à ce que les étudiants déterminent 
pertinemment où ils se tiennent sur cette question controversée et 
puissent articuler leurs raisons à l'extrémité de ce guide.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta guia educacional focaliza em elevado-estaca testar na
instrução pública e as implicações sociais, legais, pessoais, 
políticas, nacionais e locais relacionadas que cercam a edição. 
Os estudantes são convidados examinar argumentos de ambos os 
lados do debate, desenvolvendo habilidades pensando críticas enquanto
trabalham com as atividades e aprendem como suportar seus argumentos 
com evidência e razão. Espera-se que os estudantes 
determinarão eficazmente onde estão nesta edição controversa e 
possam  articular suas razões na extremidade desta guia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa guida educativa mette a fuoco su alto-picchetta la 
prova nella formazione pubblica e le implicazioni sociali, legali, 
personali, politiche, nazionali e locali relative che circondano 
l'edizione. Gli allievi sono invitati ad esaminare gli argomenti
da entrambi i lati del dibattito, sviluppando le abilità pensanti 
critiche mentre lavorano con le attività ed imparano come sostenere i
loro argomenti con prova e motivo. È previsto che gli allievi 
determinino efficacemente dove si levano in piedi su questa edizione 
discutibile e possano articolare i loro motivi all'estremità di 
questa guida.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο εκπαιδευτικός οδηγός εστιάζει στους 
υψηλός-πασσάλους εξεταστικός στη δημόσια εκπαίδευση και τις 
σχετικές κοινωνικές, νομικές, προσωπικές, πολιτικές, εθνικές και
τοπικές επιπτώσεις που περιβάλλουν το ζήτημα. Οι σπουδαστές
καλούνται για να εξετάσουν τα ορίσματα και από τις δύο πλευρές 
της συζήτησης, που αναπτύσσει τις κρίσιμες δεξιότητες σκέψης 
όπως λειτουργούν μέσω των δραστηριοτήτων και μαθαίνουν πώς να 
υποστηρίξουν τα ορίσματά τους με τα στοιχεία και το λόγο. 
Αναμένεται ότι οι σπουδαστές θα καθορίσουν αποτελεσματικά 
όπου στέκονται σε αυτό το αμφισβητούμενο ζήτημα και θα είναι σε 
θέση να αρθρώσουν τους λόγους τους στο τέλος αυτού του οδηγού.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta guía educativa se centra en alto-estaca la prueba en
la educación pública y las implicaciones sociales, legales, 
personales, políticas, nacionales y locales relacionadas que rodean 
la edición. Se invita que examinen argumentos de ambas caras 
del discusión, desarrollando habilidades de pensamiento críticas 
como trabajan con las actividades y aprenden a los estudiantes cómo 
utilizar sus argumentos con evidencia y razón. Se espera que 
los estudiantes se determinen con eficacia dónde están parados en 
esta edición polémica y puedan articular sus razones en el extremo 
de esta guía.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205337</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103528</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/you-decide-is-the-bush-administrations-no-child-left-behind-policy-of-high-stakes-testing-good-for-americas-students</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
