<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103540</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103540</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087161</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Upstairs, Downstairs: The Science of Service</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Oben Unten: Die Wissenschaft des Services</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En haut, En bas : La Science du service</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Upstairs, Downstairs: A ciência do 
serviço</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Upstairs, Downstairs: Scienza di servizio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επάνω, κάτω: Η επιστήμη της υπηρεσίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Arriba, Abajo: La ciencia del servicio</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Women's magazines published between the Civil War and World War II frequently featured articles on "the servant problem" for their middle-class readers. For mistresses, the "problem" was the inadequate supply of "competent" household help. Over the years, the solution to the problem changed. Whereas in the 19th century women were counseled to follow the ideals of Christian maternal benevolence, in the 20th century women were advised to follow principles of scientific management. As this 1912 article by Christine Frederick, an advocate of scientific management for housewives, makes clear, none of these reforms touched the heart of the real problem: servants were poorly paid (eight cents an hour in this "enlightened" household) and treated with little respect. Even so, scientific management did have some potential benefits for domestic servants. Many household workers complained about the lack of a regular schedule, constantly changing orders, and conflicting demands. If household work were truly rationalized, it might free them of some of the arbitrary, demeaning, and disorderly conditions of their work lives.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zeitschriften der Frauen veröffentlichten 
zwischen den gekennzeichneten Artikeln des Bürgerkrieges und des 
Zweiten Weltkrieges häufig auf "dem Bedienstetproblem" für ihre 
Mittelklasseleser. Für Geliebten war das "Problem" das 
unzulängliche Zubehör "der kompetenten" Haushalt Hilfe. Über 
den Jahren änderte die Lösung zum Problem. Während im 19. 
Jahrhundert wurden die Frauen geraten, den Idealen der christlichen 
mütterlichen Wohltätigkeit, in den 20. Jahrhundertfrauen zu folgen 
wurden geraten, um Grundregeln der wissenschaftlichen 
Unternehmensführung zu folgen. Als dieser Artikel 1912 durch 
Christine Frederick, bildet ein Fürsprecher der wissenschaftlichen 
Unternehmensführung für Hausfrauen, klar, keine dieser 
Verbesserungen berührte das Innere des realen Problems: 
Bedienstete waren (acht Cents ein Stunde diesbezüglich 
"erleuchteter" Haushalt) und behandelt mit wenig Respekt schlecht 
zahlend. Allerdings hatte wissenschaftliche Unternehmensführung
irgendeinen möglichen Nutzen für inländische Bedienstete. 
Viele Haushalt Arbeiter beschwerten sich über das Fehlen von 
einem regelmäßigen Zeitplan, ständig ändernden Ordnungen und 
kontroversen Nachfragen. Wenn Haushalt Arbeit wirklich 
rationalisiert wurden, konnte sie sie von einigen vom willkürlichen, 
vom Erniedrigen und von den ungeordneten Bedingungen ihrer Arbeit 
Lebensdauern freigeben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les magazines des femmes ont édité entre les 
articles fréquemment décrits de guerre civile et de deuxième guerre
mondiale sur "le problème d'domestique" pour leurs lecteurs de classe
moyenne. Pour des maîtresses, le "problème" était 
l'approvisionnement insatisfaisant en aide "compétente" de ménage. 
Au cours des années, la solution au problème a changé. 
Considérant qu'au 19ème siècle les femmes ont été 
conseillées suivre les idéaux de la bienveillance maternelle 
chrétienne, dans les 20èmes femmes de siècle ont été informées 
pour suivre des principes de gestion scientifique. En tant que 
cet article 1912 par Christine Frederick, un avocat de gestion 
scientifique pour des femmes au foyer, fait clairement, aucune de ces 
réformes a touché le coeur du problème réel : les 
domestiques étaient mal payés (huit cents par heure en cela 
ménage)"éclairé" et traité avec peu de respect. Néanmoins, 
la gestion scientifique a eu quelques avantages potentiels pour les 
domestiques domestiques. Beaucoup d'ouvriers de ménage se sont 
plaints au sujet du manque d'un programme régulier, des commandes 
changeantes constamment, et des demandes contradictoires. Si le 
travail de ménage étaient vraiment rationalisés, il pourrait les 
libérer de certaines de l'arbitraire, de se humilier, et des 
conditions désordonnées de leurs vies de travail.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os compartimentos das mulheres publicaram entre os
artigos freqüentemente caracterizados da guerra civil e da segunda 
guerra mundial "no problema do empregado" para seus leitores do 
middle-class. Para mistresses, o "problema" era a fonte 
inadequada da ajuda "competente" da casa. Sobre os anos, a 
solução ao problema mudou. Visto que no 1ø século as 
mulheres foram aconselhadas seguir os ideals do benevolence maternal 
christian, nas 20as mulheres do século foram recomendadas para seguir
princípios da gerência científica. Como este artigo 1912 por 
Christine Frederick, um advogado da gerência científica para 
housewives, faz claramente, nenhumas destas reformas tocou no 
coração do problema real: os empregados eram deficientemente 
pagos (oito centavos um a hora neste casa "enlightened") e tratado com
pouco respeito. Mesmo assim, a gerência científica teve alguns
benefícios potenciais para empregados domésticos. Muitos 
trabalhadores da casa queixaram-se sobre a falta de uma programação 
regular, de umas ordens constantemente em mudança, e de umas demandas
opondo. Se o trabalho da casa rationalized verdadeiramente, 
pôde livrá-los de algumas do arbitrário, de humilhar-se, e das 
condições desordenadas de suas vidas do trabalho.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli scomparti delle donne hanno pubblicato fra gli
articoli frequentemente descritti della seconda guerra mondiale e di 
guerra civile "sul problema del servo" per i loro lettori della classe
media. Per i mistresses, "il problema" era il rifornimento 
inadeguato di aiuto "competente" della famiglia. Nel corso degli
anni, la soluzione al problema è cambiato. Considerando che nel
diciannovesimo secolo le donne sono state consigliate seguire gli 
ideali di benevolence materno cristiano, nelle ventesime donne di 
secolo si sono raccomandate per seguire i principii della gestione 
scientifica. Come questo articolo 1912 da Christine Frederick, 
un fautore della gestione scientifica per le casalinghe, fa 
chiaramente, nessun di queste riforme ha toccato il cuore del problema
reale: i servi erano male paid (otto centesimi un l'ora in 
questo famiglia "chiarita") e trattato con poco rispetto. 
Nondimeno, la gestione scientifica ha avuta alcuni benefici 
potenziali per i servi domestici. Molti operai della famiglia 
hanno protestato circa la mancanza di programma normale, di ordini 
costantemente cambianti e di richieste stanti in conflitto. Se 
il lavoro della famiglia allineare fosse razionalizzato, potrebbe 
liberarlo di alcuni dell'arbitrario, abbassarsi e dei termini 
disordinati delle loro vite del lavoro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Περιοδικά γυναικών που δημοσιεύονται μεταξύ του 
εμφύλιου πολέμου και του παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ τα συχνά 
χαρακτηρισμένα άρθρα σχετικά με "το πρόβλημα υπαλλήλων" για τους 
αναγνώστες μεσαίων τάξεών τους. Για τις κυρίες, το 
"πρόβλημα" ήταν ο ανεπαρκής ανεφοδιασμός των "ικανών" οικιακών 
οδηγιών. Κατά τη διάρκεια των ετών, η λύση στο πρόβλημα 
άλλαξε. Εκτιμώντας ότι στο 19$ο αιώνα οι γυναίκες δέχτηκαν
συμβουλές για να ακολουθήσουν τα ιδανικά της χριστιανικής 
μητρικής καλοκαγαθίας, στο 20ό αιώνα οι γυναίκες ενθαρρύνθηκαν 
για να ακολουθήσουν τις αρχές της επιστημονικής διαχείρισης. 
Δεδομένου ότι αυτό το άρθρο του 1912 από την 
Christine Frederick, ένας συνήγορος της επιστημονικής 
διαχείρισης για τις νοικοκυρές, καθιστά σαφές, καμία από αυτές 
τις μεταρρυθμίσεις δεν άγγιξε την καρδιά του πραγματικού 
προβλήματος: οι υπάλληλοι ήταν κακώς πληρωμένοι (οκτώ σεντ
μια ώρα σε αυτήν την "διαφωτισμένη" οικογένεια) και 
μεταχειρίστηκαν με λίγο σεβασμό. Ακόμα κι έτσι, η 
επιστημονική διαχείριση είχε μερικά πιθανά οφέλη για τους 
εσωτερικούς υπαλλήλους. Πολλοί οικιακοί εργαζόμενοι 
παραπονέθηκαν για την έλλειψη ενός κανονικού προγράμματος, 
συνεχώς μεταβαλλόμενες κατατάξεις, και συγκρουόμενες απαιτήσεις. 
Εάν η οικιακή εργασία οργανώθηκε ορθολογικά αληθινά, να 
τους ελευθερώσει μερικοί από τον αυθαίρετο, τον εξευτελισμό, και 
ατίθασους τους όρους των ζωών εργασίας τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los compartimientos de las mujeres publicaron 
entre los artículos con frecuencia ofrecidos de la guerra civil y de 
la Segunda Guerra Mundial sobre "el problema del criado" para sus 
programas de lectura de la clase media. Para las amantes, el 
"problema" era la fuente inadecuada de ayuda "competente" de la casa. 
Sobre los años, la solución al problema cambió. 
Mientras que en el diecinueveavo siglo se aconsejó a las 
mujeres que siguieran los ideales de la benevolencia maternal 
cristiana, en las vigésimas mujeres del siglo fueron aconsejadas para
seguir principios de la gerencia científica. Como este 
artículo 1912 de Christine Frederick, un abogado de la gerencia 
científica para las amas de casa, hace claramente, ningunas de estas 
reformas tocó el corazón del problema verdadero: los criados 
eran mal pagados (ocho centavos por hora en esto casa "aclarada") y 
tratado con poco respecto. Incluso así pues, la gerencia 
científica tenía algunas ventajas potenciales para los criados 
domésticos. Muchos trabajadores de la casa se quejaron por la 
carencia de un horario regular, de órdenes constantemente que 
cambiaban, y de demandas que estaban en conflicto. Si el trabajo
de la casa fue racionalizado verdad, puede ser que los libere de 
algunas del arbitrario, de degradarse, y de las condiciones 
desordenadas de sus vidas del trabajo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087161</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103540</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/upstairs-downstairs-the-science-of-service</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
