<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106329</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106329</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206074</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Bioed Online</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bioed Online</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bioed En ligne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Bioed Em linha</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Bioed In linea</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Bioed on-line</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Bioed En línea</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features lessons on the water cycle and global warming, the X chromosome, sleep and daily rhythms, muscles and bones, and food and fitness. Experts offer presentations (streaming videos) on classification, cloning, viruses, infectious diseases, animal behavior, Mendelian genetics, genomes, sleep and performance, body systems, childhood obesity, asthma, ecosystems, populations, nutrition and energy, and more. Articles discuss biology news -- stem cells, bird flu, and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Merkmale Lektionen auf der Wasserschleife und das 
globale Wärmen, das X Chromosom, der Schlaf und tägliche Rhythmen, 
Muskeln und Knochen und Nahrung und Eignung. Experten bieten 
Darstellungen (strömende videos) auf Klassifikation, Klonen, Viren, 
ansteckende Krankheiten, Tierverhalten, Mendelian Genetik, Genome, 
Schlaf und Leistung, Körpersysteme, Kindheitkorpulenz, Asthma, 
Oekosysteme, Bevölkerungen, Nahrung und Energie und mehr an. 
Artikel behandeln Biologienachrichten -- Stammzellen, 
Vogelgrippe und mehr.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">leçons de dispositifs sur le cycle de l'eau et le
chauffage global, le chromosome de X, le sommeil et rythmes 
quotidiens, muscles et os, et nourriture et forme physique. Les 
experts offrent des présentations (videos coulants) sur la 
classification, le clonage, les virus, les maladies infectieuses, le 
comportement animal, la génétique de Mendelian, les génomes, le 
sommeil et l'exécution, les systèmes de corps, l'obésité 
d'enfance, l'asthme, les écosystèmes, les populations, la nutrition 
et l'énergie, et plus. Les articles discutent des nouvelles de 
biologie -- cellules de tige, grippe d'oiseau, et plus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">lições das características no ciclo da água e 
aquecer-se global, o chromosome de X, o sono e ritmos diários, 
músculos e ossos, e alimento e aptidão. Os peritos oferecem 
apresentações (videos fluindo) na classificação, o cloning, os 
vírus, doenças infectious, o comportamento animal, o genetics de 
Mendelian, os genomes, o sono e o desempenho, os sistemas do corpo, o 
obesity da infância, o asthma, os ecosystems, as populações, o 
nutrition e a energia, e mais. Os artigos discutem notícias da 
biologia -- pilhas de haste, flu do pássaro, e mais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">lezioni delle caratteristiche sul ciclo dell'acqua
ed il riscaldamento globale, il cromosoma di X, il sonno e ritmi 
quotidiani, muscoli ed ossa ed alimento ed idoneità. Gli 
esperti offrono le presentazioni (videos effluenti) sulla 
classificazione, clonazione, virus, malattie contagiose, comportamento
animale, la genetica di Mendelian, genomes, sonno e prestazioni, 
sistemi del corpo, l'obesità di infanzia, asma, ecosistemi, 
popolazioni, nutrizione ed energia e più. Gli articoli 
discutono le notizie di biologia -- cellule formative, flu 
dell'uccello e più.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χαρακτηρίζει τα μαθήματα στον κύκλο ύδατος και την 
παγκόσμια αύξηση της θερμοκρασίας λόγω του φαινομένου του 
θερμοκηπίου, το χρωμόσωμα Χ, τον ύπνο και τους καθημερινούς 
ρυθμούς, τους μυς και τα κόκκαλα, και τα τρόφιμα και την 
ικανότητα. Οι εμπειρογνώμονες προσφέρουν τις παρουσιάσεις 
(βίντεο ροής) για την ταξινόμηση, την κλωνοποίηση, τους ιούς, τις
μολυσματικές ασθένειες, τη ζωική συμπεριφορά, τη μεντελική 
γενετική, τα γονιδιώματα, τον ύπνο και την απόδοση, τα συστήματα 
σωμάτων, την παχυσαρκία παιδικής ηλικίας, το άσθμα, τα 
οικοσυστήματα, τους πληθυσμούς, τη διατροφή και την ενέργεια, και 
περισσότερους. Τα άρθρα συζητούν τις ειδήσεις της βιολογίας
-- κύτταρα μίσχων, γρίπη πουλιών, και περισσότεροι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">lecciones de las características en el ciclo del 
agua y el calentarse global, el cromosoma de X, el sueño y ritmos 
diarios, músculos y huesos, y alimento y aptitud. Los expertos 
ofrecen las presentaciones (videos que fluyen) en la clasificación, 
reproducción, los virus, las enfermedades infecciosas, el 
comportamiento animal, genética de Mendelian, los genomas, sueño
y funcionamiento, los sistemas del cuerpo, obesidad de la niñez, 
asma, los ecosistemas, las poblaciones, nutrición y energía, y más.
Los artículos discuten las noticias de la biología -- células
de vástago, gripe del pájaro, y más.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206074</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106329</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/bioed-online</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
