<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104710</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104710</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202932</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">GeoMaths - 1st Level Modules</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">GeoMaths - 1. Stufe Module</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">GeoMaths - 1ers Modules de Niveau</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">GeoMaths - 1os Módulos Do Nível</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">GeoMaths - Primi Moduli Del Livello</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">GeoMaths - 1$ες ενότητες επιπέδων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">GeoMaths - 1ros Módulos Del Nivel</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">University of College London hosts a site of notation and reference material on math skills in the context of geoscience. These exercises provide realistic geologic scenarios and work through examples, with notation on the math used to solve them. Examples include using trigonometry to find the true width of strata, logarithms to understand the Richter scale, and vectors to find plate velocities at a triple junction. Relevant vocabulary is linked to a glossary of mathematical terms. Many of the modules link to a MathHelp page for explanation of techniques used, and then come back to the geologic scenario to finish the problem. This resource is part of the Teaching Quantitative Skills in the Geosciences collection. http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Universität der Hochschule London bewirtet eine 
Site der Darstellung und des Bezugsmaterials auf Mathefähigkeiten im 
Kontext von geoscience. Diese Übungen stellen realistische 
geologische Drehbücher und Arbeit durch Beispiele, mit Darstellung 
auf Mathe zur Verfügung, das verwendet wird, um sie zu lösen. 
Beispiele schließen mit Trigonometrie, die zutreffende Breite 
der Schichten, der Logarithmen, um die Richterskala zu verstehen und 
der Vektoren zu finden, um Platte Geschwindigkeiten an einer 
dreifachen Verzweigung zu finden ein. Relevanter Wortschatz wird
mit einem Glossar der mathematischen Ausdrücke gebunden. Viele 
der Module binden mit einer MathHelp Seite für Erklärung der 
verwendeten Techniken und kommen dann zum geologischen Drehbuch 
zurück, um das Problem zu beenden. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein 
Teil der Unterricht quantitativen Fähigkeiten in der Geosciences 
Ansammlung http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'université de l'université Londres accueille 
un site de notation et de documentation de référence sur des 
qualifications de maths dans le contexte du geoscience. Ces 
exercices fournissent les scénarios et le travail géologiques 
réalistes par des exemples, en notation sur les maths employées pour
les résoudre. Les exemples incluent en utilisant la 
trigonométrie pour trouver la largeur vraie des strates, des 
logarithmes pour comprendre l'échelle de Richter, et des vecteurs 
pour trouver des vitesses de plat à une jonction triple. Le 
vocabulaire approprié est joint à un glossaire des termes 
mathématiques. Plusieurs des modules joignent à une page de 
MathHelp pour l'explication des techniques utilisées, et puis 
reviennent au scénario géologique pour terminer le problème. 
Cette ressource fait partie des qualifications quantitatives 
d'enseignement dans la collection 
http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/ de Geosciences</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A universidade da faculdade Londres hospeda um 
local da notação e do material de referência em habilidades do math
no contexto do geoscience. Estes exercícios fornecem scenarios 
e o trabalho geologic realísticos com os exemplos, com a notação no
math usado resolvê-los. Os exemplos incluem usando o 
trigonometry encontrar a largura verdadeira dos strata, dos 
logarítmos para compreender a escala de Richter, e dos vetores para 
encontrar velocidades da placa em uma junção tripla. O 
vocabulário relevante é ligado a um glossário de termos 
matemáticos. Muitos dos módulos ligam a uma página de 
MathHelp para a explanação das técnicas usadas, e voltam então ao 
scenario geologic para terminar o problema. Este recurso é 
parte das habilidades quantitative do ensino na coleção 
http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/ de Geosciences</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'università di università Londra ospita un 
luogo della notazione e del materiale di riferimento sulle abilità di
per la matematica nel contesto del geoscience. Queste 
esercitazioni forniscono i piani d'azione ed il lavoro geologici 
realistichi con gli esempi, la notazione sul per la matematica usato 
per risolverli. Gli esempi includono usando la trigonometria per
trovare la larghezza allineare degli strati, dei logaritmi per capire 
la scala di Richter e dei vettori per trovare le velocità della 
piastra ad una giunzione triplice. Il vocabolario relativo è 
collegato ad un glossario dei termini matematici. Molti dei 
moduli si collegano ad una pagina di MathHelp per spiegazione delle 
tecniche usate ed allora ritornano al piano d'azione geologico per 
rifinire il problema. Questa risorsa fa parte delle abilità 
quantitative di insegnamento nell'accumulazione 
http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/ di Geosciences</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πανεπιστήμιο των ξένιων χ/υ του Λονδίνου κολλεγίου μια
περιοχή του υλικού σημείωσης και αναφοράς στις δεξιότητες math
στα πλαίσια του geoscience. Αυτές οι ασκήσεις παρέχουν τα
ρεαλιστικά γεωλογικά σενάρια και λειτουργούν μέσω των 
παραδειγμάτων, με τη σημείωση στο math που χρησιμοποιείται για 
να τα λύσει. Τα παραδείγματα περιλαμβάνουν τη χρησιμοποίηση 
trigonometry για να βρούν το αληθινό πλάτος των στρωμάτων, των 
λογαρίθμων για να καταλάβουν την κλίμακα Richter, και των 
διανυσμάτων για να βρούν τις ταχύτητες πιάτων σε μια τριπλή 
σύνδεση. Το σχετικό λεξιλόγιο συνδέεται με ένα γλωσσάρι 
μαθηματικών όρων. Πολλές από τις ενότητες συνδέουν με μια 
σελίδα MathHelp για την εξήγηση των τεχνικών χρησιμοποιούμενων,
και επιστρέφουν έπειτα στο γεωλογικό σενάριο για να τελειώσουν το
πρόβλημα. Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς είναι μέρος των 
ποσοτικών δεξιοτήτων διδασκαλίας στη Geosciences συλλογή 
http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La universidad de la universidad Londres recibe un
sitio de la notación y del material de referencia en habilidades de 
la matemáticas en el contexto del geoscience. Estos ejercicios 
proporcionan a decorados y al trabajo geológicos realistas con 
ejemplos, de la notación en la matemáticas usada para solucionarlos.
Los ejemplos incluyen con la trigonometría para encontrar la 
anchura verdadera de estratos, de logaritmos para entender la escala 
de Richter, y de vectores para encontrar velocidades de la placa en 
una ensambladura triple. El vocabulario relevante se conecta a 
un glosario de términos matemáticos. Muchos de los módulos 
conectan a una paginación de MathHelp para la explicación de las 
técnicas usadas, y después se vuelven al decorado geológico para 
acabar el problema. Este recurso es parte de las habilidades 
cuantitativas de la enseñanza en la colección 
http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/ de Geosciences</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ROWENA BOWLES
FN:ROWENA BOWLES
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202932</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104710</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/geomaths-1st-level-modules</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
