<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108433</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108433</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974037</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Seasonal Migrations: Bald Eagle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Saisonmigrationen: Kahler Adler</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Transferts Saisonniers : Aigle Chauve</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Migrações Seasonal: Águia Bald</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Espansioni Stagionali: Aquila Calva</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εποχιακές μεταναστεύσεις: Φαλακρός αετός</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Migraciones Estacionales: Águila Calva</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Students join a biologist who uses satellite telemetry to track bald eagles back to their nests in Canada. They participate in an online contest and predict the location of each eagle's nest. Through these interrelated investigations, students discover that sunlight drives all living systems and they learn about the dynamic ecosystem that surrounds and connects them. Children follow the migrations of animals. They observe, research, and report their findings, and watch journeys progress on real-time maps. Weekly updates: Wednesdays, February-May. Guidelines, lessons, activities, reading connections, and interactive maps are included for each study.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kursteilnehmer verbinden einen Biologen, der 
Satellitenfernmessung verwendet, um kahle Adler zurück zu ihren 
Nestern in Kanada aufzuspüren. Sie nehmen an einem 
Onlinewettbewerb teil und sagen den Standort des Nestes jedes Adlers 
voraus. Durch diese zusammenhängend Untersuchungen entdecken 
Kursteilnehmer, daß Tageslicht alle lebenden Systeme antreibt und sie
über das dynamische Oekosystem erlernen, das sie umgibt und 
anschließt. Kinder folgen den Migrationen der Tiere. Sie 
beobachten, erforschen und berichten über ihre Entdeckungen, und 
Uhrreisen kommen auf Echtzeitkarten weiter. Wöchentliche 
Aktualisierungsvorgänge: Mittwoche, Februar-Mai. 
Korrekturlinien, Lektionen, Aktivitäten, Anschlüsse und 
interaktive Karten lesend sind für jede Studie enthalten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les étudiants joignent un biologiste qui emploie 
la télémétrie satellite pour dépister les aigles chauves de 
nouveau à leurs emboîtements au Canada. Ils participent à un 
concours en ligne et prévoient l'emplacement de l'emboîtement de 
chaque aigle. Par ces investigations en corrélation, les 
étudiants découvrent que la lumière du soleil pilote tous les 
systèmes vivants et ils se renseignent sur l'écosystème dynamique 
qui les entoure et relie. Les enfants suivent les transferts des
animaux. Ils observent, recherchent, et enregistrent leurs 
résultats, et les voyages de montre progressent sur les cartes en 
temps réel. Mises à jour hebdomadaires : Mercredi, 
Février-Mai. Les directives, leçons, activités, lisant des 
connexions, et des cartes interactives sont incluses pour chaque 
étude.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os estudantes juntam um biólogo que use a 
telemetria satellite seguir para trás águias bald a seus ninhos em 
Canadá. Participam em uma competição em linha e predizem a 
posição do ninho de cada águia. Com estas investigações 
relacionadas, os estudantes descobrem que a luz solar dirige todos os 
sistemas vivos e aprendem sobre o ecosystem dinâmico que os cerca e 
conecta. As crianças seguem as migrações dos animais. 
Observam, pesquisam, e relatam seus findings, e as viagens do 
relógio progridem em mapas real-time. Updates semanais: 
Quartas-feiras, Fevereiro-Maio. Os guidelines, lições, 
atividades, lendo conexões, e mapas interativos são incluídos para 
cada estudo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli allievi uniscono un biologo che usa la 
telemetria satellite per rintracciare le aquile calve di nuovo ai loro
nidi nel Canada. Partecipano ad un concorso in linea e predicono
la posizione del nido di ogni aquila. Con queste indagini 
correlate, gli allievi scoprono che la luce solare guida tutti i 
sistemi viventi ed imparano circa l'ecosistema dinamico che li 
circonda e collega. I bambini seguono le espansioni degli 
animali. Osservano, ricercano e segnalano i loro risultati ed i 
viaggi della vigilanza progrediscono sui programmi in tempo reale. 
Aggiornamenti settimanali: Mercoledì, Febbraio-Maggio. 
La guida di riferimento, lezioni, attività, leggendo i 
collegamenti ed i programmi interattivi è inclusa per ogni studio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι σπουδαστές ενώνουν έναν βιολόγο που χρησιμοποιεί 
τη δορυφορική τηλεμετρία στους φαλακρούς αετούς διαδρομής πίσω 
στις φωλιές τους στον Καναδά. Συμμετέχουν σε έναν σε 
απευθείας σύνδεση διαγωνισμό και προβλέπουν τη θέση της φωλιάς 
κάθε αετού. Μέσω αυτών των αλληλένδετων ερευνών, οι 
σπουδαστές ανακαλύπτουν ότι το φως του ήλιου οδηγεί όλα τα 
συστήματα διαβίωσης και μαθαίνουν για το δυναμικό οικοσύστημα που
τους περιβάλλει και συνδέει. Τα παιδιά ακολουθούν τις 
μεταναστεύσεις των ζώων. Παρατηρούν, έρευνα, και εκθέτουν 
τα συμπεράσματά τους, και τα ταξίδια ρολογιών προχωρούν στους σε 
πραγματικό χρόνο χάρτες. Εβδομαδιαίες αναπροσαρμογές: 
Τετάρτες, Φεβρουάριος-Μάιος. Οι οδηγίες, 
μαθήματα, δραστηριότητες, διαβάζοντας τις συνδέσεις, και τους 
διαλογικούς χάρτες συμπεριλαμβάνονται για κάθε μελέτη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los estudiantes ensamblan a biólogo que utiliza 
telemetría basada en los satélites para seguir águilas calvas de 
nuevo a sus jerarquías en Canadá. Participan en una 
competencia en línea y predicen la localización de la jerarquía de 
cada águila. Con estas investigaciones correlacionadas, los 
estudiantes descubren que la luz del sol conduce todos los sistemas 
vivos y aprenden sobre el ecosistema dinámico que los rodea y 
conecta. Los niños siguen las migraciones de animales. 
Observan, investigan, y señalan sus resultados, y los viajes 
del reloj progresan en correspondencias en tiempo real. 
Actualizaciones semanales: Miércoles, Febrero-Mayo. 
Las guías de consulta, lecciones, actividades, leyendo 
conexiones, y correspondencias interactivas son incluidas para cada 
estudio.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974037</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108433</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/seasonal-migrations-bald-eagle</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
