<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107425</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107425</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086483</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">More Logic, Less Feeling: Senator Vest Nixes Woman Suffrage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mehr Logik, Weniger Gefühl: Senator Vest 
Nixes Woman Suffrage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Plus de Logique, Moins de Sentiment : Le 
Sénateur Vest Nixes Woman Suffrage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Mais Lógica, Menos Sentimento: Senator 
Investir Nixes Mulher Suffrage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Più Logica, Meno Sensibilità: Il Senatore 
Vest Nixes Woman Suffrage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Περισσότερη λογική, λιγότερο συναίσθημα: 
Γερουσιαστής Vest Nixes Woman Suffrage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Más Lógica, Menos Sensación: Senador Vest 
Nixes Woman Suffrage</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The struggle for woman suffrage lasted almost a century, beginning with the 1848 Woman's Rights Convention at Seneca Falls, New York, and including the 1890 union of two competing suffrage organizations to form the National American Woman Suffrage Association (NAWSA). NAWSA and other organizations campaigned diligently for the vote in a variety of ways but did not achieve success until the ratification of the Nineteenth Amendment to the U.S. Constitution in 1920. The demand to change the Constitution to grant women the vote (raised by Elizabeth Cady Stanton as early as 1878) was contentious enough; but the pressure for woman suffrage advocates to address other issues often gave the debate over the vote for women a particularly divisive tone. In an 1887 speech on the floor of the U.S. Senate, Democratic Senator George G. Vest of Missouri put forth traditional arguments that a woman's proper place was at home, not the ballot box.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Kampf für Fraustimmrecht dauerte fast ein 
Jahrhundert, fing mit der 1848 Recht-Vereinbarung der Frau an den 
Seneca-Fällen, New York an, und enthält den Anschluß 1890 von zwei 
konkurrierenden Stimmrechtorganisationen, um die nationale 
amerikanische Frau-Stimmrecht-Verbindung (NAWSA) zu bilden. 
NAWSA und andere Organisationen warben, mit Sorgfalt für die 
Stimme in einer Vielzahl von Methoden aber erzielten Erfolg bis die 
Bestätigung der 19.änderung nicht zur VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Beschaffenheit 1920. Die Nachfrage, zum der Beschaffenheit zu 
den Bewilligung Frauen zu ändern die Stimme (angehoben von Elizabeth 
Cady Stanton schon in 1878) war genug streitsüchtig; aber der 
Druck, damit Fraustimmrechtfürsprecher andere Punkte gaben der 
Debatte über der Stimme für Frauen einen besonders teilenden Ton 
häufig ansprechen. In eine Rede 1887 auf dem Fußboden des 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Senats, setzte demokratischer Senator George G. 
Vest von Missouri weiter traditionelle Argumente, daß der korrekte 
Platz einer Frau zu Hause war, nicht die Wahlurne ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La lutte pour le suffrage de femme a duré presque
un siècle, commençant par 1848 la convention des droits de la femme 
aux automnes de Seneca, New York, et incluant l'union 1890 de deux
organismes de concurrence de suffrage pour former l'association 
américaine nationale de suffrage de femme (NAWSA). NAWSA et 
d'autres organismes ont fait campagne diligemment pour la voix par une
multitude de moyens mais n'ont pas réalisé le succès jusqu'à la 
ratification du dix-neuvième amendement à la constitution des 
ETATS-UNIS en 1920. La demande pour changer la constitution en 
femmes de concession la voix (augmentée par Elizabeth Cady Stanton 
dès 1878) était assez controversable ; mais la pression pour 
que les avocats de suffrage de femme abordent d'autres questions a 
souvent donné à la discussion au-dessus de la voix pour des femmes 
une tonalité particulièrement séparative. Dans un discours 
1887 sur le plancher du sénat des ETATS-UNIS, sénateur démocratique
George G. Vest du Missouri a mis en avant des arguments 
traditionnels que la place appropriée d'une femme était à la 
maison, pas l'urne de vote.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O esforço para o suffrage da mulher durou quase 
um século, começando com a convenção 1848 da mulher em quedas do 
seneca, New York das direitas, e incluindo a união 1890 de duas 
organizações competindo do suffrage para dar forma à associação 
americana nacional do suffrage da mulher (NAWSA). NAWSA e outras
organizações fizeram campanha diligently para o voto em uma 
variedade das maneiras mas não conseguiram o sucesso até o 
ratification da décima nona emenda ao constitution de ESTADOS UNIDOS 
em 1920. A demanda para mudar o constitution às mulheres da 
concessão o voto (levantado por Elizabeth Cady Stanton assim que 
1878) era contentious bastante; mas a pressão para que os 
advogados do suffrage da mulher dirijam-se a outras edições deu 
frequentemente ao debate sobre o voto para mulheres um tom 
particularmente divisive. Em um discurso 1887 no assoalho do 
senate de ESTADOS UNIDOS, o senator democrático George G. Investir de
Missouri pôs adiante argumentos tradicionais que o lugar apropriado 
de uma mulher estava na HOME, não a caixa de cédula.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La lotta per suffrage della donna ha durato quasi 
un secolo, cominciante con la convenzione 1848 della donna alle cadute
del seneca, New York di diritti ed includente l'unione 1890 di due 
organizzazioni competenti di suffrage per formare l'associazione 
americana nazionale di suffrage della donna (NAWSA). NAWSA ed 
altre organizzazioni hanno fatto una campagna diligente per il voto in
una varietà di modi ma non hanno realizzato il successo fino alla 
ratifica della diciannovesima correzione alla costituzione degli STATI
UNITI in 1920. La richiesta per cambiare la costituzione alle 
donne di concessione il voto (sollevato di Elizabeth Cady Stanton fin 
da 1878) era abbastanza polemica; ma la pressione affinchè i 
fautori di suffrage della donna richiami altre edizioni spesso ha dato
al dibattito sopra il voto per le donne un tono particolarmente che 
divide. In un discorso 1887 sul pavimento del senato degli STATI
UNITI, il senatore democratico George G. Vest del Missouri ha messo 
avanti gli argomenti tradizionali che il posto adeguato della donna 
era nel paese, non la casella di scheda elettorale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η προσπάθεια για την ψήφο γυναικών διάρκεσε σχεδόν 
έναν αιώνα, αρχίζοντας με τη 1848 Συνθήκη δικαιωμάτων της 
γυναίκας σε Σενέκα Falls, Νέα Υόρκη, και συμπεριλαμβανομένης 
της ένωσης 1890 δύο ανταγωνιστικών οργανώσεων ψήφου για να 
διαμορφώσει την εθνική αμερικανική ένωση ψήφου γυναικών 
(NAWSA). NAWSA και άλλες οργανώσεις έκαναν εκστρατεία
επιμελώς για την ψηφοφορία με ποικίλους τρόπους αλλά δεν 
επέτυχαν την επιτυχία μέχρι την επικύρωση της δέκατης έννατης 
τροποποίησης στο ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΌ σύνταγμα το 1920. Η απαίτηση
για να αλλάξει το σύνταγμα για να χορηγήσει στις γυναίκες την 
ψηφοφορία (που αυξήθηκε από Elizabeth Cady Stanton από 
1878) ήταν αρκετά εριστικό αλλά η πίεση για τους συνηγόρους 
ψήφου γυναικών να αντιμετωπίσουν άλλα ζητήματα έδωσε συχνά στη 
συζήτηση πέρα από την ψηφοφορία για τις γυναίκες έναν ιδιαίτερα
διαχωριστικό τόνο. Σε μια ομιλία 1887 στο πάτωμα της 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ Συγκλήτου, ο δημοκρατικός γερουσιαστής George G.
Vest του Μισσούρι έβαλε εμπρός τα παραδοσιακά ορίσματα ότι η 
κατάλληλη θέση μιας γυναίκας δεν ήταν στο σπίτι, το πεδίο 
ψήφου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La lucha para el sufragio de la mujer casi duró 
un siglo, comenzando con la convención 1848 de la mujer en las 
caídas del seneca, Nueva York de las derechas, e incluyendo la unión
1890 de dos organizaciones competentes del sufragio para formar la 
asociación americana nacional del sufragio de la mujer (NAWSA). 
NAWSA y otras organizaciones hicieron campaña diligente para el
voto en una variedad de maneras pero no alcanzaron éxito hasta la 
ratificación de la diecinueveavo enmienda a la constitución de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS en 1920. La demanda para cambiar la constitución
a las mujeres de la concesión el voto (levantado por Elizabeth Cady 
Stanton desde 1878) era bastante discutible; pero la presión 
para que los abogados del sufragio de la mujer traten otras ediciones 
a menudo dio a discusión sobre el voto para las mujeres un tono 
determinado divisivo. En un discurso 1887 en el suelo del senado
de ESTADOS UNIDOS, senador democrático George G. Vest de Missouri 
puso adelante los argumentos tradicionales que el lugar apropiado de 
una mujer estaba en el país, no el rectángulo de balota.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086483</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107425</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/more-logic-less-feeling-senator-vest-nixes-woman-suffrage</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
