<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103952</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103952</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086452</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Making Common Cause": The Knights' Assembly Hall</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">", Geläufige Ursache Bildend": Aula Der 
Ritter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Faisant La Cause Commune" : l'Assemblée 
Hall des Chevaliers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Fazendo A Causa Comum": O Conjunto Salão 
Dos Knights'</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Facendo Causa Comune": L'Assemblea 
Corridoio Dei Cavalieri</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Κάνοντας την κοινή αιτία": Η αίθουσα 
συμβολικών γλωσσών των ιπποτών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Haciendo Causa Común": La Asamblea Pasillo
De los Caballeros</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This description of a Washington D.C. Knights of Labor assembly hall in the late 1880s appeared in T. Fulton Gantt's novel,  Breaking the Chains: A Story of the Present Industrial Struggle ,. It was was first published in 1887, in serial form, in  The Lance,  a labor newspaper in Salem, Oregon. Many other novels from this period addressed the problems of labor conflict and inequality, but Gantt was one of the very few to see unionization as the answer to the problems of working people. Although the Knights officially prohibited lawyers ("non-producers") from membership, Gantt was both a member of the bar and the Knights. Gantt's description, which presumably drew from his own experience in District Assembly 66 in Washington, D.C., conveyed a sense of the diverse social, political, and intellectual functions that the meeting hall played for its members, as well as the issues that animated their debates.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Beschreibung von einem Washington D.C. 
Knights der Arbeitsaulas im späten 1880s erschien T. Fulton Gantts im
Roman und brach die Ketten: Eine Geschichte des anwesenden 
industriellen Kampfes. sie war wurde veröffentlicht zuerst 1887, in 
der Serienform, in der Lanze, in einer Arbeitszeitung in Salem, 
Oregon. Viele andere Romane von dieser Periode adressierten die 
Probleme Arbeitßüberschneidung und Verschiedenheit, aber Gantt war 
eins von den sehr wenigen, zum von von Unionization da die Antwort zu 
den Problemen von Arbeits Leute zu sehen. Obgleich die Ritter 
offiziell Rechtsanwälte ("Nichtproduzenten") von der Mitgliedschaft 
verboten, war Gantt ein Bauteil des Stabes und die Ritter. 
Beschreibung Gantts, die vermutlich von seiner eigenen Erfahrung
in Bezirk 66 in Washington zeichnete, Gleichstrom, übermittelte eine 
Richtung der verschiedenen Sozial-, politischen und intellektuellen 
Funktionen, die die Sitzung Halle für seine Bauteile spielte, sowie 
die Ausgaben, die ihre Debatten belebten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette description de Washington D.C. Knights de 
hall d'assemblage de travail vers la fin de 1880s est apparue en roman
de T. Fulton Gantt's, cassant les chaînes : Une histoire de la 
lutte industrielle actuelle. elle était a été éditée la première
fois en 1887, en forme séquentielle, dans la lance, journal de 
travail à Salem, Orégon. Beaucoup d'autres romans de cette 
période ont adressé les problèmes du conflit et de l'inégalité de
travail, mais Gantt était l'un très des peu pour voir la 
syndicalisation car la réponse aux problèmes de travailler des 
personnes. Bien que les chevaliers aient officiellement interdit
des avocats ("non-producteurs") de l'adhésion, Gantt était un membre
de la barre et les chevaliers. La description de Gantt, qui a 
vraisemblablement tiré de sa propre expérience dans l'Assemblée 66 
de zone à Washington, C.C, a donné un sens des fonctions sociales, 
politiques, et intellectuelles diverses que le hall de réunion a 
jouées pour ses membres, aussi bien que les issues qui ont animé 
leurs discussions.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta descrição de um Washington C.C. Knights do 
salão de conjunto labor no 1880s atrasado apareceu na novela de T. 
Fulton Gantt, quebrando as correntes: Uma história do esforço 
industrial atual. era foi publicada primeiramente em 1887, no 
formulário de série, no lance, em um jornal labor em Salem, Oregon. 
Muitas outras novelas deste período dirigiram-se aos problemas 
do conflito e do desigualdade labor, mas Gantt era um muito do poucos 
para ver o unionization porque a resposta aos problemas de trabalhar 
povos. Embora os knights proibissem oficialmente advogados 
("non-produtores") da sociedade, Gantt era  um membro da barra e os 
knights. A descrição de Gantt, que desenhou presumably de sua 
própria experiência no conjunto 66 do distrito em Washington, C.C., 
fêz saber a um sentido das funções sociais, políticas, e 
intelectuais diversas que o salão da reunião jogou para seus 
membros, as.well.as as edições que animated seus debates.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa descrizione di una Washington D.C. Knights 
del corridoio di complessivo Di lavoro verso la fine di 1880s è 
comparso in romanzo del T. Fulton Gantt, tagliato le catene: Una
storia della lotta industriale attuale. era in primo luogo è stata 
pubblicata in 1887, nella forma seriale, nella lancia, in un giornale 
di lavoro a Salem, Oregon. Molti altri romanzi da questo 
periodo hanno richiamato i problemi del conflitto di lavoro e della 
diseguaglianza, ma Gantt era uno molto dei pochi per vedere il 
unionization poichè la risposta ai problemi di funzionamento della 
gente. Anche se i cavalieri hanno proibito ufficialmente gli 
avvocati ("non-produttori") dall'insieme dei membri, Gantt era sia un 
membro della barra che i cavalieri. La descrizione del Gantt, 
che presumibilmente ha dissipato dalla sua propria esperienza in 
Assemblea 66 del distretto in Washington, DC, ha trasportato un senso 
delle funzioni sociali, politiche ed intellettuali varie che il 
corridoio di riunione ha giocato per i relativi membri, così come le 
edizioni che hanno animato i loro dibattiti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιγραφή των ιπποτών ενός της Ουάσιγκτον 
ΣΥΝΕΧΟΎΣ ΡΕΎΜΑΤΟΣ της αίθουσας συμβολικών γλωσσών εργασίας προς 
το τέλος 1880s εμφανίστηκε στο μυθιστόρημα Τ. Fulton 
gantt, που σπάζει τις αλυσίδες: Μια ιστορία της παρούσας 
βιομηχανικής προσπάθειας. Ήταν δημοσιεύθηκε αρχικά το 
1887, στην τμηματική μορφή, στη λόγχη, μια εφημερίδα εργασίας 
στο Σάλεμ, Όρεγκον. Πολλά άλλα μυθιστορήματα από αυτήν 
την περίοδο εξέτασαν τα προβλήματα της σύγκρουσης και της 
ανισότητας εργασίας, αλλά gantt ήταν ένα από πολύ λίγα για 
να δει τη συνδικαλικοποίηση ως απάντηση στα προβλήματα 
των εργαζόμενων ανθρώπων. Αν και οι ιππότες απαγόρευσαν 
επίσημα τους δικηγόρους ("μη-παραγωγοί") από την ιδιότητα 
μέλους, gantt ήταν και μέλος της ράβδου και οι ιππότες. Gantt η περιγραφή, που έσυρε πιθανώς από την εμπειρία του στη 
συμβολική γλώσσα 66 περιοχής στην Ουάσιγκτον, ΣΥΝΕΧΈΣ ΡΕΎΜΑ, 
μεταβίβασε μια αίσθηση των διαφορετικών κοινωνικών, πολιτικών, 
και διανοητικών λειτουργιών ότι η αίθουσα συνεδρίασης έπαιξε για
τα μέλη της, καθώς επίσης και των ζητημάτων που ζωντάνεψαν τις 
συζητήσεις τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta descripción de un Washington D.C. Knights 
del pasillo de ensamblaje de trabajo en el último 1880s apareció en 
la novela de T. Fulton Gantt, rompiendo los encadenamientos: Una
historia de la actual lucha industrial. era primero fue publicada en 
1887, en forma serial, en la lanza, un periódico de trabajo en Salem,
Oregon. Muchas otras novelas a partir de este período trataron 
los problemas del conflicto y de la desigualdad de trabajo, pero Gantt
era uno muy del pocos para ver la sindicalización pues la respuesta a
los problemas de trabajar a gente. Aunque los caballeros 
prohibieron oficialmente a abogados ("no-productores") de calidad de 
miembro, Gantt era un miembro de la barra y los caballeros. La 
descripción de Gantt, que trazó probablemente de su propia 
experiencia en la asamblea 66 del districto en Washington, C.C., 
transportó un sentido de las funciones sociales, políticas, e 
intelectuales diversas que el pasillo de la reunión jugó para sus 
miembros, así como las ediciones que animaron sus discusiones.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086452</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103952</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/making-common-cause-the-knights-assembly-hall</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
