<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106123</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106123</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087222</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"What Can You Get By Warre": Powhatan Exchanges Views With Captain John Smith, 1608"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Was Sie Warre Vorbei Erhalten Kann": 
Powhatan Tauscht Ansichten Mit Kapitän John Smith, 1608"Aus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Ce qui Peut Vous Passer Warre" : Powhatan 
Permute des Vues Avec Capitaine John Smith, 1608"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"O que Pode Você Começar Perto Warre": 
Powhatan Troca Vistas Com O Capitão John Smith, 1608"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Che cosa Può Voi Ottenere Vicino Warre": 
Powhatan Scambia Le Viste Con Il Capitano John Smith, 1608"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Τι μπορεί εσείς να πάρει από Warre": Το 
Powhatan ανταλλάσσει τις όψεις με τον καπετάνιο John 
Smith, 1608 "</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Qué Puede Usted Pasar A Warre": Powhatan 
Intercambia Opiniónes Por Capitán Juan Smith, El 1608"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Captain John Smith was a soldier and adventurer in Europe and Asia before he became involved in the Virginia Company's plan to establish a settlement in North America. He was aboard one of the three ships that reached Virginia in April 1607. The first settlers, ill prepared for life in the harsh environment, had few useful skills but great expectations of easy profits. They suffered from disease, malnutrition, and frequent attacks by Indians in the early years; over one half died the first winter. Smith took over Jamestown's government amid this chaos and death; he explored the region and traded for desperately needed supplies with the Indians. Smith recognized the need to establish peaceful relations with the powerful Powhatan Indians of the coastal region, and he traded English manufactured goods for much needed Indian corn. Smith recounted this exchange with the Indian leader Powhatan in his 1624  Historyie .</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kapitän John Smith war ein Soldat und ein 
Abenteurer in Europa und in Asien, bevor er im Plan der Virginia Firma
beteiligt wurde, um eine Regelung in Nordamerika herzustellen. 
Er war an Bord ein der drei Schiffe, die Virginia im April 1607 
erreichten. Die ersten Siedleren, der Kranke, der für das Leben
in der rauhen Umgebung vorbereitet wurde, hatten wenige nützliche 
Fähigkeiten aber große Erwartungen der einfachen Profite. Sie 
litten unter Krankheit, Unterernährung und frequentieren Angriffe 
durch Indians in den frühen Jahren; über einer Hälfte 
gestorben der erste Winter. Smith übernahm Regierung Jamestowns
unter diesem Chaos und Tod; er erforschte die Region und 
handelte für hoffnungslos benötigtes Zubehör mit den Indern. 
Smith erkannte die Notwendigkeit, ruhige Relationen mit den 
leistungsfähigen Powhatan Indern des Küstengebiets herzustellen, und
er handelte englische hergestellte Waren für dringend benötigten 
indischen Mais. Smith zählte diesen Austausch mit dem indischen
Führer Powhatan in seinem Historyie 1624 nach.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Capitaine John Smith était un soldat et un 
aventurier en Europe et Asie avant qu'il soit devenu impliqué dans le
plan de la compagnie de la Virginie pour établir un règlement en 
Amérique du nord. Il était à bord d'un des trois bateaux
qui ont atteint la Virginie en avril 1607. Les premiers colons, 
défectuosité disposée pour la vie dans l'environnement dur, ont eu 
peu de qualifications utiles mais grandes espérances des bénéfices 
faciles. Ils ont souffert de la maladie, malnutrition, et 
fréquentent des attaques par Indians en premières années ; 
plus d'une moitié morte le premier hiver. Smith a assuré
le gouvernement de Jamestown parmi ces chaos et mort ; il a 
exploré la région et a commercé pour les approvisionnements 
désespérément nécessaires avec les Indiens. Smith a 
identifié la nécessité d'établir des relations paisibles avec les 
Indiens puissants de Powhatan de la région côtière, et il a 
commercé les produits manufacturés anglais pour le maïs si 
nécessaire. Smith a raconté cet échange avec le Chef indien 
Powhatan dans son Historyie 1624.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O capitão John Smith foi um soldado e um 
adventurer em Europa e em Ásia antes que se tornou involvido na 
planta da companhia de Virgínia para estabelecer um estabelecimento 
em America do Norte. Era a bordo de um dos três navios que 
alcançaram Virgínia em abril 1607. Os primeiros settlers, mal 
preparado para a vida no ambiente áspero, tiveram poucas habilidades 
úteis mas expectativas grandes de lucros fáceis. Sofreram da 
doença, malnutrition, e freqüentam ataques por Indians nos anos 
adiantados; sobre uma metade morrida o primeiro inverno. 
Smith fêz exame sobre do governo de Jamestown entre estes caos 
e morte; explorou a região e negociou-a para fontes 
desesperadamente necessitadas com os indians. Smith reconheceu a
necessidade estabelecer relações calmas com os indians poderosos de 
Powhatan da região litoral, e negociou bens manufactured ingleses 
para o milho indian tão necessário. Smith recounted esta troca
com o líder indian Powhatan em seu Historyie 1624.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il capitano John Smith era un soldato e un 
adventurer Europa ed in Asia prima che fosse implicato nel programma 
dell'azienda della Virginia per stabilire uno stabilimento in America 
del Nord. Era a bordo di una delle tre navi che hanno raggiunto 
la Virginia nel mese di aprile del 1607. I primi settlers, ill 
per vita nell'ambiente duro, hanno avuti poche abilità utili ma 
aspettative grandi dei profitti facili. Hanno sofferto dalla 
malattia, malnutrizione e frequentano gli attacchi da Indians durante 
i primi anni; più di una metà morta il primo inverno. 
Smith ha assunto la direzione del governo del Jamestown in mezzo
di questi caos e morte; ha esplorato la regione ed ha 
commerciato con rifornimenti disperatamente stati necessari con 
indiani. Smith ha riconosciuto la necessità di stabilire i 
rapporti pacifici con gli indiani potenti di Powhatan della regione 
litoranea ed ha commerciato le merci manufactured inglesi con 
granturco tanto necessario. Smith ha raccontato questo scambio 
con il capo indiano Powhatan nel suo Historyie 1624.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο καπετάνιος John Smith ήταν στρατιώτης και 
τυχοδιώκτης στην Ευρώπη και την Ασία προτού να αναμιχθεί στο 
σχέδιο της επιχείρησης της Βιρτζίνια για να καθιερώσει μια 
τακτοποίηση στη Βόρεια Αμερική. Ήταν σε ένα από τα τρία 
σκάφη που έφθασαν στη Βιρτζίνια τον Απρίλιο του 1607. Οι 
πρώτοι άποικοι, άρρωστος που προετοιμάστηκε για τη ζωή στο 
σκληρό περιβάλλον, είχαν λίγες χρήσιμες δεξιότητες αλλά τις 
μεγάλες προσδοκίες των εύκολων κερδών. Έπασχαν από την 
ασθένεια, τον υποσιτισμό, και τις συχνές επιθέσεις από Ινδούς τα
πρώτα έτη  πάνω από το ένα κατά το ήμισυ πέθανε ο 
πρώτος χειμώνας. Θ*Σμητχ ανέλαβε την κυβέρνηση Jamestown 
ανάμεσα σε αυτούς τους χάος και θάνατο  εξερεύνησε την 
περιοχή και έκανε εμπόριο για τις απελπισμένα αναγκαίες 
προμήθειες με τους Ινδούς. Θ*Σμητχ αναγνώρισε την ανάγκη να 
καθιερώσει τις ειρηνικές σχέσεις με το ισχυρό Powhatan Ινδοί 
της παράκτιας περιοχής, και αντάλλαξε τα αγγλικά κατασκευασμένα 
αγαθά για πολύ αναγκαίο ινδικό καλαμπόκι. Θ*Σμητχ 
εξιστόρησε αυτήν την ανταλλαγή με τον ινδικό ηγέτη Powhatan σε
1624 του Historyie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Capitán Juan Smith era soldado y un aventurero en
Europa y Asia antes de que él llegó a estar implicado en el plan de 
la compañía de Virginia para establecer un establecimiento en 
Norteamérica. Él estaba a bordo de una de las tres naves que 
alcanzaron Virginia en abril de 1607. Los primeros colonos, 
enfermedad preparada para la vida en el ambiente áspero, tenían 
pocas habilidades útiles pero grandes expectativas de beneficios 
fáciles. Sufrieron de la enfermedad, desnutrición, y 
frecuentan ataques de indians en los años; sobre una mitad 
muerta el primer invierno. Smith asumió el control el gobierno 
de Jamestown en medio de este caos y muerte; él exploró la 
región y negoció para las fuentes desesperadamente necesitadas con 
los indios. Smith reconoció la necesidad de establecer 
relaciones pacíficas con los indios de gran alcance de Powhatan de la
región costera, y él negoció los productos manufacturados ingleses 
para el maíz indio muy necesario. Smith contó de nuevo este 
intercambio con el arranque de cinta indio Powhatan en su Historyie 
1624.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087222</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106123</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/what-can-you-get-by-warre-powhatan-exchanges-views-with-captain-john-smith-1608</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
