<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104385</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104385</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087071</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Wagner Bill is behind you!"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die Wagner Rechnung ist hinter Ihnen!"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"la facture de Wagner est derrière vous!"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"a conta de Wagner é atrás de você!"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la fattura di Wagner è dietro voi!"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Το Wagner Bill είναι πίσω από σας!"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"la cuenta de Wagner está detrás de usted!"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Wagner Bill was the most radical and far-reaching piece of legislation passed in Roosevelt's second "hundred days." Following on the heels of intense industrial unrest, large-scale strikes, and social turmoil, the act guaranteed workers the right to organize unions, and to strike, boycott and picket their employers. It also outlawed "unfair" labor practices by employers, including blacklisting union activists or intimidating workers who sought to join an independent union, and ensured workers the right to collective bargaining. This leaflet distributed by the United Automobile Workers captures the impact of the Wagner Act on union organizing, as it provided a spur for industrial unionism.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Wagner Rechnung war das radikalste und 
weitestreichende Stück von Gesetzgebung geführt an Roosevelts an 
zweiter Stelle "hundert Tagen." Folgend auf die Fersen der 
intensiven industriellen Ruhelosigkeit, der großräumigen Schläge 
und des Sozialtumultes, garantierte die Tat Arbeitern das Recht, 
Anschlüße zu organisieren und ihre Arbeitgeber anzuschlagen, zu 
boykottieren und einzupfählen. Sie ächtete auch "unfaire" 
Arbeitspraxis durch Arbeitgeber, einschließlich das Auf die schwarze 
Liste setzen der Anschlußaktivisten oder das Einschüchtern der 
Arbeiter, die suchten, eine unabhängige Gewerkschaft zu verbinden, 
und stellte Arbeitern das Recht zur Tarifverhandlung sicher. 
Dieses Blättchen, das von den vereinigten Automobil-Arbeitern 
verteilt wird, erfaßt die Auswirkung der Wagner Tat auf Anschluß 
organisierend, wie es einen Sporn für industrielles unionism zur 
Verfügung stellte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La facture de Wagner était le texte de loi le plus 
radical et le plus de grande envergure passé en jours de Roosevelt en
second lieu "cent." Suivant sur les talons du malaise industriel
intense, des grèves de grande puissance, et de l'agitation sociale, 
l'acte a garanti des ouvriers la droite d'organiser des syndicats, et 
de frapper, boycotter et palissader leurs employeurs. Il a 
également proscrit des pratiques de travail "injustes" par des 
employeurs, y compris mettre des activistes des syndicats ou intimider
sur la liste noire les ouvriers qui ont recherché à joindre un 
syndicat indépendant, et a assuré à des ouvriers la droite à la 
négociation collective. Ce feuillet distribué par les ouvriers
unis d'automobile capture l'impact de l'acte de Wagner sur 
l'union organisant, comme il a fourni une dent pour le syndicalisme 
industriel.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A conta de Wagner era a parte de legislação a mais 
radical e a mais far-reaching passada dias de Roosevelt em em segundo 
"cem." Seguindo nos saltos do unrest industrial intenso, de 
batidas em grande escala, e do turmoil social, o ato garantiu 
trabalhadores a direita organizar uniões, e golpear, boycott e picket
seus empregadores. Outlawed também práticas labor "unfair" por
empregadores, including por activistas da união ou intimidating os 
trabalhadores que procuraram juntar uma união independente, e 
assegurou a trabalhadores a direita a negociar coletivo. Este 
leaflet distribuído pelos trabalhadores unidos do automóvel captura 
o impacto do ato de Wagner na união que organizam, como forneceu um 
dente reto para o unionism industrial.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La fattura di Wagner era la parte di legislazione più 
radicale e più ampia passata in giorni del Roosevelt in secondo luogo
"cento." Seguendo sui talloni di agitazione industriale intensa,
dei colpi su grande scala e dell'agitazione sociale, l'atto ha 
garantito gli operai la destra organizzare i sindacati e colpire, 
boicottare e steccare i loro datori di lavoro. Egualmente ha 
proscritto le pratiche di lavoro "ingiuste" dai datori di lavoro, 
compreso la lista nera degli attivisti del sindacato o 
l'intimidazione degli operai che hanno cercato di unire un'unione 
indipendente ed ha accertato ad operai la destra alla contrattazione 
collettiva. Questo opuscolo distribuito dagli operai uniti 
dell'automobile blocca l'effetto della Legge di Wagner sull'unione che
organizzano, come ha fornito un dente cilindrico per il unionism 
industriale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Wagner Bill ήταν το ριζικότερο και εκτεταμένο 
κομμάτι της νομοθεσίας που πέρασαν σε δεύτερες "εκατό ημέρες 
Roosevelt." Μετά από στα τακούνια της έντονης 
βιομηχανικής ανησυχίας, των μεγάλης κλίμακας απεργιών, και της 
κοινωνικής αναταραχής, η πράξη εγγυήθηκε στους εργαζομένους το 
δικαίωμα να οργανώσει τις ενώσεις, και να χτυπήσει, να 
μποϊκοτάρει και να περιφράξει τους εργοδότες τους. Πρόγραψε
επίσης τις "αθέμιτεσ" πρακτικές εργασίας από τους εργοδότες, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένης της καταχώρησης στη μαύρη λίστα των ενεργών 
στελεχών ένωσης ή του εκφοβισμού των εργαζομένων που επιδίωξαν 
να ενώσουν μια ανεξάρτητη ένωση, και εξασφάλισε εργαζομένους το 
δικαίωμα στις συλλογικές διαπραγματεύσεις. Αυτό το φυλλάδιο
που διανέμεται από τους ενωμένους αυτοκινητικούς εργαζομένους 
συλλαμβάνει τον αντίκτυπο του νόμου Wagner στην οργάνωση 
ένωσης, δεδομένου ότι παρείχε ένα κέντρισμα για το βιομηχανικό 
συνδικαλισμό.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La cuenta de Wagner era el pedazo más radical y más de 
gran envergadura de legislación aprobado en días de Roosevelt en 
segundo lugar "cientos." Siguiendo en los talones del malestar 
industrial intenso, de huelgas en grande, y de la agitación social, 
el acto garantizó a trabajadores la derecha de ordenar uniones, y de 
pulso, de boicotear y de cercar con piquete a sus patrones. 
También proscribió prácticas de trabajo "injustas" de los 
patrones, incluyendo poner a activistas de la unión o la 
intimidación de los trabajadores que intentaron ensamblar una unión 
independiente, y aseguró a trabajadores la derecha a estipular 
colectivo. Este prospecto distribuido por los trabajadores 
unidos del automóvil captura el impacto del acto de Wagner en la 
unión que ordenan, como proporcionó a un estímulo para el unionism 
industrial.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087071</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104385</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-wagner-bill-is-behind-you</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
