<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108221</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108221</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087001</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Negro and the War": Reports in African-American Newspapers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"der Schwarze und der Krieg": Reports in den
Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Zeitungen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"le nègre et la guerre" : États en 
journaux afro-américains</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"o negro e a guerra": Relatórios em jornais
Africano-Americanos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"il negro e la guerra": Rapporti in giornali
Africano-Americani</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ο νέγρος και ο πόλεμοσ": Εκθέσεις στις 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικές εφημερίδες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"el negro y la guerra": Informes en 
periódicos Africano-Americanos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">World War I wartime production demanded the mobilization of thousands of workers to make steel and rubber, work in petrochemical industries, and build ships. Few immigrants left Europe for the United States, and workers were desperately needed to replace those who had left for military service. The following excerpts from African-American newspapers described the new opportunities and continuing struggles that black workers confronted, noting both interracial conflict and cooperation during wartime. "Organized Labor Not Friendly?" exemplified a widely held suspicion of unions among African Americans, who had previously been excluded from organized labor's ranks. "Negro Workers Are Organizing" described one response: the formation of alternative unions organized for black workers on a city-wide basis. "Big Labor Day Celebration" reported on a parade and baseball game that included black and white unionists. In "The Negro and the War," the writer found reason for optimism that President Woodrow Wilson's war aims--"to make the world safe for democracy"--might also find expression in the realization of democratic ideals at home.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kriegproduktion des Weltkrieges I verlangte die 
Mobilisierung von Tausenden Arbeitern, um Stahl und Gummi zu bilden, 
in den petrochemischen Industrien zu arbeiten, und Schiffe aufzubauen.
Wenige Immigranten, die Europa für die Vereinigten Staaten 
verlassen wurden, und Arbeiter wurden hoffnungslos benötigt, um die 
zu ersetzen, die für militärischen Service verlassen hatten. 
Die folgenden Excerpts von den Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen 
Zeitungen beschrieben die neuen Gelegenheiten und die fortfahrenden 
Kämpfe, die schwarze Arbeiter konfrontierten und beachteten 
interracial $überschneidung und Mitarbeit während des Krieges. 
"Organisierte Arbeit Nicht Freundlich?" illustrierte ein 
weit angehaltenes Misstrauen der Anschlüße unter afrikanischen 
Amerikanern, die vorher von den Rank der organisierten Arbeit 
ausgeschlossen worden waren. "Schwarze, den Arbeiter" 
organisieren, beschrieb eine Antwort: die Anordnung der 
alternativen Anschlüße organisiert für schwarze Arbeiter auf einer 
in der ganzen Stadt Grundlage. "grosse Arbeitstagesfeier" 
berichtete über ein Parade- und Baseballspiel daß enthaltene 
schwarze und weiße Unionisten. "im Schwarzen und im Krieg" fand
der Verfasser Grund für Optimismus, daß Präsident Woodrow Wilson 
Kriegziele -- "das Weltsafe für Demokratie bilden" -- Ausdruck in der
Realisierung der demokratischen Ideale auch zu Hause finden konnten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La production de temps de guerre de Première 
Guerre Mondiale a exigé la mobilisation des milliers d'ouvriers pour 
faire l'acier et le caoutchouc, pour travailler dans des industries 
pétrochimiques, et pour construire des bateaux. Peu d'immigrés
quittés l'Europe pour les Etats-Unis, et ouvriers étaient 
nécessaires désespérément pour substituer ceux qui étaient partis
pour le service militaire. Les extraits suivants des journaux 
afro-américains ont décrit les nouvelles occasions et les luttes 
continues que les ouvriers noirs ont confrontées, notant le conflit 
interracial et la coopération pendant le temps de guerre. 
"Travail Organisé Non amical?" a exemplifié un soupçon 
largement tenu des syndicats parmi les Américains africains, qui 
avaient été précédemment exclus des grades du travail organisé. 
le "nègre que les ouvriers organisent" a décrit une réponse :
la formation des syndicats alternatifs organisés pour les 
ouvriers noirs sur une base partout dans la ville. la "grande 
célébration de jour de travail" a rendu compte d'un jeu de défilé 
et de base-ball que les syndicalistes noirs et blancs inclus. 
Dans "le nègre et la guerre," l'auteur a trouvé la raison de 
l'optimisme que les objectifs de guerre du Président Woodrow Wilson 
-- "pour faire le coffre-fort du monde pour la démocratie" -- 
pourraient également trouver l'expression dans la réalisation des 
idéaux démocratiques à la maison.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A produção do wartime do world.war.i exijiu o 
mobilization dos milhares dos trabalhadores fazer o aço e a borracha,
trabalhar em indústrias petrochemical, e construir navios. 
Poucos immigrants saidos Europa para os estados unidos, e os 
trabalhadores foram necessitados desesperadamente substituir aqueles 
que tinham saido para o serviço militar. Os seguintes excerpts 
dos jornais Africano-Americanos descreveram as oportunidades novas e 
os esforços continuando que os trabalhadores pretos confrontaram, 
anotando  o conflito interracial e a cooperação durante o wartime. 
"Trabalho Organizado Nao amigável?" exemplified uma 
suspeita extensamente prendida das uniões entre os americanos 
africanos, que tinham sido excluídos previamente dos Rank do trabalho
organizado. o "negro que os trabalhadores estão organizando" 
descreveu uma resposta: a formação das uniões alternativas 
organizadas para trabalhadores pretos em uma base city-wide. "o 
celebration grande do dia labor" relatou em um jogo da parada e do 
baseball que unionists pretos e brancos incluídos. "no negro e 
na guerra," o escritor encontrou a razão para o optimism que os alvos
da guerra do presidente Woodrow Wilson -- "para fazer o cofre do mundo
para a democracia" -- puderam também encontrar a expressão no 
realization de ideals democráticos na HOME.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La produzione di wartime di world.war.i ha 
richiesto la mobilizzazione dei migliaia degli operai per fare 
l'acciaio e la gomma, per funzionare nelle industrie petrochimiche e 
per costruire le navi. Pochi immigranti Europa di sinistra per 
unito Dichiara e gli operai sono stato necessari disperatamente
per sostituire coloro che aveva andato per servizio militare. I 
seguenti brani dai giornali Africano-Americani hanno descritto le 
nuove occasioni e le lotte continue che gli operai neri hanno 
confrontato, notando sia il conflitto interracial che la cooperazione 
durante il wartime. "Lavoro Organizzato Non amichevole?" 
ha esemplificato un sospetto ampiamente tenuto dei sindacati fra
gli Americani africani, che precedentemente erano stati esclusi dalla 
truppa di lavoro organizzata. "il negro che gli operai 
stanno organizzando" ha descritto una risposta: la formazione 
dei sindacati alternativi organizzati per gli operai neri su una base 
city-wide. "la celebrazione Di lavoro grande di giorno" ha 
segnalato su un gioco di baseball e di parata che unionisti neri e 
bianchi inclusi. "nel negro e nella guerra," il produttore ha 
trovato il motivo per ottimismo che gli obiettivi di guerra del 
presidente Woodrow Wilson -- "fare la cassaforte del mondo per la 
democrazia" -- potrebbero anche trovare l'espressione nella 
realizzazione degli ideali democratici nel paese.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο παγκόσμιος πόλεμος Ι εν καιρώ πολέμου παραγωγή 
απαίτησε την κινητοποίηση χιλιάδων εργαζόμενοι για να κάνει το 
χάλυβα και το λάστιχο, να εργαστεί στις πετροχημικές βιομηχανίες,
και να ναυπηγήσει τα σκάφη. Λίγοι μετανάστες αποχώρησαν 
από την Ευρώπη για τις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες, και οι εργαζόμενοι 
απαιτήθηκαν απελπισμένα για να αντικαταστήσουν εκείνων που φεύγω 
για τη στρατιωτική θητεία. Τα ακόλουθα αποσπάσματα από τις 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικές εφημερίδες περιέγραψαν τις νέες 
ευκαιρίες και τις συνεχιμένος προσπάθειες που οι μαύροι 
εργαζόμενοι αντιμετώπισαν, σημειώνοντας και τη διαφυλετική 
σύγκρουση και τη συνεργασία κατά τη διάρκεια της εμπόλεμης 
περιόδου. "Οργανωμένη εργασία μη φιλική;" εξήγησε μια
ευρέως κρατημένη υποψία των ενώσεων μεταξύ αφρικανικών 
Αμερικανών, οι οποίοι είχαν αποκλειστεί προηγουμένως από τις 
οργανωμένες τάξεις της εργασίας. Οι "εργαζόμενοι νέγρων που
οργανώνουν" περιγράφουν μια απάντηση: ο σχηματισμός των 
εναλλακτικών ενώσεων που οργανώνεται για τους μαύρους 
εργαζομένους σε αστικού επιπέδού βάση. "Μεγάλος εορτασμός
ημέρας εργασίασ" που αναφέρεται σε μια παρέλαση και ένα παιχνίδι
μπέιζ-μπώλ που περιέλαβαν τους μαύρους και λευκούς ενωτικούς. 
"Στο νέγρο και τον πόλεμο," ο συγγραφέας βρήκε το λόγο για 
την αισιοδοξία ότι οι πολεμικοί στόχοι Προέδρου Woodrow 
Wilson's -- "για να κάνει το παγκόσμιο χρηματοκιβώτιο για τη 
δημοκρατία" -- επίσης να βρούν την έκφραση στην πραγματοποίηση 
των δημοκρατικών ιδανικών στο σπίτι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La producción del tiempo de guerra de la Primera 
Guerra Mundial exigió la movilización de millares de trabajadores 
para hacer el acero y el caucho, para trabajar en industrias 
petroquímicas, y para construir las naves. Necesitaron a pocos 
inmigrantes salidos Europa para los Estados Unidos, y a los 
trabajadores desesperadamente para substituir a los que se habían ido
para el servicio militar. Los extractos siguientes de los 
periódicos Africano-Americanos describieron las nuevas oportunidades 
y las luchas de continuación que los trabajadores negros enfrentaron,
observando conflicto interracial y la cooperación durante tiempo de 
guerra. "Trabajo Ordenado No cómodo?" ejemplificó una 
suspicacia extensamente llevada a cabo de uniones entre los americanos
africanos, que habían sido excluidos previamente de las filas del 
trabajo ordenado. el "negro que los trabajadores están 
ordenando" describió una respuesta: la formación de las 
uniones alternativas ordenadas para los trabajadores negros sobre una 
base city-wide. la "celebración grande del día de trabajo" 
señaló sobre un juego del desfile y del béisbol que los unionistas 
negros y blancos incluidos. En "el negro y la guerra," el 
programa de escritura encontró la razón del optimismo que las 
punterías de la guerra de presidente Woodrow Wilson -- "hacer la caja
fuerte del mundo para la democracia" -- pudieron también encontrar la
expresión en la realización de ideales democráticos en el país.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087001</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108221</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-negro-and-the-war-reports-in-african-american-newspapers</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
