<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108038</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108038</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086182</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">From dawn to dusk.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Von Dämmerung zu Dämmerung.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">De l'aube au crépuscule.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Do alvorecer ao dusk.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dall'alba a dusk.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Από την αυγή dusk.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">De amanecer a la oscuridad.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An unknown photographer captured this scene of men, women, and children picking cotton under the watchful eye of an overseer. Slaves on cotton plantations worked under harsh conditions. The working day began at dawn and often lasted well into the night. Work was done in gangs, where discipline and the unrelenting pace of work was enforced by a driver or overseer. Whipping was regularly used to enforce picking quotas or increase the pace of work. In what little time they had besides what they spent working for the master, slaves had to do all the chores of daily life: they prepared their own meals, washed and fed their children, cleaned their cabins, washed and mended their clothes, and, if they were especially fortunate, tended their own vegetable gardens.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein unbekannter Photograph erfaßte diese Szene der 
Männer, der Frauen und der Kinder, die Baumwolle unter dem watchful 
Auge eines Aufsehers auswählen. Sklaven auf Baumwolplantagen 
arbeiteten unter rauhen Bedingungen. Der Arbeitstag fing an der 
Dämmerung an und dauerte häufig gut in die Nacht. Arbeit wurde
in den Gruppen erledigt, in denen Disziplin und der unnachgiebige 
Schritt der Arbeit von einem Treiber oder von einem Aufseher erzwungen
wurden. Das Peitschen wurde regelmäßig verwendet, um 
Sammelnquoten zu erzwingen oder den Schritt der Arbeit zu erhöhen. 
In welcher wenig Zeit sie hatten außer, was sie das Arbeiten 
für den Meister aufwendeten, mußten Sklaven alle Chores der 
täglichen Lebensdauer tun: sie bereiteten ihre eigenen 
Mahlzeiten vor, wuschen und zogen ihre Kinder ein, gesäubert ihren 
Kabinen, gewaschen und repariert ihrer Kleidung und, wenn sie 
besonders glücklich waren, neigte ihre eigenen Gemüsegärten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un photographe inconnu a capturé cette scène des hommes,
des femmes, et des enfants sélectionnant le coton sous l'oeil 
attentif d'un contrôleur. Les esclaves sur des plantations 
de coton ont fonctionné dans des conditions dures. Le jour 
ouvrable a commencé à l'aube et souvent a bien duré dans la nuit. 
Le travail a été effectué dans les troupes, où la discipline
et le pas persistant du travail ont été imposés par un gestionnaire
ou un contrôleur. La fouettée a été régulièrement 
employée pour imposer des quotes-parts de cueillette ou pour 
augmenter le pas du travail. Dans quelle peu d'heure ils ont eue
sans compter que ce qu'ils ont dépensé travailler pour le maître, 
les esclaves ont dû faire tout les corvées de la vie quotidienne : 
ils ont préparé leurs propres repas, ont lavé et ont 
alimenté leurs enfants, nettoyés leurs carlingues, lavées et 
réparé leurs vêtements, et, s'ils étaient particulièrement 
chanceux, a tendu leurs propres potagers.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um fotógrafo desconhecido capturou esta cena dos homens, 
das mulheres, e das crianças que escolhem o algodão sob o olho 
watchful de um overseer. Os escravos em plantações do algodão
trabalharam sob circunstâncias ásperas. O dia de trabalho 
começou no alvorecer e durou frequentemente bem na noite. O 
trabalho foi feito nos grupos, onde a disciplina e o ritmo unrelenting
do trabalho foram reforçados por um excitador ou por um overseer. 
Chicotear foi usado regularmente reforçar quotas da colheita ou
aumentar o ritmo do trabalho. No que pouca hora tiveram além de
o que gastaram trabalhar para o mestre, os escravos tiveram que fazer 
todos os chores da vida diária: prepararam suas próprias 
refeições, lavaram e alimentaram suas crianças, limpadas suas 
cabines, lavadas e emendado sua roupa, e, se fossem especial 
afortunadas, tendeu seus próprios jardins vegetais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un photographer sconosciuto ha bloccato questa scena degli
uomini, delle donne e dei bambini che selezionano il cotone sotto 
l'occhio watchful di un overseer. Gli schiavi sulle piantagioni 
del cotone hanno funzionato nelle circostanze dure. La gioranata
lavorativa ha cominciato all'alba e spesso ha durato facilmente per la
notte. Il lavoro è stato fatto in gruppi, in cui la disciplina 
ed il passo inesorabile di lavoro sono stati fatti rispettare da un 
driver o da un overseer. Sbattere è stato usato regolarmente 
per fare rispettare le quote di raccolto o per aumentare il passo di 
lavoro. In che poco tempo hanno avuti oltre a che cosa hanno 
speso il funzionamento per il supervisore, gli schiavi 
hanno dovuto fare tutti i chores di vita quotidiana: hanno 
preparato i loro propri pasti, hanno lavato ed alimentato i loro 
bambini, puliti le loro baracche, lavate e riparato i loro vestiti e, 
se fossero particolarmente fortunati, ha teso i loro propri orti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένας άγνωστος φωτογράφος συνέλαβε αυτήν την σκηνή 
των ανδρών, των γυναικών, και των παιδιών που επιλέγουν το 
βαμβάκι κάτω από το προσεκτικό μάτι ενός overseer. Οι 
σκλάβοι στις φυτείες βαμβακιού εργάστηκαν υπό τους σκληρούς 
όρους. Η εργάσιμη ημέρα άρχισε στην αυγή και διάρκεσε 
συχνά καλά στη νύχτα. Η εργασία έγινε στις συμμορίες, 
όπου η πειθαρχία και ο άκαμπτος ρυθμός της εργασίας επιβλήθηκαν 
από έναν οδηγό ή overseer. Το κτύπημα χρησιμοποιήθηκε 
τακτικά για να επιβάλει τις ποσοστώσεις επιλογής ή να αυξήσει το
ρυθμό της εργασίας. Σε αυτό που λίγος χρόνος είχαν εκτός 
από αυτό που που ξόδεψαν την εργασία για τον κύριο, οι σκλάβοι 
έπρεπε να κάνουν όλες τις μικροδουλειές της καθημερινής ζωής: 
προετοίμασαν τα γεύματά τους, έπλυναν και τααΐαν τα 
παιδιά τους, καθάρισαν τις καμπίνες τους, που πλύθηκαν και 
επιδιορθωμένος τα ενδύματά τους, και, εάν ήταν ιδιαίτερα 
τυχεροί, έτεινε τους φυτικούς κήπους τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un fotógrafo desconocido capturó esta escena de hombres,
de mujeres, y de niños que escogían algodón bajo el ojo watchful de
un overseer. Los esclavos en plantaciones del algodón 
trabajaron bajo condiciones ásperas. El día laborable comenzó
en el amanecer y duró a menudo bien en la noche. El trabajo fue
hecho en las cuadrillas, donde la disciplina y el paso implacable del 
trabajo fueron hechos cumplir por un programa piloto o un overseer. 
El azotar fue utilizado regularmente para hacer cumplir 
contingentes de la cosecha o para aumentar el paso del trabajo. 
En qué poca hora tenían además de lo que pasaron el trabajo 
para el amo, los esclavos tuvieron que hacer todas las tareas de la 
vida de cada día: prepararon sus propias comidas, lavaron y 
alimentaron a sus niños, limpiados sus cabinas, lavadas y reparado 
sus ropas, y, si eran especialmente afortunados, tendió a sus propios
jardines vegetales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086182</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108038</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/from-dawn-to-dusk</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
