<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105822</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105822</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205871</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Learning Page</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Erlernenseite</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Page D'Étude</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A Página De Aprendizagem</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Pagina Imparante</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η σελίδα εκμάθησης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Paginación Que aprende</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">helps teachers use the Library of Congress's American Memory website to teach U.S. history and culture. It includes suggestions for using photos, objects, life histories and other primary sources; tools for analyzing primary sources; and a lesson framework for incorporating primary sources into all phases of instruction. It features 40 teacher-developed lessons on 17 topics, including the Revolutionary Era, Civil War, Emergence of Modern America and Great Depression.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hilfen Lehrer benutzen die Bibliothek der 
amerikanischen Speicherweb site des Kongresses, um VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Geschichte und Kultur zu unterrichten. Sie schließt Vorschläge
für das Verwenden der Fotos, der Nachrichten, der Lebengeschichten 
und anderer Primärquellen ein; Hilfsmittel für das Analysieren
von von Primärquellen; und ein Lektionrahmen für das Enthalten
von von Primärquellen in alle Phasen der Anweisung. Sie 
kennzeichnet 40 Lehrer-entwickelte Lektionen auf 17 Themen, 
einschließlich die revolutionäre Ära, Bürgerkrieg, Hervortreten 
von modernem Amerika und großem Tiefstand.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les professeurs d'aides emploient la bibliothèque
du site Web américain de la mémoire du congrès pour enseigner 
l'histoire et la culture des ETATS-UNIS. Il inclut des 
suggestions pour l'usage des photos, des objets, des histoires de la 
vie et d'autres sources primaires ; outils pour analyser des 
sources primaires ; et un cadre de leçon pour incorporer des 
sources primaires dans toutes les phases de l'instruction. Elle 
comporte 40 leçons professeur-développées sur 17 sujets, y compris 
l'ère révolutionnaire, guerre civile, apparition de l'Amérique 
moderne et grande dépression.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">os professores das ajudas usam a biblioteca do Web
site americano da memória do congress ensinar o history e a cultura 
de ESTADOS UNIDOS. Inclui sugestões para usar fotos, objetos, 
histories da vida e outras fontes preliminares; ferramentas para
analisar fontes preliminares; e uma estrutura da lição para 
incorporar fontes preliminares em todas as fases da instrução. 
Caracteriza 40 lições professor-em desenvolvimento em 17 
tópicos, including a era revolucionária, na guerra civil, no 
emergence de América moderna e no depression grande.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">gli insegnanti di aiuti usano la libreria del Web 
site americano di memoria del congresso per insegnare la storia e la 
coltura degli STATI UNITI. Include i suggerimenti per usando le 
foto, gli oggetti, i dati storici di vita ed altre sorgenti primarie; 
strumenti per analizzare le sorgenti primarie; e una 
struttura di lezione per comprendere le sorgenti primarie in tutte le 
fasi di istruzione. Caratterizza 40 lezioni 
insegnante-sviluppate su 17 soggetti, compreso l'era rivoluzionaria, 
sulla guerra civile, sull'emersione dell'America moderna e sulla 
depressione grande.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">βοηθά τη χρήση δασκάλων ο αμερικανικός ιστοχώρος 
μνήμης βιβλιοθήκης του συνεδρίου για να διδάξει την ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΥΣ 
ιστορία και τον πολιτισμό. Περιλαμβάνει τις προτάσεις για 
τις φωτογραφίες, τα αντικείμενα, τις ιστορίες ζωής και άλλες 
αρχικές πηγές  εργαλεία για τις αρχικές πηγές  και 
ένα πλαίσιο μαθήματος για τις αρχικές πηγές σε όλες τις φάσεις 
οδηγίας. Χαρακτηρίζει 40 δάσκαλος-αναπτυγμένα μαθήματα 
σε 17 θέματα, συμπεριλαμβανομένης της επαναστατικής εποχής, τον
εμφύλιο πόλεμο, την εμφάνιση της σύγχρονης Αμερικής και τη 
μεγάλη οικονομική κρίση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">los profesores de las ayudas utilizan la 
biblioteca del Web site americano de la memoria del congreso para 
enseñar la historia y la cultura de ESTADOS UNIDOS. Incluye las
sugerencias para usar las fotos, los objetos, las historias de la vida
y otras fuentes primarias; herramientas para analizar fuentes 
primarias; y un marco de la lección para incorporar fuentes 
primarias en todas las fases de la instrucción. Ofrece 40 
lecciones profesor-en desarrollo en 17 asuntos, incluyendo la era 
revolucionaria, guerra civil, la aparición de América moderna y la 
gran depresión.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205871</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105822</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-learning-page</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
