<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/424383955</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>424383955</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211979</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Rock Cycle Animations</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Felsen-Schleife-Animationen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Animations de Cycle de Roche</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Animations Do Ciclo Da Rocha</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Animazioni Del Ciclo Della Roccia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ζωτικότητες κύκλων βράχου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Animaciones Del Ciclo De la Roca</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site features Flash animations that illustrate various facets of the rock cycle. The visualizations depict rock-forming processes, such as erosion, transportation, deposition, cementation, crystallization, subduction, and eruption, that create sedimentary, igneous, and metamorphic rocks. They also show cooling environments that result in varied crystal sizes and demonstrate igneous rock classification. The animations can be paused and rewound to stress important points. These resources are suitable for use in lectures, labs, or other teaching activities.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Situationsmerkmale blinken Animationen, die
verschiedene Facetten der Felsenschleife veranschaulichen. Die 
Sichtbarmachungen stellen rock-forming Prozesse, wie Abnutzung, 
Transport, Absetzung, Zementierung, Kristallisation, Subduction und 
Eruption bildlich dar, die die sedimentären, Eruptiv- und metamorphen
Felsen herstellen. Sie auch zeigen abkühlende Umgebungen daß 
Resultat in mannigfaltigen Kristallgrößen und zeigen 
Eruptivgesteinklassifikation. Die Animationen können pausiert 
werden und gerückspult werden, um wichtige Punkte zu betonen. 
Diese Betriebsmittel sind für Gebrauch in den Vorträgen, in 
den Labors oder in anderen unterrichtenden Aktivitäten verwendbar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les dispositifs de ce site flashent les animations
qui illustrent de diverses facettes du cycle de roche. Les 
visualisations dépeignent les processus constituants de roches, tels 
que l'érosion, le transport, le dépôt, la cémentation, la 
cristallisation, la subduction, et l'éruption, qui créent les roches
sédimentaires, ignées, et métamorphiques. Elles également 
montrent les environnements de refroidissement que résultat dans des 
tailles en cristal diverses et démontrent la classification de roche 
plutonique. Les animations peuvent être faites une pause et 
rebobinées pour soumettre à une contrainte les points importants. 
Ces ressources conviennent pour l'usage dans les conférences, 
les laboratoires, ou d'autres activités d'enseignement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As características deste local piscam os 
animations que ilustram vários facets do ciclo da rocha. Os 
visualizations descrevem os processos rock-forming, tais como a 
erosão, o transporte, o deposition, o cementation, a cristalização,
o subduction, e o eruption, que críam rochas sedimentary, igneous, e 
metamorphic. Também mostram ambientes refrigerando que 
resultado em tamanhos de cristal variados e demonstram a 
classificação da rocha igneous. Os animations podem ser 
pausados e rebobinado para forçar pontos importantes. Estes 
recursos são apropriados para o uso nos lectures, nos laboratórios, 
ou em outras atividades ensinando.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Caratteristiche di questo luogo espongono a flash 
animazioni che illustrano le varie sfaccettature del ciclo della 
roccia. Le visualizzazioni descrivono i processi rock-forming, 
quali erosione, trasporto, il deposito, la cementazione, la 
cristallizzazione, il subduction ed il eruption, che creano le roccie 
sedimentarie, ignee e metamorfiche. Egualmente mostrano gli 
ambienti di raffreddamento che risultato nei formati di cristallo vari
e dimostrano la classificazione della roccia eruttiva. Le 
animazioni possono essere fatte una pausa e riavvolte per sollecitare 
i punti importanti. Queste risorse sono adatte ad uso nelle 
conferenze, in laboratori, o in altre attività d'istruzione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει τις ζωτικότητες λάμψης 
που επεξηγούν τις διάφορες απόψεις του κύκλου βράχου. Οι 
απεικονίσεις απεικονίζουν τις rock-forming διαδικασίες, όπως η 
διάβρωση, η μεταφορά, η απόθεση, το τσιμεντάρισμα, η κρυστάλλωση,
subduction, και η έκρηξη, οι οποίες δημιουργούν τους 
ιζηματώδεις, πύρινους, και μεταμορφικούς βράχους. 
Εμφανίζουν επίσης δροσίζοντας περιβάλλοντα που οδηγούν στα 
ποικίλα μεγέθη κρυστάλλου και καταδεικνύουν την ταξινόμηση 
πύρινου βράχου. Οι ζωτικότητες μπορούν να σταματηθούν και 
rewound για να τονίζουν τα σημαντικά σημεία. Αυτά τα 
στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς είναι κατάλληλα για τη χρήση στις 
διαλέξεις, τα εργαστήρια, ή άλλες δραστηριότητες διδασκαλίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las características de este sitio contellean las 
animaciones que ilustran las varias facetas del ciclo de la roca. 
Las visualizaciones representan los procesos constituyentes de 
rocas, tales como erosión, transporte, deposición, cementación, 
cristalización, subduction, y erupción, que crean rocas 
sedimentarias, ígneas, y metamórficas. También muestran 
ambientes que se refrescan que resultado en tallas cristalinas 
variadas y demuestran la clasificación de la roca ígnea. Las 
animaciones se pueden detener brevemente y rebobinar para tensionar 
puntas importantes. Estos recursos son convenientes para el uso 
en conferencias, laboratorios, u otras actividades de enseñanza.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211979</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>424383955</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/rock-cycle-animations</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
