<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105338</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105338</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086105</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Dumping Ground at the Foot of Beach Street."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Abladeplatz am Fuß der Strand-Straße."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"la terre vidante au pied de la rue de plage."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"terra despejando no pé da rua da praia."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"terra di fuoruscita al piede della via della 
spiaggia."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ντάμπινγκ έδαφος στο πόδι της οδού παραλιών."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"tierra que vacia en el pie de la calle de la 
playa."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Mid-nineteenth century immigrants inhabited a social world far removed from that of native born, middle class Americans, one often marked by economic hardship. With no government relief and only limited private efforts, poor New Yorkers often searched everywhere for means to survive. This engraving showed people scavenging on garbage barges, searching for coal, rags, and other discarded items that might be used or sold to junk dealers. The picture, according to a  Harper's Weekly  editor, showed how some people in New York were forced to live upon the refuse of respectable folk.""</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mittler-19.jahrhundertimmigranten bewohnten eine 
Sozialwelt, die weit von der des Eingeborenen gelöscht wurde, der, 
mittlere Kategorie Amerikaner, einer geboren war, der häufig durch 
ökonomische Härte gekennzeichnet wurde. Ohne Regierung 
Entlastung und nur begrenzte private Bemühungen suchte schlechtes 
neues Yorkers häufig überall nach Mitteln zu überleben. 
Dieser Stich zeigte Leuteausstossen von Unreinheiten auf den 
Abfalllastkähnen und suchte nach Kohle, Lappen und anderen 
verworfenen Einzelteilen, die an Trödler benutzt werden oder verkauft
werden konnten. Die Abbildung, entsprechend eines Harpers dem 
wöchentlichen Herausgeber, zeigte, wie einige Leute in New York 
erzwungen wurden, nach dem Abfall der beachtlichen Völker zu leben.""</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les Mi-dix-neuvième immigrés de siècle ont habité un 
monde social loin retiré de celui de l'indigène né, les Américains
de la bourgeoisie, un souvent marqué par des difficultés 
économiques. Sans le soulagement de gouvernement et seulement 
les efforts privés limités, nouveau Yorkers pauvre souvent a 
recherché partout des moyens de survivre. Cette gravure a 
montré le balayage de personnes sur des chalands d'ordures, 
recherchant le charbon, des chiffons, et d'autres éléments jetés 
qui pourraient être utilisés ou vendus aux brocanteurs. 
L'image, selon l'éditeur hebdomadaire d'un Harper, a montré 
comment certains à New York ont été forcées de vivre sur les 
ordures des gens respectables.""</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">os Mid-décimos nonos immigrants do século habitaram um 
mundo social removido distante daquele do nativo carregado, americanos
da classe média, um marcado frequentemente pelo hardship econômico. 
Com nenhuns relevo do governo e somente esforços confidenciais 
limitados, Yorkers novo deficiente procurarou frequentemente em toda 
parte por meios sobreviver. Este engraving mostrou o scavenging 
dos povos nas barcas do lixo, procurarando pelo carvão, pelos panos, 
e por outros artigos rejeitados que puderam ser usados ou vendido aos 
negociantes de sucata. O retrato, de acordo com o editor semanal
de um Harper, mostrou como alguns povos em New York foram forçados a 
viver em cima da recusa de povos respeitáveis.""</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">i Metà di-diciannovesimi immigranti di secolo hanno 
abitato un mondo sociale lontano rimosso da quello del nativo 
sopportato, gli Americani del codice categoria centrale, uno 
contrassegnato spesso dalle difficoltà economiche. Senza 
rilievo di governo e soltanto sforzi riservati limitati, povero 
nuovo Yorkers ha cercato spesso dappertutto i mezzi per sopravvivere. 
Questa incisione ha mostrato il lavaggio della gente sulle 
chiatte dell'immondizia, cercanti il carbone, i panni ed altri 
articoli scartati che potrebbero essere usati o venduti ai 
commercianti di roba di rifiuto. L'immagine, secondo l'editore 
settimanale del Harper, ha mostrato come qualche gente a New York è 
stata costretta a vivere sui rifiuti della gente respectable.""</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι μετανάστες του μέσος-δέκατου έννατου αιώνα 
κατοίκησαν σε έναν κοινωνικό κόσμο μακριά που αφαιρέθηκε από 
αυτόν της εγγενούς γεννημένης, μέσης κλάσης Αμερικανοί, ένας 
που χαρακτηρίστηκε συχνά από την οικονομική δυσκολία. 
Χωρίς την κυβερνητική ανακούφιση και μόνο τις περιορισμένες
ιδιωτικές προσπάθειες, φτωχοί Νεοϋρκέζοι έψαξαν συχνά παντού 
για τα μέσα να επιζήσουν. Αυτή η χάραξη εμφάνισε ανθρώπους
που σαρώνουν στις φορτηγίδες απορριμάτων, που ψάχνουν για τον 
άνθρακα, τα κουρέλια, και άλλα απορριμμένα αντικείμενα που να 
χρησιμοποιηθούν ή να πωληθούν στους εμπόρους παλιοπραγμάτων. 
Η εικόνα, σύμφωνα με τον εβδομαδιαίο επεξεργαστή ενός 
Harper, επέδειξε πώς μερικοί άνθρωποι στη Νέα Υόρκη 
αναγκάστηκαν να ζήσουν επάνω στα απορρίματα του αξιοσέβαστου 
λαού.""</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">los Mediados de-diecinueveavo inmigrantes del siglo 
habitaron un mundo social quitado lejos de el del natural nacido, 
americanos de la clase media, uno marcado a menudo por dificultad 
económica. Sin la relevación del gobierno y solamente 
esfuerzos privados limitados, Yorkers nuevo pobre buscó a menudo por 
todas partes para medios de sobrevivir. Este grabado mostró el 
barrido de la gente en las lanchas a remolque de la basura, buscando 
para el carbón, los trapos, y otros items desechados que se pudieron 
utilizar o vender a los distribuidores de chatarra. El cuadro, 
según el editor semanal de un Harper, mostró cómo alguna forzaron 
gente en Nueva York vivir sobre la basura de la gente respetable.""</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086105</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105338</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/dumping-ground-at-the-foot-of-beach-street</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
