<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107621</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107621</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211385</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Observe how fossils can form</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Beobachten Sie, wie Fossilien sich bilden können</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Observez comment les fossiles peuvent former</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Observe como os fossils podem dar forma</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Osservi come i fossili possono formare</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παρατηρήστε πώς τα απολιθώματα μπορούν να 
διαμορφώσουν</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Observe cómo los fósiles pueden formar</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This website hosts an animation depicting how cast and mold fossils are preserved in the rock record. Users can play, rewind, fast forward and stop the animation at any point in the formation as well as read captions outlining the process. The animation is part of the Earth Exploration Visualization collection.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Web site bewirtet eine Animation, die 
bildlich darstellt, wie Form- und Formfossilien im Felsensatz 
konserviert werden. Die Benutzer können spielen, rückspulen, 
schnelles Vorwärts und die Animation an irgendeinem Punkt in der 
Anordnung sowie gelesene Untertitelen stoppen den Prozeß umreißend. 
Die Animation ist ein Teil der Masse 
Erforschung-Sichtbarmachungansammlung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site Web accueille une animation dépeignant 
comment des fossiles de fonte et de moule sont préservés dans 
l'enregistrement de roche. Les utilisateurs peuvent jouer, se 
rebobiner, vers l'avant rapide et arrêter l'animation à un point 
quelconque dans la formation aussi bien que des légendes lues 
traçant les grandes lignes du processus. L'animation fait 
partie de la collection de visualisation d'exploration de la terre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Web site hospeda um animation que descreve 
como os fossils do molde e do molde são preservados no registro da 
rocha. Os usuários podem jogar, rebobinar, para diante rápido 
e parar o animation em algum ponto na formação as.well.as 
subtítulos lidos esboçando o processo. O animation é parte da
coleção do visualization da exploração da terra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Web site ospita una animazione che descrive
come i fossili della muffa e del getto sono conservati nel record 
della roccia. Gli utenti possono giocare, riavvolgere, di andata
veloce ed arrestare la animazione ad un punto qualunque nella 
formazione così come i titoli colti descriventi il processo. La
animazione fa parte dell'accumulazione di visualizzazione di 
esplorazione della terra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ξένιοι χ/υ αυτού του ιστοχώρου μια ζωτικότητα που 
απεικονίζει πώς τα χυτά και απολιθώματα φορμών συντηρούνται στο 
αρχείο βράχου. Οι χρήστες μπορούν να παίξουν, να 
ξανατυλίξουν, να διαβιβάσουν γρήγορα και να σταματήσουν τη 
ζωτικότητα σε οποιοδήποτε σημείο στο σχηματισμό καθώς επίσης και
να διαβάσουν τους τίτλους περιγράφοντας τη διαδικασία. Η 
ζωτικότητα είναι μέρος της συλλογής απεικόνισης γήινης 
εξερεύνησης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este Web site recibe una animación que representa
cómo los fósiles del molde y del molde se preservan en el expediente
de la roca. Los utilizadores pueden jugar, rebobinar, delantero 
rápido y parar la animación en cualquier punta en la formación así
como encabezamientos leídos contorneando el proceso. La 
animación es parte de la colección de la visualización de la 
exploración de la tierra.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JENNIFER LOOMIS
FN:JENNIFER LOOMIS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211385</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107621</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/observe-how-fossils-can-form</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
