<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105938</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105938</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087174</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"We Are Americans!": The Homestead Workers Issue a Declaration of Independence in 1936</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Wir Sind Amerikaner!": Die Gehöft-Arbeiter
geben eine Unabhängigkeitserklärung 1936 heraus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Nous Sommes des Américains!" : Les 
ouvriers de ferme émettent une déclaration de l'indépendance en 
1936</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Nós Somos Americanos!": Os trabalhadores 
do homestead emitem uma declaração de independência em 1936</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Siamo Americani!": Gli operai della 
fattoria pubblicano una dichiarazione di indipendenza in 1936</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Είμαστε Αμερικανοΐ": Οι εργαζόμενοι αγροτικών 
σπιτιών εκδίδουν μια Διακήρυξη της ανεξαρτησίας το 1936</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Somos Americanos!": Los trabajadores de la 
granja publican un declaración de la independencia en 1936</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Although many historians have emphasized the conservative dimensions of this language of Americanism--the ways that it reinforced rather than challenged the status quo--historian Gary Gerstle shows that it was considerably more complex and contradictory. He argues that it was "flexible enough to express both the social democratic and ethnic communalist visions that inspired political activism among the nation_s workers during the Great Depression. As in other communities, this working-class Americanism infused the organizing campaign of the Steel Workers Organizing Committee (SWOC) in Homestead, Pennsylvania in the summer of 1936. Four thousand steelworkers endorsed a declaration of their "inalienable rights to organize into a great industrial union, banded together with all our fellow steel workers." It was surely not an accident that they worded that declaration in conscious imitation of the Declaration of Independence.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Obgleich viele Historiker die konservativen Maße 
dieser Sprache des Amerikanismus hervorgehoben haben -- die Methoden, 
denen es anstatt verstärkte, den Status Quo herausforderte -- 
Historiker Gary Gerstle zeigt, daß er beträchtlich komplizierter und
unvereinbar war. Er argumentiert, daß er "genug flexibel war, 
die demokratischen und ethnischen communalist sozialanblicke 
auszudrücken, die politischen Aktivismus unter den nation_s Arbeitern
während des großen Tiefstands anspornten. Wie in anderen 
Gemeinschaften, goß dieser Arbeiterklasse Amerikanismus die 
organisierende Kampagne des Stahlarbeiter-Organisationsausschusses 
(SWOC) im Gehöft, Pennsylvania am Sommer von 1936 hinein. Vier 
tausend Steelworkers indossierten eine Erklärung ihrer 
"unübertragbaren Rechte, in eine große Industriegewerkschaft zu 
organisieren, mit einem Band versehen zusammen mit allen unseren 
Mitstahlarbeitern." Es war sicher nicht ein Unfall, dem sie 
diese Erklärung in der bewußten Nachahmung der 
Unabhängigkeitserklärung abfaßten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bien que beaucoup d'historiens aient souligné les
dimensions conservatrices de ce langage d'Américanisme -- les 
manières dont elle a renforcé plutôt qu'a défié le statu quo -- 
l'historien Gary Gerstle prouve qu'il était considérablement plus 
complexe et contradictoire. Il argue du fait qu'il était "assez
flexible pour exprimer les visions démocratiques et ethniques 
sociales de communalist qui ont inspiré l'activisme politique parmi 
les ouvriers de nation_s pendant la grande dépression. Comme 
dans d'autres communautés, cet Américanisme de classe ouvrière a 
infusé la campagne d'organisation du Comité d'organisation 
d'ouvriers en acier (SWOC) dans la ferme, Pennsylvanie en été de 
1936. Quatre mille travailleurs dans l'industrie sidérurgique 
ont approuvé une déclaration de leurs "droites inaliénables 
d'organiser en grand syndicat ouvrier, réunie ainsi que tous nos 
ouvriers en acier de camarade." Ce n'était sûrement pas un 
accident qu'ils ont exprimé cette déclaration dans l'imitation 
consciente de la déclaration de l'indépendance.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Embora muitos historians emfatizassem as 
dimensões conservadoras desta língua do americanism -- as maneiras 
que reforçou melhor que desafiou o quo do status -- o historian Gary 
Gerstle mostra que era consideravelmente mais complexo e 
contradictory. Discute que era "flexível bastante expressar  as
visões democráticas e étnicas sociais do communalist que inspiraram
o activism político entre os trabalhadores dos nation_s durante o 
depression grande. Como em outras comunidades, este americanism 
do working-class infused a campanha organizando do comitê organizando
de trabalhadores de aço (SWOC) no homestead, Pensilvânia no verão 
de 1936. Quatro mil steelworkers endossaram uma declaração de 
suas "direitas inalienable organizar em uma união industrial grande, 
unida junto com todos nossos trabalhadores de aço do companheiro." 
Não era certamente um acidente que exprimissem essa 
declaração no imitation conscious da declaração de independência.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Anche se molti storici hanno dato risalto alle 
dimensioni conservatrici di questo linguaggio del americanism -- i modi 
che ha rinforzato piuttosto che sfidato lo status quo -- lo storico 
Gary Gerstle indica che era considerevolmente più complesso e 
contradittorio. Sostiene che era "abbastanza flessibile 
esprimere sia le visioni democratiche che etniche sociali di 
communalist che hanno ispirato il activism politico fra gli operai dei
nation_s durante la depressione grande. Come in altre Comunità,
questo americanism della classe operaia ha infuso la campagna 
d'organizzazione del comitato di organizzazione dei lavoratori 
dell'industria siderurgica (SWOC) in fattoria, Pensilvania di estate 
di 1936. Quattro mila addetti alla lavorazione dell'acciaio 
hanno firmato una dichiarazione dei loro "diritti inalienabili di 
organizzare in un'unione industriale grande, legata insieme a tutti i 
nostri lavoratori dell'industria siderurgica del collega." Non 
era certamente un incidente che esprimessero quella dichiarazione 
nell'imitazione cosciente della dichiarazione di indipendenza.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αν και πολλοί ιστορικοί έχουν υπογραμμίσει τις 
συντηρητικές διαστάσεις αυτής της γλώσσας Americanism -- οι 
τρόποι παρά τους οποίους ενίσχυσε προκάλεσαν το καθεστώς -- ο 
ιστορικός Gary Gerstle δείχνει ότι ήταν αρκετά πιό 
σύνθετο και αντιφατικό. Υποστηρίζει ότι ήταν "αρκετά 
εύκαμπτο να εκφράσει και τα κοινωνικά δημοκρατικά και εθνικά 
οράματα communalist που ενέπνευσαν τον πολιτικό ακτιβισμό 
μεταξύ των εργαζομένων nation_s κατά τη διάρκεια της μεγάλης 
οικονομικής κρίσης. Όπως σε άλλες κοινότητες, αυτή η 
εργατική τάξη Americanism ημπότισε την εκστρατεία οργάνωσης 
των εργαζομένων χάλυβα που οργανώνουν την Επιτροπή (SWOC) στο 
αγροτικό σπίτι, η Πενσυλβανία το καλοκαίρι 1936, 
Τέσσερις χιλιάες σιδηρουργοί επικύρωσαν μια δήλωση των 
"αναφαίρετων δικαιωμάτων τους που οργανώνουν σε μια μεγάλη 
βιομηχανική ένωση, που ενώθηκε μαζί με όλους τους συντροφικούς 
εργαζομένους χάλυβά μας." _ αυτός είμαι σίγουρα όχι ένας
ατύχημα ότι αυτός διατυπώνω εκείνος δήλωση συνειδητός μίμηση ο
Διακήρυξη ανεξαρτησία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Aunque muchos historiadores han acentuado las 
dimensiones conservadoras de este lenguaje del americanism -- las 
maneras que reforzó más bien que desafió el status quo -- el 
historiador Gary Gerstle muestra que era considerablemente más 
complejo y contradictorio. Él discute que fuera "bastante 
flexible expresar las visiones democráticas y étnicas sociales del 
communalist que inspiraron activismo político entre los trabajadores 
de los nation_s durante la gran depresión. Como en otras 
comunidades, este americanism de la clase obrera infundió la campaña
de ordenación del comité de ordenación de los trabajadores de acero
(SWOC) en la granja, Pennsylvania en el verano de 1936. Cuatro 
mil trabajadores siderúrgicos endosaron un declaración de las sus 
"derechas inalienables de ordenar en una gran unión industrial, 
congregado junto con todos nuestros trabajadores de acero del 
compañero." No era seguramente un accidente que redactaron ese 
declaración en la imitación consciente del declaración de la 
independencia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087174</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105938</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/we-are-americans-the-homestead-workers-issue-a-declaration-of-independence-in-1936</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
