<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/419806406</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>419806406</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202965</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Geysers: Lower Geyser Basin</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geysire: Senken Sie Geysir-Bassin</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Geysers : Abaissez Le Bassin de Geyser</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Geysers: Abaixe A Bacia Do Geyser</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Geyser: Abbassi Il Bacino Del Geyser</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Geysers: Χαμηλότερη geyser λεκάνη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Géiseres: Baje El Lavabo Del Géiser</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Yellowstone National Park web site is dedicated to Lower Geyser Basin. It includes images and descriptions of Queen's Laundry and Sentinel Meadows, Sentinel Cone, Ojo Caliente, Pocket Basin Mud Pots, Imperial Geyser, Spray Geyser, Octopus Spring, Great Fountain Geyser, White Dome Geyser, Pink Cone Geyser, Bead Geyser, Narcissus Geyser, Steady Geyser, Silex Spring, Fountain Paint Pot, Fountain Geyser, Clepsydra Geyser, and Jelly Geyser.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Yellowstone Nationalpark Web site wird 
untererem Geysir-Bassin eingesetzt. Sie schließt Bilder und 
Beschreibungen der Wäscherei-und Hinweissymbol-Wiesen der Königin, 
des Hinweissymbol-Kegels, des Ojo Caliente, der Tasche 
Bassin-Schlamm-Töpfe, des imperialen Geysirs, des Spray-Geysirs, des 
Krake-Frühlinges, des großen Brunnen-Geysirs, des weißen 
Haube-Geysirs, des rosafarbenen Kegel-Geysirs, des Korn-Geysirs, des 
Narzisse-Geysirs, des unveränderlichen Geysirs, des 
Silex-Frühlinges, des Brunnen-Farbe Topfes, des Brunnen-Geysirs, des 
Clepsydra-Geysirs und des Gelee-Geysirs ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site Web de parc national de Yellowstone est 
consacré au bassin inférieur de geyser. Il inclut des images 
et des descriptions des prés de la blanchisserie et de la sentinelle 
de la Reine, du cône de sentinelle, de l'Ojo Caliente, des pots de 
boue de bassin de poche, du geyser impérial, du geyser de jet, du 
ressort de poulpe, du grand geyser de fontaine, du geyser blanc de 
dôme, du geyser rose de cône, du geyser de petit programme, du 
geyser de narcisse, du geyser régulier, du ressort de silex, du pot 
de peinture de fontaine, du geyser de fontaine, du geyser de 
clepsydra, et du geyser de gelée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Web site do parque nacional de Yellowstone é 
dedicado a uma bacia mais baixa do geyser. Inclui imagens e 
descrições de prados da lavanderia e da sentinela da rainha, de cone
da sentinela, de Ojo Caliente, de potenciômetros da lama da bacia do 
bolso, do geyser imperial, do geyser do pulverizador, da mola do 
polvo, do geyser grande da fonte, do geyser branco da abóbada, do 
geyser cor-de-rosa do cone, do geyser do grânulo, do geyser do 
narcissus, do geyser constante, da mola do silex, do potenciômetro da
pintura da fonte, do geyser da fonte, do geyser da clepsidra, e do 
geyser da geléia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Web site del parco nazionale di Yellowstone 
è dedicato al bacino più basso del geyser. Include le immagini
e descrizioni dei prati della lavanderia e della sentinella della 
regina, del cono della sentinella, di Ojo Caliente, dei POT del fango 
del bacino della tasca, del geyser imperiale, del geyser dello 
spruzzo, della molla del polipo, del geyser grande della fontana, del 
geyser bianco della cupola, del geyser dentellare del cono, del geyser
del branello, del geyser del narciso, del geyser costante, della molla
del silex, del POT della vernice della fontana, del geyser della 
fontana, del geyser del clepsydra e del geyser della gelatina.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο εθνικός ιστοχώρος πάρκων Yellowstone 
αφιερώνεται στη χαμηλότερη geyser λεκάνη. Περιλαμβάνει 
τις εικόνες και τις περιγραφές πλυντηρίων και sentinel της 
βασίλισσας των λιβαδιών, sentinel του κώνου, Ojo Caliente,
των δοχείων λάσπης λεκανών τσεπών, αυτοκρατορικό geyser, 
geyser ψεκασμού, της άνοιξης χταποδιών, μεγάλο geyser 
πηγών, άσπρο geyser θόλων, ρόδινο geyser κώνων, geyser 
χαντρών, geyser ναρκίσσων, σταθερό geyser, της άνοιξης 
Silex, του δοχείου χρωμάτων πηγών, geyser πηγών, geyser 
Clepsydra, και geyser ζελατίνας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este Web site del parque nacional de Yellowstone se
dedica a un lavabo más bajo del géiser. Incluye imágenes y 
las descripciones de los prados del lavadero y del centinela de la 
reina, del cono del centinela, de Ojo Caliente, de los crisoles del 
fango del lavabo del bolsillo, del géiser imperial, del géiser del 
aerosol, del resorte del pulpo, del gran géiser de la fuente, del 
géiser blanco de la bóveda, del géiser rosado del cono, del géiser
del grano, del géiser del narciso, del géiser constante, del resorte
del sílice, del crisol de la pintura de la fuente, del géiser de la 
fuente, del géiser de la clepsidra, y del géiser de la jalea.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:YELLOWSTONE NATIONAL PARK
FN:YELLOWSTONE NATIONAL PARK
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202965</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>419806406</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/geysers-lower-geyser-basin</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
