<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107891</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107891</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086388</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Korematsu  v.  United States: The U.S. Supreme Court Upholds Internment</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Korematsu V. Vereinigte Staaten: Das 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Höchste Gericht Unterstützt Internierung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Korematsu v. Etats-Unis : La Cour Suprême 
des ETATS-UNIS Confirme l'Internement</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Estados unidos v. de Korematsu: A Corte 
Suprema de ESTADOS UNIDOS Upholds O Internamento</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Korematsu v. unito Dichiara: La Corte
suprema degli STATI UNITI Sostiene L'Internamento</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Korematsu V. Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες: Το 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ ανώτατο δικαστήριο υποστηρίζει τον περιορισμό</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Korematsu v. Estados Unidos: El Tribunal 
Supremo de ESTADOS UNIDOS Mantiene La Internación</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">America fought World War II to preserve freedom and democracy, yet that same war featured the greatest suppression of civil liberties in the nation's history. In an atmosphere of hysteria, President Roosevelt, encouraged by officials at all levels of the federal government, authorized the internment of tens of thousands of American citizens of Japanese ancestry and resident aliens from Japan. One of the most important of the legal challenges to the internment policy was  Korematsu v. United States , a case brought by Fred T. Korematsu, a Nisei (an American-born person whose parents were born in Japan). Korematsu had been arrested by the FBI for failing to report for relocation and was convicted in federal court in September 1942. The U.S. Supreme Court, in a sharply divided 6-3 decision, upheld Korematsu's conviction in late 1944. The majority opinion, written by Justice Hugo Black, rejected the plaintiff's discrimination argument and upheld the government's right to relocate citizens in the face of wartime emergency.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Amerika kennzeichnete der gekämpfte Zweite 
Weltkrieg, zum von von Freiheit und von von Demokratie zu 
konservieren, dennoch das der gleiche Krieg den größten Ausgleich 
von Zivilfreiheiten in der Geschichte der Nation. In einer 
Atmosphäre der Hysterie, autorisierte Präsident Roosevelt, 
angeregt von den Beamten auf allen Stufen der Bundesregierung, die 
Internierung von 10 Tausenden der amerikanischen Bürger japanischen 
Geschlechtes und der Residentausländer von Japan. Eins von den 
wichtigsten der zugelassenen Herausforderungen zur Internierungpolitik
war Korematsu V. Vereinigte Staaten, ein Fall, der durch Fred T. 
Korematsu, ein Nisei geholt wurde (eine Amerikanisch-getragene Person 
deren Eltern in Japan geboren waren). Korematsu war durch das 
FBI festgehalten worden, damit das Nicht können für Verschiebung 
berichtet und wurde im Bundesgerichtshof im September 1942 
überführt. Das VEREINIGTE STAATEN Höchste Gericht, in einer 
scharf geteilten Entscheidung 6-3, unterstützte Überzeugung 
Korematsus spätem 1944. Die Majorität Meinung, geschrieben 
durch Justice Hugo Schwarzes, zurückgewiesen dem 
Unterscheidungargument des Zivilklägers und unterstützt dem Recht 
der Regierung, Bürger angesichts der Kriegdringlichkeit zu verlagern.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">ParAmérique la deuxième guerre mondiale 
combattue celle pour préserver la liberté et la démocratie, 
pourtant la même guerre a comporté la plus grande suppression des 
libertés civiles dans l'histoire de la nation. Dans une 
atmosphère d'hystérie, le Président Roosevelt, encouragé par des 
fonctionnaires à tous les niveaux du gouvernement fédéral, a 
autorisé l'internement des dizaines de milliers de citoyens 
américains d'ascendance japonaise et d'étrangers résidents du 
Japon. Un des plus importante des défis légaux à la politique
d'internement était Korematsu v. Etats-Unis, un cas apporté par Fred
T. Korematsu, un Nisei (une personne Américain-soutenue dont les 
parents sont nés au Japon). Korematsu été arrêté par le 
FBI pour que n'enregistre pas pour le réadressage et avait a 
été condamné dans la cour fédérale en septembre 1942. La 
cour suprême des ETATS-UNIS, dans une décision 6-3 brusquement 
divisée, a confirmé la conviction de Korematsu vers la fin de 1944. 
L'opinion de majorité, écrite par noir de Justice Hugo, 
rejetée l'argument de la discrimination du plaignant et confirmée la
droite du gouvernement de replacer des citoyens face à l'urgence de 
temps de guerre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">América a segunda guerra mundial lutada aquela 
para preservar a liberdade e a democracia, contudo a mesma guerra 
caracterizou a supressão a mais grande de liberdades civis no history
da nação. Em uma atmosfera do hysteria, o presidente 
Roosevelt, incentivado por oficiais em todos os níveis do governo 
federal, autorizou o internamento dos dez dos milhares de cidadãos 
americanos do ancestry japonês e dos estrangeiros residentes de 
Japão. Um do mais importante dos desafios legais à política 
do internamento era estados unidos v. de Korematsu, um caso trazido 
por Fred T. Korematsu, um Nisei (uma pessoa Americano-carregada cujos 
os pais fossem carregados em Japão). Korematsu tinha sido 
prendido pelo FBI para que não relate para o relocation e convicted 
na corte federal em setembro 1942. A corte suprema de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS, em uma decisão 6-3 agudamente dividida, upheld a convicção 
de Korematsu em 1944 atrasado. A opinião da maioria, escrita 
pelo preto de Justiça Hugo, rejeitada o argumento da discriminação 
do plaintiff e upheld a direita do governo relocate cidadãos na cara 
da emergência do wartime.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'America ha combattuto la seconda guerra mondiale
per conservare la libertà e la democrazia, tuttavia quella la stessa 
guerra ha caratterizzato la soppressione più grande delle libertà 
civili nella storia della nazione. In un atmosfera di hysteria, 
il presidente Roosevelt, consigliato a dai funzionari a tutti i 
livelli del governo federale, ha autorizzato l'internamento dei dieci 
dei migliaia dei cittadini americani dell'ascendenza giapponese e 
degli stranieri residenti dal Giappone. Uno degli la più 
importanti delle contestazioni alla politica di internamento era 
Korematsu v. unito Dichiara, un caso portato da Fred T. 
Korematsu, un Nisei (una persona Americano-sopportata di cui i 
genitori sono stati sopportati nel Giappone). Korematsu era 
stato arrestato dal FBI affinchè non riuscire segnali per la 
rilocazione ed è stato condannato nella corte federale nel mese di 
settembre del 1942. La Corte suprema degli STATI UNITI, in una 
decisione acutamente divisa 6-3, ha sostenuto la convinzione del 
Korematsu verso la fine del 1944. L'opinione di maggioranza, 
scritta da nero della Justice Hugo, rifiutata l'argomento di 
distinzione del querelante e sostenuta la destra del governo 
riassegnare i cittadini di fronte all'emergenza di wartime.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η Αμερική διεξήγαγε τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο ΙΙ για να 
συντηρήσει την ελευθερία και τη δημοκρατία, όμως εκείνος ο ίδιος
πόλεμος χαρακτήρισε τη μέγιστη καταστολή των αστικών ελευθεριών 
στην ιστορία του έθνους. Σε μια ατμόσφαιρα της υστερίας, ο 
Πρόεδρος Roosevelt, που ενθαρρύνθηκε από τους ανώτερους 
υπαλλήλους σε όλα τα επίπεδα της ομοσπονδιακής κυβέρνησης, 
ενέκρινε τον περιορισμό των δεκάδων χιλιάδων αμερικανικοί 
πολίτες της ιαπωνικής καταγωγής και εδρεύοντες αλλοδαποί από την
Ιαπωνία. Ένα από το σημαντικότερο των νομικών προκλήσεων 
στην πολιτική περιορισμού ήταν Korematsu V. Ηνωμένες 
Πολιτείες, μια υπόθεση που υποβλήθηκε από το Fred T. 
Korematsu, ένα Nisei (ένα αμερικανικός-γεννημένο πρόσωπο οι
του οποίου γονείς γεννήθηκαν στην Ιαπωνία). Το Korematsu 
ήταν συλλήφθείτ από τη FBI για την αποτυχία να υποβάλει 
έκθεση για την επαναμετάθεση και καταδικάστηκε στο ομοσπονδιακό 
δικαστήριο τον Σεπτέμβριο του 1942. Το ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ ανώτατο
δικαστήριο, σε μια αισθητά διαιρεμένη απόφαση 6-3, υποστήριξε 
την πεποίθηση Korematsu στα τέλη του 1944. Η άποψη 
πλειοψηφίας, που γράφτηκε από τη δικαιοσύνη Hugo Black, 
απέρριψε το όρισμα διάκρισης του ενάγοντος και υποστήριξε το 
κυβερνητικό δικαίωμα να επανεντοπιστούν οι πολίτες παρά την εν 
καιρώ πολέμου έκτακτη ανάγκη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">América la Segunda Guerra Mundial de combate ésa
para preservar la libertad y la democracia, con todo la misma guerra 
ofreció la supresión más grande de libertades civiles en la 
historia de la nación. En una atmósfera de la histeria, 
presidente Roosevelt, alentador por los funcionarios en todos los 
niveles del gobierno federal, autorizó la internación de diez de 
millares de ciudadanos americanos de ascendencia japonesa y de 
extranjeros residentes de Japón. Uno del más importante de los
desafíos legales a la política de la internación era Korematsu v. 
Estados Unidos, un caso traído por Fred T. Korematsu, un Nisei 
(persona Americano-llevada que padres nacieron en Japón). 
Korematsu había sido arrestado por el FBI para que el no poder 
señale para la realocación y fue condenado en corte federal en 
septiembre de 1942. El Tribunal Supremo de ESTADOS UNIDOS, en 
una decisión sostenidamente dividida 6-3, mantuvo la convicción de 
Korematsu en finales de 1944. La opinión de la mayoría, 
escrita por el negro de Justice Hugo, rechazada el argumento de la 
discriminación del demandante y mantenida la derecha del gobierno de 
volver a poner a los ciudadanos en la cara de la emergencia del tiempo
de guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086388</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107891</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/korematsu-v-united-states-the-u-s-supreme-court-upholds-internment</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
