<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108284</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108284</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202966</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Girls Speak Out</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mädchen Sprechen Heraus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Filles Parlent Dehors</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As Meninas Falam Para fora</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le Ragazze Parlano Fuori</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα κορίτσια μιλούν έξω</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las Muchachas Hablan Hacia fuera</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Today, over 115 million children have never set foot inside a school. The fact is that for children living in developing countries, the dream of a first day of school is yet to be realized. The daily realities of poverty, political instability, regional conflict, geography, and cultural or traditional values all play a role to varying degrees -- and the issue of gender disparity makes this fact even more staggering. Full and equal access to education (Article 26) as outlined in the 'Universal Declaration of Human Rights' and 'The Convention on the Rights of the Child' (Articles 2,3,28, and 29), has clearly been out of the reach of poor children -- and even more so in the case of girls. Nearly two-thirds of children who are denied a primary education are girls. In the least developed countries, nearly twice as many adult women than men are illiterate. (Source: UNFPA http://www.unfpa.org/icpd/10/icpd_ed.htm) If you happen to be a female, you are less likely to have access to a quality primary education and beyond -- contributing to the feminization of global poverty. Yet, there is hope despite this current state of affairs. 189 nations have pledged to meet 8 major Millennium Development Goals (MDGs) by 2015. In doing so, nations hope to improve the social and economic development of all peoples. Included in these goals are those that address education and gender disparity: MDG 2: Achieve universal and primary education. MDG 3: Promote gender equality and empower women. Through the activities outlined in this lesson, students will become familiar with the current barriers standing in the way of educational opportunity -- especially for girls. They will watch clips from the WIDE ANGLE film 'Time for School' (2003) to understand the sense of urgency surrounding this issue, the potential benefits that can result from educating girls, and the ways that local communities are trying to address these problems. Note: This lesson focuses on MDG 2 and MDG 3. An introduction to the overall goals of the Millennium Project should be presented prior to this particular lesson.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Heute über 115 Million Kindern haben nie Fuß 
innerhalb einer Schule eingestellt. Die Tatsache ist die für 
die Kinder, die in Entwicklungsländern, der Traum eines ersten Tages 
der Schule leben, soll schon verwirklicht werden. Die täglichen
Wirklichkeiten der Armut, der politischen Instabilität, der 
regionalen $überschneidung, der Geographie und der kulturellen oder 
traditionellen Werte alle spielen eine Rolle zu unterschiedlichen Grad
-- und die Ausgabe der Geschlechtverschiedenheit bildet diese Tatsache
sogar schwankend. Voller und gleicher Zugang zur Ausbildung 
(Artikel 26) wie in der ' Universalerklärung der menschlichen Rechte 
skizziert und ' die Versammlung über die Rechte des Kindes ' (Artikel
2.3.28 und 29), ist offenbar aus der Reichweite der armen Kinder -- 
und sogar so im Fall von den Mädchen heraus gewesen. Fast 
zweidrittel von Kindern, denen eine Primärausbildung verweigert 
werden, sind Mädchen. In den wenigen entwickelten Ländern fast
zweimal sind bis zu Erwachsenfrauen als Männer unwissend. 
(Quelle: UNFPA http://www.unfpa.org/icpd/10/icpd_ed.htm) 
wenn Sie geschehen, eine Frau zu sein, sind Sie weniger 
wahrscheinlich, Zugriff zu einer Qualitätsprimärausbildung zu haben 
und jenseits -- beitragend zum feminization der globalen Armut. 
Jedoch gibt es Hoffnung trotz dieser aktuellen Sachlage. 
189 Nationen haben versprochen, um 8 
Hauptjahrtausend-Entwicklung Ziele (MDGs) bis zum 2015 zu treffen. 
Wenn sie so tun, hoffen Nationen, die Sozial- und ökonomische 
Entwicklung aller Völker zu verbessern. In diesen Zielen 
geschlossen die ein, die Ausbildung und Geschlechtverschiedenheit 
adressieren: MDG 2: Erzielen Sie Universal- und 
Primärausbildung. MDG 3: Fördern Sie 
Geschlechtgleichheit und bevollmächtigen Sie Frauen. Durch die 
Aktivitäten, die in dieser Lektion umrissen werden, werden 
Kursteilnehmer mit den aktuellen Sperren vertraut, die in der Methode 
der pädagogischen Gelegenheit -- besonders für Mädchen stehen. 
Sie überwachen Clips vom Weitwinkelfilm ' Zeit für Schule ' 
(2003) die Richtung der Dringlichkeit zu verstehen diese Ausgabe, den 
Potentialnutzen, die aus dem Erziehen der Mädchen resultieren 
können, und die Methoden umgebend, denen lokale Gemeinschaften 
versuchen, diese Probleme zu adressieren. Anmerkung: Diese
Lektion konzentriert auf MDG 2 und MDG 3. Eine Einleitung zu den
gesamten Zielen des Jahrtausend-Projektes sollte vor dieser bestimmten
Lektion dargestellt werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Aujourd'hui, plus de 115 millions d'enfants n'ont 
jamais placé le pied à l'intérieur d'une école. Le fait est 
celui pour des enfants vivant dans les pays en voie de développement,
le rêve d'un premier jour d'école doit être réalisé encore. 
Les réalités quotidiennes de la pauvreté, de l'instabilité 
politique, du conflit régional, de la géographie, et des valeurs 
culturelles ou traditionnelles tous jouent un rôle aux degrés 
variables -- et la question de la disparité de genre fait ce fait 
plus chancelant. La pleine et d'accès égalité à l'éducation
(article 26) conformément 'à la déclaration universelle des droits 
de l'homme et 'la convention sur les droits de l'enfance '(articles 
2.3.28, et 29), a clairement été hors de l'extension de pauvres 
enfants -- et encore plus dans le cas des filles. Presque 
deux-tiers d'enfants qui sont niés une éducation primaire sont des 
filles. Dans les moindres pays développés, presque deux fois 
autant de femmes d'adulte que des hommes sont illettrées. 
(source : UNFPA http://www.unfpa.org/icpd/10/icpd_ed.htm) 
Si vous vous avérez justement être une femelle, vous êtes 
moins pour avoir accès à une éducation primaire de qualité et 
là-bas -- contribuant au feminization de la pauvreté globale. 
Cependant, il y a espoir en dépit de cet état de la question 
actuel. 189 nations ont mis en gage pour rencontrer 8 buts 
principaux de développement de millénium (MDGs) d'ici 2015. De
cette manière, les nations espèrent améliorer le développement 
économique social et de tous les peuples. Inclus dans ces buts 
sont ceux qui adressent l'éducation et la disparité de genre : 
MDG 2 : Réalisez l'éducation universelle et primaire. 
MDG 3 : Favorisez l'égalité de genre et autorisez les 
femmes. Par les activités tracées les grandes lignes dans 
cette leçon, les étudiants se familiariseront avec les barrières 
actuelles incommodant l'occasion éducative -- particulièrement pour 
des filles. Ils observeront des clips du film GRAND-ANGULAIRE 
'heure pour l'école '(2003) de comprendre le sens de l'urgence 
entourant cette issue, les avantages de potentiel qui peuvent 
résulter d'instruire des filles, et les manières dont les 
communautés locales essayent d'adresser ces problèmes. Note : 
Cette leçon se concentre sur MDG 2 et MDG 3. Une 
introduction aux buts globaux du projet de millénium devrait être 
présentée avant cette leçon particulière.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Hoje, sobre 115 milhão crianças nunca ajustaram 
o pé dentro de uma escola. O fato é aquele para as crianças 
que vivem em países tornando-se, o sonho de um primeiro dia da escola
deve ser realizado ainda. As realidades diárias da pobreza, da 
instabilidade política, do conflito regional, da geografia, e de 
valores cultural ou tradicionais todos jogam um papel aos graus 
variando -- e a introdução do disparity do gender faz este fato 
mesmo que desconcerta. O acesso cheio e igual à instrução 
(artigo 26) como esboçado ' na declaração universal de direitas 
humanas e ' na convenção nas direitas da criança ' (artigos 2.3.28,
e 29), foi claramente fora do alcance de crianças deficientes -- e 
mesmo mais assim no exemplo das meninas. Quase dois terços das 
crianças que são negadas uma instrução preliminar são meninas. 
Em menos países desenvolvidos, quase duas vezes tantas como 
mulheres do adulto do que homens são illiterate. (fonte: 
UNFPA http://www.unfpa.org/icpd/10/icpd_ed.htm) se você 
acontecer ser uma fêmea, você é mais menos provável ter o acesso a
uma instrução preliminar da qualidade e além -- contribuindo ao 
feminization da pobreza global. Ainda, há uma esperança apesar
deste estado de casos atual. 189 nações prometeram para 
encontrar-se com 8 objetivos principais do desenvolvimento do 
millennium (MDGs) por 2015. Em fazer assim, as nações esperam 
melhorar o desenvolvimento social e econômico de todos os povos. 
São incluídas nestes objetivos aqueles que se dirigem à 
instrução e ao disparity do gender: MDG 2: Consiga a 
instrução universal e preliminar. MDG 3: Promova a 
igualdade do gender e empower mulheres. Com as atividades 
esboçadas nesta lição, os estudantes tornar-se-ão familiares com 
as barreiras atuais que estão na maneira da oportunidade educacional 
-- especial para meninas. Prestarão atenção a grampos do 
ÂNGULO LARGO filmar ' a hora para a escola ' (2003) de compreender o 
sentido do urgency que cerca esta edição, os benefícios do 
potencial que podem resultar de educar meninas, e as maneiras que as 
comunidades locais estão tentando se dirigir a estes problemas. 
Nota: Esta lição focaliza em MDG 2 e em MDG 3. Uma
introdução aos objetivos totais do projeto do millennium deve ser 
apresentada antes desta lição particular.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Oggi, oltre 115 milione bambini non hanno regolato
mai il piede all'interno di una scuola. Il fatto è quello per i
bambini che vivono nei pæsi in via di sviluppo, il sogno di un primo 
giorno della scuola deve ancora essere realizzato. Le realtà 
quotidiane di povertà, di instabilità politica, del conflitto 
regionale, della geografia e dei valori culturali o tradizionali tutti
svolgono un ruolo ai gradi di variazione -- e l'emissione della 
disparità di genere fa questo fatto che vacilla. La parità 
d'accesso completa ed a formazione (l'articolo 26) conforme 'alla 
dichiarazione universale dei diritti dell'uomo e 'la convenzione sui 
diritti del bambino '(gli articoli 2.3.28 e 29), è stata chiaramente 
dall'estensione di poveri bambini -- ed ancor più nel caso delle 
ragazze. Quasi due terzi dei bambini che sono negati una 
formazione primaria è ragazze. Nei meno paesi sviluppati, 
altretante donne dell'adulto che gli uomini sono quasi due volte 
illetterate. (sorgente: UNFPA 
http://www.unfpa.org/icpd/10/icpd_ed.htm) se sembrate essere una 
femmina, siete meno probabili avere accesso ad una formazione primaria
di qualità e di là -- contribuendo al feminization di povertà 
globale. Tuttavia, ci è speranza malgrado questa corrente 
dichiara degli affari. 189 nazioni hanno impegnato per 
venire a contatto di 8 obiettivi importanti di sviluppo di millennio 
(MDGs) entro 2015. In tal modo, le nazioni sperano di migliorare
lo sviluppo sociale ed economico di tutta la gente. Sono inclusi
in questi obiettivi quelli che richiamano la formazione e la 
disparità di genere: MDG 2: Realizzi la formazione 
universale e primaria. MDG 3: Promuova l'uguaglianza di 
genere ed autorizzi le donne. Con le attività descritte in 
questa lezione, gli allievi diventeranno esperti con le barriere 
correnti che ostacolano l'occasione educativa -- particolarmente per 
le ragazze. Guarderanno le clip dalla pellicola GRANDANGOLARE 
'tempo per la scuola '(2003) di capire il senso di urgenza che 
circonda questa edizione, i benefici di potenziale che possono 
derivare dall'istruzione delle ragazze ed i modi che le Comunità 
locali stanno provando a richiamare questi problemi. Nota: 
Questa lezione mette a fuoco su MDG 2 e su MDG 3. 
Un'introduzione agli obiettivi generali del progetto di 
millennio dovrebbe essere presentata prima di questa lezione 
particolare.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σήμερα, πάνω από 115 εκατομμύριο παιδιά δεν έχουν
θέτουν ποτέ το πόδι μέσα σε ένα σχολείο. Το γεγονός 
είναι ότι για τα παιδιά που ζουν στις αναπτυσσόμενες χώρες, το 
όνειρο μιας πρώτης ημέρας του σχολείου πρόκειται ακόμα να 
πραγματοποιηθεί. Οι καθημερινές πραγματικότητες της ένδειας,
της πολιτικής αστάθειας, της περιφερειακής σύγκρουσης, της 
γεωγραφίας, και των πολιτιστικών ή παραδοσιακών αξιών όλες 
διαδραματίζουν έναν ρόλο σε διαφορετικό βαθμό -- και το ζήτημα 
της διαφοράς γένους κάνει αυτό το γεγονός ακόμα πιό παραπαίον.
Πλήρης και ίση πρόσβαση στην εκπαίδευση (άρθρο 26) 
σύμφωνα με τη "καθολική Διακήρυξη των ανθρώπινων δικαιωμάτων" και
"η Συνθήκη σχετικά με τα δικαιώματα του παιδιού" (τα άρθρα 
2.3.28, και 29), ήταν σαφώς από την προσιτότητα των φτωχών 
παιδιών -- και ακόμα περισσότερο στην περίπτωση των κοριτσιών. 
Σχεδόν τα δύο τρίτα των παιδιών που αμφισβητούνται μια 
πρωτοβάθμια εκπαίδευση είναι κορίτσια. Στις λιγότερες 
αναπτυγμένες χώρες, σχεδόν δύο φορές τόσο πολλές ενήλικες 
γυναίκες από τους άνδρες είναι αναλφάβητες. (Πηγή: 
UNFPA http://www.unfpa.org/icpd/10/icpd_ed.htm) εάν συμβαίνετε
να είστε θηλυκό, είναι λιγότερο πιθανό να έχετε πρόσβαση σε μια
ποιοτική πρωτοβάθμια εκπαίδευση και πέρα -- συμβάλλοντας 
feminization της σφαιρικής ένδειας. Ακόμα, υπάρχει 
ελπίδα παρά αυτήν την παρούσα παρούσα κατάσταση. 189 
έθνη έχουν δεσμεύσει να συναντήσουν 8 σημαντικούς στόχους 
ανάπτυξης χιλιετίας (MDGs) μέχρι το 2015. Με αυτό τον 
τρόπο, τα έθνη ελπίζουν να βελτιώσουν την κοινωνική και 
οικονομική ανάπτυξη όλων των λαών. Περιλαμβάνονται σε 
αυτούς τους στόχους εκείνοι που εξετάζουν τη διαφορά εκπαίδευσης
και φύλου: MDG 2: Επιτύχετε την καθολική και 
πρωτοβάθμια εκπαίδευση. MDG 3: Προωθήστε την 
ισότητα γένους και εξουσιοδοτήστε τις γυναίκες. Μέσω των 
δραστηριοτήτων που περιγράφονται σε αυτό το μάθημα, οι σπουδαστές
θα γίνουν εξοικειωμένοι με τα παρόντα εμπόδια που στέκονται με το
δρόμο της εκπαιδευτικής ευκαιρίας -- ειδικά για τα κορίτσια. 
Θα προσέξουν τους συνδετήρες από τη WIDE.ANGLE ταινία 
"χρόνος για το σχολείο" (2003) για να καταλάβουν την αίσθηση 
της επείγουσας ανάγκης που περιβάλλει αυτό το ζήτημα, τα πιθανά 
οφέλη που μπορούν να προκύψουν από την εκπαίδευση των κοριτσιών,
και τους τρόπους που οι τοπικές κοινότητες προσπαθούν να 
εξετάσουν αυτά τα προβλήματα. Σημείωση: Αυτό το 
μάθημα εστιάζει σε MDG 2 και MDG 3. Μια εισαγωγή στους 
γενικούς στόχους του προγράμματος χιλιετίας πρέπει να 
παρουσιαστεί πριν από αυτό το ιδιαίτερο μάθημα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Hoy, sobre 115 millones de niños nunca han fijado
el pie dentro de una escuela. El hecho es ése para los niños 
que viven en países en vías de desarrollo, el sueño de un primer 
día de la escuela debe todavía ser observado. Las realidades 
diarias de la pobreza, de la inestabilidad política, del conflicto 
regional, de la geografía, y de los valores culturales o 
tradicionales todos desempeñan un papel a los grados que varían -- y
la aplicación la disparidad del género hace este hecho que escalona.
La igualdad de acceso completa y a la educación (artículo 26) 
conforme al ' declaración universal de los derechos humanos y ' la 
convención sobre las derechas del niño ' (los artículos 2.3.28, y 
29), ha estado claramente fuera del alcance de niños pobres -- y más
tan en el caso de muchachas. Casi dos tercios de los niños que 
se niegan una educación primaria es muchachas. En los menos 
países desarrollados, tantas mujeres del adulto que hombres son casi 
dos veces analfabetas. (fuente: UNFPA 
http://www.unfpa.org/icpd/10/icpd_ed.htm) si usted sucede ser una 
hembra, usted es menos probable tener acceso a una educación primaria
de la calidad y más allá -- contribuyendo al feminization de la 
pobreza global. Todavía, hay esperanza a pesar de esta 
situación actual. 189 naciones han prometido para resolver 8 
metas importantes del desarrollo del milenio (MDGs) antes de 2015. 
En hacer así pues, las naciones esperan mejorar el desarrollo 
social y económico de toda la gente. Se incluyen en estas metas
los que tratan la educación y la disparidad del género: MDG 2:
Alcance la educación universal y primaria. MDG 3: 
Promueva la igualdad del género y autorice a mujeres. Con
las actividades contorneadas en esta lección, los estudiantes harán 
familiares con las barreras actuales que están paradas de la manera 
de la oportunidad educativa -- especialmente para las muchachas. 
Mirarán los clips de la película GRANANGULAR ' hora para la 
escuela ' (2003) de entender el sentido de la urgencia que rodea esta 
edición, las ventajas del potencial que puedan resultar de educar a 
muchachas, y las maneras que las comunidades locales están intentando
tratar estos problemas. Nota: Esta lección se centra en 
MDG 2 y MDG 3. Una introducción a las metas totales del 
proyecto del milenio se debe presentar antes de esta lección 
determinada.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:YOLANDA BETANCES
FN:YOLANDA BETANCES
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202966</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108284</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/girls-speak-out</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
