<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104742</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104742</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087375</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Almost Broken Spirits": Farmers in the New South</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Fast Gebrochener Geist": Landwirte im neuen
Süden</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Spiritueux Presque Cassés" : Fermiers dans
les nouveaux Sud</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Espíritos Quase Quebrados": Fazendeiros no
sul novo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Alcoolici Quasi Rotti": Coltivatori nel 
nuovo sud</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Σχεδόν σπασμένα πνεύματα": Αγρότες στο νέο 
νότο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Alcoholes Casi Rotos": Granjeros en el 
nuevo sur</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the decades following the Confederacy's 1865 defeat and the abolition of racial slavery, white southern landowners, entrepreneurs, and newspaper editors heralded the coming of a "New South" economic order. Freed from the plantation system, the South would enter the modern age, building factories to turn its cotton into cloth, its tobacco crop into finished cigars and cigarettes, and its growing coal and iron ore output into steel. But not all southerners benefited from a prosperous and industrialized New South. Mill workers, small farmers, and tenants and sharecroppers bore the brunt of the sacrifices required to build a new southern economy. These extracts from letters by tenants and farm laborers to the North Carolina Bureau of Labor Statistics in 1887 and 1889 described the depressed crop prices, usurious interest rates charged by landowners for seed and equipment, and the absence of decent schooling for children faced by southern agricultural workers.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In den Dekaden, die der der Niederlage und der 
Aufhebung Konföderation 1865 der rassischen Sklaverei folgen, 
kündigten weiße südliche Grundbesitzer, Unternehmer und 
Zeitungsverleger das Kommen einer "neuen Süd" ökonomischen Ordnung 
an. Freigegeben vom Plantagesystem, würde der Süden das 
moderne Alter eintragen und bauen würde Fabriken auf, um seine 
Baumwolle zu Tuch, sein Tabakgetreide in fertige Zigarren und in 
Zigaretten zu machen und seine wachsende Kohle und Eisenerz, das in 
Stahl ausgegeben wurde. Aber nicht alle southerners profitierten
von einem wohlhabenden und industrialisierten neuen Süden. 
Prägen Sie Arbeiter, kleine Landwirte und Pächter und 
sharecroppers Nervensäge das Hauptgewicht der Opfer, die benötigt 
werden, um eine neue südliche Wirtschaft aufzubauen. Diese 
Extrakte von den Zeichen durch Pächter und Landarbeiter zum 
Nord-Carolina Büro von Arbeitsstatistiken 1887 und 1889 beschrieben 
die niedergedrückten Getreidepreise, Wucherdie zinssätze, die von 
den Grundbesitzern für Startwert für Zufallsgenerator und 
Ausrüstung aufgeladen wurden, und das Fehlen annehmbarem Schulen für
die Kinder, die von den südlichen landwirtschaftlichen Arbeitern 
gegenübergestellt wurden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans les décennies suivant la défaite et 
l'abolition de la confédération 1865 de l'esclavage racial, les 
propriétaires fonciers, les entrepreneurs, et les éditeurs de 
journal méridionaux blancs ont annoncé venir d'un "nouvel" ordre 
économique du sud. Libéré du système de plantation, les
Sud écriraient l'âge moderne, construisant les usines pour 
transformer son coton en tissu, sa collecte de tabac dans les cigares 
et les cigarettes terminés, et son minerai croissant de charbon et de
fer sorti dans l'acier. Mais non tous les habitants du sud ont tiré
bénéfice nouveau d'un Sud prospère et industrialisé. 
Fraisez les ouvriers, les petits fermiers, et les locataires et 
le fâcheux de métayers le choc des sacrifices requis pour 
établir une nouvelle économie méridionale. Ces extraits des 
lettres par des locataires et des travailleurs de ferme au bureau 
du nord de la Caroline des statistiques de travail en 1887 et 1889
ont décrit les prix diminués de collecte, les taux d'intérêt 
d'intérêt usuraires chargés par des propriétaires fonciers pour la
graine et le matériel, et l'absence d'instruire décent pour des 
enfants faits face par les ouvriers agricoles méridionaux.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nas décadas que seguem a derrota e o abolition do
confederacy 1865 do slavery racial, os latifundiários, os 
empreendedores, e os editores de jornal do sul brancos heralded a 
vinda de uma ordem econômica "sul" nova. Livrado do sistema da 
plantação, o sul incorporaria a idade moderna, construindo fábricas
para girar seu algodão no pano, sua colheita do tabaco em charutos e 
em cigarros terminados, e seu minério crescente de carvão e de ferro
output no aço. Mas não todos os southerners beneficiaram-se de
um sul novo próspero e industrialized. Moa trabalhadores, 
fazendeiros pequenos, e tenants e furo dos sharecroppers o brunt dos 
sacrifícios requeridos para construir uma economia do sul nova. 
Estes extratos das letras por tenants e por laborers de fazenda 
ao departamento de North.carolina de statistics labor em 1887 e em 
1889 descreveram os preços comprimidos da colheita, as taxas de 
interesse usurious carregadas por latifundiários para a semente e o 
equipamento, e a ausência de educar decent para as crianças 
enfrentadas por trabalhadores agriculturais do sul.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nelle decadi che seguono la sconfitta e 
l'abolizione del confederacy 1865 di slavery razziale, i latifondisti,
gli imprenditori e gli editori di giornale del sud bianchi hanno 
annunziato venire "di nuovo" ordine economico del sud. Liberato 
dal sistema della piantagione, il sud entrerebbe nell'età moderna, 
costruente le fabbriche per trasformare nel relativo cotone il panno, 
il relativo raccolto del tabacco nei sigari e nelle sigarette rifiniti
ed il relativi carbone e minerale ferroso crescenti prodotto in 
acciaio. Ma non tutti i southerners hanno tratto beneficio nuovo
da un sud prosperoso ed industrializzato. Macini gli operai, i 
piccoli coltivatori e gli inquilini ed il foro di sharecroppers il 
brunt dei sacrifici richiesti per sviluppare una nuova economia del 
sud. Questi estratti dalle lettere dagli inquilini e dai 
lavoratori dell'azienda agricola all'ufficio del North.carolina delle 
statistiche Di lavoro in 1887 ed in 1889 hanno descritto i prezzi 
diminuiti del raccolto, i tassi di interesse usurari caricati dai 
latifondisti per il seme e l'apparecchiatura e l'assenza di istruzione
decent per i bambini affrontati dagli operai agricoli del sud.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στις δεκαετίες μετά από την ήττα 1865 της 
συνομοσπονδίας και την κατάργηση της φυλετικής σκλαβιάς, τα λευκά
νότια landowners, οι επιχειρηματίες, και οι επεξεργαστές 
εφημερίδων ανακοίνωσαν τον ερχομό μιας οικονομικής τάξης "νέου 
νότου". Ελευθερωμένος από το σύστημα φυτειών, ο νότος θα 
εισήγε τη σύγχρονη ηλικία, χτίζοντας τα εργοστάσια για να 
μετατρέψει το βαμβάκι του σε ύφασμα, τη συγκομιδή καπνών του στα 
τελειωμένα πούρα και τα τσιγάρα, και την έξοδο μεταλλεύματος 
άνθρακα και σιδήρου ανάπτυξής του στο χάλυβα. Αλλά δεν 
ωφελήθηκαν όλοι οι νότιοι από έναν ακμάζοντα και 
βιομηχανοποιημένο νέο νότο. Οι εργαζόμενοι μύλων, οι 
μικροί αγρότες, και οι μισθωτές και οι επίμορτοι καλλιεργητές 
άντεξαν την ορμή των θυσιών που απαιτήθηκαν για να χτίσουν μια 
νέα νότια οικονομία. Αυτά τα αποσπάσματα από τις 
επιστολές από τους μισθωτές και τα αγροτικά laborers στο 
γραφείο της βόρειας Καρολίνας των στατιστικών εργασίας το 1887
και το 1889 περιέγραψαν τις καταθλιπτικές τιμές συγκομιδών, τα 
usurious επιτόκια που χρεώθηκαν από τα landowners για το 
σπόρο και τον εξοπλισμό, και την απουσία κόσμιης εκπαίδευσης για 
τα παιδιά που αντιμετωπίστηκαν από τους νότιους γεωργικούς 
εργαζομένους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En las décadas que seguían la abolición del 
confederacy 1865 la derrota y de la esclavitud racial, los 
terratenientes, los empresarios, y los redactores meridionales blancos
anunciaron venir de una "nueva" orden económica del sur. 
Liberado del sistema de la plantación, el sur incorporaría la 
edad moderna, construyendo fábricas para dar vuelta a su algodón en 
el paño, su cosecha del tabaco en los cigarros y los cigarrillos 
acabados, y su mineral creciente del carbón y de hierro hecho salir 
en el acero. Pero no todos los southerners beneficiaron de un 
nuevo sur próspero e industrializado. Muela a los trabajadores,
a los granjeros pequeños, y a los arrendatarios y a alesaje de los 
sharecroppers la parte más recia de los sacrificios requeridos para 
construir una nueva economía meridional. Estos extractos de 
cartas de los arrendatarios y de los trabajadores de granja a la 
oficina de Carolina del Norte de la estadística de trabajo en 1887 y 
1889 describieron los precios presionados de la cosecha, los tipos de 
interés usurarios cargados por los terratenientes para el germen y el
equipo, y la ausencia de enseñar decente para los niños hechos 
frente por los trabajadores agrícolas meridionales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087375</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104742</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/almost-broken-spirits-farmers-in-the-new-south</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
