<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104919</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104919</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206536</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The New Genetics</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Neue Genetik</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Nouvelle Génétique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Genetics Novo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Nuova Genetica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η νέα γενετική</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Nueva Genética</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">explains the process by which all living things pass genes to their offspring. Discover how genes serve as instruction books for making molecules (such as RNA and proteins) that perform the chemical reactions in our bodies. Learn how genes influence health and disease. Find out how studies of evolution drive medical research and how computers are advancing genetics in the 21st century.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erklärt den Prozeß, durch den alle lebenden 
Sachen ihrem Sekundärteilchen Gene führen. Entdecken Sie, wie 
Gene als Anweisung Bücher für das Bilden der Moleküle dienen (wie 
RNS und Proteine) die die chemischen Reaktionen in unseren Körpern 
durchführen. Erlernen Sie, wie Gene Gesundheit und Krankheit 
beeinflussen. Finden Sie heraus, wie Studien der Entwicklung 
medizinische Forschung antreiben und wie Computer Genetik im 21. 
Jahrhundert vorrücken.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">explique le processus par lequel toutes les choses
vivantes passent des gènes à leur progéniture. Découvrez 
comment les gènes servent de livres d'instruction à faire les 
molécules (telles que l'ARN et les protéines) qui exécutent les 
réactions chimiques dans nos corps. Apprenez comment les gènes
influencent la santé et la maladie. Découvrez comment les 
études de l'évolution pilotent la recherche médicale et comment les
ordinateurs avancent la génétique au 21ème siècle.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">explica o processo por que todas as coisas vivas 
passam genes a sua prole. Descubra como os genes servem como 
livros da instrução para fazer as moléculas (tais como o RNA e as 
proteínas) que executam as reações químicas em nossos corpos. 
Aprenda como os genes influenciam a saúde e a doença. 
Encontre para fora como os estudos da evolução dirigem a 
pesquisa médica e como os computadores estão avançando o genetics 
no século XXI.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">spiega il processo tramite cui tutte le cose 
viventi passano i geni alla loro prole. Scopra come i geni 
servono da libri di istruzione per fare le molecole (quali RNA e 
proteine) che effettuano le reazioni chimiche nei nostri corpi. 
Impari come i geni influenzano la salute e la malattia. 
Scopra come gli studi su sviluppo guidano la ricerca medica e 
come i calcolatori stanno avanzando la genetica nel ventunesimo 
secolo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξηγεί τη διαδικασία από την οποία όλα τα πράγματα 
διαβίωσης περνούν τα γονίδια στον απόγονό τους. Ανακαλύψτε
πώς τα γονίδια χρησιμεύουν ως τα βιβλία οδηγίας για την παραγωγή
των μορίων (όπως το RNA και οι πρωτεϊ'νες) που εκτελούν τις 
χημικές αντιδράσεις στους οργανισμούς μας. Μάθετε πώς τα 
γονίδια επηρεάζουν την υγεία και την ασθένεια. Ανακαλύψτε 
πώς οι μελέτες της εξέλιξης οδηγούν την ιατρική έρευνα και πώς 
οι υπολογιστές προωθούν τη γενετική στο 21$ο αιώνα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">explica el proceso por el cual todas las cosas 
vivas pasan genes a su descendiente. Descubra cómo los genes 
sirven como libros de la instrucción para hacer las moléculas (tales
como RNA y proteínas) que realizan las reacciones químicas en 
nuestros cuerpos. Aprenda cómo los genes influencian salud y 
enfermedad. Descubra cómo los estudios de la evolución 
conducen la investigación médica y cómo los ordenadores están 
avanzando genética en el siglo XXI.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206536</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104919</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-new-genetics</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
