<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107320</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107320</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087427</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Belles of the Ball Game": Women's Professional Baseball League Thrives in the 1940s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Schönheiten des Kugel-Spiels": Kommt 
professionelle Baseball-Liga der Frauen in den vierziger Jahren 
vorwärts</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"belles du jeu de boule" : La ligue de 
base-ball professionnelle des femmes prospère dans les années 40</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"belles do jogo da esfera": A liga de 
baseball profissional das mulheres prospera nos 1940s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"belles del gioco della sfera": La lega di 
baseball professionale delle donne prospera nei 1940s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Belles του παιχνιδιού σφαιρών": Η ένωση 
επαγγελματιών μπέιζ-μπώλ των γυναικών αναπτύσσεται στη δεκαετία 
του '40</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"belles del juego de la bola": La liga de 
béisbol profesional de las mujeres prospera en los años 40</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The All-American Girls' Professional Baseball League lasted from 1943 to 1954. During its peak attendance year, the League attracted close to a million fans--three of whom wrote letters, included below, to correct factual misrepresentations about the objects of their affection printed in the following Collier's article. The League inspired a hit motion picture of 1992 (A League of Their Own) and continues to hold interest for many, as demonstrated by numerous websites featuring leading players. Formed during World War II when major league owners feared that the military draft might lead to suspension of play, the All-American League thrived. In the early 1950s, however, it reproduced a pattern found elsewhere in American society: women encouraged to fill jobs (previously open only to men) during the war years faced restrictions as traditional norms were reestablished. The following look at the League from the perspective of its "harried" male managers, however, offers only minimal insight into the reasons for such high ticket sales and the devotion of fans cheering players who challenged the gender barriers of their day.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die All-Amerikanischen professionelle 
Baseball-Liga der Mädchen dauerte von 1943 bis 1954. Während 
seines Höchstanwesenheit Jahres die Liga angezogen nah an Million 
Ventilatoren -- drei von wem schrieben Briefe, eingeschlossen unter, 
zu den korrekten auf Tatsachen beruhenden Misrepresentations über die
Nachrichten ihrer Neigung gedruckt im folgenden Artikel des Colliers. 
Die Liga spornte an, Bewegung Abbildung von 1992 zu schlagen 
(eine Liga von ihren Selbst) und fährt fort, Interesse für viele 
anzuhalten, wie durch die zahlreichen Web site gezeigt, die führende 
Spieler kennzeichnen. Gebildet während des Zweiten Weltkrieges,
als Hauptligainhaber fürchteten, daß der militärische Entwurf zu 
Aufhebung des Spiels führen konnte, kam die All-Amerikanische Liga 
vorwärts. In den frühen fünfziger Jahren jedoch reproduzierte
es ein Muster, das anderwohin in der amerikanischen Gesellschaft 
gefunden wurde: die Frauen, die angeregt wurden, Jobs (öffnen 
Sie nur vorher sich zu den Männern), während der Kriegsjahre zu 
füllen stellten Beschränkungen gegenüber, während traditionelle 
Normen wieder hergestellt wurden. Der folgende Blick auf die 
Liga von der Perspektive von seinem "bedrängte" die männlichen 
Manager, jedoch, minimalen Einblick der Angebote nur in die Gründe 
für solche hohe Karte Verkäufe und die Hingabe der Ventilatoren 
Spielern zujubelnd, die die Geschlechtsperren ihres Tages 
herausforderten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La ligue de base-ball professionnelle des filles 
Tout-Américaines a duré de 1943 à 1954. Pendant sa année 
maximale de assistance, la ligue attirée près d'million de 
ventilateurs -- trois de qui ont écrit des lettres, inclus 
ci-dessous, aux fausses déclarations effectives correctes au sujet 
des objets de leur affection imprimés dans l'article suivant de 
Collier. La ligue a inspiré pour frapper le film 
cinématographique de 1992 (une ligue de leurs propres) et continue à
tenir l'intérêt pour beaucoup, comme démontré par de nombreux 
sites Web comportant de principaux joueurs. Formé pendant la 
deuxième guerre mondiale quand les propriétaires principaux de ligue
ont craint que l'ébauche militaire pourrait mener à la suspension du
jeu, la ligue Tout-Américaine a prospéré. Au début des 
années 50, cependant, il a reproduit une configuration trouvée 
ailleurs dans la société américaine : les femmes encouragées
à remplir travaux (ouvrez-vous précédemment seulement aux hommes) 
pendant les années de guerre ont fait face à des restrictions 
pendant que des normes traditionnelles étaient rétablies. Le 
regard suivant à la ligue de la perspective du son "a dévasté" les 
gestionnaires mâles, cependant, l'perspicacité minimale d'offres 
seulement dans les raisons en de telles ventes élevées de billet et 
la dévotion des ventilateurs encourageant les joueurs qui ont défié
les barrières de genre de leur jour.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A liga de baseball profissional das meninas 
Todo-Americanas durou  1943 a 1954. Durante seu ano peak do 
comparecimento, a liga atraída perto de milhão ventiladores -- três
de quem escreveram letras, incluído abaixo, aos misrepresentations 
factual corretos sobre os objetos de sua afeição impressos no artigo
do seguinte collier. A liga inspirou para bater um retrato de 
movimento de 1992 (uma liga do seus próprios) e continua a prender o 
interesse para muitos, como demonstrado pelos Web site numerosos que 
caracterizam jogadores principais. Dado forma durante a segunda 
guerra mundial quando os proprietários principais da liga temeram que
o esboço militar pôde conduzir à suspensão do jogo, a liga 
Todo-Americana prosperou. Nos 1950s adiantados, entretanto, 
reproduziu um teste padrão encontrado em outra parte na sociedade 
americana: as mulheres incentivadas encher trabalhos (abra 
previamente somente aos homens) durante os anos de guerra enfrentaram 
limitações enquanto as normas tradicionais reestablished. O 
seguinte olhar na liga do perspective do seu "harried" os gerentes 
masculinos, entretanto, a introspecção mínima das ofertas somente 
nas razões para tais vendas elevadas do bilhete e a devoção dos 
ventiladores cheering os jogadores que desafiaram as barreiras do 
gender de seu dia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La lega di baseball professionale delle ragazze 
Tutto-Americane ha durato 1943 - 1954. Durante il relativo anno 
peak di presenza, la lega attratta vicino ad milione ventilatori -- 
tre di chi hanno scritto le lettere, incluso sotto, alle dichiarazioni
false effettive corrette circa gli oggetti del loro affetto stampati 
nell'articolo del seguente collier. La lega ha ispirato per 
colpire un cinema di 1992 (una lega dei loro propri) e continua a 
tenere l'interesse per molti, come dimostrato dai Web site numerosi 
che caratterizzano i giocatori principali. Formato durante la 
seconda guerra mondiale quando i proprietari importanti della lega 
hanno temuto che la brutta copia militare potrebbe condurre alla 
sospensione di gioco, la lega Tutto-Americana ha prosperato. 
Nell'inizio degli anni cinquanta, tuttavia, ha riprodotto un 
modello trovato altrove nella società americana: le donne 
consigliate a riempire i lavori (precedentemente aprasi soltanto agli 
uomini) durante gli anni di guerra hanno affrontato le limitazioni 
mentre le norme tradizionali sono state ristabilite. Il seguente
sguardo alla lega dalla prospettiva del relativo "harried" i gestori 
maschii, tuttavia, la comprensione minima di offerte soltanto nei 
motivi per tali alte vendite del biglietto e la devozione dei 
ventilatori incoraggianti i giocatori che hanno sfidato le barriere di
genere del loro giorno.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ένωση επαγγελματιών μπέιζ-μπώλ των 
όλος-αμερικανικών κοριτσιών διάρκεσε από το 1943 σε 1954, 
Κατά τη διάρκεια του μέγιστου έτους συμμετοχής του, η 
ένωση που προσελκύεται κοντά σε εκατομμύριο ανεμιστήρες -- τρεις 
από οποίος έγραψε τις επιστολές, περιέλαβαν κατωτέρω, για να 
διορθώσουν τις πραγματικές διαστρευλώσεις για τα αντικείμενα της 
αγάπης τους που τυπώθηκε στο άρθρο του ακόλουθου ανθρακωρύχου. 
Η ένωση ενέπνευσε μια ταινία χτυπήματος του 1992 (μια 
δική τους ένωση) και συνεχίζει να κρατά το ενδιαφέρον για 
πολλούς, όπως καταδεικνύονται από τους πολυάριθμους ιστοχώρους 
που χαρακτηρίζουν τους κορυφαίους φορείς. Διαμορφωμένος 
κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ όταν αναπτύχτηκαν 
σημαντικοί ιδιοκτήτες ένωσης φοβισμένοι που το στρατιωτικό 
σχέδιο να οδηγήσει στην αναστολή του παιχνιδιού, η 
όλος-αμερικανική ένωση. Στις αρχές της δεκαετίας του '50, 
εντούτοις, αναπαρήγαγε ένα πρότυπο που βρέθηκε αλλού στην 
αμερικανική κοινωνία: οι γυναίκες που ενθαρρύνθηκαν για να 
γεμίσουν τις εργασίες (προηγουμένως ανοίξτε μόνο στους άνδρες) 
κατά τη διάρκεια των πολεμικών ετών αντιμετώπισαν τους 
περιορισμούς όπως οι παραδοσιακοί κανόνες επανεγκαθιδρύθηκαν. 
Το ακόλουθο βλέμμα στην ένωση από την προοπτική του του "" 
οι αρσενικοί διευθυντές, εντούτοις, η ελάχιστη διορατικότητα 
προσφορών μόνο στους λόγους για τέτοιες υψηλές πωλήσεις 
εισιτηρίων και η αφοσίωση των ενθαρρυντικών φορέων ανεμιστήρων 
που προκάλεσαν τα εμπόδια γένους της ημέρας τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La liga de béisbol profesional de las muchachas 
Todo-Americanas duró a partir la 1943 a 1954. Durante su año 
máximo de la atención, la liga atraída cerca de millón de 
ventiladores -- tres de quién escribieron letras, incluido debajo, a 
las malas representaciones efectivas correctas sobre los objetos de su
afecto impresos en el artículo del collier siguiente. La liga 
inspiró para golpear la película de 1992 (una liga sus el propios) y
continúa llevando a cabo el interés para muchos, según lo 
demostrado por los Web site numerosos que ofrecían a jugadores 
principales. Formado durante la Segunda Guerra Mundial cuando 
los propietarios importantes de la liga temieron que el bosquejo 
militar pudo conducir a la suspensión del juego, la liga 
Todo-Americana prosperó. En los comienzos de los años 50, sin 
embargo, reprodujo un modelo encontrado a otra parte en sociedad 
americana: alentadores a las mujeres que llenen trabajos 
(ábrase previamente solamente en los hombres) durante los años de 
guerra hicieron frente a restricciones mientras que las normas 
tradicionales fueron restablecidas. La mirada siguiente en la 
liga de la perspectiva de su "harried" los encargados masculinos, sin 
embargo, la penetración mínima de las ofertas solamente en las 
razones de tales altas ventas del boleto y la dedicación de 
ventiladores animando a los jugadores que desafiaron las barreras del 
género de su día.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087427</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107320</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/belles-of-the-ball-game-womens-professional-baseball-league-thrives-in-the-1940s</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
