<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106421</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106421</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086131</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Everybody Seems to Feel Obliged to Acquire a Tan"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"jeder scheint fühlen geverpflichtet, eine 
Säurenummer zu erwerben"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"tout le monde semble au sentir obligé de saisir 
Tan"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"todos parece à sensação obrigado adquirir um 
Tan"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"ognuno sembra al sentire acquistare un Tan"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Καθένας φαίνεται να αισθάνεται υποχρεωμένος για να 
αποκτήσει ένα μαύρισμα"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"todos se parece a la sensación obligada a 
adquirir un Tan"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Before the general public began to understand the health dangers of sunlight overexposure, a fair number of white Americans devoted much time and effort to acquiring a "perfect tan." The suntan craze began in the mid-1920s, as outdoor recreation became more popular among middle-class Americans. Marketers also promoted the practice--once convinced that suntanning was not just a fad--with products designed to assist the quest to be tan. The following 1949 editorial from the popular magazine  Collier's  offers a tongue-in-cheek critique of tanning, calling attention to peer group pressures of social conformity and competitiveness inherent in tanning rituals. Absent from the piece is any consideration of the racial aspects of such a practice, centered on darkening the color of one's skin, and performed, as it was, in a multiethnic, but white-dominated society.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bevor die Öffentlichkeit anfing, die Gesundheit 
Gefahren der Tageslichtüberbelichtung zu verstehen, widmete sich eine
angemessene Anzahl von weißen Amerikanern viel Zeit und Bemühung zum
Erwerben "vervollkommnen Säurenummer." Der Suntanverrücktheit 
fing in den Mid-1920s an, während im Freienerholung unter 
Mittelklasseamerikanern populärer wurde. Marketingspezialisten 
förderten auch die Praxis -- einmal überzeugt, daß suntanning nicht
ein Fad gerecht war -- wenn die Produkte gekonzipiert sind, um die 
Suche zu unterstützen, um Säurenummer zu sein. Der folgende 
Leitartikel 1949 von den populären Angeboten des Zeitschrift Colliers
eine Zunge-in-Backe Kritik des Bräunens, Aufmerksamkeit auf 
Gleichgruppe Druck der Sozialübereinstimmung und der 
Wettbewerbsfähigkeit lenkend zugehörig in bräunenden Ritualen. 
Vom Stück ist jede mögliche Erwägung der rassischen Aspekte 
solch einer Praxis abwesend, zentriert auf dem Verdunkeln der Farbe 
von irgendjemandes Haut, und durchgeführt, wie sie, in einer 
multiethnischen, aber weiß-vorherrsch Gesellschaft war.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Avant que le grand public ait commencé à 
comprendre les dangers de santé de la surexposition de lumière du 
soleil, un nombre juste d'Américains blancs a consacré beaucoup 
d'heure et d'effort à saisir "un bronzage parfait." La manie 
de bronzage a commencé au milieu des années 20, pendant que la 
récréation extérieure devenait plus populaire parmi des Américains
de classe moyen. Les acheteurs ont également favorisé la 
pratique -- une fois convaincue que le bronzage n'était pas 
simplement une manie -- les produits étant conçu pour aider la 
recherche pour être bronzage. L'éditorial 1949 suivant des 
offres populaires de Collier de magasin une critique de 
langue-dans-joue du bronzage, attirant l'attention sur des pressions 
de groupe de pair de la conformité sociale et de la compétitivité 
inhérentes aux rituels de bronzage. Absente du morceau est 
n'importe quelle considération des aspects raciaux d'une telle 
pratique, portés sur obscurcir la couleur de sa peau, et exécutés, 
comme elle était, dans une société multi-ethnique, mais 
blanc-dominée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Antes que o público geral começou a compreender 
os perigos de saúde da sobreexposição da luz solar, um número 
justo dos americanos brancos devotou muita hora e o esforço a 
adquirir "aperfeiçoa o tan." A mania do suntan começou nos 
mid-1920s, enquanto a recreação ao ar livre se tornou mais popular 
entre americanos do middle-class. Os comerciantes promoveram 
também a prática -- convencida uma vez que suntanning não era justo
um fad -- com os produtos projetados ajudar ao quest a ser tan. 
O seguinte editorial 1949 das ofertas do collier popular do 
compartimento uma crítica do lingüeta-em-mordente de tanning, 
chamando a atenção às pressões do grupo do par do conformity 
social e do competitiveness inerentes em rituals tanning. 
Ausente da parte é toda a consideração dos aspectos raciais 
de tal prática, centrados em escurecer a cor de one's pele, e 
executados, como estava, em uma sociedade multiethnic, mas 
branco-dominada.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Prima che il grande pubblico cominci a capire i 
pericoli per la salute di sovresposizione di luce solare, un numero 
giusto di Americani bianchi ha dedicato molto tempo e lo sforzo 
all'acquisizione "perfeziona il tan." La mania di suntan ha 
cominciato nei mid-1920s, mentre la ricreazione esterna è diventato 
più popolare fra gli Americani della classe media. I marketers 
egualmente hanno promosso la pratica -- convinta una volta che 
suntanning non era giusto un fad -- con i prodotti destinati per 
aiutare la ricerca per essere tan. Il seguente editoriale 1949 
dalle offerte del collier popolare dello scomparto una valutazione 
della linguetta-in-guancica di abbronzatura, chiamante attenzione alle
pressioni del gruppo del pari di conformità sociale e di 
competitività inerenti ai rituali d'abbronzatura. Assente dalla
parte è tutta la considerazione delle funzioni razziali di una tal 
pratica, concentrate sullo scurire il colore della sua pelle ed 
effettuate, come era, in una società multiethnic, ma bianco-dominata.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Προτού να αρχίσει να καταλαβαίνει το ευρύ κοινό τους 
κινδύνους υγείας της υπερέκθεσης φωτός του ήλιου, ένας δίκαιος 
αριθμός λευκών Αμερικανών αφιέρωσε πολλούς χρόνο και προσπάθεια
στην απόκτηση ενός "τέλειου μαυρίσματος." Η suntan τρέλα
άρχισε στα μέσα τησδεκαετίας του '20, καθώς η υπαίθρια αναψυχή 
έγινε δημοφιλέστερη μεταξύ της μεσαίας τάξης Αμερικανοί. 
Οι έμποροι προώθησαν επίσης την πρακτική -- μιά φορά 
έπεισε ότι ήταν όχι μόνο μια μανία -- με τα προϊόντα με σκοπό
να βοηθήσουν την αναζήτηση για να είναι μαύρισμα. Το 
ακόλουθο κύριο άρθρο του 1949 από τις προσφορές του 
δημοφιλούς ανθρακωρύχου περιοδικών μια κριτική 
γλώσσα-$$$-ΜΑΓΟΥΛΩΝ του μαυρίσματος, που στρέφει την προσοχή για 
να κοιτάξει αδιάκριτα τις πιέσεις ομάδας της κοινωνικών 
συμμόρφωσης και της ανταγωνιστικότητας έμφυτων στα τελετουργικά 
μαυρίσματος. Απών από το κομμάτι είναι οποιαδήποτε 
εκτίμηση των φυλετικών πτυχών μιας τέτοιας πρακτικής, που 
κεντροθετούνται να σκουραίνει το χρώμα του δέρματός κάποιου, και
διενεργηθεισών, δεδομένου ότι ήταν, σε μια multiethnic, αλλά 
άσπρος-εξουσιασμένη κοινωνία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Antes de que el público en general comenzara a 
entender los peligros de salud de la sobreexposición de la luz del 
sol, un número justo de los americanos blancos dedicó mucha hora y 
el esfuerzo a adquirir "perfecciona el tan." La manía del 
bronceado comenzó en los mediados de los años veinte, mientras que 
la reconstrucción al aire libre llegó a ser más popular entre 
americanos de la clase media. Los vendedores también 
promovieron la práctica -- convencida una vez que el broncear no era 
justo un capricho -- con los productos diseñados para asistir a la 
búsqueda para ser tan. El editorial siguiente 1949 de las 
ofertas del collier popular del compartimiento una crítica de la 
lengu!eta-en-mejilla de broncear, llamando la atención a las 
presiones del grupo del par de la conformidad social y de la 
competitividad inherentes en rituales que broncean. Ausente del 
pedazo está cualquier consideración de los aspectos raciales de tal 
práctica, centrados en obscurecer el color de su piel, y realizados, 
como estaba, en una sociedad multiethnic, pero blanco-dominada.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086131</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106421</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/everybody-seems-to-feel-obliged-to-acquire-a-tan</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
