<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102865</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102865</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086173</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Fractured Fairy Tale: Meet  Little Rosebud's Lovers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zerbrochene Fairy Geschichte: Treffen 
Geliebte Wenigen Rosebuds</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Conte de fées Rompu : Les Petits Amoureux 
De Rosebud de Rassemblement</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Tale Fairy Fraturado: Reunião Amantes De 
Pouco Rosebud</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Racconto Fairy Fratturato: Raduno 
Amanti Di Poco Rosebud</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σπασμένη ιστορία νεράιδων: Συναντήστε τους 
εραστές λίγου μπουμπουκιού τριαντάφυλλου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cuento De hadas Fracturado: Reunión Amantes
De Poco Rosebud</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Little Rosebud's Lovers  was written in 1886 by Laura Jean Libbey, a popular author of popular fiction. Between 1882 and 1902, she wrote more than 50 different serials for the story papers. She was particularly known for placing working-girl heroines within sensational and melodramatic plots. In this selection, the first chapter of  Little Rosebud's Lovers , the heroine finds herself the unwitting object of desire of a wealthy Bostonian. The selection ends on a note of foreboding--in subsequent chapters Little Rosebud becomes homeless and impoverished before her inevitable redemption. What did women workers take away from their reading of the novels of Libbey and others? Historian Michael Denning has speculated that these stories were "an interruption in the present, a magical fairy tale transformation of familiar landscapes and characters, a death and rebirth that turned the social world upside down, making proud ladies [into] villains, and working-girls [into] ladies."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geliebte wenigen Rosebuds wurden 1886 von Laura 
Jean Libbey, ein populärer Autor der populären Erfindung 
geschrieben. Zwischen 1882 und 1902 schrieb sie mehr als 50 
unterschiedliche Serien für die Geschichtepapiere. Sie bekannt 
besonders für das Plazieren der Arbeitenmädchen Heldinnen innerhalb 
des sensational und der melodramatischen Plots. In dieser 
Auswahl findet sich das erste Kapitel von Geliebten wenigen Rosebuds, 
die Heldin die unwitting Nachricht des Wunsches von einem wohlhabenden
Bostonian. Die Auswahl beendet auf einer Anmerkung der Vorahnung
-- in den folgenden Kapiteln wird wenig Rosebud heimatlos und vor 
ihrer unvermeidlichen Abzahlung verarmt. Was nahmen Frauarbeiter
von ihrem Messwert der Romane von Libbey und von anderen weg? 
Historiker Michael Denning hat spekuliert, daß diese 
Geschichten "eine Unterbrechung im Geschenk, eine magische 
Transformation der fairy Geschichte der vertrauten Landschaften und 
der Zeichen, ein Tod und Wiedergeburt waren, die die 
Sozialweltoberseite unten drehten und stolze Damen [ in ] Schufte 
bildeten, und Arbeitenmädchen [ in ] Damen."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les petits amoureux de Rosebud ont été 
écrits en 1886 par Laura Jean Libbey, un auteur populaire de la 
fiction populaire. Entre 1882 et 1902, elle a écrit plus de 50 
publications périodiques différentes pour les papiers d'histoire. 
Elle a été en particulier connue pour placer des héroïnes de
travailler-fille dans les traçages sensationnels et mélodramatiques. 
Dans cette sélection, le premier chapitre des petits amoureux 
de Rosebud, la héroïne se trouve l'objet inconscient du désir 
d'un Bostonian riche. La sélection termine sur une note de 
pressentiment -- en chapitres ultérieurs petit Rosebud devient 
sans foyer et appauvri avant son rachat inévitable. Que les 
ouvrières de femmes ont-elles emporté de leur lecture des romans de 
Libbey et de d'autres ? L'historien Michael Denning a speculé 
que ces histoires étaient "une interruption dans le présent, une 
transformation magique de conte de fées des horizontaux et des 
caractères familiers, une mort et la renaissance qui ont tourné le 
monde social à l'envers, faisant aux dames fières [ dans ] des 
bandits, et aux dames de travailler-filles [ dans ]."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os amantes de pouco Rosebud foram escritos em 1886
por Laura Jean Libbey, um autor popular do fiction popular. 
Entre 1882 e 1902, escreveu mais de 50 séries diferentes para 
os papéis da história. Foi conhecida particularmente colocando
heroines da trabalh-menina dentro do sensational e dos lotes 
melodramatic. Nesta seleção, o primeiro capítulo de amantes 
de pouco Rosebud, o heroine encontra-se o objeto unwitting do desejo 
de um Bostonian rico. A seleção termina em uma nota do 
foreboding -- em capítulos subseqüentes pouco Rosebud torna-se 
desabrigado e impoverished antes de seu redemption inevitável. 
Que os trabalhadores das mulheres fizeram exame afastado de sua 
leitura das novelas de Libbey e de outro? O historian Michael 
Denning speculated que estas histórias eram "um interruption no 
presente, uma transformação mágica do tale fairy de paisagens e de 
caráteres familiares, uma morte e o rebirth que girassem o mundo 
social de cabeça para baixo, fazendo a senhoras orgulhosas [ em ] 
bandidos, e às senhoras das trabalh-meninas [ em ]."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Amanti di poco Rosebud sono stati scritti in 
1886 da Laura Jean Libbey, un autore popolare di romanzo popolare. 
Fra 1882 e 1902, ha scritto più di 50 pubblicazioni periodiche 
differenti per le carte da storia. È stata conosciuta 
specialmente per la disposizione dei heroines della funzion-ragazza 
all'interno del sensational e dei diagrammi melodramatic. In 
questa selezione, il primo capitolo degli Amanti di poco Rosebud,
il heroine si trova l'oggetto unwitting di desiderio di un Bostonian 
ricco. La selezione si conclude su una nota di foreboding -- in 
capitoli successivi poco Rosebud diventa senza casa ed impoverito 
prima della sua estinzione inevitabile. Che cosa gli operai 
delle donne hanno tolto dalla loro lettura dei romanzi di Libbey e di 
altri? Lo storico Michael Denning ha speculato che queste storia
erano "un'interruzione nel presente, una trasformazione magica di 
racconto fairy dei paesaggi e dei caratteri esperti, una morte e 
rebirth che hanno girato il mondo sociale inverso, rendendo a signore 
fiere [ in ] i furfanti ed alle signore delle funzion-ragazze [ in ]."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι εραστές λίγου μπουμπουκιού τριαντάφυλλου γράφτηκαν
το 1886 από τη Laura Jean Libbey, ένας δημοφιλής 
συντάκτης της δημοφιλούς μυθιστοριογραφίας. Μεταξύ 1882 
και 1902, έγραψε περισσότερες από 50 διαφορετικές παρουσιάσεις
σε συνέχειες για τα έγγραφα ιστορίας. Ήταν γνωστή 
ιδιαίτερα για την τοποθέτηση των ηρωϊ'δων εργάζομαι-κοριτσιών 
μέσα στις συγκλονιστικές και μελοδραματικές πλοκές. Σε 
αυτήν την επιλογή, το πρώτο κεφάλαιο των εραστών λίγου 
μπουμπουκιού τριαντάφυλλου, η ηρωϊ'δα βρίσκεται το χωρίς πρόθεση
αντικείμενο της επιθυμίας ενός πλούσιου Bostonian. Οι 
άκρες επιλογής σε μια σημείωση του προαισθήματος -- στα επόμενα 
κεφάλαια λίγο μπουμπούκι τριαντάφυλλου γίνεται άστεγο και πριν 
από την αναπόφευκτη εξαγορά της. Τι οι εργαζόμενοι γυναικών
πήραν μαζί από την ανάγνωσή τους των μυθιστορημάτων Libbey 
και άλλα; Ο ιστορικός michael Denning έχει σκεφτεί 
ότι αυτές οι ιστορίες ήταν "μια διακοπή στο παρόν, ένας 
μαγικός μετασχηματισμός ιστορίας νεράιδων των γνωστών τοπίων και
των χαρακτήρων, ένας θάνατος και μια αναγέννηση που γύρισαν τον 
κοινωνικό κόσμο ανάποδα, κάνοντας τους υπερήφανους γυναικείους 
[ ] κακοποιούς, και τις κυρίες εργάζομαι-κοριτσιών [ 
]."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Laura Jean Libbey, autor popular escribieron los 
amantes de poco Rosebud en 1886 de la ficción popular. Entre 
1882 y 1902, ella escribió más de 50 diversos cuentos por entregas 
para los papeles de la historia. La conocían determinado para 
colocar a heroínas de la trabajar-muchacha dentro del sensational y
de diagramas melodramatic. En esta selección, el primer 
capítulo de los amantes de poco Rosebud, la heroína se encuentra 
el objeto involuntario del deseo de un Bostonian rico. La 
selección termina en una nota del foreboding -- en capítulos 
subsecuentes poco Rosebud llega a ser sin hogar y empobrecido antes de
su rescate inevitable. ¿Qué los trabajadores de las mujeres 
quitaron de su lectura de las novelas de Libbey y de otros? El 
historiador Michael Denning ha especulado que estas historias eran 
"una interrupción en el presente, una transformación mágica del 
cuento de hadas de paisajes y de caracteres familiares, una muerte y 
el renacimiento que dieron vuelta al mundo social al revés, haciendo 
las señoras orgullosas [ en ] a bandidos, y las señoras de las 
trabajar-muchachas [ en ]."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086173</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102865</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/fractured-fairy-tale-meet-little-rosebuds-lovers</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
