<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104664</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104664</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087036</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Republic Is Imperiled": John L. Lewis Warns of Ignoring Laboring People</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Die Republik Wird" Gefährdet: John L. 
Lewis Warns des Ignorierens der bearbeitenleute</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"La République Est risquée" : John L. 
Lewis Warns d'ignorer les personnes travaillantes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"A República Imperiled": John L. Lewis 
Advertir de ignorar povos trabalhando</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"La Repubblica Imperiled": John L. Lewis 
Warns di ignorare la gente lavorante</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η Δημοκρατία τίθεται σε κίνδυνο": Θ*Ιοχν L. 
Lewis Warns της αδιαφορίας των εργαμένος ανθρώπων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"La República Imperiled": Juan L. Lewis 
Warns de no hacer caso de la gente que trabaja</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">John L. Lewis, President of the United Mine Workers of America, was instrumental in the organizing drive that transformed the coal fields in 1933. He had planned his campaign before the National Industrial Recovery Act (NRA) became law and even before President Franklin D. Roosevelt took office. (The National Industrial Recovery Act included a provision, section 7(a), that protected workers' right to organize.) In February 1933 (prior to the passage of the NRA), Lewis spoke passionately to the Senate Finance Committee about the need for action to protect workers. In his Senate testimony, Lewis called for emergency action, including allowing workers to unionize and replacing corporate autocracy with union democracy. He warned that if action was not forthcoming, the nation might face grave consequences and promoted unionization as the answer.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">John L. Lewis, Präsident der vereinigten Grube 
Arbeiter von Amerika, war im organisierenden Laufwerk instrumentell, 
das die Kohle auffängt 1933 umwandelte. Er hatte seine
Kampagne vor der nationalen industriellen Wiederanlauf-Tat (NRA) wurde
Gesetz und gleichmäßiges geplant, bevor Präsident Franklin D. 
Roosevelt Amt übernahm. (die nationale industrielle 
Wiederanlauf-Tat schloß eine Bestimmung, Kapitel 7(a) ein, das der 
Arbeiter schützte, die recht sind zu organisieren.) Im Februar 
1933 (vor dem Durchgang des NRA), sprach Lewis leidenschaftlich mit 
dem Senat-Finanzausschuß über die Notwendigkeit an der Tätigkeit, 
Arbeiter zu schützen. In seinem Senatzeugnis unionize Lewis, 
das Dringlichkeitstätigkeit, einschließlich das Erlauben der 
Arbeiter verlangt wird und das Ersetzen der korporativen Autokratie 
mit Anschlußdemokratie. Er warnte, daß, wenn Tätigkeit nicht 
bevorstehend war, die Nation ernste Konsequenzen und geförderten 
Unionization als die Antwort gegenüberstellen konnte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">John L. Lewis, président des mineurs unis de 
l'Amérique, était instrumental dans le lecteur d'organisation qui a 
transformé les bassins houillers en 1933. Il avait projeté sa 
campagne avant l'acte industriel national de reprise (NRA) est devenu 
loi et égal avant que le Président Franklin D. Roosevelt ait pris le
bureau. (la Loi industrielle nationale de reprise a inclus une 
disposition, la section 7(a), qui a protégé les ouvriers droits 
d'organiser.) En février 1933 (avant le passage du NRA), Lewis 
a parlé passionément au Comité de finances de sénat au sujet du 
besoin de l'action de protéger des ouvriers. Dans son 
témoignage de sénat, Lewis a nécessité des mesures d'urgence, y 
compris permettre à des ouvriers de se syndiquer et substituer
l'autocratie de corporation avec la démocratie des syndicats. 
Il a averti que si l'action n'était pas reçue, la nation 
pourrait faire face à des conséquences graves et à la 
syndicalisation favorisée comme réponse.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">John L. Lewis, presidente dos trabalhadores de 
mina unidos de América, era instrumental na movimentação 
organizando que transformou os campos de carvão em 1933. 
Planeou sua campanha antes do ato industrial nacional da 
recuperação (NRA) transformou-se lei e uniforme antes que o 
presidente Franklin D. Roosevelt fêz exame do escritório. (o 
ato industrial nacional da recuperação incluiu uma provisão, a 
seção 7(a), que protegeu os trabalhadores direitos para organizar.) 
Em fevereiro 1933 (antes da passagem do NRA), Lewis falou 
passionately ao comitê de finanças do senate sobre a necessidade 
para a ação proteger trabalhadores. Em seu testimony do 
senate, Lewis chamado para a ação de emergência, including permitir
trabalhadores unionize e substituir o autocracy incorporado com a 
democracia da união. Advertiu que se a ação não fosse 
forthcoming, a nação pôde enfrentar conseqüências graves e o 
unionization promovido como a resposta.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">John L. Lewis, presidente dei minatori uniti 
dell'America, era strumentale nell'azionamento d'organizzazione che ha
trasformato i bacini carboniferi in 1933. Aveva progettato la 
sua campagna prima della Legge industriale nazionale di recupero (NRA)
si è transformato in in legge ed in perfino prima che il presidente 
Franklin D. Roosevelt prendesse l'ufficio. (la Legge industriale
nazionale di recupero ha incluso una misura, la parte 7(a), che ha 
protetto gli operai di destra per organizzare.) Nel mese di 
febbraio del 1933 (prima del passaggio del NRA), Lewis ha parlato 
appassionato al comitato di finanza del senato della necessità per 
azione di proteggere gli operai. Nella sua testimonianza del 
senato, Lewis richiesto misure di sicurezza, compreso permettere gli 
operai unionize e la sostituzione del autocracy corporativo con la 
democrazia del sindacato. Ha avvertito che se l'azione non fosse
prossima, la nazione potrebbe affrontare le conseguenze gravi ed il 
unionization promosso come la risposta.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θ*Ιοχν L. Lewis, Πρόεδρος των ενωμένων 
εργαζομένων ορυχείου της Αμερικής, συνέβαλε στην κίνηση 
οργάνωσης που μετασχημάτισε τα πεδία άνθρακα το 1933. 
Είχε προγραμματίσει την εκστρατεία του προτού ο εθνικός 
βιομηχανικός νόμος αποκατάστασης (ΕΚΑ) να γίνει νόμος και ακόμη 
και προτού Πρόεδρος Franklin D. Roosevelt πήρε το 
γραφείο. (Ο εθνικός βιομηχανικός νόμος αποκατάστασης 
περιέλαβε μια διάταξη, παράγραφος 7 (α), η οποία προστάτευσε το 
δικαίωμα των εργαζομένων να οργανώσουν.) Τον Φεβρουάριο του 
1933 (πριν από τη μετάβαση της ΕΚΑ), Lewis μίλησε παθιασμένα
στην Επιτροπή χρηματοδότησης Συγκλήτου για την ανάγκη για την 
ενέργεια να προστατευθούν οι εργαζόμενοι. Στην κατάθεση 
Συγκλήτου του, Lewis απαίτησε την ενέργεια έκτακτης ανάγκης, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένης της άδειας των εργαζομένων για να οργανώσει σε
συνδικάτο και της αντικατάστασης της εταιρικής μονοκρατορίας με τη
δημοκρατία ένωσης. Προειδοποίησε ότι εάν η ενέργεια δεν 
ήταν προσεχής, το έθνος να αντιμετωπίσει τις σοβαρές συνέπειες 
και την προαχθείσα συνδικαλικοποίηση ως απάντηση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Juan L. Lewis, presidente de los trabajadores de 
mina unidos de América, era instrumental en el mecanismo impulsor de 
ordenación que transformó los campos del carbón en 1933. Él 
había planeado su campaña antes del acto industrial nacional de la 
recuperación (NRA) hizo ley y uniforme antes de que presidente 
Franklin D. Roosevelt tomara la oficina. (el acto industrial 
nacional de la recuperación incluyó una disposición, la sección 
7(a), que protegió a trabajadores derechos ordenar.) En febrero
de 1933 (antes del paso del NRA), Lewis habló apasionado al comité 
de finanzas del senado sobre la necesidad de la acción de proteger a 
trabajadores. En su testimonio del senado, Lewis llamado para 
las medidas de urgencia, incluyendo permitir a trabajadores unionize y
substituir autocracia corporativa por democracia de la unión. 
Él advirtió que si la acción no era próxima, la nación 
pudiera hacer frente a consecuencias graves y a la sindicalización 
promovida como la respuesta.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087036</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104664</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-republic-is-imperiled-john-l-lewis-warns-of-ignoring-laboring-people</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
