<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105019</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105019</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209864</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Ellipse definition and properties</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ellipsedefinition und -eigenschaften</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Définition et propriétés d'ellipse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Definição e propriedades do ellipse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Definizione e proprietà di ellisse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Καθορισμός και ιδιότητες έλλειψης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Definición y características de la elipse</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that show the definition and properties of an ellipse. The applet has a draggable point that shows that the sum of the distances to the foci is a constant. The web page also has links to other pages defining the various properties of an ellipse and to some ellipse constructions. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die die Definition und die Eigenschaften eines Ellipse 
zeigen. Der applet hat einen draggable Punkt, der zeigt, daß 
die Summe der Abstände zu den Foki eine Konstante ist. Die 
Webseite hat auch Links zu anderen Seiten, welche die verschiedenen 
Eigenschaften eines Ellipse definieren und zu etwas Ellipseaufbauten. 
Applet kann zum vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit einem 
Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. Nachgebrauch im 
Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von jedem möglichem web 
browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den benötigten LOGON 
wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Bestandteil des 
Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui montrent la définition et les propriétés d'une ellipse. 
L'applet a un point draggable qui prouve que la somme des 
distances aux foyers est une constante. La page Web a 
également des liens à d'autres pages définissant les diverses 
propriétés d'une ellipse et à quelques constructions d'ellipse. 
L'applet peut être agrandi à la taille de plein écran pour 
l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de classe. Le après 
utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant peut lui accéder 
encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la maison ou dans la 
bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion exigée. Cette 
ressource est un composant du projet interactif de manuel de la 
géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
mostrem a definição e as propriedades de um ellipse. O applet 
tem um ponto draggable que mostre que a soma das distâncias aos focos
é uma constante. O Web page tem também as ligações a outras 
páginas que definem as várias propriedades de um ellipse e a algumas
construções do ellipse. O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho 
de tela cheia para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. O 
depois de uso na sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez 
de todo o web browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de 
uma sessão requerido. Este recurso é um componente do projeto 
interativo do textbook da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
mostrano la definizione e le proprietà di un ellisse. Il applet
ha un punto draggable che indica che la somma delle distanze ai fuochi
è un costante. Il Web page egualmente ha collegamenti ad altre 
pagine che definiscono le varie proprietà di un ellisse e ad alcune 
costruzioni di ellisse. Il applet può essere ingrandito al 
formato di schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore dell'aula. La
post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può accederle ancora da tutto 
il web browser nel paese o nella libreria senza l'inizio attività 
richiesto. Questa risorsa è un componente del progetto 
interattivo del manuale della geometria di riferimento aperto di per 
la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
εμφανίζουν τον καθορισμό και ιδιότητες μιας έλλειψης. Το 
applet έχει ένα draggable σημείο που δείχνει ότι το ποσό 
των αποστάσεων στις εστιάσεις είναι μια σταθερά. 
Ιστοσελίδας έχει επίσης τις συνδέσεις με άλλες σελίδες 
καθορίζοντας τις διάφορες ιδιότητες μιας έλλειψης και σε μερικές 
κατασκευές έλλειψης. Το Applet μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο 
πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με έναν προβολέα τάξεων. 
Μετά από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει 
πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι
ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια εισόδου που απαιτείται. 
Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του 
ανοικτού προγράμματος εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math 
διαλογικού σε http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
muestran la definición y las características de una elipse. El
applet tiene una punta draggable que muestre que la suma de las 
distancias a los focos es una constante. El Web page también 
tiene conexiones a otras paginaciones que definen las varias 
características de una elipse y a algunas construcciones de la 
elipse. El applet se puede agrandar a la talla de la pantalla 
completa para el uso con un proyector de la sala de clase. El 
uso posterior en la sala de clase, estudiante puede tenerle acceso 
otra vez de cualquier web browser en el país o en la biblioteca sin 
la conexión requerida. Este recurso es un componente del 
proyecto interactivo del libro de textos de la geometría de la 
referencia abierta de la matemáticas en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209864</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105019</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/ellipse-definition-and-properties</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
