<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104591</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104591</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086300</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Was Able to Make My Voice Really Ring Out": The Women's Emergency Brigade in the Flint Sit-Down Strike</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ich konnte, meinen SprachRing aus wirklich zu 
bilden": Die Brigade Dringlichkeit der Frauen im Feuerstein 
Sitzen-Unten Schlag</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"je pouvais faire ma boucle de voix vraiment hors 
de" : La brigade du secours des femmes dans le silex 
Reposent-Vers le bas la grève</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"eu podia  fazer realmente meu anel da voz para 
fora de": O brigade da emergência das mulheres no flint 
Senta-Para baixo a batida</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"potevo fare il mio anello di voce realmente verso
l'esterno": La brigata di emergenza delle donne nel silice Siede
-Giù il colpo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"ήμουν σε θέση να κάνω το δαχτυλίδι φωνής μου 
πραγματικά έξω": Η ταξιαρχία έκτακτης ανάγκης των γυναικών
στην τσακμακόπετρα κάθομαι-κατεβάζει την απεργία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"podía hacer mi anillo de la voz realmente fuera 
de": La brigada de la emergencia de las mujeres en el pedernal 
Sienta -Abajo huelga</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Women's Emergency Brigade, which Genora Johnson Dollinger helped organize, saved the 1936 sit down strike at Flint, Michigan more than once. In this 1976 interview with Sherna Gluck, Dollinger recalls the famous "Battle of the Running Bulls" when police--bulls--tried to regain control of the GM plant by force. Dollinger and the other organizers of the Women's Emergency Brigade faced constant sexist attitudes in their efforts to win the strike, even as they demonstrated their determination to put their bodies and their families' well-being on the line. Sometimes this sexism took the form of an unwillingness to allow women to speak, sometimes it took gentler forms: Dollinger recalls how, in the heat of battle, a passing striker tipped his hat to her. In a key moment, Dollinger took a loudspeaker and persuaded women in the crowd to join the group in front of the plant. Overwhelmed, and afraid to shoot at women, the police abandoned their assault.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Brigade Dringlichkeit der Frauen, die Genora 
Johnson Dollinger, das geholfen wird zu organisieren, gesichert die 
1936, Schlag am Feuerstein hinsitzen, Michigan mehr als einmal. 
In diesem Interview 1976 mit Sherna Gluck, erinnert an Dollinger
die berühmte "Schlacht der laufenden Stiere" wenn die Polizei -- 
Stiere -- versucht, um Steuerung des GR. Betriebes wiederzugewinnen 
durch Kraft. Dollinger und die anderen Organisatoren der Brigade
Dringlichkeit der Frauen stellten konstante sexistische Haltung in 
ihren Bemühungen, den Schlag zu gewinnen gegenüber, selbst als sie 
ihre Ermittlung zeigten, um ihre Körper und Wohl ihrer Familien auf 
die Zeile zu setzen. Manchmal nahm dieses sexism die Gestalt 
einer Abneigung an, um Frauen zu erlauben zu sprechen, manchmal 
es annahm leichtere Gestalten: Dollinger Rückrufe, wie, in der 
Hitze der Schlacht, ein überschreitenes Schlaggerät seinen Hut zu 
ihr spitzte. In einem Schlüsselmoment nahm Dollinger einen 
Lautsprecher und überzeugte Frauen in der Masse, die Gruppe vor dem 
Betrieb zu verbinden. Überwältigt und ängstlich, auf Frauen 
zu schießen, verließ die Polizei ihren Angriff.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La brigade du secours des femmes, que Genora 
Johnson Dollinger aidé à organiser, économisé les 1936 la 
grève sur le tas au silex, le Michigan plus d'une fois. Dans 
cette entrevue 1976 avec Sherna Gluck, Dollinger rappelle la "bataille
célèbre des taureaux courants" quand police -- taureaux -- essayée 
pour regagner la commande de l'usine de GM par la force. 
Dollinger et les autres organisateurs de la brigade du secours 
des femmes ont fait face à des attitudes sexistes constantes dans 
leurs efforts de gagner la grève, même pendant qu'ils démontraient 
leur détermination pour mettre leurs corps et bien-être de leurs 
familles sur la ligne. Parfois ce sexism a pris la forme d'une 
réticence de permettre à des femmes de parler, parfois il a pris des
formes plus douces : Rappels de Dollinger comment, dans la 
chaleur de la bataille, une butée de dépassement a incliné son 
chapeau à elle. Dans un moment principal, Dollinger a pris un 
haut-parleur et a persuadé des femmes dans la foule de joindre le 
groupe devant l'usine. Accablée, et effrayé de tirer aux 
femmes, la police a abandonné leur assaut.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O brigade da emergência das mulheres, que Genora 
Johnson Dollinger ajudado organizar, conservado os 1936 senta para 
baixo a batida no flint, Michigan mais de uma vez. Nesta 
entrevista 1976 com Sherna Gluck, Dollinger recorda a "batalha famosa 
dos touros running" quando as polícias -- touros -- tentadas regain o
controle da planta do GM pela força. Dollinger e os outros 
organizers das atitudes sexist constantes enfrentadas brigade da 
emergência das mulheres em seus esforços ganhar a batida, mesmo 
enquanto demonstraram sua determinação para pôr seus corpos e bem 
estar das suas famílias sobre a linha. Às vezes este sexism 
fêz exame do formulário de um unwillingness permitir que as mulheres
falem, às vezes ele fêz exame de uns formulários mais delicados: 
Recordações de Dollinger como, no calor da batalha, um 
grevista de passagem lhe derrubou seu chapéu. Em um momento 
chave, Dollinger fêz exame de um loudspeaker e persuadiu mulheres na 
multidão juntar o grupo na frente da planta. Oprimidas, e 
receoso disparar em mulheres, as polícias abandonaram seu assalto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La brigata di emergenza delle donne, che Genora 
Johnson Dollinger contribuito ad organizzare, risparmiato i 1936 siede
giù il colpo a silice, il Michigan più di una volta. In questa
intervista 1976 con Sherna Gluck, Dollinger ricorda "la battaglia 
famosa dei tori correnti" quando polizia -- tori -- provata per 
riguadagnare il controllo della pianta di GM da forza. Dollinger
e gli altri organizzatori della brigata di emergenza delle donne hanno
affrontato gli atteggiamenti sexist costanti nei loro sforzi vincere 
il colpo, proprio mentre hanno dimostrato la loro determinazione per 
mettere i loro corpi ed il benessere delle loro famiglie sulla riga. 
A volte questo sexism ha preso la forma di un unwillingness 
permettere che le donne parlino, a volte esso ha preso le forme più 
delicate: Richiami di Dollinger come, nel calore della 
battaglia, un percussore passante ha capovolto il suo cappello a lei. 
In un momento chiave, Dollinger ha preso un altoparlante ed ha 
persuaso le donne nella folla di unire il gruppo davanti la pianta. 
Soprafata ed impaurito sparare alle donne, la polizia ha 
abbandonato il loro assalto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ταξιαρχία έκτακτης ανάγκης των γυναικών, που 
Genora Johnson Dollinger που ενισχύθηκε να οργανώσει, 
έσωσε σε το 1936 κάθεται την απεργία στην τσακμακόπετρα, 
Μίτσιγκαν περισσότερο από μία φορά. Σε αυτήν την 
συνέντευξη του 1976 με Sherna Gluck, Dollinger 
υπενθυμίζει τη διάσημη "μάχη των ταύρων τρεξίματοσ" όταν 
προσπάθησε η αστυνομία -- ταύροι -- να επανακτήσει τον έλεγχο των
εγκαταστάσεων της GM από τη δύναμη. _ Δολληνγερ και ο 
άλλος διοργανωτής ο γυναίκα ανάγκη ταξιαρχία αντιμετωπίζω 
σταθερός φυλετικός τοποθέτηση τους προσπάθεια να κερδίζω ο 
απεργία, ακόμη και όπως αυτός κατα:δεικνύω τους αποφασιστικότητα
να θέτω σε κίνδυνο τους οργανισμός και τους οικογένεια ευημερία ο
γραμμή. Μερικές φορές αυτό το sexism έλαβε τη μορφή 
μιας απροθυμίας να επιτραπούν οι γυναίκες για να μιλήσει, μερικές
φορές έλαβε τις ευγενέστερες μορφές: Το Dollinger 
υπενθυμίζει πώς, στη θερμότητα της μάχης, ένας περνώντας 
απεργός τοποθέτησε αιχμή στο καπέλο του σε την. Σε μια 
βασική στιγμή, Dollinger πήρε ένα μεγάφωνο και έπεισε τις 
γυναίκες στο πλήθος για να προσχωρήσει στην ομάδα μπροστά από 
τις εγκαταστάσεις. Συντριμμένη, και φοβισμένος να 
πυροβολήσει στις γυναίκες, η αστυνομία εγκατέλειψε την επίθεσή 
τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La brigada de la emergencia de las mujeres, que 
Genora Johnson Dollinger ayudado a ordenar, salvado los 1936 sienta 
abajo huelga en el pedernal, Michigan más de una vez. En esta 
entrevista 1976 con Sherna Gluck, Dollinger recuerda la "batalla 
famosa de los toros corrientes" cuando policía -- toros -- intentado 
para recuperar el control de la planta del GM por la fuerza. El 
Dollinger y los otros organizadores de las actitudes sexistas 
constantes hechas frente brigada de la emergencia de las mujeres en 
sus esfuerzos de ganar la huelga, incluso mientras que demostraron su 
determinación para poner sus cuerpos y el bienestar de sus familias 
en la línea. Este sexism tomó a veces la forma de una desgana 
de permitir que las mujeres hablen, él tomó a veces formas más 
apacibles: Memorias de Dollinger cómo, en el calor de la 
batalla, un huelguista que pasaba inclinó su sombrero a ella. 
En un momento dominante, Dollinger tomó un altavoz y persuadió
a mujeres en la muchedumbre ensamblar al grupo delante de la planta. 
Abrumado, y asustado tirar en las mujeres, el policía abandonó
su asalto.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086300</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104591</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-was-able-to-make-my-voice-really-ring-out-the-womens-emergency-brigade-in-the-flint-sit-down-strike</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
