<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105051</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105051</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206420</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Get It Straight: The Facts About Drugs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erhalten Sie Es Gerade: Die Tatsachen Über 
Drogen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Obtenez-La Droite : Les Faits Sur des 
Drogues</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Comece-o Reto: Os Fatos Sobre Drogas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ottengala Diritta: I Fatti Circa Le Droghe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τον πάρτε κατ' ευθείαν: Τα γεγονότα για τα 
φάρμακα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Consígalo Recto: Los Hechos Sobre Las 
Drogas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is an online prevention book written by kids for kids. It features information about controlled substances and intoxicants, and their effects. The book is helpful as a research tool for classroom assignments, and is also fun to read and share with friends. There are questions, activities, and role playing scenarios.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist ein Onlineverhinderungbuch, das von den 
Zicklein für Zicklein geschrieben wird. Es kennzeichnet 
Informationen über kontrollierte Substanzen und Rauschmittel und ihre
Effekte. Das Buch ist als Forschung Hilfsmittel für 
Klassenzimmeranweisungen nützlich und ist auch zu teilen der Spaß, 
zum mit Freunden zu lesen und. Es gibt Fragen, Aktivitäten und 
die Rolle, die Drehbücher spielt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est un livre en ligne d'empêchement écrit par 
des gosses pour des gosses. Il comporte des informations sur les
substances et les intoxicants commandés, et leurs effets. Le 
livre est utile comme outil de recherches pour des affectations de 
salle de classe, et est également amusement à lire et partager avec 
des amis. Il y a des questions, des activités, et rôle jouant 
des scénarios.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é um livro em linha da prevenção escrito por 
miúdos para miúdos. Caracteriza a informação sobre 
substâncias e intoxicants controlados, e os seus efeitos. O 
livro é útil como uma ferramenta da pesquisa para atribuições da 
sala de aula, e é também divertimento a ler e compartilhar com os 
amigos. Há umas perguntas, umas atividades, e um papel que joga
scenarios.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è un libro in linea di prevenzione scritto dai 
capretti per i capretti. Caratterizza le informazioni sulle 
sostanze e sugli intossicanti controllati ed i loro effetti. Il 
libro è utile come strumento di ricerca per le assegnazioni dell'aula
ed è egualmente divertimento da leggere e ripartirsi con gli amici. 
Ci è domande, attività e ruolo che gioca i piani d'azione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι ένα σε απευθείας σύνδεση βιβλίο πρόληψης που 
γράφεται από τα κατσίκια για τα κατσίκια. Χαρακτηρίζει τις 
πληροφορίες για τις ελεγχόμενα ουσίες και τα οινοπνευματώδη ποτά,
και τα αποτελέσματά τους. Το βιβλίο είναι χρήσιμο ως 
ερευνητικό εργαλείο για τις αναθέσεις τάξεων, και είναι επίσης 
διασκέδαση που διαβάζουν και μερίδιο με τους φίλους. 
Υπάρχουν ερωτήσεις, δραστηριότητες, και παίζοντας σενάρια 
ρόλου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es un libro en línea de la prevención escrito 
por los cabritos para los cabritos. Ofrece la información sobre
sustancias y productos tóxicos controlados, y sus efectos. El 
libro es provechoso como herramienta de la investigación para las 
asignaciones de la sala de clase, y es también diversión a leer y a 
compartir con los amigos. Hay preguntas, actividades, y papel 
que juega decorados.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206420</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105051</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/get-it-straight-the-facts-about-drugs</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
