<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104145</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104145</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211261</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">National Park Service - Park Geology</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nationalpark-Service - Park-Geologie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Service de Parc National - Géologie de Parc</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Serviço Do Parque Nacional - Geologia Do Parque</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Servizio Del Parco Nazionale - Geologia Del 
Parco</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εθνική υπηρεσία πάρκων - γεωλογία πάρκων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Servicio Del Parque Nacional - Geología Del 
Parque</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site provides information on the geology in and around the national parks. Sections of the web site are devoted to programs about disturbed lands restoration, mineral and resource management, and geology and soils. A collection of educational activities and teacher resources encourage teaching science using the national parks as examples. The web site also includes a park geology tour that allows users to select types of features they want to view, with links to photographs, maps and geology field notes from several parks.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site stellt Informationen auf der Geologie 
und um in den Nationalparks zur Verfügung. Kapitel der Web site
werden Programmen über gestörte Landwiederherstellung, Mineral und 
Betriebsmittelverwaltung und Geologie und Boden gewidmet. Eine 
Ansammlung pädagogische Aktivitäten und Lehrerbetriebsmittel regen 
unterrichtende Wissenschaft mit den Nationalparks als Beispiele an. 
Die Web site schließt auch eine Parkgeologietour ein, die 
Benutzern erlaubt, Typen der Merkmale, die sie ansehen möchten, mit 
Links zu den Fotographien auszuwählen, Karten und Geologie 
Anmerkungen von einigen Parks auffangen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site fournit des informations sur la géologie
en et autour de parcs nationaux. Des sections du site Web sont 
consacrées aux programmes sur la restauration de terres, la gestion 
de minerai et de ressource, et la géologie et les sols dérangés. 
Une collection d'activités et de ressources éducatives de 
professeur encouragent la science d'enseignement en utilisant les 
parcs nationaux comme exemples. Le site Web inclut également 
une excursion de géologie de parc qui permet à des utilisateurs de 
choisir des types de dispositifs qu'ils veulent visualiser, avec des 
liens aux photographies, des cartes et des notes de zone de géologie 
à partir de plusieurs parcs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local fornece a informação na geologia e 
em torno dos parques nacionais. As seções do Web site são 
devotadas aos programas sobre a restauração das terras, gerência de
mineral e de recurso, e geologia e solos perturbados. Uma 
coleção de atividades e de recursos educacionais do professor 
incentiva a ciência ensinando usando os parques nacionais como 
exemplos. O Web site inclui também uma excursão da geologia do
parque que permita que os usuários selecionem tipos de 
características que querem ver, com ligações às fotografias, mapas
e notas do campo da geologia de diversos parques.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo fornisce le informazioni sulla 
geologia in ed intorno ai parchi nazionali. Le sezioni del Web 
site sono dedicate ai programmi circa ripristino delle terre, gestione
delle risorse e del minerale e la geologia e terreni disturbati. 
Una collezione di attività e di risorse educative 
dell'insegnante consiglia alla scienza d'istruzione usando i parchi 
nazionali come esempi. Il Web site egualmente include un giro di
geologia del parco che permette che gli utenti selezionino i tipi di 
caratteristiche desiderano osservare, con i collegamenti alle 
fotografie, programmi e note del campo di geologia a partire da 
parecchi parchi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή παρέχει τις πληροφορίες για τη 
γεωλογία σε και γύρω από τα εθνικά πάρκα. Τα τμήματα του 
ιστοχώρου αφιερώνονται στα προγράμματα για τη διαταραγμένη 
αποκατάσταση εδαφών, το μετάλλευμα και τη διαχείριση των 
στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς, και τη γεωλογία και τα χώματα. Μια 
συλλογή των εκπαιδευτικών δραστηριοτήτων και τα στοιχεία 
συμπεριφοράς δασκάλων ενθαρρύνουν την επιστήμη διδασκαλίας 
χρησιμοποιώντας τα εθνικά πάρκα για παραδείγματα. Ο 
ιστοχώρος περιλαμβάνει επίσης έναν γύρο γεωλογίας πάρκων που 
επιτρέπει στους χρήστες για να επιλέξει τους τύπους 
χαρακτηριστικών γνωρισμάτων που θέλουν να εμφανίσουν, με τις 
συνδέσεις με τις φωτογραφίες, τους χάρτες και τις σημειώσεις 
πεδίων γεωλογίας από διάφορα πάρκα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio proporciona a la información en la 
geología en y alrededor de los parques nacionales. Las 
secciones del Web site se dedican a los programas sobre la 
restauración de las pistas, gerencia del mineral y de recurso, y 
geología y los suelos disturbados. Una colección de 
actividades y de recursos educativos del profesor anima ciencia de 
enseñanza usando los parques nacionales como ejemplos. El Web 
site también incluye un viaje de la geología del parque que permita 
que los utilizadores seleccionen tipos de características que desean 
visión, con conexiones a las fotografías, las correspondencias y las
notas del campo de la geología de varios parques.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211261</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104145</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/national-park-service-park-geology</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
