<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107242</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107242</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086800</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Sarah Smith Emery - Memories of a Massachusetts Girlhood at the Turn of the 19th century</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sarah Smith Schmirgel - Speicher von einem 
Massachusetts Girlhood an der Jahrhundertwende 19.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Émeris de Sarah Smith - mémoires d'un 
Massachusetts Girlhood à la fin du 19ème siècle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esmeril de Sarah Smith - memórias de um 
Massachusetts Girlhood na volta do 1ø século</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Smeriglio di Sarah Smith - memorie di un 
Massachusetts Girlhood alla fine del diciannovesimo secolo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σμύριδα Smith Sarah - μνήμες μιας Μασαχουσέτης 
Girlhood στο γύρισμα του 19$ου αιώνα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esmeril de Sarah Smith - memorias de un 
Massachusetts Girlhood al final del diecinueveavo siglo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Sarah Smith Emery, in her nineties when she wrote this memoir, grew up around the turn of the 19th century in the Massachusetts countryside. Her family lived on a farm near the port town of Newburyport, on the Merrimack River. Life on the farm, as she described it, was a series of peaceful routines organized by season, time of day, age, and gender. Emery described the home production of food, such as butter and cheese, and household items, including candles, soap, and clothing. Spinning, weaving, knitting, sewing, dressmaking, cooking, preserving food, and housecleaning filled this early nineteenth-century girl's life, while the men in her family farmed, butchered, and chopped wood. Militia training took place twice each year, in spring and fall. At the time that Emery was writing, the United States was rapidly shifting from an agricultural to an urban industrial economy, and nostalgia for rural life thus colored her recollections.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sarah Smith Schmirgel, in ihren neunziger Jahren, 
als sie diese Abhandlung schrieb, wuchs um die Jahrhundertwende 19. in
der Massachusetts Landschaft auf. Ihre Familie lebte auf einem 
Bauernhof nahe der Portstadt von Newburyport, auf dem Merrimack Fluß.
Das Leben auf dem Bauernhof, wie sie ihn beschrieb, war eine 
Reihe ruhige Programme, die durch Jahreszeit, Zeit, Alter und 
Geschlecht organisiert wurden. Schmirgel beschrieb die 
inländische Produktion der Nahrung, wie Butter und Käse und Haushalt
Einzelteile, einschließlich Kerzen, Seife und Kleidung. _ 
spinnen, spinnen, stricken, nähen, dressmaking, kochen, konservieren 
Nahrung, und Haus putzen füllen dies früh 19.-Jahrhundert Mädchen 
Lebensdauer, während d Mann in ihr Familie bewirtschaften, 
schlachten, und hacken Holz. Miliztraining fand zweimal jedes 
Jahr, im Frühjahr und Fall statt. Zu der Zeit als dieser 
Schmirgel schrieb, verschoben die Vereinigten Staaten schnell von 
einem landwirtschaftlichen auf eine städtische industrielle 
Wirtschaft, und Nostalgie für landwirtschaftliche Lebensdauer 
färbte folglich ihre Erinnerungen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'émeris de Sarah Smith, en quelques ses années 
'90 quand elle a écrit ce mémoire, a grandi autour du tournant du 
19ème siècle dans la campagne du Massachusetts. Sa famille a 
vécu à une ferme près de la ville gauche de Newburyport, sur le 
fleuve de Merrimack. La vie à la ferme, comme elle l'a 
décrite, était une série de sous-programmes paisibles organisés 
par saison, heure, âge, et genre. L'émeris a décrit la 
production à la maison de la nourriture, telle que le beurre et 
fromage, et des éléments de ménage, y compris les bougies, le 
savon, et l'habillement. _ tourner, tisser, tricoter, coudre, 
couture, faire cuire, préserver nourriture, et faire le ménage 
remplir ce tôt dix-neuvième-siècle fille vie, tandis que le homme 
dans son famille cultiver, envoyer à la boucherie, et couper bois. 
La formation de milice a eu lieu deux fois tous les ans, au 
printemps et la chute. Lorsque cet émeris écrivait, les 
Etats-Unis décalaient rapidement d'un agricole à une économie 
industrielle urbaine, et la nostalgie pendant la vie rurale a ainsi 
coloré ses souvenirs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O esmeril de Sarah Smith, em seus nineties quando 
escreveu este memoir, cresceu acima em torno da volta do 1ø século 
no campo de Massachusetts. Sua família viveu em uma fazenda 
perto da cidade portuária de Newburyport, no rio de Merrimack. 
A vida na fazenda, como a descreveu, era uma série das rotinas 
calmas organizadas pela estação, pela hora, pela idade, e pelo 
gender. O esmeril descreveu a produção home do alimento, tal 
como a manteiga e o queijo, e os artigos da casa, including velas, 
sabão, e roupa. _ gir, teç, knitting, sewing, dressmaking, 
cozinh, preserv alimento, e housecleaning ench este adiantado 
décimo-século menina vida, enquanto que homem seu família cultiv, 
massacr, e chopped madeira. O treinamento da milícia ocorreu 
duas vezes cada ano, na mola e na queda. Então esse esmeril 
estava escrevendo, os estados unidos estavam deslocando ràpidamente 
de um agricultural a uma economia industrial urbana, e a nostalgia 
para a vida rural coloriu assim seus recollections.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lo smeriglio di Sarah Smith, nei suoi anni '90 
quando ha scritto questa memoria, si è sviluppato in su intorno alla 
girata del diciannovesimo secolo nella campagna del Massachusetts. 
La sua famiglia ha vissuto su un podere vicino alla città port 
di Newburyport, sul fiume di Merrimack. La vita sul podere, come
lo ha descritto, era una serie di procedure pacifiche organizzate 
dalla stagione, dall'ora, dall'età e dal genere. Lo smeriglio 
ha descritto la produzione domestica di alimento, quali burro e 
formaggio ed articoli della famiglia, compreso le candele, il sapone 
ed i vestiti. _ fil, tess, lavor a maglia, cuc, dressmaking, 
cucinare, conserv alimento, e housecleaning riemp questo in anticipo 
diciannovesimo-secolo ragazza vita, mentre uomo suo famiglia coltiv, 
macell, e tagli legno. L'addestramento della milizia ha avvenuto
due volte ogni anno, in primavera e la caduta. Quando quello 
smeriglio stava scrivendo, unito Dichiara velocemente stava 
spostando da un agricolo ad un'economia industriale urbana ed il 
nostalgia per vita rurale ha colorato così i suoi ricordi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η σμύριδα Smith Sarah, στη δεκαετία του '90 της 
όταν έγραψε αυτά τα απομνημονεύματα, μεγάλωσε γύρω από τη 
στροφή του 19$ου αιώνα στην επαρχία της Μασαχουσέτης. Η 
οικογένειά της έζησε σε ένα αγρόκτημα κοντά στην πόλη λιμένων 
Newburyport, στον ποταμό Merrimack. Η ζωή στο 
αγρόκτημα, δεδομένου ότι την περιέγραψε, ήταν μια σειρά 
ειρηνικών ρουτινών που οργανώθηκαν κατά την εποχή, το χρόνο της 
ημέρας, την ηλικία, και φύλο. Η σμύριδα περιέγραψε τη 
βασική παραγωγή των τροφίμων, όπως το βούτυρο και το τυρί, και 
τα οικιακά αντικείμενα, συμπεριλαμβανομένων των κεριών, του 
σαπουνιού, και του ιματισμού. Η περιστροφή, η ύφανση, το 
πλέξιμο, το ράψιμο, dressmaking, μαγειρεύοντας, συντηρώντας τα 
τρόφιμα, και housecleaning γέμισαν τη ζωή αυτού του πρώτου 
κοριτσιού δέκατος-αιώνα, ενώ τα άτομα στην οικογένειά της 
καλλιέργησαν, σφαγμένος, και τεμάχισαν το ξύλο. Η κατάρτιση
πολιτοφυλακής πραγματοποιήθηκε δύο φορές κάθε έτος, την άνοιξη 
και πέφτει. Στο χρόνο που η σμύριδα έγραφε, οι Ηνωμένες 
Πολιτείες μετατοπίζονταν γρήγορα από μια γεωργική σε μια αστική 
βιομηχανική οικονομία, και νοσταλγία για την αγροτική ζωή 
χρωμάτισε έτσι τις αναμνήσεις της.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El esmeril de Sarah Smith, en los sus an'os 
noventa cuando ella escribió esta memoria, creció para arriba 
alrededor de la vuelta del diecinueveavo siglo en el campo de 
Massachusetts. Su familia vivió en una granja cerca de la 
ciudad portuaria de Newburyport, en el río de Merrimack. La 
vida en la granja, como ella la describió, era una serie de rutinas 
pacíficas ordenadas por la estación, la hora, la edad, y el género.
El esmeril describió la producción casera del alimento, tal 
como mantequilla y queso, y los items de la casa, incluyendo velas, 
jabón, y la ropa. _ hacer girar, tejer, hacer punto, coser, 
dressmaking, cocinar, preservar alimento, y housecleaning llenar este 
temprano diecinueveavo-siglo muchacha vida, mientras que hombre en su 
familia cultivar, matar, y tajar madera. El entrenamiento de la 
milicia ocurrió dos veces cada año, en resorte y caída. 
Cuando ese esmeril escribía, los Estados Unidos cambiaban de 
puesto rápidamente de un agrícola a una economía industrial urbana,
y la nostalgia para la vida rural coloreó así sus recuerdos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086800</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107242</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/sarah-smith-emery-memories-of-a-massachusetts-girlhood-at-the-turn-of-the-19th-century</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
