<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105504</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105504</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212425</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Teaching About Evolution and the Nature of Science</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Unterricht über Entwicklung und die Natur der 
Wissenschaft</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Enseignement au sujet d'évolution et la nature de 
la Science</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ensino sobre a evolução e a natureza da ciência</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Insegnamento circa lo sviluppo e natura di scienza</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διδασκαλία για την εξέλιξη και τη φύση της επιστήμης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Enseñanza sobre la evolución y la naturaleza de 
la ciencia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This website offers a free, online version of the National Academy Press' summary of the scientific evidence for evolution. The book has a substantial bibliography and a number of K-12 activities. Users can read the book online, download a PDF version for a minimal price or order the print version.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Web site bietet eine freie, Onlineversion der
nationalen Zusammenfassung der Akademie-Pressen des wissenschaftlichen
Beweises für Entwicklung an. Das Buch hat eine erhebliche 
Bibliographie und eine Anzahl von Aktivitäten K-12. Benutzer 
können das Buch online lesen, eine pdf Version für einen minimalen 
Preis downloaden oder die Druckversion bestellen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site Web offre une version libre et en ligne du 
sommaire des presses nationales d'académie de l'évidence 
scientifique pour l'évolution. Le livre a une bibliographie 
substantielle et un certain nombre d'activités K-12. Les 
utilisateurs peuvent lire le livre en ligne, télécharger une version
de pdf pour un prix minimal ou commander la version d'impression.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Web site oferece uma versão livre, em linha 
do sumário das imprensas nacionais do academy da evidência 
científica para a evolução. O livro tem uma bibliografia 
substancial e um número de atividades K-12. Os usuários podem 
ler o livro em linha, download uma versão do pdf para um preço 
mínimo ou requisitar a versão da cópia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Web site offre una versione libera e in 
linea del sommario delle presse nazionali dell'Accademia della prova
scientifica per sviluppo. Il libro ha una bibliografia notevole 
ed un certo numero di attività K-12. Gli utenti possono leggere
il libro in linea, trasferire una versione dal sistema centrale verso 
i satelliti del pdf per un prezzo minimo o ordinare la versione della 
stampa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος προσφέρει μια ελεύθερη, σε 
απευθείας σύνδεση έκδοση της περίληψης των εθνικών Τύπων 
ακαδημίας των επιστημονικών στοιχείων για την εξέλιξη. Το 
βιβλίο αναπτύσσει ουσιαστική βιβλιογραφία και διάφορες Κ- 12 
δραστηριότητες. Οι χρήστες μπορούν να διαβάσουν το βιβλίο 
on-line, να μεταφορτώσουν μια έκδοση PDF για μια ελάχιστη 
τιμή ή να διατάξουν την έκδοση τυπωμένων υλών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este Web site ofrece una versión libre, en línea 
del resumen de las prensas nacionales de la academia de la evidencia 
científica para la evolución. El libro tiene una bibliografía
substancial y un número de actividades K-12. Los utilizadores 
pueden leer el libro en línea, descargar una versión del pdf para un
precio mínimo o pedir la versión de la impresión.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212425</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105504</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/teaching-about-evolution-and-the-nature-of-science</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
