<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105756</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105756</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201440</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Electric Field Hockey</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Elektrisch Fangen Sie Hockey 
auf</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Hockey de Champ Électrique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Hockey Do Campo Elétrico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Hockey Del Campo elettrico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Χόκευ! ηλεκτρικών πεδίων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Hockey Del Campo Eléctrico</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Play hockey with electric charges. Place charges on the ice, then hit start to try to get the puck in the goal. View the electric field. Trace the puck's motion. Make the game harder by placing walls in front of the goal. This is a clone of the popular simulation of the same name marketed by Physics Academic Software and written by Prof. Ruth Chabay of the Dept of Physics at North Carolina State University.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <language>es</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spielen Sie Hockey mit elektrischen 
Ladungen. Plazieren Sie Ladungen auf das Eis, schlagen Sie dann 
Anfang, um zu versuchen, den Kobold im Ziel zu erhalten. Sehen 
Sie das elektrische auffangen an. Vollziehen Sie die 
Bewegung des Kobolds nach. Bilden Sie das Spiel härter, indem 
Sie Wände vor dem Ziel plazieren. Dieses ist ein Klon der 
populären Simulation des gleichen Namens, der durch Physics Academic 
Software vermarktet wird und vom Prof Ruth Chabay der Abteilung von 
Physik an der Nord-Carolina Landesuniversität geschrieben ist.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Hockey de jeu avec les frais électriques. 
L'endroit charge sur la glace, a alors frappé le début pour 
essayer d'obtenir le galet dans le but. Visualisez le champ 
électrique. Tracez le mouvement du galet. Rendez le jeu 
plus dur en plaçant des murs devant le but. C'est un clone de 
la simulation populaire du même nom lancé par le logiciel de Physics
universitaire et écrit sur le marché par prof. Ruth Chabay du 
service de la physique à l'université de l'Etat du nord de la 
Caroline.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Hockey do jogo com cargas elétricas. O 
lugar carrega no gelo, bateu então o começo para tentar começar o 
puck no objetivo. Veja o campo elétrico. Siga o movimento
do puck. Faça o jogo mais duro colocando paredes na frente do 
objetivo. Este é um clone da simulação popular do mesmo nome 
introduzído no mercado pelo software de Física Academic e escrito 
pelo prof. Ruth Chabay do departamento da física na universidade de 
estado de North.carolina.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Hockey del gioco con le cariche elettriche. 
Il posto si carica sul ghiaccio, allora ha colpito l'inizio per 
provare ad ottenere il disco di gomma nell'obiettivo. Osservi il
campo elettrico. Segua il movimento del disco di gomma. 
Renda il gioco più duro disponendo le pareti davanti 
l'obiettivo. Ciò è un clone della simulazione popolare dello 
stesso nome di marketing dal software della Physics accademico e scritto
dal prof. Ruth Chabay del reparto della fisica a North.carolina 
Dichiari l'università.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Χόκευ! παιχνιδιού με τις ηλεκτρικές δαπάνες. 
Δαπάνες θέσεων στον πάγο, έπειτα χτυπημένη έναρξη για να 
προσπαθήσει να πάρει τη σφαίρα στο στόχο. Εμφανίστε το 
ηλεκτρικό πεδίο. Επισημάνετε την κίνηση της σφαίρας. 
Καταστήστε το παιχνίδι σκληρότερο με την τοποθέτηση των 
τοίχων μπροστά από το στόχο. Αυτό είναι ένας κλώνος της 
δημοφιλούς προσομοίωσης του ίδιου ονόματος που πωλείται από το 
ακαδημαϊκό λογισμικό φυσικής και που γράφεται από τον καθ. 
Ruth Chabay του διαμερίσματος της φυσικής στο κρατικό 
πανεπιστήμιο της βόρειας Καρολίνας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Hockey del juego con las cargas eléctricas. 
El lugar carga en el hielo, entonces golpeó comienzo para 
intentar conseguir el duende malicioso en la meta. Opinión el 
campo eléctrico. Rastree el movimiento del duende malicioso. 
Haga el juego más duro colocando las paredes delante de la 
meta. Esto es una copia de la simulación popular del mismo 
nombre puesto por el software de Physics Academic y escrito por 
profesor Ruth Chabay del departamento de la física en la universidad 
de estado de Carolina del Norte.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201440</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105756</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/electric-field-hockey</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
