<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/647248595</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>647248595</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207096</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Human Genome Project Education Resources</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschliche Genom-Projekt-Ausbildung 
Betriebsmittel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ressources Humaines D'Éducation de Projet de 
Génome</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Recursos Humanos Da Instrução Do Projeto Do 
Genome</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Risorse Umane Di Formazione Di Progetto Del 
Genome</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρώπινα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς εκπαίδευσης 
προγράμματος γονιδιώματος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Recursos Humanos De la Educación Del Proyecto Del
Genoma</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">provides curriculum modules, a newsletter, a molecular genetics primer, tutorials on biomolecules and biological processes, an overview of research on mutant genes and hereditary diseases, an online resource for learning biology, publications, teaching aids, animations, and other learning resources related to genetics.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt Lehrplanmodule, ein Rundschreiben, eine 
molekulare Genetikzündkapsel, Tutorials auf Biomolekülen und 
biologischen Prozessen, einen Überblick über Forschung auf Durch 
Mutation entstehende Variation Genen und erblichen Krankheiten, ein 
Onlinehilfsmittel für erlernenbiologie, Publikationen, Lehrmittel, 
Animationen und andere erlernenbetriebsmittel, die auf Genetik in 
Verbindung gestanden werden zur Verfügung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fournit des modules de programme d'études, un 
bulletin, une amorce moléculaire de la génétique, des cours 
d'instruction sur des biomolécules et des processus biologiques, une 
vue d'ensemble de recherche sur des gènes de mutant et des maladies 
héréditaires, une ressource en ligne pour la biologie d'étude, des 
publications, des aides pédagogiques, des animations, et d'autres 
ressources d'étude liées à la génétique.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fornece os módulos do curriculum, um boletim de 
notícias, um primer molecular do genetics, tutorials em biomolecules 
e em processos biológicos, uma vista geral da pesquisa sobre genes do
mutant e doenças hereditary, um recurso em linha para a biologia de 
aprendizagem, publicações, dae (dispositivo automático de entrada) 
de ensino, animations, e outros recursos de aprendizagem relacionados 
ao genetics.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fornisce i moduli di programma di studi, un 
bollettino, un iniettore molecolare della genetica, le lezioni private
sulle biomolecole e sui processi biologici, una descrizione di ricerca
sui geni del mutante e sulle malattie ereditarie, una risorsa in linea
per biologia imparante, le pubblicazioni, i sussidi didattici, le 
animazioni ed altre risorse imparanti relative alla genetica.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρέχει τις ενότητες προγράμματος σπουδών, ένα 
ενημερωτικό δελτίο, έναν μοριακό εγχυτήρα γενετικής, τα 
σεμινάρια στα βιομόρια και τις βιολογικές διαδικασίες, μια 
επισκόπηση της έρευνας για τα γονίδια μεταλλάξεων και τις 
κληρονομικές ασθένειες, ένα σε απευθείας σύνδεση στοιχείο 
συμπεριφοράς για την εκμάθηση της βιολογίας, τις δημοσιεύσεις, τις
ενισχύσεις διδασκαλίας, τις ζωτικότητες, και άλλα στοιχεία 
συμπεριφοράς εκμάθησης σχετικά με τη γενετική.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">proporciona a módulos del plan de estudios, a un 
boletín de noticias, a una cartilla molecular de la genética, a 
guías en biomoléculas y procesos biológicos, a una descripción de 
la investigación sobre genes del mutante y enfermedades hereditarias,
a un recurso en línea para la biología que aprende, a las 
publicaciones, a las ayudas de enseñanza, a las animaciones, y a 
otros recursos que aprenden relacionados con la genética.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207096</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>647248595</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/human-genome-project-education-resources</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
