<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105659</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105659</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206590</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Lewis and Clark Expedition: Documenting the Uncharted Northwest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Lewis und Clark Expedition: 
Dokumentieren des Uncharted Nordwestens</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'expédition de Lewis et de Clark : 
Documentation du nord-ouest Inexploré</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A expedição de Lewis e de Clark: 
Documentando o noroeste de Uncharted</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La spedizione del Clark e di Lewis: 
Documentazione del nord-ovest di Uncharted</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η αποστολή Lewis και clark: Τεκμηρίωση των 
ανεξερεύνητων βορειοδυτικών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La expedición de Lewis y de Clark: 
Documentación del noroeste de Uncharted</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">recounts the expedition's crossing of the Lemhi Pass and Lolo Trail, and the time spent at Fort Clatsop near the Pacific Ocean. Although the Corps of Discovery did not realize its dream of finding a water route to the Pacific Ocean, the expedition overcame many obstacles and dangers to open the Northwest to the influence of the U.S., established relations with American Indian tribes, and gathered useful scientific documentation.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">zählt die Überfahrt der Expedition des Lemhi 
Durchlaufs und der Lolo Spur und die Zeit, die am Fort Clatsop nahe 
dem pazifischen Ozean verbracht wird nach. Obgleich das Korps 
der Entdeckung seinen Traum des Findens eines Wasserweges nicht zum 
pazifischen Ozean verwirklichte, überwand die Expedition viele 
Hindernisse und Gefahren, den Nordwesten zum Einfluß der VEREINIGTEN 
STAATEN, hergestellte Relationen mit indianischen Stämmen zu öffnen 
und erfaßte nützliche wissenschaftliche Unterlagen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">raconte le croisement de l'expédition du passage 
de Lemhi et de la traînée de Lolo, et le temps passé au fort 
Clatsop près de l'océan pacifique. Bien que les corps de la 
découverte n'aient pas réalisé son rêve de trouver un itinéraire 
de l'eau à l'océan pacifique, l'expédition a surmonté beaucoup 
d'obstacles et dangers d'ouvrir le nord-ouest à l'influence des 
ETATS-UNIS, relations établies avec les tribus indiennes, et a 
recueilli la documentation scientifique utile.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">recounts o cruzamento da expedição da passagem 
de Lemhi e da fuga de Lolo, e o tempo gastado no fort Clatsop perto do
oceano pacífico. Embora o corpo da descoberta não realizasse 
seu sonho de encontrar uma rota da água ao oceano pacífico, a 
expedição superou muitos obstáculos e perigos abrir o noroeste à 
influência dos ESTADOS UNIDOS, relações estabelecidas com os tribes
indian americanos, e recolheu a documentação científica útil.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">racconta l'incrocio della spedizione del passaggio
di Lemhi e della traccia di Lolo ed il tempo speso a 
Clatsop Forte vicino all'oceano pacifico. Anche se il 
Corpo della scoperta non ha realizzato il relativo sogno di 
individuazione dell'itinerario dell'acqua all'oceano pacifico, la 
spedizione ha sormontato molti ostacoli e pericoli aprire il 
nord-ovest all'influenza degli STATI UNITI, rapporti stabiliti con le 
tribù indiane americane ed ha riunito la documentazione 
scientifica utile.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξιστορεί το πέρασμα της αποστολής του περάσματος 
Lemhi και του ίχνους Lolo, και το χρόνο που ξοδεύεται στο 
οχυρό Clatsop κοντά στον ειρηνικό ωκεανό. Αν και 
Σώμα της ανακάλυψης δεν πραγματοποίησε το όνειρό του 
εύρεσης μιας διαδρομής ύδατος στον ειρηνικό ωκεανό, η αποστολή 
υπερνίκησε πολλούς εμπόδια και κινδύνους για να ανοίξει τα 
βορειοδυτικά στην επιρροή των ΗΠΑ, καθιερωμένες σχέσεις με τις 
αμερικανικές ινδικές φυλές, και σύλλεξε τη χρήσιμη επιστημονική 
τεκμηρίωση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">contó de nuevo la travesía de la expedición del
paso de Lemhi y del rastro de Lolo, y el tiempo pasado en la fortaleza
Clatsop cerca del Océano Pacífico. Aunque el cuerpo del 
descubrimiento no realizó su sueño de encontrar una ruta del agua al
Océano Pacífico, la expedición superó muchos obstáculos y 
peligros de abrir el noroeste en la influencia de los ESTADOS UNIDOS, 
relaciones establecidas con las tribus indias americanas, y recolectó
la documentación científica útil.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206590</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105659</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-lewis-and-clark-expedition-documenting-the-uncharted-northwest</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
