<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105438</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105438</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201130</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Crystal Growth Movies</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kristallwachstum-Filme</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Films de Croissance En cristal</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Filmes Do Crescimento De cristal</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Film Di Sviluppo Di cristallo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κινηματογράφοι αύξησης κρυστάλλου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Películas Del Crecimiento Cristalino</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site, maintained by the Department of Geology and Geophysics at the University of Wyoming, contains four QuickTime videos of actual crystal growth. To access the videos, scroll down to the bottom of the page and click on any of the downloads that are available. These videos enhance understanding of the processes involved in crystallization.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site, beibehalten durch die Abteilung von 
Geologie und von Geophysik an der Universität von Wyoming, enthält 
vier QuickTime videos des tatsächlichen Kristallwachstums. Die 
videos, auf die Rolle zur Unterseite der Seite unten zugreifen und 
irgendwelche der Downloads an klicken, die vorhanden sind. Diese
videos erhöhen Verständnis der Prozesse, die in Kristallisation mit 
einbezogen werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site, mis à jour par le service de la 
géologie et de la géophysique à l'université du Wyoming, contient 
quatre videos de QuickTime de croissance en cristal réelle. 
Pour accéder aux videos, au défilement vers le bas au bas de 
la page et au clic sur quels des téléchargements qui sont 
disponibles. Ces videos mettent en valeur l'arrangement des 
processus impliqués dans la cristallisation.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local, mantido pelo departamento da geologia 
e do geophysics na universidade de Wyoming, contem quatro videos de 
QuickTime do crescimento de cristal real. Para alcançar para 
baixo os videos, o scroll ao fundo da página e para estalar sobre 
alguns dos downloads que estão disponíveis. Estes videos 
realçam a compreensão dos processos envolvidos na cristalização.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo, effettuato dal reparto della 
geologia e della geofisica all'università de Wyoming, contiene 
quattro videos del QuickTime di sviluppo di cristallo reale. Per
accedere ai videos, al rotolo giù alla parte inferiore della pagina e
scattare sopra c'è ne dei trasferimenti dal sistema centrale verso i 
satelliti che sono disponibili. Questi videos aumentano la 
comprensione dei processi addetti alla cristallizzazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή, που διατηρείται από το τμήμα 
γεωλογίας και γεωφυσικής στο πανεπιστήμιο του Wyoming, περιέχει
τέσσερα βίντεο QuickTime της πραγματικής αύξησης κρυστάλλου. 
Για να έχετε πρόσβαση στα βίντεο, τυλίξτε κάτω στο 
κατώτατο σημείο της σελίδας και χτυπήστε σε οποιαδήποτε από 
μεταφορτώνει που είναι διαθέσιμα. Αυτά τα βίντεο ενισχύουν
την κατανόηση των διαδικασιών που περιλαμβάνονται στην 
κρυστάλλωση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio, mantenido por el departamento de la 
geología y de la geofísica en la universidad de Wyoming, contiene 
cuatro videos de QuickTime del crecimiento cristalino real. Para
tener acceso a los videos, al desfile abajo al fondo de la paginación
y hacer clic encendido cualesquiera de las transferencias directas que
están disponibles. Estos videos realzan la comprensión de los 
procesos implicados en la cristalización.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAUL HELLER
FN:PAUL HELLER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201130</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105438</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/crystal-growth-movies-title-enhanced-by-cataloger</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
