<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105802</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105802</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086660</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Negro Dogs."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Schwarze-Hunde."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Chiens de Nègre."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Do "Cães Negro."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Cani Dal Negro."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Σκυλιά νέγρων."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Perros Del Negro."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Whether attempting to escape or simply traveling at night to visit friends or family in neighboring plantations, African-American slaves were threatened by the slave patrols. These squads, often including non-slaveholders who were required to serve under state law, were notorious for their brutality. Most feared were the dogs the pattyrollers" used to track down fugitive slaves. This 1856 advertisement promoted the sale of dogs trained expressly to hunt human beings."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ob versuchend zu entgehen oder nachts wurden bedroht 
einfach, reisend zu den Besuch Freunden oder der Familie in den 
benachbarten Plantagen, Afrikanisch-Amerikanische Sklaven von den 
Sklavenpatrouillen. Diese Gruppen, häufig 
einschließlich non-slaveholders, die benoetigt wurden, um unter 
Zustandgesetz zu dienen, waren für ihre Brutalitäten notorisch. 
Die meisten, die gefürchtet wurden, waren die Hunde die 
pattyrollers ", die verwendet wurden, um Flüchtling unten 
aufzuspüren, schuftet. Diese Reklameanzeige 1856 förderte den 
Verkauf der Hunde, die ausdrücklich ausgebildet wurden, um Menschen 
zu jagen."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Si essayant de s'échapper ou simplement voyageant la nuit
aux amis ou à la famille de visite dans les plantations voisines, des
esclaves afro-américains ont été menacés par les patrouilles 
slaves. Ces pelotons, souvent comprenant les 
non-slaveholders qui ont été exigés pour servir en vertu de la loi 
d'état, étaient notoires pour leur brutalité. Les la plupart 
craintes étaient les chiens les pattyrollers "employés pour 
dépister le fugitif asservissent. Cette publicité 1856 a 
favorisé la vente des chiens qualifiés expressément pour chasser 
les êtres humains."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Se tentando se escapar ou simplesmente viajando na noite 
aos amigos ou à família da visita em plantações neighboring, os 
escravos Africano-Americanos estiveram ameaçados pelas patrulhas 
slave. Estes squads, frequentemente including os 
non-slaveholders que foram requeridos para servir sob a lei do estado,
eram notorious para seu brutality. A maioria temidos eram os 
cães os pattyrollers "usados seguir para baixo o fugitive slaves. 
Esta propaganda 1856 promoveu a venda dos cães treinados 
expressa para caçar seres humanos."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Se tentando di fuoriuscire o semplicemente viaggiando alla
notte agli amici o alla famiglia di chiamata in piantagioni vicine, 
gli schiavi Africano-Americani sono stati minacciati dalle pattuglie 
slave. Questi squads, compreso i non-slaveholders che sono stati
richiesti per servire sotto dichiarano spesso la legge, erano 
rinomati per il loro brutality. La maggior parte temuti erano i 
cani i pattyrollers "usati per rintracciare giù il fuggitivo 
assoggettano. Questa pubblicità 1856 ha promosso la vendita dei
cani addestrati espressamente per cercare gli esseri umani."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Είτε προσπαθώντας να δραπετεύσουν είτε απλά 
διακινούμενος τη νύχτα για να επισκεφτούν τους φίλους είτε την 
οικογένεια στις γειτονικές φυτείες, οι αφρικανικός-αμερικανικοί 
σκλάβοι απειλήθηκαν από τις περιπόλους σκλάβων. Αυτές οι 
ομάδες, συχνά συμπεριλαμβανομένων των μη- slaveholders που 
απαιτήθηκαν για να εξυπηρετήσουν βάσει του κρατικού νόμου, ήταν 
πασίγνωστες για τη βιαιότητά τους. Τα πιό φοβισμένος ήταν 
τα σκυλιά τα pattyrollers "που χρησιμοποιήθηκαν για να 
ανακαλύψουν τους σκλάβους προσφύγων. Αυτή η διαφήμιση 
1856 προώθησε την πώληση των σκυλιών που εκπαιδεύθηκαν ρητώς 
για να κυνηγήσουν τα ανθρώπινα οντα."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Si procuraban escaparse o simplemente viajan en la noche a
los amigos o a la familia de la visita en plantaciones vecinas, los 
esclavos Africano-Americanos fueron amenazados por las patrullas 
auxiliares. Estas escuadrillas, a menudo incluyendo los 
non-slaveholders que fueron requeridos para servir bajo ley del 
estado, eran notorias para su brutalidad. La mayoría temidos 
eran los perros los pattyrollers "usados para seguir abajo a fugitivo 
esclavizan. Este anuncio 1856 promovió la venta de los perros 
entrenados expreso para buscar seres humanos."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086660</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105802</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/negro-dogs</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
