<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107447</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107447</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200748</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Building a Winogradsky Column: An Educator Guide with Activities in Astrobiology</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Aufbauen einer Winogradsky Spalte: Eine 
Erzieher-Anleitung mit Aktivitäten in Astrobiology</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Construction d'une colonne de Winogradsky : 
Un guide d'éducateur avec des activités dans Astrobiology</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Construindo uma coluna de Winogradsky: Uma 
guia do educador com atividades em Astrobiology</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Costruzione della colonna di Winogradsky: 
Una guida dell'educatore con le attività in Astrobiology</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οικοδόμηση μιας στήλης Winogradsky: Ένας 
οδηγός εκπαιδευτικών με τις δραστηριότητες σε Astrobiology</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Construcción de una columna de Winogradsky: 
Una guía del educador con actividades en Astrobiology</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This 27-page educator guide is a NASA Quest resource about Microbial Ecology and related Astrobiology activities. Students will construct a Winogradsky Column to observe the growth of microbes in a column of mud. During this investigation students will develop a hypothesis, record their observations and results, and form conclusions. They will compare and contrast their methods during the investigation with those of the astrobiologists performing research in the field and the laboratory. It includes student handouts and assessment rubrics that may be duplicated without copyright restrictions.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Anleitung des Erziehers 27-page ist ein die 
NASA Suche Hilfsmittel über Mikrobenökologie und in Verbindung 
stehende Astrobiology Aktivitäten. Kursteilnehmer konstruieren 
eine Winogradsky Spalte, um das Wachstum der Mikroben in einer Spalte 
des Schlammes zu beobachten. Während dieser Untersuchung 
entwickeln Kursteilnehmer eine Hypothese, speichern ihre Beobachtungen
und Resultate und bilden Zusammenfassungen. Sie vergleichen und 
kontrastieren ihre Methoden während der Untersuchung mit denen der 
astrobiologists, die Forschung in auffangene und im Labor 
durchführen. Sie enthält Handbücher und Einschätzung 
Rubriken, die ohne copyrightbeschränkungen kopiert werden können.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce guide de l'éducateur 27-page est une ressource
de recherche de la NASA au sujet de l'écologie microbienne et des 
activités relatives d'Astrobiology. Les étudiants construiront
une colonne de Winogradsky pour observer la croissance des microbes 
dans une colonne de boue. Pendant cette recherche les étudiants
développeront une hypothèse, enregistreront leurs observations et 
résultats, et formeront des conclusions. Ils compareront et 
contrasteront leurs méthodes pendant la recherche avec ceux des 
astrobiologists exécutant la recherche dans le domaine et le 
laboratoire. Elle inclut les aumônes d'étudiant et les 
rubriques d'évaluation qui peuvent être reproduites sans 
restrictions de copyright.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta guia do educador 27-page é um recurso do 
quest da NASA sobre o ecology microbial e atividades relacionadas de 
Astrobiology. Os estudantes construirão uma coluna de 
Winogradsky para observar o crescimento dos micróbios em uma coluna 
da lama. Durante esta investigação os estudantes 
desenvolverão uma hipótese, gravarão seus observações e 
resultados, e dão forma a conclusões. Compararão e 
contrastarão seus métodos durante a investigação com os aqueles 
dos astrobiologists que executam a pesquisa no campo e no 
laboratório. Inclui os handouts de estudante e os rubrics da 
avaliação que podem ser duplicados sem limitações do copyright.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa guida dell'educatore 27-page è una risorsa
di ricerca della NASA circa l'ecologia microbica e le attività 
relative di Astrobiology. Gli allievi costruiranno una colonna 
di Winogradsky per osservare lo sviluppo dei microbi in una colonna di
fango. Durante questa ricerca allievi svilupperanno un'ipotesi, 
registreranno le loro osservazioni e risultati e formeranno le 
conclusioni. Confronteranno e contrapporranno i loro metodi 
durante la ricerca con quelli dei astrobiologists che realizzano la 
ricerca nel campo e nel laboratorio. Include le dispense di 
allievo e le rubriche di valutazione che possono essere duplicate 
senza limitazioni del copyright.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο οδηγός εκπαιδευτικών 27-σελίδων είναι ένα 
στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς αναζήτησης της NASA για τη μικροβιακή 
οικολογία και τις σχετικές δραστηριότητες Astrobiology. Οι
σπουδαστές θα κατασκευάσουν μια στήλη Winogradsky για να 
παρατηρήσουν την αύξηση των μικροβίων σε μια στήλη της λάσπης. 
Κατά τη διάρκεια αυτής της έρευνας οι σπουδαστές θα 
αναπτύξουν μια υπόθεση, να καταγράψει τις παρατηρήσεις και τα 
αποτελέσματά τους, και τα συμπεράσματα μορφής. Θα 
συγκρίνουν και θα αντιπαραβάλουν τις μεθόδους τους κατά τη 
διάρκεια της έρευνας με εκείνους των astrobiologists που 
εκτελούν την έρευνα στο πεδίο και το εργαστήριο. 
Περιλαμβάνει τα φυλλάδια σπουδαστών και τις ρουμπρίκες 
αξιολόγησης που μπορούν να αναπαραχθούν χωρίς περιορισμούς 
πνευματικών δικαιωμάτων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta guía del educador 27-page es un recurso de 
la búsqueda de la NASA sobre la ecología microbiana y las 
actividades relacionadas de Astrobiology. Los estudiantes 
construirán una columna de Winogradsky para observar el crecimiento 
de microbios en una columna del fango. Durante esta 
investigación los estudiantes desarrollarán una hipótesis, 
registrarán sus observaciones y resultados, y formarán conclusiones.
Compararán y pondrán en contraste sus métodos durante la 
investigación con los de los astrobiologists que realizan la 
investigación en el campo y el laboratorio. Incluye los 
folletos de estudiante y las rúbricas del gravamen que se pueden 
duplicar sin restricciones del copyright.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:DEBORAH BODONY
FN:DEBORAH BODONY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:AMBERLEE CHAUSSEE
FN:AMBERLEE CHAUSSEE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:BONNIE SAMUELSON
FN:BONNIE SAMUELSON
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:NASA QUEST
FN:NASA QUEST
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200748</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107447</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/building-a-winogradsky-column-an-educator-guide-with-activities-in-astrobiology</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
