<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104113</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104113</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211991</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Rubric for an Earth Systems Problem</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Rubrik für ein Masse Systeme Problem</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Rubrique pour un problème de systèmes de la 
terre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Rubric para um problema de sistemas da terra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Rubrica per un problema di sistemi della terra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ρουμπρίκα για ένα πρόβλημα γήινων συστημάτων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Rúbrica para un problema de sistemas de la 
tierra</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This subsite of NASA's Earth System Science Course (ESSC) describes a team exercise to develop understanding of ESS. The page includes a rubric for a problem statement, advice to students, directions for the assignment and a reference list. Users may also follow links to other parts of the ESSC website.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses subsite des Kurses Wissenschaft System 
Masse der NASAS (ESSC) beschreibt eine Teamübung, um Verständnis von
ESS zu entwickeln. Die Seite enthält eine Rubrik für eine 
Problemanweisung, Rat zu den Kursteilnehmern, Richtungen für die 
Anweisung und eine Bezugsliste. Benutzer können Links zu 
anderen Teilen der ESSC Web site auch folgen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce subsite du cours de la Science de système de 
la terre de la NASA (ESSC) décrit un exercice d'équipe pour 
développer l'arrangement d'ESS. La page inclut une rubrique 
pour un rapport de problème, le conseil aux étudiants, les 
directions pour l'affectation et une liste de référence. Les 
utilisateurs peuvent également suivre des liens à d'autres parties 
du site Web d'ESSC.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este subsite do curso da ciência do sistema da 
terra da NASA (ESSC) descreve um exercício da equipe para desenvolver
a compreensão de ESS. A página inclui um rubric para uma 
indicação do problema, o conselho aos estudantes, os sentidos para a
atribuição e uma lista de referência. Os usuários podem 
também seguir as ligações a outras partes do Web site de ESSC.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo subsite del corso di scienza del sistema 
della terra della NASA (ESSC) descrive un'esercitazione della squadra 
per sviluppare la comprensione di ESS. La pagina include una 
rubrica per un'istruzione di problema, un consiglio agli allievi, i 
sensi per l'assegnazione e un indice bibliografico. Gli utenti 
possono anche seguire i collegamenti ad altre parti del Web site di 
ESSC.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το subsite της σειράς μαθημάτων επιστήμης 
γήινων συστημάτων της NASA (ESSC) περιγράφει μια άσκηση 
ομάδων για να αναπτύξει την κατανόηση ESS. Η σελίδα 
περιλαμβάνει μια ρουμπρίκα για μια δήλωση προβλήματος, συμβουλές 
στους σπουδαστές, κατευθύνσεις για την ανάθεση και έναν κατάλογο 
αναφοράς. Οι χρήστες μπορούν επίσης να ακολουθήσουν τις 
συνδέσεις με άλλα μέρη του ιστοχώρου ESSC.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este subsite del curso de la ciencia del sistema 
de la tierra de la NASA (ESSC) describe un ejercicio del equipo para 
desarrollar la comprensión de ESS. La paginación incluye una 
rúbrica para una declaración del problema, el consejo a los 
estudiantes, las direcciones para la asignación y una lista de 
referencia. Los utilizadores pueden también seguir conexiones a
otras partes del Web site de ESSC.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ROBERT MYERS
FN:ROBERT MYERS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211991</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104113</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/rubric-for-an-earth-systems-problem</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
