<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106254</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106254</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206390</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Guilford Courthouse: A Pivotal Battle in the War for Independence</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Guilford Gericht: Eine Angelschlacht im 
Krieg für Unabhängigkeit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Tribunal de Guilford : Une bataille pivotale
dans la guerre pour l'indépendance</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Tribunal De Guilford: Uma batalha pivotal na
guerra para a independência</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Courthouse Di Guilford: Una battaglia chiave
nella guerra per indipendenza</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δικαστήριο Guilford: Μια κεντρική μάχη στον 
πόλεμο για την ανεξαρτησία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Palacio de justicia De Guilford: Una batalla
giratoria en la guerra para la independencia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">looks at this battle?how it was fought; how its outcome was characterized, including reports from both General Nathanael Greene and Lord Cornwallis; and why it was important. About 1,700 Continentals (three-year enlistees in the regular army) and 2,700 militia (mostly farmers who were nonprofessional temporary soldiers called up for short periods of service during an emergency) fought against the redcoats near this North Carolina town of fewer than 100 people.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Blicke auf dieses battle?how wurde sie gekämpft; 
wie sein Resultat gekennzeichnet wurde, einschließlich Reports 
vom General Nathanael Greene und vom Lord Cornwallis; und warum 
es wichtig war. Ungefähr Miliz 1.700 Continentals (dreijährige
enlistees in der regelmäßigen Armee) und 2.700 (meistens Landwirte, 
die die nicht fachmännischen temporären Soldaten waren, die für 
kurze Perioden des Services während einer Dringlichkeit aufgerufen 
wurden), fought.against die redcoats nahe dieser Nord-Carolina Stadt 
von weniger als 100 Leuten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">des regards à ce battle?how elle a été 
combattue ; comment ses résultats ont été caractérisés, y 
compris des états du Général Nathanael Greene et de seigneur 
Cornwallis ; et pourquoi c'était important. Environ 
milice 1.700 Continentals (enlistees de trois ans dans l'armée 
régulière) et 2.700 (la plupart du temps fermiers qui étaient les 
soldats provisoires nonprofessionnels appelés pendant des périodes 
courtes de service pendant une urgence) fought.against les redcoats 
près de cette ville du nord de la Caroline de moins de 100 
personnes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">olhares neste battle?how foi lutada; como 
seu resultado foi caracterizado, including relatórios  do general 
Nathanael Greene e do senhor Cornwallis; e porque era 
importante. A aproximadamente milícia 1.700 Continentals 
(enlistees three-year no exército regular) e 2.700 (na maior parte 
fazendeiros que eram soldados provisórios nonprofessional chamados 
acima por períodos curtos do serviço durante uma emergência) lutou 
de encontro aos redcoats perto desta cidade de North.carolina de menos
de 100 povos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">sguardi a questo battle?how è stata combattuta; 
come il relativo risultato è stato caratterizzato, compreso i 
rapporti sia dal General Nathanael Greene che dal signore Cornwallis; 
e perchè era importante. La circa 1.700 Continentals 
(enlistees triennali nell'esercito normale) e 2.700 milizia 
(principalmente coltivatori che erano soldati provvisori casuali 
chiamati in su in breve i periodi di servizio durante l'emergenza) ha 
combattuto contro i redcoats vicino a questa città del North.carolina
di meno di 100 genti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει αυτό το battle?how που αυτό πάλεψαν  
πώς η έκβασή της χαρακτηρίστηκε, συμπεριλαμβανομένων των 
εκθέσεων και από το στρατηγό Nathanael Greene και από το 
Λόρδο Cornwallis  και γιατί ήταν σημαντικό. Η 
περίπου πολιτοφυλακή 1.700 Continentals (τρίχρονα 
enlistees στον κανονικό στρατό) και 2.700 (συνήθως αγρότες 
που ήταν μη επαγγελματικοί προσωρινοί στρατιώτες που απαιτήθηκαν 
επάνω τις μικρές χρονικές περιόδους υπηρεσίας κατά τη διάρκεια 
μιας έκτακτης ανάγκης) πάλεψε ενάντια στα redcoats κοντά σε 
αυτήν την πόλη της βόρειας Καρολίνας λιγότερων από 100 
ανθρώπους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">las miradas en este battle?how fue luchada; 
cómo su resultado fue caracterizado, incluyendo informes de 
general Nathanael Greene y de señor Cornwallis; y porqué era 
importante. La cerca de milicia 1.700 Continentals (enlistees de
tres años en el ejército regular) y 2.700 (sobre todo granjeros que 
eran soldados temporales no profesionales llamados para arriba por 
períodos cortos del servicio durante una emergencia) luchó contra 
los redcoats cerca de esta ciudad de Carolina del Norte de menos de 
100 personas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206390</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106254</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/guilford-courthouse-a-pivotal-battle-in-the-war-for-independence</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
