<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103987</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103987</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207021</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Battle of Bennington: An American Victory</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Schlacht von Bennington: Ein 
Amerikanischer Sieg</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La bataille de Bennington : Une Victoire 
Américaine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A batalha de Bennington: Uma Vitória 
Americana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La battaglia di Bennington: Una Vittoria 
Americana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η μάχη Bennington: Μια αμερικανική νίκη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La batalla de Bennington: Una Victoria 
Americana</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">recounts a small but important triumph in the summer of 1777. For two months, General John Burgoyne led his army along the Lake Champlain-Hudson River corridor, capturing several American forts. In August, however, finding himself in need of provisions, wagons, and horses, he sent a force to Bennington, Vermont, to capture these supplies. What happened there contributed to the British defeat at Saratoga and helped decide the outcome of the war.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">zählt einen kleinen aber wichtigen Triumph am 
Sommer von 1777 nach. Für zwei Monate führte General John 
Burgoyne seine Armee entlang dem See Champlain-Hudson Flußflur und 
erfaßte einige amerikanische Forts. Im August mangels der 
Bestimmungen, der Lastwagen und der Pferde jedoch finden, schickte er 
Bennington eine Kraft, Vermont, um dieses Zubehör zu erfassen. 
Was dort beigetragen zur britischen Niederlage bei Saratoga und 
geholfen das, Resultat des Krieges zu entscheiden geschah.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">raconte un petit mais important triomphe en été 
de 1777. Pendant deux mois, le Général John Burgoyne a mené 
son armée le long du couloir de fleuve de Champlain-Hudson de lac, 
capturant plusieurs forts américains. En août, cependant, se 
trouvant nécessitant des dispositions, des chariots, et des chevaux, 
il a envoyé une force à Bennington, Vermontn, pour capturer ces 
approvisionnements. Ce qui s'est produit là contribué à la 
défaite britannique chez Saratoga et aidé à décider les résultats
de la guerre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">recounts um triunfo pequeno mas importante no 
verão de 1777. Por dois meses, o general John Burgoyne conduziu
a seu exército ao longo do corredor do rio de Champlain-Hudson do 
lago, capturando diversos forts americanos. Em agosto, 
entretanto, encontrando-se na necessidade das provisões, dos vagões,
e dos cavalos, emitiu uma força a Bennington, Vermont, para capturar 
estas fontes. O que aconteceu contribuído lá à derrota 
britânica em Saratoga e ajudado decidir o resultado da guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">racconta un piccolo ma trionfo importante di 
estate di 1777. Per due mesi, il General John Burgoyne ha 
condotto il suo esercito lungo il corridoio del fiume di 
Champlain-Hudson del lago, bloccante parecchi forts americani. 
In agosto, tuttavia, trovandosi necessitante le disposizioni, i 
vagoni ed i cavalli, ha trasmesso una forza a Bennington, Vermont, per
bloccare questi rifornimenti. Che cosa è accaduto là 
contribuito alla sconfitta britannica a Saratoga e contribuito a 
decidere il risultato della guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξιστορεί έναν μικρό αλλά σημαντικό θρίαμβο το 
καλοκαίρι 1777. Για δύο μήνες, ο στρατηγός John 
Burgoyne οδήγησε το στρατό του κατά μήκος του διαδρόμου 
ποταμών θχαμπλαην- Hudson λιμνών, που συλλαμβάνει διάφορα 
αμερικανικά οχυρά. Τον Αύγουστο, εντούτοις, που έχει 
ανάγκη από παροχές, βαγόνια εμπορευμάτων, και άλογα, έστειλε 
μια δύναμη σε Bennington, Βερμόντ, για να συλλάβει αυτές τις 
προμήθειες. Αυτό που συνέβη εκεί συνέβαλε στη βρετανική 
ήττα σε Saratoga και βοήθησε να αποφασίσει την έκβαση του 
πολέμου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">contó de nuevo un triunfo pequeño pero 
importante en el verano de 1777. Por dos meses, general Juan 
Burgoyne condujo a su ejército a lo largo del pasillo del río de 
Champlain-Hudson del lago, capturando varias fortalezas americanas. 
En agosto, sin embargo, encontrándose en la necesidad de 
provisiones, de carros, y de caballos, él envió una fuerza a 
Bennington, Vermont, para capturar estas fuentes. Qué sucedió 
allí contribuido a la derrota británica en Saratoga y ayudado a 
decidir al resultado de la guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207021</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103987</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-battle-of-bennington-an-american-victory</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
