<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107107</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107107</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087308</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"A Heritage of Scorn": Harper Urges A Color-Blind Cause</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ein Erbe von verachtet": Harper Drängt Auf
eine Farbenblinde Ursache</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"un héritage de dédaignent" : Harper 
Pousse Une Cause Daltonienne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"um heritage de scorn": Harper Incita Uma 
Causa Color-Blind</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"un'eredità di disprezza": Harper Sollecita
Una Causa Color-Blind</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Μια κληρονομιά της περιφρόνησησ": Το Harper 
ωθεί μια δαλτωνική αιτία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"una herencia de desprecia": Harper Impulsa 
Una Causa Color-Blind</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The struggle for woman suffrage lasted almost a century, beginning with the 1848 Woman's Rights Convention at Seneca Falls, New York, and including the 1890 union of two competing suffrage organizations to form the National American Woman Suffrage Association (NAWSA). NAWSA and other organizations campaigned diligently for the vote in a variety of ways, but did not achieve success until the ratification of the Nineteenth Amendment to the U.S. Constitution in 1920. This prolonged struggle entangled female activists in other important political and moral issues that divided the nation along racial, ethnic, and class lines, and debates over the vote for women often took a divisive tone. In this 1891 speech to the National Council of Women, African-American abolitionist, lecturer, and writer Frances Ellen Watkins Harper answered the racist charges of white suffragists who saw the vote for (white) women as a way to maintain white supremacy. The vote for African-Americans, both men and women, Harper argued, was a matter of "justice, simple justice."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Kampf für Fraustimmrecht dauerte fast ein 
Jahrhundert, fing mit der 1848 Recht-Vereinbarung der Frau an den 
Seneca-Fällen, New York an, und enthält den Anschluß 1890 von zwei 
konkurrierenden Stimmrechtorganisationen, um die nationale 
amerikanische Frau-Stimmrecht-Verbindung (NAWSA) zu bilden. 
NAWSA und andere Organisationen warben mit Sorgfalt für die 
Stimme in einer Vielzahl von Methoden, aber erzielten Erfolg bis die 
Bestätigung der 19.änderung nicht zur VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Beschaffenheit 1920. Dieser verlängerte Kampf verwickelte 
weibliche Aktivisten in anderen wichtigen politischen und moralischen 
Ausgaben, die die Nation entlang rassischem teilten, ethnisch, und in 
Kategorie Zeilen, und Debatten über der Stimme für Frauen nahmen 
häufig einen teilenden Ton. In dieser Rede 1891 zum Nationalrat
der Frauen, beantworteten Afrikanisch-Amerikanisches abolitionist, 
Lektor und Verfasser Frances Ellen Watkins Harper die rassistischen 
Ladungen der weißen suffragists, die die Stimme für (Weiß) Frauen 
als Methode, weiße Vorherrschaft beizubehalten sahen. Die 
Stimme für Afrikanisch-Amerikaner, Männer und Frauen, argumentiertes
Harper, war ein Stoff von "Gerechtigkeit, einfache Gerechtigkeit."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La lutte pour le suffrage de femme a duré presque
un siècle, commençant par 1848 la convention des droits de la femme 
aux automnes de Seneca, New York, et incluant l'union 1890 de deux
organismes de concurrence de suffrage pour former l'association 
américaine nationale de suffrage de femme (NAWSA). NAWSA et 
d'autres organismes ont fait campagne diligemment pour la voix par une
multitude de moyens, mais n'ont pas réalisé le succès jusqu'à la 
ratification du dix-neuvième amendement à la constitution des 
ETATS-UNIS en 1920. Cette lutte prolongée a empêtré les 
activistes féminins dans d'autres issues importantes qui ont divisé 
la nation le long de racial, ethnique, et lignes politiques et morales
de classe, et les discussions au-dessus de la voix pour des femmes ont
souvent pris une tonalité séparative. Dans ce discours 1891 au
Conseil national des femmes, l'abolitionniste afro-américain, le 
conférencier, et l'auteur Frances Ellen Watkins Harper ont répondu 
aux frais racistes des suffragettes blanches qui ont vu la voix pour 
des femmes (de blanc) comme voie de mettre à jour la suprématie 
blanche. La voix pour des Afro-Américains, des hommes et des 
femmes, Harper discuté, était une question de "juge, juge simple."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O esforço para o suffrage da mulher durou quase 
um século, começando com a convenção 1848 da mulher em quedas do 
seneca, New York das direitas, e incluindo a união 1890 de duas 
organizações competindo do suffrage para dar forma à associação 
americana nacional do suffrage da mulher (NAWSA). NAWSA e outras
organizações fizeram campanha diligently para o voto em uma 
variedade das maneiras, mas não conseguiram o sucesso até o 
ratification da décima nona emenda ao constitution de ESTADOS UNIDOS 
em 1920. Este esforço prolongado entangled activistas fêmeas 
em outras edições importantes que dividiram a nação ao longo de 
racial, étnico, e linhas políticas e morais da classe, e os debates 
sobre o voto para mulheres fizeram exame frequentemente de um tom 
divisive. Neste discurso 1891 ao conselho nacional das mulheres,
o abolitionist, o lecturer, e o escritor Africano-Americanos Frances 
Ellen Watkins Harper responderam às cargas racist de suffragists 
brancos que viram o voto para mulheres (do branco) como uma maneira 
manter o supremacy branco. O voto para Africano-Americanos,  
homens e mulheres, Harper discutido, era uma matéria da "justiça, 
justiça simples."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La lotta per suffrage della donna ha durato quasi 
un secolo, cominciante con la convenzione 1848 della donna alle cadute
del seneca, New York di diritti ed includente l'unione 1890 di due 
organizzazioni competenti di suffrage per formare l'associazione 
americana nazionale di suffrage della donna (NAWSA). NAWSA ed 
altre organizzazioni hanno fatto una campagna diligente per il voto in
una varietà di modi, ma non hanno realizzato il successo fino alla 
ratifica della diciannovesima correzione alla costituzione degli STATI
UNITI in 1920. Questa lotta prolungata ha impigliato gli 
attivisti femminili in altre edizioni importanti che hanno diviso la
nazione lungo razziale, etnico e righe politiche e morali del codice 
categoria ed i dibattiti sopra il voto per le donne hanno preso spesso
un tono che divide. In questo discorso 1891 al Consiglio 
nazionale delle donne, il abolitionist, il conferenziere ed il 
produttore Africano-Americani Frances Ellen Watkins Harper hanno 
risposto alle spese razziste dei suffragists bianchi che hanno visto 
il voto per le donne (di bianco) come modo effettuare il supremacy 
bianco. Il voto per gli Africano-Americani, sia uomini che 
donne, Harper discusso, era un aspetto "di giustizia, giustizia 
semplice."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η προσπάθεια για την ψήφο γυναικών διάρκεσε σχεδόν 
έναν αιώνα, αρχίζοντας με τη 1848 Συνθήκη δικαιωμάτων της 
γυναίκας σε Σενέκα Falls, Νέα Υόρκη, και συμπεριλαμβανομένης 
της ένωσης 1890 δύο ανταγωνιστικών οργανώσεων ψήφου για να 
διαμορφώσει την εθνική αμερικανική ένωση ψήφου γυναικών 
(NAWSA). NAWSA και άλλες οργανώσεις έκαναν εκστρατεία
επιμελώς για την ψηφοφορία με ποικίλους τρόπους, αλλά δεν 
επέτυχαν την επιτυχία μέχρι την επικύρωση της δέκατης έννατης 
τροποποίησης στο ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΌ σύνταγμα το 1920. Αυτή η 
παρατεταμένη προσπάθεια έμπλεξε τα θηλυκά ενεργά στελέχη σε 
άλλα σημαντικά πολιτικά και ηθικά ζητήματα που διαίρεσαν το 
έθνος κατά μήκος φυλετικού, εθνικός, και οι γραμμές κλάσης, και
οι συζητήσεις πέρα από την ψηφοφορία για τις γυναίκες πήραν 
συχνά έναν διαχωριστικό τόνο. Σε αυτήν την ομιλία 1891 
στο εθνικό Συμβούλιο των γυναικών, ο αφρικανικός-αμερικανικός 
ρεφορμιστής, ο ομιλητής, και ο συγγραφέας Frances Ellen 
Watkins Harper απάντησαν στις ρατσιστικές δαπάνες λευκοί 
suffragists που εβλέίδαν την ψηφοφορία για (τις λευκές) 
γυναίκες ως τρόπο να διατηρήσει η άσπρη υπεροχή. Η 
ψηφοφορία για αφρικανικός-Αμερικανούς, και άνδρες και γυναίκες, 
Harper που υποστηρίχτηκε, ήταν ένα θέμα "δικαιοσύνης, απλή 
δικαιοσύνη."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La lucha para el sufragio de la mujer casi duró 
un siglo, comenzando con la convención 1848 de la mujer en las 
caídas del seneca, Nueva York de las derechas, e incluyendo la unión
1890 de dos organizaciones competentes del sufragio para formar la 
asociación americana nacional del sufragio de la mujer (NAWSA). 
NAWSA y otras organizaciones hicieron campaña diligente para el
voto en una variedad de maneras, pero no alcanzaron éxito hasta la 
ratificación de la diecinueveavo enmienda a la constitución de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS en 1920. Esta lucha prolongada enredó a 
activistas femeninos en otras ediciones importantes que dividieron la 
nación a lo largo de racial, étnico, y líneas políticas y morales 
de la clase, y los discusiones sobre el voto para las mujeres tomaron 
a menudo un tono divisivo. En este discurso 1891 al consejo 
nacional de mujeres, el abolitionist, el conferenciante, y el programa
de escritura Africano-Americanos Frances Ellen Watkins Harper 
contestaron a las cargas racist de suffragists blancos que vieron el 
voto para las mujeres (del blanco) como manera de mantener la 
supremacía blanca. El voto para los Africano-Americanos, los 
hombres y las mujeres, Harper discutido, era una cuestión de 
"justicia, justicia simple."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087308</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107107</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-heritage-of-scorn-harper-urges-a-color-blind-cause</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
