<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105018</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105018</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200920</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Cloud Protocols</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wolke Protokolle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Protocoles de Nuage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Protocolos Da Nuvem</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Protocolli Della Nube</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πρωτόκολλα σύννεφων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Protocolos De la Nube</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This PDF document discusses a field activity for K-12 students. The purpose of the activity is to observe type and cover of clouds including contrails. Students will observe ten types of clouds and how many of three types of contrails are visible, how much of the sky is covered with clouds, and how much is covered by contrails. The PDF is an instructor guide with detailed advice for administering the activity and data sheets.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses pdf Dokument behandelt eine 
auffangenaktivität für Kursteilnehmer K-12. Der Zweck der
Aktivität ist, Typen und Abdeckung der Wolken einschließlich 
Contrails zu beobachten. Kursteilnehmer beobachten 10 Typen 
Wolken und wieviele von drei Typen Contrails sichtbar sind, wieviel 
des Himmels mit Wolken bedeckt wird und wieviel durch Contrails 
bedeckt wird. Das pdf ist eine Ausbilderanleitung mit 
ausführlichem Rat für das Ausüben der Aktivität und 
Leistungsblätter.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce document de pdf discute une activité de zone 
pour les étudiants K-12. Le but de l'activité est d'observer 
le type et la couverture de nuages comprenant des contrails. Les
étudiants observeront dix types de nuages et lesquels de trois types 
de contrails sont visibles, quelle quantité de ciel est couvert de 
nuages, et combien est couvert par des contrails. Le pdf est un 
guide d'instructeur avec le conseil détaillé pour gérer les 
fiches techniques d'activité et.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este original do pdf discute uma atividade do 
campo para os estudantes K-12. A finalidade da atividade é 
observar o tipo e a tampa das nuvens including contrails. Os 
estudantes observarão dez tipos de nuvens e quanto de três tipos de 
contrails são visíveis, quanto do céu são cobertas com as nuvens, 
e quanto é coberto por contrails. O pdf é uma guia do 
instrutor com conselho detalhado para administrar as folhas da 
atividade e de dados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo documento del pdf discute un'attività del 
campo per gli allievi K-12. Lo scopo dell'attività è osservare
il tipo e la copertura di nubi compreso i contrails. Gli allievi
osserveranno dieci tipi di nubi e quant0 di tre tipi di contrails sono
visibili, quanto del cielo è coperto di nubi e quanto è coperto dai 
contrails. Il pdf è una guida dell'istruttore con consiglio 
dettagliato per l'amministrazione dei fogli di dati e di attività.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το παρόν έγγραφο PDF συζητά μια δραστηριότητα 
πεδίων για Κ- 12 σπουδαστές. Ο σκοπός της δραστηριότητας 
είναι να παρατηρηθεί ο τύπος και η κάλυψη των σύννεφων 
συμπεριλαμβανομένου contrails. Οι σπουδαστές θα 
παρατηρήσουν δέκα τύπους σύννεφων και πόσοι από τρεις τύπους 
contrails είναι ορατοί, πόσο του ουρανού καλύπτεται με τα 
σύννεφα, και πόσο καλύπτεται από τα contrails. Το PDF 
είναι ένας οδηγός εκπαιδευτικών με τις λεπτομερείς συμβουλές για
τη διαχείρηση των φύλλων δραστηριότητας και στοιχείων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este documento del pdf discute una actividad del 
campo para los estudiantes K-12. El propósito de la actividad 
es observar el tipo y la cubierta de nubes incluyendo las estelas de 
vapor. Los estudiantes observarán diez tipos de nubes y 
cuántos de tres tipos de estelas de vapor son visibles, cuánto del 
cielo se cubre con las nubes, y cuánto es cubierta por las estelas de
vapor. El pdf es una guía del instructor con el consejo 
detallado para administrar las hojas de la actividad y de datos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:GLOBE PROGRAM OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA
FN:GLOBE PROGRAM OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200920</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105018</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/cloud-protocols</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
