<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104974</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104974</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087274</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"A Bill of Rights for the Indians": John Collier Envisions an Indian New Deal</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"eine Verfassung für die Inder": John 
Collier stellt sich ein indisches neues Abkommen vor</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"une déclaration des droits pour les Indiens" : 
John Collier envisage une nouvelle affaire indienne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"uma conta de direitas para os indians": O 
collier de John envisions um negócio novo indian</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"una fattura dei diritti per gli indiani": 
Il collier del John prevede un nuovo affare indiano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ένας Bill των δικαιωμάτων για τους Ινδούσ": 
Θ*Ιοχν Collier Envisions μια ινδική νέα διαπραγμάτευση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"una cuenta de las derechas para los indios": 
El collier de Juan preve un nuevo reparto indio</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">John Collier's appointment as Commissioner of Indian Affairs by Franklin Roosevelt in 1933 marked a radical reversal--in intention if not always in effect--in U.S. government policies toward American Indians that dated back to the 1887 Dawes Act. An idealistic social worker, Collier first encountered Indian culture when he visited Taos, New Mexico, in 1920, and found among the Pueblos there what he called a "Red Atlantis"--a model of living that integrated the needs of the individual with the group and that maintained traditional values. Although Collier could not win congressional backing for his most radical proposals, the Indian Reorganization Act of 1934 dramatically changed policy by allowing tribal self-government and consolidating individual land allotments back into tribal hands. Collier set out his vision for what became known as the "Indian New Deal" in this 1934 article from the  Literary Digest . Although he was sympathetic to Indians, he depicted them in a stereotypical manner.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Verabredung des John Colliers als Beauftragtes der
indischen Angelegenheiten durch Franklin Roosevelt in 1933 
kennzeichnete eine radikale Umlenkung -- in der Absicht wenn nicht 
immer in Wirklichkeit -- in den VEREINIGTE STAATEN Regierung 
politischen Richtlinien in Richtung zu den Indianern, die auf der 
Dawes Tat 1887 zurückgingen. Ein idealistic Sozialarbeiter, 
Collier traf zuerst indische Kultur an, als er Taos, New-Mexico, 1920 
besuchte und unter den Pueblos dort fand, was er ein "rotes Atlantis" 
nannte -- ein Modell von leben das integrierte die Notwendigkeiten der
Einzelperson mit der Gruppe und das behielt traditionelle Werte. 
Obgleich Collier nicht Kongreßschutzträger für seine 
radikalsten Anträge, die indische Reorganisierung-Tat von 1934 
drastisch geänderter Politik gewinnen könnte, indem er Stammes- 
Self-government erlaubte und einzelne Landzuteilungen zurück in 
Stammes- Hände vereinigte. Collier legte seinen Anblick für 
dar, was während das "indische neue Abkommen" in diesem Artikel 1934 
von der literarischen Auswahl bekannt wurde. Obgleich er zu den 
Indern sympatisch war, stellte er sie in einer stereotypischen Weise 
bildlich dar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La nomination de John Collier comme 
commissaire des affaires indiennes par Franklin Roosevelt dans 1933 a 
marqué une inversion radicale -- dans l'intention si pas toujours en 
effet -- dans des politiques de gouvernement des ETATS-UNIS vers les 
Indiens d'Amerique qui ont remonté à la Loi 1887 de Dawes. Un 
ouvrier social idéaliste, Collier a rencontré la première fois 
la culture indienne quand il a visité Taos, Nouveau-Mexique, en 1920,
et a trouvé parmi les pueblos là ce qu'il a appelé "une Atlantide 
rouge" -- un modèle de la vie cela a intégré les besoins de 
l'individu avec le groupe et cela a mis à jour des valeurs 
traditionnelles. Bien que Collier ne pourrait pas gagner le 
support congressionnel pour ses propositions plus radicales, l'acte 
indien de réorganisation de 1934 politiques excessivement changées 
en permettant art de l'auto-portrait-government tribal et en consolidant 
différentes attributions de terre de nouveau dans les mains tribales.
Collier a visé sa vision pour ce qui est devenu notoire 
pendant que "la nouvelle affaire indienne" en cet article 1934 du 
sommaire littéraire. Bien qu'il ait été bien disposé aux 
Indiens, il les a dépeints d'une façon stéréotypée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A nomeação do collier de John como o comissário
de casos indian por Franklin Roosevelt em 1933 marcou uma reversão 
radical -- na intenção if.not sempre de fato -- em políticas do 
governo de ESTADOS UNIDOS para os indians americanos que dataram para 
trás ao ato 1887 de Dawes. Um trabalhador social idealistic, 
collier encontrou primeiramente a cultura indian quando visitou Taos, 
Novo México, em 1920, e encontrou entre os povoados indíginos lá o 
que se chamou "um Atlantis vermelho" -- um modelo de viver isso 
integrou as necessidades do indivíduo com o grupo e aquele manteve 
valores tradicionais. Embora o collier não poderia ganhar o 
revestimento protetor congressional para suas propostas mais radicais,
o ato indian do reorganization de 1934 políticas dramàtica mudadas 
permitindo o self-government tribal e consolidando allotments 
individuais da terra para trás nas mãos tribais. O collier 
ajustou-se para fora de sua visão para o que se tornou sabido 
enquanto "o negócio novo indian" neste artigo 1934 do sumário 
literário. Embora fosse sympathetic aos indians, descreveu-os 
em uma maneira stereotypical.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'appuntamento del collier del John come 
commissario degli affari indiani da Franklin Roosevelt in 1933 ha 
contrassegnato un'inversione radicale -- nell'intenzione se non sempre
in effetti -- nelle politiche di governo degli STATI UNITI verso gli 
indiani americani che hanno datato dalla Legge 1887 di Dawes. Un
operaio sociale idealistic, collier in primo luogo ha incontrato la 
coltura indiana quando ha visitato Taos, Nuovo Messico, in 1920 ed ha 
trovato fra i pueblos là che cosa ha chiamato "un Atlantis rosso" -- 
un modello di vivere quello ha integrato i bisogni dell'individuo con 
il gruppo e quello ha effettuato i valori tradizionali. Anche se
il collier non potrebbe vincere la protezione congressuale per le sue 
proposte più radicali, la Legge indiana della riorganizzazione delle 
1934 politiche drammaticamente cambiate permettendo il self-government
tribale e consolidando le diverse assegnazioni della terra nuovamente 
dentro le mani tribali. Il collier ha precisato la sua visione 
per che cosa è stato conosciuto come "il nuovo affare indiano" in 
questo articolo 1934 dalla raccolta letteraria. Anche se era 
simpatico agli indiani, li ha descritti in un modo stereotypical.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο διορισμός John Collier's ως Επίτροπος των 
ινδικών υποθέσεων από Franklin Roosevelt το 1933 
χαρακτήρισε μια ριζική αντιστροφή -- στην πρόθεση εάν όχι πάντα
ουσιαστικά -- στις πολιτικές ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ κυβέρνησης προς 
αμερικανικούς Ινδούς που χρονολογημένος από το νόμο 1887 
Dawes. Ένας ιδεαλιστικός κοινωνικός λειτουργός, 
ανθρακωρύχος αντιμετώπισε αρχικά τον ινδικό πολιτισμό όταν 
επισκέφτηκε Taos, New Mexico, το 1920, και βρήκε μεταξύ
του Pueblos εκεί τι κάλεσε "κόκκινο Atlantis" -- ένα 
μοντέλο της διαβίωσης που ενσωμάτωσε τις ανάγκες του ατόμου με 
την ομάδα και που διατήρησε τις παραδοσιακές αξίες. Αν και ο
ανθρακωρύχος δεν θα μπορούσε να κερδίσει την του Κογκρέσου 
υποστήριξη για τις ριζικότερες προτάσεις του, ο ινδικός νόμος 
αναδιοργάνωσης της αλλαγμένης πολιτικής του 1934 εντυπωσιακά με
την άδεια της φυλετικής μόνος-κυβέρνησης και την παγίωση των 
μεμονωμένων διανομών εδάφους πίσω στα φυλετικά χέρια. Ο 
ανθρακωρύχος καθόρισε το όραμά του για αυτό που έγινε γνωστό ως
"ινδική νέα διαπραγμάτευση" σε αυτό το άρθρο του 1934 από τη 
λογοτεχνική αφομοίωση. Αν και ήταν συμπονετικός σε Ινδούς, 
τους απεικόνισε κατά τρόπο stereotypical.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La cita del collier de Juan como comisión de 
asuntos indios de Franklin Roosevelt en 1933 marcó una revocación 
radical -- en la intención si no siempre en efecto -- en políticas 
del gobierno de ESTADOS UNIDOS hacia los indios americanos que 
fecharon de nuevo al acto 1887 de Dawes. Un trabajador social 
idealista, collier primero encontró la cultura india cuando él 
visitó Taos, New México, en 1920, y encontró entre los pueblos 
allí lo que él llamó un "Atlantis rojo" -- un modelo de vivir eso 
integró las necesidades del individuo con el grupo y ése mantuvo 
valores tradicionales. Aunque el collier no podría ganar el 
forro del congreso para sus ofertas más radicales, el acto indio de 
la reorganización de 1934 políticas dramáticamente cambiantes 
permitiendo el gobierno autónomo tribal y consolidando asignaciones 
individuales de la pista nuevamente dentro de las manos tribales. 
El collier precisó su visión para qué se sabía mientras que 
el "nuevo reparto indio" en este artículo 1934 del resumen literario.
Aunque él era comprensivo a los indios, él los representó de 
una manera stereotypical.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087274</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104974</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-bill-of-rights-for-the-indians-john-collier-envisions-an-indian-new-deal</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
