<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103960</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103960</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204321</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Heaven or "Groundhog Day?"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Himmel oder "Groundhog Tag?"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ciel ou "jour de Groundhog?"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Heaven ou de "dia Groundhog?"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Cielo o "giorno di Groundhog?"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ουρανός ή "ημέρα Groundhog;"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cielo o "día de Groundhog?"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This unit is designed to appeal to adolescents with its non-print text base, the movie "Groundhog Day". he pre-viewing activities prepare students for the allusions in the movie and include cultural literacy. The teacher can pick and choose from the activities to apply the concept of personal growth. The teacher may select from activities for science, workplace ethics, music, computer competency, and English language arts. The teacher may modify any of the attachments to suit the students' needs and interests.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Maßeinheit ist konzipiert, um Jugendlichen mit 
seiner nichtausgedruckten Textunterseite, der Film "Groundhog Tag" zu 
gefallen. er Aktivitäten vorher sehend bereitet Kursteilnehmer 
für die Anspielungen im Film vor und schließt kulturellen 
Bildungsgrad ein. Der Lehrer kann und von den Aktivitäten 
beschließen, das Konzept des persönlichen Wachstums anzuwenden 
auswählen. Der Lehrer kann von den Aktivitäten für 
Wissenschaft, Arbeitsplatzethik, Musik, Computerkompetenz und 
englische Sprachenkünste auswählen. Der Lehrer kann 
irgendwelche der Zubehöre ändern, um der den Notwendigkeiten und den
Interessen Kursteilnehmer zu entsprechen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette unité est conçue pour faire appel aux adolescents 
avec sa base non imprimée des textes, le film "jour de Groundhog". 
il visionnant des activités préalablement préparent des 
étudiants pour les allusions dans le film et incluent l'instruction 
culturelle. Le professeur peut sélectionner et choisir des 
activités d'appliquer le concept de la croissance personnelle. 
Le professeur peut choisir parmi des activités pour la science,
l'éthique de lieu de travail, la musique, la compétence 
d'ordinateur, et les arts d'anglais. Le professeur peut modifier
n'importe laquelle de ces connexions pour convenir aux besoins et aux 
intérêts des étudiants.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta unidade é projetada apelar aos adolescents com sua 
base non-print do texto, o filme de "dia Groundhog". que 
inspeciona atividades prepara estudantes para os allusions no filme e 
inclui o literacy cultural. O professor pode escolher e 
escolhê-lo das atividades aplicar o conceito do crescimento pessoal. 
O professor pode selecionar das atividades para a ciência, os 
ethics do workplace, a música, o competency do computador, e as artes
da língua inglesa. O professor pode modificar alguns dos 
acessórios para servir as necessidades e interesses dos estudantes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa unità è destinata per fare appello agli 
adolescenti con la relativa base non stampabile del testo, il 
film "giorno di Groundhog". che vede in anteprima le 
attività prepara gli allievi per le allusioni nel film ed 
include il literacy culturale. L'insegnante può selezionare e 
scegliere dalle attività applicare il concetto di sviluppo personale.
L'insegnante può scegliere dalle attività per la scienza, 
l'etica del posto di lavoro, la musica, la competenza del calcolatore 
e le arti di lingua inglese. L'insegnante può modificare c'è 
ne dei collegamenti per soddisfare i bisogni e gli interessi degli 
allievi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η μονάδα σχεδιάζεται για να απευθυνθεί στους 
εφήβους με τη βάση κειμένων μη-τυπωμένων υλών της, ο 
κινηματογράφος "ημέρα Groundhog". δραστηριότητες προ-όψης
προετοιμάζει τους σπουδαστές για τις νύξεις στον κινηματογράφο και
περιλαμβάνει την πολιτιστική βασική εκπαίδευση. Ο δάσκαλος 
μπορεί να επιλέξει και να επιλέξει από τις δραστηριότητες να 
εφαρμόσει την έννοια της προσωπικής αύξησης. Ο δάσκαλος 
μπορεί να επιλέξει από τις δραστηριότητες για την επιστήμη, την 
ηθική εργασιακών χώρων, τη μουσική, την ικανότητα υπολογιστών, 
και τις τέχνες αγγλικής γλώσσας. Ο δάσκαλος μπορεί να 
τροποποιήσει οποιες δήποτε από τις συνδέσεις για να ανταποκριθεί 
στις ανάγκες και τα ενδιαφέροντα των σπουδαστών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta unidad se diseña para abrogar a los adolescentes con
su base non-print del texto, la película "día de Groundhog". 
él que ve actividades de antemano prepara a estudiantes para 
las alusiones en la película e incluye la instrucción cultural. 
El profesor puede escoger y elegir de las actividades aplicar el
concepto del crecimiento personal. El profesor puede seleccionar
de las actividades para la ciencia, los éticas del lugar de trabajo, 
la música, la capacidad del ordenador, y los artes del lenguaje 
inglés. El profesor puede modificar cualesquiera de las 
conexiones para satisfacer las necesidades y los intereses de los 
estudiantes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JULIA MILLUSH
FN:JULIA MILLUSH
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204321</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103960</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/heaven-or-groundhog-day</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
