<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104917</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104917</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085249</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">San Francisco General Strike</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">San Francisco Generalstreik</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Grève de San Francisco</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Batida Geral Do San Francisco</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Colpo Generale De San Francisco</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γενική απεργία του Σαν Φρανσίσκο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Huelga General De San Francisco</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Many people who were employed during the Great Depression grew increasingly dissatisfied with working conditions, and took action by forming labor unions. Although the General Strike of San Francisco took place from July 16 to 19, 1934, it had been brewing for months. In March, Harry Bridges (shown in two photographs) led his International Longshoremen?s Association (ILA, which represented the dockworkers), in a vote to strike for control of hiring halls, better pay, and better hours. The ILA strike officially began on May 9, 1934. A photograph from May 8 shows longshoremen waiting for the strike deadline, and an image from May 10 shows Bridges leading picketers down San Francisco?s Embarcadero. Other images show strikers in line for food, and a young man trying to decide whether or not to picket. On July 5, when employers tried to open the docks and unload ships, strikers clashed with 1,000 armed police officers. Photographs show police confronting the strikers with what appears to be gunsmoke on one side, and police with tear gas guns. When it was over, 64 were injured and two men were killed on what became known as "Bloody Thursday." The deaths of the men and the huge, public funeral for them (shown in two photographs), helped Bridges rally the support of other unions in the city to join the strike. This General Strike effectively shut down the city of San Francisco for four days. The strike was a success: many of the ILA?s demands were met. A photograph taken in front of the Emporium department store shows a newspaper vendor selling the issue announcing the end of the strike. The following year, 1935, the Wagner Act created the National Labor Relations Board that protects the rights of workers to organize into unions. The General Strike brought economic and political power for labor unions that would last for decades.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Viele Leute, die während des großen Tiefstands 
beschäftigt wurden, wuchsen in zunehmendem Maße mit 
Arbeitsbedingungen unzufrieden gemacht und ergriffen Maßnahmen, indem
sie Arbeiterverbände bildeten. Obgleich der Generalstreik von 
San Francisco von einem Juli 16 bis 19 stattfand, 1934, hatte er für 
Monate gebraut. Im März führten die Harry Brücken (gezeigt in
zwei Fotographien) seine internationale Longshoremen?s Verbindung 
(ILA, die die dockworkers darstellte), in einer Stimme, um zur 
Steuerung der Einstellungssäle, der besseren Bezahlung und der 
besseren Stunden anzuschlagen. Der ILA Schlag fing offiziell an 
Mai 9, 1934 an. Eine Fotographie von einem Mai 8 zeigt die 
Longshoremen, die den Schlagstichtag warten, und ein Bild von einem 
Mai 10 zeigt die Brücken, die unten Streikposten San Francisco?s 
Embarcadero führen. Andere Bilder zeigen Schlaggeräte in der 
Zeile für Nahrung und einen jungen Mann, der, zu entscheiden ob oder 
versucht nicht einzupfählen. An Juli 5, als die Arbeitgeber, 
die versucht wurden, um die Docks zu öffnen und Schiffe, 
Schlaggeräte aus dem Programm zu nehmen mit 1.000 bewaffneten 
Polizeioffizieren zusammenstießen. Fotographien zeigen die 
Polizei, welche die Schlaggeräte konfrontiert mit, was scheint, 
gunsmoke auf seitlichem einem zu sein und Polizei mit 
Tränengasgewehren. Als es rüber sein, wurden 64 verletzt und 
zwei Männer wurden beendet auf, was wurde bekannt als "blutiger 
Donnerstag." Die Todesfälle der Männer und des sehr großen, 
allgemeinen Begräbnisses für sie (gezeigt in zwei Fotographien), 
geholfene Brücken sammeln den Support anderer Anschlüße in der 
Stadt, um den Schlag zu verbinden. Dieser Generalstreik 
schaltete effektiv die Stadt von San Francisco für vier Tage ab. 
Der Schlag war ein Erfolg: viele der ILA?s Nachfragen 
wurden befriedigt. Eine Fotographie, die vor dem 
Handelszentrumabteilung Speicher genommen wird, zeigt einen Zeitung 
Verkäufer, der die Ausgabe verkauft, die das Ende des Schlages 
verkündet. Das folgende Jahr, 1935, erstellte die Wagner Tat 
das nationale Arbeitgeber-Arbeitnehmer-Beziehungen Brett, das die 
Rechte der Arbeiter schützt, in Anschlüße zu organisieren. 
Der Generalstreik holte ökonomisches und politische Energie 
für Arbeiterverbände, die wurden, für Dekaden dauern.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Beaucoup de personnes qui ont été employées 
pendant la grande dépression se sont développées de plus en plus 
mécontentes avec des conditions de travail, et ont agi en formant les
syndicats. Bien que la grève de San Francisco ait eu lieu à 
partir juillet de 16 à 19, 1934, elle avait brassé pendant des mois.
En mars, les passerelles de Harry (montrées en deux 
photographies) ont mené son association internationale de Travailleurs portuaires
(ILA, qui a représenté les dockworkers), dans une voix pour frapper 
pour la commande des bureaux d'embauchage, du meilleur salaire, et des
meilleures heures. La grève d'ILA a officiellement commencé 
9 mai 1934. Une photographie à partir mai de 8 montre des 
travailleurs portuaires attendant la date-limite de grève, et une image à partir
mai de 10 montre des passerelles menant les piquets de grève vers le 
bas San Francisco Embarcadero. D'autres images montrent des 
grèvistes dans la ligne pour la nourriture, et un jeune homme 
essayant de décider si de ne pas palissader. Juillet 5, quand 
les employeurs jugés pour ouvrir les docks et pour décharger des 
bateaux, butées se sont opposés avec 1.000 officiers de police 
armés. Les photographies montrent la police confrontant les 
butées avec ce qui semble être gunsmoke sur un latéral, et police 
avec des pistolets de gaz lacrymogène. Quand il plus de, 64 ont
été blessés et deux hommes ont été détruits sur ce qui est 
devenu notoire en tant que "jeudi sanglant." Les décès des 
hommes et de l'enterrement énorme et public pour eux (montré en deux
photographies), les passerelles aidées rassemblent le support 
d'autres syndicats dans la ville pour joindre la grève. Cette 
grève a pertinemment arrêté la ville de San Francisco pendant 
quatre jours. La grève était un succès : plusieurs des 
demandes d'ILA?s ont été satisfaites. Une photographie prise 
devant le grand magasin de centre commercial montre un constructeur de
journal vendant le titre annonçant la fin de la grève. 
L'année suivante, 1935, l'acte de Wagner a créé l'office
national de relations sociales qui protège les droites des ouvriers 
d'organiser en syndicats. La grève a apporté économique et 
puissance politique pour les syndicats qui  durer pendant des 
décennies.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Muitos povos que foram empregados durante o 
depression grande cresceram descontentados cada vez mais com 
condições de funcionamento, e fizeram exame da ação dando forma a 
uniões labor. Embora a batida geral de San Francisco ocorresse 
julho 16 a de 19, 1934, brewing por meses. Em março, as pontes 
de Harry (mostradas em duas fotografias) conduziram a sua associação
internacional de Longshoremen?s (ILA, que representou os dockworkers),
em um voto para golpear para o controle de salões empregando, do 
pagamento melhor, e de horas melhores. A batida de ILA começou 
oficialmente maio em 9, 1934. Uma fotografia maio de 8 mostra os
longshoremen que esperam o fim do prazo da batida, e uma imagem maio 
de 10 mostra as pontes que conduzem aos picketers para baixo San 
Francisco?s Embarcadero. Outras imagens mostram grevistas na 
linha para o alimento, e um homem novo que tenta decidir-se se ou não
picket. Julho em 5, quando os empregadores tentados abrir as 
docas e descarregar navios, grevistas clashed com os 1.000 oficiais de
polícias armados. As fotografias mostram as polícias que 
confrontam os grevistas com o o que parece ser gunsmoke em um lateral,
e polícias com os injetores do gás de rasgo. Quando sobre, 64 
foram feridos e dois homens foram matados em o que se tornou sabido 
como "quinta-feira sangrenta." As mortes dos homens e do funeral
enorme, público para eles (mostrado em duas fotografias), pontes 
ajudadas rally a sustentação de outras uniões na cidade para juntar
a batida. Esta batida geral fechou eficazmente abaixo a cidade 
de San Francisco por quatro dias. A batida era um sucesso: 
muitas das demandas de ILA?s foram encontradas com. Uma 
fotografia feita exame na frente da loja de departamento do emporium 
mostra um vendedor do jornal que vende a edição que anuncia o fim da
batida. O seguinte ano, 1935, o ato de Wagner criou a placa de 
relações labor nacional que protege as direitas dos trabalhadores 
organizar em uniões. A batida geral trouxe econômico e 
potência política para as uniões labor que  para durar por 
décadas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Molta gente che è stata impiegata durante la 
depressione grande si è sviluppata sempre più insoddisfatta con le 
condizioni di lavoro ed ha agito formando i sindacati di lavoro. 
Anche se il colpo generale di San Francisco ha avvenuto da 19 
luglio 16 - 1934, stava fermentando per i mesi. In marzo, i 
ponticelli del Harry (indicati in due fotografie) hanno condotto la 
sua associazione internazionale di Longshoremen?s (ILA, che ha 
rappresentato i dockworkers), in un voto per colpire per controllo dei
corridoi assumenti, della paga migliore e delle ore migliori. Il
colpo di ILA ha cominciato ufficialmente maggio su 9, 1934. Una 
fotografia maggio da 8 mostra i longshoremen che aspettano la scadenza
di colpo e un'immagine maggio da 10 mostra i ponticelli che conducono 
i picketers giù il San Francisco?s Embarcadero. Altre immagini 
mostrano i percussori nella riga per alimento e un giovane che prova a
decidere se o a non steccare. Il 5 luglio, quando i datori di 
lavoro hanno provato ad aprire i bacini ed a scaricare le navi, i 
percussori clashed con 1.000 ufficiale di polizia munito. Le 
fotografie mostrano la polizia che confronta i percussori con che cosa
sembra essere gunsmoke su uno laterale e polizia con le pistole del 
gas lacrimogeno. Quando finito, 64 sono stati danneggiati e due 
uomini sono stati uccisi su che cosa è stato conosciuto come 
"giovedì sanguinante." Le morti degli uomini e del funerale 
enorme e pubblico per loro (indicato in due fotografie), ponticelli 
aiutati radunano il supporto di altri sindacati nella città per unire
il colpo. Questo colpo generale ha interrotto efficacemente la 
città di San Francisco per quattro giorni. Il colpo era un 
successo: molte delle esigenze di ILA?s sono state risposte a. 
Una fotografia presa davanti il grande magazzino del emporium 
mostra un fornitore del giornale che vende l'edizione che annuncia la 
conclusione del colpo. Il seguente anno, 1935, la Legge di 
Wagner ha creato il Bordo Di lavoro nazionale di rapporti che 
protegge i diritti degli operai di organizzare nei sindacati. Il
colpo generale ha portato economico e potenza politica per i sindacati
di lavoro che durare le decadi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πολλά άτομα που απασχολήθηκαν κατά τη διάρκεια της 
μεγάλης οικονομικής κρίσης έγιναν όλο και περισσότερο 
δυσαρεστημένα με τις συνθήκες εργασίας, και έλαβαν μέτρα με τη 
διαμόρφωση των εργατικών συνδικάτων. Αν και η γενική 
απεργία του Σαν Φρανσίσκο πραγματοποιήθηκε από τις 16 έως 
19 Ιουλίου ..1934, παρασκεύαζε για τους μήνες. Το 
Μάρτιο, Harry Bridges (που εμφανίζεται σε δύο φωτογραφίες) 
οδήγησε τη διεθνή ένωση Longshoremen?s του (ILA, η οποία 
αντιπροσώπευσε τα dockworkers), σε μια ψηφοφορία για να χτυπήσει
για τον έλεγχο της μίσθωσης των αιθουσών, της καλύτερης αμοιβής, 
και των καλύτερων ωρών. Η απεργία ILA άρχισε επίσημα σε 
Μάιος 9, το 1934. Μια φωτογραφία από Μάιος 8 
εμφανίζει λιμενεργάτες που περιμένουν την προθεσμία απεργίας, και
μια εικόνα από Μάιος 10 εμφανίζει γέφυρες που οδηγούν τα 
picketers κάτω από το SAN Francisco?s Embarcadero. 
Αλλες εικόνες εμφανίζουν τους απεργούς στη γραμμή για τα 
τρόφιμα, και νεαρό άνδρα που προσπαθεί να αποφασίσουν εαν πρέπει
να περιφράξουν. Στις 5 Ιουλίου, όταν προσπάθησαν να 
ανοίξουν τις αποβάθρες και να ξεφορτώσουν οι εργοδότες τα σκάφη, 
οι απεργοί διαφώνησαν με 1.000 οπλισμένους αστυνομικούς. 
Οι φωτογραφίες εμφανίζουν αστυνομία που αντιμετωπίζει τους 
απεργούς με αυτό που εμφανίζεται να είναι gunsmoke σε μια 
πλευρά, και την αστυνομία με τα πυροβόλα όπλα δακρύων αέριο.
Όταν τελείωσε, 64 τραυματίστηκαν και δύο άτομα 
σκοτώθηκαν σε αυτό που έγινε γνωστό ως "αιματηρή Πέμπτη." 
Οι θάνατοι των ατόμων και η τεράστια, δημόσια κηδεία για 
τους (εμφανισμένος σε δύο φωτογραφίες), βοήθησαν τις γέφυρες να 
συναθροίσουν την υποστήριξη άλλων ενώσεων στην πόλη για να 
ενώσουν την απεργία. Αυτή η γενική απεργία διέκοψε 
αποτελεσματικά την πόλη του Σαν Φρανσίσκο για τέσσερις ημέρες. 
Η απεργία ήταν μια επιτυχία: πολλές από τις 
απαιτήσεις ILA?s ικανοποιήθηκαν. Μια φωτογραφία που 
λαμβάνεται μπροστά από το κατάστημα τμημάτων εμπορικών κέντρων 
εμφανίζει προμηθευτή εφημερίδων που πωλεί το ζήτημα 
αναγγέλλοντας το τέλος της απεργίας. Το επόμενο έτος, 
1935, ο νόμος Wagner δημιούργησε το εθνικό συμβούλιο 
σχέσεων εργασίας που προστατεύει τα δικαιώματα των εργαζομένων 
που οργανώνουν στις ενώσεις. Η γενική απεργία έφερε την 
οικονομική και πολιτική δύναμη για τα εργατικά συνδικάτα που θα 
διαρκούσαν για δεκαετίες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mucha gente que fue empleada durante la gran 
depresión creció descontentada cada vez más con condiciones de 
trabajo, y tomó la acción formando sindicatos. Aunque la 
huelga general de San Francisco ocurrió del de julio 16 a 19 de 1934,
había estado elaborando cerveza por meses. En marcha, los 
puentes de Harry (mostrados en dos fotografías) condujeron su 
asociación internacional de Longshoremen?s (ILA, que representó los 
dockworkers), en un voto para pulso para el control de pasillos que 
empleaban, de una paga mejor, y de horas mejores. La huelga de 
ILA comenzó oficialmente 9 de mayo de 1934. Una fotografía 
del de mayo 8 muestra a estibadores que esperan el plazo de la huelga,
y una imagen del de mayo 10 muestra los puentes que conducen a los 
picketers abajo San Francisco?s Embarcadero. Otras imágenes 
muestran a huelguistas en la línea para el alimento, y a hombre joven
que intenta decidir a si o no cercar con piquete. De julio el 5,
cuando los patrones intentados para abrir los muelles y para descargar
las naves, huelguistas clashed con 1.000 oficiales de policía 
armados. Las fotografías muestran a policía que enfrenta los 
huelguistas con qué aparece ser gunsmoke en uno lateral, y policía 
con los armas del gas lacrimógeno. Cuando encima, 64 fueron 
dañados y mataron a dos hombres en qué se conocía como "jueves 
sangriento." Las muertes de los hombres y del entierro enorme, 
público para ellos (mostrado en dos fotografías), los puentes 
ayudados reúnen la ayuda de otras uniones en la ciudad para ensamblar
la huelga. Esta huelga general cerró con eficacia la ciudad de 
San Francisco por cuatro días. La huelga era un éxito: 
muchas de las demandas de ILA?s fueron resueltas. Una 
fotografía tomada delante del almacén grande del emporium muestra a 
vendedor del periódico que vende la edición que anuncia el final de 
la huelga. El año siguiente, 1935, el acto de Wagner creó a 
consejo de relaciones del trabajo nacional que protege las derechas de
trabajadores de ordenar en uniones. La huelga general trajo 
económico y potencia política para los sindicatos que durar por 
décadas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085249</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104917</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/san-francisco-general-strike</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
