<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103878</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103878</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086809</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Self Determination of Free Peoples": Founding Documents of the American Indian Movement (AIM)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Selbstermittlung der freien Völker": 
Gründendokumente der indianischen Bewegung (ZIEL)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"détermination d'Art de l'auto-portrait des peuples libres" 
: Documents de fondation du mouvement indien (BUT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">do "determinação self de povos livres": 
Originais fundando do movimento indian americano (ALVO)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"determinazione di auto della gente libera": 
Documenti fondanti del movimento indiano americano (SCOPO)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Μόνος προσδιορισμός των ελεύθερων λαών": 
Ίδρυση των εγγράφων του αμερικανικού ινδικού Κινήματος 
(AIM)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"determinación del uno mismo de la gente libre": 
Documentos de fundación del movimiento indio americano 
(PUNTERÍA)</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Indian Reorganization Act of 1934 sought to restore tribal self-determination. In the early 1950s, Congress passed legislation to limit this Act, terminating some American Indian reservations and cutting economic support for others. From 1950 to 1970, more than 100 American Indian tribes lost reservation lands, and the percentage of American Indians living on reservations dropped from 87% to 45%. These changes forced young American Indians to look for work in urban areas. In 1968, young urban-based American Indians in Minnesota formed the American Indian Movement (AIM) to fight mistreatment of American Indians by police and to improve prospects for jobs, education, and housing. In the early 1970s, AIM pressured the Federal government to honor 19th-century treaties that had established Indian peoples as sovereign entities. In 1972, AIM initiated "The Trail of Broken Treaties," an intertribal caravan to reservations and subsequent march to Washington. In 1973, more than 2,000 American Indians came to Wounded Knee, South Dakota, on the Pine Ridge Reservation, following a courthouse disturbance. At this historic site where a massacre of Indians by U.S. cavalry soldiers in 1890 ended years of armed conflict, the demand for hearings on sovereignty rights was met with a siege by FBI forces, Federal marshals, and BIA police. The 71-day stand-off ended with assurances that the White House would seriously review the 1868 Fort Laramie Treaty that had recognized sovereignty of the Lakota nation and their rights to valuable lands. That promise failed to materialize, and in the next few years more than 60 AIM members were killed at Pine Ridge. By the end of the decade, plagued by repression and internal disputes, AIM declined as a leading militant organization, although one faction remains. The following foundational documents were submitted to a Congressional committee by undercover FBI informant Doug Durham, who served for a time as AIM's Director of Security.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die indische Reorganisierung-Tat von 1934 suchte, 
Stammes- Self-determination wiederherzustellen. In den frühen 
fünfziger Jahren führte Kongreß Gesetzgebung, um diese Tat zu 
begrenzen und brach etwas indianischen Reservierungen und des Schnitts
ökonomischen Support für andere ab. Von 1950 bis 1970, 
verloren mehr als 100 indianische Stämme Reservierung Länder und den
Prozentsatz der Indianer, die auf den Reservierungen leben, die von 
87% bis 45% fallengelassen wurden. Diese Änderungen erzwangen 
junge Indianer, nach Arbeit in den städtischen Bereichen zu suchen. 
1968 bildeten junge städtisch-gegründete Indianer in Minnesota
die indianische Bewegung (ZIEL) zur Kampfmißhandlung der Indianer 
durch Polizei und Aussichten für Jobs, Ausbildung und Gehäuse zu 
verbessern. In den frühen siebziger Jahren drueckte ZIEL die 
Bundesregierung, um Verträge 19th-century zu ehren, die indische 
Völker als souveräne Instanzen hergestellt hatten. 1972 
initialisiert ZIEL "die Spur der unterbrochenen Verträge," ein 
intertribal Wohnwagen zu den Reservierungen und folgender März nach 
Washington. 1973 kamen mehr als 2.000 Indianer zu verletztem 
Knie, South Dakota, auf der Kiefer-Kante-Reservierung und folgten 
einer Gerichtstörung. An dieser historischen Site, in der ein 
Blutbad der Inder durch VEREINIGTE STAATEN Kavalleriesoldaten in 1890 
Jahre der bewaffneten $überschneidung beendete, wurde die Nachfrage 
nach Hörfähigkeiten auf Hoheitrechten eine Belagerung von den FBI 
Kräften, von den Bundesmarschällen und VON DER BIA Polizei 
getroffen. Der Auslauf 71-day beendete mit Versicherungen, daß 
das Weiße Haus ernsthaft den Fort Laramie Vertrag 1868 wiederholen 
würde, der Hoheit der Lakota Nation und ihrer Rechte zu den 
wertvollen Ländern erkannt hatte. Diese Versprechung, die und 
in den nächsten Jahren verwirklichen nicht können wurde mehr als 60 
ZIEL-Bauteile, wurden an der Kiefer-Kante beendet. Ende der 
Dekade gequält durch Unterdrückung und interne Debatten, sank ZIEL 
als führende militante Organisation, obgleich eine Partei bleibt. 
Die folgenden grundlegenden Dokumente wurden bei einem 
Kongreßausschuß undercover FBI vom Berichterstatter Doug Durham 
eingegeben, der während einer Zeit als Direktor des Zieles der 
Sicherheit diente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Loi indienne de réorganisation de 1934 a 
recherché à restaurer art de l'auto-portrait-determination tribal. Au début
des années 50, le congrès a passé la législation pour limiter 
cette Loi, terminant un certain soutien économique indien de 
réservations et de coupure de d'autres. De 1950 à 1970, plus 
de 100 tribus indiennes ont détruit des terres de réservation, et le
pourcentage des Indiens d'Amerique vivant sur des réservations 
lâchées de 87% à 45%. Ces changements ont forcé de jeunes 
Indiens d'Amerique à rechercher le travail dans des zones urbaines. 
En 1968, les jeunes Indiens d'Amerique urbain-basés au 
Minnesota ont formé le mouvement indien (BUT) au mauvais traitement 
de combat des Indiens d'Amerique par la police et pour améliorer des 
perspectives pour les travaux, l'éducation, et le logement. Au 
début des années 70, le BUT a pressurisé le gouvernement fédéral 
pour honorer les traités 19th-century qui avaient établi les peuples
indiens en tant qu'entités souveraines. En 1972, le BUT lance 
"la traînée des Traités cassés," une caravane de tribus aux 
réservations et marche ultérieure à Washington. En 1973, plus
de 2.000 Indiens d'Amerique sont venus au genou blessé, Dakota 
Du sud, sur la réservation d'arête de pin, suivant une 
perturbation de tribunal. À ce site historique où un 
massacre des Indiens par des soldats de cavalerie des ETATS-UNIS 
dans 1890 a terminé des années de conflit armé, la demande des 
auditions sur des droites de la souveraineté a été rencontrée un 
siège par des forces de FBI, des maréchaux fédéraux, et la 
police de BIA. L'attente 71-day a terminé avec des assurances 
que la Maison Blanche  passerait en revue sérieusement le Traité 
1868 de Laramie de fort qui avait identifié la souveraineté de la 
nation de Lakota et de leurs droites aux terres valables. Cette 
promesse n'est pas matérialisée, et en années à venir plus de 60 
membres de BUT ont été détruites à l'arête de pin. Vers la 
fin de la décennie, infestée par répression et conflits internes, 
le BUT a diminué comme principale organisation militante, bien 
qu'une faction demeure. Les documents fondamentaux suivants ont 
été soumis à un comité congressionnel par l'informateur Doug 
Durham du capot interne FBI, qui a servi pendant un certain 
temps comme directeur du but de sécurité.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O ato indian do reorganization de 1934 procurou 
restaurar o self-determination tribal. Nos 1950s adiantados, o 
congress passou a legislação para limitar este ato, terminando 
alguma sustentação econômica indian americana dos reservations e 
cortar para outra. 1950 a 1970, mais de 100 tribes indian 
americanos perderam terras do reservation, e a porcentagem dos indians
americanos que vivem nos reservations deixados cair de 87% a 45%. 
Estas mudanças forçaram indians americanos novos a procurar o 
trabalho em áreas urbanas. Em 1968, os indians americanos 
urbano-baseados novos em Minnesota deram forma ao movimento indian 
americano (ALVO) ao mau trato da luta de indians americanos por 
polícias e para melhorar prospetos para trabalhos, instrução, e 
carcaça. Nos 1970s adiantados, o ALVO exerceu pressão sobre o 
governo federal para honrar os tratados 19th-century que tinham 
estabelecido povos indian como entidades sovereign. Em 1972, o 
ALVO inicía "a fuga de tratados quebrados," uma caravana intertribal 
aos reservations e março subseqüente a Washington. Em 1973, 
mais de 2.000 indians americanos vieram ao joelho ferido, Dakota sul, 
no reservation do cume do pinho, seguindo um distúrbio do tribunal. 
Neste local historic onde um massacre dos indians por soldados 
da cavalaria de ESTADOS UNIDOS em 1890 terminou anos de conflito 
armado, a demanda para hearings em direitas do sovereignty foi 
encontrada com com um siege por forças de FBI, por marshals federais,
e por polícias de BIA. O stand-off 71-day terminou com 
garantias que a casa branca reveria seriamente o tratado 1868 de 
Laramie do fort que tinha reconhecido o sovereignty da nação de 
Lakota e de suas direitas às terras valiosas. Essa promessa 
não materialize, e em poucos anos seguintes mais de 60 membros do 
ALVO foi matada no cume do pinho. Para o fim da década, 
flagelada pelo repression e por disputas internas, o ALVO declinou 
como uma organização militant principal, embora um faction 
remanescesse. Os seguintes originais foundational foram 
submetidos a um comitê congressional pelo informant Doug Durham de 
capa interna FBI, que serviu por um momento como o diretor do alvo da 
segurança.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Legge indiana della riorganizzazione di 1934 ha
cercato di ristabilire il self-determination tribale. 
Nell'inizio degli anni cinquanta, il congresso ha passato la 
legislazione per limitare questa Legge, terminante un certo sostegno 
economico indiano americano di taglio e di prenotazioni altri. 1950 - 1970, più di 100 tribù indiane americane hanno perso le terre
di prenotazione e la percentuale degli indiani americani che vivono 
sulle prenotazioni cadute da 87% a 45%. Questi cambiamenti hanno
forzato gli indiani americani giovani cercare il lavoro nelle aree 
urbane. In 1968, gli indiani americani urbano-basati giovani nel
Minnesota hanno formato il movimento indiano americano (SCOPO) a 
maltrattamento di lotta degli indiani americani dalla polizia e 
migliorare i prospetti per i lavori, la formazione e l'alloggiamento. 
Agli inizi degli anni 70, lo SCOPO pressured il governo federale
per honor i Trattati 19th-century che avevano istituito la gente 
indiana come entità sovrane. In 1972, lo SCOPO inizia "la 
traccia dei Trattati rotti," un caravan intertribal alle prenotazioni 
e procedere successivo a Washington. In 1973, più di 2.000 
indiani americani sono venuto al ginocchio ferrito, il Dakota del Sud,
sulla prenotazione della cresta del pino, seguente una dispersione del
courthouse. A questo luogo storico in cui un massacre degli 
indiani dai soldati del cavalry degli STATI UNITI in 1890 si è 
concluso anni del conflitto munito, la domanda delle udienze sui 
diritti della sovranità è stata incontrata un siege dalle forze del 
FBI, dai marshals federali e dalla polizia di BIA. Il 
contrappeso 71-day si è concluso con le assicurazioni che la Casa 
Bianca rivedrebbe seriamente i 1868 Trattati Forte di Laramie che
aveva riconosciuto la sovranità della nazione di Lakota e dei loro 
diritti alle terre importanti. Quella promessa non riuscita per 
attuarsi e durante i prossimi anni più di 60 membri di SCOPO è stata
uccisa alla cresta del pino. Per la fine della decade, 
contagiata da repressione e da dispute interne, lo SCOPO ha declinato 
come organizzazione principale del militante, anche se una fazione 
rimane. I seguenti documenti fondamentali sono stati presentati 
ad un comitato congressuale dall'informatore Doug Durham della 
undercover FBI, che ha servito per un certo tempo come direttore dello
scopo di sicurezza.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο ινδικός νόμος αναδιοργάνωσης του 1934 επιδίωξε να
αποκαταστήσει τη φυλετική αυτοδιάθεση. Στις αρχές της 
δεκαετίας του '50, το συνέδριο πέρασε τη νομοθεσία για να 
περιορίσει αυτόν τον νόμο, που ολοκληρώνει κάποια αμερικανική 
ινδική οικονομική υποστήριξη επιφυλάξεων και κοπής για άλλες. 
Από το 1950 ως το 1970, περισσότερες από 100 
αμερικανικές ινδικές φυλές έχασαν τα εδάφη επιφύλαξης, και το 
ποσοστό αμερικανικών Ινδών που ζουν στις επιφυλάξεις ελαττώθηκε 
από 87% σε 45%. Αυτές οι αλλαγές ανάγκασαν νέους 
αμερικανικούς Ινδούς για να ψάξουν την εργασία στις αστικές 
περιοχές. Το 1968, νέοι αστικός-βασισμένοι αμερικανικοί 
Ινδοί σε Μινεσότα διαμόρφωσαν το αμερικανικό ινδικό Κίνημα 
(AIM) για να παλεψουν την κακή μεταχείριση αμερικανικών Ινδών 
από την αστυνομία και για να βελτιώσουν τις προοπτικές για τις 
εργασίες, την εκπαίδευση, και την κατοικία. Στις αρχές της 
δεκαετίας του '70, το AIM πίεσε την ομοσπονδιακή κυβέρνηση για 
να τιμήσει τις συνθήκες 19$ος-αιώνα που είχαν καθιερώσει τους 
ινδικούς λαούς ως κυρίαρχες οντότητες. Το 1972, το AIM
άρχισε "το ίχνος των σπασμένων Συνθηκών," ένα διαφυλετικό 
τροχόσπιτο στις επιφυλάξεις και επόμενος Μάρτιος στην Ουάσιγκτον.
Το 1973, περισσότεροι από 2.000 αμερικανικοί Ινδοί 
ήρθαν στο πληγωμένο γόνατο, νότια Ντακότα, στην επιφύλαξη 
κορυφογραμμών πεύκων, μετά από μια διαταραχή δικαστηρίων. 
Επί αυτού του ιστορικού τόπου όπου μια σφαγή Ινδών από 
τους στρατιώτες ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΥ ιππικού το 1890 τελείωσε τα έτη 
ένοπλης σύγκρουσης, η απαίτηση για τις ακροάσεις στα δικαιώματα 
κυριαρχίας ικανοποιήθηκε με μια πολιορκία από τις δυνάμεις 
FBI, τα ομοσπονδιακά marshals, και την αστυνομία BIA. 
Η απόκλιση 71-ημέρας τελείωσε με τις διαβεβαιώσεις ότι ο 
λευκός οίκος θα αναθεωρούσε σοβαρά τη Συνθήκη Laramie 1868 
οχυρών που είχε αναγνωρίσει την κυριαρχία του έθνους Lakota 
και των δικαιωμάτων τους στα πολύτιμα εδάφη. Εκείνη η 
υπόσχεση απέτυχε να υλοποιήσει, και στα επόμενα μερικά έτη 
περισσότερα από 60 μέλη AIM σκοτώθηκαν στην κορυφογραμμή 
πεύκων. Μέχρι το τέλος της δεκαετίας, που μολύνθηκε από 
την καταστολή και τις εσωτερικές διαφωνίες, το AIM μειώθηκε ως 
κορυφαία στρατευμένη οργάνωση, αν και μια φατρία παραμένει. 
Τα ακόλουθα θεμελιώδη έγγραφα υποβλήθηκαν σε μια του 
Κογκρέσου επιτροπή από το μυστικό πληροφοριοδότη Doug 
Durham FBI, ο οποίος εχρησίμευσε για έναν χρόνο ως ο 
σκηνοθέτης του AIM της ασφάλειας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El acto indio de la reorganización de 1934 
intentó restablecer la autodeterminación tribal. En los 
comienzos de los años 50, el congreso aprobó la legislación para 
limitar este acto, terminando una cierta ayuda económica india 
americana de las reservaciones y el cortar para otras. A partir 
la 1950 a 1970, más de 100 tribus indias americanas perdieron pistas 
de la reservación, y el porcentaje de los indios americanos que 
vivían en las reservaciones caídas a partir de la 87% hasta el 45%. 
Estos cambios forzaron a indios americanos jóvenes buscar el 
trabajo en áreas urbanas. En 1968, los indios americanos 
urbano-basados jóvenes en Minnesota formaron el movimiento indio 
americano (PUNTERÍA) al maltratamiento de la lucha de indios 
americanos del policía y mejorar las perspectivas de trabajos, de la 
educación, y de la cubierta. En los años 70 tempranos, la 
PUNTERÍA ejerció presión sobre el gobierno federal para honrar los 
tratados 19th-century que habían establecido a gente india como 
entidades soberanas. En 1972, la PUNTERÍA inició "el rastro de
tratados quebrados," una caravana entre tribus a las reservaciones y 
marzo subsecuente a Washington. En 1973, más de 2.000 indios 
americanos vinieron a la rodilla herida, Dakota del Sur, en la 
reservación del canto del pino, siguiendo un disturbio del palacio de
justicia. En este sitio histórico en donde una masacre de 
indios de los soldados de la caballería de ESTADOS UNIDOS en 1890 
terminó los años del conflicto armado, la demanda para las 
audiencias en las derechas de la soberanía fue resuelta con un sitio 
por las fuerzas de FBI, los mariscales federales, y el policía de 
BIA. El aislamiento 71-day terminó con aseguramientos que la 
casa blanca repasaría seriamente el tratado 1868 de Laramie de la 
fortaleza que había reconocido la soberanía de la nación de Lakota 
y de las sus derechas a las pistas valiosas. Esa promesa no 
podida para materializar, y en los años próximos más de 60 miembros
de la PUNTERÍA fue matada en el canto del pino. Para el final 
de la década, plagada por la represión y conflictos internos, la 
PUNTERÍA declinó como organización militante principal, aunque 
sigue habiendo una facción. Los documentos foundational 
siguientes fueron sometidos a un comité del congreso por el 
informador Doug Durham de undercover FBI, que sirvió por una época 
como director de la puntería de la seguridad.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086809</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103878</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/self-determination-of-free-peoples-founding-documents-of-the-american-indian-movement-aim</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
