<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107112</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107112</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206186</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Exploring Magnetism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erforschender Magnetismus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Magnétisme L'explorant</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Magnetismo Explorando</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Magnetismo D'Esplorazione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Να ερευνήσει το μαγνητισμό</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Magnetismo Que explora</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a series of lessons on solar wind, solar flares, space weather, electromagnetism, and earth's magnetism. Map magnetic fields in your environment. Experiment with compass needles and circuits, electric currents and magnets, a jump rope generator, and induction in an aluminum can. Find out about sunspots, time zone math, magnetic reversals, the magnetosphere, and auroras.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist eine Reihe Lektionen auf Solarwind, 
Sonneneruptionen, Platzwetter, Elektromagnetismus und Magnetismus der 
Masse. Die magnetische Karte fängt in Ihrer Umgebung 
auf. Experiment mit Kompaßnadeln und -stromkreise, elektrische 
Ströme und Magneten, ein Sprungseilgenerator und Induktion in einer 
Aluminiumdose. Finden Sie über Sunspots, Zeitzone Mathe, 
magnetische Umlenkungen, die Magnetosphäre und die auroras heraus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est une série de leçons sur le vent solaire, 
éruptions chromosphériques, l'espace survit à, 
électromagnétisme, et magnétisme de la terre. Champs 
magnétiques de carte dans votre environnement. Expérience avec
des aiguilles et des circuits de boussole, courants et aimants 
électriques, un générateur de corde de saut, et induction dans un 
bidon d'aluminium. Découvrez au sujet des taches solaires, des 
maths de fuseau horaire, des inversions magnétiques, de la 
magnétosphère, et des auroras.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é uma série das lições no vento solar, em 
alargamentos solares, em tempo do espaço, em electromagnetism, e em 
magnetismo da terra. Campos magnéticos do mapa em seu ambiente.
Experiência com agulhas e circuitos do compasso, correntes e 
ímãs elétricos, um gerador da corda do salto, e indução em uma 
lata do alumínio. Encontre para fora sobre sunspots, math da 
zona de tempo, reversões magnéticas, a magnetosfera, e auroras.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è una serie di lezioni su vento solare, sui 
chiarori solari, sul tempo dello spazio, sull'elettromagnetismo e sul 
magnetismo della terra. Campi magnetici del programma nel vostro
ambiente. Esperimento con gli aghi e circuiti della bussola, 
correnti e magneti elettrici, un generatore della corda di salto ed 
induzione in una latta dell'alluminio. Scopra circa i sunspots, 
il per la matematica di zona di tempo, le inversioni magnetiche, la 
magnetosfera ed i auroras.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι μια σειρά μαθημάτων στον ηλιακό αέρα, τις 
ηλιακές φλόγες, το διαστημικό καιρό, τον ηλεκτρομαγνητισμό, και 
το γήινο μαγνητισμό. Μαγνητικά πεδία χαρτών στο περιβάλλον
σας. Το πείραμα με τις βελόνες και τα κυκλώματα πυξίδων, τα 
ηλεκτρικοί ρεύματα και οι μαγνήτες, μια γεννήτρια σχοινιών 
άλματος, και η επαγωγή σε ένα αργίλιο μπορούν. Ανακαλύψτε 
για τις ηλιακές κηλίδες, τη χρονική ζώνη math, τις μαγνητικές 
αντιστροφές, τη μαγνητόσφαιρα, και τις αυγές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es una serie de lecciones en el viento solar, 
flamas solares, tiempo del espacio, electromagnetismo, y el magnetismo
de la tierra. Campos magnéticos de la correspondencia en su 
ambiente. Experimento con las agujas y circuitos del compás, 
corrientes e imanes eléctricos, un generador de la cuerda del salto, 
e inducción en una lata del aluminio. Descubra sobre manchas 
solares, matemáticas de la zona de tiempo, las revocaciones 
magnéticas, la magnetosfera, y auroras.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206186</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107112</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/exploring-magnetism</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
