<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106367</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106367</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086456</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Making the Atlanta Compromise: Booker T. Washington Is Invited to Speak</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Atlanta sich vergleichen lassen: Booker 
T. Washington wird eingeladen, um zu sprechen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Faisant Atlanta compromettre : Booker T. 
Washington est invité pour parler</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fazendo a Atlanta comprometer: Booker T. 
Washington é convidado para falar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Facendo Atlanta compromettere: Booker T. 
Washington è invitato per parlare</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κάνοντας την Ατλάντα να συμβιβάσει: Booker Τ.
Ουάσιγκτον καλείται για να μιλήσει</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Haciendo que la Atlanta se compromete: Se 
invita a Booker T. Washington que hable</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">On September 18, 1895 Booker T. Washington, the noted African-American educator who was born a slave in 1858, spoke before the Cotton States and International Exposition in Atlanta. His Atlanta Compromise address, as it came to be called, was one of the most important and influential speeches in American history. Acutely conscious of the narrow limitations whites placed on African Americans' economic aspirations, Washington stressed that blacks must accommodate white people's--and especially southern whites'--refusal to tolerate blacks as anything more than sophisticated menials. In this excerpt from his best-selling autobiography  Up From Slavery  (1901) Washington explained some of the circumstances surrounding the unprecedented invitation for him to speak before a biracial audience.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">An September 18, 1895 sprach Booker T. Washington,
der beachtete Afrikanisch-Amerikanische Erzieher, dem ein Sklave 1858 
geboren war, vor den Baumwollzuständen und der internationalen 
Ausstellung in Atlanta. Seine Atlanta Kompromißadresse, da sie 
kam benannt zu werden, war eine der wichtigsten und einflußreichsten 
Reden in der amerikanischen Geschichte. Akut bewußt des 
schmalen Beschränkungen Weiß, das auf ökonomische Aspirationen der 
afrikanischen Amerikaner plaziert wurde, Washington betonte, daß 
Schwarze der weißen Leute -- und besonders des südlichen Weiß 
anpassen müssen -- die Ablehnung, zum von von Schwarzen als alles 
zuzulassen mehr als verfeinerte menials. In diesem Excerpt von 
seiner gut-verkaufenden Autobiographie oben von Slavery (1901) 
Washington erklärte einige der Umstände, welche die beispiellose 
Einladung umgeben, damit er vor einem biracial Publikum spricht.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">18 septembre 1895 Booker T. Washington, 
l'éducateur afro-américain remarquable qui est né un slave en 
1858, a parlé avant les états de coton et l'exposition 
internationale à Atlanta. Son adresse de compromis d'Atlanta, 
car elle est venue pour s'appeler, était l'un des discours les plus 
importants et les plus influents dans l'histoire américaine. 
Intensément conscient des blancs étroits de limitations 
placés sur les aspirations économiques des Américains africains, 
Washington a soumis à une contrainte que les noirs doivent faciliter 
les personnes blanches -- et particulièrement les blancs méridionaux
-- refus pour tolérer des noirs en tant que n'importe quoi des 
menials plus que sophistiqués. Dans cet extrait de sa 
autobiographie devente vers le haut d'Slavery (1901) Washingtons ont 
expliqué certaines des circonstances entourant l'invitation sans 
précédent pour qu'il parle devant une assistance biracial.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Setembro em 18, 1895 Booker T. Washington, 
educador Africano-Americano notável que foi carregado um escravo em 
1858, falou antes dos estados do algodão e da exposição 
internacional em Atlanta. Seu endereço do acordo de Atlanta, 
porque veio ser chamado, era um dos discursos os mais importantes e os
mais influential no history americano. Aguda conscious dos 
brancos estreitos das limitações colocados em aspirations 
econômicos dos americanos africanos, Washington forçou que os pretos
devem acomodar o pessoa branco -- e especial brancos do sul -- recusa 
para tolerar pretos como qualquer coisa menials mais do que 
sofisticados. Neste excerpt de seu autobiography melhor-vendendo
acima de Slavery (1901) Washington explicaram algumas das 
circunstâncias que cercam o invitation unprecedented para que fale 
antes de uma audiência biracial.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il 18 settembre 1895 Booker T. Washington, 
l'educatore Africano-Americano celebre che è stato sopportato uno 
schiavo in 1858, spoke prima che il cotone Dichiari ed 
esposizione internazionale a Atlanta. Il suo indirizzo di 
compromesso de Atlanta, poichè è venuto essere chiamato, era uno dei
discorsi più importanti e più influenti nella storia americana. 
Acutamente cosciente dei bianchi stretti di limitazioni disposti
sulle aspirazioni economiche degli Americani africani, Washington ha 
sollecitato che i neri devono accomodare la gente bianca -- e 
particolarmente i bianchi del sud -- rifiuto per tollerare i neri come
qualche cosa menials più di quanto resi sofisticato. In questo 
brano dal suo autobiography migliore-vendente in su da Slavery (1901) 
Washington hanno spiegato alcune delle circostanze gli che circondano 
l'invito senza precedente affinchè parlino prima di un pubblico 
biracial.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στις 18 Σεπτεμβρίου ..1895 Booker Τ. 
Ουάσιγκτον, ο σημειωμένος αφρικανικός-αμερικανικός εκπαιδευτικός 
που γεννήθηκε ένας σκλάβος το 1858, μίλησε πριν από τα κράτη 
βαμβακιού και τη διεθνή έκθεση στην Ατλάντα. Η διεύθυνση 
συμβιβασμού της Ατλάντας του, καθώς ήρθε να κληθεί, ήταν μια 
από τις σημαντικότερες και επιδρούσες ομιλίες στην αμερικανική 
ιστορία. Έντονα συνειδητές των στενών λευκών περιορισμών 
που τοποθετήθηκαν αφρικανικών Αμερικανών οι οικονομικές 
φιλοδοξίες, Ουάσιγκτον τόνισαν ότι οι Μαύροι πρέπει να 
προσαρμόσουν των νότιων λευκών των λευκών ανθρώπων ειδικά -- 
άρνηση να ανεχτούν οι Μαύροι ως τίποτα περισσότερο από τα 
περίπλοκα menials. Σε αυτό το απόσπασμα από τη με 
εμπορική επιτυχία αυτοβιογραφία του επάνω από τη σκλαβιά 
(1901) η Ουάσιγκτον εξήγησε μερικών από τις περιστάσεις που 
περιβάλλουν την πρωτοφανή πρόσκληση για τον για να μιλήσει πριν 
από ένα biracial ακροατήριο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">18 de septiembre de 1895 Booker T. Washington, 
el educador Africano-Americano conocido que nació un esclavo en 1858,
habló antes de los estados del algodón y de la exposición 
internacional en Atlanta. Su direccionamiento del compromiso de 
Atlanta, pues vino ser llamado, era uno de los discursos más 
importantes y más influyentes de la historia americana. Agudo 
consciente de los blancos estrechos de las limitaciones puestos en las
aspiraciones económicas de los americanos africanos, Washington 
tensionó que los negros deben acomodar la gente blanca -- y 
especialmente los blancos meridionales -- denegación para tolerar 
negros como cualquier cosa los menials más que sofisticados. En
este extracto de su autobiografía mejor-vendedora para arriba de 
Slavery (1901) Washington explicaron algunas de las circunstancias que
rodeaban la invitación sin precedente para que él hable ante una 
audiencia biracial.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086456</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106367</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/making-the-atlanta-compromise-booker-t-washington-is-invited-to-speak</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
