<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106783</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106783</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087357</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Address of the Colored State Convention to the People of the State of South Carolina</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Adresse der farbigen Zustand-Vereinbarung zu den 
Leuten des Zustandes von Südcarolina</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Adresse de la convention colorée d'état aux 
personnes de l'état de la Caroline du sud</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Endereço da convenção colorida do estado aos 
povos do estado de carolina sul</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'indirizzo del colorato Dichiara la 
convenzione alla gente del Dichiarare di Carolina del Sud</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διεύθυνση της έγχρωμης κρατικής Συνθήκης στους 
ανθρώπους του κράτους της νότιας Καρολίνας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Direccionamiento de la convención coloreada del 
estado a la gente del estado de Carolina del Sur</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In November 1865 a group of 52 black delegates met in Charleston's Zion Church to formulate a position regarding their future in the still uncertain world of the post-emancipation South. Their address invoked the language of the Declaration of Independence to claim full rights of citizenship for themselves, rights that were endangered by widespread southern "Black Codes." The Black Codes were a series of laws introduced in the months after the war by the reconstituted state legislatures of the South. These laws were enacted to restrict the movements and employment possibilities of blacks regardless of whether they had been free or enslaved before the war?in essence to replace the constrictions of slavery.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im November 1865 traf eine Gruppe von 52 schwarzen 
Delegierten in der Kirche Zion Charlestons, um eine Position 
betreffend ist ihre Zukunft in der ruhigen unsicheren Welt des 
Pfosten-Emanzipation Südens zu formulieren. Ihre Adresse rief 
die Sprache der Unabhängigkeitserklärung hervor, um volle Rechte der
Staatsbürgerschaft für selbst, Rechte zu behaupten, die wurden 
gefährdet durch weitverbreitete südliche "schwarze Codes." Die
schwarzen Codes waren Reihen Gesetze, die in den Monaten nach dem 
Krieg von den wieder hergestellten Zustandgesetzgebungen des Südens 
eingeführt wurden. Diese Gesetze wurden verordnet, um die 
Bewegungen und die Beschäftigungmöglichkeiten von Schwarzen 
unabhängig davon einzuschränken, ob sie frei gewesen waren oder 
versklavt vor dem war?in Wesentlichen, um die Zusammenziehungen der 
Sklaverei zu ersetzen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En novembre 1865 un groupe de 52 délégués noirs 
s'est réuni dans l'église de Zion de Charleston pour formuler une 
position concernant leur futur dans le monde incertain encore des 
Sud de poteau-émancipation. Leur adresse a appelé le 
langage de la déclaration de l'indépendance pour revendiquer de 
pleins droits de la citoyenneté pour eux-mêmes, les droites qui ont 
été mises en danger par "des codes noirs méridionaux répandus." 
Les codes noirs étaient des séries de lois présentées en 
mois après la guerre par les législatures d'état reconstituées des
Sud. Ces lois ont été décrétées pour limiter les 
mouvements et les possibilités d'emploi de noirs indépendamment de 
si elles avaient été libres ou ont été asservies avant l'essence 
de war?in pour substituer les constrictions de l'esclavage.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em novembro 1865 um grupo de 52 delegados pretos 
encontrou-se com na igreja de Zion de Charleston para formular uma 
posição a respeito de seu futuro no mundo incerto imóvel do sul do 
borne-post-emancipation. Seu endereço invocou a língua da 
declaração de independência para reivindicar direitas cheias do 
citizenship para se, as direitas que foram postas em perigo "por 
códigos pretos do sul difundidos." Os códigos pretos eram umas
séries das leis introduzidas nos meses após a guerra pelas 
legislaturas de estado reconstituted do sul. Estas leis foram 
decretadas para restringir os movimentos e as possibilidades do 
emprego de pretos não obstante se tinham estado livres ou enslaved 
antes da essência do war?in para substituir os constrictions do 
slavery.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nel mese di novembre del 1865 un gruppo di 52 
delegati neri ha venuto a contatto di nella chiesa di Zion de 
Charleston per formulare una posizione per quanto riguarda il loro 
futuro nel mondo incerto ancora del sud di alberino-emancipazione. 
Il loro indirizzo ha invocato il linguaggio della dichiarazione 
di indipendenza per esigere i diritti completi della cittadinanza per 
se stesso, diritti che sono stati messi "dai codici neri del sud 
diffusi." I codici neri erano una serie di leggi introdotte nei 
mesi dopo che la guerra dal ricostituita dichiarasse le 
legislature del sud. Queste leggi sono state promulgate per 
limitare i movimenti e le possibilità di occupazione di neri senza 
riguardo a se erano state libere o sono state asservite prima 
dell'essenza del war?in per sostituire le riduzioni di slavery.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τον Νοέμβριο του 1865 μια ομάδα 52 μαύρων 
εκπροσώπων συναντήθηκε στην εκκλησία Zion του Τσάρλεστον για να
διατυπώσει μια θέση σχετικά με το μέλλον τους στον ακόμα αβέβαιο
κόσμο του νότου μετα-χειραφέτησης. Η διεύθυνσή τους 
κάλεσε τη γλώσσα της Διακήρυξης της ανεξαρτησίας για να απαιτήσει
τα πλήρη δικαιώματα της υπηκοότητας για τους, δικαιώματα που 
διακυβεύθηκαν από τους διαδεδομένους νότιους "μαύρους κώδικες." 
Οι μαύροι κώδικες ήταν μια σειρά νόμων που κατατέθηκαν 
στους μήνες μετά από τον πόλεμο από τα ανασυγκροτημένα κρατικά 
νομοθετικά σώματα του νότου. Αυτοί οι νόμοι θεσπίστηκαν 
για να περιορίσουν τις κυκλοφορίες και τις δυνατότητες απασχόλησης
των Μαύρων ανεξάρτητα από εάν ήταν ελεύθεροι ή υποδούλωσαν 
πριν από την ουσία war?in για να αντικαταστήσουν τις συστολές 
της σκλαβιάς.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En noviembre de 1865 un grupo de 52 delegados 
negros se reunió en la iglesia de Zion de Charleston para formular 
una posición con respecto a su futuro en el mundo incierto inmóvil 
del sur de la poste-emancipacio'n. Su direccionamiento invocó 
el lenguaje del declaración de la independencia para demandar las 
derechas completas de la ciudadanía para sí mismos, las derechas que
fueron puestas en peligro por "códigos negros meridionales extensos."
Los códigos negros eran series de leyes introducidos en los 
meses después de la guerra por las legislaturas de estado 
reconstituidas del sur. Estos leyes fueron decretados para 
restringir los movimientos y las posibilidades del empleo de negros 
sin importar si habían estado libres o esclavizados antes de la 
esencia del war?in para substituir las constricciones de la 
esclavitud.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087357</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106783</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/address-of-the-colored-state-convention-to-the-people-of-the-state-of-south-carolina</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
