<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108629</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108629</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087062</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Treatment of the Help in Those Days Was Cruel": Hiram Munger Remembers Factory Life</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die Behandlung der Hilfe an jenen Tagen war" 
grausam: Hiram Munger Erinnert Sich das an Fabrik-Leben</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"le traitement de l'aide en ces jours était 
cruel" : Hiram Munger Se rappelle La Vie d'Usine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"o tratamento da ajuda naqueles dias era cruel": 
Hiram Munger Recorda A Vida Da Fábrica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"il trattamento dell'aiuto in quei giorni era 
crudele": Hiram Munger Si ricorda Della Vita Della Fabbrica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η επεξεργασία των οδηγιών σε εκείνες τις ημέρες ήταν
σκληρή": Το Hiram Munger θυμάται τη ζωή εργοστασίων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"el tratamiento de la ayuda en esos días era 
cruel": Hiram Munger Recuerda Vida De la Fábrica</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">After the War for Independence small-scale industrial activity spread throughout the northeastern states. Saw and grist mills had long been features of colonial life, processing local wood and grain for the rural population. In 1790 Samuel Slater, an English immigrant, set up machines for spinning cotton yarn in Pawtucket Falls, Rhode Island. New England's abundant water power drove many small textile mills. Family labor was very important in those early mills as small children often tended the machines while their parents wove the yarn into cloth. Hiram Munger worked in a small cotton factory in Massachusetts. Born into a family with scant means, Munger only worked in a textile mill for a short while, but when he recorded his autobiography forty years later he remembered the experience vividly. Hiram Munger worked at a series of manual occupations most of his life, eventually becoming an itinerant Methodist lay preacher.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nach dem Krieg für Unabhängigkeit verbritt 
kleinräumige industrielle Aktivität während der nordöstlichen 
Zustände. Säge- und Mahlguttausendstel waren lang Merkmale der
Koloniallebensdauer gewesen und lokales Holz und Korn für die 
landwirtschaftliche Bevölkerung verarbeitet. Samuel Slater 
1790 fällt ein englischer Immigrant, aufgestellte Maschinen für 
spinnendes Baumwollgarn in Pawtucket, Rhode-Insel. Neu-Englands 
reichlich vorhandenes Wasser Maschinenantrieb viele kleine 
Textiltausendstel. Familie Arbeit war in denen frühe 
Tausendstel sehr wichtig, da kleine Kinder häufig die Maschinen 
neigten, während ihre Eltern das Garn in Tuch spannen. Hiram 
Munger arbeitete in einer kleinen Baumwollfabrik in Massachusetts. 
Getragen in eine Familie mit dürftigen Mitteln, arbeitete 
Munger nur in einem Textiltausendstel für einen Kurzschluß, 
während, aber, als er seine Autobiographie vierzig Jahre später 
speicherte, er an die Erfahrung sich vividly erinnerte. Hiram 
Munger arbeitete an einer Reihe manuellen Besetzungen am meisten 
seiner Lebensdauer und schließlich stand einem reisenden 
Methodistlage Prediger.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Après la guerre pour l'indépendance l'activité 
industrielle de petite taille a écarté dans tous les états du 
nord-est. Les moulins de scie et de blé à moudre avaient 
longtemps été des dispositifs de la vie coloniale, traitant le bois 
et le grain locaux à la population rurale. En le couvreur 1790 
de Samuel, un immigré anglais, les machines installées pour le fil 
de coton de rotation dans Pawtucket tombe, île de Rhode. La 
puissance abondante de l'eau de la Nouvelle Angleterre a piloté 
beaucoup de petits moulins de textile. Le travail de famille 
était très important dans ceux les moulins tôt car les petits 
enfants ont souvent tendu les machines tandis que leurs parents 
tissaient le filé dans le tissu. Hiram Munger a fonctionné 
dans une petite usine de coton dans le Massachusetts. Soutenu 
dans une famille avec des moyens limités, Munger a seulement 
fonctionné dans un moulin de textile pour un short tandis que, mais 
quand il a enregistré son autobiographie quarante ans après il se 
rappelait l'expérience vividly. Hiram Munger a fonctionné à 
une série de métiers manuels plus de sa vie, par la suite allant 
bien à un prédicateur ambulant de configuration de méthodiste.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Após a guerra para a independência a atividade 
industrial small-scale espalhou durante todo os estados do nordeste. 
Os moinhos da serra e do grist tinham sido por muito tempo 
características da vida colonial, processando a madeira e a grão 
locais para a população rural. No telhador 1790 de Samuel, um 
immigrant inglês, máquinas acima ajustadas para o fio de algodão 
girando em Pawtucket cai, console de Rhode. A potência 
abundante da água de Nova Inglaterra dirigiu muitos moinhos pequenos 
de textile. O trabalho da família era muito importante naqueles
moinhos adiantados porque as crianças pequenas tenderam 
frequentemente as máquinas quando seus pais teceram o fio no pano. 
Hiram Munger trabalhou em uma fábrica pequena do algodão em 
Massachusetts. Carregado em uma família com meios scant, Munger
trabalhou somente em um moinho de textile para um short quando, mas 
quando gravou seu autobiography quarenta anos mais tarde recordou a 
experiência vividly. Hiram Munger trabalhou em uma série de 
ocupações manuais mais de sua vida, eventualmente assentando bem em 
um preacher itinerant da configuração do methodist.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dopo che la guerra per la diffusione industriale 
su scala ridotta di attività di indipendenza durante il di nordest 
dichiari. I laminatoi del grano da macinare e della sega
lungamente erano stati caratteristiche di vita coloniale, elaborando 
il legno ed il grano locali per la popolazione rurale. Nello 
slater 1790 di Samuel, un immigrante inglese, macchine installate per 
il filo di cotone di filatura in Pawtucket cade, Rhode-isola. 
Abbondante dell'acqua della Nuova Inghilterra dispositivo di 
presa di forza molti piccoli laminatoi della tessile. Il 
lavoro della famiglia era molto importante in quelli laminatoi in
anticipo poichè i piccoli bambini hanno teso spesso le macchine 
mentre i loro genitori hanno tessuto il filato nel panno. Hiram 
Munger ha funzionato in una piccola fabbrica del cotone in 
Massachusetts. Sopportato in una famiglia con i mezzi limitati, 
Munger ha funzionato soltanto in un laminatoio della tessile per uno 
short mentre, ma quando ha registrato il suo autobiography quaranta 
anni più successivamente si è ricordato dell'esperienza vividly. 
Hiram Munger ha funzionato ad una serie di occupazioni manuali 
più della sua vita, finalmente stando bene ad un preacher ambulante 
di disposizione del methodist.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μετά από τον πόλεμο για την ανεξαρτησία η μικρής 
κλίμακας βιομηχανική δραστηριότητα διέδωσε σε όλα τα 
βορειοανατολικά κράτη. Εβλέίδε και οι μύλοι 
αλέσματος ήταν από καιρό χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα της 
αποικιακής ζωής, που επεξεργάζονται το τοπικά ξύλο και το σιτάρι
για τον αγροτικό πληθυσμό. Το 1790 Samuel Slater, 
ένας αγγλικός μετανάστης, σύνολο επάνω στις μηχανές για το νήμα
βαμβακιού σε Pawtucket πέφτει, νησί Rhode. Η άφθονη 
υδραυλική ισχύς της Νέας Αγγλίας οδήγησε πολλούς μικρούς 
υφαντικούς μύλους. Η οικογενειακή εργασία ήταν πολύ 
σημαντική σε εκείνους τους πρόωρους μύλους δεδομένου ότι τα 
μικρά παιδιά έτειναν συχνά τις μηχανές ενώ οι γονείς τους 
ύφαναν το νήμα στο ύφασμα. Το Hiram Munger 
ελειτούργησε σε ένα μικρό εργοστάσιο βαμβακιού στη Μασαχουσέτη. 
Γεννημένος σε μια οικογένεια με τα πενιχρά μέσα, Munger 
εργάστηκε μόνο σε έναν υφαντικό μύλο για έναν κοντό ενώ, αλλά
όταν κατέγραψε την αυτοβιογραφία του σαράντα έτη αργότερα αυτός
θυμήθηκε την εμπειρία ζωντανά. Το Hiram Munger που 
απασχολείται σε μια σειρά χειρωνακτικών επαγγελμάτων στην 
μεγαλύτερη μέρος της ζωής του, τελικά που γίνεται πλανόδιο ένα 
μεθοδιστές βάζει τον ιεροκήρυκα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Después de la guerra para la independencia la 
actividad industrial en reducida escala se separó a través de los 
estados del noreste. Los molinos de la sierra y del grano para 
moler habían sido de largo características de la vida colonial, 
procesando la madera y el grano locales para la población rural. 
En el pizarrero 1790 de Samuel, un inmigrante inglés, 
instaladas las máquinas para el hilo de algodón que hace girar en 
Pawtucket cae, Rhode-isla. La potencia abundante del agua de 
Nueva Inglaterra condujo muchos molinos pequeños del textil. El
trabajo de la familia era muy importante en ésos los molinos 
tempranos pues los niños pequeños tendieron a menudo a las máquinas
mientras que sus padres tejieron el hilado en el paño. Hiram 
Munger trabajó en una fábrica pequeña del algodón en 
Massachusetts. Llevado en una familia con medios escasos, Munger
trabajó solamente en un molino del textil para un cortocircuito 
mientras que, pero cuando él registró su autobiografía cuarenta 
años más adelante él recordó la experiencia vividly. Hiram 
Munger trabajó en una serie de ocupaciones manuales más de su vida, 
eventual sintiendo bien a un predicador ambulante de la endecha del 
methodist.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087062</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108629</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-treatment-of-the-help-in-those-days-was-cruel-hiram-munger-remembers-factory-life</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
