<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/347849682</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>347849682</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086670</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"No Snuggling!" Sex Talks to Young Girls</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Kein Snuggling!" Geschlecht spricht mit 
jungen Mädchen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Aucun Snuggling!" Le sexe parle à de 
jeunes filles</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Nenhum Snuggling!" O sexo fala às meninas 
novas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Nessuno Snuggling!" Colloqui del sesso 
alle ragazze giovani</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Κανένα Snuggling!" Συζητήσεις φύλων στα νέα 
κορίτσια</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Ningún Snuggling!" El sexo habla con las 
muchachas jóvenes</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the 1920s, in part because of prohibition and the emergence of speakeasies, homosexuality became more open. At the same time, psychologists, physicians, and social reformers had been at work for several decades attempting to study, classify, categorize, and label human sexual behavior. Practices that had long been common, or at least tolerated, were now being viewed as problematic. In an excerpt from  Ten Sex Talks to Girls , published in 1914, Dr. Irving Steinhardt of New York warned that any affection or intimacy--indeed, any sort of physical contact between women at all--carried the potential for disease, pauperism, and death. Steinhardt's book attempted to classify as dangerous forms of intimacy between women that previously had seemed completely "natural."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In den zwanziger Jahren im Teil wegen des Verbots 
und im Hervortreten von Speakeasies, wurde Homosexualität 
geöffneter. Gleichzeitig waren Psychologen, Ärzte und 
SozialReformer an der Arbeit für einige Dekaden gewesen, die 
versuchen, menschliches sexuelles Verhalten zu studieren, einzustufen,
zu kategorisieren und zu beschriften. Praxis, die lang geläufig
gewesen war, oder mindestens zugelassen, wurde jetzt angesehen, wie 
problematisch. In einem Excerpt von 10 Geschlecht-Gesprächen zu
den Mädchen, veröffentlicht 1914, warnte Dr. Irving Steinhardt von 
New York, daß jede mögliche Neigung oder Intimacy -- in der Tat, 
irgendeine Sortierung des körperlichen Kontaktes zwischen Frauen an 
allen -- das Potential für Krankheit, Pauperismus und Tod trugen. 
Buch Steinhardts versuchte, sich als gefährliche Formulare von 
Intimacy zwischen Frauen einzustufen, die vorher hatten geschienen 
vollständig "natürlich."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans les années 20, en partie en raison de 
prohibition et l'apparition des bars clandestins, l'homosexualité est 
devenue plus ouverte. En même temps, les psychologues, les 
médecins, et les réformateurs sociaux avaient été au travail 
pendant plusieurs décennies essayant d'étudier, classifier, classer 
par catégorie, et étiqueter le comportement sexuel humain. Des
pratiques qui avaient longtemps été communes, ou au moins toléré, 
maintenant étaient visualisées comme problématiques. Dans un 
extrait de Dix entretiens de sexe aux filles, éditées en 1914, Dr. 
Irving Steinhardt de New York a averti que n'importe quelle affection 
ou intimité -- en effet, tout tri de contact physique entre les 
femmes du tout -- a porté le potentiel pour la maladie, le 
paupérisme, et la mort. Le livre de Steinhardt a essayé de 
classifier en tant que formes dangereuses d'intimité entre les femmes
qui précédemment avaient semblé complètement "normales."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nos 1920s, na parte por causa da proibição e no 
emergence dos speakeasies, o homosexuality tornou-se mais aberto. 
Ao mesmo tempo, os psicólogos, os médicos, e os reformers 
sociais tinham estado no trabalho por diversas décadas que tentam 
estudar, classificar, categorizar, e etiquetar o comportamento sexual 
humano. As práticas que tinham sido por muito tempo comuns, ou 
tolerado ao menos, eram vistas agora como problematic. Em um 
excerpt de dez conversas do sexo às meninas, publicadas em 1914, o 
Dr. Irving Steinhardt de New York advertiu que toda a afeição ou 
intimacy -- certamente, alguma sorte do contato físico entre mulheres
em tudo -- carregaram o potencial para a doença, o pauperism, e a 
morte. O livro de Steinhardt tentou classificar como 
formulários perigosos do intimacy entre as mulheres que tinham 
parecido previamente completamente "naturais."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Negli anni 20, in parte a causa della proibizione 
e l'emersione degli speakeasies, l'omosessualità è diventato più 
aperta. Allo stesso tempo, gli psicologi, i medici ed i 
reformers sociali erano stati sul lavoro per parecchie decadi che 
tentano di studiare, classificare, categorizzare ed identificare il 
comportamento sessuale umano. Le pratiche che lungamente erano 
state comuni, o tollerato almeno, ora stavano osservande come 
problematiche. In un brano da dieci Colloqui del sesso alle 
ragazze, pubblicate in 1914, il Dott. Irving Steinhardt di New York ha
avvertito che tutto l'affetto o intimacy -- effettivamente, qualsiasi 
ordinamento del contatto fisico fra le donne affatto -- ha trasportato
il potenziale per la malattia, il pauperismo e la morte. Il 
libro dello Steinhardt ha tentato di classificare come forme 
pericolose di intimacy fra le donne che precedentemente avevano 
sembrato completamente "naturali."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στη δεκαετία του '20, εν μέρει λόγω της απαγόρευσης 
και την εμφάνιση των speakeasies, η ομοφυλοφυλία έγινε 
ανοικτότερη. Συγχρόνως, οι ψυχολόγοι, οι παθολόγοι, και οι 
κοινωνικοί μεταρρυθμιστές ήταν στην εργασία για αρκετές 
δεκαετίες που προσπαθούν να μελετήσουν, να ταξινομήσουν, να 
ταξινομήσουν, και ονομάζουν την ανθρώπινη σεξουαλική συμπεριφορά.
Οι πρακτικές που ήταν από καιρό κοινές, ή ανεχθείς 
τουλάχιστον, εμφανίζονταν τώρα όπως προβληματικές. Σε ένα 
απόσπασμα από δέκα συζητήσεις φύλων στα κορίτσια, που 
δημοσιεύθηκαν το 1914, ο Δρ Irving Steinhardt της Νέας 
Υόρκης προειδοποίησε ότι οποιαδήποτε αγάπη ή οικειότητα -- 
πράγματι, οποιοδήποτε είδος της φυσικής επαφής μεταξύ των 
γυναικών καθόλου όλα -- έφερε τη δυνατότητα για την ασθένεια, 
την εξαθλείωση, και το θάνατο. Το βιβλίο του Steinhardt 
προσπάθησε να ταξινομήσει ως επικίνδυνες μορφές της οικειότητας 
μεταξύ των γυναικών που προηγουμένως είχαν φανεί εντελώς 
"φυσικές."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En los años 20, en parte debido a la prohibición
y la aparición de bares, la homosexualidad llegó a estar más 
abierta. En el mismo tiempo, los psicólogos, los médicos, y 
los reformadores sociales habían estado en el trabajo por varias 
décadas que procuraban estudiar, clasificar, categorizar, y etiquetar
comportamiento sexual humano. Las prácticas que habían sido de
largo comunes, o tolerado por lo menos, ahora eran vistas como 
problemáticas. En un extracto a partir de diez negociaciones 
del sexo a las muchachas, publicadas en 1914, el Dr. Irving Steinhardt
de Nueva York advirtió que cualquier afecto o intimidad -- de hecho, 
cualquier clase de contacto físico entre las mujeres en todos -- 
llevó el potencial para la enfermedad, el pauperismo, y la muerte. 
El libro de Steinhardt procuró clasificar como formas 
peligrosas de intimidad entre las mujeres que se habían parecido 
previamente totalmente "naturales."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086670</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>347849682</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/no-snuggling-sex-talks-to-young-girls</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
