<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104606</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104606</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212393</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">System Dynamics in Education: The First Steps</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">System Dynamik in der Ausbildung: Die Ersten
Jobsteps</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dynamique de système dans l'éducation : 
Les Premières Étapes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Dinâmica do sistema na instrução: As 
Primeiras Etapas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dynamics del sistema nella formazione: I 
Primi Punti</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δυναμική συστημάτων στην εκπαίδευση: Τα πρώτα 
βήματα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Dinámica del sistema en la educación: Los 
Primeros Pasos de progresión</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This pdf tutorial covers the basics of systems dynamics and the use of Stella II software. The purpose of this article, as stated by its author, is to introduce or clarify system dynamics, which together with learner-centered learning, "are alternative approaches to the status quo of strict factual education." The tutorial is meant to serve as a hands-on introduction to system dynamics and learner-centered learning for educators and others interested in learning the basics of system dynamics through computer modeling. The tutorial sets forth some of the principles of system dynamics and learner-centered learning by guiding the reader through two simple population models. This is a great resource for getting started with Stella II. It is part of Road Maps 2.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser pdf Tutorial umfaßt die Grundlagen der 
Systeme Dynamik und den Gebrauch von Stella II Software. Der 
Zweck dieses Artikels, wie von seinem Autor angegeben, ist 
einzuführen, oder System Dynamik erklären, die zusammen mit dem 
Anfänger-zentrierten Lernen, "sind alternative Annäherungen zum 
Status Quo der strengen auf Tatsachen beruhenden Ausbildung." 
Der Tutorial wird bedeutet, um als Blindeinschub Einleitung zur 
System Dynamik und zum Anfänger-zentrierten Lernen für Erzieher zu 
dienen und andere, die, an dem Lernen der Grundlagen der System 
Dynamik durch die Computerformung interessiert werden. Der 
Tutorial legte einige der Grundregeln der System Dynamik und des 
Anfänger-zentrierten Lernens fest, indem es den Leser durch zwei 
einfache Bevölkerung Modelle führte. Dieses ist ein großes 
Hilfsmittel für das Erhalten begonnen mit Stella II. Es ist ein
Teil Straßenkarten 2.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce cours d'instruction de pdf couvre les 
fondations de la dynamique de systèmes et l'utilisation du logiciel 
de Stella II. Le but de cet article, comme indiqué par son 
auteur, est de présenter ou clarifier la dynamique de système, qui 
ainsi que l'étude étudiant-centrée, "est les approches alternatives
au statu quo de l'éducation effective stricte." Le cours 
d'instruction est censé pour servir d'introduction à commande 
manuelle à la dynamique de système et à l'étude étudiant-centrée
pour des éducateurs et de d'autres intéressées à apprendre les 
fondations de la dynamique de système par modeler d'ordinateur. 
Le cours d'instruction a déterminé certains des principes de 
la dynamique de système et de l'étude étudiant-centrée en guidant 
le lecteur par deux modèles simples de population. C'est une 
grande ressource pour obtenir commencée par Stella II. Ce fait 
partie de cartes de route 2.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este tutorial do pdf cobre os princípios da 
dinâmica dos sistemas e o uso do software de Stella II. A 
finalidade deste artigo, como indicada por seu autor, é introduzir ou
para esclarecer a dinâmica do sistema, que junto com a aprendizagem 
learner-centrada, "são as aproximações alternativas ao quo do 
status da instrução factual estrita." O tutorial é 
significado servir como uma introdução hands-on à dinâmica do 
sistema e à aprendizagem learner-centrada para educadores e outra 
interessadas em aprender os princípios da dinâmica do sistema com 
modelar do computador. O tutorial determinou alguns dos 
princípios da dinâmica do sistema e da aprendizagem learner-centrada
guiando o leitor através de dois modelos simples da população. 
Este é um recurso grande para começar começado com Stella II.
É parte dos mapas de estrada 2.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa lezione privata del pdf riguarda i principi
fondamentali dei dynamics dei sistemi e l'uso del software di Stella 
II. Lo scopo di questo articolo, come dichiarato dal 
relativo autore, è introdurre o chiarire i dynamics del sistema, che 
insieme ad imparare principiante-centrato, "sono i metodi alternativi 
allo status quo di formazione effettiva rigorosa." La lezione 
privata è significata per servire da introduzione hands-on al 
dynamics del sistema e ad imparare principiante-centrato per gli 
educatori ed altre interessate ad imparare i principi fondamentali dei
dynamics del sistema con la modellistica del calcolatore. La 
lezione privata ha disposto alcuni dei principii dei dynamics del 
sistema e di imparare principiante-centrato guidando il lettore 
attraverso due modelli semplici della popolazione. Ciò è una 
risorsa grande per ottenere cominciata con Stella II. Fa parte 
dei programmi di strada 2.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το σεμινάριο pdf καλύπτει τα βασικά της 
δυναμικής συστημάτων και της χρήσης της Στέλλα ΙΙ λογισμικό. 
Ο σκοπός αυτού του άρθρου, όπως δηλώνεται από το συντάκτη
του, είναι να εισαχθεί ή να διευκρινιστεί η δυναμική συστημάτων,
η οποία μαζί με την αρχάριος-κεντροθετημένη εκμάθηση, "είναι 
εναλλακτικές προσεγγίσεις στο καθεστώς της ακριβούς πραγματικής 
εκπαίδευσης." Το σεμινάριο προορίζεται να χρησιμεύσει ως μια
εμπράγματη εισαγωγή στη δυναμική συστημάτων και την 
αρχάριος-κεντροθετημένη εκμάθηση για τους εκπαιδευτικούς και 
άλλες ενδιαφερόμενες στην εκμάθηση των βασικών της δυναμικής 
συστημάτων μέσω της διαμόρφωσης υπολογιστών. Το σεμινάριο 
εκθέτει μερικών από τις αρχές της δυναμικής συστημάτων και της 
αρχάριος-κεντροθετημένης εκμάθησης με την καθοδήγηση του 
αναγνώστη μέσω δύο απλών μοντέλων πληθυσμών. Αυτό είναι 
ένα μεγάλο στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς για να πάρει αρχισμένο με τη 
Στέλλα ΙΙ. Είναι μέρος των οδικών χαρτών 2.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta guía del pdf cubre los fundamentos de las 
dinámicas de los sistemas y el uso del software de Stella II. 
El propósito de este artículo, según lo indicado por su 
autor, es introducir o clarificar las dinámicas del sistema, que 
junto con aprender principiante-centrado, "son los acercamientos 
alternativos al status quo de la educación efectiva terminante." 
La guía se significa para servir como una introducción con 
manos a la dinámica del sistema y a aprender principiante-centrado 
para los educadores y otras interesadas en aprender los fundamentos de
las dinámicas del sistema con modelar del ordenador. La guía 
dispuso algunos de los principios de las dinámicas del sistema y de 
aprender principiante-centrado dirigiendo al programa de lectura a 
través de dos modelos simples de la población. Esto es un gran
recurso para conseguir comenzado con Stella II. Es parte de las 
correspondencias de camino 2.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:LESLIE MARTIN
FN:LESLIE MARTIN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212393</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104606</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/system-dynamics-in-education-the-first-steps</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
