<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105017</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105017</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203654</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Libby Asbestos Homepage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Libby Asbest-Homepage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Homepage d'Amiante de Libby</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Homepage Do Asbesto De Libby</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Homepage Dell'Amianto Di Libby</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αρχική σελίδα αμιάντων Libby</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Homepage Del Asbesto De Libby</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site is the public interface for the EPA's involvement with public health and environmental restoration efforts at an asbestos-contaminated vermiculite mining operation in Libby, Montana. The site provides fact sheets, press releases, documentation of community involvement, and sampling results. The site also provides links to additional resources about Libby, Montana and asbestos in general.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site ist die allgemeine Schnittstelle für 
die Miteinbeziehung des EPAs mit öffentlichem Gesundheitswesen und 
die Klimawiederherstellungbemühungen an einer Asbest-verschmutzten 
Vermiculitbergbauoperation in Libby, Montana. Die Site liefert 
Tatsache Blätter, Pressekommuniquã©s, Unterlagen der 
Gemeinschaftsmiteinbeziehung und Musterstückresultate. Die Site
stellt auch Links zu den zusätzlichen Betriebsmitteln über Libby, 
Montana und Asbest im allgemeinen zur Verfügung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site est l'interface publique pour la 
participation de l'EPA avec la santé publique et des efforts 
environnementaux de restauration à un travail dans la mine 
amiante-souillé de vermiculite dans Libby, Montana. Le site 
fournit des fiches documentaires , des communiqués de presse, la 
documentation de la participation de la communauté, et des résultats
de prélèvement. Le site fournit également des liens aux 
ressources supplémentaires au sujet de Libby, du Montana et d'amiante
en général.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local é a relação pública para a 
participação do EPA com saúde pública e esforços ambientais da 
restauração em uma operação de mineração asbesto-contaminada do 
vermiculite em Libby, Montana. O local fornece folhas do fato, 
liberações de imprensa, documentação da participação da 
comunidade, e resultados da amostragem. O local fornece também 
as ligações aos recursos adicionais sobre Libby, Montana e asbesto 
no general.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo è l'interfaccia pubblica per la 
partecipazione del EPA con sanità pubblica e gli sforzi ambientali di
ripristino ad un lavoro minerario amianto-contaminato della 
vermiculite in Libby, Montana. Il luogo fornisce i fogli di 
fatto, i comunicati stampa, la documentazione della partecipazione 
della Comunità ed i risultati di campione. Il luogo egualmente 
fornisce i collegamenti alle risorse supplementari circa Libby, il 
Montana e l'amianto in generale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή είναι η δημόσια διαπροσωπεία για τη 
συμμετοχή του EPA με τη δημόσια υγεία και τις περιβαλλοντικές 
προσπάθειες αποκατάστασης σε μια αμίαντος-μολυσμένη vermiculite
λειτουργία μεταλλείας σε Libby, Μοντάνα. Η περιοχή 
παρέχει τα ενημερωτικά δελτία, τα δελτία τύπου, την τεκμηρίωση 
της κοινοτικής συμμετοχής, και τα αποτελέσματα δειγματοληψίας. 
Η περιοχή παρέχει επίσης τις συνδέσεις με τα πρόσθετα 
στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς για Libby, τη Μοντάνα και τον αμίαντο 
γενικά.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio es el interfaz público para la 
implicación del EPA con salud pública y los esfuerzos ambientales de
la restauración en una operación de explotación minera 
asbesto-contaminada del vermiculite en Libby, Montana. El sitio 
proporciona a las hojas del hecho, a los desbloquear de prensa, a la 
documentación de la implicación de la comunidad, y a resultados del 
muestreo. El sitio también proporciona a conexiones a los 
recursos adicionales sobre Libby, Montana y el asbesto en general.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203654</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105017</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/libby-asbestos-homepage</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
