<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105195</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105195</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203792</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Marine Organisms for Aquaria and Their Required Maintenance</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Marineorganismen für Aquarien und ihre benötigte
Wartung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Organizations marines pour des aquariums et leur 
entretien requis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Organismos marinhos para aquários e sua 
manutenção requerida</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Organismi marini per gli acquari e la loro 
manutenzione richiesta</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θαλάσσιοι οργανισμοί για τα ενυδρεία και την 
απαραίτητη συντήρησή τους</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mamíferos marinos para los acuarios y su 
mantenimiento requerido</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This website offers information about ordering and taking care of marine organisms for a 10-gallon aquarium, an economical way for students to observe a mini-intertidal ecosystem of invertebrate life in the classroom. Educational references include: setting up your aquarium, seawater, organism care upon arrival, and organism care and feeding. Live marine organisms available for purchase are brittle starfish, starfish, sea urchins, grass shrimp, hermit crabs, periwinkle snails, coral, sea cucumbers, barnacles, small blue mussels, and sea lettuce. Additional links are provided for more information about the Marine Resources Center, including research programs, services, outreach/education, and policies/procedures.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Web site bietet Informationen über die 
Einrichtung und das Kümmern von von um Marineorganismen für ein 
10-Gallonen-Aquarium, eine ökonomische Methode an, damit 
Kursteilnehmer ein Mini-intertidales Oekosystem der wirbellosen 
Lebensdauer im Klassenzimmer beobachten. Pädagogische 
Referenzen schließen ein: Ihr Aquarium, Meerwasser, 
Organismusobacht nach Ankunft und Organismusobacht und -einziehen 
aufstellen. Die Phasenmarineorganismen, die für Erwerb 
vorhanden sind, sind spröde Starfish, Starfish, Seeigel, Grasgarnele,
Einsiedlerkrabben, Periwinkleschnecken, Koralle, Seegurken, 
Rankenfußkrebse, kleine blaue Miesmuscheln und Seekopfsalat. 
Zusätzliche Links werden zu mehr Information über die 
Marinebetriebsmittel zentrieren, einschließlich Forschung Programme, 
Dienstleistungen, outreach/education und policies/procedures zur 
Verfügung gestellt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site Web offre des informations sur la commande
et prendre de soin des organizations marines pour un aquarium de 
10-gallon, une voie économique pour que les étudiants observent un 
écosystème mini-intertidal de la vie invertébrée dans la salle de 
classe. Les références éducatives incluent : 
installation de votre aquarium, eau de mer, soin d'organization 
sur l'arrivée, et le soin et alimentation d'organization. Les 
organizations marines de phase disponibles pour l'achat sont les 
étoiles de mer fragiles, les étoiles de mer, les oursins, la 
crevette d'herbe, les bernard l'ermite, les escargots de bigorneau, le
corail, les concombres de mer, les bernaches, les petites moules 
bleues, et la laitue de mer. Des liens supplémentaires sont 
donnés pour plus d'informations sur les ressources marines centrent, 
y compris des programmes de recherche, des services, 
outreach/education, et policies/procedures.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Web site oferece a informação sobre 
requisitar e tomar cuidado de organismos marinhos para um aquário dos
10-gallon, uma maneira econômica para que os estudantes observem um 
ecosystem mini-mini-intertidal da vida invertebrate na sala de aula. 
As referências educacionais incluem: ajustando acima seus
aquário, seawater, cuidado do organismo em cima da chegada, e o 
cuidado e a alimentação do organismo. Os organismos marinhos 
vivos disponíveis para a compra são starfish frágeis, starfish, 
urchins de mar, shrimp da grama, caranguejos de hermit, caracóis do 
periwinkle, coral, pepinos do mar, barnacles, mexilhões azuis 
pequenos, e alface do mar. As ligações adicionais são 
fornecidas para mais informação sobre os recursos marinhos centram, 
including programas de pesquisa, serviços, outreach/education, e 
policies/procedures.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Web site offre le informazioni 
sull'ordinamento e sulla presa della cura degli organismi marini per 
un acquario di 10-gallon, un modo economico affinchè gli allievi 
osservi un ecosistema mini-intercotidale di vita invertebrata 
nell'aula. I riferimenti educativi includono: 
installazione del vostri acquario, acqua di mare, cura 
dell'organismo sull'arrivo e cura ed alimentazione dell'organismo. 
Gli organismi marini in tensione disponibili per l'acquisto sono
starfish fragili, starfish, urchins di mare, gambero dell'erba, 
granchi di hermit, lumache del periwinkle, coral, cetrioli del mare, 
barnacles, piccoli mitili blu e lattuga del mare. I collegamenti
supplementari sono forniti per le più informazioni sulle risorse 
marine si concentrano, compreso i programmi di ricerca, i servizi, 
outreach/education e policies/procedures.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος προσφέρει τις πληροφορίες για τη 
διαταγή και τη φροντίδα των θαλασσίων οργανισμών για ένα 
ενυδρείο 10-γαλονιού, ένας οικονομικός τρόπος για τους 
σπουδαστές να παρατηρηθεί ένα μίνι-διπαλιρροιακό οικοσύστημα της
ασπόνδυλης ζωής στην τάξη. Οι εκπαιδευτικές αναφορές 
περιλαμβάνουν: οργάνωση του ενυδρείου, του νερού της 
θάλασσας, της προσοχής οργανισμών σας επάνω στην άφιξη, και της 
προσοχής και της σίτισης οργανισμών. Ζήστε θαλάσσιοι 
οργανισμοί διαθέσιμοι γιατί η αγορά είναι εύθραυστος αστερίας, 
αστερίας, αχινοί, γαρίδες χλόης, καβούρια ερημιτών, σαλιγκάρια 
βιγκών, κοράλλι, αγγούρια θάλασσας, λαβίδες, μικρά μπλε μύδια, 
και μαρούλι θάλασσας. Οι πρόσθετες συνδέσεις παρέχονται για
περισσότερες πληροφορίες για το κέντρο των θαλασσίων πόρων, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένων των ερευνητικών προγραμμάτων, υπηρεσίες, 
ξεπερνούν/εκπαίδευση, και πολιτικές/διαδικασίες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este Web site ofrece la información sobre pedir y
tomar el cuidado de los mamíferos marinos para un acuario de los 
10-gallon, una manera económica para que los estudiantes observen un 
ecosistema mini-mini-intertidal de la vida invertebrada en la sala de 
clase. Las referencias educativas incluyen: setting-up su 
acuario, agua de mar, cuidado del organismo sobre llegada, y cuidado y
alimentación del organismo. Los mamíferos marinos vivos 
disponibles para la compra son estrellas de mar quebradizas, estrellas
de mar, pilluelos de mar, camarón de la hierba, cangrejos de 
ermitaño, caracoles del periwinkle, coral, pepinos del mar, 
barnacles, mejillones azules pequeños, y lechuga del mar. Las 
conexiones adicionales se proporcionan para más información sobre 
los recursos marinas centran, incluyendo programas de investigación, 
servicios, outreach/education, y policies/procedures.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MARINE RESOURCES CENTER
FN:MARINE RESOURCES CENTER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MARINE BIOLOGICAL LABORATORY
FN:MARINE BIOLOGICAL LABORATORY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203792</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105195</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/marine-organisms-for-aquaria-and-their-required-maintenance</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
