<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103632</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103632</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209811</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Circle definition and properties</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kreisdefinition und -eigenschaften</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Définition et propriétés de cercle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Definição e propriedades do círculo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Definizione e proprietà del cerchio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Καθορισμός και ιδιότητες κύκλων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Definición y características del círculo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page defining a circle. The applet shows a circle where the user can drag the center and a point on the circle. The radius line supports the definition that all points on the circle are a fixed distance from the center. The web page has the definitions of all the circle-related objects, such as diameter, chord etc, with links for each. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die einen Kreis definieren. Der applet zeigt einem 
Kreis, wo der Benutzer die Mitte und einen Punkt auf dem Kreis 
schleppen kann. Die Radiuszeile unterstützt die Definition, 
daß alle Punkte auf dem Kreis ein örtlich festgelegter Abstand von 
der Mitte sind. Die Webseite hat die Definitionen aller Kreis-in
Verbindung stehenden Nachrichten, wie Durchmesser, Akkord usw., mit 
Links für jedes. Applet kann zum vollen Bildumfang für 
Gebrauch mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. 
Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von 
jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den 
benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein 
Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven 
Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
définissant un cercle. L'applet montre à un cercle où 
l'utilisateur peut traîner le centre et un point sur le cercle. 
La ligne de rayon supporte la définition que tous les points 
sur le cercle sont une distance fixe du centre. La page Web a
les définitions de tous les objets cercle-connexes, tels que le 
diamètre, la corde etc.., avec des liens pour chacun. L'applet 
peut être agrandi à la taille de plein écran pour l'usage avec un 
projecteur de salle de classe. Le après utilisation dans la 
salle de classe, étudiant peut lui accéder encore de n'importe quel 
navigateur de Web à la maison ou dans la bibliothèque sans la 
procédure de connexion exigée. Cette ressource est un 
composant du projet interactif de manuel de la géométrie de 
référence ouverte de maths à http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
definem um círculo. O applet mostra a um círculo onde o 
usuário pode arrastar o centro e um ponto no círculo. A linha 
do raio suporta a definição que todos os pontos no círculo estão a
uma distância fixa do centro. O Web page tem as definições de
todos os objetos círculo-relacionados, tais como o diâmetro, a corda
etc., com ligações para cada um. O applet pode ser ampliado ao
tamanho de tela cheia para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. 
O depois de uso na sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la 
outra vez de todo o web browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum 
início de uma sessão requerido. Este recurso é um componente 
do projeto interativo do textbook da geometria da referência aberta 
do math em http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
definiscono un cerchio. Il applet mostra ad un cerchio dove 
l'utente può trascinare il centro e un punto sul cerchio. La 
riga del raggio sostiene la definizione che tutti i punti sul cerchio 
sono una distanza fissa dal centro. Il Web page ha le 
definizioni di tutti gli oggetti cerchio-relativi, quali il diametro, 
la corda ecc, con i collegamenti per ciascuno. Il applet può 
essere ingrandito al formato di schermo pieno per uso con un 
proiettore dell'aula. La post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo 
può accederle ancora da tutto il web browser nel paese o nella 
libreria senza l'inizio attività richiesto. Questa risorsa è 
un componente del progetto interattivo del manuale della geometria di 
riferimento aperto di per la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καθορίζουν έναν κύκλο. Το applet εμφανίζει έναν κύκλο 
όπου ο χρήστης μπορεί να σέρει το κέντρο και ένα σημείο στον 
κύκλο. Η γραμμή ακτίνας υποστηρίζει τον καθορισμό ότι όλα
τα σημεία στον κύκλο είναι μια σταθερή απόσταση από το κέντρο. 
Ιστοσελίδας έχει τους ορισμούς όλων των κύκλος-σχετικών με
τον αντικειμένων, όπως η διάμετρος, η χορδή κ.λπ..., με τις 
συνδέσεις για κάθε μια. Το Applet μπορεί να διευρυνθεί 
στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με έναν προβολέα τάξεων.
Μετά από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει 
πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι
ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια εισόδου που απαιτείται. 
Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του 
ανοικτού προγράμματος εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math 
διαλογικού σε http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
definen un círculo. El applet muestra a círculo donde el 
utilizador puede arrastrar el centro y una punta en el círculo. 
La línea del radio utiliza la definición que todas las puntas 
en el círculo son una distancia fija del centro. El Web page 
tiene las definiciones de todos los objetos ci'rculo-relacionados, 
tales como diámetro, acorde etc, con las conexiones para cada uno. 
El applet se puede agrandar a la talla de la pantalla completa 
para el uso con un proyector de la sala de clase. El uso 
posterior en la sala de clase, estudiante puede tenerle acceso otra 
vez de cualquier web browser en el país o en la biblioteca sin la 
conexión requerida. Este recurso es un componente del proyecto 
interactivo del libro de textos de la geometría de la referencia 
abierta de la matemáticas en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209811</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103632</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/circle-definition-and-properties</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
