<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108370</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108370</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087473</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Cast Down Your Bucket Where You Are": Booker T. Washington's Atlanta Compromise Speech</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Form Hinunter Ihre Wanne, In der Sie" Sind: 
Booker T. Washington Atlanta Kompromiss-Rede</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Fonte En bas de Votre Position Où Vous Êtes" : 
La Parole de Compromis d'Atlanta de Booker T. Washington</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Molde Abaixo Sua Cubeta Onde Você Está": 
Discurso Do Acordo De Atlanta De Booker T. Washington</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Getto Giù La Vostra Benna In cui Siete": 
Discorso Di Compromesso De Atlanta Di Booker T. Washington</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Χυτός κάτω από τον κάδο σας όπου είστε": Booker Τ. Ουάσιγκτον ομιλία συμβιβασμού της Ατλάντας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Molde Abajo De Su Compartimiento Donde Usted 
Está": Discurso Del Compromiso De Atlanta De Booker T. 
Washington</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1895, Booker T. Washington gave what later came to be known as the Atlanta Compromise speech before the Cotton States and International Exposition in Atlanta. His address was one of the most important and influential speeches in American history, guiding African-American resistance to white discrimination and establishing Washington as one of the leading black spokesmen in America. Washington's speech stressed accommodation rather than resistance to the racist order under which Southern African Americans lived. In 1903, Washington recorded this portion of his famous speech, the only surviving recording of his voice.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1895 gab Booker T. Washington, was später kam, 
als die Atlanta Kompromißrede vor den Baumwollzuständen bekannt und 
internationale Ausstellung in Atlanta. Seine Adresse war eine 
der wichtigsten und einflußreichsten Reden in der amerikanischen 
Geschichte, führte Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Widerstand zur weißen 
Unterscheidung und stellt Washington als einer der führenden 
schwarzen Wortführer in Amerika her. Rede Washingtons betonte 
Anpassung anstatt Widerstand zur rassistischen Ordnung, unter der 
südliche afrikanische Amerikaner lebten. 1903 speicherte 
Washington diesen Teil seiner berühmten Rede, die einzige 
Überlebenaufnahme seiner Stimme.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1895, Booker T. Washington a donné ce qui plus
tard est venu pour être connu en tant que le discours de compromis 
d'Atlanta avant les états de coton et exposition internationale à 
Atlanta. Son adresse était l'un des discours les plus 
importants et les plus influents dans l'histoire américaine, guidant 
la résistance afro-américaine à la discrimination blanche et 
établissant Washington en tant qu'un des principaux porte-parole 
noirs en Amérique. La parole de Washington a souligné le 
logement plutôt que la résistance à la commande raciste sous 
laquelle les Américains africains méridionaux ont vécu. En 
1903, Washington a enregistré cette partie de son discours célèbre,
le seul enregistrement de survie de sa voix.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1895, Booker T. Washington deu o que veio mais 
tarde ser sabido como o discurso do acordo de Atlanta antes dos 
estados do algodão e a exposição internacional em Atlanta. 
Seu endereço era um dos discursos os mais importantes e os mais
influential no history americano, guiando a resistência 
Africano-Americana à discriminação branca e estabelecendo 
Washington como um dos spokesmen pretos principais em América. 
O discurso de Washington forçou a acomodação melhor que a 
resistência à ordem racist sob que os americanos africanos do sul 
viveram. Em 1903, Washington gravou esta parcela de seu discurso
famoso, a única gravação sobreviver de sua voz.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1895, Booker il T. Washington ha dato che cosa 
più successivamente è venuto essere conosciuto come il discorso di 
compromesso de Atlanta prima che il cotone Dichiarasse ed 
esposizione internazionale a Atlanta. Il suo indirizzo era uno 
dei discorsi più importanti e più influenti nella storia americana, 
guidando la resistenza Africano-Americana a distinzione bianca e 
stabilendo Washington come uno dei portavoci neri principali in 
America. Il discorso de Washington ha sollecitato la 
sistemazione piuttosto che la resistenza all'ordine razzista sotto cui
gli Americani africani del sud hanno vissuto. In 1903, 
Washington ha registrato questa parte del suo discorso famoso, l'unica
registrazione di sopravvivenza della sua voce.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1895, Booker Τ. Ουάσιγκτον έδωσε ποιος πιό 
πρόσφατος ήρθε να μαθευτεί ως ομιλία συμβιβασμού της Ατλάντας 
ενώπιον των κρατών βαμβακιού και διεθνής έκθεση στην Ατλάντα. 
Η διεύθυνσή του ήταν μια από τις σημαντικότερες και 
επιδρούσες ομιλίες στην αμερικανική ιστορία, που καθοδηγεί την 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανική αντίσταση στην άσπρη διάκριση και που 
καθιερώνει την Ουάσιγκτον ως έναν από τους κύριους μαύρους 
εκπροσώπους στην Αμερική. Η ομιλία της Ουάσιγκτον τόνισε τη
στέγαση παρά την αντίσταση στη ρατσιστική κατάταξη κάτω από την
οποία νότιοι αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί έζησαν. Το 1903, η 
Ουάσιγκτον κατέγραψε αυτήν την μερίδα της διάσημης ομιλίας του, 
η μόνη επιζούσα καταγραφή της φωνής του.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1895, Booker T. Washington dio qué vino más 
adelante ser conocida como el discurso del compromiso de Atlanta antes
de los estados del algodón y exposición internacional en Atlanta. 
Su direccionamiento era uno de los discursos más importantes y 
más influyentes de la historia americana, dirigiendo resistencia 
Africano-Americana a la discriminación blanca y estableciendo 
Washington como uno de los portavoces negros principales en América. 
El discurso de Washington tensionó la comodidad más bien que 
la resistencia a la orden racist bajo la cual los americanos africanos
meridionales vivieron. En 1903, Washington registró esta 
porción de su discurso famoso, la única grabación el sobrevivir de 
su voz.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087473</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108370</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/cast-down-your-bucket-where-you-are-booker-t-washingtons-atlanta-compromise-speech</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
