<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105919</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105919</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087418</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Bacon's Rebellion: The Declaration (1676)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Aufstand Des Speckes: Die Erklärung (1676)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Rébellion du Lard : La Déclaration 
(1676)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Rebelião Do Bacon: A Declaração (1676)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ribellione della pancetta affumicata: La 
Dichiarazione (1676)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εξέγερση μπέϊκον: Η Διακήρυξη (1676)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Rebelión Del Tocino: El Declaración (1676)</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Economic and social power became concentrated in late seventeenth-century Virginia, leaving laborers and servants with restricted economic independence. Governor William Berkeley feared rebellion: "six parts of Seven at least are Poore, Indebted, Discontented and Armed." Planter Nathaniel Bacon focused inland colonists' anger at local Indians, who they felt were holding back settlement, and at a distant government unwilling to aid them. In the summer and fall of 1676, Bacon and his supporters rose up and plundered the elite's estates and slaughtered nearby Indians. Bacon's Declaration challenged the economic and political privileges of the governor's circle of favorites, while announcing the principle of the consent of the people. Bacon's death and the arrival of a British fleet quelled this rebellion, but Virginia's planters long remembered the spectacle of white and black acting together to challenge authority.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ökonomische und Sozialenergie wurde im späten 
Seventeenthjahrhundert Virginia konzentriert und ließ Arbeiter und 
Bedienstete mit eingeschränkter ökonomischer Unabhängigkeit. 
Gouverneur William Berkeley fürchtete Aufstand: "sechs 
Teile von sieben sind mindestens Poore, verschuldet, unzufrieden und 
bewaffnet." Pflanzer Nathaniel Speck fokussierte Zorn der 
inländischen Kolonisten an den lokalen Indern, die sie anhielten 
rückseitige Regelung und an einer entfernten Regierung glaubten, die 
abgeneigt ist, ihnen zu helfen. Am Sommer und am Fall von 1676, 
stiegen Speck und seine Verfechter oben und plünderten die Zustände 
der Auslese und schlachteten nahe gelegene Inder. Erklärung des
Speckes forderte die ökonomischen und politischen Privilegien des 
Kreises des Reglers der Lieblinge, beim Verkünden der Grundregel der 
Zustimmung von den Leuten heraus. Tod und die Ankunft des 
Speckes einer britischen Flotte unterdrückten diesen Aufstand, aber 
Pflanzer Virginias erinnerten lang sich das an Schauspiel von weißem 
und schwarzem zusammen fungieren, zum von von Berechtigung 
herauszufordern.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La puissance économique et sociale est devenue 
concentrée en dix-septième-siècle en retard la Virginie, laissant 
des travailleurs et des domestiques avec l'indépendance économique 
restreinte. Le Gouverneur William Berkeley a craint la 
rébellion : "six parts de sept sont au moins Poore, endetté, 
mécontent et armé." Le lard de Nathaniel de planteur a 
focalisé la colère des colons intérieurs aux Indiens locaux, qui 
elles se sont senties tenaient le règlement arrière, et à un 
gouvernement éloigné peu disposé à les aider. Pendant 
l'été et la chute de 1676, le lard et ses défenseurs se sont levés
vers le haut et ont pillé les domaines de l'élite et ont abattu les 
Indiens voisins. La déclaration du lard a défié les 
privilèges économiques et politiques du cercle du gouverneur des 
favoris, tout en annonçant le principe du consentement du peuple. 
La mort et l'arrivée du lard d'une flotte britannique ont 
apaisé cette rébellion, mais les planteurs de la Virginie se sont 
longtemps rappelés le spectacle de l'action blanche et noire ensemble
pour défier l'autorité.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A potência econômica e social tornou-se 
concentrada no décimo-século atrasado Virgínia, deixando laborers e
empregados com a independência econômica restrita. O regulador
William Berkeley temeu a rebelião: "seis porções de sete são
ao menos Poore, indebted, discontented e armado." O bacon de 
Nathaniel do plantador focalizou a raiva dos colonos inland nos 
indians locais, que sentiram prendiam o estabelecimento traseiro, e em
um governo distante unwilling lhes ajudar. No verão e na queda 
de 1676, o bacon e seus supporters levantaram-se acima e pilharam-se 
as propriedades do elite e slaughtered indians próximos. A 
declaração do bacon desafiou os privilégios econômicos e 
políticos do círculo do regulador dos favoritos, ao anunciar o 
princípio do consentimento dos povos. A morte e a chegada do 
bacon de uma frota britânica quelled esta rebelião, mas os 
plantadores de Virgínia recordaram por muito tempo o espetáculo de 
agir branco e preto junto para desafiar a autoridade.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'potenza economica e sociale è stato concentrata 
nel diciassettesimo-secolo tardo la Virginia, lasciando i lavoratori 
ed i servi con l'indipendenza economica limitata. Il regolatore 
William Berkeley ha temuto la ribellione: "sei parti di sette 
sono almeno Poore, obbligato, discontented e munito." La 
pancetta affumicata di Nathaniel della piantatrice ha messo a fuoco la
rabbia dei colonizzatori interni agli indiani locali, che hanno 
ritenuto erano stabilimento posteriore della tenuta e ad un 
governo distante poco disposto ad aiutarli. di estate e di 
caduta di 1676, la pancetta affumicata ed i suoi sostenitori sono 
aumentato in su ed hanno saccheggiato le proprietà dell'elite ed 
hanno macellato agli gli indiani vicini. La dichiarazione della 
pancetta affumicata ha sfidato i privilegi economici e politici del 
cerchio del regolatore dei favoriti, mentre annunciava il principio 
del consenso della gente. La morte e l'arrivo della pancetta 
affumicata di una flotta britannica hanno acquietato questa 
ribellione, ma le piantatrici della Virginia lungamente si sono 
ricordate dello spettacolo di comportarsi bianco e nero insieme per 
sfidare l'autorità.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η οικονομική και κοινωνική δύναμη έγινε συγκεντρωμένη
στον πρόσφατο δέκατος-αιώνα Βιρτζίνια, αφήνοντας τα laborers 
και τους υπαλλήλους με την περιορισμένη οικονομική ανεξαρτησία. 
Φοβισμένη εξέγερση William Μπέρκλευ! κυβερνητών: 
"έξι μέρη επτά τουλάχιστον είναι Poore, χρεωμένος, 
δυσαρεστημένος και οπλισμένος." Το μπέϊκον Nathaniel 
καλλιεργητών έστρεψε το θυμό των εσωτερικών αποίκων σε τοπικούς 
Ινδούς, οι οποίοι αισθάνθηκαν συγκρατούσαν την τακτοποίηση, και 
σε μια απόμακρη κυβέρνηση απρόθυμη να τους βοηθήσει. Το 
καλοκαίρι και την πτώση 1676, το μπέϊκον και οι υποστηρικτές 
του αυξήθηκαν επάνω και λεηλάτησαν τα κτήματα της ελίτ και 
θανάτωσαν κοντινούς Ινδούς. Η Διακήρυξη του μπέϊκον 
προκάλεσε τα οικονομικά και πολιτικά προνόμια του κύκλου του 
κυβερνήτη των συμπαθειών, αναγγέλλοντας την αρχή της συγκατάθεσης
των ανθρώπων. Ο θάνατος του μπέϊκον και η άφιξη ενός 
βρετανικού στόλου κατέστειλαν αυτήν την εξέγερση, αλλά οι 
καλλιεργητές της Βιρτζίνια θυμήθηκαν πολύ το θέαμα άσπρου και 
του Μαύρου που ενεργεί από κοινού για να προκαλέσουν την αρχή.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La potencia económica y social se concentró en el
último decimose'ptimo-siglo Virginia, dejando trabajadores y a 
criados con independencia económica restricta. El gobernador 
Guillermo Berkeley temió la rebelión: "seis porciones de siete
son por lo menos Poore, endeudado, discontented y armado." El 
tocino de Nathaniel del plantador enfocó la cólera de los colonos 
interiores en los indios locales, que se sentían celebraban el 
establecimiento posterior, y en un gobierno distante poco dispuesto 
ayudarles. En el verano y la caída de 1676, el tocino y sus 
partidarios se levantaron para arriba y pillaron los estados de la 
élite y mataron a indios próximos. El declaración del tocino 
desafió los privilegios económicos y políticos del círculo del 
gobernador de favoritos, mientras que anunciaba el principio del 
consentimiento de la gente. La muerte y la llegada del tocino de
una flota británica calmaron esta rebelión, pero los plantadores de 
Virginia recordaron de largo el espectáculo de actuar blanco y negro 
juntos para desafiar autoridad.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087418</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105919</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/bacons-rebellion-the-declaration-1676</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
