<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104594</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104594</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086735</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Playing for the Press: Strike Coverage by the Media</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spielen für die Presse: Schlag-Dichte 
durch die Media</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jeu pour la presse : Assurance de grève 
par les medias</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogar para a imprensa: Cobertura da batida 
pelos media</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giocando per la pressa: Riempimento di 
colpo dai media</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παιχνίδι για τον Τύπο: Κάλυψη απεργίας από το 
MEDIA</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El jugar para la prensa: Cobertura de la 
huelga por los media</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">While many assume that workers in the nineteenth-century American West enjoyed easily available land and a fluid social structure, the region's history of radical unionism at the turn of the century suggests otherwise. In Cripple Creek, Colorado, for example, violent conflict broke out in 1903 between members of the Western Federation of Miners (WFM) and corporate mining interests determined to crush the union. Before it was over, thirty men were dead and the union was defeated. But the battles of Cripple Creek were fought not only with bullets and dynamite--they were fought with words waged in the press. Telegrams between the New York  World , the pro-mine owner governor of Colorado, and WFM Secretary William Haywood underscored how the national press served as a public outlet in which both management and labor explained their motives and actions.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während viele annehmen, daß Arbeiter im 
19.-Jahrhundert amerikanischer Westen genossenen leicht vorhandenen 
Land und in einer flüssigen Sozialstruktur, die Geschichte der Region
des radikalen unionism an der Jahrhundertwende anders vorschlägt. 
Im Krüppel-Nebenfluß brach Kolorado z.B. heftige 
$überschneidung 1903 zwischen Bauteilen der westlichen Vereinigung 
der Bergmänner (WFM) und den korporativen gewinneninteressen, die 
festgestellt wurden, um den Anschluß zu zerquetschen aus. Bevor
es rüber sein, waren dreißig Männer tot und der Anschluß wurde 
besiegt. Aber die Schlachten des Krüppel-Nebenflusses wurden 
nicht nur mit Gewehrkugeln und Dynamit gekämpft -- they wurden mit
den Wörtern gekämpft, die in der Presse unternommen wurden. 
Telegramme zwischen der New York Welt, dem 
Promininhabergouverneur von Kolorado und WFM Sekretärin William 
Haywood unterstrichen, wie die nationale Presse während ein 
allgemeiner Anschluß diente, in dem Management und Arbeit ihre Motive
und Tätigkeiten erklärten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Tandis que beaucoup supposent que les ouvriers 
dans la terre disponible facilement appréciée par ouest américain 
de dix-neuvième-siècle et une structure sociale liquide, l'histoire 
de la région du syndicalisme radical à la fin du siècle suggère 
autrement. Dans la crique d'estropié, le Colorado, par exemple,
conflit violent a éclaté en 1903 entre les membres de la 
fédération occidentale des mineurs (WFM) et les intérêts 
d'extraction de corporation déterminés pour écraser l'union. 
Avant qu'il plus de, trente hommes étaient morts et l'union a 
été défaite. Mais les batailles de la crique d'estropié ont 
été combattues non seulement avec les balles et la dynamite -- elles
ont été combattues avec des mots faits dans la presse. Les 
télégrammes entre le monde de New York, le gouverneur de 
propriétaire de promine du Colorado, et le secrétaire William 
Haywood de WFM ont souligné comment la presse nationale a servi  une 
sortie publique en laquelle la gestion et le travail ont expliqué 
leurs motifs et actions.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quando muitos supuserem que os trabalhadores na 
terra disponível fàcilmente apreciada de décimo-século oeste 
americano e em uma estrutura social fluida, o history da região do 
unionism radical na volta do século sugerem de outra maneira. 
No creek do aleijado, Colorado, para o exemplo, conflito 
violento quebrou para fora em 1903 entre membros do federation 
ocidental dos mineiros (WFM) e os interesses minando incorporados 
determinados esmagar a união. Antes que sobre, trinta homens 
estiveram inoperantes e a união foi derrotada. Mas as batalhas 
do creek do aleijado foram lutadas não somente com balas e dinamite 
-- foram lutadas com as palavras empreendidas na imprensa. Os 
telegramas entre o mundo de New York, o regulador do proprietário do 
pro-mine de Colorado, e a secretária William Haywood de WFM 
underscored como a imprensa nacional serviu enquanto uma tomada 
pública em que  a gerência e o trabalho explicaram seus motriz e 
ações.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Mentre molti suppongono che gli operai nell'ovest
americano di diciannovesimo-secolo hanno goduto facilmente la terra 
disponibile e una struttura sociale fluida, la storia della regione 
del unionism radicale alla fine del secolo suggerisce al contrario. 
Nell'insenatura del cripple, Colorado, per esempio, conflitto 
violento ha scoppiato in 1903 fra i membri della federazione 
occidentale dei minatori (WFM) e gli interessi estraenti corporativi 
determinati per schiacciare l'unione. Prima che finito, trenta 
uomini erano guasti e l'unione è stata sconfitta. Ma le 
battaglie dell'insenatura del cripple sono state combattute non 
soltanto con le pallottole e la dinamite -- sono state combattute con 
le parole intraprese nella pressa. I telegrammi fra il mondo de 
New York, il regolatore del proprietario della promina di Colorado e 
la segretaria William Haywood di WFM hanno sottolineato come la pressa
nazionale ha servito da presa pubblica in cui sia la gestione che il 
lavoro hanno spiegato i loro motivi ed azioni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ενώ πολλοί υποθέτουν ότι οι εργαζόμενοι στην 
αμερικανική δύση δέκατος-αιώνα απόλαυσαν το εύκολα διαθέσιμο 
έδαφος και μια ρευστή κοινωνική δομή, η ιστορία της περιοχής του
ριζικού συνδικαλισμού στο γύρισμα του αιώνα προτείνει ειδάλλως. 
Cripple στον κολπίσκο, Κολοράντο, παραδείγματος χάριν, η
βίαια σύγκρουση ξέσπησε το 1903 μεταξύ των μελών της δυτικής 
ομοσπονδίας των ανθρακωρύχων (WFM) και τα εταιρικά ενδιαφέροντα
μεταλλείας αποφάσισαν να συντρίψουν την ένωση. Προτού να 
τελειώσει, τριάντα άτομα ήταν νεκρά και η ένωση νικήθηκε. 
Αλλά τις μάχες Cripple του κολπίσκου πάλεψαν όχι μόνο 
με τις σφαίρες και το δυναμίτη -- τις πάλεψαν με τις λέξεις στον 
Τύπο. Τα τηλεγραφήματα μεταξύ του κόσμου της Νέας Υόρκης, 
του pro-mine κυβερνήτη ιδιοκτητών του Κολοράντο, και WFM του 
γραμματέα William Haywood υπογράμμισαν πώς ο εθνικός Τύπος 
εχρησίμευσε ως μια δημόσια έξοδος στην οποία και η διαχείριση και
η εργασία εξήγησαν τα κίνητρα και τις ενέργειές τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mientras que muchos asumen que los trabajadores 
en la pista disponible fácilmente gozada oeste americano del 
diecinueveavo-siglo y una estructura social flúida, la historia de la
región del unionism radical al final del siglo sugieren de otra 
manera. En el cala del lisiado, Colorado, por ejemplo, conflicto
violento explotó en 1903 entre los miembros de la federación 
occidental de los mineros (WFM) y los intereses que minaban 
corporativos determinados para machacar la unión. Antes de que 
encima, treinta hombres eran muertos y la unión fue derrotada. 
Pero las batallas del cala del lisiado fueron luchadas no 
solamente con los puntos negros y la dinamita -- fueron luchadas con 
las palabras emprendidas en la prensa. Los telegramas entre el 
mundo de Nueva York, el gobernador del propietario del pro-mine de 
Colorado, y la secretaria Guillermo Haywood de WFM subrayaron cómo la
prensa nacional sirvió mientras que un enchufe público en el cual la
gerencia y el trabajo explicaron sus motivos y acciones.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086735</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104594</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/playing-for-the-press-strike-coverage-by-the-media</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
