<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108455</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108455</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205791</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Digital Workshops</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Digital Werkstätten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ateliers de Digital</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Oficinas De Digital</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gruppi di lavoro Di Digital</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ψηφιακά εργαστήρια</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Talleres De Digital</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">offers online professional development for teachers in math and science, language arts, and other areas. Watch presentations on vocabulary, phonemic awareness, reading and writing in the content areas, algebra, measurement and geometry, computation, linear equations, differentiated instruction, history, inclusive classrooms, using data to improve instruction, No Child Left Behind basics, and more. Many states offer professional development credit for teachers who participate.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">professionelle Onlineentwicklung der Angebote für 
Lehrer in Mathe und Wissenschaft, Sprachenkünste und andere Bereiche.
Überwachen Sie Darstellungen auf Wortschatz, phonemischem 
Bewußtsein, Messwert und Schreiben in den zufriedenen Bereichen, in 
der Algebra, im Messen und in der Geometrie, Übertragen auf 
Lochkarten, lineare Gleichungen, unterschiedene Anweisung, Geschichte,
einschließliche Klassenzimmer mit Daten, Anweisung zu verbessern, 
keinem Kind nach links hinter Grundlagen und mehr. Viele 
Zustände bieten professionelle Entwicklung Gutschrift für Lehrer an,
die teilnehmen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">développement professionnel en ligne d'offres pour
des professeurs dans les maths et la science, les arts de langage, et 
d'autres zones. Observez les présentations sur le vocabulaire, 
la conscience phonémique, la lecture et l'écriture dans les zones, 
l'algèbre, la mesure et la géométrie contentes, calcul, équations 
linéaires, instruction différenciée, histoire, salles de classe 
incluses, pas en utilisant les données pour améliorer l'instruction,
aucun enfant à gauche derrière des fondations, et plus. 
Beaucoup d'états offrent le degré de solvabilité professionnel de 
développement pour les professeurs qui participent.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">desenvolvimento profissional em linha das ofertas 
para professores no math e a ciência, as artes da língua, e as 
outras áreas. Preste atenção a apresentações no 
vocabulário, na consciência phonemic, na leitura e na escrita nas 
áreas, na álgebra, na medida e na geometria satisfeitas, 
computação, equações lineares, instrução diferenciada, history, 
salas de aula inclusivas, não usando dados melhorar a instrução, 
nenhuma criança à esquerda atrás dos princípios, e mais. 
Muitos estados oferecem o crédito profissional do 
desenvolvimento para os professores que participam.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">sviluppo professionale in linea di offerte per gli 
insegnanti nel per la matematica e scienza, arti di linguaggio ed 
altre zone. Guardi le presentazioni su vocabolario, su 
consapevolezza fonematica, su lettura e su scrittura nelle zone, 
nell'algebra, nella misura e nella geometria soddisfatte, il calcolo, 
le equazioni lineari, l'istruzione differenziata, la storia, aule 
comprese, non usando i dati per migliorare l'istruzione, bambino a 
sinistra dietro i principi fondamentali e più. Molti 
dichiarano l'accreditamento professionale di sviluppo di offerta 
per gli insegnanti che partecipano.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">προσφέρει τη σε απευθείας σύνδεση επαγγελματική 
ανάπτυξη για τους δασκάλους στο math και την επιστήμη, τις 
γλωσσικές τέχνες, και άλλες περιοχές. Οι παρουσιάσεις 
ρολογιών για το λεξιλόγιο, τη φθογγική συνειδητοποίηση, την 
ανάγνωση και το γράψιμο στις ικανοποιημένες περιοχές, την 
άλγεβρα, τη μέτρηση και τη γεωμετρία, υπολογισμός, γραμμικές 
εξισώσεις, διαφοροποίησαν την οδηγία, ιστορία, συμπεριλαμβάνουσες
τάξεις, χρησιμοποιώντας τα στοιχεία για να βελτιώσουν την οδηγία,
κανένα παιδί που αφέθηκε τα βασικά, και περισσότερο. Πολλά
κράτη προσφέρουν την επαγγελματική πίστωση ανάπτυξης για τους 
δασκάλους που συμμετέχουν.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">desarrollo profesional en línea de las ofertas 
para los profesores en matemáticas y ciencia, artes del lenguaje, y 
otras áreas. Mire las presentaciones en vocabulario, 
conocimiento del fonema, la lectura y la escritura en las áreas, la 
álgebra, la medida y la geometría contentas, cómputo, ecuaciones 
lineares, instrucción distinguida, historia, salas de clase 
inclusivas, usando datos para mejorar la instrucción, ningún niño a
la izquierda detrás de fundamentos, y más. Muchos estados 
ofrecen el crédito profesional del desarrollo para los profesores que
participan.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205791</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108455</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/digital-workshops</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
