<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105834</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105834</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086314</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"If We Must Die": Claude McKay Limns the "New Negro"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Wenn Wir Sterben Müssen": Claude McKay 
Limns der "neue Schwarze"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Si Nous Devons Mourir" : Claude McKay Limns
le "nouveau nègre"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Se Nós Devemos Morrer": Claude McKay Limns
"o negro novo"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Se Dobbiamo Morire": Claude McKay Limns "il
nuovo negro"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Εάν πρέπει να πεθάνουμε": Θ*Θλαuδε McKay 
Limns ο "νέος νέγροσ"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Si Debemos Morir": Claude McKay Limns el 
"nuevo negro"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Hundreds of writers and artists lived in Harlem in the 1920s and 1930s and were part of a vibrant, creative community that found its voice in what came to be called the "Harlem Renaissance." Alain Locke's 1925 collection  The New Negro --a compilation of literature by and essays about "New Negro" artists and black culture--became a "manifesto" of the movement. Some of black America's foremost writers contributed stories and poems to the volume. The work of these artists drew upon the African-American experience and expressed a new pride in black racial identity and heritage. Several factors accounted for the birth of the movement and propelled it forward. By 1920 the once white ethnic neighborhood of Harlem in upper Manhattan overflowed with recent African-American migrants from the South and the Caribbean. Black soldiers returning from World War I shared a new sense of pride, militancy, and entitlement, as expressed in Claude McKay's 1919 protest poem "If We Must Die."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hunderte Verfasser und Künstler wohnten in Harlem
in den zwanziger Jahren und in den dreißiger Jahren und waren ein 
Teil einer vibrant, kreativen Gemeinschaft, die seine Stimme fand in, 
was kam, genannt zu werden die "Harlem Renaissance." Alain 
Lockes 1925 Ansammlung die neue Schwarze --a Kompilation der Literatur
der vorbei und Versuche über Künstler "des neuen Schwarzen" und 
schwarze Kultur -- wurde ein "Manifest" der Bewegung. 
Einige von schwarzen Amerikas vordersten Verfassern trugen 
Geschichten und Gedichte zum Datenträger bei. Die Arbeit dieser
Künstler zeichnete nach der Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Erfahrung und 
drückte einen neuen Stolz in der schwarzen rassischen Identität und 
im Erbe aus. Einige Faktoren berechneten die Geburt der Bewegung
und trieben sie vorwärts an. Durch 1920, sobald weiße 
ethnische Nachbarschaft von Harlem in oberem Manhattan mit neuen 
Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Wanderern vom Süden und von den 
Karibischen Meeren überlief. Die schwarzen Soldaten, die vom 
Ersten Weltkrieg zurückkommen, teilten eine neue Richtung des 
Stolzes, des Militancy und der Bezeichnung, wie Claude McKays 1919 
ausgedrückt im Protestgedicht ", wenn wir sterben müssen."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les centaines d'auteurs et artistes ont habité 
dans Harlem dans les années 20 et les années 30 et faisaient 
partie d'une communauté vibrante et créatrice qui a trouvé sa 
voix dans ce qui est venu pour s'appeler la "Renaissance de 
Harlem." Collection d'Alain Locke 1925 la nouvelle 
compilation de --a de nègre de la littérature près et des essais au
sujet des artistes de "nouveau nègre" et de la culture noire -- est 
devenu un "manifeste" du mouvement. Certains des premiers 
auteurs de l'Amérique noire ont contribué des histoires et des 
poésies au volume. Le travail de ces artistes a utilisé 
l'expérience afro-américaine et a exprimé une nouvelle fierté en 
identité et héritage raciaux noirs. Plusieurs facteurs ont 
expliqué la naissance du mouvement et l'ont propulsé en avant. 
Par 1920 une fois que le voisinage ethnique blanc de Harlem
à Manhattan supérieure débordait avec les migrants afro-américains 
récents des Sud et des Caraïbes. Les soldats noirs 
retournant de la Première Guerre Mondiale ont partagé un nouveau 
sens de fierté, de militantisme, et de droit, comme exprimé en 
poésie de protestation de Claude McKay 1919 "si nous devons mourir."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As centenas dos escritores e dos artistas viveram 
em Harlem nos 1920s e nos 1930s e foram parte de uma comunidade 
vibrant, creativa que encontrasse sua voz em o que veio ser chamado de
"o renascimento Harlem." Coleção de Alain Locke 1925 a 
compilação nova do --a do negro da literatura perto e dos essays 
sobre "artistas do negro novo" e a cultura preta -- tornou-se um 
"manifesto" do movimento. Alguns de escritores foremost de 
América preta contribuíram histórias e poemas ao volume. O 
trabalho destes artistas desenhou em cima da experiência 
Africano-Americana e expressou um orgulho novo na identidade e no 
heritage raciais pretos. Diversos fatores explicaram o 
nascimento do movimento e propeliram-no para a frente. Por 1920 
uma vez que a vizinhança étnica branca de Harlem em Manhattan 
superior transbordou com os emigrantes Africano-Americanos recentes do
sul e das Caraíbas. Os soldados pretos que retornam do 
world.war.i compartilharam de um sentido novo do orgulho, do 
militancy, e do entitlement, como expressado no poema do protesto de 
Claude McKay 1919 "se nós devêssemos morrer."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I centinaia dei produttori e degli artisti hanno 
vissuto in Harlem negli anni 20 e nei 1930s e facevano parte di una 
Comunità vibrant e creativa che ha trovato la relativa voce in che 
cosa è venuto essere chiamato "la rinascita di Harlem." 
Accumulazione di Alain Locke 1925 la nuova compilazione di --a 
del negro di letteratura vicino e dei saggi circa "gli artisti del 
nuovo negro" e la coltura nera -- è diventato "un manifesto" del 
movimento. Alcuni di primi produttori dell'America nera hanno 
contribuito le storia ed i poems al volume. Il lavoro di questi 
artisti ha dissipato sull'esperienza Africano-Americana ed ha espresso
un nuovo orgoglio nell'identità e nell'eredità razziali nere. 
Parecchi fattori hanno rappresentato la nascita del movimento e 
lo hanno azionato in avanti. Da 1920 una volta che la vicinanza 
etnica bianca di Harlem a Manhattan superiore traboccasse con i 
migranti Africano-Americani recenti dal sud e dai Caraibi. I 
soldati neri che ritornano dal world.war.i hanno ripartito un nuovo 
senso di orgoglio, di militanza e di autorizzazione, come espresso 
in poem di protesta di Claude McKay 1919 "se dobbiamo morire."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι εκατοντάδες των συγγραφέων και των καλλιτεχνών 
έζησαν σε Harlem στη δεκαετία του '20 και τη δεκαετία του '30 
και ήταν μέρος μιας δονούμενης, δημιουργικής κοινότητας που 
βρήκε τη φωνή της σε αυτό που ήρθε να κληθεί "αναγέννηση 
Harlem." Συλλογή του 1925 του Alain Locke's η νέα 
μεταγλώττιση νέγρων AA της λογοτεχνίας κοντά και των δοκίμιων 
για τους καλλιτέχνες "νέων νέγρων" και το μαύρο πολιτισμό -- 
έγινε ένα "μανιφέστο" της μετακίνησης. Μερικοί από τους 
πρώτιστους συγγραφείς της μαύρης Αμερικής συνέβαλαν τις ιστορίες
και τα ποιήματα στην ένταση του ήχου. Η εργασία αυτών των 
καλλιτεχνών βασίστηκε στην αφρικανικός-αμερικανική εμπειρία και 
εξέφρασε μια νέα υπερηφάνεια στη μαύρες φυλετικές ταυτότητα και 
την κληρονομιά. Διάφοροι παράγοντες αποτέλεσαν τη γέννηση 
της μετακίνησης και την ώθησαν μπροστινή. Μέχρι το 1920 η
μιά φορά άσπρη εθνική γειτονιά Harlem στο ανώτερο Μανχάτταν 
ξεχείλισε με τους πρόσφατους αφρικανικός-αμερικανικούς μετανάστες
από το νότο και τις Καραϊβικές Θάλασσες. Οι μαύροι 
στρατιώτες που επιστρέφουν από τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι 
μοιράστηκαν μια νέα αίσθηση της υπερηφάνειας, της μαχητικότητας, 
και της εξουσιοδότησης, όπως εκφράζεται στο ποίημα διαμαρτυρίας 
του Claude McKay's το 1919 "εάν πρέπει να πεθάνουμε."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los centenares de programas de escritura y de 
artistas vivieron en Harlem en los años 20 y los años 30 y eran 
parte de una comunidad vibrante, creativa que encontró su voz en 
qué vino ser llamada el "renacimiento de Harlem." Colección de
Alain Locke 1925 la nueva compilación del --a del negro de la 
literatura cerca y de los ensayos sobre artistas del "nuevo negro" y 
cultura negra -- se convirtió un "manifiesto" del movimiento. 
Algunos de los primeros programas de escritura de América negra
contribuyeron historias y los poemas al volumen. El trabajo de 
estos artistas trazó sobre la experiencia Africano-Americana y 
expresó un nuevo orgullo en identidad y herencia raciales negras. 
Varios factores consideraron el nacimiento del movimiento y lo 
propulsaron adelante. Por 1920 una vez que la vecindad étnica 
blanca de Harlem en Manhattan superior desbordara con los nómadas 
Africano-Americanos recientes del sur y del Caribe. Los soldados
negros que volvían de Primera Guerra Mundial compartieron un nuevo 
sentido del orgullo, de la militancia, y del derecho, según lo 
expresado en poema de la protesta de Claude McKay 1919 "si debemos 
morir."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086314</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105834</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/if-we-must-die-claude-mckay-limns-the-new-negro</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
