<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106801</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106801</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207001</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">New York: A Documentary Film</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">New York: Ein Dokumentarischer Film</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">New York : Un Film Documentaire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">New York: Uma Película Documentary</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">New York: Una Pellicola Documentaria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Νέα Υόρκη: Ένα ντοκημαντέρ</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Nueva York: Una Película Documental</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a place where kids can explore the history of New York and activities that will help them learn more about their own towns and get involved in their communities. Visitors are introduced to 12 little-known locations in the city, can sit in the back of an animated New York cab driven by a bantering celebrity, or explore the views of 32 luminaries who discuss the city that inspired them.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist ein Platz, in dem Zicklein die Geschichte von 
New York und von Aktivitäten erforschen können, die ihnen mehr, 
über ihre eigenen Städte zu erlernen hilft und in ihren 
Gemeinschaften beteiligt zu erhalten. Besucher werden zu 12 
wenig bekannten Standorten in der Stadt, können in der Rückseite 
eines lebhaften New York Fahrerhauses sitzen eingeführt, das von 
einer neckenden Berühmtheit angetrieben wird, oder erforschen Sie die
Ansichten von 32 Luminaries, die die Stadt behandeln, die sie 
anspornte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est un endroit où les gosses peuvent explorer 
l'histoire de New York et d'activités qui les aidera à apprendre 
plus au sujet de leurs propres villes et à devenir impliquée dans 
leurs communautés. Des visiteurs sont présentés à 12 
emplacements peu connus dans la ville, peuvent se reposer dans le dos 
d'une cabine animée de New York conduite par une célébrité 
plaisantante, ou explorez les vues de 32 lumières qui discutent la 
ville qui les a inspirées.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é um lugar onde os miúdos possam explorar o 
history de New York e de atividades que lhes ajudará aprender mais 
sobre suas próprias cidades e os começar involvida em suas 
comunidades. Os visitantes são introduzidos a 12 posições 
little-known na cidade, podem sentar-se na parte traseira de um táxi 
animated de New York dirigido por uma celebridade bantering, ou 
explore as opiniões 32 luminaries que discutem a cidade que os 
inspirou.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è un posto in cui i capretti possono esplorare la
storia di New York e di attività che le aiuterà ad imparare più 
circa le loro proprie città ed ad ottenere implicate nelle loro 
Comunità. Gli ospiti sono introdotti a 12 posizioni poco noto 
nella città, possono sedersi nella parte posteriore di una carrozza 
animata de New York condotta da un celebrity bantering, o esplori i 
punti di vista di 32 luminaries che discutono la città che li ha 
ispirati.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">_ είμαι ένας θέση όπου κατσίκι μπορώ ερευνώ ο 
ιστορία Υόρκη και δραστηριότητα που θα βοηθώ αυτός μαθαίνω 
περισσότερος για τους πόλη και αναμιγνύομαι περι:λαμβάνω τους 
κοινότητα. Οι επισκέπτες εισάγονται σε 12 little-known 
θέσεις στην πόλη, μπορούν να καθίσουν στο πίσω μέρος ενός 
ζωντανεψονταυ αμαξιού της Νέας Υόρκης που οδηγείται από μια 
bantering προσωπικότητα, ή να ερευνήσουν τις όψεις 32 
luminaries που συζητούν την πόλη που τις ενέπνευσε.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es un lugar en donde los cabritos pueden explorar 
la historia de Nueva York y de las actividades que les ayudará a 
aprender más sobre sus propias ciudades y a conseguir implicadas en 
sus comunidades. Introducen a los visitantes a 12 localizaciones
poco conocidas en la ciudad, pueden sentarse en la parte posteriora de
un taxi animado de Nueva York conducido por una celebridad que bromea,
o explore las opiniones 32 lumbreras que discutan la ciudad que las 
inspiró.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207001</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106801</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/new-york-a-documentary-film</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
