<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104442</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104442</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203730</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Lunar Lander</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mondlander</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Lander Lunaire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Lander Lunar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lander Lunare</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σεληνιακό Lander</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Lander Lunar</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Can you avoid the boulder field and land safely, just before your fuel runs out, as Neil Armstrong did in 1969? Our version of this classic video game accurately simulates the real motion of the lunar lander with the correct mass, thrust, fuel consumption rate, and lunar gravity. The real lunar lander is very hard to control.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <language>es</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Können Sie den Flußstein vermeiden 
auffangen und landen sicher, kurz bevor Ihr Kraftstoff heraus
läuft, wie Neil Armstrong 1969 tat? Unsere Version dieses 
klassischen videospiels simuliert genau die reale Bewegung des 
Mondlander mit der korrekten Masse, dem Schub, der 
Kraftstoffverbrauchkinetik und der Mond-Schwerkraft. Das reale 
Mondlander ist sehr hart zu steuern.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pouvez-vous éviter le gisement de rocher et 
débarquer sans risque, juste avant que votre carburant s'épuise, 
comme Neil Armstrong a fait en 1969 ? Notre version de ce 
jeu vidéo classique simule exactement le vrai mouvement du lander 
lunaire avec la masse correcte, la poussée, la cadence de 
consommation de carburant, et la pesanteur lunaire. Il est très
difficile de contrôler le vrai lander lunaire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Pode você evitar o campo do pedregulho e 
aterrá-lo com segurança, imediatamente antes que seu combustível 
funciona para fora, como Neil Armstrong fêz em 1969? Nossa 
versão deste jogo video clássico simula exatamente o movimento real 
do lander lunar com a massa correta, a pressão, a taxa do consumo de 
combustível, e a gravidade lunar. O lander lunar real é muito 
duro de controlar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Potete evitare il giacimento del masso ed atterrare
sicuro, appena prima che il vostro combustibile si esaurisce, come 
Neil Armstrong ha fatto in 1969? La nostra versione di questo 
video gioco classico simula esattamente il movimento reale del lander 
lunare con la massa corretta, la spinta, il tasso del consumo di 
combustibile e la gravità lunare. Il lander lunare reale è 
molto duro da gestire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μπορείτε να αποφύγετε το πεδίο και το έδαφος λίθων 
ακίνδυνα, αμέσως πριν από τα τρεξίματα καυσίμων σας έξω, 
δεδομένου ότι ο Neil Armstrong έκανε το 1969; Η 
έκδοση αυτού του κλασικού τηλεοπτικού παιχνιδιού μας μιμείται 
ακριβώς την πραγματική κίνηση του σεληνιακού lander με τη 
σωστό μάζα, την ώθηση, το ποσοστό κατανάλωσης καυσίμων, και τη 
σεληνιακή βαρύτητα. Το πραγματικό σεληνιακό lander είναι
πολύ δύσκολο να ελεγχτεί.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿Puede usted evitar el campo del canto rodado y 
aterrizar con seguridad, momentos antes que su combustible se ejecuta 
hacia fuera, como Neil Armstrong hizo en 1969? Nuestra versión 
de este juego video clásico simula exactamente el movimiento 
verdadero del lander lunar con la masa correcta, el empuje, la tarifa 
de la consumición de combustible, y la gravedad lunar. El 
lander lunar verdadero es muy duro de controlar.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203730</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104442</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/lunar-lander</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
