<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103168</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103168</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087419</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Ballad to a Massacre: Private Prather's Portrait of Wounded Knee</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ballade zu einem Blutbad: Portrait privaten 
Prathers des verletzten Knies</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ballade à un Massacre : La verticale de 
Prather privé du genou blessé</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ballad a um massacre: Retrato de Prather 
confidencial de joelho ferido</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ballad ad un massacre: Ritratto del 
Prather riservato del ginocchio ferrito</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μπαλάντα σε μια σφαγή: Πορτρέτο ιδιωτικού 
Prather του πληγωμένου γονάτου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Balada a una Masacre: Retrato de Prather 
privado de la rodilla herida</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1888 Plains Indians enacted a religious ritual seeking delivery from white domination, which took the form of a five-night dance (dubbed the "Ghost Dance" by whites). Two years later, the U.S. Army extinguished this vision of hope and defiance at the battle at Wounded Knee Creek on December 29, 1890. W. H. Prather, an African-American private in the Ninth Cavalry and the regimental poet, wrote "The Indian Ghost Dance and War," which recounted in ballad form the military's perspective on the massacre at Wounded Knee. Prather's song, which became a favorite among the troops, celebrated an event that American Indians would long view as a great tragedy and injustice.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Auf 1888 Ebenen Inder verordnete eine fromme 
rituelle suchende Anlieferung von der weißen Herrschaft, die die 
Gestalt eines Fünfnachttanzes annahm (betitelt dem "Geist-Tanz" durch
Weiß). Zwei Jahre später, löschte die VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Armee diesen Anblick der Hoffnung und des Trotzes an der 
Schlacht an verletztem Knie-Nebenfluß an Dezember 29, 1890 aus. 
W. H. Prather, ein Afrikanisch-Amerikanisches privates in der 9.
Kavallerie und im Regimentsdichter, schrieb "den indischen Geist-Tanz 
und den Krieg,", die in der Balladeform die Perspektive des Militärs 
auf dem Blutbad an verletztem Knie nachzählten. Lied Prathers, 
das einem Liebling unter den Truppen stand, feierte einen Fall, daß 
Indianer sich Ansicht als große Tragödie und Unrecht sehnen würden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans 1888 Indiens de plaines a décrété une 
livraison recherchante rituelle religieuse de la domination blanche, 
qui a pris la forme d'une danse de cinq-nuit (doublée la "danse 
d'ordinateur de secours" par des blancs). Deux ans après, 
l'armée des ETATS-UNIS s'est éteinte cette vision d'espoir et de 
défit à la bataille à la crique blessée de genou décembre 29, 
1890. W. H. Prather, un Afro-Américain privé dans la neuvième 
cavalerie et le poèt régimentaire, a écrit "la danse et la guerre 
indiennes d'ordinateur de secours," qui ont raconté sous la forme de 
ballade la perspective des militaires sur le massacre au genou 
blessé. La chanson de Prather, qui est allée bien à un favori
parmi les troupes, a célébré un événement que les Indiens 
d'Amerique désireraient ardemment vue comme grandes tragédie et 
injustice.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1888 indians de planícies decretou uma entrega
procurando ritual religiosa do domination branco, que fêz exame do 
formulário de uma dança da cinco-noite (dubbed do "a dança ghost" 
por brancos). Dois anos mais tarde, o exército de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS extinguiu esta visão da esperança e do defiance na batalha em
creek ferido do joelho dezembro em 29, 1890. W. H. Prather, um 
confidencial Africano-Americano na nona cavalaria e no poeta 
regimental, escreveu "a dança e a guerra indian do ghost," que 
recounted no formulário do ballad o perspective das forças armadas 
no massacre em joelho ferido. A canção de Prather, que 
assentou bem em um favorito entre as tropas, comemorou um evento que 
os indians americanos long vista como uma tragédia e um injustice 
grandes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1888 indiani di pianure ha promulgato una 
consegna di ricerca ritual religiosa dalla dominazione bianca, che ha 
preso la forma di un ballo di cinque-notte (dubbed "il ballo del 
fantasma" dai bianchi). Due anni più successivamente, 
l'esercito degli STATI UNITI ha estinto questa visione di speranza e 
del defiance alla battaglia all'insenatura ferrita del ginocchio il 29
dicembre 1890. W. H. Prather, un riservato Africano-Americano 
nel nono cavalry e nel poet regimental, ha scritto "il ballo e la 
guerra indiani del fantasma," che hanno raccontato nella forma del 
ballad la prospettiva dei militari sul massacre al ginocchio ferrito. 
La canzone del Prather, che ha stato bene ad un favorito fra le 
truppe, ha celebrato un evento che gli indiani americani 
desidererebbero vista come una tragedia ed injustice grandi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στις πεδιάδες του 1888 Ινδοί θέσπισαν μια 
θρησκευτική τελετουργική παράδοση επιδίωξης από την άσπρη 
κυριαρχία, η οποία έλαβε τη μορφή ενός χορού πέντε-νύχτας (που
μεταγλωττίζεται το "χορό φαντασμάτων" από τα λευκά). Δύο 
έτη αργότερα, ο ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΣ στρατός εξαφάνισε αυτό το όραμα της
ελπίδας και της περιφρόνησης στη μάχη στον πληγωμένο κολπίσκο 
γονάτων στις 29 Δεκεμβρίου, 1890, Θ*Ω. Χ. Prather, ένας 
αφρικανικός-Αμερικανός ιδιωτικός στο ένατο ιππικό και ο 
συνταγματικός ποιητής, έγραψε "τον ινδικούς χορό και τον πόλεμο 
φαντασμάτων," που εξιστόρησαν με μορφή μπαλάντας την προοπτική 
των στρατιωτικών στη σφαγή στο πληγωμένο γόνατο. Το 
τραγούδι του Prather, που έγινε μια συμπάθεια μεταξύ των 
στρατευμάτων, γιόρτασε ένα γεγονός που αμερικανικοί Ινδοί θα 
εμφάνιζαν πολύ ως μεγάλες τραγωδία και αδικία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1888 indios de llanos decretó una salida que 
buscaba ritual religiosa de la dominación blanca, que tomó la forma 
de una danza de la cinco-noche (doblada la "danza del fantasma" por 
blancos). Dos años más adelante, el ejército de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS extinguió esta visión de la esperanza y del desafío en la 
batalla en el cala herido de la rodilla 29 de diciembre de 1890. 
W. H. Prather, un privado Africano-Americano en la novena 
caballería y el poeta regimental, escribió "la danza y la guerra 
indias del fantasma," que contaron de nuevo en forma de la balada la 
perspectiva de los militares en la masacre en la rodilla herida. 
La canción de Prather, que sintió bien a un favorito entre las
tropas, celebró un acontecimiento que los indios americanos 
desearían visión como una grandes tragedia e injusticia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087419</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103168</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/ballad-to-a-massacre-private-prathers-portrait-of-wounded-knee</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
