<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107208</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107208</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204614</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">What Do YOU See? (Pre-Visit)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Was Sehen SIE? (Vor-Besuchen Sie)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Que Voyez-vous ? (Pré-Visitez)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Que VOCÊ Vê? (Pre-Visite)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Che cosa Vedete? (Pre-Visiti)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τι Βλέπετε; (Προ-επίσκεψη)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿Qué USTED Ve? (Pre-Visite)</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This lesson introduces students to the importance of making accurate, detailed scientific observations, and the value of learning about others' views and perspectives regarding a specific topic or event. It also serves as an activity to prepare students for a visit to the Ackland Art Museum in Chapel Hill, NC (or any museum, real or virtual). This lesson is the first of three lessons that build upon each other, using the Ackland Art Museum as the focus.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Lektion stellt Kursteilnehmer für den Wert 
des Bildens der genauen, ausführlichen wissenschaftlichen 
Beobachtungen und des Wertes des Lernens über anderer von von 
Ansichten und von von Perspektiven betreffend sind ein spezifisches 
Thema oder einen Fall vor. Sie dient auch als Aktivität, 
Kursteilnehmer für einen Besuch zum Ackland kunst-Museum im 
Kapelle-Hügel, NC (oder irgendein Museum, real oder virtuell) 
vorzubereiten. Diese Lektion ist die erste von drei Lektionen, 
die nach einander aufbauen mit dem Ackland kunst-Museum als der Fokus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette leçon présente des étudiants à 
l'importance de faire des observations scientifiques précises et 
détaillées, et la valeur de se renseigner sur d'autres des vues et 
des perspectives concernant un sujet ou un événement spécifique. 
Elle sert également d'activité pour préparer des étudiants 
pour une visite au musée d'art d'Ackland en colline de chapelle, OR 
(ou tout musée, vrai ou virtuel). Cette leçon est la première
de trois leçons qui construisent sur l'un l'autre, en utilisant le 
musée d'art d'Ackland comme foyer.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta lição introduz estudantes à importância 
de fazer observações científicas exatas, detalhadas, e o valor de 
aprender sobre outros vistas e perspectives a respeito de um tópico 
ou de um evento específico. Serve também como uma atividade 
preparar estudantes para uma visita ao museu da arte de Ackland no 
monte do chapel, NC (ou algum museu, real ou virtual). Esta 
lição é a primeira de três lições que constroem em cima de se, 
usando o museu da arte de Ackland como o foco.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa lezione introduce gli allievi 
all'importanza di fare le osservazioni scientifiche esatte e 
dettagliate ed il valore dell'imparare circa altri le viste e le 
prospettive per quanto riguarda un soggetto o un evento specifico. 
Egualmente serve da attività preparare gli allievi per una 
chiamata al museo di arte di Ackland in collina del chapel, NC (o 
qualsiasi museo, reale o virtuale). Questa lezione è la prima 
di tre lezioni che costruiscono su a vicenda, usando il museo di arte 
di Ackland come il fuoco.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το μάθημα εισάγει τους σπουδαστές στη σημασία 
τις ακριβείς, λεπτομερείς επιστημονικές παρατηρήσεις, και την 
αξία της εκμάθησης για άλλες τις όψεις και τις προοπτικές 
σχετικά με ένα συγκεκριμένο θέμα ή ένα γεγονός. 
Χρησιμεύει επίσης ως μια δραστηριότητα να προετοιμάσει τους 
σπουδαστές για μια επίσκεψη στο μουσείο τέχνης Ackland στο 
Hill παρεκκλησιών, NC (ή οποιοδήποτε μουσείο, πραγματικός 
ή εικονικός). Αυτό το μάθημα είναι το πρώτο τριών 
μαθημάτων που χτίζουν το ένα επάνω στο άλλο, χρησιμοποιώντας το 
μουσείο τέχνης Ackland ως εστίαση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta lección introduce a estudiantes a la 
importancia de hacer observaciones científicas exactas, detalladas, y
el valor de aprender sobre otros opiniónes y perspectivas con 
respecto un asunto o a un acontecimiento específico. También 
sirve como actividad para preparar a estudiantes para una visita al 
museo del arte de Ackland en la colina de la capilla, NC (o cualquier 
museo, verdadero o virtual). Esta lección es la primera de tres
lecciones que construyan sobre uno a, usando el museo del arte de 
Ackland como el foco.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:REAGAN WEST
FN:REAGAN WEST
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204614</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107208</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/what-do-you-see-pre-visit</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
