<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108191</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108191</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202934</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">GeoMaths MathHelp Material</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">GeoMaths MathHelp Material</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Matériel de GeoMaths MathHelp</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Material De GeoMaths MathHelp</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Materiale Di GeoMaths MathHelp</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Υλικό GeoMaths MathHelp</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Material De GeoMaths MathHelp</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site provides students with mathematics self-study material which is embedded within the context of the geosciences. The material consists of many MathHelp "notebooks" covering specific mathematical topics related to a relevant geological context, such as plate velocity or cliff erosion. The notebooks contain explanations, illustrations, and examples. A mathematical glossary is also constantly available, providing a brief explanation of mathematical keywords and links to the relevant notebook. This resource is part of the Teaching Quantitative Skills in the Geosciences collection. http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site versieht Kursteilnehmer mit 
Mathematikselbststudiummaterial, das innerhalb des Kontextes der 
geosciences eingebettet wird. Das Material besteht aus viel 
MathHelp "die Notizbücher", welche die spezifischen mathematischen 
Themen umfassen, die auf einem relevanten geologischen Kontext, wie 
Platte Geschwindigkeit oder Klippe Abnutzung in Verbindung gestanden 
werden. Die Notizbücher enthalten Erklärungen, Abbildungen und
Beispiele. Ein mathematisches Glossar ist auch ständig 
vorhanden und stellt eine kurze Erklärung der mathematischen 
Schlüsselwörter und der Links zum relevanten Notizbuch zur 
Verfügung. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Teil der Unterricht 
quantitativen Fähigkeiten in der Geosciences Ansammlung 
http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site fournit à des étudiants le matériel des
mathématiques art de l'auto-portrait-study qui est inclus dans le contexte des 
geosciences. Le matériel se compose beaucoup de de MathHelp 
"cahiers" couvrant des sujets mathématiques spécifiques liés à un 
contexte géologique approprié, tel que la vitesse de plat ou 
l'érosion de falaise. Les cahiers contiennent des explications,
des illustrations, et des exemples. Un glossaire mathématique 
est également constamment disponible, fournissant une brève 
explication des mots-clés et des liens mathématiques au cahier 
approprié. Cette ressource fait partie des qualifications 
quantitatives d'enseignement dans la collection 
http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/ de Geosciences</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local fornece estudantes com o material do 
self-study da matemática que é encaixado dentro do contexto dos 
geosciences. O material consiste muito em MathHelp "cadernos" 
que cobrem os tópicos matemáticos específicos relacionados a um 
contexto geological relevante, tal como a velocidade da placa ou a 
erosão do penhasco. Os cadernos contêm explanações, 
ilustrações, e exemplos. Um glossário matemático está 
também constantemente disponível, fornecendo uma explanação breve 
de keywords e das ligações matemáticos ao caderno relevante. 
Este recurso é parte das habilidades quantitative do ensino na 
coleção http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/ de Geosciences</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo fornisce agli allievi il materiale di
autodidattica di matematica che è incluso all'interno del contesto 
dei geosciences. Il materiale consiste molto di MathHelp 
"taccuini" che riguardano i soggetti matematici specifici relativi ad
un contesto geologico relativo, quali velocità della piastra o 
erosione della scogliera. I taccuini contengono le spiegazioni, 
le illustrazioni e gli esempi. Un glossario matematico è 
egualmente costantemente disponibile, fornendo una breve spiegazione 
delle parole chiavi e dei collegamenti matematici al taccuino 
relativo. Questa risorsa fa parte delle abilità quantitative di
insegnamento nell'accumulazione http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/ 
di Geosciences</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή παρέχει στους σπουδαστές το υλικό 
μόνος-μελέτης μαθηματικών που ενσωματώνεται μέσα στο πλαίσιο των
geosciences. Το υλικό αποτελείται από πολλά MathHelp 
"σημειωματάρια" καλύπτοντας τα συγκεκριμένα μαθηματικά θέματα 
σχετικά με ένα σχετικό γεωλογικό πλαίσιο, όπως η ταχύτητα 
πιάτων ή η διάβρωση απότομων βράχων. Τα σημειωματάρια 
περιέχουν τις εξηγήσεις, τις απεικονίσεις, και τα παραδείγματα. 
Ένα μαθηματικό γλωσσάρι είναι επίσης συνεχώς διαθέσιμο, 
παρέχοντας μια συνοπτική εξήγηση των μαθηματικών λέξεων κλειδιών
και των συνδέσεων με το σχετικό σημειωματάριο. Αυτό το 
στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς είναι μέρος των ποσοτικών δεξιοτήτων 
διδασκαλίας στη Geosciences συλλογή 
http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio provee de estudiantes el material del 
self-study de las matemáticas que se embute dentro del contexto de 
los geosciences. El material consiste en mucho MathHelp 
"cuadernos" que cubren los asuntos matemáticos específicos 
relacionados con un contexto geológico relevante, tal como velocidad 
de la placa o erosión del acantilado. Los cuadernos contienen 
explicaciones, ilustraciones, y ejemplos. Un glosario 
matemático está también constantemente disponible, proporcionando a
una explicación abreviada de palabras claves y de conexiones 
matemáticas al cuaderno relevante. Este recurso es parte de las
habilidades cuantitativas de la enseñanza en la colección 
http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/ de Geosciences</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ROWENA BOWLES
FN:ROWENA BOWLES
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202934</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108191</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/geomaths-mathhelp-material</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
