<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106542</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106542</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209924</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Intersecting Secant Theorem</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Schneidenes Sekantentheorem</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Théorème Sécant d'Intersection</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Theorem Secant Cruzando-se</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Teorema Secante D'Intersezione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τεμνόμενο secant θεώρημα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Teorema Secante Que se interseca</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate the 'Intersecting Secants Theorem'. The applet shows a circle and two secant lines intersecting at a point outside the circle. The secant points and the external point are draggable. As you drag them the secant lines are redrawn and a realtime computation on the applet shows that the product of their segments are always the same. By dragging two secant points together, the Tangent-Secant Theorem is also demonstrated. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die das ' schneidene Sekante-Theorem ' zeigen. Der 
applet zeigt einen Kreis und zwei Sekantenzeilen, die an einem Punkt 
außerhalb des Kreises schneiden. Die Sekantepunkte und der 
externe Punkt sind draggable. Wie Sie sie schleppen, sind die 
Sekantenzeilen redrawn und ein Echtzeitübertragen auf Lochkarten auf 
dem applet zeigt, daß das Produkt ihrer Segmente immer dasselbe sind.
Indem man zusammen zwei Sekantenpunkte schleppt, wird das 
TangenteSekantentheorem auch gezeigt. Applet kann zum vollen 
Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert
werden. Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf 
es von jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek 
ohne den benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel 
ist ein Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven 
Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent 'le théorème d'intersection de sécantes '. 
L'applet montre un cercle et deux lignes sécantes intersectant 
à un point en dehors du cercle. Les points de sécante et le 
point externe sont draggable. Comme vous les traînez les lignes
sécantes sont redrawn et un calcul en temps réel sur l'applet prouve
que le produit de leurs segments sont toujours identique. En 
traînant deux points sécants ensemble, le théorème 
Tangente-Sécant est également démontré. L'applet peut être 
agrandi à la taille de plein écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur 
de salle de classe. Le après utilisation dans la salle de 
classe, étudiant peut lui accéder encore de n'importe quel 
navigateur de Web à la maison ou dans la bibliothèque sans la 
procédure de connexion exigée. Cette ressource est un 
composant du projet interactif de manuel de la géométrie de 
référence ouverte de maths à http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem ' o theorem se cruzando dos secants '. O applet 
mostra um círculo e duas linhas secant que cruzam-se em um ponto fora
do círculo. Os pontos do secant e o ponto externo são 
draggable. Como você os arrasta as linhas secant são redrawn e
uma computação realtime no applet mostra que o produto de seus 
segmentos é sempre o mesmo. Arrastando dois pontos secant 
junto, o theorem Tangent-tangent-Secant é demonstrado também. 
O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de tela cheia para o uso 
com um projetor da sala de aula. O depois de uso na sala de 
aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo o web browser na 
HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma sessão requerido. 
Este recurso é um componente do projeto interativo do textbook 
da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano 'il teorema d'intersezione di secanti '. Il applet 
mostra un cerchio e due righe secanti che intersecano ad un punto 
fuori del cerchio. I punti di secante ed il punto esterno sono 
draggable. Come li trascinate le righe secanti sono redrawn e un
calcolo in tempo reale sul applet indica che il prodotto dei loro 
segmenti è sempre lo stesso. Trascinando due punti secanti 
insieme, il teorema Tangente-Secante egualmente è dimostrato. 
Il applet può essere ingrandito al formato di schermo pieno per
uso con un proiettore dell'aula. La post-utilizzazione 
nell'aula, allievo può accederle ancora da tutto il web browser nel 
paese o nella libreria senza l'inizio attività richiesto. 
Questa risorsa è un componente del progetto interattivo del 
manuale della geometria di riferimento aperto di per la matematica a 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν το "τεμνόμενο secants θεώρημα". Το applet
εμφανίζει έναν κύκλο και δύο secant γραμμές που κόβουν σε 
ένα σημείο έξω από τον κύκλο. Τα secant σημεία και το 
εξωτερικό σημείο είναι draggable. Δεδομένου ότι τους 
σέρνετε οι secant γραμμές αποσύρονται και ένας σε πραγματικό 
χρόνο υπολογισμός στο applet δείχνει ότι το προϊόν των 
τμημάτων μνήμης τους είναι πάντα το ίδιο. Με να σέρει δύο
secant σημεία μαζί, το εφαπτομένη- tangent-Secant θεώρημα 
καταδεικνύεται επίσης. Το Applet μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο
πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με έναν προβολέα τάξεων. 
Μετά από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει 
πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι
ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια εισόδου που απαιτείται. 
Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του 
ανοικτού προγράμματος εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math 
διαλογικού σε http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran el ' teorema de las secantes que se interseca '. El 
applet muestra un círculo y dos líneas secantes que se intersecan en
una punta fuera del círculo. Las puntas de la secante y la 
punta externa son draggable. Como usted las arrastra las líneas
secantes son redrawn y un cómputo en tiempo real en el applet muestra
que el producto de sus segmentos es siempre igual. Arrastrando 
dos puntas secantes juntas, el teorema Tangente-Secante también es 
demostrado. El applet se puede agrandar a la talla de la 
pantalla completa para el uso con un proyector de la sala de clase. 
El uso posterior en la sala de clase, estudiante puede tenerle 
acceso otra vez de cualquier web browser en el país o en la 
biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. Este recurso es un 
componente del proyecto interactivo del libro de textos de la 
geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas en 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209924</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106542</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/intersecting-secant-theorem</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
