<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107224</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107224</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086840</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Somebody Must be Blamed": Father Coughlin Speaks to the Nation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"jemand muß getadelt werden": Vater Coughlin
spricht mit der Nation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"quelqu'un doit être blâmé" : Le père 
Coughlin parle à la nation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"alguém deve ser responsabilizado": O pai 
Coughlin fala à nação</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"qualcuno deve essere incolpato di": Il padre
Coughlin parla alla nazione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Κάποιος πρέπει να κατηγορηθεί": Ο πατέρας 
Coughlin μιλά στο έθνος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"alguien debe ser culpada": El padre Coughlin
habla a la nación</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Father Charles Coughlin occupied both a strange and a familiar place in American politics in the 1930s. Politically radical, a passionate democrat, he nevertheless was a bigot who freely vented angry, irrational charges and assertions. A Catholic priest, he broadcast weekly radio sermons that by 1930 drew as many as forty-five million listeners. Strongly egalitarian, deeply suspicious of elites, a champion of what he saw as the ordinary person's rights, Coughlin frequently and vigorously attacked capitalism, communism, socialism, and dictatorship By the mid-1930s, his talks took on a nasty edge as he combined harsh attacks on Roosevelt as the tool of international Jewish bankers with praise for the fascist leaders Benito Mussolini and Adolph Hitler. The "Radio Priest's" relentless anti-elitism pushed Roosevelt to sharpen his own critiques of elites, and in that sense Coughlin had a powerful impact on American politics beyond his immediate radio audience. This 1937 sermon, "Twenty Years Ago," reflected much of what made Coughlin popular.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Vater Charles Coughlin besetzte ein merkwürdiges 
und ein vertrauter Platz in der amerikanischen Politik im dreißiger 
Jahre politisch Radikal, ein leidenschaftlicher Demokrat, war er 
dennoch ein Frömmler, der frei die verärgerten, vernunftwidrigen 
Ladungen und die Behauptungen lüftete. Ein katholischer 
Priester, übertrug er wöchentliche Radiopredigten, die durch 1930 
bis zu wie forty-five Million Zuhörer zeichneten. Stark 
gleichmacherisch, tief mißtrauisch von den Auslesen, ein Meister von 
was er als die gewöhnlichen Rechte der Person, Coughlin häufig sah 
und kräftig Kapitalismus, Kommunismus, sozialismus und Diktatur 
bis zum den Mid-1930s angriff, nahmen seine Gespräche auf einem 
bösen Rand, während er rauhe Angriffe auf Roosevelt als das 
Hilfsmittel der internationalen jüdischen Banker mit Lob für die 
faschistischen Führer Benito Mussolini und Adolph Hitler kombinierte. 
Das "Radiounnachgiebige anti-elitism des priesters" drückte 
Roosevelt, um seine eigenen Kritiken der Auslesen zu schärfen, und in
dieser Richtung hatte Coughlin eine leistungsfähige Auswirkung auf 
amerikanische Politik über seinen sofortigen Radiopublikum hinaus. 
Vor diese Predigt 1937, "Zwanzig Jahren," reflektierte viel von,
was Coughlin populär bildete.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le père Charles Coughlin a occupé un étrange et 
un endroit familier dans la politique américaine dans des années 30 
le radical politiquement, un démocrate passionné, il néanmoins 
était un bigot qui a librement exhalé les frais et les affirmations 
fâchés et irrationnels. Un prêtre catholique, il a annoncé 
les sermons par radio hebdomadaires qui par 1930 ont dessiné l'autant
d'en tant que million d'auditeurs forty-five. Fortement 
égalitaires, profondément soupçonneux des élites, un champion de 
ce qu'il a vu comme droits de la personne ordinaire, Coughlin 
fréquemment et a vigoureusement attaqué le capitalisme, le 
communisme, le socialisme, et la dictature par le milieu des années 
30, ses entretiens ont pris un bord méchant pendant qu'il combinait 
des attaques dures sur Roosevelt comme outil des banquiers juifs 
internationaux avec l'éloge pour les Chefs fascistes Benito Mussolini
et Adolph Hitler. "l'anti-élitisme implacable du prêtre par 
radio" a poussé Roosevelt pour affiler ses propres critiques des 
élites, et dans ce sens Coughlin a eu un impact puissant sur la 
politique américaine au delà de ses assistances par radio 
immédiates. Ce sermon 1937, il y a "vingt ans," a reflété 
beaucoup de ce qui a rendu Coughlin populaire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O pai Charles Coughlin ocupou  um estranho e um 
lugar familiar na política americana dos 1930s. no radical polìtica,
uma democrata passionate, não obstante era um bigot que exalasse 
livremente cargas e afirmações irritadas, irrational. Um 
priest catholic, transmitiu os sermons de rádio semanais que por 1930
desenharam o tanto como como milhão ouvintes forty-five. 
Fortemente egalitarian, profundamente suspicious dos elites, um 
campeão de o que visse como as direitas da pessoa ordinária, 
Coughlin freqüentemente e atacasse vigorosa o capitalismo, o 
communism, o socialismo, e o dictatorship pelos mid-1930s, suas 
conversas fizeram exame em uma borda nasty enquanto combinou ataques 
ásperos em Roosevelt como a ferramenta de banqueiros jewish 
internacionais com o elogio para os líderes fascist Benito Mussolini 
e Adolph Hitler. O anti-elitism relentless "do priest de rádio"
empurrou Roosevelt para sharpen suas próprias críticas dos elites, e
nesse sentido Coughlin teve um impacto poderoso na política americana
além de suas audiências de rádio imediatas. Este sermon 1937,
"vinte anos há," refletiu muita de o que fêz Coughlin popular.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il padre Charles Coughlin ha occupato sia uno 
sconosciuto che un posto esperto nella politica americana di 1930s. 
nel radicale politicamente, una carbossimetilazione appassionata, 
tuttavia era un bigot che ha scaricato liberamente le spese e le 
asserzioni arrabbiate e irrazionali. Un priest cattolico, ha 
trasmesso per radio i sermons radiofonici settimanali che da 1930 
hanno dissipato l'altretanto come milione ascoltatori forty-five. 
Fortemente egalitari, profondamente sospettoso delle elite, un 
campione di che cosa ha visto frequentemente come i diritti della 
persona ordinaria, Coughlin e vigoroso ha attacato il capitalismo, il 
comunismo, il socialism ed il dictatorship entro i mid-1930s, i suoi 
colloqui hanno intrapreso un bordo nasty mentre ha unito gli 
attacchi duri a Roosevelt come lo strumento dei banchieri ebrei 
internazionali con elogio per i capi fascisti Benito 
Mussolini ed Adolph Hitler. Il anti-elitism relentless "del 
priest radiofonico" ha spinto Roosevelt per affilare le sue proprie 
valutazioni delle elite ed in quel senso Coughlin ha avuto un effetto 
potente sulla politica americana oltre i suoi pubblici radiofonici 
immediati. Questo sermon 1937, "venti anni fa," ha riflesso 
molto di che cosa ha reso Coughlin popolare.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο πατέρας Charles Coughlin κατέλαβε και μια 
παράξενη και γνωστή θέση στην αμερικανική πολιτική στη δεκαετία 
του '30 Πολιτικά ριζικός, ένας εμπαθής δημοκράτης, 
εντούτοις ήταν φανατικός που αέρισε ελεύθερα τις υς, παράλογους 
δαπάνες και τους ισχυρισμούς. Ένας καθολικός ιερέας, 
μετέδωσε ραδιοφωνικά τα εβδομαδιαία ραδιο κηρύγματα που μέχρι το 
1930 έσυραν τουλάχιστον σαράντα πέντε εκατομμύριο ακροατές. 
Έντονα egalitarian, βαθειά ύποπτος των elites, ενός 
πρωτοπόρου αυτού που εβλέίδε ως δικαιώματα του 
συνηθισμένου προσώπου, συχνά και σθεναρά επιτεθειμένη 
κεφαλαιοκρατία Coughlin, του κομμουνισμού, του σοσιαλισμού, και 
της δικτατορίας μέχρι τα μέσα τησδεκαετίας του '30, οι συζητήσεις
του πήραν μια δυσάρεστη άκρη δεδομένου ότι συνδύασε τις σκληρές
επιθέσεις σε Roosevelt ως εργαλείο των διεθνών εβραϊκών 
τραπεζιτών με τον έπαινο για τους φασιστικούς ηγέτες Benito 
Mussolini και Adolph hitler. Το ανηλεές αντι-ελητησμ 
του "ραδιο ιερέα" ώθησε Roosevelt για να ακονίσει τις κριτικές 
elites του, και υπό εκείνη την έννοια Coughlin άσκησε 
ισχυρή επίδραση στην αμερικανική πολιτική πέρα από το άμεσο 
ραδιο ακροατήριό του. Αυτό το κήρυγμα του 1937, "είκοσι 
έτη πριν," απεικόνισε ένα μεγάλο μέρος αυτό που κατέστησε 
Coughlin δημοφιλές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El padre Charles Coughlin ocupó un extraño y un 
lugar familiar en política americana en de los años 30 el radical 
político, demócrata apasionado, él sin embargo era un fanático que
expresó libremente cargas y aserciones enojadas, irracionales. 
Un sacerdote católico, él difundió los sermones de radio 
semanales que por 1930 trazaron tanto como millón de módulos de 
escucha forty-five. Fuertemente igualitarias, profundamente 
sospechoso de las élites, campeón de lo que él vio como las 
derechas de la persona ordinaria, Coughlin con frecuencia y atacó 
vigoroso capitalismo, comunismo, socialismo, y la dictadura por los 
mediados de los años treinta, sus negociaciones adquirieron un borde 
repugnante mientras que él combinó ataques ásperos contra Roosevelt
como la herramienta de banqueros judíos internacionales con la 
alabanza para los arranques de cinta fascistas Benito Mussolini y 
Adolph Hitler. El anti-elitism implacable del "sacerdote de 
radio" empujó Roosevelt para afilar sus propias críticas de élites,
y en ese sentido Coughlin tenía un impacto de gran alcance en 
política americana más allá de sus audiencias de radio inmediatas. 
Este sermón 1937, hace "veinte años," reflejó mucho de qué 
hizo Coughlin popular.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086840</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107224</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/somebody-must-be-blamed-father-coughlin-speaks-to-the-nation</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
