<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104090</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104090</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086955</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Higher, the Fewer": Discrimination Against Women in Academia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">", das höhere, weniger": Diskriminierung 
gegen Frauen in der Akademie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"plus le haut, les moins" : Discrimination 
contre des femmes dans le milieu universitaire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"o mais elevados, o menos": Discriminação 
de encontro às mulheres no academia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"l'più alto, il meno": Distinzione contro 
le donne in accademia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ο υψηλότερος, λιγότεροι": Διάκριση ενάντια στις
γυναίκες στον ακαδημαϊκό κόσμο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"cuanto el más alto, el menos": 
Discriminación contra mujeres en academia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">During World War II, a number of states passed legislation to combat salary inequities suffered by women workers. Many unions also adopted standards to insure that women employees received the same salaries as males who performed similar jobs. The Equal Pay Act of 1963, the first Federal legislation guaranteeing equal pay for equal work, prohibited firms engaged in interstate commerce from paying workers according to wage rates determined by sex. It did not, however, prevent companies from hiring only men for higher paying jobs. The following year, Title VII of the landmark Civil Rights Act of 1964 further prevented sex discrimination in employment, but did not include educational institutions. The following testimony to a Congressional hearing in 1970 emphasized the need to extend sex discrimination legislation to the academic world. In 1972, Congress passed the Higher Education Act. Title IX of this Act forbade federal financial assistance to educational institutions that practiced sex discrimination.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während des Zweiten Weltkrieges führte eine 
Anzahl von Zuständen Gesetzgebung zu den Kampfgehalt 
Ungerechtigkeiten, die durch Frauarbeiter erlitten wurden. Viele
Anschlüße nahmen auch Standards an, um zu versichern, daß 
Frauangestellte die gleichen Gehälter wie Männer empfingen, die 
ähnliche Jobs durchführten. Die gleiche Bezahlung Tat von 
1963, die erste Bundesgesetzgebung, die gleicher Bezahlung für 
gleiche Arbeit, verbotene Unternehmen garantiert, engagierte sich im 
landesweiten Handel vom Zahlen der Arbeiter entsprechend den 
Lohnkinetik, die durch Geschlecht festgestellt wurden. Sie nicht
verhinderte jedoch Firmen an der Einstellung der nur Männer für 
höhere zahlende Jobs. Das folgende Jahr, Titel VII der 
Grenzstein Zivilrecht-Tat der weiteren verhinderten Unterscheidung des
Geschlechtes 1964 in der Beschäftigung, aber schloß nicht 
pädagogische Anstalten ein. Das folgende Zeugnis zu einer 
Kongreßhörfähigkeit in 1970 hob die Notwendigkeit hervor, 
Geschlechtunterscheidunggesetzgebung auf die akademische Welt 
auszudehnen. 1972 führte Kongreß den Ausbildung-Tat Titel IX 
dieser Tat verbot finanzielle föderativunterstützung zu den 
pädagogischen Anstalten diese geübte Geschlechtunterscheidung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant la deuxième guerre mondiale, un certain 
nombre d'états ont passé la législation aux injustices de salaire 
de combat souffertes par des ouvrières de femmes. Beaucoup de 
syndicats ont également adopté des normes pour assurer que les 
employées ont reçu les mêmes salaires que les mâles qui ont 
exécuté les travaux semblables. La Loi d'égalité de salaires
de 1963, la première législation fédérale garantissant la salaire 
égal, les sociétés interdites s'est engagée dans le commerce entre
Etats de payer des ouvriers selon des salaires horaires déterminés 
par le sexe. Elle, cependant, n'a pas empêché des compagnies 
de louer seulement des hommes pour les travaux de paiement plus 
élevés. L'année suivante, le titre VII de la Loi de droits 
civiques de borne limite de la discrimination de sexe 1964 empêchée 
encore dans l'emploi, mais n'a pas inclus les établissements 
éducatifs. Le témoignage suivant à une audition 
congressionnelle dans 1970 a souligné la nécessité d'étendre la 
législation de discrimination de sexe au monde d'universitaire. 
En 1972, le congrès a passé le titre IX d'acte d'éducation 
plus élevée de cette Loi a interdit l'aide financière fédérale 
aux établissements éducatifs cette discrimination de sexe 
pratiquée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Durante a segunda guerra mundial, um número de 
estados passaram a legislação aos inequities do salário do combate 
sofridos por trabalhadores das mulheres. Muitas uniões adotaram
também padrões para segurar que os empregados de mulheres receberam 
os mesmos salários que os machos que executaram trabalhos similares. 
O ato de 1963, a primeira legislação federal do pagamento 
igual que garante o pagamento igual para o trabalho igual, firmas 
proibidas acoplou no comércio interstate de pagar trabalhadores de 
acordo com as taxas de salário determinadas pelo sexo. , 
entretanto, não impediu que as companhias empreguem somente homens 
para uns trabalhos pagando mais elevados. O seguinte ano, 
título VII do ato das direitas civis do marco de uma discriminação 
de sexo 1964 impedida mais adicional no emprego, mas não incluiu 
instituições educacionais. O seguinte testimony a um hearing 
congressional em 1970 emfatizou a necessidade estender a legislação 
da discriminação de sexo ao mundo academic. Em 1972, o 
congress passou o título IX do ato de uma instrução mais elevada 
deste ato proibiu o auxílio financeiro federal às instituições 
educacionais essa discriminação de sexo praticada.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Durante la seconda guerra mondiale, un certo 
numero dichiara la legislazione passata alle ingiustizie di 
stipendio di combattimento sofferte dagli operai delle donne. 
Molti sindacati egualmente hanno adottato gli standard per 
assicurare che gli impiegati di donne hanno ricevuto gli stessi 
stipendi dei maschi che hanno effettuato i lavori simili. La 
Legge di 1963, la prima legislazione federale di parità salariale che
garantisce la parità salariale per lavoro uguale, ditte proibite si 
è agganciata nel commercio da uno stato all'altro dal pagamento degli
operai secondo i tassi di stipendio determinati dal sesso. , 
tuttavia, non ha impedito alle aziende di assumere soltanto gli uomini
per gli più alti lavori di pagamento. Il seguente anno, il 
titolo VII della Legge di diritti civili del limite di ulteriore 
discriminazione in base al sesso evitata 1964 nell'occupazione, ma non
ha incluso gli istituti scolastici. La seguente testimonianza ad
un'udienza congressuale in 1970 ha dato risalto alla necessità di 
estendere la legislazione di discriminazione in base al sesso fino il 
mondo accademico. In 1972, il congresso ha passato il titolo IX 
di Legge di istruzione superiore di questa Legge ha proibito al 
concorso finanziario federale agli istituti scolastici quella 
discriminazione in base al sesso esercitata in.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ, διάφορα 
κράτη πέρασαν τη νομοθεσία στις αδικίες μισθών αγώνα που 
υποφέρονται από τους εργαζομένους γυναικών. Πολλές ενώσεις
υιοθέτησαν επίσης τα πρότυπα για να ασφαλίσουν ότι οι υπάλληλοι 
γυναικών έλαβαν τους ίδιους μισθούς με τα αρσενικά που εκτέλεσαν
τις παρόμοιες εργασίες. Ο νόμος ίσης αμοιβής του 1963, η
πρώτη ομοσπονδιακή νομοθεσία που εγγυάται την ίση αμοιβή για την
όμοια εργασία, απαγόρευσε τις εταιρίες που συμμετέχθηκαν στο 
διακρατικό εμπόριο από την πληρωμή των εργαζομένων σύμφωνα με τα
ποσοστά αμοιβών που καθορίστηκαν από το φύλο. , Εντούτοις,
δεν απέτρεψε τις επιχειρήσεις από τη μίσθωση μόνο των ατόμων για
τις υψηλότερες εργασίες πληρωμής. Το επόμενο έτος, τίτλος 
VII του νόμου αστικών δικαιωμάτων ορόσημων των περαιτέρω 
διακρίσεων λόγω φύλου του 1964 στην απασχόληση, αλλά δεν 
περιέλαβε τα εκπαιδευτικά όργανα. Η ακόλουθη 
κατάθεση σε μια του Κογκρέσου ακρόαση το 1970 υπογράμμισε την 
ανάγκη να επεκταθεί η για τις διακρίσεις λόγω φύλου νομοθεσία 
στον ακαδημαϊκό κόσμο. Το 1972, το συνέδριο πέρασε το 
νόμο τριτοβάθμιας εκπαίδευσης. Ο τίτλος ΙΧ αυτού του νόμου
απαγόρευσε την ομοσπονδιακή χρηματοδοτική συνδρομή στα 
εκπαιδευτικά όργανα που άσκησαν τις διακρίσεις λόγω 
φύλου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Durante la Segunda Guerra Mundial, un número de 
estados aprobaron la legislación a las injusticias del sueldo del 
combate sufridas por los trabajadores de las mujeres. Muchas 
uniones también adoptaron estándares para asegurar que los empleados
de mujeres recibieron los mismos sueldos que los varones que 
realizaron trabajos similares. El acto de 1963, la primera 
legislación federal de la igualdad de salario que garantizaba la 
igualdad de salario para el trabajo igual, las firmas prohibidas 
enganchó a comercio de un estado a otro de pagar a trabajadores 
según las tarifas de salario determinadas por el sexo. , sin 
embargo, no evitó que las compañías emplearan solamente a hombres 
para trabajos que pagaban más altos. El año siguiente, título
VII del acto de las derechas civiles de la señal de la 
discriminación de sexo prevenida adicional 1964 en el empleo, pero no
incluyó a instituciones educativas. El testimonio siguiente a 
una audiencia del congreso en 1970 acentuó la necesidad de ampliar la
legislación de la discriminación de sexo al mundo académico. 
En 1972, el congreso pasó el título IX del acto de una 
educación más alta de este acto prohibió ayuda financiera federal a
las instituciones educativas esa discriminación de sexo practicada.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086955</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104090</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-higher-the-fewer-discrimination-against-women-in-academia</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
