<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103841</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103841</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086125</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Equal Pay for Equal Work: The War Labor Board on Gender Inequality</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gleiche Bezahlung für gleiche Arbeit: Das 
Krieg-Arbeit Brett auf Geschlecht-Verschiedenheit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Salaire égal : Le conseil de travail de 
guerre sur l'inégalité de genre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Pagamento igual para o trabalho igual: A 
placa do trabalho da guerra no desigualdade do gender</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Parità salariale per lavoro uguale: Il 
Bordo Di lavoro di guerra su diseguaglianza di genere</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ίση αμοιβή για την όμοια εργασία: Ο πίνακας 
πολεμικής εργασίας στην ανισότητα γένους</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Igualdad de salario para el trabajo igual: 
La tarjeta del trabajo de la guerra en la desigualdad del 
género</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The War Labor Board (WLB) and its predecessor, the National Defense Mediation Board, had a profound impact on relations between employers and unions during World War II. The WLB--made up of representatives from government, labor, and management--provided protection for unions from hostile bosses, increased the wages of the lowest-paid workers, helped set industry-wide wage patterns, and established methods of resolving shop floor disputes. Although the WLB operated in routinized and bureaucratic ways, its decisions could also carry powerful ideological messages. That became clear in the following document, which insisted upon the policy of equal pay for equal work--a seemingly self-evident principle that was not standard practice in American industry. This board decision mandated equal pay for women.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Krieg-Arbeit Brett (WLB) und sein Vorgänger, 
die Nationalverteidigung-Schiedskommission, hatten eine profunde 
Auswirkung auf Relationen zwischen Arbeitgebern und Anschlüßen 
während des Zweiten Weltkrieges. Das WLB -- gebildet von den 
Repräsentanten von der Regierung, von der Arbeit und vom Management 
-- der zur Verfügung gestellte Schutz für die Anschlüße vor 
feindlichen Chefs, erhöht die Löhne der niedrig-zahlenden Arbeiter, 
geholfene gesetzte industrieweite Lohngefüge und hergestellte 
Methoden des Behebens des Systemfußbodens diskutiert. Obgleich 
das WLB, das innen bearbeitet wurde und bürokratische Methoden 
routinized, konnten seine Entscheidungen leistungsfähige ideologische
Meldungen auch tragen. Das wurde im folgenden Dokument frei, das
nach der Politik der gleichen Bezahlung für gleiche Arbeit -- eine 
scheinbar selbstverständliche Grundregel beharrte, die nicht gängige
Praxis in der amerikanischen Industrie war. Diese 
Brettentscheidung unterstellte gleichen Bezahlung für Frauen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le conseil de travail de guerre (WLB) et son 
prédécesseur, le conseil de médiation de la défense nationale, ont
eu un impact profond sur des relations entre les employeurs et les 
syndicats pendant la deuxième guerre mondiale. Le WLB -- 
composé des représentants du gouvernement, du travail, et de la 
gestion -- protection assurée pour des syndicats contre les patrons 
hostiles, accrus les salaires des ouvriers bas-payés, les 
configurations de salaire à l'échelle industrielle réglées 
aidées, et les méthodes établies de résoudre le plancher de 
système conteste. Bien que le WLB actionné dedans routinized 
et des voies bureaucratiques, ses décisions pourraient également 
diffuser les messages idéologiques puissants. Cela est devenu 
clair dans le document suivant, qui a exigé sur la politique de la 
salaire égal -- apparemment un principe de art de l'auto-portrait-evident qui 
n'était pas technique normalisée dans l'industrie américaine. 
Cette décision de panneau a exigé l'égalité de salaires pour
des femmes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A placa do trabalho da guerra (WLB) e seu 
predecessor, placa de mediation da defesa nacional, tiveram um impacto
profundo em relações entre empregadores e uniões durante a segunda 
guerra mundial. O WLB -- composto dos representantes do governo,
do trabalho, e da gerência -- proteção fornecida para as uniões 
das saliências hostis, aumentadas os salários dos trabalhadores 
baixo-pagos, testes padrões de salário industry-wide ajustados 
ajudados, e métodos estabelecidos de resolver o assoalho da loja 
disputa. Embora o WLB operado dentro routinized e maneiras 
burocráticas, suas decisões poderiam também carregar mensagens 
ideological poderosas. Isso tornou-se desobstruído no seguinte 
original, que insistiu em cima da política do pagamento igual para o 
trabalho igual -- um princípio seemingly self-evident que não fosse 
prática padrão na indústria americana. Esta decisão da placa
exijiu o pagamento igual para mulheres.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Bordo Di lavoro di guerra (WLB) ed il 
relativo predecessore, il Bordo di mediazione della difesa 
nazionale, hanno avuti un effetto profondo sui rapporti fra i datori 
di lavoro ed i sindacati durante la seconda guerra mondiale. Il 
WLB -- composto dei rappresentanti dal governo, dal lavoro e 
dalla gestione -- protezione assicurata per i sindacati dalle 
sporgenze ostili, aumentati gli stipendi degli operai 
basso-lowest-paid, modelli di stipendio su scala industriale stabiliti
aiutati e metodi stabiliti di risoluzione del pavimento del negozio 
disputa. Anche se il WLB funzionato dentro routinized e modi 
burocratici, le relative decisioni potrebbero anche trasportare i 
messaggi ideologici potenti. Quello è diventato chiaro nel 
seguente documento, che ha insistito sulla politica di parità 
salariale per lavoro uguale -- un principio apparentemente manifesto 
che non era pratica normale nell'industria americana. Questa 
decisione del bordo ha affidato la parità salariale in mandato 
per le donne.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο πίνακας πολεμικής εργασίας (WLB) και ο 
προκάτοχός του, το εθνικό συμβούλιο αμυντικής μεσολάβησης, 
άσκησαν βαθιά επίδραση στις σχέσεις μεταξύ των εργοδοτών και των
σωματείων κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ. Το 
WLB -- φιαγμένο επάνω από αντιπροσώπους από την κυβέρνηση, 
την εργασία, και τη διαχείριση -- παρείχε την προστασία για τις 
ενώσεις από τους εχθρικούς προϊσταμένους, αύξησε τις αμοιβές 
των χαμηλός-πληρωμένων εργαζομένων, βοήθησε τα καθορισμένα σε 
βιομηχανικό επίπεδο πρότυπα αμοιβών, και καθιέρωσε τις μεθόδους 
τις διαφωνίες πατωμάτων καταστημάτων. Αν και το WLB που 
χρησιμοποιήθηκε μέσα και γραφειοκρατικοί τρόποι, οι αποφάσεις της
θα μπορούσαν επίσης να φέρουν τα ισχυρά ιδεολογικά μηνύματα. 
Αυτός έγινε σαφής στο ακόλουθο έγγραφο, το οποίο επέμεινε
επάνω στην πολιτική της ίσης αμοιβής για την όμοια εργασία -- 
μια φαινομενικά αυτονόητη αρχή που δεν ήταν πρότυπη πρακτική 
στην αμερικανική βιομηχανία. Η παρούσα απόφαση πινάκων 
εξουσιοδότησε την ίση αμοιβή για τις γυναίκες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La tarjeta del trabajo de la guerra (WLB) y su 
precursor, la tarjeta de mediación de la defensa nacional, tenían un
impacto profundo en relaciones entre los patrones y las uniones 
durante la Segunda Guerra Mundial. El WLB -- compuesto de 
representantes del gobierno, del trabajo, y de la gerencia -- 
protección proporcionada para las uniones contra los jefes hostiles, 
crecientes los salarios de los trabajadores bajo-pagados, los modelos 
de salario a nivel industrial determinados ayudados, y los métodos 
establecidos de resolver el suelo del departamento disputa. 
Aunque el WLB funcionado adentro routinized y las maneras 
burocráticas, sus decisiones podrían también llevar mensajes 
ideológicos de gran alcance. Eso llegó a estar claro en el 
documento siguiente, que insistió sobre la política de la igualdad 
de salario para el trabajo igual -- un principio aparentemente 
evidente en sí que no era costumbre en industria americana. 
Esta decisión de la tarjeta asignó la igualdad de salario por 
mandato para las mujeres.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086125</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103841</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/equal-pay-for-equal-work-the-war-labor-board-on-gender-inequality</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
