<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107625</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107625</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206301</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Alien Earths</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ausländische Masse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Terres Étrangères</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Terras Estrangeiras</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Terre Straniere</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αλλοδαπή γη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Tierras Extranjeras</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">explores the formation of stars and planets and the quest for a habitable planet. Create a virtual a community of microorganisms. Try to build the perfect solar system. See how planets react with one another, and how some planets help keep our solar system stable. Look at images: see if you can recognize life.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erforscht die Anordnung der Sterne und der 
Planeten und der Suche nach einem bewohnbaren Planeten. 
Erstellen Sie ein virtuelles eine Gemeinschaft der 
Mikroorganismen. Versuchen Sie, das vollkommene Solarsystem 
aufzubauen. Sehen Sie, wie Planeten miteinander reagieren und 
wie einige Planeten helfen, unser Solarsystem beständig zu halten. 
Betrachten Sie Bilder: sehen Sie, wenn Sie das Leben 
erkennen können.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">explore la formation de tient le premier rôle et des 
planètes et la recherche pour une planète habitable. Créez un
virtuel une communauté des micro-organismes. Essayez d'établir
le système solaire parfait. Voyez comment les planètes 
réagissent entre eux, et comment quelques planètes aident à 
maintenir notre système solaire stable. Regardez les images : 
voyez si vous pouvez identifier la vie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">explora a formação das estrelas e os planetas e 
o quest para um planeta habitable. Críe um virtual uma 
comunidade dos microorganisms. Tente construir o sistema solar 
perfeito. Veja como os planetas reagem com o um outro, e como 
alguns planetas ajudam manter nosso sistema solar estável. Olhe
imagens: veja se você puder reconhecer a vida.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esplora la formazione delle stelle e pianeti e la 
ricerca per un pianeta abitabile. Crei un virtuale una Comunità
dei microorganismi. Provi a sviluppare il sistema solare 
perfetto. Veda come i pianeti reagiscono tra loro e come alcuni 
pianeti contribuiscono a mantenere il nostro sistema solare stabile. 
Guardi le immagini: veda se potete riconoscere la vita.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ερευνά το σχηματισμό των αστεριών και των πλανητών και
την αναζήτηση για έναν κατοικήσιμο πλανήτη. Δημιουργήστε 
έναν εικονικό μια κοινότητα των μικροοργανισμών. 
Προσπαθήστε να χτίσετε το τέλειο ηλιακό σύστημα. 
Δείτε πώς οι πλανήτες αντιδρούν με το ένα άλλος,
και πώς κάποιες οδηγίες πλανητών κρατούν το σταύλο ηλιακών 
συστημάτων μας. Εξετάστε τις εικόνες: δείτε 
εάν μπορείτε να αναγνωρίσετε τη ζωή.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">explora la formación de estrellas y los planetas 
y la búsqueda para un planeta habitable. Cree un virtual una 
comunidad de microorganismos. Intente construir la Sistema Solar
perfecta. Vea cómo los planetas reaccionan el uno con el otro, 
y cómo algunos planetas ayudan a mantener nuestra Sistema Solar 
estable. Mire las imágenes: vea si usted puede reconocer 
vida.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206301</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107625</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/alien-earths</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
