<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/581520344</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>581520344</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973920</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Nobel Prize: Educational Games</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nobelpreis: Pädagogische Spiele</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Prix Nobel : Jeux Éducatifs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Prêmio De Nobel: Jogos Educacionais</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Premio Nobel: Giochi Educativi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βραβείο Νόμπελ: Εκπαιδευτικά παιχνίδια</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Premio Nobel: Juegos Educativos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Play a game and find out about a Nobel Prize awarded discovery or work! These educational productions do not require previous knowledge. A central thought or issue is explored during 10-20 minutes of activity, using a specific Nobel Prize-awarded work as a springboard for the whole exercise. Students, teachers and non-professionals of all ages will enjoy testing and building their knowledge in physics, chemistry, physiology or medicine, literature, peace and economics.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spielen Sie ein Spiel und finden Sie über eine 
zugesprochene Entdeckung oder eine Arbeit des Nobelpreises heraus! 
Diese pädagogischen Produktionen benötigen nicht 
vorhergehendes Wissen. Ein zentraler Gedanke oder eine Ausgabe 
wird während 10-20 Minuten Aktivität mit einem Besonderen Nobel 
erforscht, das Arbeit als Sprungbrett für die vollständige 
Übung Preis-zugesprochen wird. Kursteilnehmer, Lehrer und 
Nichtfachleute alles Alters genießen, ihr Wissen in der Physik, 
Chemie, Physiologie oder Medizin, Literatur, Frieden und 
Volkswirtschaft zu prüfen und aufzubauen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jouez un jeu et découvrez au sujet d'une 
découverte ou d'un travail attribuée de prix Nobel ! Ces 
productions éducatives n'exigent pas la connaissance précédente. 
Une pensée ou une issue centrale est explorée pendant 10-20 
minutes d'activité, en utilisant un détail Nobel Prix-attribué le 
travail comme tremplin pour l'exercice entier. Les étudiants, 
les professeurs et les non-professionnels de tous les âges auront 
plaisir à tester et établir leur connaissance dans la physique, la 
chimie, la physiologie ou la médecine, la littérature, la paix et 
les sciences économiques.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogue um jogo e encontre-o para fora sobre uma 
descoberta ou um trabalho concedido do prêmio de nobel! Estas 
produções educacionais não requerem o conhecimento precedente. 
Um pensamento ou uma edição central são explorados durante 
10-20 minutos da atividade, usando um específico Nobel 
Prêmio-concedido o trabalho como um trampolim para o exercício 
inteiro. Os estudantes, os professores e os non-profissionais de
todas as idades apreciarão testar e construir seu conhecimento na 
física, o chemistry, o physiology ou a medicina, a literatura, a paz 
e a economia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gioc un gioco e scopra circa una scoperta o un 
lavoro ricevuta del premio Nobel! Queste produzioni educative 
non richiedono la conoscenza precedente. Un pensiero o 
un'edizione centrale è esaminare durante i 10-20 minuti di attività,
usando un Nobel specifico Premio-assegnato il lavoro come 
springboard per l'esercitazione intera. Gli allievi, gli 
insegnanti ed i non-professionisti di tutte le età godranno 
verificare e sviluppare la loro conoscenza nella fisica, chimica, la 
fisiologia o la medicina, letteratura, pace ed economia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παίξτε ένα παιχνίδι και ανακαλύψτε για μια 
απονεμημένη βραβείο ανακάλυψη ή μια εργασία Νόμπελ! Αυτές
οι εκπαιδευτικές παραγωγές δεν απαιτούν την προηγούμενη γνώση. 
Μια κεντρικό σκέψη ή ένα ζήτημα εξερευνιέται κατά τη 
διάρκεια 10-20 λεπτών της δραστηριότητας, χρησιμοποιώντας ένα 
συγκεκριμένο Νόμπελ βραβείο-που απονέμεται την εργασία ως 
αφετηρία για ολόκληρη την άσκηση. Οι σπουδαστές, οι 
δάσκαλοι και οι μη-επαγγελματίες όλων των ηλικιών θα απολαύσουν 
και τη γνώση τους εν τη φυσική, τη χημεία, τη φυσιολογία ή την 
ιατρική, τη λογοτεχνία, την ειρήνη και τα οικονομικά.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Juegue un juego y descubra sobre un 
descubrimiento o un trabajo concedido del premio Nobel! Estas 
producciones educativas no requieren conocimiento anterior. Un 
pensamiento o una edición central se explora durante 10-20 minutos de
actividad, usando un específico Nobel Premio-concedido el trabajo 
como trampolín para el ejercicio entero. Los estudiantes, los 
profesores y los no-profesionales de todas las edades gozarán el 
probar y el construir de su conocimiento en la física, química, 
fisiología o medicina, literatura, paz y economía.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973920</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>581520344</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/nobel-prize-educational-games</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
