<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104118</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104118</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206396</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Migration North to Alaska</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Migration Nord nach Alaska</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Nord de transfert vers l'Alaska</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Migração norte a Alaska</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Espansione del nord nell'Alaska</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο Βορράς μετανάστευσης στην Αλάσκα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Migración del norte a Alaska</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">encourages students to use primary documents on Alaska to study topics related to the migration of people, ideas, and culture throughout history. It offers suggestions for projects that use the Archives' photographs, letters, drawings, and it highlights economic, social, and political factors that prompted thousands to migrate to Alaska.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">regt Kursteilnehmer an, Primärdokumente auf 
Alaska zu benutzen, um die Themen zu studieren, die auf der Migration 
der Leute, der Ideen und der Kultur während der Geschichte in 
Verbindung gestanden werden. Sie bietet Vorschläge für 
Projekte an, die die Fotographien der Archive, Zeichen, Zeichnungen 
benutzen und sie die ökonomischen, Sozial- und politischen Faktoren 
markiert, die Tausenden aufforderten, nach Alaska fortzuziehen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">encourage des étudiants à employer les documents
primaires sur l'Alaska pour étudier des sujets liés au transfert des
personnes, idées, et les cultive à travers l'histoire. Il 
offre des suggestions pour les projets qui utilisent les photographies
des archives, lettres, schémas, et il met en valeur les facteurs 
économiques, sociaux, et politiques qui ont incité des milliers à 
passer en Alaska.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">incentiva estudantes usar originais preliminares 
em Alaska estudar os tópicos relacionados à migração dos povos, 
das idéias, e da cultura durante todo o history. Oferece 
sugestões para os projetos que usam as fotografias dos arquivos, 
letras, desenhos, e destaca os fatores econômicos, sociais, e 
políticos que alertaram milhares migrar a Alaska.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">consiglia agli allievi usare i documenti primari 
sull'Alaska per studiare i soggetti relativi all'espansione della 
gente, idee e coltivano attraverso la storia. Offre i 
suggerimenti per i progetti che usano le fotografie degli archivi, 
lettere, illustrazioni ed evidenzia i fattori economici, sociali e 
politici che hanno spinto le migliaia a migrare nell'Alaska.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ενθαρρύνει τους σπουδαστές για να χρησιμοποιήσει τα 
αρχικά έγγραφα σχετικά με την Αλάσκα στα θέματα μελέτης σχετικά
με τη μετανάστευση των ανθρώπων, των ιδεών, και του πολιτισμού 
καθ' όλη τη διάρκεια της ιστορίας. Προσφέρει τις προτάσεις 
για τα προγράμματα που χρησιμοποιούν τις φωτογραφίες των αρχείων, 
επιστολές, σχέδια, και δίνει έμφαση στους οικονομικούς, 
κοινωνικούς, και πολιτικούς παράγοντες που προέτρεψαν τις 
χιλιάδες για να μεταναστεύσουν στην Αλάσκα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">anima a estudiantes que utilicen documentos 
primarios en Alaska para estudiar los asuntos relacionados con la 
migración de la gente, ideas, y los cultiva a través de la historia.
Ofrece las sugerencias para los proyectos que utilizan las 
fotografías de los archivos, cartas, gráficos, y destaca los 
factores económicos, sociales, y políticos que incitaron millares 
emigrar a Alaska.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206396</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104118</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/migration-north-to-alaska</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
