<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105149</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105149</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200441</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Anatomy of a Tsunami</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Anatomie von einem Tsunami</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Anatomie d'un Tsunami</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Anatomy de um Tsunami</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Anatomia di un Tsunami</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανατομία ενός Tsunami</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Anatomía de un Tsunami</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Tsunami waves can be distinguished from ordinary ocean waves by many factors, including the tremendous amount of energy they carry, the great distance between their wave crests, and their capacity to travel at jetliner speeds across an entire ocean. In this interactive from NOVA Online, explore how the 2004 Indian Ocean tsunami -- the deadliest in recorded history -- was triggered, how its waves traveled thousands of kilometers largely unchanged, and what happened once the waves reached coastlines both near and far from their source. Grades 6-12</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Tsunami Wellen können von den gewöhnlichen 
Ozeanwellen durch viele Faktoren, einschließlich die enorme Menge von
Energie, die sie, von tragen, großen Abstand zwischen ihren Welle 
Scheiteln und von ihrer Kapazität bemerkenswert sein, mit 
Jetgeschwindigkeiten über einem gesamten Ozean zu reisen. Nahe 
diesbezüglich interaktiv vom NOVA online, erforschen Sie, wie das 
indischer Ozean 2004 tsunami -- das tödlichste in gespeicherter 
Geschichte -- gestartet wurde, wie seine Wellen Tausenden Kilometer 
groß unverändert fortpflanzten und was einmal die Wellen erreichten 
Küstenlinien und weit von ihre Quelle geschahen. Grade 6-12</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les vagues de Tsunami peuvent être distinguées 
des vagues ordinaires d'océan par beaucoup de facteurs, y compris la 
quantité énorme d'énergie qu'elles portent, de la grande distance 
entre leurs crêtes de vague, et de leur capacité de voyager aux 
vitesses d'avion de ligne à réaction à travers un océan entier. 
En cela interactif du NOVA en ligne, explorez de comment 2004 le
tsunami de l'Océan Indien -- le plus mortel dans l'histoire 
enregistrée -- a été déclenché, de comment ses vagues ont voyagé
des milliers de kilomètres en grande partie sans changement, et près
de ce que se sont produits par le passé les littoraux atteints par 
vagues et loin de leur source. Catégories 6-12</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As ondas de Tsunami podem ser distintas das ondas 
ordinárias do oceano por muitos fatores, including a quantidade 
tremenda de energia que carregam, da distância grande entre suas 
cristas da onda, e de sua capacidade viajar em velocidades do jetliner
através de um oceano inteiro. Neste interativo do NOVA em 
linha, explore de como 2004 o tsunami do Oceano Índico -- o mais 
mortal no history gravado -- foi provocado, de como suas ondas 
viajaram milhares dos quilômetros pela maior parte unchanged, e o que
aconteceram uma vez os coastlines alcançados ondas  perto e longe de 
sua fonte. Classes 6-12</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le onde di Tsunami possono essere distinte dalle 
onde ordinarie dell'oceano da molti fattori, compreso la quantità 
tremenda di energia che trasportano, della distanza grande fra le loro
creste dell'onda e di loro capacità viaggiare alle velocità del 
jetliner attraverso un intero oceano. In questo interattivo dal 
NOVA in linea, esplori a come 2004 il tsunami dell'Oceano Indiano -- 
il più mortale nella storia registrata -- è stato innescato, a come 
le relative onde hanno viaggiato migliaia dei chilometri in gran parte
identicamente ed a che cosa sono accaduto una volta le linee costiere 
raggiunte onde sia vicino che lontano dalla loro sorgente. Gradi
6-12</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα κύματα Tsunami μπορούν να διακριθούν από τα 
συνηθισμένα ωκεάνια κύματα από πολλούς παράγοντες, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένου του τεράστιου ποσού ενέργειας που φέρνουν, η 
μεγάλη απόσταση μεταξύ των λόφων κυμάτων τους, και η ικανότητά 
τους να ταξιδεψουν με τις ταχύτητες jetliner πέρα από έναν 
ολόκληρο ωκεανό. Σε αυτό διαλογικό από τη NOVA 
on-line, εξερευνήστε πώς το tsunami Ινδικού Ωκεανού του 
2004 -- ο pjo' δεαδληεστ στην καταγραμμένη ιστορία -- 
προκλήθηκε, πώς τα κύματά του ταξίδεψαν χιλιάδες χιλιόμετρα 
κατά ένα μεγάλο μέρος αμετάβλητα, και τι συνέβη μόλις έφθασαν 
τα κύματα στις ακτές και πλησίον και μακριά από την πηγή τους. 
Βαθμοί 6-12</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las ondas de Tsunami pueden ser distinguidas de 
ondas ordinarias del océano por muchos factores, incluyendo la enorme
cantidad de energía que llevan, de la gran distancia entre sus 
crestas de la onda, y de su capacidad de viajar a las velocidades del 
jetliner a través de un océano entero. En esto interactivo de 
la NOVA en línea, explore de cómo 2004 el tsunami del Océano 
Índico -- el más mortal de historia registrada -- fue accionado, de 
cómo viajaron sus ondas los millares de kilómetros en gran parte sin
cambiar, y cerca qué sucedieron una vez las líneas de la costa 
alcanzadas las ondas y lejos de su fuente. Grados 6-12</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:WGBH EDUCATIONAL FOUNDATION
FN:WGBH EDUCATIONAL FOUNDATION
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200441</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105149</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/anatomy-of-a-tsunami</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
