<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104903</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104903</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086845</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Spies for Hire: Advertising by the Pinkerton Agency</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spione für Miete: Bekanntmachen durch die 
Pinkerton Agentur</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Espions pour la location : La publicité par
l'agence de Pinkerton</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Espiões para o hire: Anunciar pela agência
de Pinkerton</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Spie per noleggio: Facendo pubblicità 
dall'agenzia di Pinkerton</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατάσκοποι για τη μίσθωση: Διαφήμιση από την 
αντιπροσωπεία Pinkerton</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Espías para el hire: Publicidad por la 
agencia de Pinkerton</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">By the early 1890s, the 2,000 active agents and 30,000 reserves of the Pinkerton National Detective Agency were larger than the standing army of the United States. In the 1880s, the Pinkertons provided services for management in 70 different labor disputes. The agency's success depended on both armed guards and the clandestine efforts of secret operatives like James McParlan, who had infiltrated Irish anthracite miners' organizations in the mid 1870s. McParlan's testimony (which historians have largely dismissed as fabricated) at the sensational "Molly Maguire" trial of 1876 helped send ten men to the gallows and broke the miners' union for a generation. This advertisement from the 1890s touted the prowess of the Pinkerton detective agency in maintaining law and order and played on corporate fears of "dissatisfaction among the laboring classes" to build business.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Durch das frühe 1890s waren die 2.000 aktiven 
Mittel und 30.000 Reserven des Pinkerton nationalen Detektivbüros 
größer als die stehende Armee der Vereinigten Staaten. Im 
1880s stellte das Pinkertons Dienstleistungen für Management in 70 
unterschiedlichen arbeitsrechtlichen Streitigkeiten zur Verfügung. 
Der Erfolg der Agentur hing von bewaffnetem Schutz und von den 
heimlichen Bemühungen der geheimen Arbeiter wie James McParlan ab, 
das hatte Organisationen der irischen Anthrazitbergmänner in des 
mittleren 1870s. McParlans dem Zeugnis (das Historiker groß 
entlassen, wie fabriziert), am sensational "Molly Maguire" Versuch von
1876 geholfen 10 Männer, zu den Galgenn zu schicken 
eingesickert und den Anschluß der Bergmänner für ein Erzeugung 
brach haben. Diese Reklameanzeige vom 1890s kündigte die 
Fähigkeit des Pinkerton Detektivbüros in beibehaltenem Gesetz und in
Ordnung an und spielte auf korporativer Furcht vor "Unzufriedenheit 
unter der Bearbeitung klassifiziert", um Geschäft aufzubauen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Par le 1890s tôt, les 2.000 agents actifs et 
30.000 réserves de l'agence de détectives nationale de Pinkerton 
étaient plus grands que l'armée debout des Etats-Unis. Dans le
1880s, le Pinkertons a fourni des services pour la gestion dans 70 
conflits de travail différents. Le succès de l'agence a 
dépendu des gardes armées et des efforts clandestins des employés 
secrets comme James McParlan, qui avait infiltré les organismes 
des mineurs anthracite irlandais dans le mi le témoignage de 1870s. 
McParlan (que les historiens ont en grande partie écarté comme 
fabriqué) à l'épreuve sensationnelle "de Maguire de molly" de 1876 
aidés pour envoyer dix hommes à la potence et a cassé l'union 
des mineurs pour une génération. Cette publicité du 1890s a 
espionné la prouesse de l'agence de détectives de Pinkerton 
dans la loi et la commande de mise à jour et a joué sur des craintes
de corporation de "mécontentement parmi travailler classe" pour 
établir des affaires.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Pelo 1890s adiantado, os 2.000 agentes ativos e 
30.000 reservas da agência detective nacional de Pinkerton eram 
maiores do que o exército ereto dos estados unidos. No 1880s, o
Pinkertons forneceu serviços para a gerência em 70 disputas labor 
diferentes. O sucesso da agência dependeu  dos protetores 
armados e dos esforços clandestine de operatives secretos como James 
McParlan, que infiltrated organizações dos mineiros anthracite irish
no testimony de 1870s. o McParlan mid (que os historians demitiram 
pela maior parte como fabricado) do "na experimentação de Maguire 
molly" do sensational de 1876 ajudados emitir dez homens ao gallows e 
quebrou a união dos mineiros para uma geração. Esta 
propaganda do 1890s touted o prowess da agência detective de 
Pinkerton na lei e na ordem mantendo e jogou-o em medos incorporados 
do "descontentamento entre trabalhar classifica" para construir o 
negócio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dal 1890s iniziale, i 2.000 agenti attivi e 30.000
riserve dell'agenzia detective nazionale di Pinkerton erano più 
grandi di l'esercito diritto del unito Dichiara. Nel 
1880s, il Pinkertons ha fornito i servizi per la gestione in 70 
dispute di lavoro differenti. Il successo dell'agenzia 
dipendeva sia dalle protezioni munite che dagli sforzi clandestini 
degli operatori segreti come James McParlan, che si era infiltrato 
nelle organizzazioni dei minatori antracite irlandesi il metà di 
nella testimonianza di 1870s. McParlan (che gli storici in gran parte 
hanno allontanato come fabbricato)"alla prova di Maguire del molly" di
sensational di 1876 contribuiti per trasmettere dieci uomini al 
gallows ed ha rotto l'unione dei minatori per una generazione. 
Questa pubblicità dal 1890s touted il prowess dell'agenzia 
detective di Pinkerton nella legge e nell'ordine effettuanti ed ha 
giocato sui timori corporativi "di malcontento fra lavorare 
classifica" per sviluppare il commercio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Από το πρόωρο 1890s, 2.000 ενεργοί πράκτορες και
30.000 επιφυλάξεις της εθνικής αντιπροσωπείας ιδιωτικών 
αστυνομικών Pinkerton ήταν μεγαλύτεροι από μόνιμος στρατός 
των Ηνωμένων Πολιτειών. Στο 1880s, το Pinkertons 
παρείχε τις υπηρεσίες για τη διαχείριση σε 70 διαφορετικές 
διαφωνίες εργασίας. Η επιτυχία της αντιπροσωπείας 
εξαρτήθηκε και από τις οπλισμένες φρουρές και από τις μυστικές 
προσπάθειες των μυστικών χειριστών όπως james McParlan, ο 
οποίος είχε διεισδύσει τις οργανώσεις των ιρλανδικών 
ανθρακιτικών ανθρακωρύχων στη μέση 1870s. McParlan's 
κατάθεση (που οι ιστορικοί έχουν απομακρύνει κατά ένα μεγάλο 
μέρος όπως κατασκευάζονται) στη συγκλονιστική δοκιμή "Molly 
Maguire" 1876 που ενισχύθηκε να στείλει δέκα άτομα στις 
αγχόνες και έσπασε την ένωση των ανθρακωρύχων για μια παραγωγή. 
Αυτή η διαφήμιση από το 1890s η ανδρεία της 
αντιπροσωπείας ιδιωτικών αστυνομικών Pinkerton στη διατήρηση 
του νόμου και της τάξης και έπαιξε στους εταιρικούς φόβους "της 
δυσαρέσκειας μεταξύ των κλάσεων εργασίασ" για να χτίσει την 
επιχείρηση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Por el 1890s temprano, los 2.000 agentes activos y
30.000 reservas de la agencia detective nacional de Pinkerton eran 
más grandes que el ejército derecho de los Estados Unidos. En 
el 1880s, el Pinkertons proporcionó a los servicios para la gerencia 
en 70 diversos conflictos de trabajo. El éxito de la agencia 
dependió de protectores armados y de los esfuerzos clandestinos de 
operarios secretos como James McParlan, que había infiltrado las 
organizaciones de los mineros de antracita irlandeses en el testimonio
de 1870s. el McParlan mediados de (que los historiadores han despedido
en gran parte según lo fabricado) en de "el ensayo Maguire del molly"
del sensational de 1876 ayudados para enviar a diez hombres a la horca
y rompió la unión de los mineros para una generación. Este 
anuncio del 1890s touted el valor de la agencia detective de Pinkerton
en ley y orden que mantenían y jugó en miedos corporativos del 
"descontento entre trabajar clasifica" para construir negocio.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086845</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104903</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/spies-for-hire-advertising-by-the-pinkerton-agency</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
