<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103699</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103699</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202549</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Story Shackles (Linking Students To Written Text)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geschichte-Fesseln (Kursteilnehmer-Schriftlichen 
Text Binden)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dispositifs d'accrochage d'Histoire (Joignant Le 
Texte Écrit D'Étudiants)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Shackles Da História (Que Ligam O Texto Escrito 
Dos Estudantes)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Anelli di trazione Di Storia (Che Collegano Il 
Testo Scritto Degli Allievi)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δεσμοί ιστορίας (γραπτό κείμενο σπουδαστών σύνδεσης)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Grillos De la Historia (Que conectan El Texto 
Escrito De los Estudiantes)</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Chain your students to reading a given text critically!! Story Shackles is an imaginative and stimulating way for students to acquire the ability to retell events of a story or text, sequence the action or happenings in a story, or to simply summarize the plot, main ideas with supporting details, or general information of a story or text.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ketten Sie Ihre Kursteilnehmer an einen gegebenen 
Text kritisch lesen! an! Geschichte-Fesseln ist ein 
phantasiereiches und anregende Methode, damit Kursteilnehmer die 
Fähigkeit, Fälle einer Geschichte oder des Textes wiederzuholen, 
sequentiell ordnen die Tätigkeit oder die Happenings in einer 
Geschichte, erwerben oder den Plot, die Grundgedanken mit 
unterstützenden Details oder die allgemeinen Informationen einer 
Geschichte oder des Textes einfach zusammenzufassen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Enchaînez vos étudiants à lire un texte donné 
en critique ! ! Les dispositifs d'accrochage d'histoire est un 
imaginatif et la voie stimulante pour que les étudiants saisissent la
capacité de raconter de nouveau des événements d'une histoire ou d'un
texte, ordonnancent l'action ou les événements dans une histoire, 
ou de récapituler simplement le traçage, les idées principales avec
les détails supportants, ou les informations générales d'une 
histoire ou d'un texte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Acorrente seus estudantes a ler um texto dado 
crìticamente!! Os shackles da história são uns imaginative e 
a maneira estimulando para que os estudantes adquiram a abilidade de 
retell eventos de uma história ou de um texto, arranja em seqüência
a ação ou os happenings em uma história, ou de sumariar 
simplesmente o lote, as idéias principais com detalhes suportando, ou
a informação geral de uma história ou de um texto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Concateni i vostri allievi a leggere un dato testo
criticamente!! Gli anelli di trazione di storia è un 
immaginativo ed il modo di stimolazione affinchè gli allievi acquisti
la capacità di retell gli eventi di una storia o di un testo, ordina 
l'azione o i happenings in serie in una storia, o di ricapitolare 
semplicemente il diagramma, le idee principali con i particolari di 
sostegno, o le generalità di una storia o di un testo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αλυσοδέστε τους σπουδαστές σας στην ανάγνωση δεσμοί 
ότι μιας οι δεδομένοι κειμένων αυστηρά ιστορίας!! είναι ένας 
επινοητικός και παρακινητικός τρόπος για τους σπουδαστές να 
αποκτήσουν τη δυνατότητα να επαναλάβουν τα γεγονότα μιας ιστορίας
ή ενός κειμένου, να τοποθετήσουν διαδοχικά την ενέργεια ή να 
συμβούν σε μια ιστορία, ή να συνοψίσουν απλά την πλοκή, τις 
βασικές ιδέες με την υποστήριξη των λεπτομερειών, ή τις γενικές 
πληροφορίες μιας ιστορίας ή ενός κειμένου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Encadene a sus estudiantes a leer un texto dado 
críticamente!! Los grillos de la historia son imaginativos y la
manera que estimula para que los estudiantes adquieran la capacidad de
retell acontecimientos de una historia o de un texto, ordena la 
acción o los sucesos en una historia, o de resumir simplemente el 
diagrama, las ideas principales con los detalles que utilizan, o la 
información de carácter general de una historia o de un texto.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:KIM RECTOR
FN:KIM RECTOR
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202549</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103699</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/story-shackles-linking-students-to-written-text</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
