<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105887</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105887</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206386</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">From Silk to Oil: Cross-Cultural Connections Along the Silk Roads</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Von Seide zu Öl: Kreuz-Kulturelle 
Anschlüsse entlang den Seidenstraßen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">De la soie à l'huile : Connexions 
Croix-Culturelles le long des routes en soie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Da seda ao óleo: Conexões 
Cruz-cross-Cultural ao longo das estradas de seda</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Da seta ad olio: Collegamenti 
Traversa-Culturali lungo le strade di seta</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Από το μετάξι στο πετρέλαιο: Διαπολιτισμικές 
συνδέσεις κατά μήκος των δρόμων μεταξιού</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">De la seda al aceite: Conexiones 
Cruz-Culturales a lo largo de los caminos de seda</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a curriculum guide for exploring China's inner Asian frontier and one of the world's oldest and most important trade routes. The 350-page guide features five independent sections. Each examines the geography, ethnic relations and political history, exchange of goods and ideas, religions, or art along the Silk Roads (beginning in the second century BCE). Each includes lesson plans, documents, maps, and board game.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist eine Lehrplananleitung für das Erforschen 
Chinas von von innerer asiatischer Grenze und einem der ältesten und 
wichtigsten Handel Wege der Welt. Die Anleitung 350-page 
kennzeichnet fünf unabhängige Kapitel. Jedes überprüft die 
Geographie, die ethnischen Relationen und die politische Geschichte, 
der Austausch von Waren und von Ideen, die Religionen oder die kunst 
entlang den Seidenstraßen (anfangend im zweiten Jahrhundert BCE). 
Jedes schließt Lektionpläne, Dokumente, Karten und Brettspiel 
ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est un guide de programme d'études pour explorer 
la frontière asiatique intérieure et un de la Chine des itinéraires
les plus anciens et les plus importants du monde du commerce. Le
guide 350-page comporte cinq sections indépendantes. Chacun 
examine la géographie, les relations ethniques et l'histoire 
politique, l'échange des marchandises et des idées, les religions, 
ou l'art le long des routes en soie (commençant au deuxième siècle 
BCE). Chacun inclut des plans de leçon, des documents, des 
cartes, et le jeu de panneau.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é uma guia do curriculum para explorar a 
fronteira asian interna e uma de China das rotas as mais velhas e as 
mais importantes do mundo do comércio. A guia 350-page 
caracteriza cinco seções independentes. Cada um examina a 
geografia, as relações étnicas e o history político, a troca dos 
bens e das idéias, as religiões, ou a arte ao longo das estradas de 
seda (que começam no segundo século BCE). Cada um inclui 
plantas da lição, originais, mapas, e jogo de placa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è una guida di programma di studi per 
l'esplorazione la frontiera asiatica interna e dell'uno della Cina di 
più vecchi e di commercio itinerari più importanti del mondo. 
La guida 350-page caratterizza cinque sezioni indipendenti. 
Ciascuno esamina la geografia, i rapporti etnici e la storia 
politica, lo scambio di merci e di idee, le religioni, o l'arte lungo 
le strade di seta (che cominciano nel secondo secolo BCE). 
Ciascuno include i programmi di lezione, i documenti, i 
programmi ed il gioco del bordo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι ένας οδηγός προγράμματος σπουδών για την 
εξερεύνηση των εσωτερικών ασιατικών συνόρων της Κίνας και ενός 
από τους δρόμους παγκόσμιου παλαιότερους και σημαντικότερους 
εμπορίου. Ο οδηγός 350-σελίδων χαρακτηρίζει πέντε 
ανεξάρτητα τμήματα. Κάθε ένας εξετάζει τη γεωγραφία, τις 
εθνικές σχέσεις και την πολιτική ιστορία, ανταλλαγή των αγαθών 
και των ιδεών, των θρησκειών, ή της τέχνης κατά μήκος των 
δρόμων μεταξιού (αρχή στο δεύτερο αιώνα BCE). Κάθε 
ένας περιλαμβάνει τα σχέδια μαθήματος, τα έγγραφα, τους χάρτες, 
και το παιχνίδι πινάκων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es una guía del plan de estudios para explorar la
frontera asiática interna y una de China de las rutas más viejas y 
más importantes del mundo del comercio. La guía 350-page 
ofrece cinco secciones independientes. Cada uno examina la 
geografía, las relaciones étnicas y la historia política, el 
intercambio de mercancías y de ideas, las religiones, o el arte a lo 
largo de los caminos de seda (que comienzan en el segundo siglo BCE). 
Cada uno incluye planes de la lección, documentos, 
correspondencias, y el juego de tarjeta.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206386</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105887</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/from-silk-to-oil-cross-cultural-connections-along-the-silk-roads</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
