<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108675</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108675</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085251</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Women in the Workforce</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Frauen in der Mannschaft</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Femmes dans la main d'oeuvre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Mulheres no workforce</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Donne nella mano d'opera</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γυναίκες στο εργατικό δυναμικό</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mujeres en la mano de obra</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">With so many American men involved in the war abroad, there was an extreme shortage of workers at home. For the first time, women entered the workforce in large numbers, learning to do industrial jobs that previously had been done by men. The shipyard "dress code" poster for women reflects the newness of their transition into blue collar work. In the early 1940s, when the photographs in this topic were taken, women working in heavy industry were a novelty and women building warships was groundbreaking. As these images show, women were engaged in work that was highly skilled, sometimes dangerous, and often involved heavy physical labor. Women played a significant role in military production. Images here depict them working in shipyards welding, drafting, repairing tools, using heavy machinery, driving trucks. Women welders became known as "Rosie," and "Rosie the Riveter" became a nickname for female workers. Women working at the California shipyards were also called "Wendy the Welder." Toward the end of the war, women made up nearly one-third of the workforce of 90,000 at the Richmond Shipyards. A few of these photographs were taken by photographer Dorothea Lange. In these images you can see the various jobs that women performed at the Richmond Shipyards, as well as the dedication and hard work they contributed to the war effort. You may also notice that there are women of color in some of the photographs, reflecting the migration of African Americans from the South into California that was occurring at the time.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wenn so viele amerikanische Männer auswärts mit 
dem beschäftigt ge$$$WESEN sind Krieg gab es einen extremen Mangel an
Arbeiter zu Hause. Zum ersten Mal meldeten Frauen die Mannschaft
in die großen Zahlen an und erlernten, industrielle Arbeiten zu 
erledigen, die vorher von den Männern erfolgt worden waren. Das
Werft"Kleid-Code" Plakat für Frauen reflektiert die Neuheit ihres 
Überganges in blaue Stellringarbeit. In den frühen vierziger 
Jahren als die Fotographien in diesem Thema genommen wurden, waren die
Frauen, die in der Schwerindustrie arbeiten, eine Neuheit und die 
Frauen, die Kriegsschiffe aufbauen, groundbreaking. Da diese 
Bilder darstellen, nahmen Frauen an Arbeit teil, die, manchmal 
gefährliche und häufig beteiligte schwere Systemtestarbeit in hohem 
Grade erfahren war. Frauen spielten eine bedeutende Rolle in der
militärischen Produktion. Bilder hier stellen sie arbeitend in 
den Werften bildlich dar, die schweissen und zeichnen und reparieren 
Hilfsmittel mit der schweren Maschinerie und treiben LKWAS an. 
Frauschweißer wurden bekannt, wie "Rosie," und "Rosie der 
Nieteneinschläger" ein Spitzname für weibliche Arbeiter wurden. 
Den Frauen, die an den Kalifornien Werften arbeiten, wurden 
genannt auch "Wendy den Schweißer." In Richtung zum Ende des 
Krieges, bildeten Frauen fast Drittel der Mannschaft von 90.000 an den
Richmond Werften. Einige dieser Fotographien wurden vom 
Photographen Dorothea Lange genommen. In diesen Bildern können 
Sie die verschiedenen Jobs sehen, die Frauen an den Richmond Werften, 
sowie die Widmung und die harte Arbeit durchführten, die, sie zur 
Kriegbemühung beitrugen. Sie können auch beachten, daß es 
Frauen der Farbe in einigen der Fotographien gibt und die Migration 
der afrikanischen Amerikaner vom Süden in Kalifornien reflektiert, 
das zu der Zeit auftrat.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Tant d'hommes américains étant impliqué à 
l'étranger dans la guerre, il y avait un manque extrême d'ouvriers 
à la maison. Pour la première fois, les femmes ont présenté 
la main d'oeuvre dans de grands nombres, apprenant à faire les 
travaux industriels qui précédemment avaient été faits par les 
hommes. L'affiche de "code de robe" de chantier naval pour des 
femmes reflète la nouveauté de leur transition dans le travail bleu 
de collier. Au début des années 40, quand les photographies 
dans ce sujet ont été prises, les femmes travaillant dans 
l'industrie lourd étaient une nouveauté et les femmes construisant 
des vaisseaux de guerre étaient d'inauguration. Car ces images 
montrent, des femmes ont été engagées dans le travail qui était 
fortement habile, travail lourd parfois dangereux et et souvent 
impliqué d'examen médical. Les femmes ont joué un rôle 
significatif dans la production militaire. Les images ici les 
dépeignent travaillant dans les chantiers navals soudant, dessinant, 
réparant des outils, à l'aide des machines lourdes, conduisant des 
camions. Les soudeuses de femmes sont devenues notoires comme 
"Rosie," et "Rosie le rivoir" sont devenus un surnom pour les ouvriers
féminins. Des femmes travaillant aux chantiers navals de la 
Californie se sont également appelées "Wendy la soudeuse." 
Vers la fin de la guerre, les femmes ont composé presque un 
tiers de la main d'oeuvre de 90.000 aux chantiers navals de Richmond. 
Quelques unes de ces photographies ont été prises par le 
photographe Dorothea Lange. Dans ces images vous pouvez voir les
divers travaux que les femmes ont exécutés aux chantiers navals de 
Richmond, aussi bien que l'attachement et le travail dur qu'elles ont 
contribué à l'effort de guerre. Vous pouvez également noter 
qu'il y a des femmes de couleur dans certaines des photographies, 
reflétant le transfert des Américains africains des Sud dans
la Californie qui se produisait alors.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Com assim muitos homens americanos envolvidos na 
guerra no exterior, havia uma falta extrema dos trabalhadores na HOME.
Para a primeira vez, as mulheres inscreveram o workforce nos 
números grandes, aprendendo fazer os trabalhos industriais que tinham
sido feitos previamente por homens. Do "o poster do código 
vestido" do shipyard para mulheres reflete o newness de sua 
transição no trabalho azul do colar. Nos 1940s adiantados, 
quando as fotografias neste tópico foram feitas exame, as mulheres 
que trabalham na indústria pesada eram um novelty e as mulheres que 
constroem navios de guerra groundbreaking. Porque estas imagens 
mostram, as mulheres foram acopladas no trabalho que era altamente 
hábil, trabalho pesado às vezes perigoso, e frequentemente involvido
do exame. As mulheres jogaram um papel significativo na 
produção militar. As imagens aqui descrevem-nos que trabalham 
nos shipyards que soldam, esboçando, reparando ferramentas, usando a 
maquinaria pesada, dirigindo caminhões. Os soldadores das 
mulheres tornaram-se sabidos como "Rosie," e "Rosie o rebitador" se 
transformaram um nickname para trabalhadores fêmeas. As 
mulheres que trabalham nos shipyards de Califórnia foram chamadas 
também "Wendy o soldador." Para o fim da guerra, as mulheres 
compuseram quase um terço do workforce de 90.000 nos shipyards de 
Richmond. Algumas destas fotografias foram feitas exame pelo 
fotógrafo Dorothea Lange. Nestas imagens você pode ver os 
vários trabalhos que as mulheres executaram nos shipyards de 
Richmond, as.well.as o dedication e o trabalho que duro contribuíram 
ao esforço da guerra. Você pode também observar que há 
mulheres da cor em algumas das fotografias, refletindo a migração de
americanos africanos do sul em Califórnia que estava ocorrendo 
naquele tempo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Con tanti uomini americani addetti alla guerra 
all'estero, ci era una scarsità estrema degli operai nel paese. 
Per la prima volta, le donne hanno registrato la mano d'opera 
nei grandi numeri, imparanti fare i lavori industriali che 
precedentemente erano stati fatti dall'uomo. "il manifesto di 
codice del vestito" dal cantiere navale per le donne riflette la 
novità della loro transizione nel lavoro blu del collare. 
Nell'inizio degli anni 40, quando le fotografie in questo 
soggetto sono state prese, le donne che lavorano nell'industria 
pesante erano una novità e le donne che costruiscono le navi da 
guerra erano approfondite. Poichè queste immagini mostrano, le 
donne sono state agganciate nel lavoro che era altamente esperto, 
lavoro fisico pesante a volte pericoloso e e spesso implicato. 
Le donne hanno svolto un ruolo significativo nella produzione 
militare. Le immagini qui lo descrivono che lavorano nei 
cantieri navali che saldano, disegnando, riparando gli strumenti, per 
mezzo del macchinario pesante, conducente i camion. I saldatori 
delle donne sono stato conosciuti come "Rosie," e "Rosie la 
rivettatrice" si sono transformati in in un nickname per gli operai 
femminili. Le donne che lavorano ai cantieri navali della 
California egualmente sono state chiamate "Wendy il saldatore." 
Verso la conclusione della guerra, le donne hanno composto quasi
un terzo della mano d'opera di 90.000 ai cantieri navali de Richmond. 
Alcune di queste fotografie sono state prese dal photographer 
Dorothea Lange. In queste immagini potete vedere i vari lavori 
che le donne hanno effettuato ai cantieri navali de Richmond, così 
come la dedica ed il lavoro che duro hanno contribuito allo sforzo di 
guerra. Potete anche notare che ci sono donne di colore in 
alcune delle fotografie, riflettendo l'espansione degli Americani 
africani dal sud nella California che stava accadendo allora.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Με τόσα πολλά αμερικανικά άτομα που συμμετέχουν στον 
πόλεμο στο εξωτερικό, υπήρξε μια ακραία έλλειψη των εργαζομένων 
στο σπίτι. Για πρώτη φορά, οι γυναίκες εισήγαγαν το 
εργατικό δυναμικό στους μεγάλους αριθμούς, που μαθαίνει να 
κάνουν τις βιομηχανικές εργασίες που προηγουμένως είχαν γίνει 
από τους άνδρες. Η αφίσα "κανόνα ένδυσησ" ναυπηγείων για 
τις γυναίκες απεικονίζει τη νεότητα της μετάβασής τους στην μπλε 
εργασία περιλαίμιων. Στις αρχές της δεκαετίας του '40, όταν
λήφθηκαν οι φωτογραφίες σε αυτό το θέμα, οι γυναίκες που 
εργάζονται στη βαριά βιομηχανία ήταν μια καινοτομία και οι 
γυναίκες που χτίζουν τα θωρηκτά. Όπως αυτές οι εικόνες 
εμφανίζουν, οι γυναίκες ασχολήθηκαν με την εργασία που ήταν πολύ
καλά καταρτισμένη, μερικές φορές επικίνδυνη, και περιέλαβε 
συχνά τη βαριά φυσική εργασία. Οι γυναίκες διαδραμάτισαν 
έναν σημαντικό ρόλο στη στρατιωτική παραγωγή. Οι εικόνες 
τους απεικονίζουν εδώ που λειτουργούν στα ναυπηγεία που ενώνουν 
στενά, που συντάσσουν, επισκευάζοντας τα εργαλεία, 
χρησιμοποιώντας τα βαριά μηχανήματα, που οδηγούν τα truck. 
Οι οξυγονοκολλητές γυναικών έγιναν γνωστοί ως "Rosie," 
και "Rosie που riveter" έγινε ένα παρωνύμιο για τη γυναίκα 
εργαζόμενοι. Οι γυναίκες που εργάζονται στα ναυπηγεία 
Καλιφόρνιας κλήθηκαν επίσης "τη Wendy οξυγονοκολλητή." 
Προς το τέλος του πολέμου, οι γυναίκες αποτέλεσαν σχεδόν το
ένα τρίτο του εργατικού δυναμικού 90.000 στα ναυπηγεία του 
Ρίτσμοντ. Μερικές από αυτές τις φωτογραφίες λήφθηκαν από 
το φωτογράφο Dorothea Lange. Σε αυτές τις εικόνες 
μπορείτε να δείτε τις διάφορες εργασίες που οι γυναίκες
που εκτελέσθηκαν στα ναυπηγεία του Ρίτσμοντ, καθώς επίσης και η 
σκληρής εργασία αφιέρωσης και αυτοί συνέβαλαν στην πολεμική 
προσπάθεια. Μπορείτε επίσης να παρατηρήσετε ότι υπάρχουν 
γυναίκες του χρώματος σε μερικές από τις φωτογραφίες, που 
απεικονίζουν τη μετανάστευση αφρικανικών Αμερικανών από το νότο 
σε Καλιφόρνια που εμφανιζόταν στο χρόνο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Con tan muchos hombres americanos implicados en la
guerra al exterior, había una escasez extrema de trabajadores en el 
país. Para la primera vez, las mujeres inscribieron a mano de 
obra en los números grandes, aprendiendo hacer los trabajos 
industriales que habían sido hechos previamente por los hombres. 
Del "el cartel código de la alineada" del astillero para las 
mujeres refleja la novedad de su transición en trabajo azul del 
collar. En los años 40 tempranos, cuando las fotografías en 
este asunto fueron tomadas, las mujeres que trabajaban en industria 
pesada eran una novedad y las mujeres que construían los buques de 
guerra groundbreaking. Pues estas imágenes muestran, 
contrataron a las mujeres al trabajo que era altamente experto, 
trabajo pesado a veces peligroso, y a menudo implicado de la 
comprobación. Las mujeres desempeñaron un papel significativo 
en la producción militar. Las imágenes aquí los representan 
que trabajan en los astilleros que sueldan, bosquejando, reparando las
herramientas, usando la maquinaria pesada, conduciendo los carros. 
Los soldadores de las mujeres se conocían como "Rosie," y 
"Rosie el remachador" se convirtieron en un apodo para los 
trabajadores femeninos. Llamaron las mujeres que trabajaban en 
los astilleros de California también "Wendy el soldador." Hacia
el final de la guerra, las mujeres compusieron casi una mitad de la 
mano de obra de 90.000 en los astilleros de Richmond. Algunas de
estas fotografías fueron tomadas por el fotógrafo Dorothea Lange. 
En estas imágenes usted puede ver los varios trabajos que las 
mujeres realizaron en los astilleros de Richmond, así como el esmero 
y el trabajo duro que contribuyeron al esfuerzo de la guerra. 
Usted puede también notar que hay mujeres del color en algunas 
de las fotografías, reflejando la migración de americanos africanos 
del sur en California que ocurría en ese entonces.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085251</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108675</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/women-in-the-workforce</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
