<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108096</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108096</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086198</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Giving a Dam: Congress Debates Hetch Hetchy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geben einer Verdammung: Kongreß Debattiert 
Hetch Hetchy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Donner un barrage : Le Congrès Discute 
Hetch Hetchy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Dando uma represa: O Congress Debate Hetch 
Hetchy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dare una diga: Il Congresso Dibatte Hetch 
Hetchy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δόσιμο ενός φράγματος: Συζητήσεις Hetch 
Hetchy συνεδρίων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Dar una presa: El Congreso Discute Hetch 
Hetchy</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The first great American conservation movement was born during the Progressive Era out of the concern that industrial growth and urban development threatened to extinguish America's wilderness. The era's most controversial environmental issue was the five-year struggle over federal approval for the flooding of a remote corner of federally-owned land in California's Yosemite National Park to build the Hetch Hetchy dam. The city of San Francisco, rebuilding after the devastating 1906 earthquake, believed the dam was necessary to meet its burgeoning needs for reliable supplies of water and electricity. In their 1913 testimony before the House Committee on Public Lands, former San Francisco Mayor James Phelan and Gifford Pinchot, the first Chief Forester of the United States and the most noted conservationist of his generation, put the utilitarian needs of San Francisco's citizens above the aesthetic and moral advantages of leaving Yosemite a pristine wilderness. In the end Congress chose management over aesthetics, voting 43-25 (with 29 abstentions) to allow the Hetch Hetchy dam on federal land.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die erste große amerikanische Erhaltung Bewegung 
wurde während der progressiven Ära aus dem Interesse heraus 
getragen, daß industrielles Wachstum und städtische Entwicklung 
bedrohten, Wildnis Amerikas auszulöschen. Die umstrittenste 
Klimaausgabe der Ära war die 
Fünfjahreskampfüberschußbundeszustimmung für die Überschwemmung 
einer Remoteecke des Bundes-besessenen Landes in Yosemite Nationalpark
Kaliforniens, zum der Hetch Hetchy Verdammung aufzubauen. Die 
Stadt von San Francisco, umbauend nach dem VerwüstenErdbeben 1906, 
glaubte, daß die Verdammung notwendig war, um seine sprießenden 
Bedürfnisse am zuverlässigen Zubehör Wasser und Elektrizität zu 
erfüllen. In ihr Zeugnis 1913 vor dem Haus-Ausschuß für 
allgemeine Länder, ehemaligem San Francisco Bürgermeister James 
Phelan und Gifford Pinchot, dem ersten Hauptförster der Vereinigten 
Staaten und dem beachteten Naturschützer seines Erzeugung, setzen Sie
die utilitaristischen Notwendigkeiten von Bürgern San Franciscos 
über den ästhetischen und moralischen Vorteilen des Verlassens 
Yosemite einer pristine Wildnis ein. Im Ende wählte wählte der
Kongreß Management über der Ästhetik und 43-25 (mit 29 Enthaltung) 
um die Hetch Hetchy Verdammung auf Bundesland zu erlauben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le premier grand mouvement américain d'économie 
a été soutenu pendant l'ère progressive hors du souci que la 
croissance industrielle et le développement urbain ont menacé de 
s'éteindre le désert de l'Amérique. L'issue environnementale 
la plus controversée de l'ère était l'approbation fédérale 
d'excédent de cinq ans de lutte pour l'inondation d'un coin à 
distance de terre fédéral-possédée en parc national de Yosemite de
la Californie pour construire le barrage de Hetch Hetchy. La 
ville de San Francisco, reconstruisant après le tremblement de 
terre 1906 de dévaster, a cru que le barrage était nécessaire pour 
satisfaire ses besoins bourgeonnants d'approvisionnements fiables en 
eau et électricité. Dans leur témoignage 1913 avant le 
comité de Chambre des terres publiques, ancien maire James 
Phelan et Gifford Pinchot de San Francisco, le premier forestier en 
chef des Etats-Unis et le protecteur de la nature le plus remarquable 
de sa génération, mettez les besoins utilitaires des citoyens de San
Francisco au-dessus des avantages esthétiques et moraux de laisser 
à Yosemite un désert primitif. À la fin le congrès a choisi 
la gestion au-dessus de l'esthétique, votant 43-25 (avec 29 
abstentions) pour permettre le barrage de Hetch Hetchy sur la terre 
fédérale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O primeiro movimento americano grande do 
conservation foi carregado durante a era progressiva fora do interesse
que o crescimento industrial e o desenvolvimento urbano ameaçaram 
extinguir a região selvagem de América. A edição ambiental a
mais controversa da era era a aprovaçã0 federal do excesso de cinco 
anos do esforço para o flooding de um canto remoto da terra 
federal-possuída no parque nacional de Yosemite de Califórnia para 
construir a represa de Hetch Hetchy. A cidade de San Francisco, 
reconstruindo após o terremoto 1906 devastating, acreditou que a 
represa era necessária para se encontrar com suas necessidades 
burgeoning para fontes de confiança da água e da eletricidade. 
Em seu testimony 1913 antes do comitê da casa em terras 
públicas, do mayor anterior James Phelan e Gifford Pinchot do San 
Francisco, do primeiro forester principal dos estados unidos e do 
conservationist o mais notável de sua geração, ponha as 
necessidades utilitarian de cidadãos do San Francisco acima das 
vantagens aesthetic e morais de sair Yosemite de uma região selvagem 
pristine. Na extremidade o congress escolheu a gerência sobre o
aesthetics, votando 43-25 (com 29 abstentions) para permitir a represa
de Hetch Hetchy na terra federal.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il primo movimento americano grande di 
conservazione è stato sopportato durante l'era progressiva dalla 
preoccupazione che lo sviluppo industriale e lo sviluppo urbano hanno 
minacciato di estinguere la selva dell'America. L'edizione 
ambientale più discutibile dell'era era l'approvazione federale 
dell'eccedenza quinquennale di lotta per il flooding di un angolo a 
distanza di terra federale-posseduta nel parco nazionale di Yosemite 
della California per costruire la diga di Hetch Hetchy. La 
città di San Francisco, ricostruente dopo il terremoto 1906 di 
devastazione, ha creduto che la diga fosse necessaria da soddisfare le
relative esigenze burgeoning dei rifornimenti certi di acqua e di 
elettricità. Nella loro testimonianza 1913 prima del comitato 
della Camera delle terre pubbliche, di ex sindaco James Phelan e 
Gifford Pinchot de San Francisco, il primo silvicoltore principale del
unito Dichiara ed il conservationist più celebre della sua 
generazione, ha messo i bisogni utilitari dei cittadini de San 
Francisco sopra i vantaggi estetici e morali di lasciare a Yosemite 
una selva pristine. Alla fine il congresso ha scelto la gestione
sopra l'estetica, votante 43-25 (con 29 astensioni) per permettere la 
diga di Hetch Hetchy su terra federale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η πρώτη μεγάλη αμερικανική μετακίνηση συντήρησης 
γεννήθηκε κατά τη διάρκεια της προοδευτικής εποχής από την 
ανησυχία ότι η βιομηχανική αύξηση και η αστική εξέλιξη 
απείλησαν να εξαφανίσουν την αγριότητα της Αμερικής. Το πιό
αμφισβητούμενο περιβαλλοντικό ζήτημα της εποχής ήταν η πενταετής
προσπάθεια πέρα από την ομοσπονδιακή έγκριση για την πλημμύρα 
μιας απομακρυσμένης γωνίας του ομοσπονδιακά-κύριου εδάφους στο 
εθνικό πάρκο Yosemite Καλιφόρνιας να χτιστεί το φράγμα 
Hetch Hetchy. Η πόλη του Σαν Φρανσίσκο, που 
επανοικοδομεί μετά από τον καταστρεπτικό σεισμό του 1906, 
εθεώρησε ότι το φράγμα ήταν απαραίτητο για να ικανοποιήσει τις 
φυτρώνοντας ανάγκες του για τις αξιόπιστες προμήθειες της 
ύδρευσης και της ηλεκτρικής ενέργειας. Στην κατάθεση του 
1913 τους ενώπιον της Επιτροπής Βουλών των δημόσιων εδαφών, το
πρώην Σαν Φρανσίσκο δήμαρχος james Phelan και Gifford 
Pinchot, ο πρώτος Προϊστάμενος δασοφύλακας των Ηνωμένων Πολιτειών
και ο σημειωμένος μαχόμενος για τη διατήρηση του φυσικού 
περιβάλλοντος της γενεάς του, έβαλε τις χρηστικές ανάγκες των 
πολιτών του Σαν Φρανσίσκο επάνω από αισθητικά και ηθικά 
πλεονέκτημα σε Yosemite μια παλιή αγριότητα. Στο τέλος το
συνέδριο επέλεξε τη διαχείριση πέρα από την αισθητική, 
ψηφίζοντας 43-25 (με 29 αποχές) για να επιτρέψει το φράγμα 
Hetch Hetchy στο ομοσπονδιακό έδαφος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El primer gran movimiento americano de la 
conservación fue llevado durante la era progresiva fuera de la 
preocupación que el crecimiento industrial y el desarrollo urbano 
amenazaron extinguir el yermo de América. La edición ambiental
más polémica de la era era la aprobación federal del excedente de 
cinco años de la lucha para el flooding de una esquina alejada de la 
pista federal-posei'da en el parque nacional de Yosemite de California
para construir la presa de Hetch Hetchy. La ciudad de San 
Francisco, reconstruyendo después del terremoto 1906 de la 
devastación, creyó que la presa era necesaria resolver sus 
necesidades burgeoning de fuentes confiables de agua y de 
electricidad. En su testimonio 1913 ante el comité de la casa 
sobre pistas públicas, alcalde anterior James Phelan y Gifford 
Pinchot de San Francisco, el primer principal silvicultor de los 
Estados Unidos y el conservationist más conocido de su generación, 
ponga las necesidades utilitarias de los ciudadanos de San Francisco 
sobre las ventajas estéticas y morales de salir Yosemite de un yermo 
prístino. En extremo el congreso eligió a gerencia sobre la 
estética, votando 43-25 (con 29 abstenciones) para permitir la presa 
de Hetch Hetchy en pista federal.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086198</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108096</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/giving-a-dam-congress-debates-hetch-hetchy</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
