<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/156691</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>156691</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>ILMoE</catalog>
            <entry>ILMoE3013</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Holocaust Resource Center</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Holocaust Hilfsmittel-Mitte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Holocauste Le Centre de Ressource</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Centro Do Recurso De Holocaust</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Centro Delle Risorse Di Holocaust</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το κέντρο των στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς ολοκαυτώματος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Centro Del Recurso De Holocaust</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Holocaust Resource Center provides easy access to in-depth information about the HolocaustThe Center has a large collection of sources from the Yad Vashem Archives, including various kinds of original Holocaust-era documentation provided in English including letters and diaries written by Jews during the Holocaust, numerous photographs and original documents. The Holocaust Resource Center serves as a repository for the collection of the testimonies of Holocaust survivors th, as well as excerpts from memoirs written by survivors after the war. The Resource Center supports this collection of primary sources with excerpts from research studies, as well as, works of art, and historical maps and charts.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">holocaust</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">holocaust education</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">research</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">archives.</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Holocaust Hilfsmittel-Mitte liefert einfachen
Zugriff zu den eingehenden Informationen über die HolocaustThe Mitte 
hat eine große Ansammlung Quellen von den Yad Vashem Archiven, 
einschließlich verschiedene Arten der ursprünglichen Holocaust-Ära 
Unterlagen, die auf englisch einschließlich die Briefe und 
Tagebücher geschrieben werden von Jews während des Holocaust, der 
zahlreichen Fotographien und der Originalurkunden bereitgestellt 
werden. Die Holocaust Hilfsmittel-Mitte dient als Behälter für
die Ansammlung der Zeugnisse von Holocaust Überlebendth, sowie 
Excerpts von den Abhandlungen, die von den Überlebenden nach dem 
Krieg geschrieben werden. Die Hilfsmittel-Mitte unterstützt 
diese Ansammlung Primärquellen mit Excerpts von den Forschung 
Studien, sowie, Kunstwerke und historische Karten und Diagramme.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Holocauste le centre de ressource fournit 
l'accès facile aux informations détaillées sur le centre de 
HolocaustThe a une grande collection de sources des archives de Yad 
Vashem, y compris de divers genres de documentation initiale de 
holocauste-era fournie en anglais comprenant des lettres et des agendas 
écrits par Jews pendant Holocauste, de nombreuses photographies et 
documents initiaux. Holocauste le centre de ressource sert de 
dépôt à la collection des témoignages Holocauste du Th de 
survivants, aussi bien que des extraits des mémoires écrits par des 
survivants après la guerre. Le centre de ressource supporte 
cette collection de sources primaires avec des extraits des études de
recherches, aussi bien que, oeuvres d'art, et cartes et diagrammes 
historiques.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O centro do recurso de Holocaust fornece o acesso
fácil à informação in-depth sobre o centro de HolocaustThe tem uma
coleção grande das fontes dos arquivos de Yad Vashem, including 
vários tipos da documentação original da Holocaust-era fornecida em
inglês including as letras e os diários escritos por Jews durante o 
Holocaust, as fotografias numerosas e os originais originais. O 
centro do recurso de Holocaust serve como um repositório para a 
coleção dos testimonies do th dos sobreviventes de Holocaust, 
as.well.as excerpts dos memoirs escritos por sobreviventes após a 
guerra. O centro do recurso suporta esta coleção de fontes 
preliminares com excerpts dos estudos da pesquisa, as.well.as, 
trabalhos de arte, e mapas e cartas históricos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il centro delle risorse di Holocaust fornisce 
l'accesso facile alle informazioni approfondite sul centro di 
HolocaustThe ha un'ampia raccolta delle sorgenti dagli archivi di Yad 
Vashem, compreso i vari generi di documentazione originale di 
Holocaust-era fornita in inglese compreso le lettere ed i diari 
scritti da Jews durante il Holocaust, le fotografie numerose ed i 
documenti originali. Il centro delle risorse di Holocaust serve 
da deposito per l'accumulazione delle testimonianze del Th dei 
superstiti di Holocaust, così come i brani dalle memorie scritte dai 
superstiti dopo la guerra. Il centro delle risorse sostiene 
questa accumulazione delle sorgenti primarie con i brani dagli studi 
di ricerca, così come, opere d'arte e programmi e tabelle storici.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το κέντρο των στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς ολοκαυτώματος 
παρέχει ότι η εύκολη πρόσβαση στις σε βάθος πληροφορίες για το 
κέντρο HolocaustThe έχει μια μεγάλη συλλογή των πηγών από τα 
αρχεία Yad Vashem, συμπεριλαμβανομένων των διάφορων ειδών 
αρχικής τεκμηρίωσης ολοκαύτωμα-εποχής που παρέχεται στα αγγλικά 
συμπεριλαμβανομένων των επιστολών και τα ημερολόγια που γράφονται 
από τους Εβραίους κατά τη διάρκεια του ολοκαυτώματος, των 
πολυάριθμων φωτογραφιών και των αρχικών εγγράφων. Το κέντρο
των στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς ολοκαυτώματος χρησιμεύει ως μια 
αποθήκη για τη συλλογή των καταθέσεων του θορίου επιζόντων 
ολοκαυτώματος, καθώς επίσης και τα αποσπάσματα από τα 
απομνημονεύματα που γράφονται από τους επιζόντες μετά από τον 
πόλεμο. Το κέντρο των στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς υποστηρίζει 
αυτήν την συλλογή των αρχικών πηγών με τα αποσπάσματα από τις 
ερευνητικές μελέτες, καθώς επίσης και, τα έργα της τέχνης, και 
τους ιστορικούς χάρτες και τα διαγράμματα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El centro del recurso de Holocaust proporciona al
acceso fácil a la información profundizada sobre el centro de 
HolocaustThe tiene una colección grande de fuentes de los archivos de
Yad Vashem, incluyendo varias clases de documentación original de la 
Holocaust-era proporcionada en inglés incluyendo las letras y los 
diarios escritos por Jews durante el Holocaust, las fotografías 
numerosas y los documentos originales. El centro del recurso de 
Holocaust sirve como depósito para la colección de los testimonios 
del th de los sobrevivientes de Holocaust, así como extractos de las 
memorias escritas por los sobrevivientes después de la guerra. 
El centro del recurso utiliza esta colección de fuentes 
primarias con los extractos de estudios de la investigación, así 
como, las obras de arte, y las correspondencias y las cartas 
históricas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">holocaust</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">holocaust Ausbildung</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Forschung</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Archive.</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">holocauste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">holocauste éducation</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">recherche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">archives.</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">holocaust</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">instrução do holocaust</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">pesquisa</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">arquivos.</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">holocaust</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">formazione del holocaust</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">ricerca</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">archivi.</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ολοκαύτωμα</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εκπαίδευση ολοκαυτώματος</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">έρευνα</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">αρχεία.</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">holocaust</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">educación del holocaust</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">investigación</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">archivos.</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <status>
            <source>statusValues</source>
            <value>final</value>
          </status>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Israel Ministry of Education
n:Israel Ministry of Education
org:Israel Ministry of Education
end:vcard</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2009-02-20</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>ILMoE</catalog>
            <entry>ILMoE3013</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Israel Ministry of Education
n:Israel Ministry of Education
org:Israel Ministry of Education
end:vcard</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2009-02-20</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>text</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="en">13-18</string>
            <string language="x-t-lre">13-18</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>other</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Yad Vashem The Holocaust Martyrs' and Heroes' Remembrance Authority Fair use of copyrighted material includes the use of protected materials for non-commercial educational purposes, such as teaching, scholarship and research. See also conditions of use at http://www1.yadvashem.org/legal_about/index_terms_conditions.html</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>597</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">Holocaust</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>70</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">anti-Semitism</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>7</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">20th Century</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>156691</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www1.yadvashem.org.il/Odot/prog/index_before_change_table.asp?gate=0-1</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
