<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/75221</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>75221</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>SDT</catalog>
            <entry>40b9f895-7000-4288-2df6-53bbe3bc7bdd#1#7</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="hu">Belgium</string>
            <string language="en">Belgium</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Belgien</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Belgique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Bélgica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Belgio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βέλγιο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Bélgica</string>
          </title>
          <language>hu</language>
          <description>
            <string language="hu">Belgium</string>
            <string language="en">Belgium</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="hu">hasonlítsák össze személyes tapasztalataikat és a látottakat-hallottakat.Az animációk megtekintése után kezdjenek hozzá az interaktív elemek megtekintéséhez. A főbb fogalmak és a releváns személyiségek megismerése után pedig feladatválasztós tesztek megoldásához. A bibliográfia és az ajánlott irodalom segítséget nyújt tágabb információk megszerzéséhez. Cél, hogy a diákok önállóan is tudjanak keresni a hagyományos könyvtárakban és a digitális adatbázisokban. A módszer: a videó, a hang és képi elemeken keresztül is megismertetni az országot.",  </string>
            <string language="en">Compare all of own experiences with the seen and heard. After the viewing of the simulationn let's start to begin to see the interactive elements.After the cognition of the main concepts and the relevant characters begin to the solution of the choosetask test. The bibliography and the suggested reading could help to getting more information.The purpose is that the students can search self in the traditional libraries and in the digital database. The method: the country is got to know through the elements of video, sound and image</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Belgien</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Belgique</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Bélgica</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Belgio</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βέλγιο</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Bélgica</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Vergleichen Sie alle eigene Erfahrungen mit gesehen und
gehört. Nachdem die Betrachtung des simulationn uns beginnen 
ließ anzufangen, das interaktive elements.After zu sehen das Erkennen
der Hauptkonzepte und der relevanten Zeichen, zur Lösung des 
choosetask Tests anzufangen. Die Bibliographie und der 
vorgeschlagene Messwert konnten zum Erhalten mehr information.The 
Zweckes helfen ist, daß die Kursteilnehmer Selbst in den 
traditionellen Bibliotheken und in der digitalen Datenbank suchen 
können. Die Methode: das Land wird begonnen, um durch die
Elemente des Bildschirmes, des Tones und des Bildes zu wissen</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Comparez toutes propres expériences au vu et 
entendues. Après que le visionnement du simulationn nous ait 
laissés commencer à commencer à voir l'elements.After interactif la
connaissance des concepts principaux et des caractères appropriés 
commencer à la solution de l'essai de choosetask. La 
bibliographie et la lecture suggérée pourraient aider à obtenir 
plus de but d'information.The est que les étudiants peuvent 
rechercher l'art de l'auto-portrait dans les bibliothèques traditionnelles et 
dans la base de données digitale. La méthode : le pays 
est fini par pour savoir par les éléments du vidéo, du bruit et de 
l'image</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Compare todas próprias experiências com visto e 
ouvidas. Depois que a visão do simulationn nos deixou começar 
começar a ver o elements.After interativo a cognição dos conceitos 
principais e dos caráteres relevantes começar à solução do teste 
do choosetask. A bibliografia e a leitura sugerida poderiam 
ajudar a começar mais finalidade de information.The são que os 
estudantes podem procurarar o self nas bibliotecas tradicionais e na 
base de dados digital. O método: o país é conhecido 
através dos elementos do vídeo, do som e da imagem</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Confronti tutte le proprie esperienze al visto a e 
sentite. Dopo che l'osservazione del simulationn li lasci 
cominciare cominciare a vedere il elements.After interattivo la 
cognizione dei concetti principali e dei caratteri relativi cominciare
alla soluzione della prova del choosetask. La bibliografia e la 
lettura suggerita potrebbero aiutare ad ottenere più scopo di 
information.The è che gli allievi possono cercare l'auto nelle 
librerie tradizionali e nella base di dati digitale. Il metodo: 
il paese è familiarizzato con attraverso gli elementi del 
video, del suono e dell'immagine</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Συγκρίνετε την όλη εμπειρία με βλέπω και 
ακουσμένη. Μετά από την όψη του simulationn αρχίστε να 
αρχίζετε να βλέπει τα διαλογικά στοιχεία Μετά από 
τη γνώση των βασικών εννοιών και των σχετικών χαρακτήρων αρχίστε
στη λύση της δοκιμής choosetask. Η βιβλιογραφία και η 
προτεινόμενη ανάγνωση θα μπορούσαν να βοηθήσουν να πάρουν 
περισσότερες πληροφορίες Ο σκοπός είναι ότι οι σπουδαστές 
μπορούν να ψάξουν μόνο στις παραδοσιακές βιβλιοθήκες και στην 
ψηφιακή βάση δεδομένων. Η μέθοδος: η χώρα γνωρίζεται
για να ξέρει μέσω των στοιχείων του βίντεο, του ήχου και της 
εικόνας</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Compare todas propias experiencias con haber visto y 
oídas. Después de que la visión del simulationn nos dejara 
comenzar a comenzar a ver el elements.After interactivo la cognición 
de los conceptos principales y de los caracteres relevantes comenzar a
la solución de la prueba del choosetask. La bibliografía y la 
lectura sugerida podrían ayudar a conseguir más propósito de 
information.The es que los estudiantes puedan buscar a uno mismo en 
las bibliotecas tradicionales y en la base de datos digital. El 
método: el país se familiariza con a través de los elementos 
del vídeo, del sonido y de la imagen</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <educational>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-T-LRE">14-15</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>presentation</value>
          </learningResourceType>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="hu">A tartalom kizárólag kizárólag az oktatás illetve tudományos kutatás céljára használható szigorúan non-profit jelleggel.</string>
            <string language="en">The content may be used for the sole purpose of illustration for teaching or scientific research and only for a strictly non-commercial purpose.</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard 
version:3.0
n:;
fn:
org:Szegedi Tudományegyetem, Kísérleti Fizikai Tanszék, Szakmódszertani Csoport
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>449</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
        <metaMetadata>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
        org:Sulinet
        version:3.0
        end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>75221</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://sdt.sulinet.hu/Player/default.aspx?g=40b9f895-7000-4288-2df6-53bbe3bc7bdd&amp;v=1&amp;b=7</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
