<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/89393290</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>89393290</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>SDT</catalog>
            <entry>b80bc7ee-cfed-41a3-8187-d72a36fdf68b#1#4</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="hu">Laokón csoport</string>
            <string language="en">The Laocon Group</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Laocon Gruppe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Groupe de Laocon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Grupo De Laocon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Gruppo Di Laocon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ομάδα Laocon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Grupo De Laocon</string>
          </title>
          <language>hu</language>
          <description>
            <string language="hu">Laokoón-csoprt (Ez a késő hellenista alkotás páratlan művészi ráérzéssel Laokoón és fiai kígyókkal vívott élet-halál küzdelmét ábrázolja. Laokoón – Trója főpapja – ellenezte a görögök fából készített ajándék lovának elfogadását. Pallas Athéné – a görögök védelmezője –, azért, hogy a falóban elhelyezett katonák bejuthassanak Trója városába, a gyanakvó Laokoónt és két gyermekét hatalmas kígyókkal szétmarcangoltatta.)</string>
            <string language="en">The Laocon Group(This late hellenist work illustrates the life- and -death struggle of Laocon and his sons with snakes. Laocon - high pries of Throy - was against the accepting the wood-made gift horse of the Greeks.Pallas Athene - the patron of the Greeks - , made huge snakes butch the suspicious Laocon and his two sons so that the soilders placed inside the wood-horse could enter the city of Throy </string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Laocon Group(This späte hellenist Arbeit 
veranschaulicht die Lebensdauer und - Todeskampf von Laocon und von 
seinen Söhnen mit Schlangen. Laocon - hohe Hebel von Throy - 
war gegen das Annehmen des Holz-gebildeten Geschenkpferds des 
Greeks.Pallas Athene - der Gönner des Griechen -, sehr große 
Schlangen butch gebildet das mißtrauische Laocon und seine zwei 
Söhne, damit die soilders, die innerhalb des Holz-Pferds plaziert 
wurden, die Stadt von Throy kommen konnten</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le travail en retard de hellenist de Laocon 
Group(This illustre la vie et - lutte de la mort de Laocon et de ses 
fils avec des serpents. Laocon - hauts leviers de Throy - était
contre recevoir le cheval bois-fait de cadeau du Greeks.Pallas Athene 
- le patron des Grecs -, fait les serpents énormes le butch le Laocon
soupçonneux et ses deux fils de sorte que les soilders placés à 
l'intérieur du bois-cheval aient pu entrer dans la ville de Throy</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O trabalho atrasado do hellenist de Laocon 
Group(This ilustra a vida e - esforço da morte de Laocon e de seus 
filhos com serpentes. Laocon - alavancas elevadas de Throy - 
estava de encontro a aceitar o cavalo madeira-feito do presente do 
Greeks.Pallas Athene - patron dos gregos -, feito serpentes enormes o 
butch o Laocon suspicious e seus dois filhos de modo que os soilders 
colocados dentro do madeira-cavalo pudessem entrar na cidade de Throy</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il lavoro ritardato di hellenist di Laocon 
Group(This illustra la vita e - lotta di morte di Laocon e dei suoi 
figli con i serpenti. Laocon - alte leve di Throy - era contro 
accettare il cavallo legno-fatto del regalo del Greeks.Pallas Athene -
il patrono dei Greci -, reso a serpenti enormi il butch il Laocon 
sospettoso ed i suoi due figli in modo che i soilders disposti 
all'interno del legno-cavallo potessero entrare nella città di Throy</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η πρόσφατη εργασία hellenist Laocon Group(This 
επεξηγεί τη ζωή - και - προσπάθεια θανάτου Laocon και των γιων 
του με τα φίδια. Το Laocon - υψηλά ανοίγω Throy - ήταν
ενάντια στην αποδοχή το ξύλινος-γίνοντα άλογο δώρων των Ελλήνων
Pallas Athene - ο προστάτης των Ελλήνων -, που έγινε τα 
τεράστια φίδια butch ύποπτο Laocon και δύο γιους του έτσι 
ώστε τα soilders που τοποθετήθηκαν μέσα στο ξύλινος-άλογο να 
μπορούν να μπούν στην πόλη Throy</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El último trabajo del hellenist de Laocon 
Group(This ilustra la vida y - lucha de la muerte de Laocon y de sus 
hijos con las serpientes. Laocon - palancas altas de Throy - 
estaba contra validar el caballo madera-hecho del regalo del 
Greeks.Pallas Athene - el patrón de los Griegos -, hecho las 
serpientes enormes el butch el Laocon sospechoso y sus dos hijos de 
modo que los soilders colocados dentro del madera-caballo pudieran 
entrar en la ciudad de Throy</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>image</value>
          </learningResourceType>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="hu">A tartalom kizárólag kizárólag az oktatás illetve tudományos kutatás céljára használható szigorúan non-profit jelleggel.</string>
            <string language="en">The content may be used for the sole purpose of illustration for teaching or scientific research and only for a strictly non-commercial purpose.</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard 
version:3.0
n:;
fn: 
org:Panem Kiadó
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>856</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
        <metaMetadata>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
        org:Sulinet
        version:3.0
        end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>89393290</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://sdt.sulinet.hu/Player/default.aspx?g=b80bc7ee-cfed-41a3-8187-d72a36fdf68b&amp;v=1&amp;b=4</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
