<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/114502</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>114502</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>oai</catalog>
    <entry>oai:s01.klascement.net:9830</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:s01.klascement.net:9830</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>KC</catalog>
            <entry>9830</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="nl">Telling the time : Bordspel</string>
          </title>
          <language>nl</language>
          <description>
            <string language="nl">Voor een Engelse les over 'telling the time' heb ik een bordspel gemaakt, gebaseerd op het alombekende ganzenbord.Ik heb er ooit een omschrijving voor geschreven in het Engels: The set-upReally plain and simple. The game is based upon one of the all-time boardgame classics: 'game of goose'. Why? Well, its a very adaptable game, with an easy to adapt board and simple - yet for my subject very effective - gameplay. And although it isn't nearly as complex as any other boardgame it does still appeal to children. As a bonus the number of players is almost infinite, although the board will get pretty crowded after a while.What do you need?My selfmade board. On my selfmade board the different spaces of the game trail are replaced by mini-clocks, a 'go 3 spaces back'-space, a question mark space and an exclamation mark space.You also need the little clocks which you can find in the word document attached. You need to print these clocks recto verso and cut them out. So on one side you find a drawing of a clock with pointers and on the other side the written time.Then there are also 'fact cards' and 'do cards' which have to be taken and executed when landing on a question mark (do card) or an exclamation mark (fact card). These cards also have a back and front. On the front you print the tasks or facts about time, on the back the side with the question mark or the exclamation mark.And last but not least you of course need one die and the number of pawns as there are players. Oh yes, the pupils also need a dictionary (at least two per game group).The game playThe game play is very easy. In turns the pupils throw the one die and immediately move the number of eyes on the die. Then they perform the action belonging to that space:- a mini clock: the cut out mini clocks are placed on the 'clock spaces' on the board with the clock face at the top. The pupil looks at the clock and tries to tell the time in front of his fellow players. Afterwards he checks the back of the mini clock to see whether he was right or not. If he was right he can stay on this space. If he was wrong he goes back to where he came from.- Father time does not like you, go back 3 places: speaks for itself I guess. This is inserted to prevent the game from ending too soon and to prevent smarter pupils finishing way sooner than others.- Go back to start: same as the above (idea stolen from Monopoly)- Exclamation mark: the pupil takes a card from the pile of cards with the exclamation mark and reads out the fact about time on the back of the card to his fellow players. This is of course an exercise on reading aloud, pronunciation and they learn something more about time in general and some English culture (Big Ben, Greenwich, Stonehenge etc).- Question mark: the pupil takes a card from the pile of cards with the question mark and reads out the time related tasks on the back of the card to his fellow players and performs it. This is again an exercise on reading aloud and pronunciation but they also have to tell the time in a familiar situation or use their dictionary. When finished with the card they shove it back under the pile of cards.That's it. Of course they have to end right on the hourglass. Not one number of eyes more or less.  Have fun and I'd appreciate it if you could let me know what you think of it! Maybe do some suggestions or help me improve it.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="nl">talen</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="nl">game</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="nl">klok</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="nl">pair work</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="nl">time</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="nl">tijd</string>
          </keyword>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <aggregationLevel>
            <source>aggregationLevelValues</source>
            <value>4</value>
          </aggregationLevel>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <version>
            <string language="nl">2008-10-27 18:54:22</string>
          </version>
          <status>
            <source>statusValues</source>
            <value>final</value>
          </status>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2008-11-03T11:45:49.00Z</dateTime>
            </date>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD 
VERSION:3.0 
N:KlasCement
FN:KlasCement 
EMAIL;TYPE=INTERNET:info@klascement.net 
ORG: KlasCement
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:s01.klascement.net:oai:s01.klascement.net:9830</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>KC</catalog>
            <entry>oai:s01.klascement.net:9830</entry>
          </identifier>
          <metadataSchema>MELTv1.0</metadataSchema>
          <language>nl</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:Klascement
N:Klascement
ORG:Klascement
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T15:37:10.66Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <technical>
          <format>application/zip</format>
        </technical>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>open activity</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">12-19</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <annotation>
          <entity>Lieze Ketelslagers</entity>
          <date>
            <dateTime>2008-12-26</dateTime>
          </date>
        </annotation>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>oai</catalog>
      <entry>9830</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <identifier>
        <catalog>oai</catalog>
        <entry>9830</entry>
      </identifier>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.klascement.net/9830/?ref=aspect</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
