<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222709</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222709</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/lahiverkko</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/lahiverkko</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/lahiverkko</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Local area network</string>
            <string language="fi">Lähiverkko</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lokales Netzwerk</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Réseau local</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Rede de área local</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Rete locale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δίκτυο τοπικής περιοχής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Red de área local</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Local area network is a two-part, interactive learning object, by means of which the student implements local area network cabling and hardware installation for the local area networks appearing in the program, taking into account the EN 50173-1 standard. The aim of the study material is to illustrate the structure of a local area network so that it also meets needs arising in future. The learning object illustrates the requisite devices and cablings and looks for answers to questions arising in connection with installation. Finally, the object provides feedback on whether the solution implemented by the student corresponds to the requirements of the standard, and a summary of the hardware and materials used.</string>
            <string language="fi">Lähiverkko on kaksiosainen, interaktiivinen oppimisaihio, jonka avulla opiskelija toteuttaa lähiverkko-kaapeloinnin ja laitteisto-kokoonpanon ohjelmassa esiintyville lähiverkoille huomioiden EN 50173-1-standardin. Oppimateriaalin tavoitteena on havainnollistaa lähiverkon rakenne siten, että se täyttää myös tulevaisuudessa esiintyvät tarpeet. Oppimisaihiossa havainnollistetaan tarvittavat laitteet ja kaapeloinnit sekä etsitään vastaukset asennuksen yhteydessä esiin nouseviin kysymyksiin. Aihio antaa lopuksi palautteen, vastaako opiskelijan toteuttama ratkaisu standardin vaatimuksia, ja yhteenvedon käytetyistä laitteista ja materiaaleista. Materiaali edellyttää Flash -laajennusta selaimeen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lokales Netzwerk ist eine zweiteilige, 
interaktive erlernennachricht, mittels deren das lokale Netzwerk der 
Kursteilnehmerwerkzeuge, das kabeln und die Hardwareinstallation für 
die lokalen Netzwerke, die im Programm, den en 50173-1 Standard in 
Betracht ziehend erscheinen. Das Ziel des Studie Materials ist, 
die Struktur eines lokalen Netzwerks zu veranschaulichen, damit sie 
auch die Bedürfnisse erfüllt, die in der Zukunft entstehen. 
Die erlernennachricht veranschaulicht die erforderlichen 
Einheiten und die cablings und sucht nach Antworten zu den Fragen, die
in Zusammenhang mit Installation entstehen. Schließlich liefert
die Nachricht Feedback an, ob die Lösung, die vom Kursteilnehmer 
eingeführt wird, den Anforderungen des Standards entspricht, und eine
Zusammenfassung der Hardware und der Materialien, die benutzt werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le réseau local est un objet d'étude en deux 
parties et interactif, au moyen de lequel le réseau local 
d'instruments d'étudiant câblant et installation de matériel pour 
les réseaux locaux apparaissant dans le programme, tenant compte de 
la norme d'en 50173-1. Le but du matériel d'étude est 
d'illustrer la structure d'un réseau local de sorte qu'elle 
satisfasse également les besoins surgissant à l'avenir. 
L'objet d'étude illustre les dispositifs et les cablings requis
et recherche des réponses aux questions concernant l'installation. 
En conclusion, l'objet fournit le feedback en fonction si la 
solution mise en application par l'étudiant correspond aux conditions
de la norme, et un sommaire du matériel et des matières employés.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A rede de área local é um objeto de 
aprendizagem two-part, interativo, por meio de que a rede de área 
local dos instrumentos do estudante que cabografam e instalação de 
ferragem para as redes de área local que aparecem no programa, 
fazendo exame no cliente do padrão do EN 50173-1. O alvo do 
material do estudo é ilustrar a estrutura de uma rede de área local 
de modo que se encontre com também as necessidades que se levantam no
futuro. O objeto de aprendizagem ilustra os dispositivos e os 
cablings requisite e procura respostas às perguntas que levantam-se 
em relação à instalação. Finalmente, o objeto fornece o 
feedback sobre se a solução executada pelo estudante corresponde às
exigências do padrão, e um sumário da ferragem e dos materiais 
usados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La rete locale è un oggetto imparante in due 
parti e interattivo, per mezzo di cui la rete locale degli strumenti 
dell'allievo che legano ed installazione di hardware per le reti 
locali che compaiono nel programma, considerante lo standard dell'en 
50173-1. Lo scopo del materiale di studio è illustrare la 
struttura di una rete locale in modo che egualmente soddisfaccia le 
esigenze che presentano in futuro. L'oggetto imparante illustra 
i dispositivi ed i cablings richiesti e cerca le risposte alle domande
che riguardante l'installazione. Per concludere, l'oggetto 
fornisce le risposte sopra se la soluzione effettuata dall'allievo 
corrisponde ai requisiti dello standard e un sommario del hardware e 
dei materiali utilizzati.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το δίκτυο τοπικής περιοχής είναι ένα διμερές, 
διαλογικό αντικείμενο εκμάθησης, με τη βοήθεια του οποίου ο 
σπουδαστής εφαρμόζει την τηλεγράφηση δικτύων τοπικής περιοχής 
και την εγκατάσταση υλικού για τα δίκτυα τοπικής περιοχής που 
εμφανίζονται στο πρόγραμμα, λαμβάνοντας υπόψη τα EN πρότυπα 
50173-1. Ο στόχος του υλικού μελέτης είναι να 
διευκρινιστεί η δομή ενός δικτύου τοπικής περιοχής έτσι ώστε 
ικανοποιεί επίσης τις ανάγκες που προκύπτουν στο μέλλον. Το
αντικείμενο εκμάθησης επεξηγεί τις απαραίτητες συσκευές και τις 
τηλεγραφήσεις και ψάχνει τις απαντήσεις στις ερωτήσεις που 
προκύπτουν σχετικά με την εγκατάσταση. Τέλος, το 
αντικείμενο παρέχει την ανατροφοδότηση εάν η λύση που 
εφαρμόζεται από το σπουδαστή αντιστοιχεί στις απαιτήσεις των 
προτύπων, και μια περίληψη του υλικού και των υλικών 
χρησιμοποιούμενων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La red de área local es un objeto que aprende 
bipartito, interactivo, por medio de el cual la red de área local de 
los instrumentos del estudiante que cablegrafía e instalación de 
dotación física para las redes de área local que aparecen en el 
programa, considerando el estándar del EN 50173-1. La puntería
del material del estudio es ilustrar la estructura de una red de área
local de modo que también resuelva las necesidades que se presentan 
en futuro. El objeto que aprende ilustra los dispositivos y los 
cablings indispensables y busca respuestas a las preguntas que se 
presentan en la conexión con la instalación. Finalmente, el 
objeto proporciona a feedback encendido si la solución puesta en 
ejecucio'n por el estudiante corresponde a los requisitos del 
estándar, y a un resumen de la dotación física y de los materiales 
usados.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Antti Ahola
n:Ahola;Antti
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Lauri Kurvonen
n:Kurvonen;Lauri
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Datafisher Oy
n:Datafisher Oy
org:Datafisher Oy
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Ulriikka Savela-Huovinen
n:Savela-Huovinen;Ulriikka
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/E7729AA1-757A-7CA3-6FC5-E15031A931A4</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/E7729AA1-757A-7CA3-6FC5-E15031A931A4</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Ilkka Mäkitalo
n:Mäkitalo;Ilkka 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:54:02.76Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>simulation</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>vocational education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">16-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd-nc/1.0/</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>657</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1369</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1289</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>652</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/lahiverkko</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/lahiverkko</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
