<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/78702</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>78702</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/maantieto/jaakausi_1/index.html</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/maantieto/jaakausi_1/index.html</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/maantieto/jaakausi_1/index.html</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Ice age2, The life cycle of a glacier</string>
            <string language="fi">Jääkausi2, Jäätikön elinkaari</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eis age2, der Lebenszyklus eines Gletschers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Glace age2, le cycle de vie d'un glacier</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Gelo age2, o ciclo de vida de uma geleira</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ghiaccio age2, il ciclo di vita di un ghiacciaio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πάγος age2, ο κύκλος ζωής ενός παγετώνα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Hielo age2, el ciclo vital de un glaciar</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Ice age2 -section, Part 1: The life cycle of a glacier shows how glaciers change the landscape. Words and concepts related to glaciers and Ice Age topography are explained in the material.

This material forms part of a broader, Ice age module. The Ice age2 module does not require prior studies.

The Ice age2 section contains exercise tasks. The material also contains additional tasks, which can be done, for example, together with the class in order to gain more in-depth knowledge. There are instructions for utilising the material on each page. Study can be started by doing the related tasks, by watching the animation and the related links, after which the learner can test his/her knowledge. An atlas is required for performing some tasks.

The teaching material is suitable for independent work, but greater benefit is obtained through group work (online discussions). It would be good for the teacher/support person to go through the material in advance in order for him/her to be able to plan the headings of the group discussions and reports.

Macromedia Flash 7 is required for using the Ice age2 material. If this feature is missing (the tasks cannot be downloaded), the update can be done on the website.

This material has been produced for the European Union’s Celebrate project.</string>
            <string language="fi">Jääkausi2 -osio, Osa 1: Jäätikön elinkaari kertoo, miten jäätiköt muuttavat maisemaa. Jäätiköihin ja jääkauden aikaisiin pinnanmuotoihin liittyvät sanat ja käsitteet selitään aineistossa. 

Tämä aineisto on osa laajempaa, Jääkausi -nimistä kokonaisuutta. Jääkausi2 -kokonaisuus ei edellytä ennakko-opintoja.

Jääkausi2 -osio sisältää harjoitustehtäviä. Aineisto sisältää myös lisätehtäviä, jotka voidaan tehdä esimerkiksi yhdessä luokan kanssa tietojen syventämiseksi. Jokaisella sivulla on ohjeita materiaalin hyödyntämiseen. Opiskelu voidaan aloittaa tekemällä siihen liittyvät tehtävät, katsomalla animaatio ja siihen liittyvät linkit, jonka jälkeen oppija voi testata tietonsa. Joidenkin tehtävien suorittamiseen tarvitaan kartasto.

Opetusaineisto soveltuu itsenäiseen työskentelyyn, mutta suurempi hyöty saadaan ryhmätyön kautta (verkkokeskustelut). Opettajan/tukihenkilön olisi hyvä käydä aineisto läpi etukäteen voidakseen suunnitella ryhmäkeskustelujen ja raporttien otsikot.

Jääkausi2 -aineiston käyttöä varten tarvitaan Macromedia Flash 7 – versio. Mikäli tätä ominaisuutta ei ole (tehtäviä ei voida ladata), voidaan päivitys tehdä sivustolla.  

Tämä aineisto on tuotettu Euroopan Unionin Celebrate-projektia varten.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="fi">onsilo</string>
            <string language="fi">sanduri</string>
            <string language="fi">moreeni</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eis age2 - Kapitel, Teil 1: Der Lebenszyklus
eines Gletschers zeigt, wie Gletscher die Landschaft ändern. 
Die Wörter und Konzepte, die auf Gletschern in Verbindung 
gestanden werden und Eiszeittopographie werden in den material.This 
Materialformen zerteilen von einem ausgedehnterem, Eiszeitmodul 
erklärt. Das Modul des Eises age2 benötigt nicht vorheriges 
Kapitel des studies.The Eises age2 enthält Übung Aufgaben. Das
Material enthält auch zusätzliche Aufgaben, die erfolgt werden 
können, z.B. zusammen mit der Kategorie, um eingehenderes Wissen zu 
gewinnen. Es gibt Anweisungen für das Verwenden des Materials 
auf jeder Seite. Studie kann begonnen werden, indem man die in 
Verbindung stehenden Aufgaben tut, indem man die Animation und die in 
Verbindung stehenden Links überwacht, nachdem kann der Anfänger 
seins/ihr Wissen prüfen. Ein Atlas wird für das Durchführen 
der irgendein tasks.The Lehrmittel ist verwendbar für unabhängige 
Arbeit benoetigt, aber grösserer Nutzen wird durch Gruppe Arbeit 
erreicht (Onlinediskussionen). Es würde gut für die 
teacher/support Person sein, das Material im voraus durchzulaufen, 
damit him/her, um zu können, die Kopftexte der Gruppe Diskussionen 
und des reports.Macromedia Blitzes 7 zu planen für das Verwenden des 
Materials des Eises age2 benoetigt wird. Wenn dieses Merkmal 
(die Aufgaben können nicht downloadet werden), fehlt, kann der 
Aktualisierungsvorgang auf dem website.This Material erfolgt werden 
ist produziert worden für das europäische Union?s feiern Projekt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Glace age2 - section, partie 1 : Le cycle de
vie d'un glacier montre comment les glaciers changent l'horizontal. 
Des mots et les concepts liés aux glaciers et la topographie de
période glaciaire sont expliqués sous les formes de matériel de 
material.This partie d'un plus large, module de période glaciaire. 
Le module de la glace age2 n'exige pas la section antérieure de
la glace age2 de studies.The contient l'exercice charge. 
Le matériel contient également supplémentaire 
charge, qui peut être fait, par exemple, ainsi que la classe
afin de gagner la connaissance plus détaillée. Il y a des 
instructions pour utiliser le matériel sur chaque page. 
L'étude peut être commencée en faisant le connexe 
charge, en observant l'animation et les liens relatifs, 
après quoi l'étudiant peut tester sa connaissance. Un atlas 
est exigé pour exécuter le matériel didactique d'un certain 
tasks.The convient au travail indépendant, mais un plus grand 
avantage est obtenu par le travail de groupe (discussions en ligne). 
Il serait bon que la personne de teacher/support passe à 
l'avance par le matériel afin him/her pour pouvoir projeter les 
entêtes des discussions et du flash 7 de groupe de reports.Macromedia
soit exigé pour l'usage du matériel de la glace age2. Si ce 
dispositif est manquant (charge ne peut pas être 
téléchargé), la mise à jour peut être faite sur le matériel de 
website.This a été produite pour l'Union?s européen célèbrent le 
projet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Gelo age2 - seção, parte 1: O ciclo de 
vida de uma geleira mostra como as geleiras mudam a paisagem. As
palavras e os conceitos relacionados às geleiras e ao topography da 
idade de gelo são explicados nos formulários do material de 
material.This parte de um mais largo, módulo da idade de gelo. 
O módulo do gelo age2 não requer a seção prévia do gelo 
age2 de studies.The contem tarefas do exercício. O material 
contem também as tarefas adicionais, que podem ser feitas, para o 
exemplo, junto com a classe a fim ganhar o conhecimento mais in-depth.
Há umas instruções para utilizar o material em cada página. 
O estudo pode ser começado fazendo as tarefas relacionadas, 
prestando atenção ao animation e às ligações relacionadas, depois
do qual o learner pode testar his/her conhecimento. Um atlas é 
requerido executando o material de ensino de algum tasks.The é 
apropriado para o trabalho independente, mas um benefício mais grande
é obtido através do trabalho do grupo (discussões em linha). 
Seria bom para a pessoa de teacher/support atravessar adiantado 
o material para que him/her para poder  planear os títulos das 
discussões do grupo e do flash 7 de reports.Macromedia é requerido 
usando o material do gelo age2. Se esta característica faltar 
(as tarefas não podem downloaded), o update pode ser feito no 
material de website.This estêve produzido para o Union?s europeu 
comemora o projeto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ghiaccio age2 - sezione, parte 1: Il ciclo 
di vita di un ghiacciaio mostra come i ghiacciai cambiano il 
paesaggio. Le parole ed i concetti relativi ai ghiacciai ed alla
topografia di età di ghiaccio sono spiegati nelle forme del materiale
di material.This parte di un più vasto, modulo di età di ghiaccio. 
Il modulo del ghiaccio age2 non richiede la sezione anteriore 
del ghiaccio age2 di studies.The contiene le mansioni di 
esercitazione. Il materiale egualmente contiene le mansioni 
supplementari, che possono essere fatte, per esempio, insieme al 
codice categoria per guadagnare la conoscenza più approfondita. 
Ci sono istruzioni per l'utilizzazione del materiale ad ogni 
pagina. Lo studio può essere iniziato facendo le mansioni 
relative, guardando la animazione ed i collegamenti relativi, dopo di 
che il principiante può verificare la sua conoscenza. Un 
atlante è richiesto per l'effettuazione del materiale didattico di 
qualche tasks.The è adatto a lavoro indipendente, ma il più notevole
beneficio è ottenuto attraverso il lavoro de gruppo (discussioni in 
linea). Sarebbe buono affinchè la persona di teacher/support 
passi in anticipo attraverso il materiale nell'ordine affinchè 
him/her possa da progettare le intestazioni delle discussioni del 
gruppo ed il flash 7 di reports.Macromedia è richiesto per usando il 
materiale del ghiaccio age2. Se questa caratteristica manca (le 
mansioni non possono essere trasferite), l'aggiornamento può essere 
fatto sul materiale di website.This è stato prodotto per Unione Europea 
celebra il progetto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πάγος age2 - τμήμα, μέρος 1: Ο κύκλος ζωής 
ενός παγετώνα επιδεικνύει πώς οι παγετώνες αλλάζουν το τοπίο. 
Οι λέξεις και οι έννοιες σχετικές με τους παγετώνες και την 
τοπογραφία ηλικίας πάγου εξηγούνται στον υλικό Αυτό το 
υλικό αποτελεί μέρος μιας ενότητας ευρύτερης, ηλικίας πάγου. 
Η ενότητα πάγου age2 δεν απαιτεί τις προγενέστερες 
μελέτες Το τμήμα πάγου age2 περιέχει τις στοιχειώδεις 
εργασίες άσκησης. Το υλικό περιέχει επίσης τις πρόσθετες 
στοιχειώδεις εργασίες, οι οποίες μπορούν να γίνουν, 
παραδείγματος χάριν, μαζί με την κλάση προκειμένου να αποκτηθεί 
περισσότερη σε βάθος γνώση. Υπάρχουν οδηγίες για τη 
χρησιμοποίηση του υλικού σε κάθε σελίδα. Η μελέτη μπορεί 
να αρχίσει με να κάνει τις σχετικές στοιχειώδεις εργασίες, με την
προσοχή της ζωτικότητας και των σχετικών συνδέσεων, και μετά ο 
αρχάριος μπορεί να εξετάσει τη γνώση του/της. Ένας 
άτλαντας απαιτείται για την εκτέλεση μερικών στοιχειωδών 
εργασιών Το εκπαιδευτικό υλικό είναι κατάλληλο για την 
ανεξάρτητη εργασία, αλλά το μεγαλύτερο όφελος λαμβάνεται μέσω 
της εργασίας ομάδας (σε απευθείας σύνδεση συζητήσεις). Θα 
ήταν καλό για το δάσκαλο/το πρόσωπο υποστήριξης να περάσει από 
το υλικό εκ των προτέρων για αυτός/είναι σε θέση να 
προγραμματίσει τους τίτλους των συζητήσεων και των εκθέσεων 
ομάδας η λάμψη 7 Macromedia απαιτείται για τη χρησιμοποίηση του
υλικού πάγου age2. Εάν αυτό το χαρακτηριστικό γνώρισμα 
λείπει (οι στοιχειώδεις εργασίες δεν μπορούν να μεταφορτωθούν), η
αναπροσαρμογή μπορεί να γίνει στον ιστοχώρο Αυτό το υλικό 
έχει παραχθεί για το ευρωπαϊκό Union?s γιορτάζει το 
πρόγραμμα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Hielo age2 - sección, parte 1: El ciclo 
vital de un glaciar muestra cómo los glaciares cambian el paisaje. 
Las palabras y los conceptos relacionados con los glaciares y la
topografía de la edad de hielo se explican en las formas del material
de material.This parte de un más amplio, módulo de la edad de hielo.
El módulo del hielo age2 no requiere la sección anterior del 
hielo age2 de studies.The contiene tareas del ejercicio. El 
material también contiene las tareas adicionales, que pueden ser 
hechas, por ejemplo, junto con la clase para ganar un conocimiento 
más profundizado. Hay instrucciones para utilizar el material 
en cada paginación. El estudio puede ser comenzado haciendo las
tareas relacionadas, mirando la animación y las conexiones 
relacionadas, después de lo cual el principiante puede probar su 
conocimiento. Un atlas se requiere para realizar el material 
didáctico de algún tasks.The es conveniente para el trabajo 
independiente, pero la mayor ventaja se obtiene a través del trabajo del
grupo (discusiones en línea). Sería bueno que la persona de 
teacher/support pase a través del material por adelantado en la orden
para que him/her pueda planear los títulos de las discusiones del 
grupo y el flash 7 de reports.Macromedia se requiere para usar el 
material del hielo age2. Si esta característica falta (las 
tareas no pueden ser descargadas), la actualización se puede hacer en
el material de website.This se ha producido para el Union?s europeo 
celebra proyecto.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Christian Komonen
n:Komonen;Christian
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Arto Hiltunen
n:Hiltunen;Arto
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Margaretha Ehnberg
n:Ehnberg;Margaretha
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Oppomedia Oy
n:Oppomedia Oy
org:Oppomedia Oy
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/316BB89A-74EC-C71B-E467-FBF07B60BFDC</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/316BB89A-74EC-C71B-E467-FBF07B60BFDC</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Annika Ranta
n:Ranta;Annika 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:54:27.01Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>exploration</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>demonstration</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">11-19</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Creative commons Nimeä-epäkaupallinen-Ei muutettuja teoksia 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>540</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>224</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>223</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>543</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/maantieto/jaakausi_1/index.html</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/maantieto/jaakausi_1/index.html</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
