<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/235355</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>235355</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi/perusopetus/liikunta/opetusmateriaalit_eri_lajeista/jalkapallo</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/perusopetus/liikunta/opetusmateriaalit_eri_lajeista/jalkapallo</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/perusopetus/liikunta/opetusmateriaalit_eri_lajeista/jalkapallo</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Football</string>
            <string language="fi">Jalkapallo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Fußball</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le football</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Football</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gioco del calcio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ποδόσφαιρο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Balompié</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Football is suitable for each class level owing to its low threshold for starting. The sport develops physical and motor capacities and social skills through the versatile use of play. The purpose of the website is for the teacher to find quickly and effectively support for the planning and implementation of the content of his/her lessons. The website contains tips organised by age-group for various exercises and games to develop playing skills as well as clear and simple sample lessons consisting of warm-up play, a skill section and the actual game. The samples also include references to the required equipment and tips for the teacher. The website supports Fair Play ideology.</string>
            <string language="fi">Jalkapallo sopii jokaiselle luokka-asteelle sen matalan aloituskynnyksen vuoksi. Laji kehittää monipuolisesti ja leikinomaisesti fyysis-motorisia ominaisuuksia sekä sosiaalisia taitoja. Verkkosivuston tarkoituksena on, että opettaja löytäisi nopeasti ja tehokkaasti tuen oppituntiensa sisällön suunnitteluun ja toteutukseen. Sivustolle on koottu vuosiluokittain jäsennettyjä vinkkejä erilaisiin palloilutaitoja kehittäviin harjoituksiin ja leikkeihin sekä selkeitä ja yksinkertaisia mallitunteja, jotka koostuvat alkuleikistä, taito-osuudesta ja pelihetkestä. Malleissa on mainittu myös tarvittavat välineet sekä vinkkejä opettajalle. Sivusto tukee Kaikki Pelaa -ideologiaa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Fußball ist für jede Kategorie Stufe infolge von
seinem niedrigen Schwellwert für das Beginnen verwendbar. Der 
Sport entwickelt die Systemtest- und Bewegungskapazitäten und die 
Sozialfähigkeiten durch den vielseitigen begabt Gebrauch von Spiel. 
Der Zweck der Web site ist, damit der Lehrer schnell findet und 
effektiv für die Planung und die Implementierung des Inhalts sein/ihr
Lektionen unterstützt. Die Web site enthält die Spitzen, die 
durch Altersklasse für verschiedene Übungen organisiert werden und 
die Spiele, zum des Spielens von von Fähigkeiten sowie die freien und
einfachen Beispiellektionen zu entwickeln, die aus Vorwärmung 
bestehen, spielen, ein Fähigkeit Kapitel und das tatsächliche Spiel.
Die Proben schließen auch Referenzen auf der benötigten 
Ausrüstung und Spitzen für den Lehrer ein. Die Web site 
unterstützt angemessene Spielideologie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le football convient à chaque niveau de classe 
dû à son bas seuil pour commencer. Le sport développe des 
capacités d'examen médical et de moteur et des qualifications 
sociales par l'utilisation souple du jeu. Le but du site Web est
pour que le professeur trouve rapidement et à supporte pertinemment 
pour la planification et la mise en place de la teneur de ses leçons.
Le site Web contient des extrémités organisées par le groupe 
d'âge pour différents exercices et jeux pour développer jouer des 
qualifications aussi bien que des leçons claires et simples 
d'échantillon se composant du jeu de préchauffage, d'une section de 
compétence et du jeu réel. Les échantillons incluent 
également des références au matériel exigé et des extrémités 
pour le professeur. Le site Web supporte l'idéologie de franc 
jeu.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O football é apropriado para cada nível da 
classe devido a seu ponto inicial baixo para começar. O esporte
desenvolve capacidades do exame e do motor e habilidades sociais com o
uso versátil do jogo. A finalidade do Web site é para que o 
professor encontre rapidamente e suporte eficazmente para o 
planeamento e a execução do índice de his/her lições. O Web
site contem as pontas organizadas pelo age-group para que os vários 
exercícios e jogos desenvolvam jogar habilidades as.well.as as 
lições desobstruídas e simples da amostra que consistem no jogo do 
warm-up, em uma seção da habilidade e no jogo real. As 
amostras incluem também referências ao equipamento requerido e 
pontas para o professor. O Web site suporta o ideology justo do 
jogo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il gioco del calcio è adatto ad ogni livello del 
codice categoria a causa della relativa soglia bassa per cominciare. 
Lo sport sviluppa la capienza del motore e di fisico medica e le
abilità sociali con l'uso versatile di gioco. Lo scopo del Web 
site è affinchè l'insegnante trovi rapidamente e da contributo 
efficacemente alla progettazione ed all'implementazione del contenuto 
delle sue lezioni. Il Web site contiene le punte organizzate 
dalla fascia d'età per vari esercitazioni e giochi per sviluppare il 
gioco delle abilità così come le lezioni libere e semplici del 
campione che consistono del gioco di preriscaldamento, di una sezione 
di abilità e del gioco reale. I campioni egualmente includono i
riferimenti all'apparecchiatura richiesta e le punte per l'insegnante.
Il Web site sostiene l'ideologia giusta del gioco.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το ποδόσφαιρο είναι κατάλληλο για κάθε επίπεδο 
κλάσης εξ αιτίας της χαμηλής μεγάλης μονάδας του για την έναρξη.
Ο αθλητισμός αναπτύσσει τις φυσικές και ικανότητες μηχανών 
και τις κοινωνικές δεξιότητες μέσω της ευπροσάρμοστης χρήσης του 
παιχνιδιού. Ο σκοπός του ιστοχώρου είναι για το δάσκαλο να 
βρεί γρήγορα και αποτελεσματικά υποστήριξη για τον προγραμματισμό
και την εφαρμογή του περιεχομένου των μαθημάτων του/της. Ο 
ιστοχώρος περιέχει τις άκρες που οργανώνονται από την κλάση για 
τις διάφορα ασκήσεις και τα παιχνίδια για να αναπτύξουν τις 
παίζοντας δεξιότητες καθώς επίσης και τα σαφή και απλά μαθήματα
δειγμάτων που αποτελούνται από το παιχνίδι προθέρμανσης, ένα 
τμήμα ικανότητας και το πραγματικό παιχνίδι. Τα δείγματα 
περιλαμβάνουν επίσης τις αναφορές στον απαραίτητο εξοπλισμό και 
τις άκρες για το δάσκαλο. Ο ιστοχώρος υποστηρίζει τη δίκαιη
ιδεολογία παιχνιδιού.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El balompié es conveniente para cada nivel de la 
clase debido a su umbral bajo para comenzar. El deporte 
desarrolla capacidades de la comprobación y del motor y habilidades 
sociales con el uso versátil del juego. El propósito del Web 
site está para que el profesor encuentre rápidamente y utilice con 
eficacia para las hojas de operación (planning) y la puesta en 
práctica del contenido de su lecciones. El Web site contiene 
las extremidades ordenadas por el grupo de misma edad para que los 
varios ejercicios y juegos desarrollen jugar habilidades así como las
lecciones claras y simples de la muestra que consisten en el juego del
calentamiento, una sección de la habilidad y el juego real. Las
muestras también incluyen referencias al equipo requerido y las 
extremidades para el profesor. El Web site utiliza ideología 
justa del juego.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Suomen Palloliitto
n:Suomen Palloliitto
org:Suomen Palloliitto
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/BAD514A4-E372-FC40-A28D-5FA7F362E871</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/BAD514A4-E372-FC40-A28D-5FA7F362E871</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Katja Pajuluoma
n:Pajuluoma;Katja 
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:36:08.87Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>guide</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">6-16</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://www.edu.fi/prime102.aspx</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>974</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>987</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1285</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi/perusopetus/liikunta/opetusmateriaalit_eri_lajeista/jalkapallo</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/perusopetus/liikunta/opetusmateriaalit_eri_lajeista/jalkapallo</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
