<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222886</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222886</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi/page.asp?path=498,1329,1522,84175</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/page.asp?path=498,1329,1522,84175</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/page.asp?path=498,1329,1522,84175</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Miina, Ville and the riddle of culture - teacher’s guide</string>
            <string language="fi">Miina, Ville ja kulttuurin arvoitus - opettajan opas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Miina, Ville und das Rätsel der Kultur - 
teacher?s Anleitung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Miina, Ville et l'énigme de la culture - guide de
teacher?s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Miina, Ville e o riddle da cultura - guia dos 
teacher?s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Miina, Ville ed il riddle di coltura - guida dei 
teacher?s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Miina, Ville και το αίνιγμα του πολιτισμού - 
teacher?s οδηγός</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Miina, Ville y la criba de la cultura - guía de 
los teacher?s</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Miina, Ville and the riddle of culture is a textbook on ethics, which is intended for use mainly in lessons for classes 4 and 5. The book corresponds in content to course E in the national core curriculum. The purpose of the pictures, questions and stories in the book is to encourage pupils to think and discuss, and its core objective is for pupils to acquire skill at good thinking. The themes cover the fifth part of the syllabus of six hours per week in years 1−5. The book can be used as support for study in various combined groups in classes 1−5, but it is best suited to fifth-graders. The content of the book is grouped in accordance with the four subject areas of the curriculum so that one theme from each is discussed: Relationships and moral growth: Freedom of thought, Self-knowledge and cultural identity: Culture, Community and human rights: Equality and peace, as well as Man and the world: Sustainable development.</string>
            <string language="fi">Miina, Ville ja kulttuurin arvoitus on elämänkatsomustiedon oppikirja, joka on tarkoitettu käytettäväksi lähinnä 4. ja 5. luokan tunneilla. Kirja vastaa sisällöltään opetussuunnitelman perusteiden kurssia E. Kirjan kuvien, kysymysten ja kertomusten tarkoitus on virittää pohtimaan ja keskustelemaan, ja sen keskeinen tavoite on oppilaille muodostuva hyvä ajattelun taito. Teemat kattavat 1−5 vuosiluokkien kuuden viikkotunnin oppimäärästä viidennen osuuden. Kirjaa voi käyttää opiskelun tukena erilaisissa 1.−5.-luokkien yhdysryhmissä, mutta parhaiten se soveltuu noin viidesluokkalaisille. Kirjan sisältö on ryhmitelty opetussuunnitelman neljän aihepiirin mukaisesti niin, että jokaisesta on esillä yksi teema: Ihmissuhteet ja moraalinen kasvu: Ajattelun vapaus, Itsetuntemus ja kulttuuri-identiteetti: Kulttuuri, Yhteisö ja ihmisoikeudet: Tasa-arvo ja rauha, sekä Ihminen ja maailma: Kestävä kehitys.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Miina, Ville und das Rätsel der Kultur ist ein 
Lehrbuch auf Ethik, die für Gebrauch hauptsächlich in den Lektionen 
für Kategorien 4 und 5 bestimmt ist. Das Buch entspricht im 
Inhalt Kurs E im nationalen Kernlehrplan. Der Zweck der 
Abbildungen, der Fragen und der Geschichten im Buch ist, Schüler 
anzuregen zu denken und zu behandeln, und sein Kernlernziel ist, damit
Pupillen Fähigkeit am guten Denken erwerben. Die Themen 
umfassen das fünfte Teil des Syllabus von sechs Stunden pro Woche in 
den Jahren 1?5. Das Buch kann als Support für Studie in den 
verschiedenen kombinierten Gruppen in den Kategorien 1?5 benutzt 
werden, aber es wird gut zu den Fünftsortierern entsprochen. 
Der Inhalt des Buches wird in der Übereinstimmung mit den vier 
Bereichen des Lehrplans so gruppiert, daß ein Thema von jedem 
behandelt wird: Verhältnisse und moralisches Wachstum: 
Freiheit des Gedankens, des Self-knowledge und der kulturellen 
Identität: Kultur, Gemeinschaft und menschliche Rechte: 
Gleichheit und Frieden, sowie Mann und die Welt: 
Stützbare Entwicklung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Miina, Ville et l'énigme de la culture est un 
manuel sur l'éthique, qui est destinée pour l'usage principalement 
dans les leçons pour les classes 4 et 5. Le livre correspond 
dans le contenu au cours E du programme d'études national de noyau. 
Le but des images, des questions et des histoires dans le livre 
est d'encourager des élèves à penser et discuter, et son objectif 
de noyau est pour que les pupilles saisissent la compétence à la 
bonne pensée. Les thèmes couvrent la cinquième partie du 
programme de six heures par semaine en années 1?5. Le livre 
peut être utilisé comme support pour l'étude dans divers groupes 
combinés dans les classes 1?5, mais il est plus adapté aux 
cinquième-niveleuses. La teneur du livre est groupée selon les
quatre domaines du programme d'études de sorte qu'un thème de chacun
soit discuté : Rapports et croissance morale : Liberté 
de pensée, de art de l'auto-portrait-knowledge et d'identité culturelle : 
Culture, Communauté et droits de l'homme : Égalité et 
paix, aussi bien que l'homme et le monde : Développement 
soutenable.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Miina, Ville e o riddle da cultura são um 
textbook no ethics, que é pretendido para o uso principalmente nas 
lições para as classes 4 e 5. O livro corresponde no índice 
ao curso E no curriculum nacional do núcleo. A finalidade dos 
retratos, das perguntas e das histórias no livro é incentivar os 
alunos pensar e discutir, e seu objetivo do núcleo é para que as 
pupilas adquiram a habilidade em pensar bom. Os temas cobrem a 
quinta parte do syllabus de seis horas por a semana nos anos 1?5. 
O livro pode ser usado como a sustentação para o estudo em 
vários grupos combinados nas classes 1?5, mas é servido melhor aos 
quinto-graduadores. O índice do livro é agrupado de acordo com
as quatro áreas sujeitas do curriculum de modo que um tema de cada um
seja discutido: Relacionamentos e crescimento moral: 
Liberdade do pensamento, do self-knowledge e da identidade 
cultural: Cultura, comunidade e direitas humanas: 
Igualdade e paz, as.well.as o homem e o mundo: 
Desenvolvimento sustainable.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Miina, Ville ed il riddle di coltura è un manuale
sull'etica, che è intesa per uso pricipalmente nelle lezioni per i 
codici categoria 4 e 5. Il libro corrisponde nel soddisfare al 
corso E nel programma di studi nazionale di nucleo. Lo scopo 
delle immagini, delle domande e delle storia nel libro è consigliare 
agli allievi pensare e discutere ed il relativo obiettivo di nucleo è
affinchè le pupille acquisti l'abilità a buon pensare. I temi 
riguardano la quinta parte del programma di sei ore alla settimana 
durante gli anni 1?5. Il libro può essere usato come supporto 
per lo studio in vari gruppi uniti nei codici categoria 1?5, ma è 
più adatto ai quinto-selezionatori. Il contenuto del libro è 
raggruppato in conformità con i quattro settori del programma di 
studi in moda da discutere un tema da ciascuno: Rapporti e 
sviluppo morale: Libertà di pensiero, di autocoscienza e 
dell'identità culturale: Coltura, Comunità e diritti 
dell'uomo: Uguaglianza e pace, così come l'uomo ed il mondo: 
Sviluppo sostenibile.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Miina, Ville και το αίνιγμα του πολιτισμού 
είναι ένα εγχειρίδιο στην ηθική, η οποία προορίζεται για τη 
χρήση κυρίως στα μαθήματα για τις κλάσεις 4 και 5. Το 
βιβλίο αντιστοιχεί στο περιεχόμενο στη σειρά μαθημάτων ε στο 
εθνικό πρόγραμμα σπουδών πυρήνων. Ο σκοπός των εικόνων, 
των ερωτήσεων και των ιστοριών στο βιβλίο είναι να ενθαρρυνθούν 
οι μαθητές για να σκεφτεί και να συζητήσει, και ο στόχος πυρήνων 
του είναι για τους μαθητές να αποκτήσει την ικανότητα στην καλή 
σκέψη. Τα θέματα καλύπτουν το πέμπτο μέρος της διδακτέας 
ύλης έξι ωρών την εβδομάδα στα έτη 1?5. Το βιβλίο 
μπορεί να χρησιμοποιηθεί ως υποστήριξη για τη μελέτη στις 
διάφορες συνδυασμένες ομάδες στις κλάσεις 1?5, αλλά είναι 
καταλληλότερο στα γκρέιντερ-γκρέιντερ. Το περιεχόμενο του 
βιβλίου ομαδοποιείται σύμφωνα με τις τέσσερις θεματικές περιοχές
του προγράμματος σπουδών έτσι ώστε ένα θέμα από κάθε ένα 
συζητείται: Σχέσεις και ηθική αύξηση: Ελευθερία της 
σκέψης, self-knowledge και της πολιτιστικής ταυτότητας: Τα
κοινοτικών και ανθρώπινων δικαιώματα πολιτισμού,: Ισότητα 
και ειρήνη, καθώς επίσης και άτομο και ο κόσμος: Βιώσιμη 
ανάπτυξη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Miina, Ville y la criba de la cultura es un libro 
de textos en el ética, que se piensa para el uso principalmente en 
las lecciones para las clases 4 y 5. El libro corresponde en 
contenido al curso E en el plan de estudios nacional de la base. 
El propósito de los cuadros, de las preguntas y de las 
historias en el libro es animar a pupilas que piensen y discutan, y su
objetivo de la base está para que las pupilas adquieran habilidad en 
el buen pensamiento. Los temas cubren la quinto parte del 
programa de seis horas por semana en los años 1?5. El libro se 
puede utilizar como ayuda para el estudio en varios grupos combinados 
en las clases 1?5, pero se satisface lo más mejor posible a los 
quinto-graduadores. El contenido del libro se agrupa de acuerdo 
con los cuatro temas del plan de estudios para discutir un tema de 
cada uno: Lazos y crecimiento moral: Libertad del 
pensamiento, del conocimiento de sí mismo y de la identidad cultural:
Cultura, comunidad y derechos humanos: Igualdad y paz, 
así como hombre y el mundo: Desarrollo sostenible.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Ritva Tuominen
n:Tuominen;Ritva
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Satu Honkala
n:Honkala;Satu
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/3BFD6DEB-ADBE-D3ED-AE7B-46A6E7BABCC4</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/3BFD6DEB-ADBE-D3ED-AE7B-46A6E7BABCC4</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Annika Ranta
n:Ranta;Annika 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-03-14T00:44:15.89Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>open activity</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">7-12</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Nimeä - Epäkaupallinen - Ei muutettuja teoksia 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>388</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>441</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>303</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>299</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1024</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi/page.asp?path=498,1329,1522,84175</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/page.asp?path=498,1329,1522,84175</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
