<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222891</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222891</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi/page.asp?path=498;1329;1528;21094;19155;39424</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/page.asp?path=498;1329;1528;21094;19155;39424</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/page.asp?path=498;1329;1528;21094;19155;39424</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Handball</string>
            <string language="fi">Käsipallo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Handball</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Handball</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Handball</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Handball</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Χάντμπολ</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Balonmano</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Handball is an easy and fun game for pupils of all ages and skills. Players usually get into the swing of the game quickly in the very first practice session. The game can be adapted for a small hall and with adapted equipment. The purpose of the website is for the teacher to find quickly and effectively support for the planning and implementation of the content of his/her lessons. The website consists of instructions for the teacher, descriptions of the rules and main skills of the game as well as instructions and tips organised by age-group for various forms of the game, exercises and ball games to develop handball skills, the purpose of which is to help the teacher to choose appropriate teaching contents.</string>
            <string language="fi">Käsipallo on helppo ja hauska peli kaikenikäisille ja -taitoisille oppilaille. Sujuvaan peliin päästään yleensä nopeasti heti ensimmäisellä harjoittelukerralla. Peliä voi soveltaen pelata pienessäkin salissa ja sovelletuin välinein. Verkkosivuston tarkoituksena on, että opettaja löytäisi nopeasti ja tehokkaasti tuen oppituntiensa sisällön suunnitteluun ja toteutukseen. Sivusto koostuu ohjeista opettajalle, pelin sääntöjen ja keskeisten taitojen kuvauksista sekä vuosiluokittain jäsennetyistä ohjeista ja vinkeistä erilaisiin pelimuotoihin, lajiharjoitteisiin ja käsipallotaitoja kehittäviin palloleikkeihin, joiden tarkoituksena on auttaa opettajaa tarkoituksenmukaisten opetussisältöjen valitsemisessa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Handball ist ein einfaches und Spaßspiel für 
Pupillen alles Alters und Fähigkeiten. Spieler erhalten 
normalerweise in das Schwingen des Spiels schnell in der allerersten 
Praxissitzung. Das Spiel kann für eine kleine Halle und mit 
angepaßter Ausrüstung angepaßt werden. Der Zweck der Web site
ist, damit der Lehrer schnell findet und effektiv für die Planung und
die Implementierung des Inhalts sein/ihr Lektionen unterstützt. 
Die Web site besteht aus Anweisungen für den Lehrer, 
Beschreibungen der Richtlinien und Hauptfähigkeiten des Spiels sowie 
Anweisungen und die Spitzen, die durch Altersklasse für verschiedene 
Formulare des Spiels, der Übungen und der Kugelspiele organisiert 
werden, um Handballfähigkeiten zu entwickeln, dessen Zweck ist, dem 
Lehrer zu helfen, passenden unterrichtenden Inhalt zu wählen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le handball est un jeu facile et d'amusement pour 
des pupilles de tous les âges et qualifications. Les joueurs 
entrent habituellement dans l'oscillation du jeu rapidement en toute 
première session de pratique. Le jeu peut être adapté pour un
petit hall et avec le matériel adapté. Le but du site Web est 
pour que le professeur trouve rapidement et à supporte pertinemment 
pour la planification et la mise en place de la teneur de ses leçons.
Le site Web se compose des instructions pour le professeur, des 
descriptions des règles et des qualifications principales du jeu 
aussi bien que des instructions et des extrémités organisées par le
groupe d'âge pour différentes formes du jeu, des exercices et des 
jeux de boule pour développer les qualifications de handball, dont le
but est d'aider le professeur à choisir le contenu d'enseignement 
approprié.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O handball é um jogo fácil e do divertimento 
para as pupilas de todas as idades e habilidades. Os jogadores 
começam geralmente no balanço do jogo rapidamente muito na primeira 
sessão da prática. O jogo pode ser adaptado para um salão 
pequeno e com equipamento adaptado. A finalidade do Web site é 
para que o professor encontre rapidamente e suporte eficazmente para o
planeamento e a execução do índice de his/her lições. O Web
site consiste em instruções para o professor, descrições das 
réguas e habilidades principais do jogo as.well.as instruções e 
pontas organizadas pelo age-group para vários formulários do jogo, 
dos exercícios e dos jogos da esfera para desenvolver as habilidades 
do handball, a finalidade de que é ajudar ao professor escolher 
índices ensinando apropriados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il handball è un gioco di divertimento e facile 
per le pupille di tutte le età ed abilità. I giocatori entrano
solitamente rapidamente nell'oscillazione del gioco nella primissima 
sessione di pratica. Il gioco può essere adattato per un 
piccolo corridoio e con apparecchiatura adattata. Lo scopo del 
Web site è affinchè l'insegnante trovi rapidamente e da contributo 
efficacemente alla progettazione ed all'implementazione del contenuto 
delle sue lezioni. Il Web site consiste delle istruzioni per 
l'insegnante, descrizioni delle regole ed abilità principali del 
gioco così come le istruzioni e punte organizzate dalla fascia d'età
per varie forme del gioco, delle esercitazioni e dei giochi della 
sfera per sviluppare le abilità di handball, lo scopo di cui è 
aiutare l'insegnante a scegliere il soddisfare d'istruzione adatto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το χάντμπολ είναι ένα εύκολο και παιχνίδι 
διασκέδασης για τους μαθητές όλων των ηλικιών και των δεξιοτήτων.
Οι παίκτες παίρνουν συνήθως στην ταλάντευση του παιχνιδιού 
γρήγορα στην πρώτη -πρώτη περίοδο επικοινωνίας πρακτικής. 
Το παιχνίδι μπορεί να προσαρμοστεί για μια μικρή αίθουσα 
και με τον προσαρμοσμένο εξοπλισμό. Ο σκοπός του ιστοχώρου 
είναι για το δάσκαλο να βρεί γρήγορα και αποτελεσματικά 
υποστήριξη για τον προγραμματισμό και την εφαρμογή του 
περιεχομένου των μαθημάτων του/της. Ο ιστοχώρος αποτελείται 
από τις οδηγίες για το δάσκαλο, τις περιγραφές των κανόνων και 
τις βασικές δεξιότητες του παιχνιδιού καθώς επίσης και των 
οδηγιών και τις άκρες που οργανώνονται από την κλάση για τις 
διάφορες μορφές του παιχνιδιού, των ασκήσεων και των παιχνιδιών 
σφαιρών για να αναπτύξουν τις δεξιότητες χάντμπολ, ο σκοπός των 
οποίων είναι να ενισχυθεί ο δάσκαλος για να επιλέξει το 
κατάλληλο περιεχόμενο διδασκαλίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El balonmano es un juego fácil y de la diversión
para las pupilas de todas las edades y habilidades. Los 
jugadores consiguen generalmente en el oscilación del juego 
rápidamente en la primera sesión de la práctica. El juego se 
puede adaptar para un pasillo pequeño y con el equipo adaptado. 
El propósito del Web site está para que el profesor encuentre 
rápidamente y utilice con eficacia para las hojas de operación 
(planning) y la puesta en práctica del contenido de su lecciones. 
El Web site consiste en las instrucciones para el profesor, las 
descripciones de las reglas y las habilidades principales del juego 
así como instrucciones y las extremidades ordenadas por el grupo de 
misma edad para las varias formas del juego, de los ejercicios y de 
los juegos de la bola para desarrollar las habilidades del balonmano, 
el propósito de las cuales es ayudar al profesor a elegir contenido 
de enseñanza apropiado.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Suomen Käsipalloliitto
n:Suomen Käsipalloliitto
org:Suomen Käsipalloliitto
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/59656F89-2104-6E35-CC85-5EE0E9027B3F</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/59656F89-2104-6E35-CC85-5EE0E9027B3F</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Annika Ranta
n:Ranta;Annika 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-03-14T00:43:37.61Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>guide</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">6-16</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://www.edu.fi/page.asp?path=498,507,19640</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>1285</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>987</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>974</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi/page.asp?path=498;1329;1528;21094;19155;39424</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/page.asp?path=498;1329;1528;21094;19155;39424</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
