<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/80541</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>80541</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www2.edu.fi/etalukio/kursseja/ranska7</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www2.edu.fi/etalukio/kursseja/ranska7</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www2.edu.fi/etalukio/kursseja/ranska7</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Course 7 : Culture</string>
            <string language="fi">Kurssi 7 : Kulttuuri</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kurs 7: Kultur</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cours 7 : Culture</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Curso 7: Cultura</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Corso 7: Coltura</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σειρά μαθημάτων 7: Πολιτισμός</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Curso 7: Cultura</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <language>fr</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A materials bank of French culture to which students can return at various stages of their language studies. They may improve their knowledge of French culture at the start of their studies: the Finnish basic text provides a secure basis for research, and most of the links contain versions in other languages as well as French. The course sections are independent entities that can be used in any order. The material may be utilised both in individual pieces of work and longer projects. Also suitable for independent study and group work. Includes a test on cultural knowledge.</string>
            <string language="fi">Ranskan kulttuurin materiaalipankki, johon voidaan palata kielenopintojen eri vaiheissa. Ranskan kulttuurin tuntemusta voi kasvattaa jo opintojen alussa: suomenkielinen perusteksti antaa turvallisen pohjan tutkimuksille, ja useimmista linkeistä löytyy ranskan lisäksi myös muun kielisiä versioita. Kurssin jaksot ovat itsenäisiä kokonaisuuksia joita voidaan käyttää missä hyvänsä järjestyksessä. Aineistoa voidaan hyödyntää sekä yksittäisissä töissä että pidemmissä projekteissa. Soveltuu myös itseopiskeluun ja ryhmätöihin. Sisältää testin kulttuuritietoudesta.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="fi">Opetushallitus</string>
            <string language="en">historialliset_henkilöt</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Materialbank der französischen Kultur, zu 
der Kursteilnehmer an den verschiedenen Stadien ihrer Sprache 
zurückkommen können, studiert. Sie können ihr Wissen der 
französischen Kultur beim Anfang ihrer Studien verbessern: der 
finnische grundlegende Text stellt eine sichere Grundlage für 
Forschung zur Verfügung, und die meisten Links enthalten Versionen in
anderen Sprachen sowie Franzosen. Die Kurskapitel sind 
unabhängige Instanzen, die in jeder möglicher Ordnung benutzt werden
können. Das Material kann in den einzelnen Stücken Arbeit und 
längeren Projekten verwendet werden. Auch verwendbar für 
unabhängige Studie und Gruppe Arbeit. Schließt einen Test auf 
kulturellem Wissen ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une banque de matériaux de culture française à 
laquelle les étudiants peuvent retourner à de diverses étapes de 
leur langage étudie. Elles peuvent améliorer leur connaissance
de culture française au début de leurs études : le texte de 
base finlandais fournit une base bloquée pour la recherche, et la 
plupart des liens contiennent des versions dans d'autres langages 
comme le Français. Les sections de cours sont des entités 
indépendantes qui peuvent être utilisées dans n'importe quelle 
commande. Le matériel peut être utilisé dans différents 
morceaux de travail et de plus longs projets. En outre 
approprié au travail indépendant d'étude et de groupe. Inclut
un essai sur la connaissance culturelle.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um banco dos materiais da cultura francesa a que 
os estudantes podem retornar em vários estágios de sua língua 
estuda. Podem melhorar seu conhecimento da cultura francesa no 
início de seus estudos: o texto básico finnish fornece uma 
base segura para a pesquisa, e a maioria das ligações contêm 
versões em outras línguas assim como o francês. As seções 
do curso são as entidades independentes que podem ser usadas em toda 
a ordem. O material pode ser utilizado  em partes individuais de
trabalho e de uns projetos mais longos. Também apropriado para 
o trabalho independente do estudo e do grupo. Inclui um teste no
conhecimento cultural.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Una banca dei materiali di coltura francese 
a cui gli allievi possono ritornare nelle varie fasi del loro 
linguaggio studia. Possono migliorare la loro conoscenza di 
coltura francese all'inizio dei loro studi: il testo di base 
finlandese fornisce una base sicura per ricerca e la maggior parte dei
collegamenti contengono le versioni in altri linguaggi come pure il 
francese. Le sezioni di corso sono entità indipendenti che 
possono essere usate in tutto l'ordine. Il materiale può essere
utilizzato sia nelle diverse parti di lavoro che dei progetti più 
lunghi. Inoltre adatto a lavoro de gruppo indipendente e di 
studio. Include una prova su conoscenza culturale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια τράπεζα υλικών του γαλλικού πολιτισμού στον οποίο
οι σπουδαστές μπορούν να επιστρέψουν στα διάφορα στάδια των 
γλωσσικών μελετών τους. Μπορούν να βελτιώσουν τη γνώση 
γαλλικού πολιτισμού τους στην έναρξη των μελετών τους: το 
φινλανδικό βασικό κείμενο παρέχει μια ασφαλή βάση για την 
έρευνα, και οι περισσότερες από τις συνδέσεις περιέχουν τις 
εκδόσεις σε άλλες γλώσσες καθώς επίσης και γαλλικά. Τα 
τμήματα σειράς μαθημάτων είναι ανεξάρτητες οντότητες που 
μπορούν να χρησιμοποιηθούν σε οποιαδήποτε κατάταξη. Το 
υλικό μπορεί να χρησιμοποιηθεί και στα μεμονωμένα κομμάτια της 
εργασίας και των πιό μακροχρόνιων προγραμμάτων. Επίσης 
κατάλληλος για την ανεξάρτητες μελέτη και την ομάδα εργαστείτε. 
Περιλαμβάνει μια δοκιμή στην πολιτιστική γνώση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una batería de los materiales de la cultura 
francesa a la cual los estudiantes pueden volver en las varias etapas 
de su lenguaje estudia. Pueden mejorar su conocimiento de la 
cultura francesa en el comienzo de sus estudios: el texto 
básico finlandés proporciona a una base segura para la 
investigación, y la mayoría de las conexiones contienen versiones en
otros lenguajes tan bien como francés. Las secciones del curso 
son las entidades independientes que se pueden utilizar en cualquier 
orden. El material se puede utilizar en pedazos individuales de 
trabajo y de proyectos más largos. También conveniente para el
trabajo independiente del estudio y del grupo. Incluye una prueba 
en conocimiento cultural.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">historialliset_henkilöt</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">historialliset_henkilöt</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">historialliset_henkilöt</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">historialliset_henkilöt</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">historialliset_henkilφt</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">historialliset_henkilöt</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Heli Laiho
n:Laiho;Heli
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Eeva Pajari
n:Pajari;Eeva
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Twinkle Oy
n:Twinkle Oy
org:Twinkle Oy
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/E6F79DBD-3341-DDE1-14D0-9ECA42FD5D00</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/E6F79DBD-3341-DDE1-14D0-9ECA42FD5D00</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pekka Pirhonen
n:Pirhonen;Pekka 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:49:23.21Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>glossary</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>course</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>enquiry-oriented activity</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">16-19</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://www.oph.fi/etalukio/kayttoehdot/</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>299</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>520</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>668</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>303</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>518</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www2.edu.fi/etalukio/kursseja/ranska7</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www2.edu.fi/etalukio/kursseja/ranska7</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
