<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/235264</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>235264</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi/perusopetus/historia_yhteiskuntaoppi/liiketoimintaosaaminen</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/perusopetus/historia_yhteiskuntaoppi/liiketoimintaosaaminen</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/perusopetus/historia_yhteiskuntaoppi/liiketoimintaosaaminen</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Business expertise, a series of articles</string>
            <string language="fi">Liiketoimintaosaaminen -artikkelisarja</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geschäft Sachkenntnis, eine Reihe Artikel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Expertise d'affaires, une série d'articles</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Perícia do negócio, uma série dos artigos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Perizia di affari, una serie di articoli</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιχειρησιακή πείρα, μια σειρά άρθρων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Maestría del negocio, una serie de artículos</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">From the 75th anniversary publication of Kauppatieteen yhdistys (Finnish Academy of Management) entitled Liiketoimintaosaaminen kilpailykykymme keskiössä (Business expertise at the centre of our competitiveness), selected articles in PDF format to shed light on the various sides of business expertise. The articles can be utilised in upper secondary education and vocational education in the teaching of entrepreneurship and economics. The articles are suitable, for example, as material for presentations and essays, for use as a reference or as supplementary reading. For teachers of basic education, the articles provide background material for teaching. They help to understand the operations of enterprises and public organisations, also explaining the basics of work in these organisations.</string>
            <string language="fi">Kauppatieteellisen yhdistyksen julkaisemasta 75-vuotisjuhlakirjasta ”Liiketoimintaosaaminen kilpailukykymme keskiössä” valittuja
pdf-muotoisia artikkeleita valottamassa liiketoimintaosaamisen monia puolia. Artikkeleita voidaan hyödyntää lukiokoulutuksessa ja ammatillisessa koulutuksessa yrittäjyyden ja kansantalouden opetuksessa. Artikkelit sopivat esimerkiksi esitelmä- ja kirjoitusaineistoksi, referenssikäyttöön tai oheislukemistoksi. Perusopetuksen opettajille artikkelit tarjoavat taustamateriaalia opetukseen. Ne auttavat ymmärtämään yritysten ja julkisten organisaatioiden toimintaa valaisten myös  työskentelyn lähtökohtia näissä organisaatioissa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Von der 75th Jahrestag Publikation von 
Kauppatieteen erlaubten yhdistys (finnische Akademie des Managements) 
Liiketoimintaosaaminen kilpailykykymme keskiössä (Geschäft 
Sachkenntnis in der Mitte unserer Wettbewerbsfähigkeit), ausgewählte
Artikel im pdf Format, um Licht auf den verschiedenen Seiten der 
Geschäft Sachkenntnis zu verschütten. Die Artikel können in 
der obersekundarausbildung und in der beruflichen Ausbildung im 
Unterricht der Unternehmergeisten und der Volkswirtschaft verwendet 
werden. Die Artikel sind, z.B., als Material für Darstellungen 
und Versuche, für Gebrauch als Referenz oder als Ergänzungsmesswert 
verwendbar. Für Lehrer der grundlegenden Ausbildung, stellen 
die Artikel Hintergrundmaterial für das Unterrichten zur Verfügung. 
Sie helfen, die Operationen von Unternehmen und von 
Öffentlichkeit Organisationen zu verstehen und auch erklären die 
Grundlagen der Arbeit in diesen Organisationen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">De la soixante-quinzième publication 
d'anniversaire de Kauppatieteen les yhdistys (académie finlandaise de
gestion) ont autorisé le keskiössä de kilpailykykymme de 
Liiketoimintaosaaminen (expertise d'affaires au centre de notre 
compétitivité), articles choisis dans le format de pdf pour jeter la
lumière des divers côtés de l'expertise d'affaires. Les 
articles peuvent être utilisés dans l'éducation secondaire 
deuxième cycle et l'éducation professionnelle dans l'enseignement de
l'esprit d'entreprise et des sciences économiques. Les articles
conviennent, par exemple, comme matériel pour des présentations et 
des essais, pour l'usage comme référence ou en tant que lecture 
supplémentaire. Pour des professeurs d'éducation de base, les 
articles prévoient la matière de base pour l'enseignement. Ils
aident à comprendre les exécutions des entreprises et des organismes
de public, expliquant également les fondations du travail dans ces 
organismes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Da 75th publicação do anniversary de 
Kauppatieteen os yhdistys (academy finnish da gerência) intitularam o
keskiössä do kilpailykykymme de Liiketoimintaosaaminen (perícia no 
centro de nosso competitiveness), artigos selecionados do negócio no 
formato do pdf para verter a luz nos vários lados da perícia do 
negócio. Os artigos podem ser utilizados na instrução 
secundária superior e na instrução vocacional no ensino do 
empreendimento e da economia. Os artigos são apropriados, para 
o exemplo, como o material para apresentações e essays, para o uso 
como uma referência ou como a leitura suplementar. Para 
professores da instrução básica, os artigos fornecem o material de 
fundo para ensinar. Ajudam compreender as operações das 
empresas e das organizações do público, explicando também os 
princípios do trabalho nestas organizações.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dalla settantacinquesima pubblicazione di 
anniversario di Kauppatieteen i yhdistys (Accademia finlandese della
gestione) hanno autorizzato il keskiössä del kilpailykykymme di 
Liiketoimintaosaaminen (perizia al centro della nostra 
competitività), articoli selezionati di affari nel formato del pdf 
per fare la luce dai vari lati di perizia di affari. Gli 
articoli possono essere utilizzati nella formazione 
superiore-secondaria e nella formazione professionale 
nell'insegnamento dell'attività imprenditoriale e dell'economia. 
Gli articoli sono adatti, per esempio, come materiale per le 
presentazioni ed i saggi, ad uso come riferimento o come lettura 
supplementare. Per gli insegnanti di formazione di base, gli 
articoli prevedono il materiale di base per insegnare. 
Contribuiscono a capire i funzionamenti delle imprese e delle 
organizzazioni del pubblico, anche spieganti i principi fondamentali 
di lavoro in queste organizzazioni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Από την 75η επέτειο η δημοσίευση Kauppatieteen 
yhdistys (φινλανδική ακαδημία της διαχείρισης) εξουσιοδότησε 
kilpailykykymme το keskiφssδ Liiketoimintaosaaminen 
(επιχειρησιακή πείρα στο κέντρο της ανταγωνιστικότητάς μας), 
επιλεγμένα άρθρα με τη μορφή PDF για να ρίξει το φως στις 
διάφορες πλευρές της επιχειρησιακής πείρας. Τα άρθρα 
μπορούν να χρησιμοποιηθούν στην ανώτερη δευτεροβάθμια εκπαίδευση 
και την επαγγελματική εκπαίδευση στη διδασκαλία του 
επιχειρηματικού πνεύματος και των οικονομικών. Τα άρθρα 
είναι κατάλληλα, παραδείγματος χάριν, ως υλικό για τις 
παρουσιάσεις και τα δοκίμια, για τη χρήση ως αναφορά ή ως 
συμπληρωματική ανάγνωση. Για τους δασκάλους της βασικής 
εκπαίδευσης, τα άρθρα παρέχουν το υλικό υποβάθρου για τη 
διδασκαλία. Βοηθούν να καταλάβουν τις διαδικασίες των 
επιχειρήσεων και των δημόσιων οργανώσεων, εξηγώντας επίσης τα 
βασικά της εργασίας σε αυτές τις οργανώσεις.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">De la 75.a publicación del aniversario de 
Kauppatieteen los yhdistys (academia finlandesa de gerencia) dieron 
derecho el keskiössä del kilpailykykymme de Liiketoimintaosaaminen 
(maestría en el centro de nuestra competitividad), artículos 
seleccionados del negocio en formato del pdf para verter la luz en las
varias caras de la maestría del negocio. Los artículos se 
pueden utilizar en la educación superior-secundaria y la educación 
vocacional en la enseñanza del espíritu emprendedor y de la 
economía. Los artículos son convenientes, por ejemplo, como 
material para las presentaciones y los ensayos, para el uso como 
referencia o como lectura suplementaria. Para los profesores de 
la educación básica, los artículos proporcionan al material de base
para enseñar. Ayudan a entender las operaciones de empresas y 
de organizaciones del público, también explicando los fundamentos 
del trabajo en estas organizaciones.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/B4170390-D234-D0A6-C36A-27099092AAF7</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/B4170390-D234-D0A6-C36A-27099092AAF7</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Katja Pajuluoma
n:Pajuluoma;Katja 
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:35:50.53Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>vocational education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">12-19</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://www.edu.fi/prime102.aspx</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>168</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>429</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi/perusopetus/historia_yhteiskuntaoppi/liiketoimintaosaaminen</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/perusopetus/historia_yhteiskuntaoppi/liiketoimintaosaaminen</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
