<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222990</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222990</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/ammatilliset_kielet/autotalli/fimg/index.html</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/ammatilliset_kielet/autotalli/fimg/index.html</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/ammatilliset_kielet/autotalli/fimg/index.html</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Autotalli [Garage]</string>
            <string language="fi">Autotalli</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Autotalli [ Garage ]</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Autotalli [ Garage ]</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Autotalli [ Garagem ]</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Autotalli [ Garage ]</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Autotalli [ γκαράζ ]</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Autotalli [ Garage ]</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this Finnish-language teaching programme, pupils learn about the tools and professional language of the car industry through the aid of exercises. First the language learner is introduced to the words through pictures, then dives into the rich spoken language and does various things under the guidance of a native speaker. After this, s/he practises the same language material (vocabulary and structures) in various ways through the aid of different types of tasks. The aim of the tasks is for the learner to have to react to the instructor’s encouragements and requests and thereby develop his/her functional ability.</string>
            <string language="fi">Suomenkielisessä ammatillisen koulutukseen kohdistuvassa opetusohjelmassa tutustutaan harjoitusten avulla autoalan työvälineisiin ja ammattikieleen. Ensin kielen oppija tutustuu sanoihin kuvien kautta, sukeltaa sitten rikkaaseen puhuttuun kieleen ja tekee erilaisia asioita puhujan opastamana. Tämän jälkeen samaa kieliainesta (sanastoa ja rakenteita) harjoitetaan monipuolisesti erilaisten tehtävätyyppien avulla. Tehtävien tavoitteena on, että oppija joutuu reagoimaan opastajan kehotuksiin ja pyyntöihin ja sitä kautta kehittämään toiminnallisuuttaan.Materiaalia voidaan käyttää yhtenä kokonaisuutena tai osissa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In diesem Finnisch-Sprachenlernprogramm erlernen 
Schüler über die Hilfsmittel und die professionelle Sprache der 
Automobilindustrie durch das Hilfsmittel von Übungen. Zuerst 
wird der Sprachenanfänger zu den Wörtern durch Abbildungen 
eingeführt, dann taucht in die reiche gesprochene Sprache und tut 
verschiedene Sachen unter der Anleitung eines Muttersprachlers. 
Nach diesem übt s/he das gleiche Sprachenmaterial (Wortschatz 
und Strukturen) in den verschiedenen Methoden durch das Hilfsmittel 
der unterschiedlichen Typen von Aufgaben. Das Ziel der Aufgaben 
ist, damit der Anfänger zu den instructor?s Ermutigungen und den 
Anträgen reagieren und seine/ihr Funktionsfähigkeit dadurch 
entwickeln muß.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans ce programme d'enseignement de 
Finlandais-langage, les élèves se renseignent sur les outils et le 
langage professionnel de l'industrie automobile par l'aide des 
exercices. D'abord l'étudiant de langage est présenté aux 
mots par des images, puis plonge dans le langage parlé riche et fait 
de diverses choses sous les conseils d'un naturel. Après ceci, 
s/he pratique le même matériel de langage (vocabulaire et 
structures) dans diverses voies par l'aide de différents types de 
charge. Le but du charge est pour que 
l'étudiant doive réagir aux encouragements et aux demandes 
d'instructor?s et développer de ce fait ses capacités 
fonctionnelles.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Neste programa de ensino da Finnish-língua, os 
alunos aprendem sobre as ferramentas e a língua profissional da 
indústria de carro através do dae (dispositivo automático de 
entrada) dos exercícios. Primeiramente o learner de língua é 
introduzido às palavras através dos retratos, então mergulha na 
língua falada rica e faz várias coisas sob a orientação de um 
altofalante nativo. Após este, s/he pratica o mesmo material da
língua (vocabulário e estruturas) em várias maneiras através do 
dae (dispositivo automático de entrada) de tipos diferentes de 
tarefas. O alvo das tarefas é para que o learner tenha que 
reagir aos incentivos e aos pedidos dos instructor?s e desenvolver 
desse modo his/her abilidade funcional.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questo programma di insegnamento di 
Finlandese-linguaggio, gli allievi imparano circa gli strumenti ed il 
linguaggio professionale dell'industria automobilistica attraverso il 
sussidio delle esercitazioni. In primo luogo lo studente di 
lingue è introdotto alle parole attraverso le immagini, allora si 
tuffa nel linguaggio parlato ricco e fa le varie cose sotto il 
consiglio di un indigeno. Dopo questo, s/he si esercita nello 
stesso materiale di linguaggio (vocabolario e strutture) in vari modi 
attraverso il sussidio dei tipi differenti di mansioni. Lo scopo
delle mansioni è affinchè il principiante debba reagire agli 
incoraggiamenti ed alle richieste dei instructor?s e quindi sviluppare
la sua abilità funzionale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτό το πρόγραμμα φινλανδικός-γλωσσικής 
διδασκαλίας, οι μαθητές μαθαίνουν για τα εργαλεία και την 
επαγγελματική γλώσσα της αυτοκινητοβιομηχανίας μέσω της ενίσχυσης
των ασκήσεων. Πρώτα ο γλωσσικός αρχάριος εισάγεται στις 
λέξεις μέσω των εικόνων, κατόπιν βουτά σε πλούσια προφορική 
γλώσσα και κάνει τα διάφορα πράγματα κάτω από την καθοδήγηση 
ενός φυσικού ομιλητή. Μετά από αυτό, s/he ασκεί το 
ίδιο γλωσσικό υλικό (λεξιλόγιο και δομές) με τους διάφορους 
τρόπους μέσω της ενίσχυσης των διαφορετικών τύπων στοιχειωδών 
εργασιών. Ο στόχος των στοιχειωδών εργασιών είναι για τον 
αρχάριο να πρέπει να αντιδράσει στις ενθαρρύνσεις και τα αιτήματα
instructor?s και με αυτόν τον τρόπο να αναπτύξει τη λειτουργική
δυνατότητά του/της.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En este programa de enseñanza del 
Finlande's-lenguaje, las pupilas aprenden sobre las herramientas y el 
lenguaje profesional de la industria automovilística a través de la 
ayuda de ejercicios. Primero introducen a las palabras a través
de cuadros, entonces se zambulle en el lenguaje hablado rico y hace al
principiante de lenguaje varias cosas bajo dirección de un nativo. 
Después de esto, s/he practica el mismo material del lenguaje 
(vocabulario y las estructuras) de varias maneras a través de la 
ayuda de diversos tipos de tareas. La puntería de las tareas 
está para que el principiante tenga que reaccionar a los estímulos y
a las peticiones de los instructor?s y de tal modo desarrollar su 
capacidad funcional.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Lingonet Oy
n:Lingonet Oy
org:Lingonet Oy
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/CBEC44F8-29AE-5449-279E-EB08559169FD</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/CBEC44F8-29AE-5449-279E-EB08559169FD</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Terhikki Rimmanen
n:Rimmanen;Terhikki 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:36:26.10Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>vocational education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>special education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">15-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/ammatilliset_kielet/page3.html</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>1369</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>709</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>461</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1322</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/ammatilliset_kielet/autotalli/fimg/index.html</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/ammatilliset_kielet/autotalli/fimg/index.html</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
