<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222932</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222932</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/pesula</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/pesula</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/pesula</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Laundry</string>
            <string language="fi">Pesula</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wäscherei</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Blanchisserie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Lavanderia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lavanderia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πλυντήριο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Lavadero</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The material contains two learning objects on the machines used in an institutional laundry. The material is intended as study material for textile care and is suitable in particular for a textile care operative’s qualification-oriented study. The material serves both as teacher’s support material in contact teaching and as support for independent study. The first object provides basic information on the structure and functioning of a continuous-action washing machine. Students can also practise washing through the aid of a simulator on the pages. The second object presents the factors influencing the wash event and introduces students to washing mechanics in particular. The animations on the pages illustrate the regulation of washing mechanics and the structure of garment washing programs.</string>
            <string language="fi">Aineisto on tarkoitettu tekstiilihuollon oppimateriaaliksi sekä opettajan tukimateriaaliksi lähiopetuksessa että itsenäisen opiskelun tueksi. Se sopii erityisesti 
tekstiilihuoltajan tutkintotavoitteiseen opiskeluun. Aineistoon kuuluu kaksi oppimisaihiota, jotka käsittelevät laitospesulan koneita. Ensimmäisessä aihiossa annetaan perustiedot jatkuvatoimisen pesukoneen rakenteesta ja toiminnasta. Oppimisaihiota "Pesutapahtuma" voidaan käyttää myös muissa koulutuksissa havainnollistamaan pyykinpesukoneen toimintaa ja hoito-ohjemerkintöjen tulkintaa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Material enthält zwei erlernennachrichten 
auf den Maschinen, die in einer Institutionswäscherei benutzt werden.
Das Material wird als Studie Material für Textilobacht 
beabsichtigt und ist- insbesondere für eine Qualifikation-orientierte
Studie der Textilobacht operative?s verwendbar. Das Material 
dient wie teacher?s Hilfsmaterial im Kontaktunterricht und als Support
für unabhängige Studie. Die erste Nachricht stellt 
grundlegende Informationen auf der Struktur und dem Arbeiten einer 
Ununterbrochentätigkeit Waschmaschine zur Verfügung. 
Kursteilnehmer können durch das, Hilfsmittel eines Simulators 
auf den Seiten zu waschen auch üben. Die zweite Nachricht 
stellt die Faktoren dar, die den Wäschefall beeinflussen und stellt 
Kursteilnehmer zu waschenden Mechanikern insbesondere vor. Die 
Animationen auf den Seiten veranschaulichen die Regelung der 
waschenden Mechaniker und der Struktur der waschenden Programme des 
Kleides.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le matériel contient deux objets d'étude sur 
les machines utilisées dans une blanchisserie institutionnelle. 
Le matériel est destiné comme matériel d'étude pour le soin 
de textile et convient en particulier à une étude 
qualification-orientée par operative?s de soin de textile. Le 
matériel sert comme matériel de support de teacher?s en contact 
enseignement et de soutien d'étude indépendante. Le premier 
objet fournit des informations de base sur la structure et le 
fonctionnement d'une machine à laver de continu-action. Les 
étudiants peuvent également pratiquer laver par l'aide d'un 
simulateur aux pages. Le deuxième objet présente les facteurs 
influençant l'événement de lavage et présente des étudiants à la
mécanique de lavage en particulier. Les animations aux pages 
illustrent le règlement des mécanismes de lavage et de la structure 
des programmes de lavage de vêtement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O material contem dois objetos de aprendizagem 
nas máquinas usadas em uma lavanderia institutional. O material
é pretendido como o material do estudo para o cuidado de textile e é
apropriado no detalhe para um estudo qualificação-orientado 
operative?s do cuidado de textile. O material serve  como 
material de sustentação dos teacher?s no ensino do contato e como a 
sustentação para o estudo independente. O primeiro objeto 
fornece a informação básica na estrutura e em funcionar de uma 
máquina de lavagem da contínuo-ação. Os estudantes podem 
também praticar lavar-se através do dae (dispositivo automático de 
entrada) de um simulador nas páginas. O segundo objeto 
apresenta os fatores que influenciam o evento da lavagem e introduz 
estudantes aos mecânicos de lavagem no detalhe. Os animations 
nas páginas ilustram o regulamento de mecânicos de lavagem e da 
estrutura de programas de lavagem do garment.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il materiale contiene due oggetti imparanti sulle
macchine utilizzate in una lavanderia istituzionale. Il 
materiale è inteso come materiale di studio per cura della tessile ed
è adatto in particolare a studio qualificazione-orientato operative?s
di cura della tessile. Il materiale serve sia come materiale di 
sostegno dei teacher?s nell'insegnamento del contatto che da sostegno 
lo studio indipendente. Il primo oggetto fornisce le 
informazioni di base sulla struttura e sul funzionamento di una 
lavatrice di continuo-azione. Gli allievi possono anche 
esercitarsi in lavarsi attraverso il sussidio di un simulatore alle 
pagine. Il secondo oggetto presenta i fattori che influenzano 
l'evento della lavata ed introduce gli allievi ai meccanici di 
lavaggio in particolare. Le animazioni alle pagine illustrano la
regolazione dei meccanismi di lavaggio e della struttura dei programmi
di lavaggio dell'indumento.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το υλικό περιέχει δύο αντικείμενα εκμάθησης στις 
μηχανές που χρησιμοποιούνται σε ένα θεσμικό πλυντήριο. Το 
υλικό προορίζεται ως υλικό μελέτης για την υφαντική προσοχή και 
είναι κατάλληλο ειδικότερα για μια υφαντική 
προσόν-προσανατολισμένη στους μελέτη προσοχής operative?s. 
Το υλικό χρησιμεύει και ως teacher?s υλικό υποστήριξης 
στη διδασκαλία επαφών και ως η υποστήριξη για την ανεξάρτητη 
μελέτη. Το πρώτο αντικείμενο παρέχει τις βασικές 
πληροφορίες για τη δομή και τη λειτουργία ενός πλυντηρίου ρούχων
συνεχής-ενέργειας. Οι σπουδαστές μπορούν επίσης να 
ασκήσουν μέσω της ενίσχυσης ενός προσομοιωτή στις σελίδες. 
Το δεύτερο αντικείμενο παρουσιάζει τους παράγοντες που 
επηρεάζουν το γεγονός πλυσίματος και εισάγει τους σπουδαστές 
στους μηχανικούς πλύσης ειδικότερα. Οι ζωτικότητες στις 
σελίδες επεξηγούν τον κανονισμό των μηχανικών πλύσης και τη δομή
των προγραμμάτων πλύσης ενδυμάτων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El material contiene dos objetos que aprenden en 
las máquinas usadas en un lavadero institucional. El material 
se piensa como material del estudio para el cuidado del textil y es 
conveniente en el detalle para un estudio calificacio'n-orientado los 
operative?s del cuidado del textil. El material sirve como 
material de ayuda de los teacher?s en la enseñanza del contacto y 
como ayuda para el estudio independiente. El primer objeto 
proporciona a la información básica en la estructura y el 
funcionamiento de una lavadora de la continuo-accio'n. Los 
estudiantes pueden también practicar el lavarse a través de la ayuda
de un simulador en las paginaciones. El segundo objeto presenta 
los factores que influencian el acontecimiento de la colada e 
introduce a estudiantes a los mecánicos que se lavan en detalle. 
Las animaciones en las paginaciones ilustran la regulación de 
los mecánicos que se lavan y de la estructura de los programas que se
lavan de la ropa.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Riitta Tammenoksa
n:Tammenoksa;Riitta
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Zento Oy
n:Zento Oy
org:Zento Oy
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/7528DA53-2341-E72D-28D0-3C70812CA6DE</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/7528DA53-2341-E72D-28D0-3C70812CA6DE</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Eeva-Liisa Vihinen
n:Vihinen;Eeva-Liisa 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:55:18.06Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>guide</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>simulation</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>vocational education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">16-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">OPH</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>1387</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1304</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1369</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/pesula</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/pesula</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
