<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222728</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222728</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www02.oph.fi/etalukio/historia/autonomia/index.html</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www02.oph.fi/etalukio/historia/autonomia/index.html</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www02.oph.fi/etalukio/historia/autonomia/index.html</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">History of Finland from prehistory to the era of autonomy</string>
            <string language="fi">Suomen vaiheet esihistoriasta autonomian aikaan</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geschichte von Finnland von der Vorgeschichte zur 
Ära der Autonomie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Histoire de la Finlande de la préhistoire à 
l'ère de l'autonomie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">History de Finland do prehistory à era da 
autonomia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Storia della Finlandia da prehistory all'era di 
autonomia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ιστορία της Φινλανδίας από την προϊστορία στην εποχή
της αυτονομίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Historia de Finlandia de la prehistoria a la era de
la autonomía</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Examines the roots of Finnish people and how the concept of Finland gradually arose. Deals with population, social, economic and cultural history, as well as political history. The history of the Finnish people is connected to the development of the Baltic region.

The material aims to revise and deepen the themes of the optional course in the history of Finland in the upper secondary school, varying the viewpoint from the macro level to microhistory. Contains exercises and matriculation examination tasks in history.</string>
            <string language="fi">Tarkastelee suomalaisten juuria ja sitä, miten käsitys Suomesta vähitellen syntyi. Käsittelee sekä väestö-, sosiaali-, talous- ja kulttuurihistoriaa että poliittista historiaa. Suomalaisten vaiheet liitetään osaksi Itämeren alueen kehitystä. Aineiston tarkoituksena on kerrata ja syventää lukion valinnaisen Suomen historian kurssin teemoja vaihdellen näkökulmaa makrotasolta mikrohistoriaan. Sisältää harjoituksia ja historian ylioppilaskoetehtäviä.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="fi">Suomi</string>
            <string language="en">Suomi</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Überprüft die Wurzeln der finnischen Leute und 
wie das Konzept von Finnland stufenweise entstand. Abkommen mit 
Bevölkerung, Sozial-, ökonomischer und kultureller Geschichte, sowie
politische Geschichte. Die Geschichte der finnischen Leute wird 
an die Entwicklung der baltischen region.The materiellen Ziele 
angeschlossen, um die Themen des wahlweise freigestellten Kurses in 
der Geschichte von Finnland in der obersekundarschule zu verbessern 
und zu vertiefen und verändert die Veranschaulichung von der 
Makrostufe zu microhistory. Enthält Übungen und matriculation 
Prüfung Aufgaben in der Geschichte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Examine les racines des personnes finlandaises et 
comment le concept de la Finlande a graduellement surgi. 
Affaires avec l'histoire de population, sociale, économique et 
culturelle, aussi bien que l'histoire politique. L'histoire des 
personnes finlandaises est reliée au développement des objectifs 
matériels baltiques de region.The pour mettre à jour et approfondir 
les thèmes du cours facultatif de l'histoire de la Finlande dans 
l'école secondaire deuxième cycle, changeant le point de vue du 
macro niveau à microhistory. Contient des exercices et l'examen
d'immatriculation charge dans l'histoire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Examina as raizes dos povos finnish e como o 
conceito de Finland se levantou gradualmente. Negócios com 
history da população, o social, o econômico e o cultural, 
as.well.as o history político. O history dos povos finnish é 
conectado ao desenvolvimento dos alvos materiais Báltico de 
region.The para revisar e aprofundar os temas do curso opcional no 
history de Finland na escola secundária superior, variando o 
viewpoint do nível macro a microhistory. Contem exercícios e 
tarefas da examinação do matriculation no history.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Esamina le radici della gente finlandese e come il 
concetto della Finlandia ha presentato gradualmente. Affari con 
storia sociale, economica e culturale della popolazione, così come 
storia politica. La storia della gente finlandese è collegata 
allo sviluppo degli obiettivi materiali baltici di region.The per 
modificare ed approfondire i temi del corso facoltativo nella storia 
della Finlandia nella scuola superiore-secondaria, variante il punto 
di vista dal livello a macroistruzione a microhistory. Contiene 
le esercitazioni e le mansioni dell'esame di matriculation nella 
storia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εξετάζει τις ρίζες των φινλανδικών ανθρώπων και πώς η
έννοια της Φινλανδίας προέκυψε βαθμιαία. Εξετάζει τον 
πληθυσμό, την κοινωνική, οικονομική και πολιτιστική ιστορία, 
καθώς επίσης και την πολιτική ιστορία. Η ιστορία των 
φινλανδικών ανθρώπων συνδέεται με την ανάπτυξη της βαλτικής 
περιοχής Το υλικό στοχεύει να αναθεωρήσει και να εμβαθύνει 
τα θέματα της προαιρετικής σειράς μαθημάτων στην ιστορία της 
Φινλανδίας στην ανώτερη δευτεροβάθμια εκπαίδευση, που ποικίλλει 
την άποψη από το μακρο επίπεδο σε microhistory. Περιέχει 
τις ασκήσεις και τις στοιχειώδεις εργασίες εξέτασης εγγραφής στην
ιστορία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Examina las raíces de la gente finlandesa y cómo 
se presentó el concepto de Finlandia gradualmente. Repartos con
la historia de la población, social, económica y cultural, así como
historia política. La historia de la gente finlandesa está 
conectada con el desarrollo de las punterías materiales bálticas de 
region.The para revisar y para profundizar los temas del curso 
opcional en la historia de Finlandia en la escuela 
superior-secundaria, variando el punto de vista del nivel macro a 
microhistory. Contiene ejercicios y tareas de la examinación 
del matriculation en historia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Suomi</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Suomi</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Suomi</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Suomi</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Suomi</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Suomi</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Jouni Kauhanen
n:Kauhanen;Jouni
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Mikko Niemi
n:Niemi;Mikko
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Tytti Niemi
n:Niemi;Tytti
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/D77DD80F-3137-33CC-6015-4558B2E0190E</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/D77DD80F-3137-33CC-6015-4558B2E0190E</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pekka Pirhonen
n:Pirhonen;Pekka 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:50:22.11Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>course</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>glossary</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">15-19</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://www02.oph.fi/etalukio/kayttoehdot/</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>1019</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1378</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>492</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>590</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>298</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>345</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>802</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>126</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www02.oph.fi/etalukio/historia/autonomia/index.html</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www02.oph.fi/etalukio/historia/autonomia/index.html</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
