<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103438</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103438</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203854</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Mathematical and Statistical Models</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematische und statistische Modelle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Modèles mathématiques et statistiques</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Modelos matemáticos e estatísticos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Modelli matematici e statistici</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικά μοντέλα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Modelos matemáticos y estadísticos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Starting Point module discusses teaching with mathematical and statistical models in entry-level geoscience courses. Mathematical models of systems grow out of equations that determine how a system changes from one state to the next and/or how one variable depends on the value or state of other variables. Statistical Models include issues such as statistical characterization of numerical data, estimating the probabilistic future behavior of a system based on past behavior, extrapolation or interpolation of data based on some best-fit, error estimates of observations, or spectral analysis of data or model generated output. This site includes information describing mathematical and statistical models: numerical and analytical, why they are useful, how to use them and examples of their use. There is additional information on Excel, Stella, and interactive on-line modeling environments.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Ausgangspunktmodul behandelt Unterricht mit
den mathematischen und statistischen Modellen in den Eintrag-Stufe 
geoscience Kursen. Mathematische Modelle der Systeme wachsen 
heraus von den Gleichungen, die wie einer Systemäenderung von einem 
Zustand am folgenden feststellen und/oder wie eine Variable vom Wert 
oder vom Zustand anderer Variablen abhängt. Statistische 
Modelle schließen Ausgaben wie statistische Kennzeichnung der 
numerischen Daten ein und schätzen das zukünftige 
probabilistischverhalten eines Systems, das an hinter Verhalten, 
Extrapolation gegründet wird, oder Interpolation der Daten, die auf 
einigem basierten, gut-paßte, Fehlerschätzungen von Beobachtungen 
oder spektrale Analyse von Daten oder von Modell festgelegter Ausgabe.
Diese Site schließt die Informationen ein, welche die 
mathematischen und statistischen Modelle beschreiben: numerisch 
und analytisch, warum sie nützlich sind, wie man sie und Beispiele 
ihres Gebrauches verwendet. Es gibt zusätzliche Informationen 
übertreffen an, Stella und interaktive Onlineformenumgebungen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce module de point de départ discute 
l'enseignement avec les modèles mathématiques et statistiques dans 
des cours de geoscience d'entrée-niveau. Les modèles 
mathématiques des systèmes se développent hors des équations qui 
déterminent comment des changements de système à partir d'un état 
au prochain et/ou comment une variable dépend de la valeur ou de 
l'état d'autres variables. Les modèles statistiques incluent 
des issues telles que la caractérisation statistique des données 
numériques, estimant le futur comportement probabiliste d'un système
basé en fonction après le comportement, extrapolation ou 
l'interpolation des données basées sur le quelque meilleur-s'est 
adaptée, des évaluations d'erreur des observations, ou analyse 
spectrale des données ou de la sortie produite par modèle. Ce 
site inclut l'information décrivant les modèles mathématiques et 
statistiques : numérique et analytique, pourquoi ils sont 
utiles, comment utiliser eux et des exemples de leur utilisation. 
Il y a de l'information supplémentaire excellent en fonction, 
Stella, et environnements modelants en ligne interactifs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este módulo do ponto começar discute o ensino 
com os modelos matemáticos e estatísticos em cursos do geoscience do
entrada-nível. Os modelos matemáticos dos sistemas crescem 
fora das equações que determinam como mudanças de sistema de um 
estado ao seguinte e/ou como uma variável depende do valor ou do 
estado de outras variáveis. Os modelos estatísticos incluem 
edições tais como a caracterização estatística de dados 
numéricos, estimando o comportamento futuro probabilistic de um 
sistema baseado sobre após o comportamento, extrapolation ou o 
interpolation dos dados baseados no algum melhor-coube, estimativas do
erro das observações, ou análise spectral dos dados ou da saída 
gerada modelo. Este local inclui a informação que descreve 
modelos matemáticos e estatísticos: numérico e analítico, 
porque são úteis, como usar os e exemplos de seu uso. Há uma 
informação adicional excel sobre, Stella, e ambientes modelando em 
linha interativos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo modulo del punto di partenza discute 
l'insegnamento con i modelli matematici e statistici nei corsi di 
geoscience del entrata-livello. I modelli matematici dei sistemi
si sviluppano dalle equazioni che determinano come i cambiamenti di 
sistema da uno dichiarano al seguente e/o come una variabile 
dipende dal valore o dichiari di altre variabili. I 
modelli statistici includono le edizioni quale la descrizione 
statistica dei dati numerici, valutante il comportamento futuro 
probabilistico di un sistema basato sopra oltre comportamento, 
l'estrapolazione o l'interpolazione dei dati basati sul qualche 
migliore-misura, valutazioni di errore delle osservazioni, o analisi 
spettrale dei dati o dell'uscita generata modello. Questo luogo 
include le informazioni che descrivono i modelli matematici e 
statistici: numerico ed analitico, perchè sono utili, come 
usare loro e gli esempi del loro uso. Ci sono le informazioni 
supplementari sopra eccellono, Stella ed ambienti modellanti in linea 
interattivi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η ενότητα αφετηρίας συζητά τη διδασκαλία με τα 
μαθηματικά και στατιστικά μοντέλα στις βαθμολογίας εισαγωγής σειρές 
μαθημάτων geoscience. Τα μαθηματικά μοντέλα των 
συστημάτων αυξάνονται από τις εξισώσεις που καθορίζουν πώς ένα 
σύστημα αλλάζει από ένα κράτος στην επόμενη ή/και πώς μια 
μεταβλητή εξαρτάται από την αξία ή την κατάσταση άλλων 
μεταβλητών. Τα στατιστικά μοντέλα περιλαμβάνουν τα ζητήματα
όπως ο στατιστικός χαρακτηρισμός των αριθμητικών στοιχείων, 
υπολογίζοντας την πιθανολογική μελλοντική συμπεριφορά ενός 
συστήματος βασισμένου στην προηγούμενη συμπεριφορά, την παρέκταση
ή την παρεμβολή των στοιχείων βασισμένων σε μερικές καλής 
εφαρμογής, εκτιμήσεις σφάλματος των παρατηρήσεων, ή της 
φασματικής ανάλυσης των στοιχείων ή παραγμένης της μοντέλο 
εξόδου. Αυτή η περιοχή περιλαμβάνει τις πληροφορίες 
περιγράφοντας τα μαθηματικά και στατιστικά μοντέλα: 
αριθμητικός και αναλυτικός, γιατί είναι χρήσιμοι, πώς να 
χρησιμοποιήσουν τους και τα παραδείγματα της χρήσης τους. 
Υπάρχουν πρόσθετες πληροφορίες για Excel, τη Στέλλα, και 
τα διαλογικά σε απευθείας σύνδεση περιβάλλοντα διαμόρφωσης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este módulo del punto de partida discute la 
enseñanza con los modelos matemáticos y estadísticos en cursos del 
geoscience del entrada-nivel. Los modelos matemáticos de 
sistemas crecen fuera de las ecuaciones que se determinan cómo los 
cambios de un sistema a partir de un estado al siguiente y/o cómo una
variable depende del valor o del estado de otras variables. Los 
modelos estadísticos incluyen ediciones tales como caracterización 
estadística de datos numéricos, estimando el comportamiento futuro 
probabilistic de un sistema basado encendido más allá del 
comportamiento, extrapolación o la interpolación de los datos 
basados en algún mejor-cupo, las estimaciones del error de 
observaciones, o análisis espectral de datos o de la salida generada 
modelo. Este sitio incluye la información que describe modelos 
matemáticos y estadísticos: numérico y analítico, porqué 
son útiles, cómo utilizar los y ejemplos de su uso. Hay 
información adicional encendido sobresale, Stella, y los ambientes 
que modelan en línea interactivos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203854</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103438</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/mathematical-and-statistical-models</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
