<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106847</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106847</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212761</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The very latest SOHO (Solar and Heliospheric Observatory) images</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die sehr neuesten SOHO (Solar und Heliospheric 
Sternwarte) Bilder</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les images de SOHO  les dernières (solaire et 
observatoire de Heliospheric)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As imagens muito as mais atrasadas de SOHO (solar 
e obervatório de Heliospheric)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le immagini osservatorio di Heliospheric e solare 
(di SOHO ultime)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι πολύ πιό πρόσφατες (ηλιακό και παρατηρητήριο 
Heliospheric) εικόνες SOHO</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las imágenes muy más últimas de SOHO (solar y 
observatorio de Heliospheric)</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Solar and Heliospheric Observatory (SOHO) project is being carried out between the European Space Agency and NASA. The goal of the observatory is to gather information about and images of the sun and space weather. This site contains the very latest images from the SOHO observatory. Images are available in a variety of sizes to download and a near real-time screen saver of SOHO images is also available for download. Users can also access old images and real-time movies of the sun.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Solar- und Heliospheric Sternwarte (SOHO) 
Projekt wird zwischen der Europäischen Weltraumorganisation und der 
NASA durchgeführt. Das Ziel der Sternwarte ist, Informationen 
über zu erfassen und Bilder der Sonne und des Platzes verwittern. 
Diese Site enthält die sehr neuesten Bilder von der SOHO 
Sternwarte. Bilder sind vorhanden in einer Vielzahl von Größen
zu downloaden und ein naher Echtzeitbildschirmretter der SOHO Bilder 
ist auch für Download vorhanden. Benutzer können alte Bilder 
und auf Echtzeitfilme der Sonne auch zugreifen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le projet solaire et de Heliospheric de 
l'observatoire (SOHO) est mis à exécution entre l'Agence européenne
de l'espace et la NASA. Le but de l'observatoire est de 
recueillir des informations sur et les images du soleil et de l'espace
survivent à. Ce site contient les images  les dernières de
l'observatoire de SOHO. Les images sont disponibles dans une 
variété de tailles pour télécharger et un épargnant en temps 
réel proche d'écran des images de SOHO est également disponible 
pour le téléchargement. Les utilisateurs peuvent également 
accéder à de vieilles images et à films en temps réel du soleil.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O projeto solar e de Heliospheric do obervatório 
(SOHO) está sendo realizado entre a agência de espaço européia e a
NASA. O objetivo do obervatório é recolher a informação 
sobre e as imagens do sol e do espaço resistem. Este local 
contem as imagens muito as mais atrasadas do obervatório de SOHO. 
As imagens estão disponíveis em uma variedade dos tamanhos 
para download e um saver real-time próximo da tela de imagens de SOHO
está também disponível para o download. Os usuários podem 
também alcançar imagens velhas e filmes real-time do sol.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il progetto di Heliospheric e solare 
dell'osservatorio (SOHO) sta effettuando fra l'Ente Spaziale Europeo e
la NASA. L'obiettivo dell'osservatorio è di riunire 
le informazioni su e le immagini del sole e dello spazio espongono 
all'aria. Questo luogo contiene le immagini ultime 
dall'osservatorio di SOHO. Le immagini sono a disposizione in 
una varietà di formati per trasferire e un risparmiatore in tempo 
reale vicino dello schermo delle immagini di SOHO è egualmente 
disponibile per il trasferimento dal sistema centrale verso i 
satelliti. Gli utenti possono anche accedere alle vecchie 
immagini ed ai film in tempo reale del sole.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το ηλιακού και παρατηρητήριων Heliospheric (SOHO) 
πρόγραμμα εκτελείται μεταξύ της ευρωπαϊκής διαστημικής 
αντιπροσωπείας και της NASA. Ο στόχος του παρατηρητήριου 
είναι να συγκεντρωθούν οι πληροφορίες για και οι εικόνες του 
ήλιου και του διαστημικού καιρού. Αυτή η περιοχή περιέχει 
τις πολύ πιό πρόσφατες εικόνες από το παρατηρητήριο SOHO. 
Οι εικόνες είναι διαθέσιμες σε ποικίλα μεγέθη για να 
μεταφορτώσουν και ένας κοντινός σε πραγματικό χρόνο οικονόμος 
οθόνης των εικόνων SOHO είναι επίσης διαθέσιμος για 
μεταφορτώνει. Οι χρήστες μπορούν επίσης να έχουν πρόσβαση 
στις παλαιές εικόνες και τους σε πραγματικό χρόνο κινηματογράφους
του ήλιου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El proyecto solar y de Heliospheric del 
observatorio (SOHO) se está realizando entre la Agencia Espacial 
Europea y la NASA. La meta del observatorio es recopilar la 
información sobre y las imágenes del sol y del espacio resisten. 
Este sitio contiene las imágenes muy más últimas del 
observatorio de SOHO. Las imágenes están disponibles en una 
variedad de tallas para descargar y un ahorrador en tiempo real 
cercano de la pantalla de las imágenes de SOHO está también 
disponible para la transferencia directa. Los utilizadores 
pueden también tener acceso a viejas imágenes y a las películas en 
tiempo real del sol.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:SOLAR HELIOSPHERIC OBSERVATORY
FN:SOLAR HELIOSPHERIC OBSERVATORY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212761</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106847</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-very-latest-soho-solar-and-heliospheric-observatory-images</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
