<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102876</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102876</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086158</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Fire, Fire, Scorch, Scorch!": Testimony from the Negro Plot Trials in New York, 1741</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Feuer, Feuer, Brandfleck, Brandfleck!": 
Zeugnis von den Schwarze-Plot-Versuchen in New York, 1741</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le "Feu, Le Feu, Roussissement, Roussissement!" : 
Témoignage des épreuves de traçage de nègre à New York, 
1741</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Fogo, Fogo, Scorch, Scorch!": Testimony das
experimentações do lote do negro em New York, 1741</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Fuoco, Fuoco, Bruciatura, Bruciatura!": 
Testimonianza dalle prove del diagramma del negro a New York, 
1741</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Πυρκαγιά, πυρκαγιά, scorch, scorch!": 
Κατάθεση από τις δοκιμές πλοκών νέγρων στη Νέα Υόρκη, 
1741</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Fuego, Fuego, Quemadura, Quemadura!": 
Testimonio de los ensayos del diagrama del negro en Nueva York, 
1741</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">On March 18, 1741, the first of a series of suspicious fires broke out in New York's Fort George. When a few weeks later a black man was seen running from the scene of one of these fires the cry went up: "The negroes are rising!" The extent of the plot, or even if there really was a plot, has never been absolutely proven. What is true is that the threat of a slave uprising was enough to send the city's white population into hysteria. Of the 181 people arrested during the "Great Negro Plot," 34 were sentenced to death and 72 were transported from New York. In this excerpt from the trials, several important witnesses provided evidence. Peggy was a white prostitute who lived in the home of John Hughson, a riverfront tavenkeeper and, like shoemaker John Romme, a receiver of stolen goods. Peggy's room was paid for by Caesar, a slave with whom she had a child. Today the trial transcripts are valuable for what they reveal about the shady, waterfront world shared by slaves, free blacks, and poor whites in 18th-century New York.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">An März 18, 1741, brach das erste einer Reihe 
mißtrauischer Feuer im Fort George New York aus. Als einige 
Wochen später ein schwarzer Mann gesehener Betrieb von der Szene von 
einem dieser Feuer war, ging der Schrei oben: "die Schwarzen 
steigen!" Der Umfang eines Plots oder sogar, wenn es wirklich 
einen Plot gab, ist nie absolut nachgewiesen worden. Was 
zutreffend ist, ist, daß die Drohung eines Sklavenaufstiegs genug 
war, zum der weißen Bevölkerung der Stadt in Hysterie zu 
senden. Von den 181 Leuten, die während des "großen 
Schwarze-Plots," wurden 34 festgehalten wurden, zum Tod verurteilt und
72 wurden von New York transportiert. In diesem Excerpt von den 
Versuchen, stellten einige wichtige Zeugen Beweis zur Verfügung. 
Peggy war ein weißes Prostituiertees, das im Haus von John 
Hughson, ein riverfront tavenkeeper und, wie Schuster John Romme, ein 
Empfänger der gestohlenen Waren lebte. Raum Peggys war für 
durch Caesar, ein Sklave zahlend, mit dem sie ein Kind hatte. 
Heute sind die Probeabschriften die wertvoll für was sie über 
das schattige aufdecken, Ufergegendwelt, die durch Sklaven geteilt 
werden, freie Schwarze und schlechtes Weiß in 18th-century New York.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">18 mars 1741, le premier d'une série des feux 
soupçonneux a éclaté dans le fort George de New York. 
Quand quelques semaines plus tard un homme noir était 
fonctionnement vu de la scène d'un de ces feux le cri est monté : 
"les nègres se lèvent!" L'ampleur du traçage, ou même 
s'il y avait vraiment un traçage, jamais n'a été absolument 
prouvée. Ce qui est vrai est que la menace d'un soulèvement 
slave était assez pour envoyer la population blanche de la ville
dans l'hystérie. Des 181 personnes arrêtées pendant le "grand
traçage de nègre," 34 ont été condamnés à la mort et 72 ont 
été transportés de New York. Dans cet extrait des épreuves, 
plusieurs témoins importants ont fourni l'évidence. Peggy 
était une prostituée blanche qui a vécu dans la maison de John 
Hughson, un tavenkeeper de riverfront et, comme le cordonnier John 
Romme, un récepteur des marchandises volées. La pièce de 
Peggy était payée pour par César, un slave avec qui elle a eu 
un enfant. Aujourd'hui les transcriptions d'essai sont monde 
valables pour ce qu'elles indiquent au sujet de l'ombreux, de bord de 
mer partagé par des esclaves, noirs libres, et blancs pâles dans 
18th-century New York.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Março em 18, 1741, o primeiro de uma série de 
fogos suspicious quebrou para fora no fort George de New York. 
Quando algumas semanas mais tarde um homem preto era corredor 
visto da cena de um destes fogos o grito foi acima: "os negroes 
estão levantando-se!" A extensão do lote, ou mesmo se havia 
realmente um lote, não foi provada nunca absolutamente. O que 
é verdadeiro é que a ameaça de um uprising slave era bastante para 
emitir a população branca da cidade no hysteria. Dos 181 povos
prendidos durante "o lote grande do negro," 34 foram sentenciados à 
morte e 72 foram transportados de New York. Neste excerpt das 
experimentações, diversas testemunhas importantes forneceram a 
evidência. Peggy era um prostitute branco que vivesse na HOME 
de John Hughson, um tavenkeeper do riverfront e, como o shoemaker John
Romme, um receptor de bens roubados. O quarto de Peggy era pago 
para por Caesar, um escravo com quem teve uma criança. Hoje os 
transcripts experimentais são mundo valiosos para o que revelam sobre
o shady, do waterfront compartilhado por escravos, pretos livres, e 
brancos deficientes em 18th-century New York.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il 18 marzo 1741, il primo di una serie di fuochi 
sospettosi ha scoppiato in George Forte de New York. 
Quando alcune settimane più successivamente un uomo nero era 
funzionamento visto dalla scena di uno di questi fuochi il gridare
è andato in su: "i negroes stanno aumentando!" Il limite 
del diagramma, o persino se ci realmente fosse un diagramma, 
assolutamente non è stato dimostrato mai. Che cosa è allineare
è che la minaccia di una rivolta slave era abbastanza per 
trasmettere la popolazione bianca della città in hysteria. 
Della 181 gente arrestata durante "il diagramma grande del 
negro," 34 sono stati sentenziati alla morte e 72 sono stati 
trasportati da New York. In questo brano dalle prove, parecchi 
testimoni importanti hanno fornito la prova. Peggy era un 
prostitute bianco che ha vissuto nella sede di John Hughson, un 
tavenkeeper del riverfront e, come il calzolaio John Romme, una 
ricevente delle merci rubate. La stanza del Peggy era paid per 
da Caesar, uno schiavo con quale ha avuta un bambino. Oggi le 
trascrizioni di prova sono mondo de waterfront, l'ombreggiato circa 
rivelano che cosa per importanti compartecipe dagli schiavi, neri 
liberi ed i poveri bianchi in 18th-century New York.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στις 18 Μαρτίου ..1741, η πρώτη μιας σειράς 
ύποπτων πυρκαγιών ξέσπησε στο οχυρό George της Νέας Υόρκης. 
Όταν μερικές εβδομάδες αργότερα ένα μαύρο άτομο 
εβλέίδε τρέχοντας από τον τόπο διαδραματιζόμενων 
γεγονότων μια από αυτές τις πυρκαγιές η κραυγή ανέβηκε: 
"Οι νέγροι αυξάνονταϊ" Η έκταση της πλοκής, ή ακόμα
και εάν πραγματικά υπήρξε μια πλοκή, δεν είναι ποτέ απολύτως 
αποδεδειγμένη. Αυτό που είναι αληθινό είναι ότι η απειλή 
μιας έγερσης σκλάβων ήταν αρκετή να στείλει το λευκό πληθυσμό 
της πόλης στην υστερία. Από τους 181 ανθρώπους που 
συλλήφθηκαν κατά τη διάρκεια της "μεγάλης πλοκής νέγρων," 34 
καταδικάστηκαν στο θάνατο και 72 μεταφέρθηκαν από τη Νέα 
Υόρκη. Σε αυτό το απόσπασμα από τις δοκιμές, διάφοροι 
σημαντικοί μάρτυρες παρείχαν τα στοιχεία. Η Peggy ήταν 
λευκιά πόρνη που έζησε στο σπίτι John Hughson, ενός 
riverfront tavenkeeper και, όπως τον υποδηματοποιό John 
Romme, ενός δέκτη των κλεμμένων αγαθών. Το δωμάτιο της 
Peggy πληρώθηκε από Caesar, ένας σκλάβος με τον οποίο είχε
ένα παιδί. Σήμερα τα δοκιμαστικά αντίγραφα είναι πολύτιμα
για αυτό που αποκαλύπτουν για το σκιερό, κόσμο προκυμαιών κοινό 
στους σκλάβους, τους ελεύθερους Μαύρους, και τα φτωχά λευκά στον 
18$ος-αιώνα Νέα Υόρκη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">De marcha la 18 de 1741, el primer de una serie de
fuegos sospechosos explotó en la fortaleza George de Nueva York. 
Cuando algunas semanas un hombre negro era más adelante 
funcionamiento visto de la escena de uno de estos fuegos el grito fue 
para arriba: "los negros se están levantando!" El 
fragmento del diagrama, o aún si realmente había un diagrama, nunca 
no se ha probado absolutamente. Cuál es verdad es que la 
amenaza de una sublevación auxiliar era bastante para enviar la 
población blanca de la ciudad en histeria. De las 181 personas 
arrestadas durante el "gran diagrama del negro," 34 fueron condenados 
a la muerte y 72 fueron transportados de Nueva York. En este 
extracto de los ensayos, varios testigos importantes proporcionaron a 
evidencia. Peggy era una prostitute blanca que vivió en el 
hogar de Juan Hughson, un tavenkeeper del riverfront y, como el 
zapatero Juan Romme, un receptor de mercancías robadas. El 
sitio de Peggy era pagado para por Caesar, esclavo con quien ella 
tenía un niño. Las transcripciones de ensayo son hoy mundo 
valiosas para lo que revelan sobre el sombrío, de la línea de costa 
compartido por los esclavos, los negros libres, y los blancos pobres 
en 18th-century Nueva York.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086158</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102876</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/fire-fire-scorch-scorch-testimony-from-the-negro-plot-trials-in-new-york-1741</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
