<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108405</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108405</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209784</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Interior of an angle </string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Innere eines Winkels</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Intérieur d'un angle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Interior de um ângulo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Interiore di un angolo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εσωτερικό μιας γωνίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Interior de un ángulo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate the concept of the interior of an angle. The applet shows an angle where the user can drag the points that define it. A free-floating point can be dragged, and any time it is in the interior of the angle it 'lights up' to show that fact. It can be seen that the interior region stretches out to infinity even if the angle is defined by finite-length segments. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die das Konzept des Innerens eines Winkels zeigen. Der
applet zeigt einem Winkel, wo der Benutzer die Punkte schleppen kann, 
die ihn definieren. Ein frei-sich hin- und herbewegender Punkt 
kann geschleppt werden und immer wenn er innerhalb des Winkels ist, es
' beleuchtet oben ', um diese Tatsache zu zeigen. Es kann 
gesehen werden, daß die Innenregion heraus zur Unbegrenztheit 
ausdehnt, selbst wenn der Winkel durch Begrenztlänge Segmente 
definiert wird. Applet kann zum vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch 
mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. 
Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von 
jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den 
benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein 
Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven 
Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent le concept de l'intérieur d'un angle. L'applet 
montre à un angle où l'utilisateur peut traîner les points qui le 
définissent. Un point libre-flottant peut être traîné, et 
quand il est à l'intérieur de l'angle il 's'allume 'pour montrer ce 
fait. Il peut voir que la région intérieure s'étend dehors à
l'infini même si l'angle est défini par des segments de 
fini-longueur. L'applet peut être agrandi à la taille de plein
écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de classe. Le 
après utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant peut lui 
accéder encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la maison ou 
dans la bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion exigée. 
Cette ressource est un composant du projet interactif de manuel 
de la géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem o conceito do interior de um ângulo. O applet mostra
a um ângulo onde o usuário pode arrastar os pontos que o definem. 
Um ponto livre-flutuando pode ser arrastado, e quando está no 
interior do ângulo ele ' ilumina-se acima ' para mostrar esse fato. 
Pode-se ver que a região interior estica para fora à 
infinidade mesmo se o ângulo é definido por segmentos do 
finito-comprimento. O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de 
tela cheia para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. O depois 
de uso na sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo 
o web browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma 
sessão requerido. Este recurso é um componente do projeto 
interativo do textbook da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano il concetto dell'interiore di un angolo. Il applet 
mostra ad un angolo dove l'utente può trascinare i punti che lo 
definiscono. Un punto digalleggiante può essere trascinato e 
qualunque momento è all'interno dell'angolo esso 'si illumina in su 
'per mostrare quel fatto. Può essere visto che la regione 
interna allunga fuori all'infinità anche se l'angolo è definito dai 
segmenti di limitato-lunghezza. Il applet può essere ingrandito
al formato di schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore dell'aula. 
La post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può accederle ancora 
da tutto il web browser nel paese o nella libreria senza l'inizio 
attività richiesto. Questa risorsa è un componente del 
progetto interattivo del manuale della geometria di riferimento aperto
di per la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν την έννοια του εσωτερικού μιας γωνίας. Το 
applet εμφανίζει μια γωνία όπου ο χρήστης μπορεί να σέρει τα 
σημεία που τον καθορίζουν. Ένα ελεύθερος-επιπλέοντας 
σημείο μπορεί να σέρθεί, και οποτεδήποτε είναι στο εσωτερικό 
της γωνίας αυτό "ανάβει επάνω" για να δείξει εκείνο το γεγονός.
Μπορεί να δει που η εσωτερική περιοχή τεντώνει 
έξω στο άπειρο ακόμα κι αν η γωνία καθορίζεται από τα τμήματα 
μνήμης πεπερασμένος-μήκους. Το Applet μπορεί να 
διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με έναν 
προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο 
σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε 
ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια 
εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς 
είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος εγχειριδίων 
γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran el concepto del interior de un ángulo. El applet 
muestra a ángulo donde el utilizador puede arrastrar las puntas que 
lo definen. Una punta libre-flotante se puede arrastrar, y 
cualquier momento está en el interior del ángulo él ' se enciende 
para arriba ' para mostrar ese hecho. Puede ser visto que la 
región interior estira hacia fuera al infinito incluso si el ángulo 
es definido por segmentos de la finito-longitud. El applet se 
puede agrandar a la talla de la pantalla completa para el uso con un 
proyector de la sala de clase. El uso posterior en la sala de 
clase, estudiante puede tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier web 
browser en el país o en la biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. 
Este recurso es un componente del proyecto interactivo del libro
de textos de la geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas
en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209784</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108405</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/interior-of-an-angle</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
