<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108017</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108017</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211715</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Pseudo-nitzschia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Pseudo-nitzschia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pseudo-nitzschia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Pseudo-nitzschia-nitzschia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Pseudo-nitzschia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ψευδο- Nitzschia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Pseudo-nitzschia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Monterey Bay Aquarium Research Institute (MBARI) website provides comprehensive scientific information about Pseudo-nitzschia, an important toxin-producing species associated with Amnesic Shellfish Poisoning. Information is organized into the following categories: taxonomy, morphology and anatomy, chemistry, toxin production, reproduction and life history, motility, ecology and natural history, identification methods, field work, and acknowledgements. The website also has a link to general information about diatoms.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Web site des Monterey 
Bucht-Aquarium-Forschungsinstituts (MBARI) liefert komplette 
Fachinformation über Pseudo-nitzschia, eine wichtige toxinerzeugende 
Sorte, die mit Amnesic Schalentier-Vergiftung verbunden ist. 
Informationen werden in die folgenden Kategorien organisiert: 
Taxonomie, Morphologie und Anatomie, Chemie, 
Giftstoffproduktion, Wiedergabe und Lebengeschichte, Motilität, 
Ökologie und Naturgeschichte, Kennzeichenmethoden, fangen 
Arbeit und Quittungen auf. Die Web site hat auch ein Link zu den
allgemeinen Informationen über Diatomeen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site Web de l'institut de recherche de 
recherche d'aquarium de compartiment de Monterey (MBARI) fournit 
l'information scientifique complète au sujet de Pseudo-nitzschia, des
espèces toxinogènes importantes liées à l'empoisonnement de 
mollusques et crustacés d'Amnesic. L'information est organisée
en catégories suivantes : taxonomie, morphologie et anatomie, 
chimie, production de toxine, reproduction et histoire de la vie, 
motilité, écologie et histoire naturelle, méthodes 
d'identification, travaux sur le terrain, et accusés de réception. 
Le site Web a également un lien aux informations générales au
sujet des diatomées.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Web site do instituto de pesquisa do aquário
da baía de Monterey (MBARI) fornece a informação científica 
detalhada sobre pseudo-nitzschia-nitzschia, uma espécie 
toxin-producing importante associada com o envenenamento do marisco de
Amnesic. A informação é organizada nas seguintes categorias: 
taxonomy, morfologia e anatomy, chemistry, produção do toxin, 
reprodução e history da vida, motility, ecology e history natural, 
métodos da identificação, trabalho de campo, e reconhecimentos. 
O Web site tem também uma ligação à informação geral sobre
os diatoms.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Web site dell'istituto di ricerca 
dell'acquario della baia di Monterey (MBARI) fornisce l'informazione 
scientifica completa su Pseudo-nitzschia, una specie tossinogena 
importante connessa con avvelenamento dei crostacei di Amnesic. 
Le informazioni sono organizzate nelle seguenti categorie: 
tassonomia, morfologia ed anatomia, chimica, produzione della 
tossina, riproduzione e storia di vita, motilità, ecologia e storia 
naturale, metodi dell'identificazione, lavoro di campo e 
ringraziamenti. Il Web site egualmente ha un collegamento a 
generalità sulle diatomee.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος ερευνητικού ιδρύματος ενυδρείων 
κόλπων Monterey (MBARI) παρέχει τις εκτενείς επιστημονικές 
πληροφορίες για το ψευδο- Nitzschia, ένα σημαντικό 
toxin-producing είδος που συνδέεται με την αμνησιακή 
δηλητηρίαση οστρακόδερμων. Οι πληροφορίες οργανώνονται στις 
ακόλουθες κατηγορίες: ταξονομία, μορφολογία και ανατομία, 
χημεία, παραγωγή τοξινών, αναπαραγωγή και ιστορία ζωής, 
motility, οικολογία και φυσική ιστορία, μέθοδοι προσδιορισμού,
επιτόπια έρευνα, και αναγνωρίσεις. Ο ιστοχώρος έχει επίσης
μια σύνδεση με τις γενικές πληροφορίες για τα διάτομα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este Web site del instituto de investigación del 
acuario de la bahía de Monterey (MBARI) proporciona a la información
científica comprensiva sobre Pseudo-nitzschia, una especie 
toxin-producing importante asociada al envenenamiento de los 
crustáceos de Amnesic. La información se ordena en las 
categorías siguientes: taxonomía, morfología y anatomía, 
química, producción de la toxina, reproducción e historia de la 
vida, motility, ecología e historia natural, métodos de la 
identificación, trabajo en el terreno, y acuses de recibo. El 
Web site también tiene una conexión a la información de carácter 
general sobre diatomeas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JENNIFER SHIN
FN:JENNIFER SHIN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MONTEREY BAY AQUARIUM RESEARCH INSTITUTE
FN:MONTEREY BAY AQUARIUM RESEARCH INSTITUTE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211715</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108017</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/pseudo-nitzschia</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
