<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104270</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104270</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212200</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Sources of Common Contaminants and Their Health Effects</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Quellen der geläufigen Verschmutzer und ihrer 
Gesundheit Effekte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sources des contaminants communs et de leurs effets
de santé</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fontes de contaminadores comuns e de seus efeitos 
de saúde</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sorgenti degli agenti inquinanti comuni e dei loro 
effetti sulla salute</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πηγές κοινών μολυσματικών παραγόντων και τους 
επιπτώσεων στην υγεία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fuentes de contaminantes comunes y de sus efectos 
de salud</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This EPA site features a table showing various contaminants, their common sources, and health effects of exposure. Examples include heavy metals, solvents, pesticides, herbicides and PCBs. The site also provides links to information about how to deal with exposure to toxic materials.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses EPA Situationsmerkmale eine Tabelle, die 
verschiedene Verschmutzer, ihre Sourceschaltungen und Gesundheit 
Effekte der Berührung zeigt. Beispiele enthalten Schwermetalle,
Lösungsmittel, Schädlingsbekämpfungsmittel, Herbizide und PCBs. 
Die Site stellt auch Links zu den Informationen über zur 
Verfügung, wie man Belastung durch giftige Materialien beschäftigt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dispositifs de ce site d'EPA une table montrant de 
divers contaminants, leurs sources communes, et effets de santé 
d'exposition. Les exemples incluent les métaux lourds, les 
dissolvants, les pesticides, les herbicides et le PCBs. Le site 
fournit également des liens aux informations sur la façon traiter 
l'exposition aux matériaux toxiques.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Características deste local de EPA uma tabela que 
mostra vários contaminadores, suas fontes comuns, e efeitos de saúde
da exposição. Os exemplos incluem metais pesados, solventes, 
pesticides, herbicides e PCBs. O local fornece também as 
ligações à informação sobre como tratar da exposição aos 
materiais tóxicos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Caratteristiche di questo luogo di EPA una tabella 
che mostra i vari agenti inquinanti, le loro sorgenti comuni e gli 
effetti sulla salute di esposizione. Gli esempi includono i 
metalli pesanti, i solventi, gli antiparassitari, i diserbanti e PCBs.
Il luogo egualmente fornisce i collegamenti alle informazioni su
come occuparsi di esposizione ai materiali tossici.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή EPA χαρακτηρίζει έναν πίνακα που 
παρουσιάζει τους διάφορους μολυσματικούς παράγοντες, τις κοινές 
πηγές τους, και επιπτώσεις στην υγεία της έκθεσης. Τα 
παραδείγματα περιλαμβάνουν τα βαριά μέταλλα, τους διαλύτες, τα 
φυτοφάρμακα, τα ζιζανιοκτόνα και PCBs. Η περιοχή παρέχει 
επίσης τις συνδέσεις με τις πληροφορίες για το πώς να εξετάσει 
την έκθεση στα τοξικά υλικά.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Características de este sitio de EPA un vector que
muestra los varios contaminantes, sus fuentes comunes, y efectos de 
salud de la exposición. Los ejemplos incluyen los metales 
pesados, los solventes, los pesticidas, los herbicidas y PCBs. 
El sitio también proporciona a conexiones a la información 
sobre cómo ocuparse de la exposición a los materiales tóxicos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212200</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104270</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/sources-of-common-contaminants-and-their-health-effects</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
