<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108704</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108704</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206838</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Keys Ranch: Where Time Stood Still</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Taste-Ranch: Wo Zeit Noch Stand</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ranch de Clés : Là où Le Temps Se tenait 
Toujours</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Rancho Das Chaves: Onde O Tempo Estêve 
Ainda</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ranch Di Tasti: Dove Il Tempo Ha stato 
Fermo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αγρόκτημα πλήκτρων: Όπου ο χρόνος στάθηκε 
ακόμα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Rancho De los Claves: Donde El Tiempo 
Todavía Estaba parado</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">tells the story of Bill Keys, whose ranch was the center of a desert network of homesteaders and miners in the early 1900s. At age 15, Keys left his Russian parents' home in Nebraska to work at mills, mines, and cattle ranches. In 1917, he filed on an 80-acre homestead under the Homestead Act and began building the ranch. To support his family, he raised goats, chickens, and cattle; grew fruits and vegetables; and operated a stamp mill.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erklärt die Geschichte der Rechnung Tasten, deren
Ranch die Mitte eines Wüste Netzes von homesteaders und von 
Bergmännern in den frühen 1900s war. An Alter 15, ließen 
Tasten seiner russischen Eltern Haupt in Nebraska zur Arbeit an den 
Tausendsteln, an den Gruben und an den Viehranchs. 1917 
archivierte er auf einem Gehöft 80-acre unter der Gehöft-Tat und 
fing an, die Ranch aufzubauen. Um seine Familie zu 
unterstützen, hob er Ziegen, Hühner und Vieh an; wuchs Obst 
und Gemüse; und funktioniert einem Stempeltausendstel.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dit l'histoire des clés de facture, dont le ranch
était le centre d'un réseau de désert des propriétaires et des 
mineurs au début des années 1900. À l'âge 15, les clés ont 
laissé ses parents russes à la maison au Nébraska au travail aux 
moulins, aux mines, et aux ranchs de bétail. En 1917, il a 
introduit sur une ferme 80-acre sous l'acte de ferme et a commencé à
construire le ranch. Pour supporter sa famille, il a élevé des
chèvres, des poulets, et des bétail ; a accru des fruits et 
des légumes ; et fonctionné un moulin de timbre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">diz a história das chaves da conta, cujo o rancho
era o centro de uma rede do deserto dos homesteaders e dos mineiros 
nos 1900s adiantados. Na idade 15, as chaves deixaram seus pais 
russian home em Nebraska ao trabalho em moinhos, em minas, e em 
ranchos do gado. Em 1917, arquivou em um homestead 80-acre sob o
ato do homestead e começou a construir o rancho. Para suportar 
sua família, levantou cabras, galinhas, e gado; cresceu frutas 
e vegetais; e operado um moinho de selo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">dice alla storia dei tasti della fattura, di cui 
il ranch era il centro di una rete del deserto dei homesteaders e dei 
minatori all'inizio degli anni 1900. All'età 15, i tasti hanno 
lasciato i suoi genitori russi domestici nel Nebraska a lavoro ai 
laminatoi, alle miniere ed ai ranch dei bestiami. In 1917, ha 
archiviato su una fattoria 80-acre a norma della legge della fattoria 
ed ha cominciato a costruire il ranch. Per sostenere la sua 
famiglia, ha alzato le capre, i polli ed i bestiami; ha 
sviluppato le frutta e le verdure; e funzionato un macinatoio a 
pestelli.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">λέει την ιστορία των πλήκτρων Bill, το των οποίων 
αγρόκτημα ήταν το κέντρο ενός δικτύου ερήμων homesteaders και
των ανθρακωρύχων στις αρχές των δεκαετιών του 20ου αιώνα. 
Στην ηλικία 15, τα πλήκτρα άφησαν το σπίτι των ρωσικών 
γονέων του στη Νεμπράσκα στην εργασία στους μύλους, τα ορυχεία, 
και τα αγροκτήματα βοοειδών. Το 1917, αρχειοθέτησε σε ένα
αγροτικό σπίτι 80-στρέμματος στο πλαίσιο του νόμου αγροτικών 
σπιτιών και άρχισε το αγρόκτημα. Για να υποστηρίξει την 
οικογένειά του, ανέθρεψε τις αίγες, τα κοτόπουλα, και τα βοοειδή
αυξήθηκε τα φρούτα και τα λαχανικά  και 
ενεργοποιημένος έναν μύλο γραμματοσήμων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">cuenta la historia de los claves de la cuenta, que
rancho era el centro de una red del desierto de homesteaders y de 
mineros en los 1900s tempranos. En la edad 15, los claves 
dejaron sus padres rusos caseros en Nebraska al trabajo en los 
molinos, las minas, y los ranchos de los ganados. En 1917, él 
clasifió en una granja 80-acre bajo acto de la granja y comenzó a 
construir el rancho. Para utilizar a su familia, él crió 
cabras, pollos, y ganados; creció las frutas y los vehículos; 
y funcionado un molino de sello.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206838</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108704</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/keys-ranch-where-time-stood-still</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
