<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105461</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105461</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087316</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"A Make-Believe World": Contestants Testify to Deceptive Quiz Show Practices</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Eine Bilden-Glauben Welt": Kandidaten 
bezeugen zur trügerischen Quiz-Erscheinen-Praxis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Un Monde de Faire-Croyance" : Les 
contestants témoignent aux pratiques en matière trompeuses 
d'exposition de jeu</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Um Mundo Faç-Acreditar": Os contestants 
testify às práticas deceptive da mostra do quiz</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Un Mondo Di Fa-Cred": I contestants 
testimoniano alle pratiche ingannevoli di esposizione di quiz</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Τύπος-θεωρήστε τον κόσμο": Οι αγωνιζόμενοι 
πιστοποιούν στον παραπλανητικό διαγωνισμό γνώσεων εμφανίζουν 
πρακτικές</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Un Mundo De la Hacer-Creencia": Los 
contestants atestiguan a las prácticas engañosas de la demostración
del concurso</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Television had become the nation's largest medium for advertising by the mid-1950s, when the Revlon cosmetics corporation agreed to sponsor  The $64,000 Question , the first prime-time network quiz show to offer contestants fabulous sums of money. As Revlon's average net profit rose in the next four years from $1.2 million to $11 million, a plethora of quiz shows tried to replicate its success. At the height of their popularity, in 1958, 24 network quiz shows--relatively easy and inexpensive to produce--filled the prime-time schedule. Many took pains in their presentation to convey an aura of authenticity--contestants chosen from ordinary walks of life pondered fact-based questions inside sound-proof isolation booths that insured they received no outside assistance. To guarantee against tampering prior to airtime, bank executives and armed guards made on-air deliveries of sealed questions and answers said to be verified by authorities from respected encyclopedias or university professors. When the public learned in 1959 that a substantial number of shows had been rigged, a great many were offended. One survey, however, showed that quite a few viewers didn't care. Following the revelations, prime-time quiz shows went off the air, replaced in large part by series telefilms, many of which were Westerns. The industry successfully fended off calls for regulation, and by blaming sponsors and contracted producers, networks minimized damage and increased their control over programming decisions. In the following testimony to a Congressional subcommittee, one contestant offered proof that he had been coached, while a second refused to acknowledge "moral qualms" in perpetrating the fraud. A third, a teenager, related how she "goofed" and won a match that she was supposed to tie.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Fernsehen war der größte Medium der Nation für 
das Bekanntmachen geworden, bis zum den Mid-1950s, als die Revlon 
Kosmetikkorporation damit einverstandenWAR, die Frage $64.000 zu 
fördern, das erste Haupt-Zeit Netz-Quizerscheinen, zum Kandidaten der
fabelhaften Summen Geldes anzubieten. Während Revlons 
durchschnittlicher Reingewinn in die folgenden vier Jahre von $1.2 
Million bis $11 Million stieg, versuchte eine Fülle Quizerscheinen, 
seinen Erfolg zu wiederholen. Auf der Höhe ihrer Popularität, 
1958, füllten 24 Netzquizerscheinen -- verhältnismäßig einfach und
billig zu produzieren -- den Haupt-Zeit Zeitplan. Viele nahmen 
die Schmerz in ihrer Darstellung, um eine Aura von Echtheit zu 
übermitteln -- die Kandidaten, die von den gewöhnlichen Bezirken 
erwogene Tatsache-gegründete Fragen innerhalb der schalldichten 
Lokalisierung Stände gewählt wurden, daß Versicherte sie keine 
äußere Unterstützung empfingen. Um gegen das Abgeben vor 
airtime zu garantieren, sagten die Bankleitprogramme und bewaffneter 
Schutz, die Aufluft Anlieferungen der Siegelfragen und der Antworten 
gebildet wurden durch Behörden von respektierten Enzyklopädien oder 
von Universitätsprofessoren überprüft zu werden. Als die 
Öffentlichkeit 1959 erfuhr, daß eine erhebliche Anzahl von 
Erscheinen in Ordnung gebracht worden war, wurden ein großes viele 
beleidigt. Eine Übersicht zeigte jedoch, daß ziemlich viele 
Projektoren sich nicht interessierten. Nach den Enthüllung 
gingen Haupt-Zeit Quizerscheinen weg von der Luft, ersetzt im großen 
Teil durch Serie telefilms, von denen viele Westerns waren. Die 
Industrie wehrte erfolgreich weg von den Aufrufen für Regelung und 
indem sie Förderer tadelte ab und schloß Vertrag Produzenten ab, 
setzten Netze Beschädigung herab und erhöhten ihre Steuerung über 
programmierenentscheidungen. Im folgenden Zeugnis zu einer 
Kongreßunterausschuß, bot ein Kandidat Beweis an, daß er trainiert 
worden war, während eine Sekunde ablehnte, "moralische Qualms" zu 
bestätigen, wenn sie den Betrug verübte. Ein Third, ein 
Jugendlicher, in Verbindung gestanden wie sie "vermasselt" und 
gewonnen einer Übereinstimmung, die ihr binden sollte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La télévision était devenue le plus grand 
support de la nation pour annoncer par le milieu des années 50, quand
la société de produits de beauté de Revlon a accepté de 
commanditer la question $64.000, la première exposition de jeu de 
réseau de principal-temps pour offrir à des contestants des sommes 
fabuleuses d'argent. Pendant que le bénéfice net moyen de 
Revlon montait en quatre années à venir de $1.2 millions à $11 
millions, une pléthore d'expositions de jeu a essayé de replier son 
succès. À la taille de leur popularité, en 1958, 24 
expositions de jeu de réseau -- relativement faciles et peu 
coûteuses à produire -- ont rempli programme de principal-temps. 
Beaucoup ont pris des douleurs dans leur présentation pour 
donner une aura de l'authenticité -- contestants choisis des secteurs
ordinaires des questions fait-basées considérées à l'intérieur 
des cabines insonorisées d'isolement que les assurés ils n'ont reçu
aucune aide extérieure. Pour garantir contre le trifouillage 
avant l'airtime, des cadres de banque et les gardes armées faits les 
livraisons de sur-air des questions et des réponses scellées ont dit
d'être vérifiés par des autorités des encyclopédies ou des 
professeurs respectés d'université. Quand le public a appris 
en 1959 qu'un nombre substantiel d'expositions avait été calé, un 
grand beaucoup a été offensé. Une étude, cependant, a 
prouvé que quelques visualisateurs ne se sont pas inquiétés. 
Après les révélations, les expositions de jeu de 
principal-temps sont allées outre de l'air, substitué dans la grande
partie par les telefilms de série, dont beaucoup étaient Westerns. 
L'industrie a avec succès défendu outre des appels pour le 
règlement, et en blâmant des commanditaires et a contracté des 
producteurs, les réseaux ont réduit au minimum des dommages et ont 
augmenté leur contrôle des décisions de programmation. Dans 
le témoignage suivant à un sous-comité congressionnel, un 
contestant a offert la preuve qu'il avait été donné des leçons 
particulières, alors qu'une seconde refusait de reconnaître "des 
scrupules moraux" en commettant la fraude. Un tiers, un 
adolescent, associé comment elle "ratée son coup" et gagnée une 
allumette qu'elle a été censée attacher.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A televisão tinha-se transformado o media o maior
da nação para anunciar pelos mid-1950s, quando o corporation dos 
cosméticos de Revlon concordou patrocinar a pergunta $64.000, a 
primeira mostra do quiz da rede do principal-tempo para oferecer a 
contestants somas fabulous do dinheiro. Enquanto o lucro 
líquido médio de Revlon se levantou nos quatro anos seguintes de 
$1.2 milhão a $11 milhões, um plethora de mostras do quiz tentou 
replicate seu sucesso. Na altura de sua popularidade, em 1958, 
24 mostras do quiz da rede -- relativamente fáceis e baratas de 
produzir -- encheram a programação do principal-tempo. Muitos 
fizeram exame de dores em sua apresentação para fazer saber a um 
aura do authenticity -- contestants escolhidos das caminhadas 
ordinárias de perguntas fato-baseadas pondered da vida dentro das 
cabines sound-proof da isolação que os insured eles não receberam 
nenhum auxílio exterior. Para garantir de encontro a alterar 
antes do airtime, os executivos do banco e os protetores armados 
feitos entregas do em-ar de perguntas e de respostas seladas disseram 
ser verificados por autoridades das enciclopédias ou dos professores 
respeitados da universidade. Quando o público aprendeu em 1959 
que um número substancial das mostras tinha sido equipado, um grande 
muitos offended. Um exame, entretanto, mostrou que alguns 
visores não se importaram. Depois dos revelations, as mostras 
do quiz do principal-tempo foram fora do ar, substituído na parte 
grande pelos telefilms da série, muitos de que eram Westerns. A
indústria afastou com sucesso fora dos atendimentos para o 
regulamento, e responsabilizando patrocinadores e contraiu produtores,
as redes minimizaram os danos e aumentaram seu controle sobre 
decisões de programação. No seguinte testimony a uma 
subcomissão congressional, um contestant ofereceu a prova que tinha 
sido treinado, quando um segundo recusou reconhecer "qualms morais" em
perpetrating o fraud. Um third, um teenager, relacionado como 
ela "goofed" e ganhada um fósforo que fosse suposta amarrar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La televisione si era transformata in nel più 
grande media della nazione per la pubblicità entro i mid-1950s, 
quando la società delle estetiche di Revlon ha accosentito per 
patrocinare la domanda $64.000, la prima esposizione di quiz della 
rete di principale-tempo per offrire a contestants le somme fabulous 
di soldi. Mentre il profitto netto medio del Revlon è aumentato
durante i quattro anni successivi da $1.2 milione - $11 milione, una 
pletora di esposizioni di quiz ha provato a ripiegare il relativo 
successo. All'altezza della loro popolarità, in 1958, 24 
esposizioni di quiz della rete -- relativamente facili ed economiche 
produrre -- hanno riempito il programma di principale-tempo. 
Molti hanno preso i dolori nella loro presentazione per 
trasportare un aura dell'autenticità -- contestants scelti dai 
settori ordinari le domande fatto-basate pondered all'interno delle 
cabine insonorizzate di isolamento che gli assicurati non hanno 
ricevuto assistenza esterna. Per garantire contro l'alterazione 
prima del airtime, i quadri della banca e le protezioni munite 
resi a consegne dell'su-aria delle domande e delle risposte sigillate 
hanno detto essere verificati dalle autorità dalle enciclopedie o dai
professori rispettati dell'università. Quando il pubblico ha 
imparato in 1959 che un numero notevole di esposizioni era stato 
attrezzato, un grande molti è stato offenduto. Un'indagine, 
tuttavia, ha indicato che alcuni visori non si sono preoccupati. 
A seguito delle rivelazioni, le esposizioni di quiz di 
principale-tempo sono andato fuori dell'aria, sostituita nella grande 
parte dai telefilms di serie, molti di cui erano Westerns. 
L'industria ha parato con successo fuori delle richieste per la 
regolazione ed incolpando dei garanti ed ha contratto i produttori, le
reti hanno minimizzato danni ed hanno aumentato il loro controllo 
sopra le decisioni di programmazione. Nella seguente 
testimonianza ad un sottocomitato congressuale, un contestant ha 
offerto la prova che era stato istruito, mentre un secondo ha 
rifiutato di ringraziare "i qualms morali" nel perpetrating la frode. 
Un terzo, un adolescente, riguardante come lei "goofed" e vinta 
una corrispondenza che è stata supposta di legare.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η τηλεόραση είχε γίνει το μεγαλύτερο μέσο του έθνους
για μέχρι τα μέσα τησδεκαετίας του '50, όταν εμφανίζει για να 
προσφερθούν η εταιρία καλλυντικών Revlon που συμφωνείται για να
υποστηρίξει την ερώτηση $64.000, ο πρώτος διαγωνισμός γνώσεων 
πρωταρχικός-χρονικό δικτύων στους αγωνιζομένους τα μυθικά ποσά 
των χρημάτων. Καθώς το μέσο καθαρό κέρδος Revlon 
αυξήθηκε στα επόμενα τέσσερα έτη από $1,2 εκατομμύριο έως 
$11 εκατομμύρια, ένας μεγάλος αριθμός διαγωνισμοου γνώσεων 
εμφανίζει προσπαθημένος να ξαναδιπλώσει την επιτυχία του. 
Στο ύψος της δημοτικότητάς τους, το 1958 ο διαγωνισμός 
γνώσεων ..24 δικτύων εμφανίζει ότι -- σχετικά εύκολος και 
ανέξοδος να παραγάγει -- γέμισε το πρωταρχικός-χρονικό 
πρόγραμμα. Πολλοί κατέβαλαν τις προσπάθειες στην 
παρουσίασή τους για να μεταβιβάσουν μια αύρα της αυθεντικότητας 
-- οι αγωνιζόμενοι που επιλέχτηκαν από τα συνηθισμένα κοινωνικά 
στρώματα συλλογίστηκαν γεγονός-βασισμένες ερωτήσεις μέσα στους 
sound-proof θαλάμους απομόνωσης ότι ασφαλισμένοι που δεν 
έλαβαν καμία εξωτερική βοήθεια. Για να εγγυηθούν ενάντια 
να πειράξουν πριν από το airtime, οι ανώτεροι υπάλληλοι 
τραπεζών και οι οπλισμένες φρουρές έκαναν τις παραδόσεις-ΑΈΡΑ 
των σφραγισμένων ερωταποκρίσεων που ειπώθηκαν για να ελεγχθούν 
από τις αρχές από τις σεβαστές εγκυκλοπαίδειες ή τους 
πανεπιστημιακούς καθηγητές. Όταν το κοινό έμαθε το 1959 
ότι ένας ουσιαστικός αριθμός εμφανίζει ήταν εξοπλισμένο, πολύς
ήταν. Μια έρευνα, εντούτοις, έδειξε ότι κάμποσες 
εμφανίσεις δεν φρόντισαν. Μετά από τις αποκαλύψεις, ο 
πρωταρχικός-χρονικός διαγωνισμός γνώσεων εμφανίζει ότι πήγε 
από τον αέρα, που αντικαταστάθηκε στο μεγάλο μέρος από τη σειρά
telefilms, πολλές από την οποία ήταν Westerns. Η 
βιομηχανία προστάτευσε επιτυχώς από τις κλήσεις για τον 
κανονισμό, και με την επίπληξη των χορηγών και συμβλήθηκε τους 
παραγωγούς, ελαχιστοποιημένη δίκτυα ζημία και αύξησε τον έλεγχό
τους του προγραμματισμού των αποφάσεων. Στην ακόλουθη 
κατάθεση σε μια του Κογκρέσου υποεπιτροπή, ένας αγωνιζόμενος 
πρόσφερε την απόδειξη ότι ήταν προγυμνασμένος, ενώ ένα 
δευτερόλεπτο αρνήθηκε να αναγνωρίσει τους "ηθικούς δισταγμούσ" να
διαπράξει την απάτη. Ένα τρίτο, ένας έφηβος, αφορούσε 
πώς "" και κέρδισε μια αντιστοιχία ότι ήταν υποτιθέμενη για να 
δέσει.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La televisión se había convertido en el media 
más grande de la nación para anunciar por los mediados de los años 
cincuenta, cuando la corporación de los cosméticos de Revlon acordó
patrocinar la pregunta $64.000, la primera demostración del concurso 
de la red del primero-tiempo para ofrecer a contestants sumas 
fabulosas de dinero. Mientras que el beneficio neto medio de 
Revlon se levantó en los cuatro años próximos a partir de $1.2 
millón a $11 millones, una plétora de demostraciones del concurso 
intentó replegar su éxito. En la altura de su renombre, en 
1958, 24 demostraciones del concurso de la red -- relativamente 
fáciles y baratas producir -- llenaron el horario del primero-tiempo.
Muchos tomaron dolores en su presentación para transportar una 
aureola de la autenticidad -- contestants elegidos de caminatas 
ordinarias de las preguntas hecho-basadas pondered de la vida dentro 
de cabinas insonoras del aislamiento que los asegurados ellos no 
recibieron ninguna ayuda exterior. Para garantizar contra tratar
de forzar antes de airtime, los ejecutivos de la batería y los 
protectores armados hechos las salidas del en-aire de preguntas y de 
respuestas selladas dijeron ser verificados por autoridades de las 
enciclopedias o de los profesores respetados de la universidad. 
Cuando el público aprendió en 1959 que un número substancial 
de demostraciones había sido aparejado, un grande muchos fue 
ofendido. Una encuesta, sin embargo, mostró que bastantes 
espectadores no cuidaron. Después de las revelaciones, las 
demostraciones del concurso del primero-tiempo salieron el aire, 
substituido en parte grande por los telefilms de la serie, muchos de 
los cuales eran Westerns. La industria apartó con éxito de las
llamadas para la regulación, y culpando a patrocinadores y contrajo a
productores, las redes redujeron al mínimo daño y aumentaron su 
control sobre decisiones de programación. En el testimonio 
siguiente a un subcomité del congreso, un contestant ofreció la 
prueba que lo habían entrenado, mientras que un segundo rechazó 
reconocer "naúseas morales" en perpetrar el fraude. Un 
tercero, adolescente, relacionado cómo ella "goofed" y ganada un 
emparejamiento que le supusieron atar.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087316</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105461</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-make-believe-world-contestants-testify-to-deceptive-quiz-show-practices</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
