<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104945</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104945</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205802</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Toulouse-Lautrec and Montmartre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Toulouse-Lautrec und Montmartre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Toulouse-Lautrec et Montmartre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Toulouse-Lautrec-Lautrec e Montmartre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Toulouse-Lautrec-Lautrec e Montmartre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τουλούζη- Lautrec και Montmartre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Toulouse-Lautrec y Montmartre</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">focuses on paintings, posters, and other works by Lautrec depicting the decadent spirit and bohemian life of this hilltop working-class district on the outskirts of Paris at the turn of the 20th century. A special web feature discusses Montmartre celebrities, cafes and cabarets, brothels, and circuses portrayed by Lautrec (1864-1901), as well as his first lithograph -- the poster that made him an overnight sensation.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Foki auf Anstrichen, Plakaten und anderen Arbeiten
durch Lautrec, der den decadent Geist und die böhmische Lebensdauer 
dieses Gipfelarbeiterklassebezirkes auf dem Randgebiet von Paris 
an der Jahrhundertwende 20. bildlich darstellt. Ein spezielles 
Web-Merkmal behandelt die Montmartre Berühmtheiten, Kaffee und 
Kabaretts, Bordelle und Zirkusse, die von Lautrec (1864-1901) 
geschildert werden, sowie seine erste Lithographie -- das Plakat, das 
ihn eine Nachtempfindung bildete.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les foyers sur des peintures, des affiches, et 
autre fonctionne à côté de Lautrec dépeignant l'esprit décadent 
et la vie de Bohème de cette zone de classe ouvrier de sommet sur les
périphéries de Paris à la fin du 20ème siècle. Un 
dispositif spécial de Web discute des célébrités, des cafés et 
des cabarets, des bordels, et des cirques de Montmartre dépeints par 
Lautrec (1864-1901), comme sa première lithographie -- l'affiche qui 
lui a fait une sensation durant la nuit.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">focos em pinturas, em posteres, e em outros 
trabalhos por Lautrec que descreve o espírito decadent e a vida 
bohemian deste distrito do working-class do hilltop nos outskirts de 
Paris na volta do 20o século. Uma característica especial do 
Web discute celebridades, cafés e cabarés, brothels, e circuses de 
Montmartre portrayed por Lautrec (1864-1901), assim como seu primeiro 
lithograph -- o poster que lhe fêz um sensation de noite.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">i fuochi sulle pitture, sui manifesti e su altro 
funziona da Lautrec che descrive lo spirito decadent e la durata della
Boemia di questo distretto della classe operaia del hilltop sui 
outskirts di Parigi alla fine del ventesimo secolo. Una 
caratteristica speciale di Web discute i celebrities, caffè e 
cabaret, brothels e circuses di Montmartre ritratti da Lautrec 
(1864-1901), come pure la sua prima litografia -- il manifesto che gli
ha reso una sensazione di notte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εστίαση στα έργα ζωγραφικής, τις αφίσες, και άλλες 
εργασίες από Lautrec που απεικονίζει το παρακμιακό πνεύμα και 
τη Βοημίας ζωή αυτής της περιοχής εργατικών τάξεων κορυφών 
υψώματος στα περίχωρα του Παρισιού στο γύρισμα του 20ού αιώνα. 
Ένα ειδικό χαρακτηριστικό γνώρισμα Ιστού συζητά τις 
προσωπικότητες Montmartre, τους καφέδες και cabarets, 
πορνεία, και circuses απεικονισμένος από Lautrec 
(1864-1901), καθώς επίσης και πρώτο lithograph του -- η 
αφίσα που του έκανε μια ολονύκτια αίσθηση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">los focos en pinturas, los carteles, y otro 
trabajan por Lautrec que representa el alcohol decadente y la vida 
bohemia de este districto de la clase obrera del hilltop en las 
cercanías de París al final del vigésimo siglo. Una 
característica especial del Web discute las celebridades, los cafés 
y los cabaretes, los burdeles, y los circos de Montmartre 
retratados por Lautrec (1864-1901), tan bien como su primera 
litografía -- el cartel que le hizo una sensación de noche.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205802</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104945</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/toulouse-lautrec-and-montmartre</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
