<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105348</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105348</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974062</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Plants and the Season</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Betriebe und die Jahreszeit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Usines et la saison</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Plantas e a estação</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Piante e la stagione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εγκαταστάσεις και η εποχή</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Plantas y la estación</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Children explore plant growth in their own gardens, running an experiment that tracks the arrival of Spring. Through these interrelated investigations, students discover that sunlight drives all living systems and they learn about the dynamic ecosystem that surrounds and connects them. Fall: Students plant gardens. Monthly updates: Fridays, September-December. Spring: Students report when tulips emerge and bloom and map Spring's northward journey. Weekly updates: Fridays, February-May. Guidelines, lessons, activities, reading connections, and interactive maps are included for each study.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kinder erforschen Betriebswachstum in ihren 
eigenen Gärten und lassen ein Experiment laufen, das die Ankunft des 
Frühlinges aufspürt. Durch diese zusammenhängend 
Untersuchungen entdecken Kursteilnehmer, daß Tageslicht alle lebenden
Systeme antreibt und sie über das dynamische Oekosystem erlernen, das
sie umgibt und anschließt. Fall: 
Kursteilnehmerbetriebsgärten. 
Monatsaktualisierungsvorgänge: Freitag, 
September-Dezember. Frühling: Kursteilnehmerreport, wenn 
Tulpen nördliche Reise des Frühlinges auftauchen und blühen und 
abbilden. Wöchentliche Aktualisierungsvorgänge: Freitag,
Februar-Mai. Korrekturlinien, Lektionen, Aktivitäten, 
Anschlüsse und interaktive Karten lesend sind für jede Studie 
enthalten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les enfants explorent la croissance de plantes de 
leurs propres jardins, exécutant une expérience qui dépiste 
l'arrivée du ressort. Par ces investigations en corrélation, 
les étudiants découvrent que la lumière du soleil pilote tous les 
systèmes vivants et ils se renseignent sur l'écosystème dynamique 
qui les entoure et relie. Chute : Jardins d'usine 
d'étudiants. Mises à jour mensuelles : Vendredi, 
Septembre-Décembre. Ressort : État d'étudiants quand 
les tulipes émergent et fleurissent et tracent le voyage du nord du 
ressort. Mises à jour hebdomadaires : Vendredi, 
Février-Mai. Les directives, leçons, activités, lisant des 
connexions, et des cartes interactives sont incluses pour chaque 
étude.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As crianças exploram o crescimento de planta em 
seus próprios jardins, funcionando uma experiência que siga a 
chegada da mola. Com estas investigações relacionadas, os 
estudantes descobrem que a luz solar dirige todos os sistemas vivos e 
aprendem sobre o ecosystem dinâmico que os cerca e conecta. 
Queda: Jardins da planta dos estudantes. Updates 
mensais: Sextas-feiras, Setembro-Dezembro. Mola: 
Relatório dos estudantes quando os tulips emergirem e 
florescerem e traçarem a viagem para o norte da mola. Updates 
semanais: Sextas-feiras, Fevereiro-Maio. Os guidelines, 
lições, atividades, lendo conexões, e mapas interativos são 
incluídos para cada estudo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I bambini esplorano lo sviluppo di pianta nei loro
propri giardini, facenti funzionare un esperimento che rintraccia 
l'arrivo della molla. Con queste indagini correlate, gli allievi
scoprono che la luce solare guida tutti i sistemi viventi ed imparano 
circa l'ecosistema dinamico che li circonda e collega. Caduta: 
Giardini della pianta degli allievi. Aggiornamenti 
mensili: Venerdì, Settembre-Dicembre. Molla: 
Rapporto degli allievi quando i tulips emergono e fioriscono e 
tracciano il viaggio verso nord della molla. Aggiornamenti 
settimanali: Venerdì, Febbraio-Maggio. La guida di 
riferimento, lezioni, attività, leggendo i collegamenti ed i 
programmi interattivi è inclusa per ogni studio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα παιδιά ερευνούν την αύξηση εγκαταστάσεων των κήπων
τους, που τρέχουν ένα πείραμα που ακολουθεί την άφιξη της 
άνοιξης. Μέσω αυτών των αλληλένδετων ερευνών, οι 
σπουδαστές ανακαλύπτουν ότι το φως του ήλιου οδηγεί όλα τα 
συστήματα διαβίωσης και μαθαίνουν για το δυναμικό οικοσύστημα που
τους περιβάλλει και συνδέει. Πτώση: Οι σπουδαστές 
φυτεύουν τους κήπους. Μηνιαίες αναπροσαρμογές: 
Παρασκευές, Σεπτέμβριος-Δεκέμβριος. Ανοιξη: Οι 
σπουδαστές εκθέτουν πότε οι τουλίπες προκύπτουν και ανθίζουν και
χαρτογραφούν το ταξίδι βορράς της άνοιξης. 
Εβδομαδιαίες αναπροσαρμογές: Παρασκευές, 
Φεβρουάριος-Μάιος. Οι οδηγίες, μαθήματα, 
δραστηριότητες, διαβάζοντας τις συνδέσεις, και τους διαλογικούς 
χάρτες συμπεριλαμβάνονται για κάθε μελέτη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los niños exploran crecimiento vegetal en sus 
propios jardines, ejecutando un experimento que siga la llegada del 
resorte. Con estas investigaciones correlacionadas, los 
estudiantes descubren que la luz del sol conduce todos los sistemas 
vivos y aprenden sobre el ecosistema dinámico que los rodea y 
conecta. Caída: Jardines de la planta de los estudiantes.
Actualizaciones mensuales: Viernes, Septiembre-Diciembre. 
Resorte: Informe de los estudiantes cuando los tulipanes 
emergen y florecen y asocian el viaje que da al norte del resorte. 
Actualizaciones semanales: Viernes, Febrero-Mayo. 
Las guías de consulta, lecciones, actividades, leyendo 
conexiones, y correspondencias interactivas son incluidas para cada 
estudio.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974062</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105348</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/plants-and-the-season</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
