<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108666</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108666</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205918</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">American Masters: Alfred Stieglitz</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Amerikanische Meister: Alfred Stieglitz</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Maîtres Américains : Alfred Stieglitz</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Mestres Americanos: Alfred Stieglitz</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Supervisori Americani: Alfred Stieglitz</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αμερικανικοί κύριοι: Θ*Αλφρεδ Stieglitz</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Amos Americanos: Alfred Stieglitz</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">presents an essay, timeline, video clips, and interviews examining this photographer, artist, and art impresario. Stieglitz was a powerful force in the arts of the early 20th century and an important interpreter of emerging modern culture. This web site is a companion to first full-length film biography of the photographer, Alfred Stieglitz: The Eloquent Eye.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt einen Versuch, ein timeline, videoclips und
Interviews, die diesen Photographen, Künstler und kunstimpresario 
überprüfen dar. Stieglitz war eine leistungsfähige Kraft in 
den künsten des frühen 20. Jahrhunderts und in einem wichtigen 
Interpreter der auftauchenden modernen Kultur. Diese Web site 
ist ein Begleiter zur ersten in voller Länge Filmbiographie des 
Photographen, Alfred Stieglitz: Das Redegewandte Auge.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">présente un essai, une chronologie, des clips 
visuels, et des entrevues examinant ces photographe, artiste, et 
imprésario d'art. Stieglitz était une force puissante dans les
arts du début du 20ème siècle et un interprète important de 
culture moderne naissante. Ce site Web est un compagnon à la 
première biographie intégrale de film du photographe, Alfred 
Stieglitz : l'Oeil Éloquent.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">apresenta um essay, um timeline, uns grampos 
video, e umas entrevistas que examinam estes fotógrafo, artista, e 
impresario da arte. Stieglitz era uma força poderosa nas artes 
do 20o século adiantado e em um intérprete importante da cultura 
moderna emergente. Este Web site é um companheiro à primeira 
biografia full-length da película do fotógrafo, Alfred Stieglitz: 
O Olho Eloquent.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">presenta un saggio, un timeline, lle video clip e 
lle interviste che esaminano questi photographer, artista ed 
impresario di arte. Stieglitz era una forza potente nelle arti 
di inizio del 20esimo secolo ed in un interpretatore importante di 
coltura moderna d'emersione. Questo Web site è un compagno alla
prima biografia integrale della pellicola del photographer, Alfred 
Stieglitz: L'Occhio Eloquente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρουσιάζει ένα δοκίμιο, μια υπόδειξη ως προς το 
χρόνο, τηλεοπτικούς συνδετήρες, και τις συνεντεύξεις που 
εξετάζουν αυτόν τον φωτογράφο, τον καλλιτέχνη, και το 
impresario τέχνης. Το Stieglitz ήταν μια ισχυρή δύναμη
στις τέχνες του πρόωρου 20ού αιώνα και έναν σημαντικό διερμηνέα
του αναδυόμενου σύγχρονου πολιτισμού. Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος 
είναι σύντροφος στην πρώτη ολόκληρη βιογραφία ταινιών του 
φωτογράφου, Alfred Stieglitz: Το εύγλωττο μάτι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">presenta un ensayo, un timeline, clips video, y 
entrevistas que examinan a este fotógrafo, artista, y empresario del 
arte. Stieglitz era una fuerza de gran alcance en los artes del 
vigésimo siglo temprano y un intérprete importante de la cultura 
moderna que emergía. Este Web site es un compañero a la 
primera biografía integral de la película del fotógrafo, Alfred 
Stieglitz: El Ojo Elocuente.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205918</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108666</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/american-masters-alfred-stieglitz</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
