<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106345</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106345</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207164</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Time of the Lincolns</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Zeit des Lincolns</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La période du Lincolns</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A época do Lincolns</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il periodo del Lincolns</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο χρόνος του Lincolns</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La época del Lincolns</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">a companion website to the film Abraham and Mary Lincoln: A House Divided, examines the context and conflicts surrounding the Civil War. Topics include the partisan politics of the time, the battle for abolition, the Underground Railroad, African American troops, and women's rights. The site offers soldiers' letters, newspaper articles, and other primary sources, along with a teacher's guide.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">eine Begleiterweb site zum Film Abraham und Mary 
Lincoln: Ein Haus teilte, überprüft den Kontext und die 
$überschneidungen, welche die Bürgerkrieg-Themen umgeben, schließen
die parteigängerische Politik der Zeit, die Schlacht für Aufhebung, 
die unterirdische Eisenbahn, die afrikanischen amerikanischen Truppen 
und die Rechte der Frauen ein. Die Site bietet Zeichen der 
Soldaten, Zeitungsartikel und andere Primärquellen, zusammen mit der 
Anleitung eines Lehrers an.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">un site Web de compagnon au film Abraham et Mary 
Lincoln : Une Chambre a divisé, examine le contexte et les 
conflits entourant les sujets de guerre civile incluent la politique 
partisane du moment, la bataille pour l'abolition, le chemin de fer 
souterrain, les troupes américaines africaines, et les droits des 
femmes. Le site offre les lettres des soldats, les articles de 
journal, et d'autres sources primaires, avec le guide d'un professeur.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">um Web site do companheiro à película Abraham e 
Mary Lincoln: Uma casa dividiu, examina o contexto e os 
conflitos que cercam os tópicos da guerra civil incluem a política 
partisan do momento, a batalha para o abolition, a estrada de ferro 
subterrânea, tropas americanas africanas, e direitas das mulheres. 
O local oferece letras dos soldados, artigos de jornal, e outras
fontes preliminares, junto com a guia de um professor.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">un Web site del compagno alla pellicola Abraham e 
Mary Lincoln: Una Camera ha diviso, esamina il contesto ed i 
conflitti che circondano i soggetti di guerra civile includono la 
politica partigiana del momento, la battaglia per l'abolizione, la 
ferrovia sotterranea, le truppe americane africane ed i diritti delle 
donne. Il luogo offre le lettere dei soldati, gli articoli di 
stampa ed altre sorgenti primarie, con la guida dell'insegnante.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ένας ιστοχώρος συντρόφων στην ταινία Abraham και 
Mary Λίνκολν: Ένα σπίτι που διαιρείται, εξετάζει το 
πλαίσιο και συγκρούεται περιβάλλων τον εμφύλιο πόλεμο. Τα 
θέματα περιλαμβάνουν την αντιστασιακή πολιτική του χρόνου, τη 
μάχη για την κατάργηση, τον υπόγειο σιδηρόδρομο, τα αφρικανικά 
αμερικανικά στρατεύματα, και τα δικαιώματα των γυναικών. Η 
περιοχή προσφέρει τις επιστολές των στρατιωτών, τα άρθρα 
εφημερίδων, και άλλες αρχικές πηγές, μαζί με τον οδηγό ενός 
δασκάλου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">un Web site del compañero a la película Abraham 
y Maria Lincoln: Una casa dividió, examina el contexto y los 
conflictos que rodean los asuntos de la guerra civil incluyen la 
política partisana de la época, la batalla para la abolición, el 
ferrocarril subterráneo, las tropas americanas africanas, y las 
derechas de las mujeres. El sitio ofrece las cartas de los 
soldados, los artículos periodísticos, y otras fuentes primarias, 
junto con la guía de un profesor.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207164</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106345</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-time-of-the-lincolns</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
