<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106207</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106207</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087206</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"We Took Away Their Best Lands, Broke Treaties": John Collier Promises to Reform Indian Policy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Wir Nahmen Ihre Besten Länder, Brachen 
Verträge" Weg: John Collier-Versprechungen, indische Politik zu
verbessern</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Nous Avons emporté Leurs Meilleures Terres, 
Avons cassé Des Traités" : Promesses de John Collier de 
reformer la politique indienne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Nós Removemos Suas Mais melhores Terras, 
Quebramos Tratados": Promessas do collier de John de reformar a 
política indian</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Abbiamo tolto Le Loro Terre Migliori, Abbiamo 
rotto I Trattati": Promesse di collier del John riformare 
politica indiana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Πήραμε μαζί τα καλύτερα εδάφη τους, σπάσαμε τις 
Συνθήκεσ": Θ*Ιοχν Collier Promises να μεταρρυθμιστεί η 
ινδική πολιτική</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Quitamos Sus Mejores Pistas, Rompimos Tratados": 
Promesas del collier de Juan de reformar la política india</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">John Collier's appointment as Commissioner of Indian Affairs by Franklin Roosevelt in 1933 marked a radical reversal--in intention if not always in effect--in U.S. government policies toward American Indians that dated back to the 1887 Dawes Act. An idealistic social worker, Collier first encountered Indian culture when he visited Taos, New Mexico, in 1920, and found among the Pueblos there what he called a "Red Atlantis"--a model of living that integrated the needs of the individual with the group and that maintained traditional values. As Commissioner, Collier proposed a sweeping set of reforms to reverse the previous half century of federal policy. Although he could not win congressional backing for his most radical proposals, the Indian Reorganization Act of 1934 dramatically changed policy by allowing tribal self-government and consolidating individual land allotments back into tribal hands. His 1938 report as Commissioner of Indian Affairs combined a frank indictment of the broken promises of the past with an insistence that the Indian Service, since 1933, had made a "concerted effort" to rectify those past mistakes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Verabredung des John Colliers als Beauftragtes der
indischen Angelegenheiten durch Franklin Roosevelt in 1933 
kennzeichnete eine radikale Umlenkung -- in der Absicht wenn nicht 
immer in Wirklichkeit -- in den VEREINIGTE STAATEN Regierung 
politischen Richtlinien in Richtung zu den Indianern, die auf der 
Dawes Tat 1887 zurückgingen. Ein idealistic Sozialarbeiter, 
Collier traf zuerst indische Kultur an, als er Taos, New-Mexico, 1920 
besuchte und unter den Pueblos dort fand, was er ein "rotes Atlantis" 
nannte -- ein Modell von leben das integrierte die Notwendigkeiten der
Einzelperson mit der Gruppe und das behielt traditionelle Werte. 
Als Beauftragter Collier vorgeschlagen ein fegendes Set 
Verbesserungen, zum des vorhergehenden halben Jahrhunderts von 
Bundespolitik aufzuheben. Obgleich er nicht 
Kongreßschutzträger für seine radikalsten Anträge, die indische 
Reorganisierung-Tat von 1934 drastisch geänderter Politik gewinnen 
könnte, indem er Stammes- Self-government erlaubte und einzelne 
Landzuteilungen zurück in Stammes- Hände vereinigte. Sein 
Report 1938, da Beauftragter der indischen Angelegenheiten eine 
aufrichtige Anklage der unterbrochenen Versprechungen der 
Vergangenheit mit einer Beharrlichkeit kombinierte, daß der indische 
Service, seit 1933, eine "beratene Bemühung" gebildet hatte, jene 
letzten Fehler gleichzurichten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La nomination de John Collier comme 
commissaire des affaires indiennes par Franklin Roosevelt dans 1933 a 
marqué une inversion radicale -- dans l'intention si pas toujours en 
effet -- dans des politiques de gouvernement des ETATS-UNIS vers les 
Indiens d'Amerique qui ont remonté à la Loi 1887 de Dawes. Un 
ouvrier social idéaliste, Collier a rencontré la première fois 
la culture indienne quand il a visité Taos, Nouveau-Mexique, en 1920,
et a trouvé parmi les pueblos là ce qu'il a appelé "une Atlantide 
rouge" -- un modèle de la vie cela a intégré les besoins de 
l'individu avec le groupe et cela a mis à jour des valeurs 
traditionnelles. Comme commissaire, Collier proposé un 
ensemble de balayage de réformes pour renverser demi de siècle 
précédent de la politique fédérale. Bien qu'il ne pourrait 
pas gagner le support congressionnel pour ses propositions plus 
radicales, l'acte indien de réorganisation de 1934 politiques 
excessivement changées en permettant art de l'auto-portrait-government tribal et 
en consolidant différentes attributions de terre de nouveau dans les 
mains tribales. Son état 1938 car le commissaire des affaires 
indiennes a combiné un acte d'accusation franc des promesses cassées
du passé avec une insistance que le service indien, depuis 1933, 
avait fait "un effort concerté" de rectifier ces erreurs passées.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A nomeação do collier de John como o comissário
de casos indian por Franklin Roosevelt em 1933 marcou uma reversão 
radical -- na intenção if.not sempre de fato -- em políticas do 
governo de ESTADOS UNIDOS para os indians americanos que dataram para 
trás ao ato 1887 de Dawes. Um trabalhador social idealistic, 
collier encontrou primeiramente a cultura indian quando visitou Taos, 
Novo México, em 1920, e encontrou entre os povoados indíginos lá o 
que se chamou "um Atlantis vermelho" -- um modelo de viver isso 
integrou as necessidades do indivíduo com o grupo e aquele manteve 
valores tradicionais. Como o comissário, collier proposto um 
jogo varrendo das reformas para inverter o meio século precedente da 
política federal. Embora não poderia ganhar o revestimento 
protetor congressional para suas propostas mais radicais, o ato indian
do reorganization de 1934 políticas dramàtica mudadas permitindo o 
self-government tribal e consolidando allotments individuais da terra 
para trás nas mãos tribais. Seu relatório 1938 porque o 
comissário de casos indian combinou um indictment frank das promessas
quebradas do passado com um insistence que o serviço indian, desde 
1933, tinha feito "um esforço concerted" retificar aqueles erros 
passados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'appuntamento del collier del John come 
commissario degli affari indiani da Franklin Roosevelt in 1933 ha 
contrassegnato un'inversione radicale -- nell'intenzione se non sempre
in effetti -- nelle politiche di governo degli STATI UNITI verso gli 
indiani americani che hanno datato dalla Legge 1887 di Dawes. Un
operaio sociale idealistic, collier in primo luogo ha incontrato la 
coltura indiana quando ha visitato Taos, Nuovo Messico, in 1920 ed ha 
trovato fra i pueblos là che cosa ha chiamato "un Atlantis rosso" -- 
un modello di vivere quello ha integrato i bisogni dell'individuo con 
il gruppo e quello ha effettuato i valori tradizionali. Come 
commissario, collier proposto un insieme scopante delle riforme per 
invertire il mezzo secolo precedente di politica federale. Anche
se non potrebbe vincere la protezione congressuale per le sue proposte
più radicali, la Legge indiana della riorganizzazione delle 1934 
politiche drammaticamente cambiate permettendo il self-government 
tribale e consolidando le diverse assegnazioni della terra nuovamente 
dentro le mani tribali. Il suo rapporto 1938 poichè il 
commissario degli affari indiani ha unito un atto d'accusa franco 
delle promesse rotte dell'esperienza con un'insistenza che il servizio
indiano, dal 1933, aveva fatto "uno sforzo concordato" rettificare 
quegli errori passati.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο διορισμός John Collier's ως Επίτροπος των 
ινδικών υποθέσεων από Franklin Roosevelt το 1933 
χαρακτήρισε μια ριζική αντιστροφή -- στην πρόθεση εάν όχι πάντα
ουσιαστικά -- στις πολιτικές ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ κυβέρνησης προς 
αμερικανικούς Ινδούς που χρονολογημένος από το νόμο 1887 
Dawes. Ένας ιδεαλιστικός κοινωνικός λειτουργός, 
ανθρακωρύχος αντιμετώπισε αρχικά τον ινδικό πολιτισμό όταν 
επισκέφτηκε Taos, New Mexico, το 1920, και βρήκε μεταξύ
του Pueblos εκεί τι κάλεσε "κόκκινο Atlantis" -- ένα 
μοντέλο της διαβίωσης που ενσωμάτωσε τις ανάγκες του ατόμου με 
την ομάδα και που διατήρησε τις παραδοσιακές αξίες. Σαν 
Επίτροπο, ο ανθρακωρύχος πρότεινε ένα σκουπίζοντας σύνολο 
μεταρρυθμίσεων για να αντιστρέψει τον προηγούμενο μισό αιώνα της 
ομοσπονδιακής πολιτικής. Αν και δεν θα μπορούσε να κερδίσει 
την του Κογκρέσου υποστήριξη για τις ριζικότερες προτάσεις του, ο 
ινδικός νόμος αναδιοργάνωσης της αλλαγμένης πολιτικής του 1934
εντυπωσιακά με την άδεια της φυλετικής μόνος-κυβέρνησης και την 
παγίωση των μεμονωμένων διανομών εδάφους πίσω στα φυλετικά 
χέρια. Η έκθεση του 1938 του ως Επίτροπος των ινδικών 
υποθέσεων συνδύασε μια ειλικρινή μήνυση των σπασμένων υποσχέσεων
του παρελθόντος με μια επιμονή ότι η ινδική υπηρεσία, από το 
1933, είχε καταβάλει "συμφωνημένη προσπάθεια" να αποκαταστήσει
εκείνα τα προηγούμενα λάθη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La cita del collier de Juan como comisión de 
asuntos indios de Franklin Roosevelt en 1933 marcó una revocación 
radical -- en la intención si no siempre en efecto -- en políticas 
del gobierno de ESTADOS UNIDOS hacia los indios americanos que 
fecharon de nuevo al acto 1887 de Dawes. Un trabajador social 
idealista, collier primero encontró la cultura india cuando él 
visitó Taos, New México, en 1920, y encontró entre los pueblos 
allí lo que él llamó un "Atlantis rojo" -- un modelo de vivir eso 
integró las necesidades del individuo con el grupo y ése mantuvo 
valores tradicionales. Como comisión, collier propuesto un 
conjunto que barre de reformas para invertir el medio siglo anterior 
de la política federal. Aunque él no podría ganar el forro 
del congreso para sus ofertas más radicales, el acto indio de la 
reorganización de 1934 políticas dramáticamente cambiantes 
permitiendo el gobierno autónomo tribal y consolidando asignaciones 
individuales de la pista nuevamente dentro de las manos tribales. 
Su informe 1938 pues la comisión de asuntos indios combinó una
acusación franca de las promesas quebradas del pasado con una 
insistencia que el servicio indio, desde 1933, había hecho un 
"esfuerzo concertado" de rectificar esos últimos errores.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087206</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106207</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/we-took-away-their-best-lands-broke-treaties-john-collier-promises-to-reform-indian-policy</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
