<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105814</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105814</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201072</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Coral Bleaching: Making Our Oceans Whiter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Koralle Bleiche: Unsere Ozeane Weißer 
Bilden</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Blanchissement de Corail : Rendant Nos 
Océans Plus blancs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Descorar-se Do Coral: Fazendo Nossos Oceanos
Mais brancos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Imbianchimento Del Coral: Rendendo I Nostri 
Oceani Più bianchi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Λεύκανση κοραλλιών: Καθιστώντας τους ωκεανούς 
μας πιό άσπρους</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Blanquear Del Coral: Haciendo Nuestros 
Océanos Más blancos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Coral Bleaching: Making our Oceans Whiter lesson was developed by National Geographic. This lesson plan deals with coral reefs and the recent increase in coral bleaching. The students will be learning about the ecology of reefs, the habitats they create, the algal symbiosis that ends with bleaching, and the role of human impact. The plan also outlines a role-playing debate for the students, and an in-character written assignment to come up with a compromise to protect the reefs and the economies that depend on them. On this Starting Point page, teachers can find learning goals, teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment hints and references and resources dealing with this exercise. It also describes the context in which the virtual tour, another feature of the webpage, is best used.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Koralle Bleiche: Das Bilden unsere 
Ozeane der weißeren Lektion wurde von National Geographic entwickelt.
Dieser Lektionplan beschäftigt Korallenriffe und die neue 
Zunahme der korallenroten Bleiche. Die Kursteilnehmer werden 
über die Ökologie von Reefs, von Lebensräumen, die sie herstellen, 
von Algensymbiose, die mit der Bleiche beendet, und von Rolle der 
menschlichen Auswirkung erlernen. Der Plan umreißt auch eine 
Rolle spielendes Debatte für die Kursteilnehmer und eine Inzeichen 
schriftliche Anweisung, um mit einem Kompromiß oben zu kommen, die 
Reefs und die Wirtschaftssysteme zu schützen, die von ihnen 
abhängen. Auf dieser Ausgangspunktseite können Lehrer die 
erlernenziele, unterrichtende Anmerkungen und Spitzen, Lehrmittel, 
Einschätzung Tips und Referenzen und Betriebsmittel beschäftigend 
diese Übung finden. Sie beschreibt auch den Kontext, in dem die
virtuelle Tour, ein anderes Merkmal der Webseite, gut verwendet wird.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Blanchissement de Corail : La fabrication
nos océans d'une leçon plus blanche a été développée par 
National Geographic. Ce plan de leçon traite les récifs de 
corail et l'augmentation récente du blanchissement de corail. 
Les étudiants se renseigneront sur l'écologie des récifs, des
habitats qu'ils créent, de la symbiose d'algues qui termine avec le 
blanchissement, et du rôle de l'impact humain. Le plan trace 
les grandes lignes également d'une discussion jouante un rôle pour 
les étudiants, et d'une affectation écrite parcaractère pour être 
soulevé avec un compromis pour protéger les récifs et les 
économies qui dépendent d'eux. À cette page de point de 
départ, les professeurs peuvent trouver des buts d'étude, des notes 
et des extrémités d'enseignement, matériel didactique, des conseils
d'évaluation et des références et des ressources traitant cet 
exercice. Il décrit également le contexte dans lequel 
l'excursion virtuelle, un autre dispositif de la page Web, mieux 
est utilisée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Descorar-se Do Coral: Fazer a nossos oceanos
uma lição mais branca foi desenvolvido por Nacional Geográfico. 
Esta planta da lição trata dos recifes corais e do aumento 
recente em descorar-se coral. Os estudantes estarão aprendendo 
sobre o ecology dos recifes, dos habitats que críam, do symbiosis 
algal que termina com se descorar, e do papel do impacto humano. 
A planta esboça também um debate role-playing para os 
estudantes, e uma atribuição escrita em-caráter para vir acima com 
um acordo proteger os recifes e as economias que dependem deles. 
Nesta página do ponto começar, os professores podem encontrar 
os objetivos de aprendizagem, as notas e as pontas ensinando, os 
materiais de ensino, as sugestões da avaliação e as referências e 
os recursos tratando deste exercício. Descreve também o 
contexto em que a excursão virtual, uma outra característica do Web 
page, é usada melhor.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'Imbianchimento Del Coral: Rendere ai 
nostri oceani la lezione più bianca è stato sviluppato da National 
Geographic. Questo programma di lezione si occupa dei reefs di 
corallo e dell'aumento recente nell'imbianchimento di corallo. 
Gli allievi impareranno circa l'ecologia dei reefs, degli 
habitat che creano, della simbiosi d'alghe che si conclude con 
l'imbianchimento e del ruolo di effetto umano. Il programma 
egualmente descrive un dibattito d'atteggiamento per gli allievi e 
un'assegnazione scritta in-carattere per fornire un compromesso 
proteggere i reefs e le economie che dipendono da loro. A questa
pagina del punto di partenza, gli insegnanti possono trovare gli 
obiettivi imparanti, note e punte d'istruzione, materiali didattici, 
suggerimenti di valutazione e riferimenti e risorse occupantesi di 
questa esercitazione. Egualmente descrive il contesto in cui il 
giro virtuale, un'altra caratteristica del Web page, è usato il più 
bene.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η λεύκανση κοραλλιών: Η παραγωγή των ωκεανών μας
το πιό άσπρο μάθημα αναπτύχθηκε από εθνικό γεωγραφικό. 
Αυτό το σχέδιο μαθήματος εξετάζει τις κοραλλιογενείς 
υφάλους και την πρόσφατη αύξηση στη λεύκανση κοραλλιών. Οι 
σπουδαστές θα μαθαίνουν για την οικολογία των σκοπέλων, οι 
βιότοποι που δημιουργούν, η φυκώδης συμβίωση που τελειώνει με τη 
λεύκανση, και το ρόλο του ανθρώπινου αντίκτυπου. Το σχέδιο 
περιγράφει επίσης μια ρόλος-παίζοντας συζήτηση για τους 
σπουδαστές, και μια μέσα γραπτή ανάθεση για να βρεί έναν 
συμβιβασμό να προστατεύσει τους σκοπέλους και τις οικονομίες που 
εξαρτώνται από τους. Σε αυτήν την σελίδα αφετηρίας, οι 
δάσκαλοι μπορούν να βρούν τους στόχους εκμάθησης, τις σημειώσεις
και τις άκρες διδασκαλίας, τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, τους 
υπαινιγμούς αξιολόγησης και τις αναφορές και τα στοιχεία 
συμπεριφοράς εξετάζοντας αυτήν την άσκηση. Περιγράφει 
επίσης το πλαίσιο στο οποίο ο εικονικός γύρος, ένα άλλο 
χαρακτηριστικό γνώρισμα του webpage, χρησιμοποιείται καλύτερα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Blanquear Del Coral: La fabricación 
nuestros océanos de una lección más blanca fue desarrollada por 
National Geographic. Este plan de la lección se ocupa de los 
filones coralinos y del aumento reciente en blanquear coralino. 
Los estudiantes aprenderán sobre la ecología de filones, de 
los habitat que crean, de la simbiosis algal que termina con 
blanquear, y del papel del impacto humano. El plan también 
contornea un discusión de actuación de papeles para los estudiantes,
y una asignación escrita en-cara'cter para venir para arriba con un 
compromiso proteger los filones y las economías que dependen de 
ellas. En esta paginación del punto de partida, los profesores 
pueden encontrar las metas que aprenden, las notas y las extremidades 
de enseñanza, los materiales didácticos, las indirectas del gravamen
y las referencias y los recursos ocupándose de este ejercicio. 
También describe el contexto en el cual el viaje virtual, otra 
característica del Web page, se utiliza lo más mejor posible.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201072</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105814</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/coral-bleaching-making-our-oceans-whiter</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
