<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103451</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103451</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209894</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Polygon </string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Polygon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Polygone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Polygon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Poligono</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πολύγωνο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Polígono</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate polygons. The applet shows a polygon which is initially an irregular convex pentagon. The user can drag any vertex and a message shows if it becomes concave. The user can also alter the number of sides from 3 to 99, the title changing to reflect it's name up to 12 sides. You can also make it regular, dragging a vertex then changes all vertices to maintain it as regular. The web page has many definitions and links to the various forms and orders of polygon. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die Polygone zeigen. Der applet zeigt einem Polygon, 
welches zuerst ein unregelmäßiges konvexes Pentagon ist. Der 
Benutzer kann alle mögliche Erscheinen des Gipfels und einer Meldung 
schleppen, wenn er konkav wird. Der Benutzer kann die Zahl 
Seiten von 3 bis 99 auch ändern, der Name, der ändert, um ihn zu 
reflektieren, ist Namensbis 12 Seiten. Sie können ihn 
regelmäßig auch bilden und einen Gipfel schleppen, ändern dann alle
Gipfel, um ihn beizubehalten, wie regelmäßig. Die Webseite hat
viele Definitionen und Links zu den verschiedenen Formularen und zu 
den Ordnungen des Polygons. Applet kann zum vollen Bildumfang 
für Gebrauch mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. 
Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von 
jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den 
benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein 
Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven 
Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent des polygones. L'applet montre à un polygone ce
qui est au commencement un pentagone convexe irrégulier. 
L'utilisateur peut traîner toutes les expositions de sommet et 
d'un message s'il devient concave. L'utilisateur peut également
modifier le nombre de côtés de 3 à 99, le titre changeant pour le 
refléter est les jusqu'à 12 côtés nommés. Vous pouvez 
également le rendre régulier, traînant un sommet change alors tous 
les sommets pour le mettre à jour comme régulier. La 
page Web a beaucoup de définitions et liens aux diverses formes et 
commandes du polygone. L'applet peut être agrandi à la taille 
de plein écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de classe. 
Le après utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant peut 
lui accéder encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la maison 
ou dans la bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion exigée. 
Cette ressource est un composant du projet interactif de manuel 
de la géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem polygons. O applet mostra a um polygon qual é 
inicialmente um pentagon convexo irregular. O usuário pode 
arrastar todas as mostras do vertex e de uma mensagem se se tornar 
côncavo. O usuário pode também alterar o número dos lados de
3 a 99, o título que muda para refleti-lo é até 12 lados 
conhecidos. Você pode também fazê-lo regular, arrastando um 
vertex muda então todos os vertices para mantê-lo como regular. 
O Web page tem muitas definições e ligações aos vários 
formulários e ordens do polygon. O applet pode ser ampliado ao 
tamanho de tela cheia para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. 
O depois de uso na sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la 
outra vez de todo o web browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum 
início de uma sessão requerido. Este recurso é um componente 
do projeto interativo do textbook da geometria da referência aberta 
do math em http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano i poligoni. Il applet mostra ad un poligono quale è 
inizialmente un pentagono convesso irregolare. L'utente può 
trascinare tutte le esposizioni del messaggio e di vertice se diventa 
concavo. L'utente può anche alterare il numero di lati da 3 a 
99, il titolo che cambia per rifletterlo è fino a 12 lati nomi. 
Potete anche renderli normale, trascinando un vertice allora 
cambiate tutti i vertici per effettuarli come normale. Il Web 
page ha molti definizioni e collegamenti alle vari forme ed ordini del
poligono. Il applet può essere ingrandito al formato di schermo
pieno per uso con un proiettore dell'aula. La post-utilizzazione
nell'aula, allievo può accederle ancora da tutto il web browser nel 
paese o nella libreria senza l'inizio attività richiesto. 
Questa risorsa è un componente del progetto interattivo del 
manuale della geometria di riferimento aperto di per la matematica a 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν τα πολύγωνα. Το applet εμφανίζει ένα 
πολύγωνο που είναι αρχικά ένα ανώμαλο κυρτό Πεντάγωνο. Ο 
χρήστης μπορεί να σέρει οποιοδήποτε vertex και ένα μήνυμα 
εμφανίζει εάν γίνεται κοίλο. Ο χρήστης μπορεί επίσης να 
αλλάξει τον αριθμό πλευρών από 3 έως 99, ο τίτλος που 
αλλάζει για να απεικονίσει αυτό είναι όνομα μέχρι 12 
πλευρές. Μπορείτε επίσης να τον καταστήσετε κανονικό, το 
σύρσιμο vertex αλλάζει έπειτα όλα vertices για να τον 
διατηρήσει όπως κανονικό. Ιστοσελίδας έχει πολλούς 
ορισμούς και συνδέσεις με τις διάφορες μορφές και τις κατατάξεις 
του πολυγώνου. Το Applet μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες 
μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με έναν προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά
από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε
τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη 
βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το
στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού 
προγράμματος εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού 
σε http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran polígonos. El applet muestra a polígono cuál es 
inicialmente un pentágono convexo irregular. El utilizador 
puede arrastrar cualquier demostración de la cima y de un mensaje si 
llega a ser cóncavo. El utilizador puede también alterar el 
número de caras a partir del 3 a 99, el título que cambia para 
reflejarlo es hasta 12 caras conocidas. Usted puede también 
hacerlo regular, arrastrando una cima entonces cambia todas las cimas 
para mantenerla como regular. El Web page tiene muchas 
definiciones y conexiones a las varias formas y órdenes del 
polígono. El applet se puede agrandar a la talla de la pantalla
completa para el uso con un proyector de la sala de clase. El 
uso posterior en la sala de clase, estudiante puede tenerle acceso 
otra vez de cualquier web browser en el país o en la biblioteca sin 
la conexión requerida. Este recurso es un componente del 
proyecto interactivo del libro de textos de la geometría de la 
referencia abierta de la matemáticas en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209894</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103451</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/polygon</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
