<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103123</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103123</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087298</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"A Foretaste of the Orient": John Murray Criticizes the AFL</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ein Foretaste des Orientes": John Murray 
kritisiert das AFL</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"un avant-goût de l'Orient" : John Murray 
critique l'AFL</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"um foretaste do Oriente": John Murray 
critica o AFL</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"un foretaste dell'Oriente": John Murray 
critica il AFL</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Foretaste της Ανατολήσ": Θ*Ιοχν Murray 
Criticizes το AFL</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"un anticipo del Oriente": Juan Murray 
critica el AFL</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Most historians who have written about the 1903 strike of Mexican and Japanese farm workers against the Oxnard, California, sugar beet growers have relied on John Murray's first-hand account of the strike and its aftermath. Murray, a socialist union organizer, went to Oxnard after learning of the strike through newspaper accounts of strike-related violence and rioting. Along with fellow union organizer Fred C. Wheeler, Murray assisted the farm workers' union, the Japanese-Mexican Labor Association (JMLA), in negotiations with the Western Agricultural Contracting Company, which contracted laborers for local sugar beet farmers. When the American Federation of Labor refused to grant a charter to the JMLA unless the union excluded all Asian workers, Murray wrote this article, "A Foretaste of the Orient," as both a chronicle of the strike and as a biting criticism of the AFL's refusal to accept Asian- and African-American workers as members.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die meisten Historiker, die über den Schlag 1903 
der mexikanischen und japanischen Landarbeiter gegen das Oxnard, 
Kalifornien geschrieben haben, Zuckerrübezüchter haben auf John 
Murrays aus erster Hand bezogenes Konto des Schlages und seiner 
Nachmahd gebaut. Murray, ein sozialistischer 
Anschlußorganisator, ging zu Oxnard, nachdem er des Schlages durch 
Zeitung Konten der anschlagen-in Verbindung stehenden Gewalttätigkeit
erlernt hatte und randaliert hatte. Entlang mit 
Mitanschlußorganisator Fred C. Wheeler, Murray unterstützte den 
Anschluß der Landarbeiter, die Japanisch-Mexikanische 
Arbeitsverbindung (JMLA), in den Vermittlungen mit Western 
Agricultural Contracting Company, die Vertrag Arbeiter für lokale 
Zuckerrote Rübe Landwirte abschlossen. Als die amerikanische 
Vereinigung der Arbeit ablehnte, eine Charter dem JMLA zu bewilligen, 
es sei denn der Anschluß alle asiatischen Arbeiter ausschloß, 
schrieb Murray diesen Artikel, "ein Foretaste des Orientes," als 
Chronik des Schlages und als beißende Kritik von der Ablehnung des 
AFLs, um die asiatischen und Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Arbeiter als 
Bauteile anzunehmen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La plupart des historiens qui ont écrit au sujet 
de la grève 1903 des ouvriers mexicains et japonais de ferme contre 
l'Oxnard, la Californie, cultivateurs de betterave à sucre ont 
compté sur le compte de première main de John Murray de la grève et
de sa conséquence. Murray, un organisateur socialiste des 
syndicats, est allé à Oxnard après avoir appris de la grève par 
des comptes de journal de violence frapper-connexe et s'être ameuté.
Avec l'organisateur Fred C. Wheeler, Murray des syndicats de 
camarade a aidé le syndicat de ferme, l'association de travail 
Japonais-Mexicaine (JMLA), dans les négociations avec Western 
Agricultural Contracting Company, qui ont contracté des travailleurs 
pour les fermiers locaux de betterave à sucre. Quand la 
fédération américaine du travail a refusé d'accorder une charte au
JMLA à moins que l'union ait exclu tous les ouvriers asiatiques, 
Murray a écrit cet article, "un avant-goût de l'Orient," comme 
chronique de la grève et comme critique acérée du refus de l'AFL 
pour recevoir les ouvriers asiatique- et afro-américains comme membres.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A maioria de historians que escreveram sobre a 
batida 1903 de trabalhadores de fazenda mexicanos e japoneses de 
encontro ao Oxnard, Califórnia, growers da beterraba de açúcar 
confiaram no cliente first-hand de John Murray da batida e de seu 
aftermath. Murray, um organizer socialist da união, foi a 
Oxnard após a aprendizagem da batida com os clientes do jornal de 
violência golpe-relacionada e amotinar-se. Junto com o 
organizer Fred C. Wheeler da união do companheiro, Murray ajudou à 
união de trabalhadores da fazenda, a associação labor 
Japonês-Mexicana (JMLA), nas negociações com os Ocidental 
Agricultural Contracting Companhia, que contraíram laborers para 
fazendeiros locais da beterraba de açúcar. Quando o federation
americano do trabalho recusou conceder uma carta patente ao JMLA a 
menos que a união excluísse todos os trabalhadores asian, Murray 
escreveu este artigo, "um foretaste do Oriente," como  um chronicle da
batida e como um criticism cortante da recusa do AFL para aceitar 
trabalhadores asian- e Africano-Americanos como membros.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La maggior parte dei storici che hanno scritto 
circa il colpo 1903 della manodopera agricola messicana e giapponese 
contro il Oxnard, la California, coltivatori della barbabietola di 
zucchero hanno contato sul cliente di prima mano del John Murray del 
colpo e del relativo guaime. Murray, un organizzatore socialista
del sindacato, è andato a Oxnard dopo avere imparato del colpo con i 
clienti del giornale della violenza colpire-relativa ed essere 
sollevatsi. Con l'organizzatore Fred C. Wheeler, Murray del 
sindacato del collega ha aiutato l'unione della manodopera agricola, 
l'associazione Di lavoro di Japanese-messicano (JMLA), nelle 
trattative con gli Western Agricultural Contracting Company, che hanno
contratto i lavoratori per i coltivatori locali della barbabietola di 
zucchero. Quando la federazione americana del Lavoro ha 
rifiutato di assegnare una lettera al JMLA a meno che l'unione escluda
tutti gli operai asiatici, Murray ha scritto questo articolo, "un 
foretaste dell'Oriente," come sia chronicle del colpo che come critica
mordace del rifiuto del AFL per accettare gli operai asiatici ed 
Africano-Americani come membri.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι περισσότεροι ιστορικοί που έχουν γράψει για την 
απεργία του 1903 των μεξικάνικων και ιαπωνικών αγροτών ενάντια
στο Oxnard, Καλιφόρνια, καλλιεργητές ζαχαροτεύτλων έχουν 
στηριχθεί στον από πρώτο χέρι απολογισμό John Murray's της 
απεργίας και της συνέπειάς του. Το Murray, ένας 
σοσιαλιστικός διοργανωτής ένωσης, επέρασε σε Oxnard μετά από 
να μάθει της απεργίας από τους απολογισμούς εφημερίδων της 
απεργία-σχετικής βίας και να στασιάσει. Μαζί με το 
συντροφικό διοργανωτή Fred C. Wheeler ένωσης, Murray 
βοήθησε το σωματείο των αγροτών, η ιαπωνικός-μεξικάνικη ένωση 
εργασίας (JMLA), στις διαπραγματεύσεις με δυτικό Agricultural
Contracting Company, οι οποίες συμβλήθηκαν τα laborers για 
τους τοπικούς αγρότες ζαχαροτεύτλων. Όταν η αμερικανική 
ομοσπονδία της εργασίας αρνήθηκε να χορηγήσει έναν χάρτη στο 
JMLA εκτός αν η ένωση απέκλεισε όλους τους ασιατικούς 
εργαζομένους, Murray έγραψε αυτό το άρθρο, "foretaste της 
Ανατολής," όπως και εξιστορήστε κατά γράμμα της απεργίας και ως 
κριτική δαγκώματος της άρνησης του AFL να αποδεχθεί Ασιάτης - 
και αφρικανικός-αμερικανικοί εργαζόμενοι ως μέλη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La mayoría de los historiadores que han escrito 
sobre la huelga 1903 de los trabajadores de granja mexicanos y 
japoneses contra el Oxnard, California, cultivadores de la remolacha 
han confiado en la cuenta de primera mano de Juan Murray de la huelga 
y de sus consecuencias. Murray, organizador socialista de la 
unión, fue a Oxnard después de aprender de la huelga con cuentas del
periódico de la violencia pulso-relacionada y de desenfrenarse. 
Junto con el organizador Fred C. Wheeler, Murray de la unión 
del compañero asistió a la unión de trabajadores de granja, la 
asociación de trabajo Japone's-Mexicana (JMLA), en negociaciones con 
los Western Agricultural Contracting Company, que contrajeron a 
trabajadores para los granjeros locales de la remolacha. Cuando 
la federación americana del trabajo rechazó conceder una carta al 
JMLA a menos que la unión excluyera a todos los trabajadores 
asiáticos, Murray escribió este artículo, "un anticipo del 
Oriente," como chronicle de la huelga y como crítica penetrante de la
denegación del AFL para validar a trabajadores asiáticos y 
Africano-Americanos como miembros.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087298</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103123</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-foretaste-of-the-orient-john-murray-criticizes-the-afl</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
