<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108667</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108667</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087256</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Yale Professor William Graham Sumner Prescribes Laissez-Faire for Depression Woes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Yale Professor William Graham Sumner Prescribes 
Laissez-Faire für Tiefstand-Elende</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Professeur William Graham Sumner Prescribes 
Laissez-Faire de Yale pour des ennuis de dépression</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Professor William Graham Sumner Prescrever 
Laissez-Faire de Yale para woes do depression</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il professor William Graham Sumner Prescribes 
Laissez-Faire di Yale per la noia di depressione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Yale καθηγητής William Graham Sumner 
Prescribes Laissez-Faire για τις θλίψεις κατάθλιψης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Profesor Guillermo Graham Sumner Prescribes 
Laissez-Faire de Yale para las aflicciones de la depresión</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">With depression looming as a continual threat to the U.S. economy in the late 19th century, Americans debated how the government should respond to hard times--a question still unanswered today. Manufacturers--then as now--usually took the position that government should not interfere with the workings of the "free market." Manufacturers found support for their laissez-faire positions in the speeches and writings of the leading academic experts of the day. On August 22, 1878, Yale faculty member William Graham Sumner testified before a select committee of the U.S. House of Representatives charged with investigating the Causes of the General Depression in Labor and Business. Sumner preached a strict "hands-off" approach to ameliorating the widespread economic dislocations then plaguing the country.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wenn der Tiefstand als kontinuierliche Drohung 
auftaucht, zur VEREINIGTE STAATEN Wirtschaft im des späten 19. 
jahrhunderts Jahrhundert, debattierten Amerikaner, wie die Regierung 
auf harte Zeiten noch reagieren sollte -- eine Frage, die heute 
unbeantwortet ist. Hersteller -- dann als jetzt -- nahmen 
normalerweise die Position, daß Regierung nicht die Funktionen des 
"freien Marktes behinderen sollte." Hersteller fanden Support 
für ihre Laissez-Faire Positionen in den Reden und in den Schreiben 
der führenden akademischen Experten des Tages. An August 22, 
1878, Yale Lehrkörperbauteil William Graham Sumner bezeugte, bevor 
ein auserwählter Ausschuß des VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Repräsentantenhauses mit dem Nachforschen der Ursachen des 
allgemeinen Tiefstands in der Arbeit und im Geschäft auflud. 
Sumner predigte strenge "Hände-weg" sich nähern zum Verbessern
der weitverbreiteten ökonomischen Versetzungen, die dann das Land 
quälen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Avec la dépression apparaissant indistinctement 
comme menace continuelle à l'économie des ETATS-UNIS vers la fin du 
19ème siècle, les Américains ont discuté comment le gouvernement 
devrait répondre aux périodes difficiles -- une question encore sans
réponse aujourd'hui. Les constructeurs -- puis en tant que 
maintenant -- ont habituellement pris la position que le gouvernement 
ne devrait pas gêner les fonctionnements "du marché libre." 
Les constructeurs ont trouvé le soutien de leurs positions de 
laissez-faire dans les discours et les écritures des principaux 
experts en matière d'universitaire du jour. 22 août 1878, 
membre William Graham Sumner de corps enseignant de Yale a témoigné 
avant qu'un comité choisi de la chambre des représentants des 
ETATS-UNIS ait chargé d'étudier les causes de la dépression 
générale dans le travail et les affaires. Sumner a prêché 
les "mains-hors fonction" strictes s'approchent à améliorer les 
dislocations économiques répandues infestant alors le pays.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Com o depression que aparece como uma ameaça 
contínua à economia de ESTADOS UNIDOS no 1ø século atrasado, os 
americanos debateram como o governo deve responder às épocas duras 
-- uma pergunta ainda não respondida hoje. Os fabricantes -- 
então como agora -- fizeram exame geralmente da posição que o 
governo não deve interferir com os funcionamentos "do mercado livre."
Os fabricantes encontraram a sustentação para suas posições 
do laissez-faire nos discursos e nas escritas dos peritos academic 
principais do dia. Agosto em 22, 1878, membro William Graham 
Sumner da faculdade de Yale testified antes que um comitê seleto da 
casa de ESTADOS UNIDOS de representantes carregou com investigar as 
causas do depression geral no trabalho e no negócio. Sumner 
preached as "mãos-fora estritas" aproxima-se a melhorar os 
dislocations econômicos difundidos que flagelam então o país.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Con la depressione che appare in lontananza come 
minaccia continua all'economia degli STATI UNITI verso la fine del 
diciannovesimo secolo, gli Americani hanno dibattuto come il governo 
dovrebbe rispondere ancora ai periodi duri -- una domanda senza 
risposta oggi. I fornitori -- allora come ora -- hanno preso 
solitamente la posizione che il governo non dovrebbe interferire con i
funzionamenti "del mercato libero." I fornitori hanno trovato il
sostegno le loro posizioni di "laissez faire" nei discorsi e nelle 
scritture degli esperti accademici principali del giorno. Il 22 
agosto 1878, il membro William Graham Sumner della facoltà di Yale ha
testimoniato prima di un comitato ristretto della Camera dei 
rappresentanti degli STATI UNITI caricati dello studio delle cause 
della depressione generale nel Lavoro e nel commercio. 
Sumner ha predicato "mani-fuori" rigorose si avvicina a a 
migliorare le dislocazioni economiche diffuse allora che contagiano il
paese.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Με την κατάθλιψη που εμφανίζεται ως συνεχής απειλή 
στην ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ οικονομία προς το τέλος του 19$ου αιώνα, 
Αμερικανοί συζήτησαν πώς η κυβέρνηση πρέπει να αποκριθεί στους 
σκληρούς χρόνους -- μια ερώτηση ακόμα αναπάντητη σήμερα. 
Οι κατασκευαστές -- έπειτα όπως τώρα -- συνήθως 
υποστήριξαν τη θέση ότι η κυβέρνηση δεν πρέπει να παρεμποδίσει 
τα έργα της "ελεύθερης αγοράς." Οι κατασκευαστές βρήκαν την
υποστήριξη για τις θέσεις ελεύθερης οικονομίας τους στις ομιλίες 
και τις γραφές των κύριων ακαδημαϊκών εμπειρογνωμόνων της 
ημέρας. Στις 22 Αυγούστου ..1878, το μέλος William 
Graham Sumner ικανότητας Yale πιστοποίησε ενώπιον μιας 
επίλεκτης επιτροπής του ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΥ οίκου των αντιπροσώπων που 
χρεώθηκε με την έρευνα των αιτιών της γενικής κατάθλιψης στην 
εργασία και την επιχείρηση. Το Sumner κήρυξε μια ακριβή 
"hands-off" προσέγγιση στη βελτίωση των διαδεδομένων 
οικονομικών εξαρθρώσεων που μολύνουν έπειτα τη χώρα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Con la depresión asomando como amenaza continua a
la economía de ESTADOS UNIDOS en la a fines del siglo XIX, los 
americanos discutieron cómo el gobierno debe todavía responder a las
épocas duras -- una pregunta por contestar hoy. Los fabricantes
-- entonces como ahora -- tomaron generalmente la posición que el 
gobierno no debe interferir con los funcionamientos del "mercado 
libre." Los fabricantes encontraron la ayuda para sus posiciones
del liberalismo en los discursos y las escrituras de los expertos 
académicos principales del día. 22 de agosto de 1878, 
miembro Guillermo Graham Sumner de la facultad de Yale atestiguó 
antes de que un comité selecto de la cámara de ESTADOS UNIDOS de 
representantes cargara con investigar las causas de la depresión 
general en trabajo y negocio. Sumner predicó las "manos-apagado
terminantes" se acerca a mejorar las dislocaciones económicas 
extensas entonces que plagaban el país.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087256</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108667</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/yale-professor-william-graham-sumner-prescribes-laissez-faire-for-depression-woes</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
