<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103881</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103881</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206829</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Neuroscience for Kids</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Neurologie für Zicklein</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Neurologie pour des gosses</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Neuroscience para miúdos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Neuroscienza per i capretti</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Νευρολογία για τα κατσίκια</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Neurología para los cabritos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">explores the brain and nervous system. Learn about brain development, brain lobes, the cerebral cortex, the skull, blood supply, brain fitness, neurons, the autonomic nervous system, sensory systems, the spinal cord, laughter and the brain, the musical brain, face recognition, drug effects, neurological and mental disorders, and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erforscht das Gehirn und das nervöse System. 
Erlernen Sie über Gehirnentwicklung, Gehirnvorsprung, die 
zerebrale Rinde, der Schädel, Blutzubehör, Gehirneignung, Neuronen, 
das autonome nervöse System, sensorische Systeme, das Rückenmark, 
Gelächter und das Gehirn, das musikalische Gehirn, die Gesicht 
Anerkennung, die Drogenwirkungen, neurologische und Geistesstörungen 
und mehr.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">explore le cerveau et le système nerveux. 
Renseignez-vous sur le développement de cerveau, les lobes de 
cerveau, le cortex cérébral, le crâne, approvisionnement de sang, 
forme physique de cerveau, neurones, le système nerveux autonome, les
systèmes sensoriels, le cordon médullaire, rire et le cerveau, le 
cerveau musical, l'identification de visage, les effets de la drogue, 
des troubles neurologiques et mentaux, et plus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">explora o cérebro e o sistema nervoso. 
Aprenda sobre o desenvolvimento do cérebro, os lóbulos do 
cérebro, o cortex cerebral, o skull, fonte do sangue, aptidão do 
cérebro, neurônios, o sistema nervoso autonomic, sistemas sensory, o
cabo spinal, laughter e o cérebro, o cérebro musical, o recognition 
da cara, os efeitos de droga, disorders neurological e mentais, e 
mais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esplora il cervello ed il sistema nervoso. 
Impari circa sviluppo del cervello, lobi del cervello, la 
corteccia cerebrale, il cranio, rifornimento di anima, idoneità del 
cervello, neuroni, il sistema nervoso autonomo, sistemi sensoriali, il
midollo spinale, laughter ed il cervello, il cervello musicale, il 
riconoscimento della faccia, gli effetti della droga, disturbi 
neurologici e mentali e più.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ερευνά τον εγκέφαλο και το νευρικό σύστημα. 
Μάθετε για την ανάπτυξη εγκεφάλου, τους λοβούς εγκεφάλου, 
τον εγκεφαλικό φλοιό, το κρανίο, τον ανεφοδιασμό αίματος, την 
ικανότητα εγκεφάλου, τους νευρώνες, το αυτόνομο νευρικό σύστημα,
τα αισθητήρια συστήματα, το νωτιαίο μυελό, το γέλιο και τον 
εγκέφαλο, το μουσικά εγκέφαλο, την αναγνώριση προσώπου, τα 
αποτελέσματα φαρμάκων, τις νευρολογικές και διανοητηκές 
διαταραχές, και περισσότερους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">explora el cerebro y el sistema nervioso. 
Aprenda sobre el desarrollo del cerebro, los lóbulos del 
cerebro, la corteza cerebral, el cráneo, fuente de la sangre, aptitud
del cerebro, las neuronas, el sistema nervioso autonómico, los 
sistemas sensoriales, la médula espinal, risa y el cerebro, el 
cerebro musical, el reconocimiento de la cara, los efectos de la 
droga, los desórdenes neurológicos y mentales, y más.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206829</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103881</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/neuroscience-for-kids</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
