<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103544</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103544</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087216</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Welfare capitalism and its conceits.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wohlfahrt Kapitalismus und seine Einbildungen.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Capitalisme d'assistance sociale et ses vanités.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Capitalismo de bem-estar e seus conceits.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Capitalismo di assistenza sociale ed i relativi 
conceits.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κεφαλαιοκρατία ευημερίας και οι αλαζονείες του.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Capitalismo de bienestar y sus conceits.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A 1929 installment of J. R. Williams's popular comic strip  Out Our Way  poked fun at the illusions held by some of the workers who bought stocks in the companies that employed them. High wages, good benefits, and employee welfare programs became means for large employers to maintain stable labor relations. Besides stock-purchase plans, some companies offered pensions, subsidized housing and mortgages, insurance, and sports programs. In many cases, these employee welfare programs were distributed through company unions</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Ratenzahlung 1929 J. R. Williams des populären 
komischen Streifens aus unserer Methode stieß Spaß an den 
Illusionen, die von einigen der Arbeiter angehalten wurden, die Aktien
in den Firmen kauften, die sie beschäftigten. Hohe Löhne, 
guter Nutzen und Angestelltwohlfahrt Programme wurden Mittel, damit 
große Arbeitgeber beständige Arbeitgeber-Arbeitnehmer-Beziehungen 
beibehalten. Außer Vorrat-kaufen Sie Pläne, einige Firmen, die
Pensionen angeboten werden, subventioniertes Gehäuse und Hypotheken, 
Versicherung und sports Programme. In vielen Fällen wurden 
diese Angestelltwohlfahrt Programme durch Betriebsgewerkschaften 
verteilt</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un acompte 1929 de présentation horizontale sur microfilm
populaire de J. R. Williams hors de notre voie a poussé l'amusement 
aux illusions tenues par certains des ouvriers qui ont acheté des 
stocks aux compagnies qui les ont employées. Les salaires 
élevés, les bons avantages, et les programmes d'assistance sociale 
des employés sont devenus des moyens pour que les grands employeurs 
mettent à jour des relations sociales stables. Sans compter que
provision-achetez les plans, quelques compagnies offertes des 
pensions, le logement subventionné et les hypothèques, assurance, et
fôlatrez des programmes. Dans beaucoup de cas, ces programmes 
d'assistance sociale des employés ont été distribués par des 
syndicat-maisons</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uma prestação 1929 da tira comic popular de J. R. 
Williams para fora de nossa maneira picou o divertimento nos illusions
prendidos por alguns dos trabalhadores que compraram o estoque nas 
companhias que as empregaram. Os salários elevados, os 
benefícios bons, e os programas do bem-estar do empregado 
transformaram-se meios para que os empregadores grandes mantenham 
relações labor estáveis. Além de estoque-compre plantas, 
algumas companhias oferecidas pensões, a carcaça subsidized e os 
mortgages, seguro, e ostente programas. Em muitos casos, estes 
programas do bem-estar do empregado foram distribuídos através das 
uniões de companhia</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Una rata 1929 della striscia comic popolare del J. R. 
Williams verso l'esterno il nostro modo ha colpito il divertimento 
alle illusioni tenute da alcuni degli operai che hanno comprato gli 
stock nelle aziende che le hanno impiegate. Gli alti stipendi, i
buoni benefici ed i programmi di assistenza sociale degli impiegati si
sono transformati in in mezzi affinchè i grandi datori di lavoro 
effettuino i rapporti di lavoro stabili. Oltre a azione-compri 
i programmi, alcune aziende offerte le pensioni, l'alloggiamento 
sovvenzionato e le ipoteche, assicurazione e mette in mostra i 
programmi. In molti casi, questi programmi di assistenza sociale
degli impiegati sono stati distribuiti attraverso i sindacati di 
azienda</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια δόση του 1929 της δημοφιλούς σειράς κόμικς Θ*ι.
Ρ. Ουίλιαμς έξω ο τρόπος μας έσπρωξε τη διασκέδαση στις 
παραισθήσεις που κατέχουν μερικοί από τους εργαζομένους που 
αγόρασαν τα αποθέματα στις επιχειρήσεις που τους χρησιμοποίησαν. 
Οι υψηλές αμοιβές, τα καλά οφέλη, και τα προγράμματα 
ευημερίας υπαλλήλων έγιναν μέσα για τους μεγάλους εργοδότες να 
διατηρήσουν τις σταθερές σχέσεις εργασίας. Εκτός από τα 
σχέδια απόθεμα-αγορών, μερικές επιχειρήσεις πρόσφεραν τις 
συντάξεις, την επιδοτούμενες κατοικία και τις υποθήκες, την 
ασφάλεια, και τα αθλητικά προγράμματα. Σε πολλές 
περιπτώσεις, αυτά τα προγράμματα ευημερίας υπαλλήλων 
διανεμήθηκαν μέσω των ενώσεων επιχείρησης</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una instalación 1929 de la historieta popular de J. R. 
Williams fuera de nuestra manera empujó la diversión en las 
ilusiones llevadas a cabo por algunos de los trabajadores que 
compraron la acción en las compañías que las emplearon. Los 
altos salarios, las buenas ventajas, y los programas del bienestar del
empleado se convirtieron en medios para que los patrones grandes 
mantengan relaciones de trabajo estables. Además de 
accio'n-compre los planes, algunas compañías ofrecidas pensiones, la
cubierta subvencionada y las hipotecas, seguro, y se divierte 
programas. En muchos casos, estos programas del bienestar del 
empleado fueron distribuidos a través de uniones de compañía</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087216</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103544</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/welfare-capitalism-and-its-conceits</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
