<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104260</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104260</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086175</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Freedom or death.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Freiheit oder Tod.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Liberté ou mort.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Liberdade ou morte.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Libertà o morte.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ελευθερία ή θάνατος.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Libertad o muerte.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Soon after passage of the Fugitive-Slave Law, Margaret Garner fled from her Kentucky master with her four children. Slave patrollers followed her to Ohio. Faced with capture, Garner killed two of her children rather than have them return to slavery. The surviving children were taken from her and, on the return trip to Kentucky, Garner drowned herself in the Ohio River. Her story inspired an acclaimed nineteenth-century painting by Thomas S. Noble (on which this engraving was based) and Toni Morrison's Pulitzer Prize novel,  Beloved .</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bald nach Durchgang des Flüchtling-Sklave Gesetzes, floh 
Margaret Speicher von ihrem Kentucky Meister mit ihren vier Kindern. 
Sklavenpatrollers folgten ihr nach Ohio. 
Gegenübergestellt mit Sicherung, beendete Speicher, zwei ihrer 
Kinder anstatt hat sie Rückhol zur Sklaverei. Die überlebenden
Kinder wurden von ihr und, auf der Rückreise nach Kentucky genommen, 
ansammeln ertrunken im Ohio Fluß. Ihre Geschichte spornte einen
mit Beifall begrüßten 19.-Jahrhundert Anstrich durch Thomas S. Noble
(auf, welchem dieser Stich basierte) und Toni Morrisons Pulitzer den 
Prize Roman an, geliebt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Peu après le passage de la loi de Fugitive-slave, le 
grenier de Margaret s'est sauvé de son maître du Kentucky avec ses
quatre enfants. Les patrollers slaves l'ont suivie en Ohio.
Confronté à la saisie, le grenier a détruit deux de ses 
enfants plutôt que les a de retour à l'esclavage. Les enfants 
survivants ont été portés d'elle et, en voyage de retour au 
Kentucky, recueillent noyé dans le fleuve de l'Ohio. Son 
histoire a inspiré une peinture acclamée de dix-neuvième-siècle 
par Thomas S. Noble (sur ce que cette gravure a été basée) et roman
professionnel de Pulitzer de Toni Morrison, aimé.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Logo após a passagem da lei do Fugitive-Escravo, o garner
de Margaret fujiu de seu mestre de Kentucky com suas quatro crianças.
Os patrollers slave seguiram-na a Ohio. Enfrentado com 
captação, o garner matou duas de suas crianças melhor que tem-nas 
do retorno ao slavery. As crianças sobrevivendo foram feitas 
exame dela e, no desengate do retorno a Kentucky, garner afogado no 
rio de Ohio. Sua história inspirou uma pintura aclamada de 
décimo-século por Thomas S. Nobre (em qual este engraving foi 
baseado) e pela novela premiada de Pulitzer de Toni Morrison, beloved.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Presto dopo il passaggio della legge dello 
Fuggitivo-Schiavo, il garner di Margaret è fuggito dal suo 
supervisore del Kentucky con i suoi quattro bambini. I 
patrollers slave la hanno seguita nell'Ohio. Affrontato al 
bloccaggio, il garner ha ucciso due dei suoi bambini piuttosto che li 
ha di ritorno a slavery. I bambini sopravviventi sono stati 
presi da lei e, sul viaggio di ritorno nel Kentucky, garner annegato 
nel fiume dell'Ohio. La sua storia ha ispirato una pittura 
applaudita di diciannovesimo-secolo da Thomas S. Noble (su quale 
questa incisione è stata basata) e dal romanzo premiato di Pulitzer 
di Toni Morrison, caro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σύντομα μετά από τη μετάβαση του νόμου 
πρόσφυγας-σκλάβων, Margaret Garner που από τον κύριο του 
Κεντάκυ της με τέσσερα παιδιά της. Τα patrollers σκλάβων 
την ακολούθησαν στο Οχάιο. Αντιμέτωπος με τη σύλληψη, 
συγκεντρώστε σκοτωμένα δύο από τα παιδιά της παρά να αυτοί 
υπάρξουν να επιστρέψουν στη σκλαβιά. Τα επιζόντα παιδιά 
λήφθηκαν από την και, στο επιστροφής ταξίδι στο Κεντάκυ, 
συγκεντρώνουν πνιμμένος στον ποταμό του Οχάιου. Η ιστορία 
της ενέπνευσε μια επευφημημένη ζωγραφική δέκατος-αιώνα από τον 
Thomas S. Noble (στην οποία αυτή η χάραξη ήταν 
βασισμένη) και Toni Morrison's βραβείο Pulitzer νέο, 
αγαπημένος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Pronto después del paso de la ley del Fugitivo-Esclavo, 
el garner de Margaret huyó de su amo de Kentucky con sus cuatro 
niños. Los patrollers auxiliares la siguieron a Ohio. 
Hecho frente con captura, el garner mató a dos de sus niños 
más bien que los tiene de vuelta a la esclavitud. Llevaron de 
ella y, en el viaje de vuelta a Kentucky, garner los niños que 
sobrevivían ahogado en el río de Ohio. Su historia inspiró 
una pintura aclamada del diecinueveavo-siglo por Thomas S. Noble (en 
cuál fue basado este grabado) y la novela premiada de Pulitzer de 
Toni Morrison, querida.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086175</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104260</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/freedom-or-death</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
