<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108669</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108669</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205291</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">You've Come a Long Way, Baby</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sie sind ein langer Weg, Baby gekommen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Vous êtes venu un long chemin, bébé</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Você veio uma maneira longa, bebê</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Siete venuto un modo lungo, bambino</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Έχετε έρθει ένας μακροχρόνιος τρόπος, μωρό</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Usted ha venido una manera larga, bebé</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">1900 House is PBS' twist on reality television (for example, the popular series Survivor), in which a group of people are put in unusual surroundings and their every move is videotaped. Here we are privy to the life of a family that has volunteered to simulate life in 1900 England for three months. Through their experiences the viewer gains an appreciation for just how much life has changed in the last 100 years. By watching these video clips and completing the activities, students will gain a perspective on and an appreciation for how drastically life has changed in the last 100 years, especially for women.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Haus 1900 ist Torsion PBS' auf Wirklichkeit 
Fernsehen (zum Beispiel, der populäre Serie Überlebende), in dem 
eine Gruppe Leute in ungewöhnliche Umlagerungen eingesetzt werden und
ihre jede Bewegung videotaped. Hier sind wir zum Leben einer 
Familie geheim, die sich freiwillig erboten hat, das Leben England 
1900 für drei Monate zu simulieren. Durch ihre Erfahrungen 
gewinnt der Projektor eine Anerkennung für, gerade wieviel das Leben 
in den letzten 100 Jahren geändert hat. Indem sie diese 
Bildschirmclips überwachen und die Aktivitäten durchführen, 
gewinnen Kursteilnehmer eine Perspektive an und eine Anerkennung für,
wie drastisch das Leben in den letzten 100 Jahren geändert hat, 
besonders für Frauen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">la Chambre 1900 est la torsion de PBS à la 
télévision de réalité (par exemple, le survivant populaire de 
série), en laquelle un groupe de personnes sont mis dans des 
environnements peu communs et leur chaque mouvement est enregistré en
vidéo. Ici nous sommes privés à la vie d'une famille qui a 
offert pour simuler la vie en l'Angleterre 1900 pendant trois mois. 
Par leurs expériences le visualisateur gagne une appréciation 
pour juste combien la vie a changé en 100 dernières années. 
En observant ces clips de vidéo et en terminant les activités,
les étudiants gagneront une perspective en fonction et une 
appréciation pour la façon dont rigoureusement la vie a changé en 
100 dernières années, particulièrement pour des femmes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">a casa 1900 é torção de PBS' na televisão da 
realidade (para o exemplo, o sobrevivente popular da série), em que 
um grupo de povos é posto em arredors incomuns e seu cada movimento 
é gravado. Aqui nós somos privy à vida de uma família que se
ofereça para simular a vida em Inglaterra 1900 por três meses. 
Com suas experiências o visor ganha uma apreciação para 
apenas quanto a vida mudou nos últimos 100 anos. Prestando 
atenção a estes grampos do vídeo e terminando as atividades, os 
estudantes ganharão um perspective sobre e uma apreciação para como
dràstica a vida mudou nos últimos 100 anos, especial para mulheres.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">la Camera 1900 è torsione del PBS sulla 
televisione di realtà (per esempio, il superstite popolare di serie),
in cui un gruppo di persone è messo nei dintorni insoliti ed il loro 
ogni movimento è registrato. Qui siamo privy alla vita di una 
famiglia che si è offerta volontariamente per simulare la vita in 
Inghilterra 1900 per tre mesi. Con le loro esperienze il visore 
guadagna un apprezzamento per appena quanto la vita ha cambiato 
durante i 100 anni ultimi. Guardando queste clip del video e 
completando le attività, gli allievi guadagneranno una prospettiva 
sopra e un apprezzamento per quanto drasticamente la vita è cambiato 
durante i 100 anni ultimi, particolarmente per le donne.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">1900 το σπίτι είναι συστροφή PBS στην τηλεόραση
πραγματικότητας (παραδείγματος χάριν, ο δημοφιλής επιζών 
σειράς), στην οποία μια ομάδα ανθρώπων τίθεται στα ασυνήθιστα 
περίχωρα και την κάθε κίνησή τους είναι βιντεοσκοπημένος. 
Εδώ είμαστε μυημένοι στη ζωή μιας οικογένειας που έχει 
προσφερθεί εθελοντικά να μιμηθεί τη ζωή το 1900 Αγγλία για 
τρεις μήνες. Μέσω της εμπειρίας τους η εμφάνιση κερδίζει 
μια εκτίμηση για ακριβώς πόση ζωή έχει αλλάξει τα τελευταία 
100 χρόνια. Με την προσοχή αυτών των τηλεοπτικών 
συνδετήρων και την ολοκλήρωση των δραστηριοτήτων, οι σπουδαστές θα
κερδίσουν μια προοπτική επάνω και μια εκτίμηση για πόσο δραστικά
η ζωή έχει αλλάξει τα τελευταία 100 χρόνια, ειδικά για τις 
γυναίκες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">la casa 1900 es torcedura de PBS en la televisión
de la realidad (por ejemplo, el sobreviviente popular de la serie), en
la cual ponen a un grupo de gente en alrededores inusuales y se graba 
su cada movimiento. Aquí somos privy a la vida de una familia 
que se ha ofrecido voluntariamente a simular vida en Inglaterra 1900 
por tres meses. Con sus experiencias el espectador gana un 
aprecio para apenas cuánto la vida ha cambiado en los 100 años 
pasados. Mirando estos clips del vídeo y terminando las 
actividades, los estudiantes ganarán una perspectiva encendido y un 
aprecio para cómo la vida ha cambiado drástico en los 100 años 
pasados, especialmente para las mujeres.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205291</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108669</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/youve-come-a-long-way-baby</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
