<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103400</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103400</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207216</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">We the People... The Citizen and the Constitution</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wir die Leute... Der Bürger und die 
Beschaffenheit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Nous le peuple... Le citoyen et la 
constitution</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nós os povos... O cidadão e o 
constitution</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Noi la gente... Il cittadino e la 
costituzione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εμείς οι άνθρωποι... Ο πολίτης και το σύνταγμα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Nosotros la gente... El ciudadano y la 
constitución</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Helps elementary and secondary school students understand the history and principles of our constitutional government. The program focuses on the U.S. Constitution and Bill of Rights and fosters civic competence and responsibility. Upon completion of program, classes are encouraged to participate in simulated congressional hearings that allow students to demonstrate their knowledge of the Constitution and the Bill of Rights.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die grundlegenden Hilfen und die 
Sekundärschulekursteilnehmer verstehen die Geschichte und die 
Grundregeln unserer konstitutionellen Staatsform. Das Programm 
konzentriert auf die VEREINIGTE STAATEN Beschaffenheit und die 
Verfassung und fördert bürgerliche Kompetenz und Verantwortlichkeit.
Nach Beendigung des Programms, werden Kategorien angeregt, an 
simulierten Kongreßhörfähigkeiten teilzunehmen, die Kursteilnehmern
erlauben, ihr Wissen der Beschaffenheit und die Verfassung zu 
demonstrieren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les aides élémentaires et les étudiants 
d'école secondaire comprennent l'histoire et les principes de notre 
gouvernement constitutionnel. Le programme se concentre sur la 
constitution des ETATS-UNIS et la déclaration des droits et stimule 
la compétence et la responsabilité civiques. Sur 
l'accomplissement du programme, des classes sont encouragées à 
participer aux auditions congressionnelles simulées qui permettent à
des étudiants de démontrer leur connaissance de la constitution et 
la déclaration des droits.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As ajudas elementares e os estudantes da escola 
secundária compreendem o history e os princípios de nosso governo 
constitutional. O programa focaliza no constitution de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS e na conta de direitas e promove o competence e a 
responsabilidade civic. Em cima da conclusão do programa, as 
classes são incentivadas participar nos hearings congressionais 
simulados que permitem que os estudantes demonstrem seu conhecimento 
do constitution e a conta de direitas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli aiuti elementari e gli allievi della scuola 
secondaria capiscono la storia ed i principii del nostro governo 
costituzionale. Il programma si concentrare sulla costituzione 
degli STATI UNITI e sulla fattura dei diritti e promuove la competenza
e la responsabilità civiche. A completamento del programma, i 
codici categoria sono consigliati a partecipare alle udienze 
congressuali simulate che permettono che gli allievi dimostrino la 
loro conoscenza della costituzione e la fattura dei diritti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι σπουδαστές στοιχειώδους και δευτεροβάθμιας 
εκπαίδευσης οδηγιών καταλαβαίνουν την ιστορία και τις αρχές της 
συνταγματικής κυβέρνησής μας. Το πρόγραμμα εστιάζει στο 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ σύνταγμα και το Bill των δικαιωμάτων και ενθαρρύνει 
την πολιτικές ικανότητα και την ευθύνη. Με την ολοκλήρωση 
του προγράμματος, οι κλάσεις ενθαρρύνονται για να συμμετέχουν στις
μιμούμενες του Κογκρέσου ακροάσεις που επιτρέπουν στους 
σπουδαστές για να καταδείξουν τη γνώση τους του συντάγματος και 
του Bill των δικαιωμάτων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las ayudas elementales y los estudiantes de la 
escuela secundaria entienden la historia y los principios de nuestro 
gobierno constitucional. El programa se centra en la 
constitución de ESTADOS UNIDOS y la cuenta de las derechas y fomenta 
capacidad y responsabilidad cívicas. Sobre la terminación del 
programa, se anima a las clases participen en las audiencias del 
congreso simuladas que permiten que los estudiantes demuestren su 
conocimiento de la constitución y la cuenta de las derechas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207216</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103400</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/we-the-people-the-citizen-and-the-constitution</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
