<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107510</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107510</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086661</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">New faces.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Neue Gesichter.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Nouveaux visages.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Caras novas.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sconosciuti.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Νέα πρόσωπα.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Caras nuevas.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The human cost of World War I was enormous. The prolonged trench warfare ended the lives of 1.8 million Germans, 1.7 million Russians, 1.4 million French, 1.2 million Austro-Hungarians, and over 900,000 British. 112,000 American troops also died, mostly from disease. Many of those who didn't die were left with horrible wounds. Here, plaster casts of the mutilated faces of soldiers wounded in battle are shown next to their reconstructions, carried out with the aid of new prosthetic devices. They represent one legacy of the First World War and the imperfect attempts to contend with its gruesome effects.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die menschlichen Kosten des Ersten Weltkrieges waren 
enorm. Die verlängerte Grabenkriegsführung beendete die 
Lebensdauern von 1.8 Million Deutschen, 1.7 Million Russen, 1.4 
Million Franzosen, 1.2 Million Austro-Ungarn und über 900.000 Briten.
112.000 amerikanische Truppen starben auch, meistens an der 
Krankheit. Viele von denen, die nicht starben, wurden mit 
schrecklichen Wunden gelassen. Hier werden Pflasterformen der 
verstümmelten Gesichter der Soldaten, die in der Schlacht verwundet 
werden, nahe bei ihren Rekonstruktionen gezeigt, durchgeführt mit dem
Hilfsmittel der neuen prothetischen Einheiten. Sie stellen eine 
Legacy des ersten Weltkrieges und der unvollständigen Versuche, mit 
seinen grauenhaften Effekten zu ringen dar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le coût humain de Première Guerre Mondiale était 
énorme. La guerre prolongée de fossé a terminé les vies de 
1.8 million d'Allemands, 1.7 million de Russes, 1.4 million de 
Français, 1.2 million d'Austro-Hongrois, et plus de 900.000 Anglais. 
112.000 troupes américaines sont également mortes, la plupart 
du temps de la maladie. Beaucoup de ceux qui ne sont pas morts 
ont été laissés avec les blessures horribles. Ici, des fontes
de plâtre des visages mutilés des soldats enroulés dans la bataille
sont montrées à côté de leurs reconstructions, effectuées à 
l'aide de nouveaux dispositifs prosthétiques. Elles 
représentent un legs de la première guerre mondiale et des 
tentatives imparfaites de faire face à ses effets horribles.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O custo humano do world.war.i era enorme. A guerra 
prolongada da trincheira terminou as vidas de 1.8 milhão alemães, 
1.7 milhão russians, 1.4 milhão franceses, 1.2 milhão 
Austro-austro-Hungarians, e sobre 900.000 Ingleses. 112.000 
tropas americanas morreram também, na maior parte da doença. 
Muita daquelas que não morreram foi deixada com as feridas 
horrible. Aqui, os moldes do emplastro das caras mutiladas dos 
soldados feridos na batalha são mostrados ao lado de seus 
reconstructions, realizados com o dae (dispositivo automático de 
entrada) de dispositivos protéticos novos. Representam um 
legacy da primeira guerra de mundo e das tentativas imperfeitas 
contend com seus efeitos gruesome.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il costo umano del world.war.i era enorme. La guerra
prolungata della trincea si è conclusa le vite di 1.8 milione 
tedeschi, 1.7 milione Russi, 1.4 milione francesi, 1.2 milione 
Austro-Ungheresi ed oltre 900.000 Britannici. 112.000 truppe 
americane egualmente sono morto, principalmente dalla malattia. 
Molti di coloro che non è morto sono stati lasciati con le 
ferite horrible. Qui, i getti dell'intonaco delle facce mutilate
dei soldati feriti nella battaglia sono indicati vicino alle loro 
ricostruzioni, effettuate con l'aiuto di nuovi dispositivi prostetici.
Rappresentano un'eredità della prima guerra mondiale e dei 
tentativi imperfetti contendersi con i relativi effetti orribili.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το ανθρώπινο κόστος του παγκόσμιου πολέμου ήμουν 
τεράστιος. Η παρατεταμένη εχθροπραξία τάφρων τελείωσε τις 
ζωές 1,8 εκατομμύριο Γερμανών, 1,7 εκατομμύριο Ρώσων, 
1,4 εκατομμύριο Γάλλων, 1,2 εκατομμύριο αυστροουγγρικών, και
πάνω από 900.000 Βρετανών. 112,000 Τα αμερικανικά 
στρατεύματα πέθαναν επίσης, συνήθως από την ασθένεια. 
Πολλοί από εκείνους που δεν πέθαναν αφέθηκαν με τις 
φρικτές πληγές. Εδώ, το ασβεστοκονίαμα πετά των 
ακρωτηριασμένων προσώπων του πληγωμένου στρατιωτών στη μάχη 
εμφανίζεται δίπλα στις αναδημιουργίες τους, που πραγματοποιούνται 
με την ενίσχυση των νέων προσθετικών συσκευών. 
Αντιπροσωπεύουν μια κληρονομιά του πρώτου παγκόσμιου 
πολέμου και των ατελών προσπαθειών να υποστηρίξουν με τα 
φρικιαστικά αποτελέσματά του.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El coste humano de Primera Guerra Mundial era enorme. 
La guerra prolongada del foso terminó las vidas de 1.8 millones
de alemanes, 1.7 millones de rusos, 1.4 millones de franceses, 1.2 
millones de Austro-Hu'ngaros, y sobre 900.000 Británicos. 
112.000 tropas americanas también murieron, sobre todo de 
enfermedad. Muchos de los que no murieron fueron dejados con las
heridas horribles. Aquí, los moldes del yeso de las caras 
mutiladas de los soldados heridos en batalla se muestran al lado de 
sus reconstrucciones, realizadas con la ayuda de nuevos dispositivos 
prostéticos. Representan una herencia de la primera guerra 
mundial y de las tentativas imperfectas de afirmar con sus efectos 
espantosos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086661</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107510</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/new-faces</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
