<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103254</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103254</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086838</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"So Must We Be One..., Otherwise We Shall Be All Gone Shortly": Narragansett Chief Miantonomi Tries to Form an Alliance Against Settlers in New England and Long Island, 1640s.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Müssen Wir Ein So Sein..., Andernfalls 
Werden Wir Ganz Kurz "Gegangen: Narragansett Hauptmiantonomi 
versucht, ein Bündnis gegen Siedleren in Neu-England und im Long 
Island, 1640s zu bilden.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Ainsi Devons Nous Être Un..., Autrement 
Nous Serons tout allés Sous peu ": Narragansett Miantonomi en 
chef essaye de former une alliance contre des colons en Nouvelle 
Angleterre et longue île, 1640s.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Assim Devemos Nós Ser Um..., Se não Nós 
Seremos idos Toda Logo ": Narragansett Miantonomi principal 
tenta dar forma a um alliance de encontro aos settlers em Nova 
Inglaterra e no console longo, 1640s.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Così Dobbiamo Essere Uno..., Altrimenti 
Interamente Saremo andati Presto ": Narragansett Miantonomi 
principale prova a formare un'alleanza contro i settlers in Nuova 
Inghilterra ed isola lunga, 1640s.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Έτσι πρέπει να είμαστε ένα..., Διαφορετικά θα 
είμαστε όλοι σύντομα ": Το Narragansett Προϊστάμενος 
Miantonomi προσπαθεί να διαμορφώσει μια συμμαχία ενάντια στους 
αποίκους στη Νέα Αγγλία και το μακρύ νησί, 1640s.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Tan Debemos Ser Uno..., Si no Nos Irán Todo
Pronto ": Narragansett principal Miantonomi intenta formar una 
alianza contra colonos en Nueva Inglaterra y la isla larga, 1640s.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Lion Gardener, author of this 1660 narrative, was an English military engineer who came to Connecticut in 1635 to oversee the construction of the fort and town of Saybrook. Thus he was present for the Pequot War of 1637, in which Connecticut settlers massacred the Pequot Indians. Gardener, who had advised against engaging with the Pequots, left Connecticut in 1639 and settled in Long Island. There he lived on Gardener's Island, which he bought from Wyandanch, the sachem (chief) of the Montaukett tribe, with whom he had friendly relations. In the early 1840s, Miantonomi, the sachem of the Narragansetts, a rival of the Montauketts, came to Long Island to create an alliance with the Montauketts and other local tribes against the English. Gardener and Wyandanch succeeded in contacting the leaders of nearby Connecticut for help, the plan was stopped, and Miantomi was captured and executed the following year.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Löwe-Gärtner, Autor von diesen 1660 Darstellung, war ein
englischer militärischer Ingenieur, der zu Connecticut 1635 kam, den 
Aufbau des Forts und Stadt von Saybrook zu beaufsichtigen. So 
war er für den Pequot Krieg von 1637 anwesend, in dem Connecticut 
Siedleren die Pequot Inder massakrierten. Gärtner, der gegen 
das Engagieren im Pequots, linkes Connecticut 1639 geraten hatte und 
im Long Island abgerechnet. Dort lebte er auf Insel des 
Gärtners, die er von Wyandanch kaufte, das sachem (Leiter) des 
Montaukett Stammes, mit dem er freundliche Relationen hatte. Im 
frühen 1840s kam Miantonomi, das sachem des Narragansetts, ein Rivale
des Montauketts, zum Long Island, ein Bündnis mit dem Montauketts und
andere lokale Stämme herzustellen gegen Englisch. Der Gärtner 
und Wyandanch, die gefolgt wurden, mit, mit den Führern von nahe 
gelegenem Connecticut für Hilfe in Verbindung zu treten, der Plan, 
gestoppt wurden, und Miantomi wurde erfaßt und das folgende Jahr 
durchführte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le jardinier de lion, auteur de ces 1660 récit, était un
ingénieur militaire anglais qui est venu au Connecticut en 1635 pour 
surveiller la construction du fort et la ville de Saybrook. 
Ainsi il était présent pour la guerre de Pequot de 1637, dans 
laquelle des colons du Connecticut massacrés les Indiens de Pequot. 
Jardinier, qui avait informé contre engager dans le Pequots, le
Connecticut gauche en 1639 et s'était établi en longue île. 
Là il a vécu sur l'île du jardinier, qu'il a achetée de 
Wyandanch, le sachem (chef) de la tribu de Montaukett, avec qui il a 
eu des relations amicales. Dans le 1840s tôt, Miantonomi, le 
sachem du Narragansetts, un rival du Montauketts, est venu à la 
longue île pour créer une alliance avec le Montauketts et d'autres 
tribus locales contre l'anglais. Le jardinier et le Wyandanch 
réussis en contactant les amorces du Connecticut voisin pour l'aide, 
le plan ont été arrêtés, et Miantomi a été capturé et a 
exécuté l'année suivante.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O gardener do leão, autor destes 1660 narrativa, era um 
coordenador militar inglês que viesse a Connecticut em 1635 oversee a
construção do fort e a cidade de Saybrook. Assim estava atual 
para a guerra de Pequot de 1637, em que os settlers de Connecticut 
massacred os indians de Pequot. Gardener, que tinha recomendado 
de encontro a acoplar com o Pequots, Connecticut esquerdo em 1639 e se
tinha estabelecido no console longo. Lá viveu no console do 
gardener, que comprou de Wyandanch, o sachem (chefe) do tribe de 
Montaukett, com quem teve relações amigáveis. No 1840s 
adiantado, Miantonomi, o sachem do Narragansetts, um rival do 
Montauketts, veio ao console longo criar um alliance com o Montauketts
e outros tribes locais de encontro ao inglês. O gardener e 
Wyandanch sucedidos em contatar os líderes de Connecticut próximo 
para a ajuda, a planta foram parados, e Miantomi foi capturado e 
executou o seguinte ano.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il giardiniere del leone, autore di questi 1660 
descrizione, era un assistente tecnico militare inglese che è venuto 
a Connecticut in 1635 sorvegliare la costruzione del forte e la 
città di Saybrook. Così era presente per la guerra di Pequot 
di 1637, in cui i settlers del Connecticut massacred gli indiani di 
Pequot. Giardiniere, che si era espresso contro l'aggancio con 
il Pequots, Connecticut di sinistra in 1639 e si era depositato in 
isola lunga. Là ha vissuto sull'isola del giardiniere, che ha 
comprato da Wyandanch, il sachem (capo) della tribù di Montaukett, 
con quale ha avuto rapporti amichevoli. Nel 1840s iniziale, 
Miantonomi, il sachem del Narragansetts, un rivale del Montauketts, è
venuto all'isola lunga creare un'alleanza con il Montauketts ed altre 
tribù locali contro l'inglese. Il giardiniere e Wyandanch 
riusciti a mettersi in contatto con i capi adi Connecticut 
vicino per aiuto, il programma sono stati arrestati e Miantomi è 
stato bloccato ed eseguito il seguente anno.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο κηπουρός λιονταριών, συντάκτης αυτού του αφηγήματος
1660, ήταν αγγλικός στρατιωτικός μηχανικός που ήρθε στο 
Κοννέκτικατ το 1635 να επιτηρήσει την κατασκευή του οχυρού και 
της πόλης Saybrook. Κατά συνέπεια ήταν παρών για τον 
πόλεμο Pequot 1637, στον οποίο οι άποικοι του Κοννέκτικατ 
κατάσφαξαν το Pequot Ινδοί. Ο κηπουρός, που είχε 
συμβουλεψει ενάντια στη δέσμευση με το Pequots, άφησε το 
Κοννέκτικατ το 1639 και εγκατέστησε στο μακρύ νησί. Εκεί
έζησε στο νησί του κηπουρού, το οποίο αγόρασε από Wyandanch, 
το sachem (προϊστάμενος) της φυλής Montaukett, με την οποία 
είχε τις φιλικές σχέσεις. Στο πρόωρο 1840s, 
Miantonomi, το sachem του Narragansetts, ένας ανταγωνιστής 
του Montauketts, ήρθε στο μακρύ νησί να δημιουργήσει μια 
συμμαχία με το Montauketts και άλλες τοπικές φυλές ενάντια 
στους Αγγλους. Τον κηπουρό και Wyandanch που πέτυχαν σε 
επαφή των ηγετών του κοντινού Κοννέκτικατ για τις οδηγίες, το 
σχέδιο σταμάτησαν, και Miantomi συλλήφθηκε και εκτελέσθηκε το 
επόμενο έτος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El jardinero del león, autor de estos 1660 narrativa, era
un ingeniero militar inglés que vino a Connecticut en 1635 supervisar
la construcción de la fortaleza y la ciudad de Saybrook. Así 
él estaba presente para la guerra de Pequot de 1637, en la cual los 
colonos de Connecticut masacraron a indios de Pequot. 
Jardinero, que había aconsejado contra el acoplamiento con el 
Pequots, Connecticut izquierdo en 1639 y había colocado en la isla 
larga. Allí él vivió en la isla del jardinero, que él 
compró de Wyandanch, el sachem (jefe) de la tribu de Montaukett, con 
la cual él tenía relaciones cómodas. En el 1840s temprano, 
Miantonomi, el sachem del Narragansetts, rival del Montauketts, vino a
la isla larga crear una alianza con el Montauketts y otras tribus 
locales contra el inglés. Pararon al jardinero y Wyandanch 
tenidos éxito en entrar en contacto con a los arranques de cinta de 
Connecticut próximo para la ayuda, el plan, y Miantomi fue capturado 
y ejecutó el año siguiente.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086838</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103254</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/so-must-we-be-one-otherwise-we-shall-be-all-gone-shortly-narragansett-chief-miantonomi-tries-to-form-an-alliance-against-settlers-in-new-england-and-long-island-1640s</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
