<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106273</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106273</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087472</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Cartoonists on the Picket Line: The Walt Disney Studio Strike</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Karikaturenzeichner auf der Pfosten-Zeile: 
Der Walt Disney Studio-Schlag</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Réalisateurs de dessins animés sur le piquet de 
grève : La Grève de Studio de Walt Disney</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Cartoonists na linha de piquete: A Batida Do
Estúdio De Walt Disney</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Cartoonists sulla riga di picchetto: Il 
Colpo Dell'Studio Del Walt Disney</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σκιτσογράφοι στη γραμμή στύλων: Η απεργία 
στούντιο Walt Disney</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Dibujantes en la línea de piquete: La 
Huelga Del Estudio De Walt Disney</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A wave of strikes in 1941 affected at least one West Coast industry previously untouched by the labor movement. By the 1930s, animation had become a significant sector of the Hollywood film industry, its production based on factorylike techniques of mass production. World War II deprived Walt Disney of his lucrative foreign market at just the moment when he needed it most; neither  Pinocchio  nor  Fantasia  had earned revenues to cover their high production costs and, with the expensive relocation of his studio to Burbank, Disney faced a $4.5 million debt. Relations with his employees worsened as Disney cut wages, laid off staff, and denied long-deferred bonuses. Answering writer Dorothy Parker's admonition "Don't let Mickey Mouse become a rat," other unions came to the support of the Disney strikers. The business agent of the Brotherhood of Painters, Decorators, and Paperhangers, Herb Sorrell, testified before a congressional subcommittee that the strikers were bolstered by sympathizers in the other animation studios, principally Warner Brothers' Schlesinger studio.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Welle von Schlägen in 1941 beeinflußte 
mindestens eine Westküsteindustrie, die durch die Arbeiterbewegung 
vorher unberührt ist. Bis zum den dreißiger Jahren war 
Animation ein bedeutender Sektor der Hollywood Filmindustrie, seine 
Produktion geworden, die auf factorylike Techniken der 
Großserienfertigung basierte. Der Zweite Weltkrieg beraubte 
Walt Disney seinen lukrativen Auslandsmarkt gerade am Moment, als er 
ihn am meisten benötigte; weder hatten Pinocchio noch Phantasie
Einkommen erworben, um ihre hohen Produktion Kosten zu umfassen und, 
mit der kostspieligen Verschiebung seines Studios nach Burbank, 
stellte Disney eine Schuld $4.5 Million gegenüber. Relationen 
mit seinen Angestellten verschlechterten sich, während Disney Löhne 
schnitt, Personal ablegte und lang-aufgeschobene Prämien verweigerte.
Antwortenden Verfasser Dorothy Parkers lassen Ermahnung 
"Mickymaus eine Ratte nicht werden," kamen andere Anschlüße zum 
Support der Disney Schlaggeräte. Der Handelsvertreter der 
Bruderschaft der Maler, der Dekorateure und des Paperhangers, Kraut 
Sorrell, bezeugte bevor eine Kongreßunterausschuß, daß die 
Schlaggeräte von den Gleichgesinnten in den anderen Animationstudios 
gepolstert wurden, allgemein Studio Schlesinger der Warner Brüder.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une vague des grèves dans 1941 a affecté au 
moins une industrie occidentale de côte précédemment intacte par le
mouvement de travail. Par les années 30, l'animation était 
devenue un secteur significatif de l'industrie de film de Hollywood, 
sa production basée sur des techniques de factorylike de production 
en série. La deuxième guerre mondiale a privé Walt Disney de 
son marché étranger lucratif juste au moment où il a eu besoin 
d'elle plus ; ni Pinocchio ni fantaisie n'avait gagné des 
revenus pour couvrir leurs coûts de production élevés et, avec le 
réadressage cher de son studio vers Burbank, Disney a fait face à 
une dette $4.5 millions. Les relations avec ses employés ont 
empiré pendant que Disney coupait des salaires, congédiait le 
personnel, et niait des bonifications long-reportées. La 
remontrance de Dorothy Parker de réponse d'auteur "ne laissent pas la
souris de Mickey devenir un rat," d'autres syndicats sont venus au 
support des butées de Disney. L'agent d'affaires commercial de 
la confrérie des peintres, des décorateurs, et du Paperhangers, 
herbe Sorrell, a témoigné avant qu'un sous-comité congressionnel 
que les butées ont été soutenues par des sympathisants dans les 
autres studios d'animation, principalement studio de Schlesinger des 
frères de Warner.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uma onda das batidas em 1941 afetou ao menos uma 
indústria ocidental da costa previamente untouched pelo movimento 
labor. Pelos 1930s, o animation tinha-se transformado um setor 
significativo da indústria da película de Hollywood, sua produção 
baseada em técnicas do factorylike da produção maciça. A 
segunda guerra mundial privou Walt Disney de seu mercado extrangeiro 
lucrative apenas no momento em que a necessitou mais; nem 
Pinocchio nem o fantasia tinham ganhado rendimentos para cobrir seus 
custos de gastos de fabricação elevados e, com o relocation caro de 
seu estúdio a Burbank, Disney enfrentou um débito $4.5 milhões. 
As relações com seus empregados worsened enquanto Disney 
cortou salários, colocou fora a equipe de funcionários, e negou 
bônus longo-adiados. O admonition de Dorothy Parker respondendo
do escritor "não deixa o rato de Mickey transformar-se um rato," 
outras uniões vieram à sustentação dos grevistas de Disney. 
O agente de negócio do brotherhood dos pintores, dos 
decoradores, e do Paperhangers, herb Sorrell, testified antes que uma 
subcomissão congressional que os grevistas bolstered por sympathizers
nos outros estúdios do animation, principalmente estúdio de 
Schlesinger dos irmãos de Warner.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un'onda dei colpi in 1941 ha interessato almeno 
un'industria ad ovest del litorale precedentemente non trattata 
tramite il movimento di lavoro. Entro i 1930s, la animazione si
era transformata in in un settore significativo dell'industria della 
pellicola di Hollywood, la relativa produzione basata sulle tecniche 
del factorylike di fabbricazione in serie. La seconda guerra 
mondiale ha privato Walt Disney del suo mercato straniero lucrativo 
appena al momento in cui la ha avuta bisogno più; nè Pinocchio
nè il fantasia aveva guadagnato i redditi per coprire i loro alti 
costi di produzione e, alla rilocazione costosa del suo studio a 
Burbank, Disney ha affrontato un debito $4.5 milioni. I rapporti
con i suoi impiegati hanno peggiorato mentre Disney ha tagliato gli 
stipendi, ha congedato il personale ed ha negato le indennità 
lungo-rinviate. Il admonition di Dorothy Parker di risposta del 
produttore "non lascia il mouse di Mickey transformarsi in in un 
ratto," altri sindacati sono venuto al supporto dei percussori del 
Disney. L'agente di affari della fratellanza dei pittori, dei 
decoratori e di Paperhangers, l'erba Sorrell, ha testimoniato prima 
che un sottocomitato congressuale che i percussori sono stati 
sostenuti dai simpatizzanti negli altri studi di animazione, 
principalmente studio di Schlesinger dei fratelli del Warner.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα κύμα των απεργιών το 1941 είχε επιπτώσεις 
τουλάχιστον σε μια βιομηχανία δυτικών ακτών προηγουμένως άθικτη 
από τη μετακίνηση εργασίας. Μέχρι τη δεκαετία του '30, η 
ζωτικότητα είχε γίνει ένας σημαντικός τομέας της βιομηχανίας 
ταινιών Hollywood, η παραγωγή της βασισμένη στις τεχνικές 
factorylike μαζικής παραγωγής. Ο παγκόσμιος πόλεμος ΙΙ 
στέρησε Walt Disney από την προσοδοφόρα ξένη αγορά του 
ακριβώς στη στιγμή όταν την χρειάστηκε πιό πολύ  ούτε 
Pinocchio ούτε Fantasia δεν είχε κερδίσει τα εισοδήματα για 
να καλύψει τις υψηλές δαπάνες παραγωγής τους και, την ακριβή 
επαναμετάθεση του στούντιό του στο Μπούρμπανκ, Disney 
αντιμετώπισε ένα χρέος $4,5 εκατομμυρίων. Οι σχέσεις με 
τους υπαλλήλους του που επιδεινώθηκαν ως Disney έκοψαν τις 
αμοιβές, σταματημένο προσωπικό, και αρνήθηκαν τα 
μακρύς-αναβεβλημένα επιδόματα. Απαντώντας στην 
προειδοποίηση Dorothy Parker's συγγραφέων "μην αφήστε το 
ποντίκι Mickey να γίνει ένας αρουραίος," άλλες ενώσεις ήρθαν
στην υποστήριξη των απεργών Disney. Ο επιχειρησιακός 
πράκτορας της αδελφοσύνης των ζωγράφων, των Διακοσμητής, και 
Paperhangers, χορτάρι Sorrell, πιστοποίησε ενώπιον μιας του 
Κογκρέσου υποεπιτροπής ότι οι απεργοί υποστηρίχτηκαν από τους 
υποστηρικτές στα άλλα στούντιο ζωτικότητας, κυρίως στούντιο 
Schlesinger των αδελφών Warner.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una onda de huelgas en 1941 afectó por lo menos 
una industria del oeste de la costa previamente sin tocar por el 
movimiento de trabajo. Por los años 30, la animación se había
convertido en un sector significativo de la industria de la película 
de Hollywood, su producción basada en técnicas del factorylike de la
producción en masa. La Segunda Guerra Mundial privó a Walt 
Disney de su mercado no nativo lucrativo en apenas el momento en que 
él la necesitó más; ni Pinocchio ni el fantasia había ganado
réditos para cubrir sus altos costes de producción y, con la 
realocación costosa de su estudio a Burbank, Disney hizo frente a una
deuda $4.5 millones. Las relaciones con sus empleados se 
empeoraron mientras que Disney cortó salarios, despidió al personal,
y negó primas largo-diferidas. La advertencia de Dorothy Parker
que contesta del programa de escritura "no deja el ratón de Mickey 
convertirse en una rata," otras uniones vinieron a la ayuda de los 
huelguistas de Disney. El agente comercial de la fraternidad de 
pintores, de decoradores, y de Paperhangers, hierba Sorrell, 
atestiguó antes de que un subcomité del congreso que los huelguistas
fueron alentados por los simpatizantes en los otros estudios de la 
animación, principalmente estudio de Schlesinger de los hermanos de 
Warner.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087472</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106273</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/cartoonists-on-the-picket-line-the-walt-disney-studio-strike</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
