<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106395</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106395</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207241</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Valley Forge</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Senke-Schmiede</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Forge de Vallée</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Forja Do Vale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Forgia Della Valle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η κοιλάδα σφυρηλατεί</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fragua Del Valle</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">looks at the campsite that marked a turning point in the American Revolution. By 1777, General Washington had suffered more defeats than victories. He sought a winter campsite that would allow observation of the British army without exposure to surprise attack. In December, he led 12,000 men into Valley Forge, Pennsylvania, while the British camped 20 miles away in Philadelphia. Nearly 2,000 American soldiers died of disease. But the Continental Army learned discipline and organization.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">betrachtet den Campingplatz, der einen Drehpunkt 
in der amerikanischen Umdrehung kennzeichnete. Bis zum 1777 
hatte General Washington mehr Niederlagen als Siege erlitten. Er
suchte einen Wintercampingplatz, der Beobachtung der britischen Armee 
ohne Aussetzung zum Überraschung Angriff erlauben würde. Im 
Dezember führte er 12.000 Männer in Senke-Schmiede, Pennsylvania, 
während das britische kampiert 20 Meilen entfernt in Philadelphia. 
Fast 2.000 amerikanische Soldaten starben an der Krankheit. 
Aber die kontinentale Armee erlernte Disziplin und Organisation.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">regarde le terrain de camping qui a marqué un tournant en
révolution américaine. D'ici 1777, le Général Washington 
avait souffert plus de défaites que des victoires. Il a 
recherché un terrain de camping d'hiver qui permettrait l'observation de 
l'armée britannique sans exposition à l'attaque de surprise. 
En décembre, il a mené 12.000 hommes dans la forge de vallée,
Pennsylvanie, alors que le britannique campé 20 milles loin à 
Philadelphie. Presque 2.000 soldats américains sont morts de la
maladie. Mais l'armée continentale a appris la discipline et 
l'organisation.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">olha o campsite que marcou um ponto de giro na 
volta americana. Por 1777, o general Washington tinha sofrido 
mais derrotas do que vitórias. Procurou um campsite do inverno 
que permitisse a observação do exército britânico sem exposição 
ao ataque da surpresa. Em dezembro, conduziu a 12.000 homens na 
forja do vale, Pensilvânia, quando o britânico acampado 20 milhas 
afastado em Filadélfia. Quase 2.000 soldados americanos 
morreram da doença. Mas o exército continental aprendeu a 
disciplina e a organização.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">guarda il campsite che ha contrassegnato una 
svolta nella rivoluzione americana. Entro 1777, il General 
Washington aveva sofferto più sconfitte che le vittorie. Ha 
cercato un campsite di inverno che permetterebbe l'osservazione 
dell'esercito britannico senza esposizione all'attacco di sorpresa. 
In dicembre, ha condotto 12.000 uomini nella forgia della valle,
Pensilvania, mentre il britannico accampato 20 miglia via a 
Filadelfia. Quasi 2.000 soldati americani sono morto della 
malattia. Ma l'esercito continentale ha imparato la disciplina e
l'organizzazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει το campsite που χαρακτήρισε μια κρίσιμη 
καμπή στην αμερικανική επανάσταση. Από 1777, ο στρατηγός
Washington είχε υποστεί περισσότερες ήττες από τις νίκες. 
Επιδίωξε έναν χειμώνα campsite ότι θα επέτρεπε την 
παρατήρηση του βρετανικού στρατού χωρίς έκθεση στην 
αιφνιδιαστική επίθεση. Το Δεκέμβριο, οδήγησε 12.000 
άτομα στην κοιλάδα σφυρηλατεί, Πενσυλβανία, ενώ οι Βρετανοί 
στρατοπέδευσαν 20 μίλια μακριά στη Φιλαδέλφεια. Σχεδόν 
2.000 αμερικανικοί στρατιώτες πέθαναν της ασθένειας. 
Αλλά ο ηπειρωτικός στρατός έμαθε την πειθαρχία και την 
οργάνωση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">mira el sitio para acampar que marcó un momento 
crucial en la revolución americana. Antes de 1777, general 
Washington había sufrido más derrotas que victorias. Él 
buscó un sitio para acampar del invierno que permitiría la 
observación del ejército británico sin la exposición al ataque de 
la sorpresa. En diciembre, él condujo a 12.000 hombres en la 
fragua del valle, Pennsylvania, mientras que el británico acampado 20
millas lejos en Philadelphia. Casi 2.000 soldados americanos 
murieron de enfermedad. Pero el ejército continental aprendió 
disciplina y la organización.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207241</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106395</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/valley-forge</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
