<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103864</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103864</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202811</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Just Like Brian Wilson Did: Using Allusion to Teach Imagery and Theme</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gerecht Wie Brian Wilson: Verwenden von von 
Anspielung, um Bilder und Thema zu unterrichten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Juste Comme Brian Wilson  : Utilisation de 
l'allusion pour enseigner le langage figuré et le thème</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Justo Como Brian Wilson : Usando o allusion 
ensinar o imagery e o tema</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giusto Come Brian Wilson: Usando Allusione
per insegnare linguaggio figurato e tema</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ακριβώς όπως το Brian Wilson Did: 
Χρησιμοποίηση της νύξης για να διδάξει τα καλολογικά 
στοιχεία και το θέμα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Justo Como Brian Wilson : Usar la alusión 
para enseñar imágenes y tema</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Beginning ENG I students are introduced to the general concepts of imagery (including symbolism) and theme in short literature in a lesson that features two contemporary pop songs and their lyrics. Serves as a useful attention getting exercise for low-level ENG I students who must become familiar with general literary concepts and terms for the ENG I EOC.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">AnfangenKursteilnehmer ENGLISCH I werden zu den 
allgemeinen Konzepten der Bilder (einschließlich Symbolismus) und des
Themas in der kurzen Literatur in einer Lektion eingeführt, die zwei 
zeitgenössische Knallliede und ihre Lyriken kennzeichnet. 
Serves als nützliche Aufmerksamkeit, die Übung für niedrige 
Kursteilnehmer ENGLISCH I erhält, die mit allgemeinen literarischen 
Konzepten und Bezeichnungen für ENGLISCH vertraut werden müssen I 
EOC.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Des étudiants commençants de l'ANGLAIS I sont 
présentés aux concepts généraux du langage figuré (symbolisme y 
compris) et du thème en littérature courte dans une leçon qui 
comporte deux chansons contemporaines de bruit et leur lyrique. 
Servir d'attention utile obtenant l'exercice pour les étudiants
inférieurs de l'ANGLAIS I qui doivent se familiariser avec des 
concepts et des limites littéraires généraux pour l'ANGLAIS I EOC.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os estudantes de começo do INGLÊS I são 
introduzidos aos conceitos gerais do imagery (simbolismo including) e 
do tema na literatura curta em uma lição que caracterize duas 
canções contemporary do PNF e seus lyrics. Saques como uma 
atenção útil que começa o exercício para os estudantes de baixo 
nível do INGLÊS I que devem se tornar familiares com os conceitos e 
os termos literários gerais para o INGLÊS I EOC.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli allievi d'inizio di INGLESE I sono introdotti 
ai concetti generali del linguaggio figurato (symbolism compreso) e 
del tema in letteratura corta in una lezione che caratterizza due 
canzoni contemporanee di schiocco ed i loro lyrics. Serv da 
attenzione utile che ottiene esercitazione per gli allievi a basso 
livello di INGLESE I che devono diventare esperti con i concetti ed i 
termini letterari generali per l'INGLESE I EOC.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι σπουδαστές αρχής ENG Ι εισάγονται στις γενικές 
έννοιες των καλολογικών στοιχείων (συμπεριλαμβανομένου του 
συμβολισμού) και του θέματος στην κοντή λογοτεχνία σε ένα μάθημα
που χαρακτηρίζει δύο σύγχρονα λαϊκά τραγούδια και τα λυρικά 
ποιήματά τους. Χρησιμεύει ως μια χρήσιμη προσοχή που 
παίρνει την άσκηση για τους χαμηλού επιπέδου σπουδαστές ENG Ι 
που πρέπει να γίνουν εξοικειωμένοι με τις γενικούς λογοτεχνικούς 
έννοιες και τους όρους για το ENG Ι EOC.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Introducen a los estudiantes del INGLÉS que 
comienzan I a los conceptos generales de las imágenes (simbolismo 
incluyendo) y del tema en literatura corta en una lección que ofrezca
dos canciones contemporáneas del estallido y sus líricas. 
Servicios como atención útil que consigue el ejercicio para 
los estudiantes bajos del INGLÉS I que deben hacer familiares con 
conceptos y términos literarios generales para el INGLÉS I EOC.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JEFFREY WEEKS
FN:JEFFREY WEEKS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202811</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103864</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/just-like-brian-wilson-did-using-allusion-to-teach-imagery-and-theme</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
