<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107620</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107620</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087211</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"We Will All Be Poor Here Together": A Young Family Homesteads in Nebraska, 1872</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Alle Wir Sind Hier Zusammen" Arm: Eine 
Junge-Familie Gehöfte in Nebraska, 1872</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Nous Serons Tout Pauvres Ici Ensemble" : 
Fermes d'une famille de jeunes au Nébraska, 1872</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Nós Todos Seremos Deficientes Aqui Junto": 
Homesteads de uma família dos jovens em Nebraska, 1872</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Tutti Saremo Poveri Qui Insieme": 
Fattorie della famiglia dei giovani nel Nebraska, 1872</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Όλοι θα είμαστε φτωχοί εδώ μαζί": Αγροτικά 
σπίτια μιας νέα οικογένειας στη Νεμπράσκα, 1872</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Todos Seremos Pobres Aquí Junto": Granjas 
de una familia de los jóvenes en Nebraska, 1872</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Homestead Act of 1862 opened the Great Plains for Euro-American settlement. The law allowed anyone to claim 160 acres after payment of a nominal fee. Final title to the land followed after five years of occupation and the improvement of the claim. While many of the Act's supporters intended its benefits to go to urban workers, city dwellers found it difficult even to raise the fees much less the capital necessary for farm equipment and supplies. Many Civil War veterans did move West, including Uriah Oblinger and other residents of older farming areas such as Indiana. He and two of his wife's brothers took advantage of the Homestead Act in the fall of 1872. Uriah's letters to his family described the emerging community of young settlers who had migrated to the Nebraska territory to start new lives with their families.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Gehöft-Tat von 1862 öffnete die Prairien 
für Euro-american Regelung. Das Gesetz ließ jedermann 160 
Morgen nach Zahlung einer nominalen Gebühr behaupten. 
Abschließender Name zum Land folgte nach fünf Jahren Besetzung
und Verbesserung des Anspruches. Während viele der Verfechter 
der Tat seinen Nutzen beabsichtigten, um zu den städtischen Arbeitern
zu gehen, fanden Stadtbewohner es schwierig sogar, die Gebühren viel 
anzuheben, die das Kapital weniger sind, das für landwirtschaftliche 
Maschinen und Zubehör notwendig ist. Viele Bürgerkriegveterane
zogen nach Westen, einschließlich Uriah Oblinger und andere Bewohner 
von den älteren bewirtschaftenden Bereichen wie Indiana um. Er 
und zwei von Brüdern seiner Frau zogen Nutzen aus der Gehöft-Tat im 
Fall von 1872. Zeichen Uriahs zu seiner Familie beschrieben die 
auftauchende Gemeinschaft der jungen Siedleren, die zur Nebraska 
Gegend fortgezogen waren, um zu beginnen neue Lebensdauern mit ihren 
Familien.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'acte de ferme de 1862 a ouvert les grandes 
plaines pour le règlement de euro-american. La loi a 
permis à n'importe qui de réclamer 160 acres après le paiement des 
honoraires nominaux. Le titre final à la terre a suivi après 
cinq ans de métier et de l'amélioration de la réclamation. 
Tandis que plusieurs des défenseurs de l'acte destinaient ses 
avantages pour aller aux ouvriers urbains, les habitants de ville 
l'ont trouvé difficile même de soulever les honoraires beaucoup 
moins le capital nécessaire pour le matériel et les 
approvisionnements de ferme. Beaucoup d'anciens combattants 
civils se sont déplacés à l'ouest, y compris Uriah Oblinger et 
d'autres résidants des zones cultivatrices plus anciennes telles que 
l'Indiana. Lui et deux des frères de son épouse ont tiré 
profit de l'acte de ferme en automne de 1872. Les lettres 
d'Uriah à sa famille ont décrit la communauté naissante des jeunes 
colons qui avaient passé au territoire du Nébraska pour commencer 
les nouvelles vies avec leurs familles.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O ato do homestead de 1862 abriu as planícies 
grandes para o estabelecimento Euro-Americano. A lei permitiu 
que qualquer um reivindicasse 160 acres após o pagamento de uma taxa 
nominal. O título final à terra seguiu após cinco anos da 
ocupação e da melhoria da reivindicação. Quando muitos dos 
supporters do ato pretenderam seus benefícios ir aos trabalhadores 
urbanos, os moradores da cidade encontraram difícil mesmo de levantar
muito as taxas menos o capital necessário para o equipamento e as 
fontes de fazenda. Muitos veterans de guerra civil moveram-se 
para o oeste, including Uriah Oblinger e outros residentes de umas 
áreas cultivando mais velhas tais como Indiana. E dois de 
irmãos da sua esposa fizeram exame da vantagem do ato do homestead na
queda de 1872. As letras de Uriah a sua família descreveram a 
comunidade emergente dos settlers novos que tinham migrado ao 
território de Nebraska para começar vidas novas com suas famílias.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Legge della fattoria di 1862 ha aperto le 
pianure grandi per lo stabilimento di euro-american. La 
legge ha permesso che chiunque esigesse 160 acri dopo il pagamento di 
una tassa nominale. Il titolo finale alla terra è seguito dopo 
cinque anni dell'occupazione e del miglioramento del reclamo. 
Mentre molti dei sostenitori della Legge hanno inteso i relativi
benefici per andare agli operai urbani, gli abitanti della città lo 
hanno trovato difficile persino alzare le tasse molto meno il capitale
necessario per le attrezzature ed i rifornimenti dell'azienda 
agricola. Molti veterani di guerra civile si sono mossi verso 
ovest, compreso Uriah Oblinger ed altri residenti di più vecchie zone
d'agricoltura quale l'Indiana. Lui e due dei fratelli della sua 
moglie hanno approfittato della Legge della fattoria nell'autunno di 
1872. Le lettere del Uriah alla sua famiglia hanno descritto la 
Comunità d'emersione dei settlers giovani che avevano migrato al 
territorio del Nebraska per cominciare nuove vite con le loro 
famiglie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο νόμος αγροτικών σπιτιών 1862 άνοιξε τις μεγάλες 
πεδιάδες για την ευρω-αμερικανική τακτοποίηση. Ο νόμος 
επέτρεψε σε καθενός για να απαιτήσει 160 στρέμματα μετά από 
την καταβολή μιας ονομαστικής αμοιβής. Τελικός τίτλος στο 
έδαφος που ακολουθείται μετά από πέντε έτη επαγγέλματος και της
βελτίωσης της αξίωσης. Ενώ πολλοί από τους υποστηρικτές 
του νόμου σκόπευαν τα οφέλη του για να πάνε στους αστικούς 
εργαζομένους, οι κάτοικοι πόλεων το βρήκαν δύσκολο ακόμη και να 
αυξήσουν τις αμοιβές πολύ λιγότερο το κεφάλαιο απαραίτητο για 
τον αγροτικούς εξοπλισμό και τις προμήθειες. Πολλοί 
παλαίμαχοι εμφύλιου πολέμου κίνησαν τη δύση, συμπεριλαμβανομένου
Uriah Oblinger και άλλων κατοίκων των παλαιότερων περιοχών 
καλλιέργειας όπως το Ινδιάνα. Αυτός και δύο από τους 
αδελφούς της συζύγου του εκμεταλλεύθηκαν το νόμο αγροτικών 
σπιτιών το φθινόπωρο 1872, επιστολών Uriah στην οικογένειά 
του περιέγραψαν την αναδυόμενη κοινότητα των νέων αποίκων που 
είχαν μεταναστεύσει στο έδαφος της Νεμπράσκας για να αρχίσουν τις
νέες ζωές με τις οικογένειές τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El acto de la granja de 1862 abrió los grandes 
llanos para el establecimiento de euro-american. La ley 
permitió que cualquier persona demandara 160 acres después del pago 
de un honorario nominal. El título final a la pista siguió 
después de cinco años de ocupación y de la mejora de la demanda. 
Mientras que muchos de los partidarios del acto pensaron sus 
ventajas para ir a los trabajadores urbanos, los habitantes de la 
ciudad encontraron difícil incluso de levantar los honorarios mucho 
menos el capital necesario para el equipo y las fuentes de granja. 
Muchos veteranos de guerra civil se movieron al oeste, 
incluyendo Uriah Oblinger y otros residentes de más viejas áreas que
cultivaban tales como Indiana. Él y dos de los hermanos de su 
esposa se aprovecharon del acto de la granja en la caída de 1872. 
Las cartas de Uriah a su familia describieron a comunidad que 
emergía de los colonos jóvenes que habían emigrado al territorio de
Nebraska para comenzar las nuevas vidas con sus familias.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087211</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107620</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/we-will-all-be-poor-here-together-a-young-family-homesteads-in-nebraska-1872</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
