<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106043</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106043</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086303</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Was Sure of Getting a Trade": John Fitch's Long Journey Towards Becoming an Artisan</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ich war vom Erhalten eines Handels" sicher: 
John Fitchs lange Reise in Richtung zum Werden ein Handwerker</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"j'étais sûr d'obtenir un commerce" : Long
voyage de John Fitch vers devenir un artisan</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"eu era certo de começar um comércio": 
Viagem longa de John Fitch para transformar-se um artisan</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"ero sicuro di ottenere un commercio": 
Viaggio lungo del John Fitch verso transformarsi in un 
artigianale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"ήμουν βέβαιος για ένα εμπόριο": Μακρύ ταξίδι 
John Fitch's προς να γίνει ένας χειροτεχνικός</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"era seguro de conseguir un comercio": Viaje
largo de Juan Fitch hacia hacer un artesano</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In colonial America, apprenticeship was the usual means by which young men entered a trade and master craftsmen obtained the labor necessary to staff their workshops. A young man's guardian signed an indenture (contract) for a period of time and the apprentice in turn was to receive food, lodging, and knowledge of "the mysteries of the trade," or traditional craft practices. For young John Fitch of Connecticut in the 1760s, anxious "to learn a trade" and "subsist myself in a genteel way when I came for myself," that exchange was no simple matter. The Cheney brothers, Connecticut clockmakers who were innovated in making moving wooden clocks that were far cheaper than the usual brass ones, were not eager to share either their dinner or their knowledge of clockmaking with Fitch. He found himself caught between his father's and his master's patriarchal expectations of receiving his labor, while he had to worry about how he would support himself when he came of age.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In Kolonialamerika war Lehre die üblichen Mittel,
durch die junge Männer einen Handel eintrugen und Haupthandwerker die
Arbeit erhielt, die notwendig ist, ihre Werkstätten mit Personal zu 
versorgen. Ein Wächter des jungen Mannes unterzeichnete eine 
errichtete Urkunde (Vertrag) während eines Zeitabschnitts und der 
Lehrling sollte der Reihe nach Nahrung, Unterkunft und Wissen "der 
Geheimnisse des Handels," oder der traditionellen Fertigkeitpraxis 
empfangen. Für jungen John Fitch von Connecticut im 1760s, in 
dem Bestreben ", einen Handel zu erlernen" und "subsist in einer 
genteel Methode, als ich für mich kam," dieser Austausch war kein 
einfacher Stoff. Die Cheney Brüder, Connecticut clockmakers, 
die erneuert wurden, wenn man bewegende hölzerne Taktgeber bildete, 
die weit preiswerter als der übliche Messing eine waren, waren nicht 
eifrig, entweder ihr Abendessen oder ihr Wissen von Clockmaking mit 
Fitch zu teilen. Er fand sich abgefangen zwischen seinem Vater 
und seinem patriarchalische Erwartungen des Meisters des Empfangens 
Arbeits seins, während er sich sorgen mußte um, wie er sich 
unterstützen würde, als er vom Alter kam.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En Amérique coloniale, l'apprentissage était les
moyens habituels par lesquels les jeunes hommes ont écrit un commerce
et des artisans de maître a obtenu le travail nécessaire pour 
fournir leurs ateliers. Un gardien de jeune homme a signé un 
contrat synallagmatique bilatéral (contrat) pendant une période et 
l'apprenti devait alternativement recevoir la nourriture, le logement,
et la connaissance "des mystères du commerce," ou des pratiques en 
matière traditionnelles de métier. Pour jeune John Fitch du 
Connecticut dans le 1760s, impatient "d'apprendre un commerce" et 
"subsistez-vous d'une voie distinguée quand je suis venu pour me," 
cet échange n'était aucune matière simple. Les frères de 
Cheney, les horlogers du Connecticut qui ont été innovés en
faisant les horloges en bois en mouvement qui étaient bien meilleur 
marché que le laiton habituel ceux, n'étaient pas désireux de 
partager leur dîner ou leur connaissance de horlogerie avec Fitch. 
Il s'est trouvé attrapé entre son père et le sien les 
espérances patriarcales du maître de recevoir le sien de travail, 
alors qu'il devait s'inquiéter de la façon dont il se supporterait 
quand il est venu de l'âge.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em América colonial, o apprenticeship era os 
meios usuais por que os homens novos incorporaram um comércio e 
artesãos do mestre obteve o trabalho necessário staff suas oficinas.
Um guardian de homem novo assinou um indenture (contrato) por um
período de tempo e o aprendiz devia por sua vez receber o alimento, o
alojamento, e o conhecimento "dos mistérios do comércio," ou de 
práticas tradicionais do ofício. Para John novo Fitch de 
Connecticut no 1760s, ansioso "para aprender um comércio" e "não 
subsist em uma maneira genteel quando eu vim para myself," essa troca 
era nenhuma matéria simples. Os irmãos de Cheney, os 
clockmakers de Connecticut que innovated em fazer os pulsos de disparo
de madeira móveis que eram distante mais baratos do que o bronze 
usual uns, não estavam ansiosos para compartilhar de seu jantar ou de
seu conhecimento de clockmaking com o Fitch. Encontrou-se 
travado entre seu pai e his expectativas patriarchal do mestre de 
receber his labor, quando teve que se preocupar sobre como se 
suportaria quando veio da idade.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In America coloniale, l'apprendistato era i mezzi 
usuali da cui i giovani hanno fornito un commercio ed artigiani del 
supervisore ha ottenuto il lavoro necessario per fornire i loro 
workshop di personale. Un guardiano del giovane ha firmato un 
indenture (contratto) per un periodo di tempo e l'apprendista a sua 
volta doveva ricevere l'alimento, l'alloggio e la conoscenza "dei 
misteri del commercio," o delle pratiche tradizionali del mestiere. 
Per John giovane Fitch di Connecticut nel 1760s, ansioso 
"imparare un commercio" e "sussistasi in un modo genteel quando sono 
venuto per me," quello scambio era materia semplice. I fratelli 
di Cheney, clockmakers del Connecticut che innovated nel fare gli 
orologi di legno muoventesi che erano ben più poco costosi 
dell'ottone usuale un, non erano desiderosi di ripartire il loro 
pranzo o la loro conoscenza di clockmaking con Fitch. Si è 
trovato interferito fra il suo padre e suo aspettative patriarchal del
supervisore di ricezione del suo lavoro, mentre ha dovuto 
preoccuparsi per come si sosterrebbe quando è venuto dell'età.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στην αποικιακή Αμερική, η μαθητεία ήταν ο 
συνηθισμένος τρόπος με τον οποίο οι νεαροί άνδρες εισήγαγαν ένα
εμπόριο και οι κύριοι βιοτέχνες έλαβαν την εργασία απαραίτητη να
επανδρώσει τα εργαστήριά τους. Ένας νέος ανθρώπινος 
φύλακας υπέγραψε ένα indenture (σύμβαση) για μια χρονική 
περίοδο και ο μαθητευόμενος επρόκειτο στη συνέχεια να λάβει τα 
τρόφιμα, την κατοικία, και τη γνώση "των μυστηρίων του εμπορίου,"
ή των παραδοσιακών πρακτικών τεχνών. Για νέο John 
Fitch του Κοννέκτικατ στο 1760s, ανήσυχο "να μάθει ένα 
εμπόριο" και "να υπαρχτεί με έναν καλοαναθρεμένο τρόπο όταν 
ήρθα για με," εκείνη η ανταλλαγή δεν ήταν κανένα απλό θέμα. 
Οι Cheney αδελφοί, ρολογάδες του Κοννέκτικατ που 
καινοτομήθηκαν στην παραγωγή των κινούμενων ξύλινων ρολογιών που 
ήταν πολύ φτηνότερα από τα συνηθισμένα ορείχαλκου, δεν ήταν 
πρόθυμοι να μοιραστούν είτε το γεύμα τους είτε τη γνώση 
ωρολογοποιίας τους με Fitch. Βρέθηκε πιασμένου μεταξύ των
πατριαρχικών προσδοκιών του πατέρα και του κυρίου του του λήψης 
της εργασίας του, ενώ έπρεπε να ανησυχήσει για το πώς θα 
υποστηριζόταν όταν ενηλικιώθηκε.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En América colonial, el aprendizaje era los 
medios generalmente por los cuales los hombres jóvenes incorporaron 
un comercio y los artesanos del amo obtuvo el trabajo necesario para 
proveer de personal sus talleres. Un guarda del hombre joven 
firmó un contrato (contrato) por un período del tiempo y el aprendiz
alternadamente debía recibir el alimento, el alojamiento, y el 
conocimiento "de los misterios del comercio," o de las prácticas 
tradicionales del arte. Para Juan joven Fitch de Connecticut en 
el 1760s, impaciente por "aprender un comercio" y "subsístase de una 
manera genteel cuando vine para me," ese intercambio no era ninguna 
materia simple. Los hermanos de Cheney, los clockmakers de 
Connecticut que fueron innovados en la fabricación de los relojes de 
madera de mudanza que eran lejos más baratos que el latón 
generalmente unos, no eran impacientes compartir su cena o su 
conocimiento de clockmaking con Fitch. Él se encontró cogido 
entre su padre y el suyo las expectativas patriarchal del amo de 
recibir el suyo de trabajo, mientras que él tuvo que preocuparse de 
cómo él se utilizaría cuando él vino de edad.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086303</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106043</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-was-sure-of-getting-a-trade-john-fitchs-long-journey-towards-becoming-an-artisan</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
