<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103896</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103896</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209939</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">3:4:5 triangle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">3:4:5 Dreieck</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">triangle de 3:4:5</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">triângulo de 3:4:5</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">triangolo di 3:4:5</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">τρίγωνο 3:4:5</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">triángulo de 3:4:5</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate the properties of a 3:4:5 triangle - one of the Pythagorean triples. The applet shows a right triangle that can be resized by dragging any vertex. As it is dragged, the remaining vertices change so that the triangle's side remain in the ration 3:4:5. The text on the page has an example of how the triangle can be used to measure a right angle on even large objects. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die die Eigenschaften eines 3:4:5 Dreiecks - eine der 
pythagoräischen Dreiergruppen zeigen. Der applet zeigt ein 
rechtes Dreieck, das die Größe neu bestimmt werden kann, indem man 
jeden möglichen Gipfel schleppt. Während er geschleppt wird, 
ändern die restlichen Gipfel, damit die Seite des Dreiecks in der 
Zuteilung 3:4:5 bleiben. Der Text auf der Seite hat ein Beispiel
von, wie das Dreieck benutzt werden kann, um einen rechten Winkel auf 
sogar großen Nachrichten zu messen. Applet kann zum vollen 
Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert
werden. Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf 
es von jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek 
ohne den benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel 
ist ein Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven 
Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent les propriétés d'une triangle de 3:4:5 - un des 
triples pythagoriens. L'applet montre une bonne triangle qui 
peut être remise à la côte en traînant n'importe quel sommet. 
Pendant qu'il est traîné, les sommets restants changent de 
sorte que le côté de la triangle demeurent dans la ration 3:4:5. 
Le texte à la page a un exemple de la façon dont la triangle 
peut être employée pour mesurer un angle droit sur même de grands 
objets. L'applet peut être agrandi à la taille de plein écran
pour l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de classe. Le après 
utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant peut lui accéder 
encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la maison ou dans la 
bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion exigée. Cette 
ressource est un composant du projet interactif de manuel de la 
géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem as propriedades de um triângulo de 3:4:5 - um se triplicar
pythagorean. O applet mostra um triângulo direito que possa 
resized arrastando todo o vertex. Enquanto é arrastado, os 
vertices restantes mudam de modo que o lado do triângulo remanesça 
na ração 3:4:5. O texto na página tem um exemplo de como o 
triângulo pode ser usado medir um ângulo direito mesmo em objetos 
grandes. O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de tela cheia 
para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. O depois de uso na 
sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo o web 
browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma sessão 
requerido. Este recurso é um componente do projeto interativo 
do textbook da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano le proprietà di un triangolo di 3:4:5 - uno dei tripli 
pythagorean. Il applet mostra un giusto triangolo che può 
essere ridimensionato trascinando tutto il vertice. Mentre è 
trascinato, i vertici restanti cambiano in modo che il lato del 
triangolo rimanga nella razione 3:4:5. Il testo alla pagina ha 
un esempio di come il triangolo può essere usato per misurare un 
angolo retto persino sui grandi oggetti. Il applet può essere 
ingrandito al formato di schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore 
dell'aula. La post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può 
accederle ancora da tutto il web browser nel paese o nella libreria 
senza l'inizio attività richiesto. Questa risorsa è un 
componente del progetto interattivo del manuale della geometria di 
riferimento aperto di per la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν τις ιδιότητες ενός τριγώνου 3:4:5 - ένα από τα 
πυθαγορικά τριπλάσια. Το applet εμφανίζει σωστό τρίγωνο 
που μπορεί να επαναταξινομηθεί με το σύρσιμο οποιουδήποτε 
vertex. Δεδομένου ότι σέρνεται, υπόλοιπα vertices 
αλλάζουν έτσι ώστε η πλευρά του τριγώνου παραμένει στο δελτίο 
τροφίμων 3:4:5. Το κείμενο στη σελίδα έχει ένα 
παράδειγμα για το πώς το τρίγωνο μπορεί να χρησιμοποιηθεί για να 
μετρήσει μια σωστή γωνία ακόμη και στα μεγάλα αντικείμενα. 
Το Applet μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης
για τη χρήση με έναν προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση 
στην τάξη, ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από
οποιοδήποτε ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς 
την άδεια εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο 
συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος 
εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran las características de un triángulo de 3:4:5 - uno de los
triples pythagorean. El applet muestra un triángulo derecho que
pueda ser vuelto a clasificar según el tamaño arrastrando cualquier 
cima. Mientras que se arrastra, las cimas restantes cambian de 
modo que siga habiendo la cara del triángulo en la ración 3:4:5. 
El texto en la paginación tiene un ejemplo de cómo el 
triángulo se puede utilizar para medir un angulo recto en incluso 
objetos grandes. El applet se puede agrandar a la talla de la 
pantalla completa para el uso con un proyector de la sala de clase. 
El uso posterior en la sala de clase, estudiante puede tenerle 
acceso otra vez de cualquier web browser en el país o en la 
biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. Este recurso es un 
componente del proyecto interactivo del libro de textos de la 
geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas en 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209939</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103896</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/3-4-5-triangle</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
