<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106175</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106175</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086068</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Defending Home and Hearth: Walter White Recalls the 1906 Atlanta Race Riot</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Verteidigendes Haus und Herd: Walter Weiß 
erinnert an den Atlanta Rennen-Aufstand 1906</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Maison et foyer défendants : Le blanc de 
Walter rappelle l'émeute 1906 de course d'Atlanta</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">HOME e hearth defendendo: O branco de Walter 
recorda o motim 1906 da raça de Atlanta</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sede e focolare difendenti: Il bianco di 
Walter ricorda il tumulto 1906 della corsa de Atlanta</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Οικία" και δάπεδο τζακιού υπεράσπισης: Walter White Recalls η φυλετική ταραχή της Ατλάντας του 
1906</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Hogar y hogar que defienden: El blanco de 
Walter recuerda el alboroto 1906 de la raza de Atlanta</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The riots that broke out between 1898 and 1906 were part of a pattern of anti-black violence that included several hundred lynchings each year. One of the most savage race riots in these years erupted in Atlanta on September 22, 1906 after vague reports of African Americans harassing white women. Over five days at least ten black people were killed while Atlanta's police did nothing to protect black citizens, going so far as to confiscate guns from black Atlantans while allowing whites to remain armed. In this selection from his memoirs, Walter White, the future head of the NAACP recalled how, at age 13, he and his father defended their home from white rioters.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Aufstände, die zwischen 1898 und 1906 
ausbrachen, waren ein Teil eines Musters der Anti-schwarzen 
Gewalttätigkeit, das mehreree hundert lynchings jedes Jahr enthielt. 
Einer der wildesten Rennenaufstände in diesen Jahren brach in 
Atlanta an September 22, 1906 nach vagen Reports der afrikanischen 
Amerikaner aus, die weiße Frauen bedrängen. Über fünf Tagen 
mindestens wurden 10 schwarze Leute beendet, während Polizei Atlantas
nichts tat, schwarze Bürger zu schützen und gingen soweit, Gewehren 
von schwarzem Atlantans beim Lassen von von Weiß zu konfiszieren 
bewaffnet bleiben. In dieser Auswahl von seinen Abhandlungen, 
rief Walter Weiß, der zukünftige Kopf des NAACP wieder auf, wie, an 
Alter 13, er und sein Vater ihr Haus von den weißen rioters 
verteidigten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les émeutes qui ont éclaté entre 1898 et 1906 
faisaient partie d'une configuration de violence anti-noire qui a 
inclus tous les ans plusieurs centaines de lynchings. Une des 
émeutes de course les plus sauvages en ces années a éclaté à 
Atlanta 22 septembre 1906 après des états vagues des Américains 
africains harcelant les femmes blanches. Plus de cinq jours au 
moins dix personnes noires ont été détruites alors que la police 
d'Atlanta ne faisait rien à protéger les citoyens noirs, allant 
autant que confisquer des pistolets d'Atlantans noir tout en 
permettant à des blancs de demeurer armés. Dans cette 
sélection à partir de ses mémoires, le blanc de Walter, la future 
tête du NAACP a rappelé comment, à l'âge 13, lui et son père ont 
défendu leur maison des rioters blancs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os motins que quebraram para fora entre 1898 e 
1906 eram parte de um teste padrão da violência anti-preta que 
incluísse diverso cem lynchings cada ano. Um dos motins os mais
selvagens da raça nestes anos erupted em Atlanta setembro em 22, 1906
após relatórios vagos dos americanos africanos que harassing as 
mulheres brancas. Sobre cinco dias onde ao menos dez povos 
pretos foram matados quando as polícias de Atlanta não fizeram nada 
proteger cidadãos pretos, indo assim distante a respeito de 
confiscate injetores de Atlantans preto ao permitir que os brancos 
remanesçam armados. Nesta seleção de seus memoirs, o branco 
de Walter, a cabeça futura do NAACP recordou como, na idade 13, e seu
pai defenderam sua HOME dos rioters brancos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I tumulti che hanno scoppiato fra 1898 e 1906 
facevano parte di un modello della violenza anti-nera che ha incluso 
ogni anno diverse centinaia lynchings. Uno dei tumulti della 
corsa più selvaggi durante questi anni ha scoppiato a Atlanta 
il 22 settembre 1906 dopo i rapporti vaghi degli Americani africani 
che harassing le donne bianche. Oltre cinque giorni almeno dieci
genti nere sono state uccise mentre la polizia de Atlanta non ha fatto
niente proteggere i cittadini neri, andando per quanto confiscare le 
pistole da Atlantans nero mentre permetteva che i bianchi rimangano 
muniti. In questa selezione dalle sue memorie, il bianco di 
Walter, la testa futura del NAACP ha ricordato come, all'età 13, lui 
ed il suo padre hanno difeso la loro sede dai rioters bianchi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι ταραχές που ξέσπησαν μεταξύ 1898 και 1906 
ήταν μέρος μιας μορφής της αντι-μαύρης βίας που περιέλαβε τα 
αρκετά λυντσαρίσματα κάθε έτος. Μια από τις πιό άγριες 
φυλετικές ταραχές σε αυτά τα έτη εξερράγη στην Ατλάντα στις 
22 Σεπτεμβρίου ..1906 μετά από τις ασαφείς εκθέσεις 
αφρικανικών Αμερικανών που παρενοχλούν τις λευκές γυναίκες. 
Πάνω από πέντε ημέρες τουλάχιστον δέκα μαύροι άνθρωποι 
σκοτώθηκαν ενώ η αστυνομία της Ατλάντας δεν έκανε τίποτα για να 
προστατεύσει τους μαύρους πολίτες, που προχωρούν τόσο πολύ ώστε
να δημεύσει τα πυροβόλα όπλα από μαύρο Atlantans ενώ 
επιτρέποντας στα λευκά για να παραμείνει οπλισμένα. Σε 
αυτήν την επιλογή από τα απομνημονεύματά του, walter White,
ο μελλοντικός προϊστάμενος του NAACP υπενθύμισε πώς, στην 
ηλικία 13, αυτός και ο πατέρας του υπεράσπισαν το σπίτι τους 
από τους λευκούς στασιαστές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los alborotos que explotaron entre 1898 y 1906 
eran parte de un modelo de la violencia contra-negra que incluyó 
vario cientos lynchings cada año. Uno de los alborotos más 
salvajes de la raza de estos años entró en erupción en Atlanta de 
septiembre el 22 de 1906 después de informes vagos de los americanos 
africanos que acosaban las mujeres blancas. Sobre cinco días 
por lo menos mataron a diez personas negras mientras que el policía 
de Atlanta no hizo nada proteger a ciudadanos negros, yendo en cuanto 
a confiscar los armas de Atlantans negro mientras que permitían que 
los blancos sigan siendo armados. En esta selección de sus 
memorias, el blanco de Walter, el jefe futuro del NAACP recordó 
cómo, en la edad 13, él y su padre defendieron su hogar de los 
rioters blancos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086068</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106175</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/defending-home-and-hearth-walter-white-recalls-the-1906-atlanta-race-riot</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
