<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103877</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103877</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202981</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Global Fluid Dynamics Laboratory (GDFL) Gallery</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Globale Flüssige Galerie Des Dynamik-Labor(GDFL)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Galerie Liquide Globale du Laboratoire de 
Dynamique (GDFL)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Galeria Fluida Global Do Laboratório Da Dinâmica
(GDFL)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Galleria Fluida Globale Del Laboratorio Di 
Dynamics (GDFL)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σφαιρική ρευστή εργαστηριακή (GDFL) στοά δυναμικής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Galería Flúida Global Del Laboratorio De la 
Dinámica (GDFL)</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This page contains several visualizations which have been prepared in the course of the Global Fluid Dynamics Laboratory's (GFDL) research. Images cover topics such as hurricanes, global warming, radiative transfer, stratospheric processes, El Nino, cyclones and storms, Jupiter and Mars. Some topics also include animations and detailed descriptions. These are offered as examples of various visualization techniques and how they might be used to convey complex results as understandable images. A number of visualizations are also available in the form of annotated handouts.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Seite enthält einige Sichtbarmachungen, die
im Verlauf der globale flüssige Forschung des Dynamik-Labors (GFDL) 
vorbereitet worden sind. Bildabdeckungthemen wie Hurrikane, 
globale wärmende, Strahlungsübertragung, stratospheric Prozesse, EL 
Nino, Wirbelstürme und Stürme, Jupiter und Mars. Einige Themen
schließen auch Animationen und ausführliche Beschreibungen ein. 
Diese werden als Beispiele der verschiedenen 
Sichtbarmachungtechniken angeboten und wie sie verwendet werden 
konnten, um komplizierte Resultate als verständliche Bilder zu 
übermitteln. Eine Anzahl von Sichtbarmachungen sind auch in 
Form von angemerkten Mitteilungsblättern vorhanden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette page contient plusieurs visualisations qui 
ont été préparées au cours de la recherche du laboratoire liquide 
global de dynamique (GFDL). Les sujets de couverture d'images 
tels que des ouragans, transfert chauffant et radiatif global, les 
processus stratosphériques, EL Nino, cyclones et donne l'assaut à, 
Jupiter et Mars. Quelques sujets incluent également des 
animations et des descriptions détaillées. Ceux-ci sont 
offerts comme exemples de diverses techniques de visualisation et 
comment ils pourraient être employés pour donner des résultats 
complexes en tant qu'images compréhensibles. Un certain nombre 
de visualisations sont également disponibles sous forme d'aumônes 
annotées.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta página contem diversos visualizations que 
foram preparados no curso da pesquisa do laboratório fluido global da
dinâmica (GFDL). Tópicos da tampa das imagens tais como 
furacões, transferência aquecendo-se, radiative global, processos 
stratospheric, EL Nino, cyclones e tempestades, Jupiter e Marte. 
Alguns tópicos incluem também animations e descrições 
detalhadas. Estes são oferecidos como exemplos de várias 
técnicas do visualization e como puderam ser usadas fazer saber a 
resultados complexos como imagens compreensíveis. Um número de
visualizations estão também disponíveis no formulário de handouts 
anotados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa pagina contiene parecchie visualizzazioni 
che sono state preparate nel corso della ricerca del laboratorio 
fluido globale di dynamics (GFDL). Soggetti della copertura di 
immagini quali gli uragani, trasferimento di riscaldamento e 
radiattivo globale, processi stratosferici, EL Nino, cicloni e 
tempeste, Jupiter e Marte. Alcuni soggetti egualmente includono 
le animazioni e le descrizioni dettagliate. Questi sono offerti 
come esempi di varie tecniche di visualizzazione e come potrebbero 
essere usate per trasportare i risultati complessi come immagini 
comprensibili. Un certo numero di visualizzazioni sono 
egualmente disponibili sotto forma di le dispense annotate.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η σελίδα περιέχει διάφορες απεικονίσεις που 
έχουν προετοιμαστεί κατά τη διάρκεια της έρευνας του σφαιρικού 
ρευστού εργαστηρίου δυναμικής (GFDL). Οι εικόνες 
καλύπτουν τα θέματα όπως οι τυφώνες, η παγκόσμια αύξηση της 
θερμοκρασίας λόγω του φαινομένου του θερμοκηπίου, η της 
ακτινοβολίας μεταφορά, οι στρατοσφαιρικές διαδικασίες, Ελ Νίνιο, 
οι κυκλώνες και οι θύελλες, Δίας και ο Αρης. Μερικά θέματα
περιλαμβάνουν επίσης τις ζωτικότητες και τις λεπτομερείς 
περιγραφές. Αυτοί προσφέρονται ως παραδείγματα των διάφορων
τεχνικών απεικόνισης και πώς να χρησιμοποιηθούν για να 
μεταβιβάσουν τα σύνθετα αποτελέσματα ως κατανοητές εικόνες. 
Διάφορες απεικονίσεις είναι επίσης διαθέσιμες υπό μορφή 
σχολιασμένων φυλλάδιων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta paginación contiene varias visualizaciones 
que han estado preparadas en el curso de la investigación del 
laboratorio flúido global de la dinámica (GFDL). Asuntos de la
cubierta de las imágenes tales como huracanes, transferencia que se 
calienta, radiativa global, procesos estratosféricos, EL Nino, 
ciclones y tormentas, Júpiter y Marte. Algunos asuntos también
incluyen animaciones y descripciones detalladas. Éstos se 
ofrecen como ejemplos de las varias técnicas de la visualización y 
cómo puede ser que sean utilizadas para transportar resultados 
complejos como imágenes comprensibles. Un número de 
visualizaciones están también disponibles en la forma de folletos 
anotados.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202981</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103877</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/global-fluid-dynamics-laboratory-gdfl-gallery</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
