<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/2147476540</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>2147476540</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202921</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Geologic Time</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geologische Zeit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Temps Géologique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Tempo Geologic</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Tempo Geologico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γεωλογικός χρόνος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Tiempo Geológico</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site provides animations, images, interactive maps and videos that can be used to teach about the concept of geologic time. Visual resources cover some specific topics of earth history including plate tectonics, continental drift, relative age dating and paleontology. These resources are appropriate for an introductory level geology course.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site liefert Animationen, Bilder, 
interaktive Karten und videos, die verwendet werden können, um über 
das Konzept der geologischen Zeit zu unterrichten. 
Sichtbetriebsmittel umfassen einige spezifische Themen der Masse
Geschichte einschließlich Plattentektonik, Kontinentaltrift, die 
relative Alter Datierung und Paläontologie. Diese 
Betriebsmittel sind für einen einleitenden waagerecht ausgerichteten 
Geologiekurs angebracht.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site fournit les animations, les images, les 
cartes interactives et les videos qui peuvent être employés pour 
enseigner au sujet du concept du temps géologique. Les 
ressources visuelles couvrent quelques sujets spécifiques de 
l'histoire de la terre comprenant la tectonique de plat, la dérive 
continentale, dater relatif d'âge et la paléontologie. Ces 
ressources sont appropriées pour un cours de niveau préliminaire de 
géologie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local fornece os animations, as imagens, os 
mapas interativos e os videos que podem ser usados ensinar sobre o 
conceito do tempo geologic. Os recursos visuais cobrem alguns 
tópicos específicos do history da terra including o tectonics de 
placa, a tração continental, datar relativo da idade e o 
paleontology. Estes recursos são apropriados para um curso 
nivelado introdutório da geologia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo fornisce le animazioni, le immagini, 
i programmi interattivi ed i videos che possono essere usati per 
insegnare circa il concetto di tempo geologico. Le risorse 
visive riguardano alcuni soggetti specifici di storia della terra 
compreso la tettonica di piastra, la direzione continentale, datare 
relativo di età e la paleontologia. Queste risorse sono adatte 
per un corso livellato introduttivo di geologia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή παρέχει τις ζωτικότητες, τις εικόνες, 
τους διαλογικούς χάρτες και τα βίντεο που μπορούν να 
χρησιμοποιηθούν για να διδάξουν για την έννοια του γεωλογικού 
χρόνου. Τα οπτικά στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς καλύπτουν μερικά 
συγκεκριμένα θέματα της γήινης ιστορίας συμπεριλαμβανομένης της 
τεκτονικής πιάτων, της ηπειρωτικής κλίσης, της σχετικών 
χρονολόγησης ηλικίας και της παλαιοντολογίας. Αυτά τα 
στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς είναι κατάλληλα για μια εισαγωγική σειρά 
μαθημάτων γεωλογίας επιπέδων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio proporciona a las animaciones, a las 
imágenes, a las correspondencias interactivas y a los videos que se 
pueden utilizar para enseñar sobre el concepto del tiempo geológico.
Los recursos visuales cubren algunos asuntos específicos de la 
historia de la tierra incluyendo la tectónica de placa, la deriva 
continental, fechar relativo de la edad y paleontología. Estos 
recursos son apropiados para un curso llano introductorio de la 
geología.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202921</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>2147476540</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/geologic-time</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
