<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107704</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107704</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206771</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Children in Urban America</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kinder in städtischem Amerika</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Enfants en Amérique urbaine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Crianças em América urbana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Bambini in America urbana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παιδιά στην αστική Αμερική</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Niños en América urbana</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">shows how children experienced city life during the last century and a half. The site features hundreds of documents and images about children in Milwaukee County, Wisconsin, drawn from newspapers, government, and other official records, oral histories and memoirs, and other sources.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">zeigt, wie Kinder das Stadtleben während des 
letzten Jahrhunderts und einer Hälfte erfuhren. Die 
Situationsmerkmalhunderte der Dokumente und der Bilder über Kinder in
der Milwaukee Grafschaft, Wisconsin, gezeichnet von den Zeitungen, 
Regierung und andere amtliche Sätze, Mundgeschichten und Abhandlungen
und andere Quellen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">montre comment les enfants ont éprouvé la vie de
ville pendant le dernier siècle et une moitié. Les centaines 
de dispositifs de site de documents et images au sujet des enfants 
dans le comté de Milwaukee, le Wisconsin, tiré des journaux, 
gouvernement, et d'autres actes officiels, histoires orales et 
mémoires, et d'autres sources.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">mostra como as crianças experimentaram a vida da 
cidade durante o último século e uma metade. As centenas das 
características de local dos originais e as imagens sobre crianças 
no condado de Milwaukee, Wisconsin, desenhado dos jornais, o governo, 
e outros registros oficiais, histories orais e memoirs, e outras 
fontes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">mostra come i bambini hanno avvertito la vita 
della città durante il secolo scorso e la metà. Le centinaia 
delle caratteristiche di luogo dei documenti ed immagini circa i 
bambini nella contea di Milwaukee, Wisconsin, dissipato dai giornali, 
governo ed altre atti ufficiali, dati storici orali e memorie ed altre
sorgenti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">επιδεικνύει πώς τα παιδιά δοκίμασαν τη ζωή πόλεων 
κατά τη διάρκεια του τελευταίου αιώνα και ενός μισού. Η 
περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει τις εκατοντάδες των εγγράφων και των εικόνων
για τα παιδιά στο νομό του Μιλγουώκι, Wisconsin, που προέρχεται
από τις εφημερίδες, την κυβέρνηση, και άλλα επίσημα αρχεία, 
προφορικές ιστορίες και απομνημονεύματα, και άλλες πηγές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">muestra cómo los niños experimentaron vida de la
ciudad durante el siglo pasado y una mitad. Los centenares de 
las características de sitio de documentos e imágenes sobre niños 
en el condado de Milwaukee, Wisconsin, trazado de los periódicos, 
gobierno, y otros expedientes oficiales, historias orales y memorias, 
y otras fuentes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206771</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107704</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/children-in-urban-america</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
