<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102988</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102988</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086814</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Setting Up a Successful Journalistic Learning Community</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine erfolgreiche journalistische 
erlernengemeinschaft aufstellen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Installation d'une Communauté d'étude 
journalistique réussie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ajustando acima uma comunidade de aprendizagem 
journalistic bem sucedida</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Installazione della Comunità imparante 
journalistic riuscita</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σύσταση μιας επιτυχούς δημοσιογραφικής μαθαίνοντας 
Κοινότητας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Setting-up a una comunidad que aprende 
periodística acertada</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this website, Wojcicki describes how participation in a journalistic learning community can motivate even the most recalcitrant student. The website includes sample copies of the newspaper, The Campanile and the magazine, Verde, which are examples of the kinds of student outcomes that can be achieved when students are excited about learning and have ownership of their learning and the product of their learning: the publications. Wojcicki's students have won several major national and international competitions over the past fifteen years. Both publications are self-supporting which means that all students in the program are responsible for learning how to sell ads and to interact with the community. This helps students develop important interpersonal skills and also acts as a public relations mechanism for the school and for the newspaper. It also brings the community closer to the school and makes people feel as though they are active participants in the education process.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In dieser Web site beschreibt Wojcicki, wie 
Teilnahme an einer journalistischen erlernengemeinschaft sogar den 
recalcitrant Kursteilnehmer motivieren kann. Die Web site 
schließt Beispielexemplare der Zeitung, des Glockenturms und der 
Zeitschrift, Verde ein, die Beispiele der Arten der 
Kursteilnehmerresultate sind-, die erzielt werden, wenn Kursteilnehmer
über das Lernen aufgeregt werden und Besitz ihres Lernens und das 
Produkt ihres Lernens haben können: die Publikationen. 
Kursteilnehmer Wojcickis haben einige nationale und 
hauptsächlichweltweite Konkurrenzen über den letzten fünfzehn 
Jahren gewonnen. Beide Publikationen sind selbsttragend, das 
bedeutet, daß alle Kursteilnehmer im Programm für das Lernen 
verantwortlich sind, wie man ADS verkauft und auf die Gemeinschaft 
einwirkt. Dieses hilft Kursteilnehmern, wichtige 
Zwischenpersonalfähigkeiten zu entwickeln und dient auch als eine 
Öffentlichkeitsarbeiteinheit für die Schule und für die Zeitung. 
Es auch holt die Gemeinschaft näeher an der Schule und läßt 
Leute glauben, als wenn sie aktive Teilnehmer an den Ausbildung 
Prozeß sind.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans ce site Web, Wojcicki décrit comment la 
participation à une communauté d'étude journalistique peut motiver 
même l'étudiant le plus récalcitrant. Le site Web inclut les 
copies témoin du journal, du campanile et du magasin, Verde, qui sont
des exemples des genres de résultats d'étudiant qui peuvent être 
réalisés quand des étudiants sont excités au sujet de l'étude et 
avoir la propriété de leur étude et le produit de leur étude : 
les publications. Les étudiants de Wojcicki ont gagné 
plusieurs compétitions internationales nationales et principales au 
cours des quinze dernières années. Les deux publications sont 
art de l'auto-portrait-supporting qui signifient que tous les étudiants dans le 
programme sont responsables d'apprendre comment vendre l'ADS et agir 
l'un sur l'autre avec la communauté. Ceci aide des étudiants 
à développer des qualifications interpersonnelles importantes et 
agit également en tant que mécanisme de relations publiques pour 
l'école et pour le journal. Il également apporte la 
communauté plus près de l'école et incite des personnes à se 
sentir comme s'elles sont les participants actifs au processus 
d'éducation.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Neste Web site, Wojcicki descreve como a 
participação em uma comunidade de aprendizagem journalistic pode 
motivate mesmo o estudante o mais recalcitrant. O Web site 
inclui as cópias da amostra do jornal, do campanile e do 
compartimento, Verde, que são exemplos dos tipos dos resultados do 
estudante que podem ser conseguidos quando os estudantes são 
excitados sobre a aprendizagem e ter a posse da sua aprendizagem e o 
produto da sua aprendizagem: as publicações. Os 
estudantes de Wojcicki ganharam diversas competições nacionais e 
internacionais principais sobre os quinze anos passados. Ambas 
as publicações são self-supporting que significa que todos os 
estudantes no programa são responsáveis para aprender como vender o 
ads e interagir com a comunidade. Isto ajuda a estudantes 
desenvolver habilidades interpersonal importantes e age também como 
um mecanismo das relações públicas para a escola e para o jornal. 
Também traz a comunidade mais perto da escola e faz povos 
sentir como se são participants ativos no processo da instrução.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questo Web site, Wojcicki descrive come la 
partecipazione ad una Comunità imparante journalistic può motivare 
persino l'allievo più recalcitrant. Il Web site include le 
copie del campione del giornale, del campanile e dello scomparto, 
Verde, che sono esempi dei generi di risultati dell'allievo che 
possono essere realizzati quando gli allievi sono eccitati circa 
imparare ed avere la proprietà del loro imparare ed il prodotto del 
loro imparare: le pubblicazioni. Gli allievi del Wojcicki 
hanno vinto parecchi concorsi nazionali ed internazionali importanti 
in questi ultimi quindici anni. Entrambe le pubblicazioni sono 
autosufficienti che significa che tutti gli allievi nel programma sono
responsabili dell'imparare come vendere il ads ed interagirsi con la 
Comunità. Ciò aiuta gli allievi a sviluppare le abilità tra 
persone importanti ed egualmente funge da meccanismo di pubbliche 
relazioni per la scuola e per il giornale. Egualmente porta la 
Comunità più vicino alla scuola ed incita la gente a ritenere come 
se siano partecipanti attivi al processo di formazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτόν τον ιστοχώρο, Wojcicki περιγράφει πώς η 
συμμετοχή σε μια δημοσιογραφική μαθαίνοντας κοινότητα μπορεί να 
παρακινήσει ακόμη και τον πιό απειθή σπουδαστή. Ο 
ιστοχώρος περιλαμβάνει τα αντίγραφα δειγμάτων της εφημερίδας, του
καμπαναριού και του περιοδικού, Verde, τα οποία είναι 
παραδείγματα των ειδών εκβάσεων σπουδαστών που μπορούν να 
επιτευχθούν όταν διεγείρονται οι σπουδαστές για την εκμάθηση και 
έχουν την ιδιοκτησία της εκμάθησής τους και το προϊόν της 
εκμάθησής τους: οι δημοσιεύσεις. Οι σπουδαστές του 
Wojcicki έχουν κερδίσει διάφορους σημαντικούς εθνικούς και 
διεθνείς ανταγωνισμούς κατά τη διάρκεια των προηγούμενων 
δεκαπέντε ετών. Και οι δύο δημοσιεύσεις είναι 
αυτοφερόμενες που σημαίνει ότι όλοι οι σπουδαστές στο πρόγραμμα 
είναι αρμόδιοι για την εκμάθηση πώς να πωλήσουν τις αγγελίες και
να αλληλεπιδράσουν με την κοινότητα. Αυτό βοηθά τους 
σπουδαστές να αναπτύξουν τις σημαντικές διαπροσωπικές δεξιότητες 
και ενεργεί επίσης ως μηχανισμός δημόσιων σχέσεων για το σχολείο
και για την εφημερίδα. Φέρνει επίσης την κοινότητα πιό 
κοντά στο σχολείο και κάνει τους ανθρώπους να αισθανθούν σαν 
είναι ενεργοί συμμετέχοντες στη διαδικασία εκπαίδευσης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En este Web site, Wojcicki describe cómo la 
participación en una comunidad que aprende periodística puede 
motivar incluso al estudiante ma's recalcitrant. El Web site 
incluye las copias de la muestra del periódico, del campanile y del 
compartimiento, Verde, que son ejemplos de las clases de resultados 
del estudiante que puedan ser alcanzados cuando excitan a los 
estudiantes sobre aprender y tener propiedad de su aprender y el 
producto de su aprender: las publicaciones. Los 
estudiantes de Wojcicki han ganado varias competiciones nacionales e 
internacionales importantes sobre los últimos quince años. 
Ambas publicaciones son autosuficientes que significa que todos 
los estudiantes en el programa son responsables de aprender cómo 
vender el ads y obrar recíprocamente con la comunidad. Esto 
ayuda a estudiantes a desarrollar habilidades interpersonales 
importantes y también actúa como mecanismo de las relaciones 
públicas para la escuela y para el periódico. También trae a 
comunidad más cercano a la escuela y hace que la gente se siente como
si ella es participantes activos en el proceso de la educación.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ESTHER WOJCICKI
FN:ESTHER WOJCICKI
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086814</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102988</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/setting-up-a-successful-journalistic-learning-community-1</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
