<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104979</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104979</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212865</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Transnational Pollution: Why Are You Dumping on Me?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Übernationale Verunreinigung: Warum geben 
Sie auf mir aus?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pollution Transnationale : Pourquoi 
videz-vous sur moi ?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Poluição Transnational: Por que você 
está despejando em mim?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Inquinamento Sopranazionale: Perchè state 
facendo uscire su me?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διεθνική ρύπανση: Γιατί καταγράφετε σε με;</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Contaminación Transnacional: ¿Por qué 
usted está vaciando en mí?</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This lesson familiarizes students with the different types of transnational pollution, and gives them an opportunity to role-play in a hypothetical case of transnational pollution involving the Danube River. The major goal of this activity is to show students that an incident in one nation may well have serious environmental consequences for other nations. Additionally, it will give students an opportunity to role-play complex roles that are meaningful and consequential to global concerns. The lesson plan and accompanying handout are highly detailed with a clearly described scenario and characters and detailed activities and questions for the students. On this Starting Point page, teachers can find learning goals, teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment hints and references and resources dealing with this exercise. It also describes the context in which the virtual tour is best used.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Lektion macht Kursteilnehmer mit den 
unterschiedlichen Typen der übernationalen Verunreinigung vertraut, 
und gibt ihnen eine Gelegenheit, in einem hypothetischen Fall 
übernationaler Verunreinigung Rolle zu spielen den Donau Fluß mit 
einbeziehend. Das Hauptziel dieser Aktivität ist darzustellen, 
daß Kursteilnehmer, daß ein Ereignis in einer Nation hervorquellen 
kann, ernste Klimakonsequenzen für andere Nationen haben Sie. 
Zusätzlich gibt es Kursteilnehmern eine Gelegenheit, Rolle zu 
spielen komplizierte Rollen, die aussagefähig und zu den globalen 
Interessen logisch folgend sind. Der Lektionplan und das 
Begleitenmitteilungsblatt werden in hohem Grade mit einem offenbar 
beschriebenen Drehbuch und Zeichen und genau geschilderte Aktivitäten
und Fragen für die Kursteilnehmer genau geschildert. Auf dieser
Ausgangspunktseite können Lehrer die erlernenziele, unterrichtende 
Anmerkungen und Spitzen, Lehrmittel, Einschätzung Tips und Referenzen
und Betriebsmittel beschäftigend diese Übung finden. Sie 
beschreibt auch den Kontext, in dem die virtuelle Tour gut verwendet 
wird.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette leçon familiarise des étudiants avec les 
différents types de pollution transnationale, et leur donne une 
occasion de jouer un rôle dans un cas hypothétique de pollution 
transnationale impliquant le fleuve de Danube. Le but principal 
de cette activité est de montrer que des étudiants qu'un incident 
dans une nation peut jaillir ayez les conséquences environnementales 
graves pour d'autres nations. Supplémentaire, il donnera à des
étudiants une occasion de jouer un rôle les rôles complexes qui 
sont signicatifs et consécutifs aux soucis globaux. Le plan de 
leçon et l'aumône d'accompagnement sont fortement détaillés avec 
un scénario clairement décrit et des caractères et des activités 
et des questions détaillées pour les étudiants. À cette page
de point de départ, les professeurs peuvent trouver des buts 
d'étude, des notes et des extrémités d'enseignement, matériel 
didactique, des conseils d'évaluation et des références et des 
ressources traitant cet exercice. Il décrit également le 
contexte dans lequel l'excursion virtuelle mieux est utilisée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta lição familiariza estudantes com os tipos 
diferentes de poluição transnational, e dá-lhes uma oportunidade de
role-play em um exemplo hipotético da poluição transnational que 
envolve o rio de Danúbio. O objetivo principal desta atividade 
é mostrar que estudantes que um incident em uma nação pode jorrar 
tenha conseqüências ambientais sérias para outras nações. 
Adicionalmente, dará a estudantes uma oportunidade de role-play
os papéis complexos que são significativos e consequential aos 
interesses globais. A planta da lição e o handout acompanhar 
são detalhados altamente com um scenario claramente descrito e 
caráteres e atividades e perguntas detalhadas para os estudantes. 
Nesta página do ponto começar, os professores podem encontrar 
os objetivos de aprendizagem, as notas e as pontas ensinando, os 
materiais de ensino, as sugestões da avaliação e as referências e 
os recursos tratando deste exercício. Descreve também o 
contexto em que a excursão virtual é usada melhor.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa lezione rende familiare gli allievi ai tipi 
differenti di inquinamenti sopranazionali e dà loro un'occasione 
atteggiarsi in un caso ipotetico di inquinamento sopranazionale che 
coinvolge il fiume del Danubio. L'obiettivo principale di questa
attività è di mostrare che allievi che un avvenimento in una nazione
può scaturire abbia conseguenze ambientali gravi per altre nazioni. 
Ulteriormente, darà ad allievi un'occasione atteggiarsi ruoli 
complessi che sono espressivi e conseguenti alle preoccupazioni 
globali. Il programma di lezione e la dispensa accompagnare 
altamente sono dettagliati con un piano d'azione chiaramente descritto
e caratteri ed attività e domande dettagliate per gli allievi. 
A questa pagina del punto di partenza, gli insegnanti possono 
trovare gli obiettivi imparanti, note e punte d'istruzione, materiali 
didattici, suggerimenti di valutazione e riferimenti e risorse 
occupantesi di questa esercitazione. Egualmente descrive il 
contesto in cui il giro virtuale è usato il più bene.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το μάθημα εξοικειώνει τους σπουδαστές με τους 
διαφορετικούς τύπους διεθνικών ρυπάνσεων, και τους δίνει ένα 
ρόλος-παιχνίδι ευκαιρίας σε μια υποθετική περίπτωση διεθνικής 
ρύπανσης που περιλαμβάνει τον ποταμό Δούναβη. Ο 
σημαντικότερος στόχος αυτής της δραστηριότητας είναι να 
εμφανιστεί στους σπουδαστές ότι ένα γεγονός σε ένα έθνος 
μπορεί καλά να έχει τις σοβαρές περιβαλλοντικές συνέπειες για 
άλλα έθνη. Επιπλέον, θα δώσει στους σπουδαστές ένα 
ρόλος-παιχνίδι ευκαιρίας σύνθετοι ρόλοι που είναι σημαντικοί 
και επακόλουθοι στις σφαιρικές ανησυχίες. Το σχέδιο 
μαθήματος και το συνοδευτικό φυλλάδιο είναι ιδιαίτερα λεπτομερή 
με ένα σαφώς περιγεγραμμένο σενάριο και τους χαρακτήρες και τις 
λεπτομερείς δραστηριότητες και τις ερωτήσεις για τους σπουδαστές. 
Σε αυτήν την σελίδα αφετηρίας, οι δάσκαλοι μπορούν να 
βρούν τους στόχους εκμάθησης, τις σημειώσεις και τις άκρες 
διδασκαλίας, τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, τους υπαινιγμούς αξιολόγησης 
και τις αναφορές και τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς εξετάζοντας αυτήν 
την άσκηση. Περιγράφει επίσης το πλαίσιο στο οποίο ο 
εικονικός γύρος χρησιμοποιείται καλύτερα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta lección familiariza a estudiantes con los diversos 
tipos de contaminación transnacional, y les da una oportunidad de 
actuar en papel en un caso hipotético de la contaminación 
transnacional que implica el río de Danubio. La meta principal 
de esta actividad es mostrar que los estudiantes que un incidente en 
una nación puede manar tenga consecuencias ambientales serias para 
otras naciones. Además, dará a estudiantes una oportunidad de 
actuar en papel los papeles complejos que son significativos y 
consecuentes a las preocupaciones globales. El plan de la 
lección y el folleto del acompañamiento se detallan altamente con un
decorado claramente descrito y los caracteres y las actividades y las 
preguntas detalladas para los estudiantes. En esta paginación 
del punto de partida, los profesores pueden encontrar las metas que 
aprenden, las notas y las extremidades de enseñanza, los materiales 
didácticos, las indirectas del gravamen y las referencias y los 
recursos ocupándose de este ejercicio. También describe el 
contexto en el cual el viaje virtual se utiliza lo más mejor posible.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212865</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104979</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/transnational-pollution-why-are-you-dumping-on-me</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
