<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108286</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108286</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206503</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Photographs of the 369th Infantry and African Americans During World War I</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Fotographien der 369. Infanterie und der 
afrikanischen Amerikaner während des Ersten Weltkrieges</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Photographies de la 369th infanterie et des 
Américains africains pendant la Première Guerre Mondiale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fotografias da 369th infantaria e dos americanos 
africanos durante o world.war.i</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fotografie della 369th fanteria e degli Americani 
africani durante il world.war.i</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Φωτογραφίες του 369th πεζικού και των αφρικανικών 
Αμερικανών κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου Ι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fotografías de la 369a infantería y de los 
americanos africanos durante Primera Guerra Mundial</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features an all-black regiment that rose to fame at a time when the Army, federal workers, and other parts of society were segregated. The 369th Infantry, also known as the Harlem Hellfighters, was among the first regiments to arrive in France in 1917 after the U.S. declared war on Germany. Under the command of mostly white officers, the regiment spent 191 days in combat, longer than any other American unit, and emerged as one of the most highly decorated regiments during the Great War.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">kennzeichnet ein all-schwarzes Regiment, das zum 
Ruhm stieg, zu einer Zeit als die Armee, die Bundesarbeiter und andere
Teile der Gesellschaft getrennt wurden. Die 369. Infanterie, 
alias das Harlem Hellfighters, gehörten zu den ersten Regimenten, zum
in Frankreich 1917 anzukommen, nachdem die VEREINIGTEN STAATEN Krieg 
auf Deutschland erklärten. Unter dem Befehl meistens der 
weißen Offiziere, verbrachte das Regiment 191 Tage im Kampf, länger 
als jede andere amerikanische Maßeinheit, und aufgetaucht als eins 
der in hohem Grade verzierten Regimente während des großen Krieges.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">comporte un régiment tout-noir qui s'est levé à
la renommée à un moment où l'armée, les ouvriers fédéraux, et 
d'autres parties de la société ont été isolés. La 369th 
infanterie, également connue sous le nom de Harlem Hellfighters, 
était parmi les premiers régiments à arriver en France en 1917 
après que les ETATS-UNIS aient déclaré la guerre sur l'Allemagne. 
Sous la commande la plupart du temps des officiers blancs, le 
régiment a passé 191 jours dans le combat, plus longtemps que 
n'importe quelle autre unité américaine, et émergé en tant qu'un 
des régiments le plus fortement décorés pendant la grande guerre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">caracteriza um regiment todo-preto que se levante 
à fama em uma hora em que o exército, os trabalhadores federais, e 
outras partes da sociedade fossem segregados. A 369th 
infantaria, sabida também como o Harlem Hellfighters, era entre os 
primeiros regiments a chegar em France em 1917 depois que os ESTADOS 
UNIDOS declararam a guerra em Germany. Sob o comando na maior 
parte dos oficiais brancos, o regiment gastou 191 dias no combate, 
mais por muito tempo do que toda a outra unidade americana, e emerso 
como um dos regiments o mais altamente decorados durante a guerra 
grande.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">caratterizza un regiment tutto-nero che è 
aumentato a fama in un momento in cui l'esercito, gli operai federali 
ed altre parti della società sono stati segregati. La 369th 
fanteria, anche conosciuta come il Harlem Hellfighters, era fra i 
primi regiments da arrivare in Francia in 1917 dopo che gli STATI 
UNITI dichiarassero la guerra con Germania. Sotto il comando 
principalmente degli ufficiali bianchi, il regiment ha 
speso 191 giorno nel combattimento, più lungamente di 
qualunque altra unità americana ed emerso come uno dei regiments il 
più altamente decorati durante la guerra grande.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χαρακτηρίζει ένα όλος-μαύρο σύνταγμα εκείνο το 
ανήλθε στη φήμη σε μία εποχή που διαχωρίστηκαν ο στρατός, οι 
ομοσπονδιακοί εργαζόμενοι, και άλλα μέρη της κοινωνίας. Το 
369th πεζικό, επίσης γνωστό ως Harlem Hellfighters, ήταν 
μεταξύ των πρώτων συνταγμάτων για να φθάσει στη Γαλλία το 1917
μετά από τον κηρυγμένο οι ΗΠΑ πόλεμο στη Γερμανία. Κάτω 
από την εντολή των συνήθως λευκών ανώτερων υπαλλήλων, το 
σύνταγμα που ξοδεύεται 191 ημέρες στον αγώνα, περισσότερο από
οποιαδήποτε άλληδήποτε αμερικανική μονάδα, και που διαφαίνεται 
ως ένα από τα ο πιό ιδιαίτερα διακοσμημένα συντάγματα κατά τη 
διάρκεια του μεγάλου πολέμου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece un regimiento todo-negro que se levantó a 
la fama en un momento en que segregaron al ejército, a los 
trabajadores federales, y a otras partes de la sociedad. La 369a
infantería, también conocida como el Harlem Hellfighters, estaba 
entre los primeros regimientos a llegar en Francia en 1917 después de
que los ESTADOS UNIDOS declararan guerra en Alemania. Bajo 
comando sobre todo de los oficiales blancos, el regimiento pasó 191 
días en combate, más de largo que cualquier otra unidad americana, y
emergido como uno de los regimientos lo más altamente posible 
adornados durante la gran guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206503</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108286</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/photographs-of-the-369th-infantry-and-african-americans-during-world-war-i</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
