<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103580</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103580</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206853</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Our Documents: Tools for Educators</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Unsere Dokumente: Hilfsmittel für Erzieher</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Nos Documents : Outils pour des éducateurs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nossos Originais: Ferramentas para 
educadores</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I Nostri Documenti: Strumenti per gli 
educatori</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα έγγραφά μας: Εργαλεία για τους εκπαιδευτικούς</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Nuestros Documentos: Herramientas para los 
educadores</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is designed to help teachers use in the classroom 100 of the most important documents in our nation's history. The 100 milestone documents appear on a timeline, along with descriptions telling why they're important. Key themes are discussed?rights and responsibilities, individuals and society, state and federal power, and commerce and regulation. Guidelines suggest ways to use primary sources as teaching tools.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist konzipiert, Lehrergebrauch im Klassenzimmer 
100 der wichtigsten Dokumente in der Geschichte unserer Nation zu 
helfen. Die 100 Meilensteindokumente erscheinen auf einem 
timeline, zusammen mit den Beschreibungen, die erklären, warum sie 
wichtig sind. Schlüsselthemen sind discussed?rights und 
Verantwortlichkeiten, Einzelpersonen und Gesellschaft, Zustand und 
Bundesenergie und Handel und Regelung. Korrekturlinien schlagen 
Methoden vor, Primärquellen als unterrichtende Hilfsmittel zu 
verwenden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est conçu pour aider l'utilisation de professeurs
dans la salle de classe 100 des documents les plus importants dans 
l'histoire de notre nation. Les 100 documents d'étape 
importante apparaissent sur une chronologie, avec des descriptions 
indiquant pourquoi ils sont importants. Les thèmes principaux 
sont des discussed?rights et des responsabilités, des individus et 
société, état et puissance fédérale, et commerce et règlement. 
Les directives suggèrent des voies d'utiliser des sources 
primaires en tant qu'outils d'enseignement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é projetado ajudar ao uso dos professores na sala
de aula 100 dos originais os mais importantes no history da nossa 
nação. Os 100 originais do marco miliário aparecem em um 
timeline, junto com as descrições que dizem porque são importantes.
Os temas chaves são discussed?rights e responsabilidades, 
indivíduos e sociedade, estado e potência federal, e comércio e 
regulamento. Os guidelines sugerem maneiras usar fontes 
preliminares como ferramentas ensinando.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è destinato a aiutare l'uso degli insegnanti 
nell'aula 100 dei documenti più importanti nella storia della nostra 
nazione. I 100 documenti della pietra compaiono su un timeline, 
con le descrizioni che dicono a perchè sono importanti. I temi 
chiave sono discussed?rights e le responsabilità, individui e 
società, dichiarano e potenza federale e commercio e 
regolazione. La guida di riferimento suggerisce i modi usare le 
sorgenti primarie come strumenti d'istruzione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">σχεδιάζεται για να βοηθήσει τη χρήση δασκάλων στην 
τάξη 100 των σημαντικότερων εγγράφων στην ιστορία του έθνους 
μας. Τα 100 έγγραφα κύριων σημείων εμφανίζονται σε μια 
υπόδειξη ως προς το χρόνο, μαζί με τις περιγραφές λέγοντας γιατί
είναι σημαντικά. Τα βασικά θέματα είναι discussed?rights
και ευθύνες, άτομα και κοινωνία, κράτος και ομοσπονδιακή δύναμη,
και εμπόριο και κανονισμός. Οι οδηγίες προτείνουν τους 
τρόπους να χρησιμοποιηθούν οι αρχικές πηγές ως εργαλεία 
διδασκαλίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">se diseña ayudar a uso de los profesores en la 
sala de clase 100 de los documentos más importantes de la historia de
nuestra nación. Los 100 documentos del jalón aparecen en un 
timeline, junto con las descripciones que dicen porqué son 
importantes. Los temas dominantes son discussed?rights y 
responsabilidades, individuos y sociedad, estado y potencia federal, y
comercio y regulación. Las guías de consulta sugieren maneras 
de utilizar fuentes primarias como herramientas de enseñanza.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206853</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103580</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/our-documents-tools-for-educators</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
