<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104607</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104607</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086890</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The American Woman's Home .</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Amerikanischen Frau Haupt.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Femme Américaine À la maison.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A Mulher Americana Home.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Donna Americana Domestica.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η "Οικία" της αμερικανικής γυναίκας.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Mujer Americana Casera.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The rise of a new Northern middle class brought with it new ideals of family life and gender roles. While men worked outside the home, women were to preside over the domestic sphere, not only by performing household labor but also by setting a moral example for children and creating a haven that was protected from the outside world. This frontispiece and title page came from a popular 1869 guide to the formation and Maintenance of Economical</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Anstieg einer neuen mittleren Nordkategorie geholt mit
ihr neue Ideale der Familienleben- und Geschlechtrollen. 
Während Männer außerhalb des Hauses arbeiteten, Frauen dem 
inländischen Bereich, nicht nur, indem sie Haushalt Arbeit aber auch 
indem durchführten die Einstellung eines moralischen Beispiels für 
Kinder und das Herstellen eines Hafens vorsitzen sollten, der vor der 
äußeren Welt geschützt wurde. Dieses Frontispiz und 
Titelblatt kamen von einer populären Anleitung 1869 zur Anordnung und
von der Wartung von ökonomischem</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'élévation d'une nouvelle bourgeoisie nordique 
apportée avec elle nouveaux idéaux des rôles de la vie et de genre 
de famille. Tandis que les hommes travaillaient en dehors de la 
maison, les femmes devaient présider au-dessus de la sphère 
domestique, non seulement en exécutant le travail de ménage mais 
également en plaçant un exemple moral pour des enfants et en créant
un asile qui a été protégé contre le monde extérieur. Ces 
frontispice et page titre sont venus d'un guide 1869 populaire de la 
formation et de l'entretien d'économique</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A ascensão de uma classe média do norte nova trazida com
ela ideals novos de papéis da vida e do gender de família. 
Quando os homens trabalharam fora da HOME, as mulheres deviam 
preside sobre a esfera doméstica, não somente executando o trabalho 
da casa mas também ajustando um exemplo moral para crianças e 
criando um haven que fosse protegido do mundo exterior. Estes 
frontispiece e página de título vieram de uma guia 1869 popular à 
formação e da manutenção de econômico</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'aumento di nuovo codice categoria centrale nordico 
portato con esso nuovi ideali dei ruoli di vita e di genere di 
famiglia. Mentre gli uomini hanno lavorato fuori della sede, le 
donne dovevano presiedere la sfera domestica, non soltanto effettuando
il lavoro della famiglia ma anche regolando un esempio morale per
i bambini e creando un porto che è stato protetto dal mondo esterno. 
Questi frontispiece e pagina di titolo sono venuto da una guida 
popolare 1869 alla formazione e da una manutenzione di economico</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η άνοδος μια νέα βόρεια μέση κλάση που παρουσιάζεται
με τον τα νέα ιδανικά των ρόλων οικογενειακών ζωής και γένους. 
Ενώ οι άνδρες εργάστηκαν έξω από το σπίτι, οι γυναίκες 
επρόκειτο να προεδρεύσουν πέρα από την εσωτερική σφαίρα, όχι 
μόνο με την εκτέλεση της οικιακής εργασίας αλλά και με τον 
καθορισμό ενός ηθικού παραδείγματος για τα παιδιά και τη 
δημιουργία ενός λιμανιού που προστατεύθηκε από τον εξωτερικό 
κόσμο. Αυτή η σελίδα frontispiece και τίτλου προήλθε 
από έναν δημοφιλή οδηγό 1869 στο σχηματισμό και τη συντήρηση 
οικονομικού</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La subida de una nueva clase media norteña traída con 
ella nuevos ideales de los papeles de la vida y del género de 
familia. Mientras que los hombres trabajaron fuera del hogar, 
las mujeres debían presidir la esfera doméstica, no solamente 
realizando el trabajo de la casa pero también fijando un ejemplo 
moral para los niños y creando un asilo que fue protegido contra el 
mundo exterior. Este frontispiece y paginación de título 
vinieron de una guía popular 1869 a la formación y del mantenimiento
de económico</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086890</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104607</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-american-womans-home</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
