<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103583</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103583</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205937</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Traveling Culture: Circuit Chautauqua in the Twentieth Century</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Reisende Kultur: Stromkreis Chautauqua im 
zwanzigsten Jahrhundert</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Culture de Déplacement : Circuit Chautauqua
au vingtième siècle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Cultura Viajando: Circuito Chautauqua no 
vigésimo século</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Coltura Mobile: Circuito Chautauqua nel 
ventesimo secolo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διακινούμενος πολιτισμός: Κύκλωμα Chautauqua 
στον εικοστό αιώνα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cultura Que viaja: Circuito Chautauqua en el
vigésimo siglo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site presents nearly 8,000 publicity brochures, ads, and talent circulars for more than 4,500 lecturers, teachers, preachers, politicians, actors, singers, magicians and others who performed in these touring Chautauquas. Founded in 1874 to train Sunday school teachers, Chautauquas spread from their initial incarnation on New York's Lake Chautauqua. By the 1910s, these assemblies could be found almost everywhere, presenting a message of self and civic improvement to millions of Americans.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site stellt fast 8.000 Werbebroschüren, ADS
und Talentrundschreiben für mehr als 4.500 Lektoren, Lehrer, 
Prediger, Politiker, Schauspieler, Sänger, Magier und andere dar, die
in diesen durchführten, die Chautauquas bereisen. Gegründet 
1874, um Sonntagsschule Lehrer auszubilden, verbritt Chautauquas von 
ihrer Ausgangsinkarnation auf See Chautauqua New.yorks. Bis zum 
den 1910s konnten diese Versammlungen fast überall gefunden werden 
und eine Meldung von Selbst- und von bürgerlicher Verbesserung 
Millionen Amerikanern darstellen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site présente presque 8.000 brochures de 
publicité, ADS, et circulaires de talent pour plus de 4.500 
conférenciers, professeurs, prédicateurs, politiciens, acteurs, 
chanteurs, magiciens et autres qui ont exécuté dans ces derniers 
voyageant Chautauquas. Fondé en 1874 pour former des 
professeurs d'école de dimanche, Chautauquas a écarté de leur 
incarnation initiale sur le lac Chautauqua New.york's. Par les 
années 10, ces assemblages pourraient être trouvés presque partout,
présentant un message d'art de l'auto-portrait et d'amélioration civique aux 
millions d'Américains.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local apresenta quase 8.000 folhetos do 
publicity, ads, e circulares do talent para mais de 4.500 lecturers, 
professores, preachers, políticos, atores, singers, mágicos e outros
que executaram nestes que excursionam Chautauquas. Fundado em 
1874 para treinar professores da escola de domingo, Chautauquas 
espalhou de seu incarnation inicial no lago Chautauqua New.york. 
Pelos 1910s, estes conjuntos poderiam ser encontrados quase em 
toda parte, apresentando uma mensagem do self e da melhoria civic aos 
milhões dos americanos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo presenta quasi 8.000 opuscoli di 
pubblicità, il ads e le circonvallazioni di talento per più di 4.500
conferenzieri, insegnanti, preachers, politici, attori, cantanti, 
maghi ed altri che hanno effettuato in questi che fanno un giro di 
Chautauquas. Fondato in 1874 per addestrare gli insegnanti della
scuola di domenica, Chautauquas si è sparso dal loro incarnation 
iniziale sul lago Chautauqua New.york. Entro gli anni 10, questi
complessivi potrebbero essere trovati quasi dappertutto, presentando 
un messaggio dell'auto e del miglioramento civico a milioni di 
Americani.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή παρουσιάζει τα σχεδόν 8.000 
φυλλάδια δημοσιότητας, αγγελίες, και εγκυκλίους ταλέντου για τους
περισσότερους από 4.500 ομιλητές, τους δασκάλους, τους 
ιεροκήρυκες, τους πολιτικούς, τους δράστες, τους τραγουδιστές, 
τους μάγους και άλλους που απέδωσαν σε αυτά τα να περιοδεύσουν 
Chautauquas. Ιδρυμένο το 1874 για να εκπαιδεύσει τους 
σχολικούς δασκάλους της Κυριακής, Chautauquas διέδωσε από την 
αρχική ενσάρκωσή τους στη λίμνη Chautauqua της Νέας Υόρκης. 
Από το 1910s, αυτές οι συμβολικές γλώσσες θα μπορούσαν 
να βρεθούν σχεδόν παντού, παρουσιάζοντας ένα μήνυμα της μόνης 
και πολιτικής βελτίωσης στα εκατομμύρια Αμερικανών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio presenta casi 8.000 folletos de la 
publicidad, el ads, y las circulares del talento para más de 4.500 
conferenciantes, profesores, predicadores, políticos, agentes, 
cantantes, magos y otros que se realizaron en éstos que viajaban 
Chautauquas. Fundado en 1874 para entrenar a profesores de la 
escuela de domingo, Chautauquas se separó de su encarnación inicial 
en el lago Chautauqua New.york's. Por los años 10, estos 
ensamblajes podrían ser encontrados casi por todas partes, 
presentando un mensaje del uno mismo y de la mejora cívica a millones
de americanos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205937</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103583</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/traveling-culture-circuit-chautauqua-in-the-twentieth-century</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
