<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105772</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105772</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206910</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Oberlin History as American History</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Oberlin Geschichte als amerikanische Geschichte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Histoire d'Oberlin en tant qu'histoire 
américaine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">History de Oberlin como o history americano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Storia di Oberlin come storia americana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ιστορία Oberlin ως αμερικανική ιστορία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Historia de Oberlin como historia americana</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">offers exhibits that tell about the lives and histories of the people of Oberlin, Ohio. The website features the story of an Amistad captive, Oberlin women and the struggle for equality, and the city's cooperative tradition. It also includes city maps and pictures, letters and essays related to the city's founding and development, newspaper articles regarding the Niagara movement, and census data.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Angebotausstellungen, die über die Leben und die 
Geschichten der Leute von Oberlin, Ohio erklären. Die Web site 
kennzeichnet die Geschichte eines Amistad Gefangenen, der Oberlin 
Frauen und des Kampfes für Gleichheit und der kooperativen Tradition 
der Stadt. Sie enthält auch die Stadtkarten und -abbildungen, 
Zeichen und Versuche, die auf der Gründung und Entwicklung der Stadt 
in Verbindung gestanden werden, die Zeitungsartikel betreffend sind 
die Niagara Bewegung und Zählungdaten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">objets exposés d'offres qui indiquent au sujet 
des vies et des histoires des personnes d'Oberlin, Ohio. Le site
Web comporte l'histoire d'un captif d'Amistad, des femmes d'Oberlin et
la lutte pour l'égalité, et la tradition coopérative de la ville. 
Il inclut également des cartes et des images de ville, des 
lettres et des essais liés à la fondation et le développement de la
ville, des articles de journal concernant le mouvement de Niagara, et 
des données de recensement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">exibições das ofertas que dizem sobre as vidas e
os histories dos povos de Oberlin, Ohio. O Web site caracteriza 
a história de um cativo de Amistad, mulheres de Oberlin e o esforço 
para a igualdade, e a tradição cooperativa da cidade. Inclui 
também os mapas e os retratos da cidade, as letras e os essays 
relacionados a fundar e desenvolvimento da cidade, os artigos de 
jornal a respeito do movimento de Niagara, e os dados de census.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esposizioni di offerte che dicono a circa le vite 
ed i dati storici della gente di Oberlin, Ohio. Il Web site 
caratterizza la storia di un prigioniero di Amistad, donne di Oberlin 
e la lotta per uguaglianza e la tradizione cooperativa della città. 
Egualmente include i programmi ed immagini della città, lettere
e saggi relativi a fondare e sviluppo della città, articoli di stampa
per quanto riguarda il movimento del Niagara e dati censuali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">οι προσφορές εκθέτουν που λένε για τις ζωές και τις 
ιστορίες των ανθρώπων Oberlin, Οχάιο. Ο ιστοχώρος 
χαρακτηρίζει την ιστορία ενός αιχμαλώτου Amistad, των γυναικών
Oberlin και της προσπάθειας για την ισότητα, και της 
συνεταιριστικής παράδοσης της πόλης. Περιλαμβάνει επίσης 
τους χάρτες και τις εικόνες πόλεων, τις επιστολές και τα δοκίμια 
σχετικούς με την ίδρυση και την ανάπτυξη της πόλης, τα άρθρα 
εφημερίδων σχετικά με τη μετακίνηση Niagara, και τα στοιχεία 
απογραφής.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">objetos expuestos de las ofertas que hablan de las
vidas y de las historias de la gente de Oberlin, Ohio. El Web 
site ofrece la historia de un cautivo de Amistad, las mujeres de 
Oberlin y la lucha para la igualdad, y la tradición cooperativa de la
ciudad. También incluye las correspondencias y los cuadros de 
la ciudad, las cartas y los ensayos relacionados con la fundación y 
el desarrollo de la ciudad, los artículos periodísticos con respecto
al movimiento de Niagara, y los datos de censo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206910</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105772</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/oberlin-history-as-american-history</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
