<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106718</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106718</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211712</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Protist Image Data</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Protist Bild-Daten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Données d'Image de Protist</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Dados Da Imagem De Protist</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dati Di Immagine Di Protist</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στοιχεία εικόνας Protist</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Datos De la Imagen De Protist</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Protist Image Data (PID) is an online database that provides pictures and short descriptions of selected Protist genera, especially those genera whose species are frequently used as experimental organisms or are important in studies of organismal evolution. Up-to-date information is provided on the morphology, taxonomy and phylogenetic relationships of these organisms. Information on PID pages is arranged by the following: Introduction, Appearance, Ultrastructure, Reproduction and Life History, Similar Genera, Classification, Taxonomy and Nomenclature, Cultures, Selected References, and Internet Resources.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Protist Bild-Daten (PID) sind eine 
Onlinedatenbank, die Abbildungen und kurze Beschreibungen der 
ausgewählten Protist Klassen, besonders jene Klassen liefert, deren 
Sorten häufig als experimentelle organismen verwendet werden oder in 
den Studien der organismal Entwicklung wichtig sind. Aktuelle 
Informationen werden auf der Morphologie, der Taxonomie und den 
phylogenetischen Verhältnissen dieser organismen zur Verfügung 
gestellt. Informationen über PID Seiten werden durch das 
folgende geordnet: Einleitung, Aussehen, Ultrastruktur, 
Wiedergabe und Leben-Geschichte, ähnliche Klassen, Klassifikation, 
Taxonomie und Bezeichnung, Kulturen, ausgewählte Referenzen und 
Internet Informationsquellen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les données d'image de Protist (PID) sont une 
base de données en ligne qui fournit des images et des descriptions 
courtes des genres choisis de Protist, particulièrement ces genres 
dont les espèces sont fréquemment utilisées en tant 
qu'organizations expérimentales ou sont importantes dans les études 
de l'évolution organismal. Des informations à jour sont 
fournies sur la morphologie, la taxonomie et les rapports 
phylogénétiques de ces organizations. L'information aux pages 
de PID est arrangée par ce qui suit : Introduction, aspect, 
ultrastructure, reproduction et histoire de la vie, genres semblables,
classification, taxonomie et nomenclature, cultures, références 
choisies, et ressources d'Internet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os dados da imagem de Protist (PID) são uma base 
de dados em linha que forneça retratos e descrições curtas de 
genera selecionados de Protist, especial aqueles genera cujas as 
espécies freqüentemente são usadas como organismos experimentais ou
são importantes nos estudos da evolução organismal. A 
informação moderna é fornecida na morfologia, no taxonomy e nos 
relacionamentos phylogenetic destes organismos. A informação 
em páginas de PID é arranjada pelo seguinte: Introdução, 
aparência, ultrastructure, reprodução e history da vida, genera 
similares, classificação, taxonomy e nomenclatura, culturas, 
referências selecionadas, e recursos de Internet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I dati di immagine di Protist (PID) sono una base 
di dati in linea che fornisce le immagini e le descrizioni corte dei 
generi selezionati di Protist, particolarmente quei generi di cui le 
specie frequentemente sono usate come organismi sperimentali o sono 
importanti negli studi su sviluppo organismal. Le informazioni 
aggiornate sono fornite sulla morfologia, sulla tassonomia e sui 
rapporti filogenetici di questi organismi. Le informazioni alle 
pagine di PID sono organizzate da quanto segue: Introduzione, 
apparenza, ultrastruttura, riproduzione e storia di vita, generi 
simili, classificazione, tassonomia e nomenclatura, colture, 
riferimenti selezionati e risorse di Internet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το στοιχείο εικόνας Protist (PID) είναι μια σε 
απευθείας σύνδεση βάση δεδομένων που παρέχει τις εικόνες και τις
σύντομες περιγραφές των επιλεγμένων Protist γενών, ειδικά 
εκείνα τα γένη τα των οποίων είδη χρησιμοποιούνται συχνά ως 
πειραματικοί οργανισμοί ή είναι σημαντικά στις μελέτες της 
organismal εξέλιξης. Οι ενημερωμένες πληροφορίες 
παρέχονται για τη μορφολογία, την ταξονομία και τις φυλογενετικές 
σχέσεις αυτών των οργανισμών. Οι πληροφορίες για τις 
σελίδες PID τακτοποιούνται από τα εξής: Εισαγωγή, 
εμφάνιση, ultrastructure, ιστορία αναπαραγωγής και ζωής, 
παρόμοια γένη, ταξινόμηση, ταξονομία και ονοματολογία, 
πολιτισμοί, επιλεγμένες αναφορές, και στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς 
Διαδικτύου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los datos de la imagen de Protist (PID) son una 
base de datos en línea que proporciona a cuadros y a descripciones 
cortas de los géneros seleccionados de Protist, especialmente esos 
géneros que especies se utilicen como organismos experimentales o 
sean con frecuencia importantes en estudios de la evolución 
organismal. La información actualizada se proporciona en la 
morfología, la taxonomía y los lazos phylogenetic de estos 
organismos. La información en las paginaciones de PID es 
arreglada por el siguiente: Introducción, aspecto, 
ultraestructura, reproducción e historia de la vida, géneros 
similares, clasificación, taxonomía y nomenclatura, culturas, 
referencias seleccionadas, y recursos de Internet.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CHARLES O'KELLY
FN:CHARLES O'KELLY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:TIM LITTLEJOHN
FN:TIM LITTLEJOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211712</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106718</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/protist-image-data</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
