<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105226</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105226</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202620</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Diary of a Tar Heel Confederate Soldier</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Tagebuch eines Teer-Ferse-verbündeten Soldaten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Agenda d'un soldat confédéré de talon de 
goudron</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Diário de um soldado confederate do salto do 
piche</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Diario di un soldato confederato del tallone del 
catrame</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ημερολόγιο ενός ομόσπονδου στρατιώτη τακουνιών 
πίσσας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Diario de un soldado confederado del talón del 
alquitrán</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this lesson students read the account of a private from Charlotte who served in the Civil War and grew tired of only hearing about the war from the perspectives of officers. After reading his experiences as a "man behind the gun" students will write their own point-of-view piece. They also have the opportunity to read other diary accounts from the war available through Documenting the American South.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In den Kursteilnehmern dieser Lektion gelesen dem 
Konto von einem privatem von Charlotte, das im Bürgerkrieg diente und
von über den Krieg von den Perspektiven der Offiziere nur hören 
müde wuchs. Nach dem Ablesen seiner Erfahrungen als die ", Mann
hinter Gewehr" Kursteilnehmer schreibt ihr eigenes Punkt-von-Ansicht 
Stück. Sie haben auch die Gelegenheit, andere Tagebuchkonten 
vom vorhandenen durchgehenden des Krieges zu lesen, den amerikanischen
Süden dokumentierend.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans des étudiants de cette leçon lus le compte 
d'un privé de Charlotte qui a servi dans la guerre civile et s'est 
développé fatigué d'entendre parler seulement de la guerre des 
perspectives des officiers. Après lecture de ses expériences 
comme l'"homme derrière pistolet" des étudiants écrira leur propre 
morceau de point-de-vue. Ils ont également l'occasion de lire 
d'autres comptes d'agenda du traversant disponible de guerre 
documentant les Sud américains.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nos estudantes desta lição lidos o cliente de um
confidencial de Charlotte que serviu na guerra civil e cresceu tired 
somente da audição sobre a guerra dos perspectives dos oficiais. 
Após ter lido suas experiências como o "homem atrás do 
injetor" estudantes escreverá sua própria parte da ponto-$$$-VISTA. 
Têm também a oportunidade de ler outros clientes do diário do
direto disponível da guerra documentando o sul americano.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Negli allievi di questa lezione colti il cliente 
di un riservato da Charlotte che ha servito nella guerra civile e si 
è sviluppata stanco soltanto di sentire parlare della guerra 
dalle prospettive degli ufficiali. Dopo la lettura delle sue 
esperienze come "l'uomo dietro pistola" allievi scriverà la loro 
propria parte di punto-de-vista. Egualmente hanno l'occasione 
leggere altri clienti del diario dal diretto disponibile di guerra 
documentando il sud americano.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτό το μάθημα οι σπουδαστές διάβασαν τον 
απολογισμό ενός ιδιωτικού από το Σαρλόττα που εξυπηρέτησε στον 
εμφύλιο πόλεμο και έγινε κουρασμένο μόνο να ακούσει για τον 
πόλεμο από τις προοπτικές των ανώτερων υπαλλήλων. Μετά 
από να διαβάσουν την εμπειρία του ως "άτομο πίσω από το 
πυροβόλο όπλο" οι σπουδαστές θα γράψουν το κομμάτι άποψής τους.
Έχουν επίσης την ευκαιρία να διαβάσουν άλλους απολογισμούς
ημερολογίων από τον πόλεμο διαθέσιμο μέσω της τεκμηρίωσης του 
αμερικανικού νότου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En los estudiantes de esta lección leídos la 
cuenta de un privado de Charlotte que sirvió en la guerra civil y 
creció cansada solamente de oír hablar la guerra de las perspectivas
de oficiales. Después de leer sus experiencias como el "hombre 
detrás del arma" los estudiantes escribirá su propio pedazo de la 
punta-de-vista. También tienen la oportunidad de leer otras 
cuentas del diario del directo disponible de la guerra documentando el
sur americano.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MEGHAN MCGLINN
FN:MEGHAN MCGLINN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202620</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105226</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/diary-of-a-tar-heel-confederate-soldier</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
