<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103342</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103342</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086106</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Durable White Supremacy": Belle Kearney Puts Black Men in Their Place</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Haltbare Weiße Vorherrschaft": Schönheit
Kearney setzt schwarze Männer in ihren Platz ein</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Suprématie Blanche Durable" : La belle 
Kearney met les hommes noirs dans leur endroit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Supremacy Branco Durável": O belle Kearney
põe homens pretos em seu lugar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Supremacy Bianco Durevole": Il belle 
Kearney mette gli uomini neri nel loro posto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ανθεκτική άσπρη υπεροχή": Το Belle Kearney
βάζει τα μαύρα άτομα σε ισχύ τους</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Supremacía Blanca Durable": El belle 
Kearney pone a hombres negros en su lugar</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The struggle for woman suffrage lasted almost a century, beginning with the 1848 Woman's Rights Convention at Seneca Falls, New York, and including the 1890 union of two competing suffrage organizations to form the National American Woman Suffrage Association (NAWSA). NAWSA and other organizations campaigned diligently for the vote in a variety of ways, but did not achieve success until the ratification of the Nineteenth Amendment to the U.S. Constitution in 1920. This prolonged struggle entangled female activists in other important political and moral issues that divided the nation along racial, ethnic, and class lines, and debates over the vote for women often took a divisive tone. Some white women suffrage leaders were willing to use class, ethnic, and racial arguments to bolster the case for granting white women the vote. Belle Kearney, a white Mississippi suffragist who addressed the 1903 NAWSA convention, raised the specter of black male political power to argue for the enfranchisement of white women.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Kampf für Fraustimmrecht dauerte fast ein 
Jahrhundert, fing mit der 1848 Recht-Vereinbarung der Frau an den 
Seneca-Fällen, New York an, und enthält den Anschluß 1890 von zwei 
konkurrierenden Stimmrechtorganisationen, um die nationale 
amerikanische Frau-Stimmrecht-Verbindung (NAWSA) zu bilden. 
NAWSA und andere Organisationen warben mit Sorgfalt für die 
Stimme in einer Vielzahl von Methoden, aber erzielten Erfolg bis die 
Bestätigung der 19.änderung nicht zur VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Beschaffenheit 1920. Dieser verlängerte Kampf verwickelte 
weibliche Aktivisten in anderen wichtigen politischen und moralischen 
Ausgaben, die die Nation entlang rassischem teilten, ethnisch, und in 
Kategorie Zeilen, und Debatten über der Stimme für Frauen nahmen 
häufig einen teilenden Ton. Einige weiße Fraustimmrechtführer
waren bereit, die Kategorie, ethnisch und die rassischen Argumente zu 
verwenden, um den Kasten für bewilligende weiße Frauen zu polstern 
die Stimme. Schönheit Kearney, ein weißes Mississippi 
suffragist, das zu der 1903 NAWSA Versammlung sprach, angehoben der 
Erscheinung der schwarzen männlichen politischen Energie, für das 
enfranchisement der weißen Frauen zu argumentieren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La lutte pour le suffrage de femme a duré presque
un siècle, commençant par 1848 la convention des droits de la femme 
aux automnes de Seneca, New York, et incluant l'union 1890 de 
deux organismes de concurrence de suffrage pour former l'association 
américaine nationale de suffrage de femme (NAWSA). NAWSA et 
d'autres organismes ont fait campagne diligemment pour la voix par une
multitude de moyens, mais n'ont pas réalisé le succès jusqu'à la 
ratification du dix-neuvième amendement à la constitution des 
ETATS-UNIS en 1920. Cette lutte prolongée a empêtré les 
activistes féminins dans d'autres issues importantes qui ont divisé 
la nation le long de racial, ethnique, et lignes politiques et morales
de classe, et les discussions au-dessus de la voix pour des femmes ont
souvent pris une tonalité séparative. Quelques amorces 
blanches de suffrage de femmes étaient disposées à employer la 
classe, ethnique, et les arguments raciaux pour soutenir la caisse 
pour les femmes blanches d'octroi la voix. Belle Kearney, une 
suffragette blanche du Mississippi qui s'est adressée à la 
convention de 1903 NAWSA, élevée le spectre de la puissance 
politique mâle noire de plaider pour l'enfranchisement des femmes 
blanches.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O esforço para o suffrage da mulher durou quase 
um século, começando com a convenção 1848 da mulher em quedas do 
seneca, New York das direitas, e incluindo a união 1890 de duas 
organizações competindo do suffrage para dar forma à associação 
americana nacional do suffrage da mulher (NAWSA). NAWSA e outras
organizações fizeram campanha diligently para o voto em uma 
variedade das maneiras, mas não conseguiram o sucesso até o 
ratification da décima nona emenda ao constitution de ESTADOS UNIDOS 
em 1920. Este esforço prolongado entangled activistas fêmeas 
em outras edições importantes que dividiram a nação ao longo de 
racial, étnico, e linhas políticas e morais da classe, e os debates 
sobre o voto para mulheres fizeram exame frequentemente de um tom 
divisive. Alguns líderes brancos do suffrage das mulheres eram 
dispostos usar a classe, étnica, e argumentos raciais bolster a caixa
para mulheres brancas concedendo o voto. Belle Kearney, um 
suffragist branco de Mississippi que se dirigisse à convenção de 
1903 NAWSA, levantado o specter da potência política masculina preta
discutir para o enfranchisement das mulheres brancas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La lotta per suffrage della donna ha durato quasi 
un secolo, cominciante con la convenzione 1848 della donna alle cadute
del seneca, New York di diritti ed includente l'unione 1890 di due 
organizzazioni competenti di suffrage per formare l'associazione 
americana nazionale di suffrage della donna (NAWSA). NAWSA ed 
altre organizzazioni hanno fatto una campagna diligente per il voto in
una varietà di modi, ma non hanno realizzato il successo fino alla 
ratifica della diciannovesima correzione alla costituzione degli STATI
UNITI in 1920. Questa lotta prolungata ha impigliato gli 
attivisti femminili in altre edizioni importanti che hanno diviso 
la nazione lungo razziale, etnico e righe politiche e morali del 
codice categoria ed i dibattiti sopra il voto per le donne hanno preso
spesso un tono che divide. Alcuni capi bianchi di 
suffrage delle donne erano disposti ad usare il codice categoria, 
etnico e gli argomenti razziali per sostenere la cassa per le donne 
bianche d'assegnazione il voto. Belle Kearney, un suffragist 
bianco del Mississippi che ha parlato alla convenzione di 1903 NAWSA, 
alzato lo spettro di potenza politica maschio nera parlare a favore 
del enfranchisement delle donne bianche.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η προσπάθεια για την ψήφο γυναικών διάρκεσε σχεδόν 
έναν αιώνα, αρχίζοντας με τη 1848 Συνθήκη δικαιωμάτων της 
γυναίκας σε Σενέκα Falls, Νέα Υόρκη, και συμπεριλαμβανομένης 
της ένωσης 1890 δύο ανταγωνιστικών οργανώσεων ψήφου για να 
διαμορφώσει την εθνική αμερικανική ένωση ψήφου γυναικών 
(NAWSA). NAWSA και άλλες οργανώσεις έκαναν εκστρατεία
επιμελώς για την ψηφοφορία με ποικίλους τρόπους, αλλά δεν 
επέτυχαν την επιτυχία μέχρι την επικύρωση της δέκατης έννατης 
τροποποίησης στο ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΌ σύνταγμα το 1920. Αυτή η 
παρατεταμένη προσπάθεια έμπλεξε τα θηλυκά ενεργά στελέχη σε 
άλλα σημαντικά πολιτικά και ηθικά ζητήματα που διαίρεσαν το 
έθνος κατά μήκος φυλετικού, εθνικός, και οι γραμμές κλάσης, και
οι συζητήσεις πέρα από την ψηφοφορία για τις γυναίκες πήραν 
συχνά έναν διαχωριστικό τόνο. Μερικοί λευκοί ηγέτες 
ψήφου γυναικών ήταν πρόθυμοι να χρησιμοποιήσουν τα εθνικών, και 
φυλετικών ορίσματα κλάσης, να υποστηρίξουν την περίπτωση για στις
λευκές γυναίκες την ψηφοφορία. Το Belle Kearney, 
λευκός suffragist του Μισισιπή που απευθύνθηκε στη σύμβαση 
NAWSA του 1903, αύξησε το φάσμα της μαύρης αρσενικής 
πολιτικής δύναμης να υποστηρίξει το enfranchisement των λευκών 
γυναικών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La lucha para el sufragio de la mujer casi duró 
un siglo, comenzando con la convención 1848 de la mujer en las 
caídas del seneca, Nueva York de las derechas, e incluyendo la unión
1890 de dos organizaciones competentes del sufragio para formar la 
asociación americana nacional del sufragio de la mujer (NAWSA). 
NAWSA y otras organizaciones hicieron campaña diligente para el
voto en una variedad de maneras, pero no alcanzaron éxito hasta la 
ratificación de la diecinueveavo enmienda a la constitución de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS en 1920. Esta lucha prolongada enredó a 
activistas femeninos en otras ediciones importantes que dividieron la 
nación a lo largo de racial, étnico, y líneas políticas y morales 
de la clase, y los discusiones sobre el voto para las mujeres tomaron 
a menudo un tono divisivo. Algunos arranques de cinta blancos 
del sufragio de las mujeres estaban dispuestos a utilizar la clase, 
étnica, y argumentos raciales para alentar la caja para las mujeres 
blancas que concedían el voto. Belle Kearney, un suffragist 
blanco de Mississippi que se dirigió a la convención de 1903 NAWSA, 
levantado el espectro de la potencia política masculina negra de 
discutir para el enfranchisement de las mujeres blancas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086106</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103342</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/durable-white-supremacy-belle-kearney-puts-black-men-in-their-place</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
