<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107578</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107578</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086495</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Music Can Make You Feel Like You're Not Quite So Helpless:" Pete Seeger on People's Music</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Musik Kann Sie Gefühl Bilden, Wie Sie Sind Nicht 
Ziemlich So Hilflos:" Peter Seeger auf Musik der Leute</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La "Musique Peut vous faire La Sensation Comme 
Vous N'êtes pas Tout à fait Si Délaissé :" Peter Seeger sur 
la musique des personnes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A "Música Pode Fazer-lhe A Sensação Como Você 
Não é Completamente Assim Helpless:" Pete Seeger na música do
pessoa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"La Musica Può Rendervi Il Tatto Come Non siete 
Abbastanza Così Helpless:" Pete Seeger su musica della gente</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η μουσική μπορεί να σας κάνει να αισθανθείτε όπως 
σας δεν είναι αρκετά τόσο ανίσχυρη:" Pete Seeger στη 
μουσική των ανθρώπων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La "Música Puede Hacerle La Sensación Como Usted
No es Absolutamente Tan Desamparado:" Pete Seeger en la música 
de la gente</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Pete Seeger, folksinger, songwriter, and activist, provides a remarkable link between the radical culture of the 1930_s and the protest culture of the 1960_s. In 1940 Seeger met Woody Guthrie and the two formed the Almanac Singers, a leftist singing group that recorded pacifist and pro-union songs. After the war, Seeger formed the Weavers, a popular folk music group, but his successful career was hurt by Cold War red-baiting. While he lived and worked under siege for his political views during the 1950_s, Seeger had a large impact on the protest culture of the 1960_s, penning some of the era_s most important songs, including a variation on a spiritual that became the anthem "We Shall Overcome." In the 1970_s and 1980_s, Seeger focused on environmentalism, but he continued to appear at benefit concerts and rallies, and his musical legacy of protest singing continues to influence the way Americans speak out.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Peter Seeger, folksinger, songwriter und Aktivist, 
stellt ein bemerkenswertes Link zwischen der radikalen Kultur des 
1930_s und der Protestkultur des 1960_s zur Verfügung. getroffenes Seeger 1940 waldiges bildeten Guthrie und die zwei die 
Almanach-Sänger, eine linksgerichtete singende Gruppe, die pacifist und 
Pro-Anschluß Liede speicherte. Nach dem Krieg bildete Seeger 
die Weber, eine populäre Volksmusikgruppe, aber seine erfolgreiche 
Karriere wurde verletzt, indem man kalter Krieg rot-anlockte. 
Während er unter Belagerung für seine politischen Ansichten 
während des 1950_s lebte und arbeitete, hatte Seeger eine große 
Auswirkung auf die Protestkultur des 1960_s und sperrte einige der 
era_s die meisten wichtigen Liede, einschließlich eine Variante auf 
Angelegenheiten ein, die die Hymne wurden, ", das wir 
überwinden." Im 1970_s und im 1980_s konzentrierte Seeger auf 
Umweltbewegung, aber er fuhr fort, an den Wohltätigkeitskonzerten und
den Sammlungen zu erscheinen, und seine musikalische Legacy des 
Protestsingens fährt fort, die Methode zu beeinflussen, die 
Amerikaner heraus sprechen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Peter Seeger, folksinger, parolier, et 
activiste, fournit un lien remarquable entre la culture radicale du 
1930_s et la culture de protestation du 1960_s. En Seeger 1940 
rencontré Guthrie boisé et les deux ont formé les chanteurs 
d'almanach, un groupe chanteur de gauche qui a enregistré des 
chansons de pacifiste et de pro-union. Après la guerre, 
Seeger a formé les tisserands, un groupe populaire de musique 
folklorique, mais sa carrière réussie a été blessée par la 
rouge-amorce de guerre froide. Tandis qu'il vivait et 
travaillait sous le siège pour ses vues politiques pendant le 1950_s,
Seeger a eu un grand impact sur la culture de protestation du 1960_s, 
parquant certains des era_s la plupart des chansons importantes, y 
compris une variation sur un chant religieux qui est devenu le 
hymne "que nous surmonterons." Dans le 1970_s et le 
1980_s, Seeger s'est concentré sur l'environnementalisme, mais il a 
continué à apparaître aux concerts et aux rassemblements 
d'avantage, et son legs musical du chant de protestation continue à 
influencer la voie que les Américains parlent dehors.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Pete Seeger, folksinger, songwriter, e activista, 
fornece uma ligação notável entre a cultura radical do 1930_s e a 
cultura do protesto do 1960_s. Em Seeger 1940 encontrado com 
Guthrie woody e os dois deram forma aos singers do almanac, um grupo 
cantando leftist que gravasse canções do pacifist e da pro-união. 
Após a guerra, Seeger deu forma aos weavers, um grupo popular 
da música popular, mas sua carreira bem sucedida foi ferida 
vermelho-red-baiting da guerra fria. Quando viveu e trabalhou 
sob o siege para suas vistas políticas durante o 1950_s, Seeger teve 
um impacto grande na cultura do protesto do 1960_s, penning alguns dos
era_s a maioria de canções importantes, including uma variação em 
um espiritual que se transformasse o anthem "que nós superaremos." 
No 1970_s e no 1980_s, Seeger focalizou no environmentalism, mas
continuou a aparecer em concerts e em rallies de benefício, e seu 
legacy musical de cantar do protesto continua a influenciar a maneira 
que os americanos falam para fora.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Pete Seeger, folksinger, songwriter e attivista,
fornisce un collegamento notevole fra la coltura radicale del 1930_s e
la coltura di protesta del 1960_s. In Seeger 1940 venuto a 
contatto di Guthrie boscoso ed i due hanno formato i cantanti del 
almanac, un gruppo di canto di sinistra che ha registrato le canzoni 
dell'pro-unione e di pacifist. Dopo la guerra, Seeger ha formato
i tessitori, un gruppo popolare di musica di piega, ma la sua carriera
riuscita è stata danneggiata rosso-adescando di guerra fredda. 
Mentre ha vissuto e lavorato sotto il siege per i suoi punti di 
vista politici durante il 1950_s, Seeger ha avuto un grande effetto 
sulla coltura di protesta del 1960_s, rinchiudente alcuni dei era_s la
maggior parte delle canzoni importanti, compreso una variazione su uno
spiritual che si è transformato in nel anthem "che sormonteremo." 
Nel 1970_s e nel 1980_s, Seeger ha messo a fuoco su 
environmentalism, ma ha continuato a comparire ai concerti ed ai 
raduni di beneficio e la sua eredità musicale di canto di protesta 
continua ad influenzare il modo che gli Americani parlano fuori.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Pete Seeger, folksinger, τραγουδοποιός, και 
ενεργό στέλεχος, παρέχει μια αξιοπρόσεκτη σύνδεση μεταξύ του 
ριζικού πολιτισμού του 1930_s και του πολιτισμού διαμαρτυρίας 
του 1960_s. Το 1940 Seeger συνερχόμενο ξύλινο 
Guthrie και τα δύο διαμόρφωσαν τους τραγουδιστές ημερολογίων, 
μια αριστερή τραγουδώντας ομάδα που κατέγραψε τα ειρηνόφιλα
και τραγούδια υπέρ-ένωσης. Μετά από τον πόλεμο, Seeger 
διαμόρφωσε τους υφαντές, μια δημοφιλής λαϊκή ομάδα μουσικής, 
αλλά η επιτυχής σταδιοδρομία του βλάφθηκε με να 
κόκκινος-δελεάσει ψυχρού πολέμου. Ενώ έζησε και εργάστηκε
κάτω από την πολιορκία για τις πολιτικές όψεις του κατά τη 
διάρκεια του 1950_s, Seeger άσκησε μεγάλη επίδραση στον 
πολιτισμό διαμαρτυρίας του 1960_s, περιφράζοντας μερικών από 
το era_s τα περισσότερα σημαντικά τραγούδια, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένης μιας παραλλαγής σε ένα σπιρίτσουαλ που έγινε 
ο ύμνος "που θα υπερνικήσουμε." Στο 1970_s και το 
1980_s, Seeger εστίασε στο environmentalism, αλλά συνέχισε
να εμφανίζεται στις συναυλίες οφελών και τις συναθροίσεις, και η 
μουσική κληρονομιά του τραγουδιού διαμαρτυρίας συνεχίζει να 
επηρεάζει τον τρόπο που Αμερικανοί μιλούν έξω.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Pete Seeger, folksinger, compositor, y activista, 
proporciona a una conexión notable entre la cultura radical del 
1930_s y la cultura de la protesta del 1960_s. En Seeger 1940 
resuelto Guthrie arbolado y los dos formaron a cantantes del almanac, 
grupo cantante izquierdista que registró canciones del pacifist y de 
la favorable-unio'n. Después de la guerra, Seeger formó a 
tejedores, grupo popular de la música tradicional, pero su carrera 
acertada fue lastimada rojo-hostigando de la guerra fría. 
Mientras que él vivió y trabajó bajo sitio para sus opiniones
políticas durante el 1950_s, Seeger tenía un impacto grande en la 
cultura de la protesta del 1960_s, encerrando algunos de los era_s la 
mayoría de las canciones importantes, incluyendo una variación en un
espiritual que se convirtió en el himno "que superaremos." En 
el 1970_s y el 1980_s, Seeger se centró en environmentalism, pero él
continuó apareciendo en los conciertos y las reuniones de ventaja, y 
su herencia musical de cantar de la protesta continúa influenciando 
la manera que los americanos hablan hacia fuera.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086495</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107578</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/music-can-make-you-feel-like-youre-not-quite-so-helpless-pete-seeger-on-peoples-music</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
