<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107102</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107102</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211240</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">National Association of Geoscience Teachers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nationale Verbindung der Geoscience Lehrer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Association nationale des professeurs de 
Geoscience</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Associação nacional de professores de 
Geoscience</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Associazione nazionale degli insegnanti di 
Geoscience</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εθνική ένωση των δασκάλων Geoscience</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Asociación nacional de los profesores de 
Geoscience</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The National Association of Geoscience Teachers (NAGT) was established in 1938. Its purpose is to foster improvement in the teaching of earth sciences at all levels of formal and informal instruction, to emphasize the cultural significance of the earth sciences and to disseminate knowledge in this field to the general public. NAGT organizes the technical program in geoscience education at every GSA Annual Meeting, and in this context also sponsors numerous technical sessions, workshops, and field trips. The organization also fosters advances in the teaching and learning of geoscience by means of scholarship aid to summer field-camp students, professional workshops for geoscience faculty, its Distinguished Speaker Series, and the Journal of Geoscience Education and through its partnership with the National Association for Black Geologists and Geophysicists. The NAGT website contains links to membership information, award and scholarship opportunities, featured links, teacher resources and organizational announcements. Users can also access the NAGT publication, Journal of Geoscience Education and companion websites for several Physical Geology laboratory manuals.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die nationale Verbindung der Geoscience Lehrer 
(NAGT) wurde 1938 hergestellt. Sein Zweck ist, Verbesserung im 
Unterricht der Geowissenschaften auf allen Stufen von formalem zu 
fördern und formlose Anweisung, die kulturelle Stichhaltigkeit der 
Geowissenschaften hervorzuheben und Wissen diesbezüglich zu 
verbreiten fangen zur Öffentlichkeit auf. NAGT 
organisiert das technische Programm in der geoscience Ausbildung bei 
jeder GSA jährlichen Sitzung, und in diesem Kontext fördert auch 
zahlreiche technische Sitzungen, Werkstätten und fängt 
Reisen auf. Die Organisation fördert auch Fortschritte im 
Unterricht und im Lernen von geoscience mittels des 
Gelehrsamkeithilfsmittels zu den Kursteilnehmern des Sommers 
fangene-camp, zu den professionellen Werkstätten für geoscience 
Lehrkörper, zu seiner bemerkenswerten Lautsprecher-Serie und zum 
Journal der Geoscience Ausbildung und durch seine Teilhaberschaft mit 
der nationalen Verbindung für schwarze Geologen und Geophysicists. 
Die NAGT Web site enthält Links Mitgliedschaft Informationen, 
Preis- und Gelehrsamkeitzu den gelegenheiten, zu gekennzeichneten 
Links, zu den Lehrerbetriebsmitteln und zu den organisatorischen 
Ansagen. Benutzer können die NAGT Publikation, Journal der 
Geoscience Ausbildung und auf Begleiterweb site für einige 
Geologielaborhandbücher auch zugreifen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'association nationale des professeurs de 
Geoscience (NAGT) a été établie en 1938. Son but est de 
stimuler l'amélioration de l'enseignement des sciences de la terre à
tous les niveaux de l'instruction formelle et sans cérémonie, de 
souligner la signification culturelle des sciences de la terre et de 
diffuser la connaissance dans ce domaine au grand public. NAGT 
organise le programme technique dans l'éducation de geoscience lors 
de chaque réunion annuelle de GSA, et dans ce contexte commandite 
également de nombreuses sessions techniques, ateliers, et voyages de 
zone. L'organisation stimule également des avances dans 
l'enseignement et l'étude du geoscience au moyen d'aide de bourse aux
étudiants de zone-camp d'été, aux ateliers professionnels pour le 
corps enseignant de geoscience, à ses séries distinguées de 
haut-parleur, et au journal de l'éducation de Geoscience et par son 
association avec l'association nationale pour les géologues et les 
Géophysiciens noirs. Le site Web de NAGT contient des liens aux 
occasions de l'information, de récompense et de bourse d'adhésion, 
aux liens décrits, aux ressources de professeur et aux annonces 
d'organisation. Les utilisateurs peuvent également accéder à 
la publication de NAGT, au journal de l'éducation de Geoscience et 
aux sites Web de compagnon pour plusieurs manuels de laboratoire de 
géologie physique.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A associação nacional dos professores de 
Geoscience (NAGT) foi estabelecida em 1938. Sua finalidade é 
promover a melhoria no ensino de ciências de terra em todos os 
níveis da instrução formal e informal, para emfatizar o significado
cultural das ciências de terra e para disseminate o conhecimento 
neste campo ao público geral. NAGT organiza o programa técnico
na instrução do geoscience em cada reunião anual de GSA, e neste 
contexto patrocina também sessões técnicas numerosas, oficinas, e 
desengates de campo. A organização promove também avanços no
ensino e na aprendizagem do geoscience por meio do dae (dispositivo 
automático de entrada) do scholarship aos estudantes do 
campo-acampamento do verão, às oficinas profissionais para a 
faculdade do geoscience, a sua distinta série do altofalante, e ao 
jornal da instrução de Geoscience e com sua parceria com a 
associação nacional para geólogos pretos e Geophysicists. O 
Web site de NAGT contem as ligações às oportunidades da 
informação, da concessão e do scholarship da sociedade, às 
ligações caracterizadas, aos recursos do professor e aos anúncios 
organizational. Os usuários podem também alcançar a 
publicação de NAGT, o jornal da instrução de Geoscience e os Web 
site do companheiro para diversos manuais de laboratório da geologia 
física.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'associazione nazionale degli insegnanti di 
Geoscience (NAGT) è stata stabilita in 1938. Il relativo scopo 
è promuovere il miglioramento nell'insegnamento delle scienze della 
terra a tutti i livelli di istruzione convenzionale ed informale, per 
dare risalto all'importanza culturale delle scienze della terra e per 
diffondere la conoscenza in questo campo al grande pubblico. 
NAGT organizza il programma tecnico nella formazione di 
geoscience ad ogni riunione annuale di GSA ed in questo contesto 
egualmente patrocina le sessioni tecniche numerose, i seminari ed i 
viaggi di campo. L'organizzazione egualmente promuove gli 
avanzamenti nell'insegnamento e nell'imparare del geoscience per mezzo
di sussidio di borsa agli allievi dell'campo-accampamento di estate, 
ai workshop professionali per la facoltà di geoscience, alla relativa
serie distinta dell'altoparlante ed al giornale di formazione di 
Geoscience e con la relativa associazione con l'associazione nazionale
per i geologi neri e Geophysicists. Il Web site di NAGT contiene
i collegamenti alle occasioni delle informazioni, del premio e di 
borsa di insieme dei membri, ai collegamenti descritti, alle risorse 
dell'insegnante ed agli annunci organizzativi. Gli utenti 
possono anche accedere alla pubblicazione di NAGT, al giornale di 
formazione di Geoscience ed ai Web site del compagno per parecchi 
manuali di laboratorio di geologia fisica.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η εθνική ένωση των δασκάλων Geoscience (NAGT) 
καθιερώθηκε σε 1938, Ο σκοπός του είναι να ενθαρρύνει τη 
βελτίωση στη διδασκαλία των γήινων επιστημών σε όλα τα επίπεδα 
επίσημης και άτυπης οδηγίας, να υπογραμμίσει την πολιτιστική 
σημασία των γήινων επιστημών και να διαδώσει τη γνώση σε αυτό το
πεδίο στο ευρύ κοινό. NAGT οργανώνει το τεχνικό 
πρόγραμμα στην εκπαίδευση geoscience σε κάθε ετήσια συνεδρίαση
GSA, και σε αυτό το πλαίσιο υποστηρίζει επίσης τις πολυάριθμα 
τεχνικά περιόδους επικοινωνίας, τα εργαστήρια, και τα ταξίδια 
πεδίων. Η οργάνωση ενθαρρύνει επίσης τις προόδους στη 
διδασκαλία και την εκμάθηση του geoscience με τη βοήθεια της 
ενίσχυσης υποτροφιών στους σπουδαστές θερινών πεδίο-στρατόπεδων,
τα επαγγελματικά εργαστήρια για τη σχολή geoscience, τη 
διακεκριμένη σειρά ομιλητών της, και το περιοδικό της εκπαίδευσης
Geoscience και μέσω της συνεργασίας της με την εθνική ένωση για
τους μαύρους γεωλόγους και τους γεωφυσικούς. Ο ιστοχώρος 
NAGT περιέχει τις συνδέσεις με τις πληροφορίες ιδιότητας 
μέλους, βραβείο και οι ευκαιρίες υποτροφιών, χαρακτήρισαν τις 
συνδέσεις, τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς δασκάλων και τις οργανωτικές 
ανακοινώσεις. Οι χρήστες μπορούν επίσης να έχουν πρόσβαση 
στη δημοσίευση NAGT, το περιοδικό της εκπαίδευσης Geoscience 
και τους ιστοχώρους συντρόφων για διάφορα φυσικά εργαστηριακά 
εγχειρίδια γεωλογίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La asociación nacional de los profesores de 
Geoscience (NAGT) fue establecida en 1938. Su propósito es 
fomentar la mejora en la enseñanza de las geologías en todos los 
niveles de la instrucción formal e informal, de acentuar la 
significación cultural de las geologías y de diseminar conocimiento 
en este campo entre el público en general. NAGT ordena el 
programa técnico en la educación del geoscience en cada reunión 
anual de GSA, y en este contexto también patrocina sesiones técnicas
numerosas, talleres, y disparos al campo. La organización 
también fomenta avances en la enseñanza y aprender del geoscience 
por medio de ayuda de la beca a los estudiantes del campo-campo del 
verano, a los talleres profesionales para la facultad del geoscience, 
a su serie distinguida del altavoz, y al diario de la educación de 
Geoscience y con su sociedad con la asociación nacional para los 
geólogos negros y Geophysicists. El Web site de NAGT contiene 
conexiones a las oportunidades de la información, de la concesión y 
de la beca de la calidad de miembro, a las conexiones ofrecidas, a los
recursos del profesor y a los avisos de organización. Los 
utilizadores pueden también tener acceso a la publicación de NAGT, 
al diario de la educación de Geoscience y a los Web site del 
compañero para varios manuales de laboratorio de la geología 
física.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211240</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107102</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/national-association-of-geoscience-teachers</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
