<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108575</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108575</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200668</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Biological Soil Crusts</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Biologische Boden-Krusten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Croûtes Biologiques de Sol</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Crostas Biológicas Do Solo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Croste Biologiche Del Terreno</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βιολογικές εδαφολογικές κρούστες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cortezas Biológicas Del Suelo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This USGS Canyonlands Research Station site features a series of web pages focusing on biological soil crusts. Biological soil crusts are the community of organisms living at the surface of desert soils. Major components are cyanobacteria, green algae, microfungi, mosses, liverworts, and lichens. The site provides a menu of links to biological soil crust pages including Crusts 101: an introduction to biological soil crusts, an advanced page with a downloadable 90-page report on soil crusts, a gallery of biological soil crust images and figures, references, the Canyon Country Ecosystems Research Site (CCERS), and other related links. Links to the U.S. Bureau of Land Management, USGS, and the National Park Service are also provided.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses USGS Canyonlands 
Forschungsstation-Situationsmerkmale, die eine Reihe Webseiten, die 
auf biologischen Boden konzentrieren, verkrustet. Biologische 
Bodenkrusten sind die Gemeinschaft der organismen lebend an der 
Oberfläche der Wüstenböden. Hauptbestandteile sind 
cyanobacteria, grüne Algen, Mikropilze, Moose, liverworts und 
Flechten. Die Site stellt ein Menü der Links zu den 
biologischen Bodenkrusteseiten einschließlich Krusten 101 zur 
Verfügung: eine Einleitung in biologische Bodenkrusten, eine 
hochentwickelte Seite mit einem downloadable Report 90-page über 
Bodenkrusten, eine Galerie der biologischen Bodenkrustebilder und eine
Abbildungen, Referenzen, die Schlucht-Land-Oekosysteme erforschen Site
(CCERS) und andere in Verbindung stehende Links. Links zum 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Büro des Land-Managements, des USGS und des 
Nationalpark-Services werden auch zur Verfügung gestellt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dispositifs de ce d'USGS Canyonlands de recherches
site de centre que une série de pages Web se concentrant sur le sol
biologique se couvre d'une croûte. Les croûtes biologiques de 
sol sont la communauté des organizations vivant sur la surface des 
sols de désert. Les composants principaux sont cyanobacteria, 
algues vertes, micro-fongus, mousses, liverworts, et lichens. Le
site fournit un menu des liens aux pages biologiques de croûte de sol
comprenant les croûtes 101 : une introduction aux croûtes 
biologiques de sol, à une page avançée avec un état 90-page 
downloadable sur des croûtes de sol, à une galerie des images 
biologiques de croûte de sol et aux figures, références, les 
écosystèmes de pays de gorge recherchent le site (CCERS), et 
d'autres liens relatifs. Des liens au bureau des ETATS-UNIS de 
la gestion de terre, de l'USGS, et du service de parc national sont 
également fournis.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Características que deste local da estação de 
pesquisa de USGS Canyonlands uma série dos Web pages que focalizam no
solo biológico crusts. As crostas biológicas do solo são a 
comunidade dos organismos que vive na superfície de solos de deserto.
Os componentes principais são cyanobacteria, algas verdes, 
microfungi, musgos, liverworts, e lichens. O local fornece um 
menu das ligações às páginas biológicas da crosta do solo 
including as crostas 101: uma introdução às crostas 
biológicas do solo, a uma página avançada com um relatório 90-page
downloadable em crostas do solo, a uma galeria de imagens biológicas 
da crosta do solo e às figuras, referências, os ecosystems do país 
da garganta pesquisa o local (CCERS), e outras ligações 
relacionadas. As ligações ao departamento de ESTADOS UNIDOS da
gerência da terra, do USGS, e do serviço do parque nacional são 
fornecidas também.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Caratteristiche che di questo di USGS Canyonlands 
di ricerca luogo della stazione una serie di Web pagi che mettono a 
fuoco sul terreno biologico crusts. Le croste biologiche del 
terreno sono la Comunità degli organismi che vive alla superficie dei
terreni di deserto. I componenti importanti sono cyanobacteria, 
alghe verdi, microfunghi, muschi, liverworts e licheni. Il luogo
fornisce un menu dei collegamenti alle pagine biologiche della crosta 
del terreno compreso le croste 101: un'introduzione alle croste 
biologiche del terreno, ad una pagina avanzata con un rapporto 
downloadable 90-page sulle croste del terreno, ad una galleria delle 
immagini biologiche della crosta del terreno ed alle figure, 
riferimenti, gli ecosistemi del paese del canyon ricerca il luogo 
(CCERS) ed altri collegamenti relativi. I collegamenti 
all'ufficio degli STATI UNITI della gestione della terra, di USGS e 
del servizio del parco nazionale egualmente sono forniti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή ερευνητικών USGS Canyonlands 
σταθμών χαρακτηρίζει μια σειρά ιστοσελίδας που εστιάζουν στις 
βιολογικές εδαφολογικές κρούστες. Οι βιολογικές 
εδαφολογικές κρούστες είναι η κοινότητα των οργανισμών που ζει 
στην επιφάνεια των χωμάτων ερήμων. Σημαντικά συστατικά 
είναι cyanobacteria, πράσινα άλγη, microfungi, βρύα, 
liverworts, και λειχήνες. Η περιοχή παρέχει έναν 
κατάλογο επιλογής των συνδέσεων με τις βιολογικές σελίδες 
εδαφολογικών κρουστών συμπεριλαμβανομένων των κρουστών 101: 
μια εισαγωγή στις βιολογικές εδαφολογικές κρούστες, μια 
προηγμένη σελίδα με μια τηλεκατεγραφόμενη έκθεση 90-σελίδων 
σχετικά με τις εδαφολογικές κρούστες, μια στοά των βιολογικών 
εικόνων και των αριθμών εδαφολογικών κρουστών, των αναφορών, της 
περιοχής οικοσυστημάτων χώρας φαραγγιών ερευνητικής (CCERS), 
και άλλων σχετικών συνδέσεων. Οι συνδέσεις με το ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ
γραφείο της διαχείρισης εδάφους, USGS, και της εθνικής 
υπηρεσίας πάρκων παρέχονται επίσης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Características de este de USGS Canyonlands de 
investigación sitio del centro que una serie de Web pages que se 
centran en suelo biológico forma una costra. Las cortezas 
biológicas del suelo son la comunidad de organismos que vive en la 
superficie de los suelos de desierto. Los componentes 
importantes son cyanobacteria, algas verdes, microhongos, musgos, 
liverworts, y liquenes. El sitio proporciona a un menú de 
conexiones a las paginaciones biológicas de la corteza del suelo 
incluyendo las cortezas 101: una introducción a cortezas 
biológicas del suelo, a una paginación avanzada con un informe 
downloadable 90-page sobre las cortezas del suelo, a una galería de 
las imágenes biológicas de la corteza del suelo y a las figuras, 
referencias, los ecosistemas del país de la barranca investiga el 
sitio (CCERS), y otras conexiones relacionadas. Las conexiones a
la oficina de ESTADOS UNIDOS de la gerencia de la pista, de USGS, y 
del servicio del parque nacional también se proporcionan.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:USGS CANYONLANDS RESEARCH STATION
FN:USGS CANYONLANDS RESEARCH STATION
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:USGS
FN:USGS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200668</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108575</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/biological-soil-crusts</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
