<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105661</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105661</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086984</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The "Man in the Street" Reacts to Pearl Harbor</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der "Durchschnittsmensch" reagiert zum Pearl 
Harbor</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'"homme de la rue" réagit au port de perle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O "homem na rua" reage ao porto de pérola</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"l'uomo qualunque" reagisce al porto di perla</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το "άτομο στην οδό" αντιδρά στο λιμάνι μαργαριταριών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El "hombre medio" reacciona al puerto de perla</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Japanese attack on Pearl Harbor, Hawaii, on December 7, 1941, stunned virtually everyone in the United States military. Japan's carrier-launched bombers found Pearl Harbor totally unprepared. President Franklin Roosevelt quickly addressed Congress to ask for a declaration of war. In the wake of the attack and Roosevelt's speech, folklorists employed by the Library of Congress rushed out to the streets of Washington, D. C., to record public reaction. The selection of "man on the street" interviews showed a wide range of public responses to the attack and to FDR's speech. Young servicemen seemed most concerned about canceled furloughs, while a Polish immigrant swore his undying loyalty to the United States. African Americans in a poolhall insisted on their people's contribution to American history.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der japanische Angriff auf Pearl Harbor, Hawaii, 
an Dezember 7, 1941, betäubt praktisch jeder im Vereinigte Staaten 
Militär. Japans Fördermaschine-ausgestoßene Bomber fanden 
Pearl Harbor total unvorbereitet. Präsident Franklin Roosevelt 
sprach schnell zu Kongreß, um um eine Erklärung des Krieges zu 
bitten. Unmittelbar nach dem Angriff und Rede Roosevelts hetzten
die Folkloristen, die durch die Bibliothek des Kongresses beschäftigt
wurden, heraus zu den Straßen von Washington, D. C., um allgemeine 
Reaktion zu speichern. Die Auswahl "Mann auf der Straße" der 
Interviews zeigte eine breite Strecke der allgemeinen Antworten zum 
Angriff und zur Rede FDR. Junge Soldaten schienen über 
beendete zeitweilige Entlassungen am beteiligtesten, während ein 
polnischer Immigrant seine undying Loyalität in die Vereinigten 
Staaten schwur. Afrikanische Amerikaner in einem poolhall 
bestanden auf Beitrag ihrer Leute zur amerikanischen Geschichte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'attaque japonaise sur le port de perle, Hawaï, 
7 décembre 1941, assommé pratiquement chacun dans les militaires 
des Etats-Unis. Les bombardiers porteur-lancés du Japon ont 
trouvé le port de perle totalement non préparé. Le Président
Franklin Roosevelt s'est rapidement adressé au congrès pour demander
une déclaration de guerre. À la suite de l'attaque et de la 
parole de Roosevelt, les folkloristes employés par la bibliothèque 
du congrès se sont précipités dehors aux rues de Washington, D. C.,
pour enregistrer la réaction publique. La sélection "homme des
entrevues sur rue" a montré un éventail de réponses publiques à 
l'attaque et à la parole du FDR. Les jeunes soldats ont semblé
les plus intéressés sur des congé annulés, alors qu'un immigré 
polonais jurait son fidélité impérissable aux Etats-Unis. Les
Américains africains dans un poolhall ont insisté pour la 
contribution de leurs personnes à l'histoire américaine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O ataque japonês no porto de pérola, Havaí, 
dezembro em 7, 1941, stunned virtualmente todos nos estados unidos 
militares. Os bombardeiros portador-lançados de Japão 
encontraram o porto de pérola totalmente unprepared. O 
presidente Franklin Roosevelt dirigiu-se rapidamente ao congress para 
pedir uma declaração da guerra. Na vigília do ataque e do 
discurso de Roosevelt, os folklorists empregados pela biblioteca do 
congress apressaram-se para fora às ruas de Washington, D. C., para 
gravar a reação pública. A seleção "homem de entrevistas na
rua" mostrou uma escala larga de respostas públicas ao ataque e ao 
discurso do FDR. Os recrutas novos pareceram os mais 
interessados sobre furloughs cancelados, quando um immigrant polonês 
jurou sua lealdade undying aos estados unidos. Os americanos 
africanos em um poolhall insistiram na contribuição do seu pessoa ao
history americano.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'attacco giapponese al porto di perla, Hawai, il 
7 dicembre 1941, stordito virtualmente tutto in unito Dichiara 
i militari. I bombardieri elemento-lanciati del Giappone hanno 
trovato il porto di perla completamente non preparato. Il 
presidente Franklin Roosevelt ha parlato rapidamente al congresso per 
chiedere una dichiarazione della guerra. Come conseguenza 
dell'attacco e del discorso del Roosevelt, i folklorists impiegati 
dalla libreria del congresso hanno scorso veloce fuori alle vie di 
Washington, il D. C., per registrare la reazione del pubblico. 
La selezione "uomo delle interviste sulla via" ha mostrato una 
vasta gamma degli atteggiamenti dell'opinione pubblica all'attacco ed 
a discorso del FDR. I tecnici di manutenzione giovani hanno 
sembrato più interessati circa i furloughs annullati, mentre un 
immigrante polacco ha giurato che la sua lealtà undying al unito 
Dichiara. Gli Americani africani in un poolhall hanno 
insistito sul contributo della loro gente a storia americana.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ιαπωνική επίθεση στο λιμάνι μαργαριταριών, Χαβάη, 
στις 7 Δεκεμβρίου ..1941, ζάλισε ουσιαστικά ο στις Ηνωμένες 
Πολιτείες στρατιωτικές. Τα μεταφορέας-προωθημένα 
βομβαρδιστικά αεροπλάνα της Ιαπωνίας βρήκαν το λιμάνι 
μαργαριταριών συνολικά απροετοίμαστο. Ο Πρόεδρος Franklin
Roosevelt εξέτασε γρήγορα το συνέδριο που ρωτά για μια δήλωση 
του πολέμου. Αμέσως μετά την επίθεση και την ομιλία 
Roosevelt, folklorists που απασχολήθηκαν από τη βιβλιοθήκη 
του συνεδρίου όρμηξαν έξω στις οδούς της Ουάσιγκτον, Δ. Γ., για 
να καταγράψουν τη δημόσια αντίδραση. Η επιλογή "του ατόμου 
στην οδό" συνεντεύξεις εμφάνισε ευρύ φάσμα των δημόσιων 
απαντήσεων στην επίθεση και στην ομιλία FDR. Νέα 
servicemen φάνηκαν τα πιό ενδιαφερόμενοτα για ακυρωμένος 
furloughs, ενώ ένας πολωνικός μετανάστης ορκίζομαι την 
αθάνατη πίστη του στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες. Αφρικανικοί 
Αμερικανοί σε ένα poolhall επέμειναν στη συμβολή των ανθρώπων 
τους στην αμερικανική ιστορία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El ataque japonés contra el puerto de perla, 
Hawaii, 7 de diciembre de 1941, atontado virtualmente cada uno en 
los militares de Estados Unidos. Los bombarderos 
portador-lanzados de Japón encontraron el puerto de perla totalmente 
sin preparación. Presidente Franklin Roosevelt se dirigió 
rápidamente al congreso para pedir un declaración de la guerra. 
En la estela del ataque y del discurso de Roosevelt, los 
folklorists empleados por la biblioteca del congreso acometieron hacia
fuera a las calles de Washington, D. C., para registrar la reacción 
pública. La selección "hombre en de las entrevistas de la 
calle" mostró una amplia gama de respuestas públicas al ataque y al 
discurso del FDR. Los mecánicos jóvenes se parecían los más 
en cuestión sobre furloughs cancelados, mientras que un inmigrante 
polaco juró su lealtad undying a los Estados Unidos. Los 
americanos africanos en un poolhall insistieron en la contribución de
su gente a la historia americana.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086984</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105661</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-man-in-the-street-reacts-to-pearl-harbor</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
