<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107092</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107092</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086293</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Seen My Opportunities and I Took 'Em.": An Old-Time Pol Preaches Honest Graft</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"I, das meinen Gelegenheiten gesehen wurden und ich
nahmen ' EM.": Eine Alt-Zeit Pol Predigt Ehrliche 
Transplantation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"I vu mes occasions et moi avons pris la 'fin de 
support." : Un Pôle D'autrefois Prêche La Greffe Honnête</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"I visto minhas oportunidades e eu fizemos exame ' 
do Em.": Um Velho-Tempo Pol Preaches O Graft Honesto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la I vista le mie occasioni ed io hanno preso 'il 
Em.": Un Vecchio-Tempo Pol Predica L'Innesto Onesto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ι Που εβλέίδε Em τις ευκαιρίες μου και 
πήρα".": Ένα αλλοτινό POL κηρύσσει το τίμιο εμβόλιο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"I considerado mis oportunidades y yo tomamos el ' 
Em.": Un Viejo-Tiempo Pol Predica El Injerto Honesto</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">One of the famous, albeit not the most important of the old-time political bosses, was George Washington Plunkitt. Although he was well known in New York City political circles in the late-nineteenth and early-twentieth centuries, his enduring fame came from a very short book with a very long subtitle:  Plunkitt of Tammany Hall: A Series of Very Plain Talks on Very Practical Politics, Delivered by Ex-Senator George Washington Plunkitt, the Tammany Philosopher, from his Rostrum--the New York County Courthouse Bootblack Stand . Journalist William Riordan listened to Plunkitt's talks and published them as interviews in various local newspapers. In 1905, he published them in a book, which became a classic on American urban politics, one still widely read today. Amidst political cynicism, Plunkitt also preached the virtues of hard work, sobriety, and even (as in this talk on "honest graft") honesty.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eins vom berühmten, obwohl nicht von den 
wichtigsten der Altzeit politischen Chefs, war George Washington 
Plunkitt. Obgleich er New York City in den politischen Kreisen 
in den spät-19. und früh-zwanzigsten Jahrhunderten weithin bekannt 
war, kam sein aushaltener Ruhm von einem sehr kurzen Buch mit einem 
sehr langen Untertitel: Plunkitt von Tammany Hall: 
Eine Reihe sehr normale Gespräche auf sehr praktischen 
Politiken, geliefert vom Ex-Senator George Washington Plunkitt, dem 
Tammany Philosophen, von seinem Rostrum -- der New York 
Grafschaft-Gericht Bootblack Standplatz. Journalist William 
Riordan hörte zu den Gesprächen Plunkitts und ihnen als Interviews 
in den verschiedenen lokalen Zeitungen veröffentlicht. 1905 
veröffentlichte er sie in einem Buch, das ein Klassiker auf 
amerikanischer städtischer Politik wurde, eine Stille, die weit heute
gelesen wurde. Unter politischem Zynismus predigte Plunkitt auch
die Tugenden der harten Arbeit, der Nüchternheit und der sogar (wie 
in diesem Gespräch auf "ehrlicher Transplantation") Ehrlichkeit.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un du célèbre, quoique pas des plus importante 
des patrons politiques d'autrefois, était George Washington 
Plunkitt. Bien qu'il ait été bien connu en cercles politiques 
de New York City aux tard-dix-neuvième et tôt-vingtième siècles, 
sa renommée durable est venue d'un livre très court avec un 
sous-titre très long : Plunkitt de Tammany hall : Une 
série d'entretiens très ordinaires sur la politique très pratique, 
fournie par Ex-Sénateur George Washington Plunkitt, le philosophe
de Tammany, de son rostrum -- le stand de Bootblack de tribunal du 
comté de New York. Le journaliste William Riordan a écouté 
les entretiens de Plunkitt et édité leur en tant qu'entrevues dans 
divers journaux locaux. En 1905, il les a édités dans un 
livre, qui est devenu un classique sur la politique urbaine 
américaine, un distillateur largement lu aujourd'hui. Parmi le 
cynisme politique, Plunkitt a également prêché les vertus du 
travail dur, de la sobriété, et même (comme dans cet entretien sur 
"la greffe honnête") de l'honnêteté.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um do famoso, albeit não do mais importante das 
saliências políticas do velho-tempo, era George Washington Plunkitt.
Embora fosse conhecido bem em círculos políticos de New York 
City nos tarde-décimos nonos e cedo-vigésimos séculos, sua fama 
resistindo veio de um livro muito curto com um subtítulo muito longo:
Plunkitt de Tammany salão: Uma série de conversas muito 
lisas na política muito prática, entregada pelo Ex-ex-Senator George
Washington Plunkitt, no filósofo de Tammany, de seu rostrum -- o 
carrinho de Bootblack do tribunal do condado de New York. O 
journalist William Riordan escutou conversas de Plunkitt e publicado 
lhes como entrevistas em vários jornais locais. Em 1905, 
publicou-os em um livro, que se transformasse um clássico na 
política urbana americana, um destilador lido extensamente hoje. 
Entre o cynicism político, Plunkitt preached também os virtues
do trabalho duro, do sobriety, e mesmo (como nesta conversa "no graft 
honesto") do honesty.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Uno del famoso, anche se non degli la più 
importanti delle sporgenze politiche di vecchio-tempo, era George 
Washington Plunkitt. Anche se era ben noto nei cerchi politici 
de New York City nei in ritardo-diciannovesimi e presto-ventesimi 
secoli, la sua fama duratura è venuto da un libro molto corto con un 
sottotitolo molto lungo: Plunkitt di Tammany corridoio: 
Una serie di Colloqui molto normali sulle politiche molto 
pratiche, trasportata dal Ex-Senatore George Washington Plunkitt, sul 
filosofo di Tammany, dal suo rostrum -- il basamento di Bootblack del 
courthouse della contea de New York. Il giornalista William 
Riordan ha ascoltato i colloqui del Plunkitt e pubblicato loro come
interviste in vari giornali locali. In 1905, li ha pubblicati in
un libro, che si è transformato in in un classico sulla politica 
urbana americana, un alambicco ampiamente colto oggi. In mezzo 
di cynicism politico, Plunkitt egualmente ha predicato le virtù di 
lavoro duro, di sobriety e perfino (come in questo colloquio 
"sull'innesto onesto") dell'onestà.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένας από το διάσημο, αν και όχι ο σημαντικότερος των 
αλλοτινών πολιτικών προϊσταμένων, ήταν George Ουάσιγκτον 
Plunkitt. Αν και ήταν γνωστός καλά στους πολιτικούς 
κύκλους πόλεων της Νέας Υόρκης στους πρόσφατος-δέκατους 
έννατους και πρόωρος-εικοστούς αιώνες, η υπομένοντας φήμη του 
προήλθε από ένα πολύ κοντό βιβλίο με έναν πολύ μακρύ 
υπότιτλο: Plunkitt της αίθουσας Tammany: Μια 
σειρά πολύ σαφών συζητήσεων στην πολύ πολιτική, που παραδίδεται
πρακτική από Ex-Senator George Ουάσιγκτον Plunkitt, το 
φιλόσοφο Tammany, από το Rostrum του -- η στάση Bootblack 
δικαστηρίων νομών της Νέας Υόρκης. Ο δημοσιογράφος 
William Riordan άκουσε τις συζητήσεις Plunkitt και τις 
δημοσίευσε ως συνεντεύξεις στις διάφορες τοπικές εφημερίδες. 
Το 1905, τους δημοσίευσε σε ένα βιβλίο, που έγινε ένας 
κλασικός στην αμερικανική αστική πολιτική, μια ακόμα ευρέως που 
διαβάστηκε σήμερα. Στη μέση του πολιτικού κυνισμού, 
Plunkitt κήρυξε επίσης τις αρετές της σκληρής εργασίας, 
ηρεμία, και ακόμα και (όπως σε αυτήν την συζήτηση στο "τίμιο 
εμβόλιο") τιμιότητα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Uno del famoso, no obstante no del más importante 
de los jefes políticos del viejo-tiempo, era George Washington 
Plunkitt. Aunque él era bien sabido en los círculos políticos
de New York City en los tarde-diecinueveavo y temprano-vige'simos 
siglos, su fama que aguantaba vino de un libro muy corto con un 
subtítulo muy largo: Plunkitt de Tammany pasillo: Una 
serie de negociaciones muy llanas sobre las políticas muy prácticas,
entregada por Ex-Senador George Washington Plunkitt, el filósofo de 
Tammany, de su rostrum -- el soporte de Bootblack del palacio de 
justicia del condado de Nueva York. El periodista Guillermo 
Riordan escuchó las negociaciones de Plunkitt y publicado les como 
entrevistas en varios periódicos locales. En 1905, él los 
publicó en un libro, que se convirtió en una obra clásica en 
política urbana americana, un alambique leído extensamente hoy. 
En medio de cinismo político, Plunkitt también predicó las
virtudes del trabajo duro, de la sobriedad, e incluso (como en esta 
charla sobre "injerto honesto") de la honradez.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086293</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107092</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-seen-my-opportunities-and-i-took-em-an-old-time-pol-preaches-honest-graft</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
