<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106723</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106723</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087442</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Bobbed Hair Blues: A Mexican-American Song Laments "Las Pelonas"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ruckartig bewogenes Haar-Blau: Ein 
Mexikanisch-Amerikanisches Lied Bejammert "Las Pelonas"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bleus Pendillés de Cheveux : Une Chanson 
Mexicain-Américaine Déplore "Las Pelonas"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Azuis Sacudidos Do Cabelo: Uma Canção 
Mexicano-Americana Laments "Las Pelonas"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Azzurri Bobbed Dei Capelli: Una Canzone Di 
messicano-american Deplora "Las Pelonas"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μπλε τρίχας Bobbed: Ένα Μεξικανοαμερικάνο 
τραγούδι θρηνεί "Las Pelonas"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Azul Meneados Del Pelo: Una Canción 
Mexicano-Americana Lamenta De "Las Pelonas"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The "new woman" of the 1910s and 1920s rejected the pieties (and often the politics) of the older generation, smoked and drank in public, celebrated the sexual revolution, and embraced consumer culture. The flapper portrayed in cartoons, ads, and nationally circulated journalism, however, was almost always white, with features that denoted Northern European origins. She was also frequently shown with luxury goods or in exclusive settings. But young women of many ethnic groups also took up flapper styles and embraced the spirit of youthful rebellion. A popular song attested to generational conflict among Mexican Americans in San Antonio. In "Las Pelonas"--"The Bobbed Heads," or "Flappers"--the singer lamented the influence of Anglo youth culture on his Mexican-American community. [English version follows original in Spanish.]</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die "neue Frau" der 1910s und der zwanziger Jahre 
wies die pieties (und häufig die Politik) des älteren Erzeugung 
zurück, rauchte und trank in der Öffentlichkeit, gefeiert die 
sexuelle Umdrehung und umfaßte Verbraucherkultur. Die 
Prallplatte, die in den Karikaturen, ADS und national verteilter 
Journalismus geschildert wurde war jedoch, mit Merkmalen fast immer 
weiß, die europäische Nordursprung bezeichneten. Sie wurde 
auch häufig mit Luxuxwaren oder in den exklusiven Einstellungen 
gezeigt. Aber junge Frauen vieler ethnischer Gruppen auch nahmen
Prallplattearten auf und umfaßten den Geist des jugendlichen 
Aufstands. Ein populäres Lied bezeugte zur 
Generations-A$überschneidung unter mexikanischen Amerikanern in San 
Antonio. In "Las Pelonas" -- "die ruckartig bewogenen Köpfe," 
oder "Prallplatten" -- der Sänger bejammerte den Einfluß der 
Anglojugendkultur auf seine Mexikanisch-Amerikanische Gemeinschaft. 
[ englische Version folgt Vorlage auf spanisch. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La "nouvelle femme" des années 10 et des années 
20 a rejeté les pieties (et souvent la politique) de la génération 
plus ancienne, a fumé et a bu l'en public, célébré la révolution 
sexuelle, et culture embrassée du consommateur. L'aileron 
dépeint dans les dessins animés, ADS, et le journalisme 
nationalement distribué, cependant, était presque toujours blanc, 
avec les dispositifs qui ont dénoté des origines européennes 
nordiques. Elle a été également fréquemment montrée avec 
les marchandises de luxe ou dans les configurations exclusives. 
Mais les jeunes femmes de beaucoup de groupes ethniques ont 
également pris des modèles d'aileron et ont embrassé l'esprit de la
rébellion jeune. Une chanson populaire a certifié au conflit 
de generations parmi les Américains mexicains dans San Antonio. 
Dans "Las Pelonas" -- "les chefs pendillés," ou "des ailerons" 
-- le chanteur a déploré l'influence de la culture anglo de la 
jeunesse sur son communauté Mexicain-Américaine. [ la version 
anglaise suit l'original dans l'Espagnol. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"a mulher nova" dos 1910s e dos 1920s rejeitou os 
pieties (e frequentemente a política) da geração mais velha, fumou 
e bebeu-os no público, comemorado a volta sexual, e cultura embraced 
do consumidor. O flapper portrayed nos cartoons, ads, e 
journalism nacionalmente circulado, entretanto, era quase sempre 
branco, com características que denotaram origens européias do 
norte. Foi mostrada também freqüentemente com bens luxuosos ou
em ajustes exclusivos. Mas as mulheres novas de muitos grupos 
étnicos fizeram exame também acima de estilos do flapper e embraced 
o espírito da rebelião jovem. Uma canção popular atestou ao 
conflito generational entre americanos mexicanos em San Antonio. 
Em "Las Pelonas" -- "as cabeças sacudidas," ou "flappers" -- o 
singer lamented a influência da cultura anglo da juventude em sua 
comunidade Mexicano-Americana. [ a versão inglesa segue o 
original no espanhol. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la nuova donna" degli anni 10 e degli anni 20 ha 
rifiutato i pieties (e spesso la politica) di più vecchia 
generazione, ha fumato e bevuto in pubblico, celebrato la rivoluzione 
sessuale e coltura abbracciata del consumatore. La falda 
ritratta nei fumetti, ads e giornalismo nazionalmente distribuito, 
tuttavia, era quasi sempre bianca, con le caratteristiche che hanno 
denotato le origini europee nordiche. Egualmente è stata 
indicata frequentemente con le merci di lusso o nelle regolazioni 
esclusive. Ma le donne giovani di molti gruppi etnici egualmente
hanno preso gli stili della falda ed hanno abbracciato lo spirito 
della ribellione youthful. Una canzone popolare ha attestato al
conflitto generational fra gli Americani messicani in San Antonio. 
"in Las Pelonas" -- "le teste bobbed," o "falde" -- il cantante 
ha deplorato l'influenza della coltura anglo della gioventù sulla sua
Comunità di messicano-american. [ la versione inglese segue 
l'originale nello Spagnolo. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η "νέα γυναίκα" του 1910s και της δεκαετίας του '20 
απέρριψε τις ευσέβειες (και συχνά την πολιτική) της παλαιότερης 
γενεάς, κάπνισε και ήπιε στο κοινό, γιόρτασε τη σεξουαλική 
επανάσταση, και αγκαλίασε τον καταναλωτικό πολιτισμό. Το 
πτερύγιο απεικόνισε στα κινούμενα σχέδια, αγγελίες, και η εθνικά
κυκλοφορημένη δημοσιογραφία, εντούτοις, ήταν σχεδόν πάντα 
άσπρη, με τα χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα που έδειξαν τη βόρεια 
ευρωπαϊκή προέλευση. Επίσης συχνά εμφανίστηκε με τα αγαθά
πολυτέλειας ή στις αποκλειστικές τιμές των παραμέτρων. 
Αλλά οι νέες γυναίκες πολλών εθνικών ομάδων έλαβαν 
επίσης τις μορφές πτερυγίων και αγκαλίασαν το πνεύμα της 
νεανικής εξέγερσης. Ένα δημοφιλές τραγούδι που βεβαιώνεται
στη σύγκρουση generational μεταξύ μεξικάνικων Αμερικανών στο 
SAN Antonio. "Σε Las Pelonas" -- "τα κεφάλια 
Bobbed," ή "τα πτερύγια" -- ο τραγουδιστής θρήνησε την επιρροή
του πολιτισμού νεολαίας Anglo στη Μεξικανοαμερικάή κοινότητά 
του. [ Η αγγλική εκδοχή ακολουθεί αρχικό στα ισπανικά. 
]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La "nueva mujer" de los años 10 y de los años 20
rechazó los pieties (y a menudo la política) de la más vieja 
generación, fumó y bebió en el público, celebrado la revolución 
sexual, y cultura abrazada del consumidor. La aleta retratada en
las historietas, ads, y periodismo nacionalmente circulado, sin 
embargo, era casi siempre blanca, con las características que 
denotaron orígenes europeos norteños. También le mostraron 
con frecuencia con las mercancías de lujo o en configuraciones 
exclusivas. Pero las mujeres jóvenes de muchos grupos étnicos 
también tomaron estilos de la aleta y abrazaron el alcohol de la 
rebelión joven. Una canción popular atestiguó al conflicto 
generational entre americanos mexicanos en San Antonio. En "Las 
Pelonas" -- "las pistas meneadas," o "las aletas" -- el cantante 
lamentó de la influencia de la cultura anglo de la juventud en su 
comunidad Mexicano-Americana. [ la versión inglesa sigue 
original en español. ]</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087442</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106723</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/bobbed-hair-blues-a-mexican-american-song-laments-las-pelonas</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
