<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105800</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105800</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087406</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Are Sleeping Cars Protected by the Constitution? Mr. Dooley on the Pullman Strike</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Werden Schlafwagen durch die Beschaffenheit 
geschützt? Herr Dooley auf dem Pullman-Schlag</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Est-ce que des voitures de sommeil sont protégées
par la constitution ? M. Dooley sur la grève de pullman</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Carros dormindo são protegidos pelo constitution? 
Sr. Dooley na batida do Pullman</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli automobili di sonno sono protetti dalla 
costituzione? Sig. Dooley sul colpo del pullman</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα βαγόνια ύπνου προστατεύονται από το σύνταγμα; 
Ο κ. Dooley στην απεργία Pullman</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿Los coches durmientes son protegidos por la 
constitución? Sr. Dooley en la huelga del pullman</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1893 the newspaperman Peter Finley Dunne began publishing a regular series in the Chicago  Evening Post  featuring dialogues between an Irish bartender named Martin Dooley, and his Irish friend and customer, Henessey. The local column quickly achieved national renown and syndication in newspapers across the country. Dunne's dialogues drew upon prevalent ethnic stereotypes that were a staple of late nineteenth-century American humor. Dooley regularly commented on both local and national events. Thus, it was not surprising that he would have something to say about the dramatic strike by the American Railway Union against Chicago's Pullman Palace Car Company that had shut down rail lines across the United States in 1894. In the July 7, 1894, column included here (read by an actress), Dunne poked fun at George Pullman's claims that the strike was a violation of the U.S. Constitution.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In 1893 fing der Newspaperman Peter Finley Dunne 
an, eine regelmäßige Serie im Chicago Abend-Pfosten zu 
veröffentlichen, der Dialoge zwischen einem irischen Barmixer 
kennzeichnet, der Martin Dooley benannt wurde, und sein irischer 
Freund und Kunde, Henessey. Die lokale Spalte erzielte schnell 
nationales Renommee und Syndikatsbildung in den Zeitungen über 
dem Land. Dialoge Dunnes zeichneten nach überwiegenden 
ethnischen Stereotypen, die eine Heftklammer spätes 19.-Jahrhundert 
der amerikanischen Stimmung waren. Dooley kommentierte 
regelmäßig die lokalen und nationalen Fälle. So überraschte 
es nicht, daß er etwas, über den drastischen Schlag durch den 
amerikanischen Bahnanschluß gegen Pullman Palace Car Company zu sagen
Chicagos haben würde, der Schiene Zeilen über den Vereinigten 
Staaten 1894 abgeschaltet hatte. Im Juli 7, 1894, Spalte hier 
eingeschlossen (gelesen durch einen Schauspielerin), Dunne gestoßener
Spaß an den Ansprüchen des George Pullmans, daß der Schlag eine 
Verletzung der VEREINIGTE STAATEN Beschaffenheit war.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans 1893 le journaliste Peter Finley Dunne a 
commencé à éditer une série régulière dans le poteau de soirée 
de Chicago comportant des dialogues entre un barman irlandais nommé 
Martin Dooley, et son ami et client irlandais, Henessey. La 
colonne locale a rapidement réalisé la renommée et la syndication 
nationales en journaux à travers le pays. Les dialogues de 
Dunne ont utilisé les stéréotypes ethniques répandus qui étaient 
une agrafe d'humeur américaine de dix-neuvième-siècle en retard. 
Dooley a régulièrement présenté ses observations sur des 
événements locaux et nationaux. Ainsi, il n'étonnait pas 
qu'il aurait quelque chose à dire au sujet de la grève excessive par
l'union ferroviaire américaine contre Pullman Palace Car Company de 
Chicago qui avait arrêté des lignes de rail à travers les 
Etats-Unis en 1894. En 7 juillet 1894, colonne incluse ici (lu 
par une actrice), amusement poussé par Dunne aux réclamations du 
pullman's de George que la grève était une violation de la 
constitution des ETATS-UNIS.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1893 o newspaperman Peter Finley Dunne começou 
a publicar uma série regular no borne da noite de Chicago que 
caracteriza diálogos entre um bárman irish nomeado Martin Dooley, e 
seus amigo e cliente irish, Henessey. A coluna local conseguiu 
rapidamente o renown e o syndication nacionais nos jornais através do
país. Os diálogos de Dunne desenharam em cima dos stereotypes 
étnicos prevalent que eram um grampo do humor americano de 
décimo-século atrasado. Dooley comentou regularmente  em 
eventos locais e nacionais. Assim, não estava surpreendendo que
teria algo para dizer sobre a batida dramática pela união railway 
americana de encontro a Pullman Palácio Carro Companhia de Chicago 
que tinha fechado abaixo linhas do trilho através dos estados unidos 
em 1894. Julho no 7, 1894, coluna incluída aqui (lido por uma 
actriz), divertimento picado Dunne em reivindicações do Pullman de 
George que a batida era uma violação do constitution de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1893 il newspaperman Peter Finley Dunne ha 
cominciato a pubblicare una serie normale nell'alberino di sera del 
Chicago che caratterizza i dialoghi fra un barista irlandese chiamato 
Martin Dooley ed il suoi amico e cliente irlandesi, Henessey. La
colonna locale ha realizzato rapidamente il renown e lo syndication 
nazionali in giornali attraverso il paese. I dialoghi del Dunne 
hanno dissipato sugli stereotipi etnici prevalenti che erano una 
graffetta di umore americano del diciannovesimo-secolo tardo. 
Dooley ha commentato regolarmente sia gli eventi locali che 
nazionali. Quindi, non stava sorpresendo che avrebbe qualcosa da
dire circa il colpo drammatico dall'unione ferroviaria americana 
contro Pullman Palace Car Company del Chicago che aveva interrotto le 
righe della guida attraverso unito Dichiara in 1894. In 7
luglio 1894, colonna inclusa qui (colto da un actress), divertimento 
colpito Dunne ai reclami del pullman di George che il colpo era una 
violazione della costituzione degli STATI UNITI.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1893 ο δημοσιογράφος Peter Finley Dunne 
άρχισε μια κανονική σειρά στο ταχυδρομείο βραδιού του Σικάγου 
που χαρακτηρίζει τα διαλογικά παράθυρα μεταξύ ιρλανδικό 
bartender που ονομάστηκε Martin Dooley, και τον ιρλανδικούς
φίλο και τον πελάτη του, Henessey. Η τοπική στήλη 
επέτυχε γρήγορα την εθνικά φήμη και το syndication στις 
εφημερίδες σε ολόκληρη τη χώρα. Τα διαλογικά παράθυρα του 
Dunne βασίστηκαν στα επικρατόντα εθνικά στερεότυπα που ήταν 
μια βάση του πρόσφατου αμερικανικού χιούμορ δέκατος-αιώνα. 
Το Dooley σχολίασε τακτικά και τα τοπικά και εθνικά 
γεγονότα. Κατά συνέπεια, δεν ήταν εκπληκτικό ότι θα είχε 
κάτι λέω για τη δραματική απεργία από την αμερικανική ένωση 
σιδηροδρόμων ενάντια σε Pullman Palace Car Company του 
Σικάγου που είχε διακόψει τις γραμμές ραγών στις Ηνωμένες 
Πολιτείες το 1894. Τις 7 Ιουλίου ..1894, στήλη που 
περιλαμβάνεται εδώ (διαβασμένος από μια ηθοποιό), σπρωγμένη 
Dunne διασκέδαση στις αξιώσεις George Pullman's ότι η 
απεργία ήταν μια παραβίαση του ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΥ συντάγματος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1893 el newspaperman Peter Finley Dunne comenzó
a publicar una serie regular en el poste de la tarde de Chicago que 
ofrecía diálogos entre un camarero irlandés nombrado Martin Dooley,
y su amigo y cliente irlandeses, Henessey. La columna local 
alcanzó rápidamente renombre y el syndication nacionales en 
periódicos a través del país. Los diálogos de Dunne trazaron
sobre los estereotipos étnicos frecuentes que eran una grapa del 
humor americano del último diecinueveavo-siglo. Dooley comentó
regularmente respecto a acontecimientos locales y nacionales. 
Así, no sorprendía que él tendría algo que decir sobre la 
huelga dramática por la unión ferroviaria americana contra Pullman 
Palace Car Company de Chicago que había cerrado líneas del carril a 
través de los Estados Unidos en 1894. En 7 de julio de 1894,
columna incluida aquí (leído por una actriz), diversión empujada 
Dunne en las demandas del pullman de George que la huelga era una 
violación de la constitución de ESTADOS UNIDOS.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087406</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105800</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/are-sleeping-cars-protected-by-the-constitution-mr-dooley-on-the-pullman-strike</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
