<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105248</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105248</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086827</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Should a Catholic Be President?: A Contemporary View of the 1928 Election</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wenn ein katholisches Präsident? ist: Eine 
zeitgenössische Ansicht der Wahl 1928</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Si un catholique est président ? : Une vue 
contemporaine de l'élection 1928</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Se um catholic for presidente?: Uma vista 
contemporary da eleição 1928</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Se un cattolico è presidente?: Una vista 
contemporanea dell'elezione 1928</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εάν ήταν ένας καθολικός Πρόεδρος;: Μια 
σύγχρονη όψη της εκλογής του 1928</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Si un católico es presidente?: Una vista 
contemporánea de la elección 1928</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Religion figured prominently in the 1928 presidential election when Alfred E. Smith, the Democratic governor of New York, became the first Catholic to run as the candidate of a major political party. Smith, who ran against the Republican Secretary of Commerce Herbert Hoover, tried to downplay the subject of his religion. In this article from  Atlantic Monthly  of April 1927, lawyer Charles Marshall argued that loyalty to the Catholic Church conflicted with loyalty to the United States.  Atlantic Monthly  editor Ellery Sedgwick had solicited the Marshall letter, although he was himself a Smith supporter. He thought that the religious debate was inevitable, and he tried to place it on an intellectual plane. Although the article revealed anti-Catholic biases, Marshall's views were less strident than those of many contemporaries.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Religion stellte vorstehend in der 
Präsidentenwahl 1928 dar, als Alfred E. Smith, der demokratische 
Gouverneur von New York, der erste Katholische wurde, zum als der 
Anwärter einer politischen hauptsächlichPartei zu laufen. 
Smith, der gegen den republikanischen Minister fuer 
Handel-Herbert Staubsauger lief, versuchte, das Thema seiner Religion 
unterzutreiben. In diesem Artikel von der atlantischen 
Monatszeitschrift von April 1927, argumentierte Rechtsanwalt Charles 
Marschall, daß Loyalität zur katholischen Kirche mit Loyalität in 
die Vereinigten Staaten widersprach. Atlantischer 
Monatsherausgeber Ellery Sedgwick hatte das Marschallzeichen erbeten, 
obgleich er selbst ein Smith Verfechter war. Er dachte, daß die
fromme Debatte unvermeidlich war, und er versuchte, sie auf eine 
intellektuelle Fläche zu plazieren. Obgleich der Artikel 
Anti-Katholische Vorspannungen aufdeckte, waren Ansichten des 
Marschalls weniger scharf als die vieler Zeitgenossen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La religion a figuré en évidence dans 
l'élection 1928 présidentielle quand Alfred E. Smith, le gouverneur 
démocratique de New York, est devenu le premier catholique à 
exécuter en tant que candidat d'une partie politique importante. 
Smith, qui a exécuté contre le secrétaire républicain de 
l'aspirateur d'Herbert de commerce, a essayé de réduire la valeur du
sujet de sa religion. En cet article de revue mensuelle 
atlantique d'avril 1927, le maréchal de Charles d'avocat a argué du 
fait que la fidélité à l'église catholique était en conflit avec 
la fidélité aux Etats-Unis. L'éditeur mensuel atlantique 
Ellery Sedgwick avait sollicité la lettre de maréchal, bien qu'il 
ait été lui-même un défenseur de Smith. Il a pensé que la 
discussion religieuse était inévitable, et il a essayé de la placer
sur un avion intellectuel. Bien que l'article ait indiqué des 
polarisations anti-Catholiques, les vues du maréchal étaient moins 
stridentes que ceux de beaucoup de contemporains.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A religião figurou proeminente na eleição 1928 
presidencial quando Alfred E. Smith, regulador democrático de New 
York, se transformou o primeiro catholic a funcionar como o candidato 
de um partido político principal. Smith, que funcionou de 
encontro à secretária republicana do hoover de Herbert do comércio,
tentou downplay o assunto de sua religião. Neste artigo da 
revista mensal atlantic de abril 1927, o marshall de Charles do 
advogado discutiu que a lealdade à igreja catholic opôs à lealdade 
aos estados unidos. O editor mensal atlantic Ellery Sedgwick 
solicited a letra do marshall, embora fosse ele mesmo um supporter de 
Smith. Pensou de que o debate religioso era inevitável, e 
tentou colocá-lo em um plano intelectual. Embora o artigo 
revelasse polarizações anti-anti-Catholic, as opiniões do marshall 
eram mais menos strident do que aquelas de muitos comtemporâneos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La religione ha calcolato prominente nell'elezione
presidenziale 1928 quando Alfred E. Smith, il regolatore democratico 
di New York, è diventato il primo cattolico da funzionare come il 
candidato di un partito politico importante. Smith, che ha 
funzionato contro la segretaria Repubblicana del hoover del Herbert di 
commercio, ha provato a downplay l'argomento di sua religione. 
In questo articolo dal mensile atlantico di aprile del 1927, il 
marshall del Charles dell'avvocato ha sostenuto che la lealtà alla 
chiesa cattolica ha stato in conflitto con lealtà al unito 
Dichiara. L'editore mensile atlantico Ellery Sedgwick 
aveva sollecitato la lettera del marshall, anche se era egli stesso un
sostenitore dello Smith. Ha pensato che il dibattito religioso 
fosse inevitabile ed ha provato a disporlo su un aereo intellettuale. 
Anche se l'articolo ha rivelato le polarizzazioni 
anti-Cattoliche, i punti di vista del marshall erano meno strident che
quelli di molti contemporanei.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θρησκεία που βρίσκεται κυρίως στην προεδρική εκλογή 
του 1928 όταν ο Alfred E. Smith, ο δημοκρατικός 
κυβερνήτης της Νέας Υόρκης, έγινε πρώτος ο καθολικός για να 
τρέξει ως υποψήφιο ενός σημαντικού πολιτικού κόμματος. 
Θ*Σμητχ, που αντιτέθηκε το δημοκρατικό γραμματέα του 
εμπορίου Herbert Hoover, δοκίμασε σε downplay το θέμα της 
θρησκείας του. Σε αυτό το άρθρο από ατλαντική μηνιαία τον 
Απριλίου του 1927, ο δικηγόρος Charles Marshall υποστήριξε
ότι η πίστη στην καθολική εκκλησία συγκρούομαι με την πίστη στις
Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες. Ο ατλαντικός μηνιαίος επεξεργαστής 
Ellery Sedgwick είχε ζητήσει τη Marshall επιστολή, αν και 
ήταν ο ίδιος υποστηρικτής Smith. Σκέφτηκε ότι η 
θρησκευτική συζήτηση ήταν αναπόφευκτη, και προσπάθησε να το 
τοποθετήσει σε ένα διανοητικό αεροπλάνο. Αν και το άρθρο 
αποκάλυψε αντι-καθολικές πολώσεις, Marshall's οι όψεις ήταν 
λιγότερο τραχιές από εκείνοι πολλών συγχρόνων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La religión calculó prominente en la elección 
presidencial 1928 cuando Alfred E. Smith, el gobernador democrático 
de Nueva York, hizo el primer católico a ejecutarse como el candidato
de un partido político importante. Smith, que se ejecutó 
contra la secretaria republicana de la aspiradora de Herberto del 
comercio, intentó downplay el tema de su religión. En este 
artículo de la publicación mensual atlántica de abril de 1927, el 
ordenar de Charles del abogado discutió que la lealtad a la iglesia 
católica estuviera en conflicto con lealtad a los Estados Unidos. 
El editor mensual atlántico Ellery Sedgwick había solicitado 
la carta del ordenar, aunque él era sí mismo un partidario de Smith.
Él pensó que el discusión religioso era inevitable, y él 
intentó ponerlo en un plano intelectual. Aunque el artículo 
reveló diagonales contra-Cato'licos, las opiniones del ordenar eran 
menos estridentes que las de muchos contemporáneos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086827</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105248</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/should-a-catholic-be-president-a-contemporary-view-of-the-1928-election</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
