<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108556</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108556</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973919</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">River City Project</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Fluss-Stadt-Projekt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Projet de Ville de Fleuve</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Projeto Da Cidade Do Rio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Progetto Della Città Del Fiume</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πρόγραμμα πόλεων ποταμών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Proyecto De la Ciudad Del Río</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">As visitors to River City, students travel back in time, bringing their 21st century skills and technology to address 19th century problems. With funding from the National Science Foundation, we have developed an interactive computer simulation for middle grades science students to learn scientific inquiry and 21st century skills. River City has the look and feel of a video game but contains content developed from National Science Education Standards, National Educational Technology Standards, and 21st Century Skills. All middle grades (6-9) teachers in North America are invited to participate in the River City Project.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Als Besucher zur Fluss-Stadt, reisen 
Kursteilnehmer zurück in Zeit und holen ihre Fähigkeiten und 
Technologie des 21. Jahrhunderts, 19. Jahrhundertprobleme zu 
adressieren. Mit der Finanzierung vom National Science 
Foundation, haben wir eine interaktive Computersimulation entwickelt, 
damit Mitte Grad-Wissenschaft Kursteilnehmer Fähigkeiten der 
wissenschaftlichen Anfrage und des 21. Jahrhunderts erlernen. 
Fluss-Stadt hat den Blick und das Gefühl eines videospiels aber
enthält den Inhalt, der von den nationalen Wissenschaft Ausbildung 
Standards, von den nationalen pädagogischen Technologie-Standards und
von den 21. Jahrhundert-Fähigkeiten entwickelt wird. Alle 
Lehrer der Mitte Grade (6-9) in Nordamerika werden eingeladen, am 
Fluss-Stadt-Projekt teilzunehmen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Comme visiteurs à la ville de fleuve, les 
étudiants voyagent en arrière à temps, apportant leurs 
qualifications et technologie de 21ème siècle adresser les 19èmes 
problèmes de siècle. Avec le financement à partir du National
Science Foundation, nous avons développé une simulation sur 
ordinateur interactive pour que les étudiants de la science de 
catégories de milieu apprennent des qualifications d'enquête 
scientifique et de 21ème siècle. La ville de fleuve a le 
regard et la sensation d'un jeu vidéo mais contient le contenu 
développé à partir des normes nationales d'éducation de la 
Science, des normes éducatives nationales de technologie, et des 
qualifications de 21ème siècle. Tous les professeurs des 
catégories de milieu (6-9) en Amérique du nord sont invités à 
participer au projet de ville de fleuve.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Como visitantes à cidade do rio, os estudantes 
viajam para trás a tempo, trazendo suas habilidades e tecnologia do 
século XXI dirigir-se a 1øs problemas do século. Com 
financiar do National Science Foundation, nós desenvolvemos uma 
simulação de computador interativa para que os estudantes da 
ciência das classes do meio aprendam habilidades do inquérito 
científico e do século XXI. A cidade do rio tem o olhar e a 
sensação de um jogo video mas contem o índice desenvolvido dos 
padrões nacionais da instrução da ciência, dos padrões 
educacionais nacionais da tecnologia, e das habilidades do século 
XXI. Todos os professores das classes do meio (6-9) em America 
do Norte são convidados participar no projeto da cidade do rio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Come ospiti alla città del fiume, gli allievi 
viaggiano indietro a tempo, portando le loro abilità e tecnologia di 
ventunesimo secolo richiamare i diciannovesimi problemi di secolo. 
Con costituire un fondo per dal National Science Foundation, 
abbiamo sviluppato una simulazione su elaboratore interattiva 
affinchè gli allievi di scienza dei gradi della metà impariamo le 
abilità di ventunesimo secolo e di inchiesta scientifica. La 
città del fiume ha lo sguardo ed il tatto di video gioco ma contiene 
il soddisfare sviluppato dagli standard nazionali di formazione di 
scienza, dagli standard educativi nazionali di tecnologia e dalle 
abilità di ventunesimo secolo. Tutti gli insegnanti dei gradi 
della metà (6-9) in America del Nord sono invitati a partecipare al 
progetto della città del fiume.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σαν επισκέπτες στην πόλη ποταμών, οι σπουδαστές 
ταξιδεύουν πίσω εγκαίρως, φέρνοντας τις δεξιότητες και την 
τεχνολογία του 21$ου αιώνα τους για να εξετάσουν τα προβλήματα του
19$ου αιώνα. Με τη χρηματοδότηση από το εθνικό ίδρυμα 
επιστήμης τις δεξιότητες, έχουμε αναπτύξει μια διαλογική 
προσομοίωση υπολογιστών για τους μέσους σπουδαστές επιστήμης 
βαθμών για να μάθουμε επιστημονικής έρευνας και του 21$ου αιώνα. 
Η πόλη ποταμών ρίχνει τη ματιά και την αίσθηση ενός 
τηλεοπτικού παιχνιδιού αλλά περιέχει το περιεχόμενο που 
αναπτύσσεται από τα εθνικά πρότυπα εκπαίδευσης επιστήμης, τα 
εθνικά εκπαιδευτικά πρότυπα τεχνολογίας, και τις δεξιότητες του 
21$ου αιώνα. Όλη η μέση βαθμολογεί (69) τους δασκάλους 
στη Βόρεια Αμερική καλείται για να συμμετέχει στο πρόγραμμα 
πόλεων ποταμών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Como visitantes a la ciudad del río, los 
estudiantes viajan detrás en tiempo, trayendo sus habilidades y 
tecnología del siglo XXI tratar los diecinueveavo problemas del 
siglo. Con el financiamiento del National Science Foundation, 
hemos desarrollado una simulación de ordenador interactiva para que 
los estudiantes de la ciencia de los grados del centro aprendan 
habilidades de la pregunta científica y del siglo XXI. La 
ciudad del río tiene la mirada y la sensación de un juego video pero
contiene el contenido desarrollado de estándares nacionales de la 
educación de la ciencia, de estándares educativos nacionales de la 
tecnología, y de habilidades del siglo XXI. Se invita a todos 
los profesores de los grados del centro (6-9) en Norteamérica que 
participen en el proyecto de la ciudad del río.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973919</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108556</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/river-city-project</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
