<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103470</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103470</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086764</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Public Responsibilities . . . Public Wrongs": Union Officials Blame the Taft-Hartley Act for Mob Antiunion Violence</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Allgemeine Verantwortlichkeiten. . . 
Allgemeines Unrecht ": Anschluß-Beamte tadeln die 
Taft-Hartley Tat für Pöbel Antiunion Gewalttätigkeit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Responsabilités Publiques. . . 
Maux Publics ": Les fonctionnaires des syndicats blâment 
la Loi de Taft-Hartley de la violence d'Antiunion de foule</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Responsabilidades Públicas. . . 
Erros Públicos ": Os oficiais da união responsabilizam o
ato de Taft-Hartley pela violência de Antiunion do mob</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Responsabilità Pubbliche. . . 
Torti Pubblici ": I funzionari del sindacato incolpano 
della Legge di Taft-Hartley la violenza di Antiunion del mob</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Δημόσιες ευθύνες. .. Το κοινό βλάπτει ": 
Οι ανώτεροι υπάλληλοι ένωσης κατηγορούν το νόμο ταφτ- 
Hartley για τη βία όχλου Antiunion</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Responsabilidades Públicas. . . 
Males Públicos ": Los funcionarios de la unión culparon 
el acto de Taft-Hartley por la violencia de Antiunion de la multitud</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the late 1940s, large labor unions and major corporations worked out an accord that would guide labor-management relations for the next quarter century. During this period, unions benefited from high wages and relative stability, while relegating company decision-making to management. Many workers in certain geographic areas and sectors of employment, however, were not affected by the accord. In "union-free" Gainesville, Georgia, union representatives had started to organize a predominately female workforce in a large poultry plant. In the following statement to a House subcommittee on labor-management relations, Roy F. Scheurich, vice-president of the Amalgamated Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen of North America related a violent mob attack led by company officials. Joseph M. Jacobs, the union's general counsel, then argued that language in the Taft-Hartley Act, which regulated labor-management relations, allowed employers "apparent immunity" from legal responsibility for mob violence against labor representatives unless direct involvement could be proven. The Taft-Hartley Act, passed in 1947 by a Republican-led Congress over President Harry S. Truman's veto, amended provisions of the 1935 Wagner Act. Jacobs argued for restoration of the Wagner Act's language. In September 1951, one month after this hearing, a trial examiner for the National Labor Relations Board held the Jewell Company liable for instigating the riot described in the statement.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In den späten vierziger Jahren arbeiteten große 
Arbeiterverbände und Hauptkorporationen eine Übereinstimmung aus, 
die Arbeitsmanagementrelationen für das folgende Vierteljahrhundert 
führen würde. Während dieser Periode profitierten Anschlüße
von den hohen Löhnen und von der relativen Stabilität, beim 
Relegieren von von Firmabeschlußfassung zum Management. Viele 
Arbeiter in bestimmten geographischen Bereichen und in Sektoren der 
Beschäftigung jedoch wurden nicht durch die Übereinstimmung 
beeinflußt. In "Anschluß-freiem" Gainesville hatte Georgia, 
Anschlußrepräsentanten begonnen, eine überwiegend weibliche 
Mannschaft in einem großen Geflügelbetrieb zu organisieren. In
der folgenden Anweisung zu einer Hausunterausschuß auf 
Arbeitsmanagementrelationen, stand Roy F. Scheurich, Vizepräsident 
der amalgamierten Fleisch-Schnittmeister und der Metzger-Arbeiter von 
Nordamerika einen heftigen Pöbelangriff in Verbindung, der von den 
Firmabeamten geführt wurde. Joseph M. Jacobs, der allgemeine 
Berater des Anschlußes, dann argumentiert, daß Sprache in der 
Taft-Hartley Tat, die Arbeitsmanagementrelationen regelte, 
Arbeitgebern "offensichtliche Immunität" von der zugelassenen 
Verantwortlichkeit für Pöbelgewalttätigkeit gegen 
Arbeitsrepräsentanten zugestand, es sei denn direkte Miteinbeziehung 
nachgewiesen werden könnte. Die Taft-Hartley Tat, geführt 
worden 1947 von einem Republikanisch-führenden Kongreß über 
Präsident Harry S. Trumans Veto, änderte Bestimmungen der Wagner Tat
1935 Jacobs, das für Wiederherstellung der Sprache der Wagner Tat 
argumentiert wurde. Im September 1951, ein Monat nach dieser 
Hörfähigkeit, hielt ein Probeprüfer für das nationale 
Arbeitgeber-Arbeitnehmer-Beziehungen Brett Jewell Company 
verantwortlich für das Anstiften des Aufstands an, der in der 
Anweisung beschrieben wurde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Vers la fin des années 40, les grands syndicats 
et les sociétés principales ont établi une entente qui guiderait 
des relations de travail de gestion pour le siècle quart suivant. 
Pendant cette période, les syndicats ont tiré bénéfice des 
salaires élevés et de la stabilité relative, tout en reléguant la 
prise de décision de compagnie à la gestion. Beaucoup 
d'ouvriers dans de certains zones et secteurs géographiques d'emploi,
cependant, n'ont pas été affectés par l'entente. Dans 
Gainesville "union-libre", la Géorgie, représentants des syndicats 
avait commencé à organiser une main d'oeuvre d'une matière 
prédominante féminine à une grande usine de volaille. Dans le
rapport suivant à un sous-comité de Chambre sur des relations de 
travail de gestion, Roy F. Scheurich, vice-président des coupeurs de 
viande et des ouvriers fusionnés de boucher de l'Amérique 
du nord a associé une attaque violente de foule menée par des 
fonctionnaires de compagnie. Joseph M. Jacobs, l'avocat-conseil 
général des syndicats, alors argué du fait que le langage dans 
l'acte de Taft-Hartley, qui a réglé des relations de travail de 
gestion, a permis à des employeurs "l'immunité apparente" de la 
responsabilité légale de la violence de foule contre les 
représentants de travail à moins que la participation directe 
pourrait être montrée. L'acte de Taft-Hartley, passé en 1947 
par un congrès Républicain-mené au-dessus du veto du Président 
Harry S. Truman's, a modifié des dispositions de l'acte 1935 de 
Wagner Jacobs discuté pour la restauration du langage de l'acte 
de Wagner. En septembre 1951, pendant un mois après cette 
audition, un examinateur d'essai pour l'office national de relations 
sociales a jugé Jewell Company responsable de inciter l'émeute 
décrite dans le rapport.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nos 1940s atrasados, as uniões labor grandes e os
corporation principais trabalharam para fora de um acordo que guiasse 
relações labor da gerência para o século de um quarto seguinte. 
Durante este período, as uniões beneficiaram-se dos salários 
elevados e da estabilidade relativa, ao relegating a tomada de 
decisão da companhia à gerência. Muitos trabalhadores em 
determinados áreas e setores geográficos do emprego, entretanto, 
não foram afetados pelo acordo. Em Gainesville "união-livre", 
Geórgia, representantes de união tinha começado organizar um 
workforce predominately fêmea em uma planta grande das aves 
domésticas. Na seguinte indicação a uma subcomissão da casa 
em relações labor da gerência, Roy F. Scheurich, vice-presidente 
dos cortadores da carne e dos trabalhadores amalgamated do carniceiro 
de America do Norte relacionou um ataque violento do mob conduzido por
oficiais da companhia. Joseph M. Jacobs, conselho geral da 
união, discutido então que a língua no ato de Taft-Hartley, que 
regulou relações labor da gerência, permitiu a empregadores "o 
immunity aparente" da responsabilidade legal para a violência do mob 
de encontro aos representantes labor a menos que a participação 
direta poderia ser provada. O ato de Taft-Hartley, passado em 
1947 por um congress Republicano-conduzido sobre o veto do presidente 
Harry S. Truman, emendou provisões do ato 1935 de Wagner Jacobs 
discutido para a restauração da língua do ato de Wagner. Em 
setembro 1951, um mês após este hearing, um examinador experimental 
para a placa de relações labor nacional manteve o Jewell Companhia 
responsável para instigating o motim descrito na indicação.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Verso la fine dei 1940s, i grandi sindacati 
di lavoro e le società importanti hanno risolto un accordo che 
guiderebbe i rapporti di lavoro-management per il secolo quarto 
prossimo. Durante questo periodo, i sindacati hanno tratto 
beneficio dagli alti stipendi e dalla stabilità relativa, mentre 
relegavano la risoluzione dell'azienda alla gestione. Molti 
operai nelle determinati zone e settori geografici di occupazione, 
tuttavia, non sono stati influenzati dall'accordo. In 
Gainesville "unione-libero", la Georgia, rappresentanti sindacali 
aveva cominciato organizzare una mano d'opera predominately femminile 
in una grande pianta del pollame. Nella seguente istruzione ad 
un sottocomitato della Camera sui rapporti di lavoro-management, 
Roy F. Scheurich, vice presidente delle taglierine della carne e degli
operai amalgamati del macellaio dell'America del Nord ha collegato un 
attacco violento del mob condotto dai funzionari dell'azienda. 
Joseph M. Jacobs, il consulente legale generale del sindacato, 
allora sostenuto che il linguaggio nella Legge di Taft-Hartley, che ha
regolato i rapporti di lavoro-management, ha conceduto a datori di 
lavoro "l'immunità apparente" dalla responsabilità legale della 
violenza del mob contro i rappresentanti di lavoro a meno che la 
partecipazione diretta potrebbe essere dimostrata. La Legge di 
Taft-Hartley, passata in 1947 da un congresso di repubblicano-led sopra 
il veto del presidente Harry S. Truman, ha emendato le disposizioni 
della Legge 1935 di Wagner Jacobs discusso per ripristino del 
linguaggio della Legge di Wagner. Nel mese di settembre del 
1951, un mese dopo questa udienza, un ispettore di prova per il 
Bordo Di lavoro nazionale di rapporti ha giudicato il Jewell 
Company responsabile per l'istigazione del tumulto descritto 
nell'istruzione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Προς το τέλος της δεκαετίας του '40, μεγάλα εργατικά 
συνδικάτα και σημαντικές εταιρίες επέλυσαν μια συμφωνία που θα 
καθοδηγούσε τις εργασία-διοικητικές σχέσεις για τον επόμενο 
αιώνα τετάρτων. Κατά τη διάρκεια αυτής της περιόδου, οι 
ενώσεις ωφελήθηκαν από τις υψηλές αμοιβές και τη σχετική 
σταθερότητα, στέλνοντας τη λήψη αποφάσεων επιχείρησης στη 
διαχείριση. Πολλοί εργαζόμενοι σε ορισμένους γεωγραφικούς 
περιοχές και τομείς της απασχόλησης, εντούτοις, δεν επηρεάστηκαν 
από τη συμφωνία. Σε "ένωση-ελεύθερο" Gainesville, 
Γεωργία, οι συνδικαλιστικοί εκπρόσωποι είχαν αρχίσει να 
οργανώνουν ένα κυρίως γυναικείο εργατικό δυναμικό σε μεγάλες 
εγκαταστάσεις πουλερικών. Στην ακόλουθη δήλωση σε μια 
υποεπιτροπή σπιτιών στις εργασία-διοικητικές σχέσεις, ο Roy 
F. Scheurich, αντιπρόεδρος των συγχωνευμένων κοπτών κρέατος 
και εργάτες χασάπηδων της Βόρειας Αμερικής αφορούσε μια βίαια 
επίθεση όχλου που οδηγείται από τα στελέχη επιχείρησης. 
Θ*Ιοσεπχ M. Jacobs, η γενική συμβουλή της ένωσης, 
έπειτα υποστήριξε ότι η γλώσσα στο νόμο ταφτ- Hartley, που 
ρύθμισε τις εργασία-διοικητικές σχέσεις, επέτρεψε στους 
εργοδότες τη "προφανή ασυλία" από τη νομική ευθύνη για τη βία 
όχλου ενάντια στους αντιπροσώπους εργασίας εκτός αν η άμεση 
συμμετοχή θα μπορούσε να αποδειχθεί. Το νόμο ταφτ- 
Hartley, το 1947 από ένα δημοκρατικός-οδηγημένο συνέδριο 
που πέρασε πέρα από το βέτο Προέδρου Harry S. Truman's, 
τροποποίησε τις διατάξεις του νόμου Wagner του 1935. Το
Jacobs υποστήριξε την αποκατάσταση της γλώσσας του νόμου 
Wagner. Τον Σεπτέμβριο του 1951, έναν μήνα μετά από 
αυτήν την ακρόαση, ένας δοκιμαστικός εξεταστής για το εθνικό 
συμβούλιο σχέσεων εργασίας κράτησε την επιχείρηση Jewell 
υπεύθυνη για την υποκίνηση της ταραχής που περιγράφηκε στη 
δήλωση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En los últimos años 40, los sindicatos grandes y
las corporaciones importantes resolvieron un acuerdo que dirigiría 
las relaciones de trabajo de la gerencia para el siglo cuarto 
próximo. Durante este período, las uniones beneficiaron de 
altos salarios y de estabilidad relativa, mientras que relegaban la 
toma de decisión de la compañía a la gerencia. El acuerdo no 
afectaron a muchos trabajadores en ciertos áreas y sectores 
geográficos de empleo, sin embargo. En Gainesville 
"unio'n-libre", Georgia, representantes de unión había comenzado a 
ordenar a una mano de obra predominately femenina en una planta grande
de las aves de corral. En la declaración siguiente a un 
subcomité de la casa en relaciones de trabajo de la gerencia, Roy F. 
Scheurich, vice presidente de los cortador de la carne y de los 
trabajadores unidos del carnicero de Norteamérica relacionó un 
ataque violento de la multitud conducido por los funcionarios de la 
compañía. José M. Jacobs, el consejo general de la unión, 
entonces discutido que el lenguaje en el acto de Taft-Hartley, que 
reguló relaciones de trabajo de la gerencia, no prohibiera a patrones
"inmunidad evidente" de la responsabilidad legal de la violencia de la
multitud contra representantes de trabajo a menos que la implicación 
directa podría ser probada. El acto de Taft-Hartley, pasado en 
1947 por un congreso Republicano-conducido sobre veto de presidente 
Harry S. Truman, enmendó las provisiones del acto 1935 de Wagner 
Jacobs discutido para la restauración del lenguaje del acto de 
Wagner. En septiembre de 1951, un mes después de esta 
audiencia, un examinador de ensayo para el consejo de relaciones del 
trabajo nacional sostuvo el Jewell Company obligado para instigar al 
alboroto descrito en la declaración.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086764</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103470</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/public-responsibilities-public-wrongs-union-officials-blame-the-taft-hartley-act-for-mob-antiunion-violence</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
