<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106051</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106051</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206452</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A Nation Repays Its Debt: The National Soldiers' Home and Cemetery in Dayton, Ohio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Nation Erstattet Seine Schuld Zurück: 
Der nationalen das Haus und Kirchhof Soldaten in Dayton, Ohio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une Nation Rembourse Sa Dette : La maison et
le cimetière des soldats nationaux à Dayton, Ohio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uma Nação Reembolsa Seu Débito: A HOME e 
cemetery dos soldados nacionais em Dayton, Ohio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Una Nazione Rimborsa Il Relativo Debito: La 
sede e cimitero dei soldati nazionali a Dayton, Ohio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα έθνος ξεπληρώνει το χρέος του: Η "Οικία" 
και το νεκροταφείο των εθνικών στρατιωτών στο Νταίυτον, Οχάιο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una Nación Compensa Su Deuda: El hogar y 
cementerio de los soldados nacionales en Dayton, Ohio</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">tells how the federal government created a network of soldiers' homes and national cemeteries to honor Civil War veterans. The 110-acre Dayton cemetery contains the remains of veterans from the Revolutionary War, the Civil War, the War of 1812, the Mexican War, the Spanish American War, and all 20th century military conflicts.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erklärt, wie die Bundesregierung ein Netz der 
Häuser und der nationalen Kirchhöfe der Soldaten erstellte, um 
Bürgerkriegveterane zu ehren. Der 110-acre Dayton Kirchhof 
enthält des Remains der Veterane vom revolutionären Krieg, der 
Bürgerkrieg, der Krieg von 1812, der mexikanische Krieg, der 
spanische amerikanische Krieg, und alles 20. Jahrhundertmilitär 
widerspricht.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dit que le gouvernement fédéral a créé un 
réseau des maisons et des cimetières nationaux des soldats pour 
honorer les anciens combattants civils. Le cimetière de 
110-acre Dayton contient les restes des vétérans de la guerre 
révolutionnaire, la guerre civile, la guerre de 1812, la guerre 
mexicaine, la guerre américaine espagnole, et tous les 20èmes 
militaires de siècle sont en conflit.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">diz como o governo federal criou uma rede de HOME 
e de cemeteries nacionais dos soldados para honrar veterans de guerra 
civil. O cemetery de 110-acre Dayton contem o remains dos 
veterans da guerra revolucionária, a guerra civil, a guerra de 1812, 
a guerra mexicana, a guerra americana espanhola, e todas as 20as 
forças armadas do século opõem.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">dice a come il governo federale ha creato una rete
delle sedi e dei cimiteri nazionali dei soldati per honor i veterani 
di guerra civile. Il cimitero di 110-acre Dayton contiene il 
remains dei veterani dalla guerra rivoluzionaria, la guerra civile, la
guerra di 1812, la guerra messicana, la guerra americana spagnola e 
tutti i ventesimi militari di secolo sono in conflitto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">λέει πώς η ομοσπονδιακή κυβέρνηση δημιούργησε ένα 
δίκτυο των εθνικών νεκροταφείων των στρατιωτών των σπιτιών και 
για να τιμήσει τους παλαιμάχους εμφύλιου πολέμου. Το 
νεκροταφείο του Νταίυτον 110-στρέμματος περιέχει τα υπολείμματα 
των παλαιμάχων από τον επαναστατικό πόλεμο, τον εμφύλιο πόλεμο, 
τον πόλεμο 1812, το μεξικάνικο πόλεμο, τον ισπανικό 
αμερικανικό πόλεμο, και όλες τις στρατιωτικές συγκρούσεις του 
20ού αιώνα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">dice cómo el gobierno federal creó una red de 
los hogares y de los cementerios nacionales de los soldados para 
honrar a veteranos de guerra civil. El cementerio de 110-acre 
Dayton contiene el restos de veteranos de la guerra revolucionaria, la
guerra civil, la guerra de 1812, la guerra mexicana, la guerra 
americana española, y todos los vigésimos militares del siglo están
en conflicto.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206452</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106051</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/a-nation-repays-its-debt-the-national-soldiers-home-and-cemetery-in-dayton-ohio</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
