<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107544</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107544</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086496</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Must a Fellow Wait to Die?": Workers Write to Frances Perkins</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"muß eine Mitwartezeit, sterben?": Arbeiter 
schreiben Frances Perkins</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"doit une attente de camarade mourir?" : Les 
ouvriers écrivent à Frances Perkins</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"deve uma espera do companheiro morrer?": Os 
trabalhadores escrevem a Frances Perkins</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"deve un'attesa del collega morire?": Gli 
operai scrivono a Frances Perkins</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Πρέπει ένας συνεργάτης να περιμένει να πεθάνει;": 
Οι εργαζόμενοι γράφουν στη Frances Perkins</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"debe una espera del compañero morir?": Los 
trabajadores escriben a Frances Perkins</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Silicosis, a deadly lung disease caused when workers inhale fine particles of silica dust--a mineral found in sand, quartz, and granite--became a national cause clbre during the Great Depression when it was recognized as a significant disease among lead, zinc, and silver miners, sandblasters, and foundry and tunnel workers. In 1938 the federal government declared silicosis America_s number one industrial health problem and Secretary of Labor Frances Perkins convened a National Silicosis Conference in Washington, D.C. Despite such attempts to deal with the silicosis crisis, workers continued to complain of their plight. Hundreds of letters were sent to federal officials from across the country. The three letters included here (sent to Secretary Perkins) attested to workers' desperation and to their confidence that the government would agree to investigate.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Silikose, eine tödliche Lungenkrankheit 
verursachte, wann Arbeiter Feinpartikel des Silikonstaubes -- ein 
Mineral gefunden im Sand, Quarz und Granit -- wurden ein nationales 
Ursache clbre während des großen Tiefstands inhalieren, als es als 
bedeutende Krankheit unter Leitung, Zink- und Silberergmänner, 
Sandstrahler und Gießerei- und Tunnelarbeiter erkannt wurde. In
1938 erklärte die Bundesregierung industrielles Problem Gesundheit 
der Silikose America_s Zahl eine und Minister fuer Arbeit Frances 
Perkins kam eine nationale Silikose-Konferenz in Washington, D.C. 
Despite solche Versuche, die Silikosekrise, die Arbeiter zu 
beschäftigen zusammen, die fortgesetzt wurden, um sich von ihrer Lage
zu beschweren. Den Bundesbeamten über vom Land Hunderte Briefe 
wurden geschickt. Die drei Zeichen schlossen (gesendet der 
Sekretärin Perkins) hier bezeugt zur Verzweiflung der Arbeiter und zu
ihrem Vertrauen ein, daß die Regierung damit einverstandenSEIN würde
nachzuforschen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La silicose, une affection pulmonaire mortelle a 
causé quand les ouvriers inhalent les particules fines de la 
poussière de silice -- un minerai trouvé en sable, quartz, et granit
-- sont devenus un clbre national de cause pendant la grande 
dépression quand on l'a identifié comme maladie significative parmi 
le fil de sortie, le zinc, et les mineurs argentés, les sableuses, et
les ouvriers de fonderie et de tunnel. Dans 1938 le gouvernement
fédéral a déclaré le problème de santé industriel du numéro un 
d'America_s de silicose et le secrétaire du travail Frances Perkins a
assemblé une conférence nationale de silicose à Washington, D.C. 
Despite de telles tentatives de traiter la crise de silicose, ouvriers
continués pour se plaindre de leur situation difficile. Des 
centaines de lettres ont été envoyées aux fonctionnaires fédéraux
de à travers le pays. Les trois lettres ont inclus ici (envoyé
à secrétaire Perkins) certifié au désespoir des ouvriers et à 
leur confiance que le gouvernement accepterait d'étudier.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O silicosis, uma doença de pulmão mortal causou 
quando os trabalhadores inhale partículas finas da poeira de silicone
-- um mineral encontrado na areia, o quartzo, e o granito -- se 
transformaram um clbre nacional da causa durante o depression grande 
quando se reconheceu como uma doença significativa entre a ligação,
o zinco, e os mineiros de prata, os sandblasters, e os trabalhadores 
do foundry e do túnel. Em 1938 o governo federal declarou o 
problema de saúde industrial do número um de America_s do silicosis 
e a secretária de trabalho Frances Perkins reuniu uma conferência 
nacional do silicosis em Washington, C.C. Apesar tais tentativas de 
tratar da crise do silicosis, trabalhadores continuados a queixar-se 
de seu plight. As centenas das letras foram emitidas aos 
oficiais federais através do país. As três letras incluíram 
aqui (emitido à secretária Perkins) atestado ao desperation dos 
trabalhadores e a sua confiança que o governo concordaria investigar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La silicosi, un'affezione polmonare mortale ha 
causato quando gli operai inalano le particelle fini della polvere di 
silicone -- un minerale trovato in sabbia, quarzo e granito -- si sono
transformati in in un clbre nazionale di causa durante la depressione 
grande quando è stato riconosciuto come malattia significativa fra 
cavo, zinco e minatori d'argento, sabbiatori ed operai del traforo e 
della fonderia. In 1938 il governo federale ha dichiarato il 
problema di salute industriale di numero uno di America_s di silicosi 
e la segretaria di Frances Di lavoro Perkins ha convocato un 
congresso nazionale di silicosi in Washington, D.C. Despite tali 
tentativi di occuparsi della crisi di silicosi, operai continuati per 
lamentarsi della loro situazione difficile. Le centinaia delle 
lettere sono state trasmesse ai funzionari federali attraverso dal 
paese. Le tre lettere hanno incluso qui (trasmesso alla 
segretaria Perkins) attestato a desperation degli operai ed alla loro 
riservatezza che il governo accosentirebbe per studiare.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η πυριτίαση, μια θανάσιμη ασθένεια πνευμόνων 
προκάλεσε πότε οι εργαζόμενοι εισπνέουν τα λεπτά μόρια της 
σκόνης πυριτίου -- ένα μετάλλευμα που βρίσκεται στην άμμο, το 
χαλαζία, και το γρανίτη -- έγιναν μια εθνική αιτία clbre κατά
τη διάρκεια της μεγάλης οικονομικής κρίσης όταν αναγνωρίστηκε ως
σημαντική ασθένεια μεταξύ του μολύβδου, του ψευδάργυρου, και των 
ασημένιων ανθρακωρύχων, sandblasters, και των εργαζομένων 
χυτηρίων και σηράγγων. Το 1938 η ομοσπονδιακή κυβέρνηση 
δήλωσε τον αριθμό America_s πυριτίασης ένα βιομηχανικό 
πρόβλημα υγείας και ο γραμματέας της εργασίας Frances 
Perkins συγκάλεσε μια εθνική διάσκεψη πυριτίασης στην 
Ουάσιγκτον, ΣΥΝΕΧΈΣ ΡΕΎΜΑ Παρά τέτοιες προσπάθειες να 
εξεταστεί η κρίση πυριτίασης, οι εργαζόμενοι συνέχισαν να 
παραπονιούνται για τη δύσκολη θέση τους. Οι εκατοντάδες των 
επιστολών στάλησαν στους ομοσπονδιακούς ανώτερους υπαλλήλους από
σε ολόκληρη τη χώρα. Οι τρεις επιστολές συμπεριλαμβανόμενες 
εδώ (σταλμένος στο γραμματέα Perkins) βεβαιωμένος στην 
απογοήτευση των εργαζομένων και στην εμπιστοσύνη τους που η 
κυβέρνηση θα συμφωνούσε να ερευνήσει.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La silicosis, una enfermedad de la pulmón mortal 
causó cuando los trabajadores inhalan partículas finas del polvo de 
silicona -- un mineral encontrado en arena, cuarzo, y granito -- 
hicieron un clbre nacional de la causa durante la gran depresión 
cuando fue reconocido como enfermedad significativa entre el terminal 
de componente, cinc, y los mineros de plata, los sandblasters, y los 
trabajadores de la fundición y del túnel. En 1938 el gobierno 
federal declaró problema de salud industrial del número uno de 
America_s de la silicosis y la secretaria del trabajo Frances Perkins 
convocó una conferencia nacional de la silicosis en Washington, D.C. 
Despite tales tentativas de ocuparse de la crisis de la silicosis, 
trabajadores continuados para quejarse de su apuro. Los 
centenares de letras fueron enviados a los funcionarios federales a 
través del país. Las tres cartas incluyeron aquí (enviado a 
la secretaria Perkins) atestiguado a la desesperación de los 
trabajadores y a su confianza que el gobierno acordaría investigar.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086496</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107544</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/must-a-fellow-wait-to-die-workers-write-to-frances-perkins</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
