<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103930</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103930</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212367</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Sun Spot Analysis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sonne-Punkt-Analyse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Analyse de Tache du Soleil</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Análise Do Ponto Do Sol</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Analisi Del Punto Del Sole</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανάλυση σημείων ήλιων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Análisis Del Punto Del Sol</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this activity, introductory students use Excel to graph monthly mean Greenwich sunspot numbers from 1749 to 2004 and perform a spectral analysis of the data using the free software program "Spectra". Short answer and thought questions related to the graphical data are asked throughout the assignment. On this Starting Point page, users can access information about the exercise's learning goals, context for use, teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment ideas, references and topics covered.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In dieser Aktivität übertrifft einleitender 
Kursteilnehmergebrauch, um Monatszeitschrift Mittelgreenwich 
Sunspotzahlen von 1749 bis 2004 graphisch darzustellen und eine 
spektrale Analyse der Daten mit dem freien Software-Programm 
"Spektren" durchzuführen. Kurze Antwort- und Gedankenfragen 
standen auf den graphischen Daten werden gefragt während der 
Anweisung in Verbindung. Auf dieser Ausgangspunktseite können 
Benutzer auf Informationen über die erlernenziele der Übung, Kontext
für Gebrauch-, die Unterrichtenumfaßten anmerkungen und Spitzen, 
Lehrmittel, Einschätzung Ideen, Referenzen und Themen zugreifen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cette activité, l'utilisation préliminaire 
d'étudiants excellent pour représenter graphiquement des nombres 
moyens de tache solaire de Greenwich de revue mensuelle de 1749 à 
2004 et pour exécuter une analyse spectrale des données en utilisant
le programme libre "spectres" de logiciel. Les questions courtes
de réponse et de pensée ont associé aux données graphiques sont 
demandées dans toute l'affectation. À cette page de point de 
départ, les utilisateurs peuvent accéder aux informations sur les 
buts d'étude de l'exercice, contexte pour les extrémités 
d'utilisation, d'enseignement les notes et, le matériel didactique, 
les idées d'évaluation, les références et les sujets couverts.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta atividade, o uso introdutório dos estudantes
excel para representar graficamente números médios do sunspot de 
Greenwich da revista mensal de 1749 a 2004 e para executar uma 
análise spectral dos dados usando o programa livre "spectra" do 
software. As perguntas curtas da resposta e do pensamento 
relacionaram-se aos dados gráficos são perguntadas durante todo a 
atribuição. Nesta página do ponto começar, os usuários 
podem alcançar a informação sobre os objetivos de aprendizagem do 
exercício, contexto para as pontas do uso, ensinar as notas e, os 
materiais de ensino, as idéias da avaliação, as referências e os 
tópicos cobertos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questa attività, l'uso introduttivo degli 
allievi eccelle per rappresentare graficamente i numeri medi di 
sunspot de Greenwich del mensile da 1749 a 2004 e per effettuare 
un'analisi spettrale dei dati usando il programma libero "spettri" del
software. Le domande corte di pensiero e di risposta si sono 
riferite ai dati grafici sono chieste a durante l'assegnazione. 
A questa pagina del punto di partenza, gli utenti possono 
accedere alle informazioni sugli obiettivi imparanti 
dell'esercitazione, contesto per le punte di istruzione, di uso note 
e, i materiali didattici, le idee di valutazione, i riferimenti ed i 
soggetti coperti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτήν την δραστηριότητα, οι εισαγωγικοί σπουδαστές 
χρησιμοποιούν Excel στους μηνιαίους μέσους όρους ηλιακής 
κηλίδας του Γκρήνουιτς γραφικών παραστάσεων από 1749 έως το 
2004 και εκτελούν μια φασματική ανάλυση των στοιχείων 
χρησιμοποιώντας το ελεύθερο πρόγραμμα λογισμικού "φάσματα". 
Η σύντομη απάντηση και οι σκεπτόμενες ερωτήσεις σχετικές με
τα γραφικά στοιχεία απαιτούνται σε όλη την ανάθεση. Σε 
αυτήν την σελίδα αφετηρίας, οι χρήστες μπορούν να έχουν 
πρόσβαση στις πληροφορίες για τους στόχους εκμάθησης της άσκησης,
πλαίσιο για τη χρήση, τις σημειώσεις και τις άκρες διδασκαλίας, 
τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, τις ιδέες αξιολόγησης, τις αναφορές και τα
θέματα που καλύπτονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta actividad, el uso introductorio de los 
estudiantes sobresale para representar números malos de la mancha 
solar gra'ficamente de Greenwich de la publicación mensual a partir 
de 1749 a 2004 y para realizar un análisis espectral de los datos 
usando el programa libre "espectros" del software. Las preguntas
cortas de la respuesta y del pensamiento se relacionaron con los datos
gráficos se piden a través de la asignación. En esta 
paginación del punto de partida, los utilizadores pueden tener acceso
a la información sobre las metas que aprenden del ejercicio, contexto
para las extremidades del uso, de la enseñanza las notas y, los 
materiales didácticos, las ideas del gravamen, las referencias y los 
asuntos cubiertos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ROBERT MACKAY
FN:ROBERT MACKAY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212367</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103930</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/sun-spot-analysis</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
