<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106608</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106608</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087141</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Trials of the Trail: African-American Cowboy Will Crittendon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Versuche der Spur: Afrikanisch-Amerikanischer
Cowboy-Wille Crittendon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Épreuves de la traînée : Volonté 
Afro-américaine Crittendon de Cowboy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Experimentações da fuga: Vontade 
Africano-Americana Crittendon Do Vaqueiro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Prove della traccia: Volontà 
Africano-Americana Crittendon Del Cowboy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δοκιμές του ίχνους: Αφρικανικός-αμερικανικά ο 
κάουμπου! Crittendon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ensayos del rastro: Voluntad 
Africano-Americana Crittendon Del Vaquero</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The cowboy of Western mythology rode the range during the heyday of the long cattle drives in the l860s and 1870s. Despite the individualism emphasized in myth, most cowhands were employees of Eastern and European capitalists who raised cattle as a corporate enterprise to serve a growing appetite for beef in the U.S. Cowboys were overworked hired hands who rode in freezing wind and rain or roasted in the Texas sun; searched for lost cattle; mended fences; ate monotonous and bad food; and suffered stampedes, quicksand, blizzards, floods, and drought. The work was hard, dangerous, and often lonely; pay averaged from $25 to $40 a month. Many became cowboys for lack of other job opportunities; one of every three cowboys was an African American or Mexican.   Black cowboy Will Crittendon recounted his experiences as a cowboy in Texas in this interview conducted by the Federal Writers Project in the 1930s.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Cowboy der westlichen Mythologie ritt die 
Strecke während der Blütezeit der langen Viehlaufwerke im l860s 
und im 1870s. trotz des Individualismus, der im Mythus hervorgehoben 
wurde, waren die meisten cowhands Angestellte von östlichem und 
europäische Kapitalisten, die Vieh als korporatives Unternehmen zum 
Serve ein wachsender Appetit an Rindfleisch in den VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Cowboys anhoben, waren überarbeitete angestellte Hände, die in 
einfrierenden Wind und in Regen ritten oder in der Texas Sonne 
gebraten; nach verlorenem Vieh gesucht; reparierte Zäune;
aß monotone und falsche Nahrung; und erlittene Anstürme,
Quicksand, Blizzarde, Fluten und Dürre. Die Arbeit war hart 
häufig einsam, gefährlich, und; Bezahlung berechnete von $25 
bis 0 $40 ein Monat. Viele wurden Cowboys für Mangel an anderen
Jobgelegenheiten; einer jeder drei Cowboys war ein afrikanisches
amerikanisches oder ein mexikanisch. Schwarzer Cowboy Wille 
Crittendon zählte seine Erfahrungen nach, wie ein Cowboy in Texas in 
diesem Interview, das mit den Bundesverfassern geleitet wird, in die 
dreißiger Jahre sich projizieren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le cowboy de la mythologie occidentale est monté 
l'intervalle pendant l'apogée des longs lecteurs de bétail dans 
le l860s et le 1870s. En dépit de l'individualisme souligné 
dans le mythe, la plupart des cowhands étaient des employés 
d'oriental et les capitalistes européens qui ont élevé des bétail 
comme entreprise de corporation au service un appétit croissant pour 
le boeuf dans les cowboys des ETATS-UNIS étaient des mains manuelles 
louées surchargées qui sont montés sous le vent et la pluie de 
congélation ou rôti dans le soleil du Texas ; recherché les 
bétail perdus ; barrières réparées ; a mangé de la 
nourriture monotone et gâtée ; et ruées souffertes, 
sable mouvant, tempêtes de neige, inondations, et sécheresse. Le 
travail était dur, dangereux, et souvent isolé ; le salaire a 
fait la moyenne de de $25 à $40 par mois. Beaucoup sont devenus
des cowboys par manque d'autres possibilités d'emploi ; un sur 
tous les trois cowboys était un américain africain ou mexicain. 
La volonté noire Crittendon de cowboy a raconté ses 
expériences comme un cowboy dans le Texas dans cette entrevue 
conduite par les auteurs fédéraux projettent dans les années 30.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O vaqueiro do mythology ocidental montou a escala 
durante o heyday das movimentações longas do gado no l860s e no 
1870s. apesar do individualism emfatizado no mito, a maioria de 
cowhands eram empregados de oriental e os capitalistas europeus que 
levantaram o gado como uma empresa incorporada para o saque um apetite
crescente para a carne nos vaqueiros de ESTADOS UNIDOS eram as mãos 
empregadas overworked que montaram no vento e na chuva se congelando 
ou roasted no sol de Texas; procurarado por gado perdido; 
cercas emendadas; comeu o alimento monotonous e mau; 
e stampedes sofridos, quicksand, blizzards, inundações, e 
seca. O trabalho era duro, perigoso, e frequentemente só; 
o pagamento calculou a média  de $25 a $40 um o mês. 
Muitos transformaram-se vaqueiros para a falta de outras 
oportunidades de trabalho; um de cada três vaqueiros era um 
americano africano ou mexicano. A vontade preta Crittendon do 
vaqueiro recounted suas experiências como um vaqueiro em Texas nesta 
entrevista conduzida pelos escritores federais se projeta nos 1930s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il cowboy della mitologia occidentale ha guidato 
la gamma durante il heyday degli azionamenti lunghi dei bestiami nel 
l860s e nel 1870s. malgrado il individualism dato risalto a nel mito, 
la maggior parte dei cowhands erano impiegati di orientale ed i 
capitalisti europei che hanno alzato i bestiami come un'impresa 
corporativa per servire un appetito crescente per rinforza nei 
cowboys degli STATI UNITI erano mani assunte sovraccariche che hanno 
guidato in vento e pioggia gelidi o arrostito nel sole del Texas; 
cercato i bestiami persi; recinzioni riparate; ha 
mangiato l'alimento monotono e difettoso; e fughe precipitose 
sofferte, quicksand, blizzards, inondazioni e siccità. Il 
lavoro era duro, pericoloso e spesso solo; la paga ha avuto una 
media di $25 - $40 un il mese. Molti sono diventato cowboys per 
mancanza di altre occasioni di lavoro; uno di ogni tre cowboys 
era un americano africano o messicano. La volontà nera 
Crittendon del cowboy ha raccontato le sue esperienze come un cowboy 
nel Texas in questa intervista condotta dai produttori federali si 
proietta nei 1930s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο κάουμπου! της δυτικής μυθολογίας οδήγησε τη σειρά 
κατά τη διάρκεια του απόγειου των μακροχρόνιων κινήσεων βοοειδών
στο l860s και 1870s. Παρά τον ατομικισμό που 
υπογραμμίστηκε στο μύθο, οι περισσότεροι cowhands ήταν 
υπάλληλοι των ανατολικών και ευρωπαϊκών κεφαλαιοκρατών που 
ανέθρεψαν τα βοοειδή δεδομένου ότι μια εταιρική επιχείρηση για 
να εξυπηρετήσει μια αυξανόμενη όρεξη για το βόειο κρέας στους 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΥΣ κάουμπου! ήταν καταπονημένα μισθωμένα χέρια που 
οδήγησαν στο πάγωμα του αέρα και της βροχής ή έψησαν στον ήλιο 
του Τέξας  αναζητημένος για τα χαμένα βοοειδή  
επιδιορθωμένες φραγές  έφαγε τα μονότονα και κακά 
τρόφιμα  και υποσμένες άτακτες φυγές, κινούμενη άμμος, 
χιονοθύελλες, πλημμύρες, και ξηρασία. Η εργασία ήταν 
σκληρή, επικίνδυνη, και συχνά μόνη  πληρώστε υπολογισμένος
κατά μέσο όρο από $25 έως $40 μηνιαίως. Πολλοί 
έγιναν κάουμπου! ελλείψει άλλων ευκαιριών εργασίας  ένας 
από κάθε τρεις κάουμπου! ήταν αφρικανικός ένας αμερικανικός ή 
μεξικάνικος. Ο μαύρος κάουμπου! Crittendon εξιστόρησε την
εμπειρία του ως κάουμπου! στο Τέξας σε αυτήν την συνέντευξη που 
πραγματοποιείται από το ομοσπονδιακό πρόγραμμα συγγραφέων στη 
δεκαετία του '30.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El vaquero de la mitología occidental montó el 
rango durante el apogeo de los mecanismos impulsores largos de los
ganados en el l860s y el 1870s. a pesar de el individualismo acentuado
en mito, la mayoría de los cowhands eran empleados de del este y los 
capitalistas europeos que criaron ganados como empresa corporativa al 
servicio un apetito cada vez mayor para la carne de vaca en los 
vaqueros de ESTADOS UNIDOS eran las manos empleadas con exceso de 
trabajo que montaron en viento y lluvia que congelaban o asado en el 
sol de Tejas; buscado para ganados perdidos; cercas 
reparadas; comió el alimento monótono y malo; y 
precipitaciones sufridas, arena movediza, ventiscas, inundaciones, y 
sequía. El trabajo era duro, peligroso, y a menudo solo; 
la paga hizo un promedio a partir del $25 a $40 por mes. 
Muchos hicieron vaqueros para la carencia de otras oportunidades
de trabajo; uno de cada tres vaqueros era un americano africano 
o mexicano. La voluntad negra Crittendon del vaquero contó de 
nuevo sus experiencias como un vaquero en Tejas en esta entrevista 
conducida por los programas de escritura federales proyecta en los 
años 30.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087141</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106608</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/trials-of-the-trail-african-american-cowboy-will-crittendon</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
