<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104326</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104326</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087505</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Congress Investigates the 1934 San Francisco Strike</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kongreß forscht den San Francisco Schlag 1934 
nach</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le congrès étudie la grève 1934 de San 
Francisco</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O congress investiga a batida 1934 do San 
Francisco</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il congresso studia il colpo 1934 de San 
Francisco</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το συνέδριο ερευνά την απεργία του Σαν Φρανσίσκο του 
1934</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El congreso investiga la huelga 1934 de San 
Francisco</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The nationwide labor upsurge of 1934 reached its peak in San Francisco. On May 9, 1934, leaders of the International Longshoremen's Association (ILA) called a strike of all West Coast dockworkers, demanding a wage scale, a "closed shop" (union membership as a requirement of employment), and union-administered hiring halls. A few days later seamen and teamsters joined the strike, effectively stopping all shipping from San Diego to Seattle. Enraged employers, backed by a sympathetic mayor and police chief, used every means available to open the waterfront and protect strikebreakers, whom they imported in large numbers. Working closely with local politicians and the press, the employers set out to convince the public that the strike was controlled by "Reds" intent on overthrowing the government. These scare tactics led to an investigation of employer actions by a Senate subcommittee.  Violations of Free Speech and Rights of Labor , the subcommittee's 1942 report, described the concerted efforts of the Industrial Association, the newspapers, and the San Francisco police to discredit the strike.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die allgemein Arbeitsaufwallung von 1934 erreichte
seine Spitze in San Francisco. Auf Mai 9, 1934, Führern der 
internationalen Verbindung der Longshoremens (ILA) genannt einen 
Schlag aller Westküste dockworkers, eine Lohnskala, einen 
"zugänglichen Computerraum" (Anschlußmitgliedschaft als Anforderung 
der Beschäftigung) und Anschluß-ausgeübte Einstellungssäle 
verlangend. Einige Tagspäter Matrosen und teamsters verbanden 
den Schlag und effektiv stoppten alles Verschiffen von San Diego nach 
Seattle. Die erzürnten Arbeitgeber, unterstützt von einem 
sympatischen Bürgermeister und von einem Polizeileiter, verwendeten 
jedes die Mittel, die, die Ufergegend zu öffnen und Streikbrecher
zu schützen vorhanden sind, die sie in große Zahlen importierten. 
Nah arbeitend mit lokalen Politikern und der Presse, legten die 
Arbeitgeber dar, um die Öffentlichkeit zu überzeugen, daß der 
Schlag durch "Rot" Absicht auf dem Besiegen der Regierung gesteuert 
wurde. Diese Schrecken Taktiken führten zu eine Untersuchung 
der Arbeitgebertätigkeiten durch eine Senatunterausschuß. 
Verletzungen der freien Rede und Rechte der Arbeit, der Report 
der Unterausschusses 1942, beschrieben die beratenen Bemühungen der 
industriellen Verbindung, der Zeitungen, und der San Francisco 
Polizei, den Schlag zu diskreditieren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La croissance de travail dans tout le pays de 1934
a atteint sa crête dans San Francisco. Sur 9 mai 1934, 
amorces de l'association des Travailleurs portuaires internationaux (ILA) 
appelée une grève de tous les dockworkers occidentaux de côte, 
exigeant une échelle des salaires, "un système fermé" (adhésion 
des syndicats comme condition d'emploi), et les bureaux d'embauchage 
union-gérés. Quelques de jours marins et teamsters plus tard 
ont joint la grève, arrêtant pertinemment toute l'expédition de San
Diego à Seattle. Les employeurs exaspérés, soutenus par un 
maire et un chef bien disposés de police, ont utilisé chaque des 
moyens disponibles pour ouvrir bord de mer et protéger les briseurs 
de grève, qu'ils ont importés dans de grands nombres. 
Travaillant étroitement avec les politiciens locaux et la 
presse, les employeurs se sont mis à convaincre le public que la 
grève a été contrôlée par l'intention de "rouges" sur renverser 
le gouvernement. Ces tactique d'alarme a mené à une recherche 
sur des actions d'employeur par un sous-comité de sénat. Les 
violations du discours libre et les droites du travail, l'état du 
sous-comité 1942, ont décrit les efforts concertés de l'association
industrielle, des journaux, et de la police de San Francisco de 
critiquer la grève.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O upsurge labor de âmbito nacional de 1934 
alcançou seu pico em San Francisco. Maio em 9, 1934, em 
líderes da associação dos longshoremen internacionais (ILA) chamada
uma batida de todos os dockworkers ocidentais da costa, exijindo uma 
escala de salário, "uma loja closed" (sociedade da união como uma 
exigência do emprego), e salões empregando união-administrados. 
Alguns dos dias seamen e teamsters mais tarde juntaram a batida,
parando eficazmente todo o transporte de San Diego a Seattle. Os
empregadores enraged, suportados por um mayor e por um chefe 
sympathetic das polícias, usaram cada os meios disponíveis para 
abrir o waterfront e para proteger os strikebreakers, quem importaram 
em números grandes. Trabalhando pròxima com políticos locais 
e a imprensa, os empregadores ajustaram-se para fora para convencer o 
público que a batida estêve controlada pela intenção dos 
"vermelhos" em overthrowing o governo. Estas táticas do scare 
conduziram a uma investigação de ações do empregador por uma 
subcomissão do senate. As violações do discurso livre e as 
direitas do trabalho, o relatório da subcomissão 1942, descreveram 
os esforços concerted da associação industrial, dos jornais, e das 
polícias do San Francisco desacreditar a batida.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'aumento di lavoro nazionale di 1934 ha 
raggiunto il relativo picco a San Francisco. Maggio su 9, 1934, 
sui capi dell'associazione dei longshoremen internazionali 
(ILA) chiamata un colpo di tutti i dockworkers ad ovest del litorale, 
esigente una scala di stipendio, "un negozio chiuso" (insieme dei 
membri del sindacato come requisito di occupazione) ed i corridoi 
assumenti unione-amministrati. Alcuni di giorni marinai e 
teamsters più successivamente hanno unito il colpo, arrestante 
efficacemente tutto il trasporto da San Diego a Seattle. I 
datori di lavoro enraged, sostenuti da un sindaco e da un capo 
simpatici della polizia, hanno usato ogni i mezzi disponibili aprire 
waterfront e proteggere i crumiri, quale hanno importato nei grandi 
numeri. Funzionando molto attentamente con i politici locali e 
la pressa, i datori di lavoro hanno precisato per convincere il 
pubblico che il colpo è stato gestito tramite l'intenzione "di colori
rossi" sul overthrowing il governo. Queste tattiche di spavento 
hanno condotto ad un'indagine sulle azioni del datore di lavoro da un 
sottocomitato del senato. Le violazioni di discorso libero ed i 
diritti del Lavoro, la relazione del sottocomitato 1942, hanno 
descritto gli sforzi concordati dell'associazione industriale, dei 
giornali e della polizia de San Francisco screditare il colpo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η σε εθνικό επίπεδο άνοδος εργασίας του 1934 
έφθασε στην αιχμή της στο Σαν Φρανσίσκο. Σε Μάιος 9 
..1934, οι ηγέτες της ένωσης των διεθνών λιμενεργατών (ILA) 
κάλεσαν μια απεργία όλων των dockworkers δυτικών ακτών, που 
απαιτεί μια κλίμακα αμοιβών, ένα "κλειστό κατάστημα" (ιδιότητα 
μέλους ένωσης ως απαίτηση της απασχόλησης), και τις 
ένωση-διεξαχθείσες αίθουσες μίσθωσης. Μερικές ημέρες 
αργότερα οι ναυτικοί και τα teamsters ένωσαν την απεργία, 
σταματώντας αποτελεσματικά όλα από το Σαν Ντιέγκο στο Σιάτλ. 
Οι εξοργισμένοι εργοδότες, που υποστηρίχτηκαν από έναν 
συμπονετικούς δήμαρχο και μια αστυνομία προϊστάμενος, χρησιμοποίησαν
κάθε μέσα διαθέσιμα για να ανοίξουν την προκυμαία και να 
προστατεύσουν strikebreakers, τα οποία εισήγαγαν στους μεγάλους
αριθμούς. Συνεργαμένος στενά με τους τοπικούς πολιτικούς 
και τον Τύπο, οι εργοδότες καθόρισαν να πείσουν το κοινό ότι η 
απεργία ελέγχθηκε από την πρόθεση "κοκκίνων" στη νίκη της 
κυβέρνησης. Αυτή η τακτική τρόμου οδήγησε σε μια έρευνα 
για τις ενέργειες εργοδοτών από μια υποεπιτροπή Συγκλήτου. 
Οι παραβιάσεις της ελεύθερης ομιλίας και τα δικαιώματα της 
εργασίας, η έκθεση του 1942 της υποεπιτροπής, περιέγραψαν τις 
κοινές προσπάθειες της βιομηχανικής ένωσης, των εφημερίδων, και 
της αστυνομίας του Σαν Φρανσίσκο για να δυσφημήσουν την απεργία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El aumento de trabajo a nivel nacional de 1934 
alcanzó su pico en San Francisco. 9 de mayo de 1934, 
arranques de cinta de la asociación de los estibadores 
internacionales (ILA) llamada una huelga de todos los dockworkers del 
oeste de la costa, exigiendo una escala de salario, un "departamento 
cerrado" (calidad de miembro de la unión como requisito del empleo), 
y pasillos que emplean unio'n-administrados. Algunos de los 
días marineros y teamsters más adelante ensamblaron la huelga, 
parando con eficacia todo el envío de San Diego a Seattle. Los 
patrones enfurecidos, movidos hacia atrás por un alcalde y un jefe 
comprensivos del policía, utilizaron cada los medios disponibles 
abrir la línea de costa y proteger a los rompehuelgas, a que 
importaron en números grandes. Trabajando de cerca con los 
políticos locales y la prensa, los patrones precisaron para convencer
al público de que la huelga fuera controlada por intento de los 
"rojos" en el derrocamiento del gobierno. Estas táctica del 
susto condujeron a una investigación de las acciones del patrón por 
un subcomité del senado. Las violaciones del discurso libre y 
las derechas del trabajo, el informe del subcomité 1942, describieron
los esfuerzos concertados de la asociación industrial, de los 
periódicos, y del policía de San Francisco de desacreditar la 
huelga.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087505</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104326</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/congress-investigates-the-1934-san-francisco-strike</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
