<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104162</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104162</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086726</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Philip Is Breathing Out Threatenings and Slaughter": Hetty Shepard's Fears about the Future of New England, 1675-77</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Philip atmet aus Threatenings und Gemetzel": 
Hetty Shepards Furcht über die Zukunft von Neu-England, 
1675-77</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Philip respire hors de Threatenings et 
d'abattage" : Craintes de Hetty Shepard au sujet du futur de la 
Nouvelle Angleterre, 1675-77</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Philip está respirando para fora de Threatenings
e de slaughter": Medos de Hetty Shepard sobre o futuro de Nova 
Inglaterra, 1675-77</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Philip sta respirando verso l'esterno 
Threatenings ed il macello": Timori di Hetty Shepard circa il 
futuro della Nuova Inghilterra, 1675-77</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Θ*Πχηληπ Is Breathing Out Threatenings και 
σφαγή": Φόβοι Shepard Hetty για το μέλλον της Νέας 
Αγγλίας, 1675-77</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Philip está respirando fuera de Threatenings y 
de matanza": Miedos de Hetty Shepard sobre el futuro de Nueva 
Inglaterra, 1675-77</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Hetty Shepard lived in late-17th century New England during the conflict known as King Philip's War, or Metacom's War. Her family lived in Rhode Island, where her diary begins, but they soon moved to Boston when a pan-Indian military offensive rolled back English settlements to within twelve miles of the Massachusetts capital. The war even reached within her household as her father contemplated service, and suspicion descended on their Indian servant, George. Her uncle Benjamin Church won great renown for his skill as an "Indian fighter" by matching the guerrilla tactics of the Native Americans. At the same time, Hetty was consumed with religious concerns, such as fear about her devotion. She and many others--ministers and laity alike--worried about the loss of the fierce piety characteristic of the first generation of Puritan settlers.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hetty Shepard lebte im late-17th Jahrhundert 
Neu-England während der $überschneidung, die als König Philips War 
bekannt ist, oder War. Her Metacoms Familie lebte in der Rhode-Insel, 
in der ihr Tagebuch anfängt, aber sie zogen bald nach Boston um, als 
eine Wanne-Indische militärische Offensive zurück englische 
Regelungen zu innerhalb zwölf Meilen des Massachusetts Kapitals 
rollte. Der Krieg erreichte sogar innerhalb ihres Haushalts als 
ihr Vater erwogener Service und des Misstrauens, das auf ihrem 
indischen Bediensteten, George abgestiegen wurde. Ihre Onkel 
Benjamin Kirche gewann großes Renommee für seine Fähigkeit 
als "indischer Kämpfer", indem sie die Bandenkämpfertaktiken der 
gebürtigen Amerikaner zusammenbrachte. Gleichzeitig wurde Hetty
mit frommen Interessen, wie Furcht über ihre Hingabe verbraucht. 
Sie und viele andere -- Minister und laity gleich -- gesorgt um 
den Verlust der heftigen Frömmigkeit charakteristisch vom ersten 
Erzeugung der puritanischen Siedleren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Hetty Shepard a vécu dans le siècle Nouvelle 
Angleterre de late-17th pendant le conflit connu sous le nom de guerre
de roi Philip, ou la guerre de Metacom. Sa famille a habité
dans île de Rhode, où son agenda commence, mais ils se sont bientôt 
déplacés à Boston quand une offensive militaire casserole-Indienne 
a roulé en arrière des règlements anglais à au-dessous de douze 
milles du capital du Massachusetts. La guerre a même atteint 
dans son ménage en tant que son service contemplé par père, et le 
soupçon est descendu sur leur domestique indien, George. 
Son église d'oncle Benjamin a gagné la grande renommée pour 
sa compétence comme "combattant indien" en appariant la tactique de 
guérillero des Américains indigènes. En même temps, Hetty a 
été consommé avec des soucis religieux, tels que la crainte 
concernant sa dévotion. Elle et beaucoup d'autres -- ministres 
et laïcs de même -- inquiétées de la perte de la piété 
féroce caractéristique de la génération des colons puritains.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Hetty Shepard viveu no século Nova Inglaterra de 
late-17th durante o conflito sabido como Guerra do rei Philip, ou a 
família de Guerra Ela de Metacom viveu no console de Rhode, onde seu 
diário começa, mas moveram-se logo para Boston quando uma ofensiva 
militar bandeja-pan-Indian rolou para trás estabelecimentos ingleses 
dentro de doze milhas do capital de Massachusetts. A guerra 
alcançou mesmo dentro de sua casa como seu serviço contemplado pai, 
e de suspeita descida em seu empregado indian, George. Sua 
igreja do tio Benjamin ganhou o renown grande para sua habilidade como
"um lutador indian" combinando as táticas do guerrilla dos americanos
nativos. Ao mesmo tempo, Hetty foi consumido com interesses 
religiosos, tais como o medo sobre sua devoção. Ela e muita 
outra -- ministros e laity igualmente -- preocupadas sobre a perda do 
piety feroz característico da primeira geração de settlers puritan.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Hetty Shepard ha vissuto nel secolo Nuova 
Inghilterra di late-17th durante il conflitto conosciuto come War del 
re Philip, o la famiglia della War. Her del Metacom ha vissuto in 
Rhode-isola, in cui il suo diario comincia, ma presto si sono mossi 
verso Boston quando un'offensiva militare vaschetta-Indiana ha 
rotolato indietro gli stabilimenti inglesi entro a dodici miglia del 
capitale del Massachusetts. La guerra persino ha raggiunto 
all'interno della sua famiglia come suo servizio contemplato padre e 
del sospetto disceso sul loro servo indiano, George. La sua 
chiesa dello zio Benjamin ha vinto il renown grande per la sua 
abilità come "combattente indiano" abbinando le tattiche del 
guerrigliero degli Americani natali. Allo stesso tempo, Hetty è 
stato consumato con le preoccupazioni religiose, quale timore circa la
sua devozione. Lei e molti altre -- ministro e laity egualmente 
-- preoccupate per la perdita del piety feroce caratteristico della 
prima generazione dei settlers puritan.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Hetty Shepard έζησε στον πρόσφατος-17$ο αιώνα 
Νέα Αγγλία κατά τη διάρκεια της σύγκρουσης γνωστής ως πόλεμος 
του Philip βασιλιάδων, ή τον πόλεμο Metacom. Η 
οικογένειά της έζησε στη Ρόδο, όπου το ημερολόγιό της αρχίζει,
αλλά κινήθηκαν σύντομα προς τη Βοστώνη όταν κύλησε πίσω μια 
παν-ινδική στρατιωτική επίθεση τις αγγλικές τακτοποιήσεις μέσα 
σε δώδεκα μίλια από το κεφάλαιο της Μασαχουσέτης. Ο 
πόλεμος που επιτεύχθηκε ακόμη και μέσα στην οικογένειά της ως 
πατέρας της συλλογίστηκε την υπηρεσία, και η υποψία κατέβηκε στον
ινδικό υπάλληλό τους, George. Ο θείος της Benjamin 
Church κέρδισε τη μεγάλη φήμη για την ικανότητά του ως 
"ινδικό μαχητή" με το ταίριασμα της τακτικής ανταρτών των 
εγγενών Αμερικανών. Συγχρόνως, Hetty καταναλώθηκε με τις 
θρησκευτικές ανησυχίες, όπως ο φόβος για την αφοσίωσή της. 
Αυτή και πολλές άλλες -- υπουργοί και laity ίδια -- 
ανησύχησαν για την απώλεια της άγριας ευσέβειας χαρακτηριστικής 
της πρώτης γενεάς των πουριτανών αποίκων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Hetty Shepard vivió en el siglo Nueva Inglaterra 
de late-17th durante el conflicto conocido como War de rey Philip, o 
la familia de War. Her de Metacom vivió en la Rhode-isla, en donde su
diario comienza, pero pronto se movieron a Boston cuando una ofensiva 
militar cacerola-India rodó detrás establecimientos ingleses a doce 
millas del capital de Massachusetts. La guerra incluso alcanzó 
dentro de su casa como su servicio comtemplado padre, y de la 
suspicacia descendida en su criado indio, George. Su iglesia de 
tío Benjamin ganó el gran renombre para su habilidad como 
"combatiente indio" correspondiendo con las táctica del guerrilla de 
los americanos nativos. En el mismo tiempo, Hetty fue consumido 
con preocupaciones religiosas, tales como miedo por su dedicación. 
Ella y muchos otras -- ministros y laity igualmente -- 
preocupadas de la pérdida de la piedad feroz característica de la 
primera generación de colonos puritan.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086726</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104162</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/philip-is-breathing-out-threatenings-and-slaughter-hetty-shepards-fears-about-the-future-of-new-england-1675-77</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
