<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108420</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108420</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973942</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Medicine Games: Fight Beriberi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Medizin-Spiele: Kampf Beriberi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jeux de Médecine : Combat Beriberi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogos Da Medicina: Luta Beriberi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giochi Della Medicina: Lotta Beriberi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παιχνίδια ιατρικής: Πάλη Beriberi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Juegos De la Medicina: Lucha Beriberi</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Play a game and find out about a Nobel Prize awarded discovery or work! Before the 20th century, no one had heard of vitamins. It was Christiaan Eijkman who first pointed out a substance in rice skin, which was later to be known as vitamin B1. For this, and for his new ways of investigating, as well as for the methods he used to control diseases caused by vitamin deficiency, Eijkman was awarded the 1929 Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spielen Sie ein Spiel und finden Sie über eine 
zugesprochene Entdeckung oder eine Arbeit des Nobelpreises heraus! 
Vor dem 20. Jahrhundert hatten niemand von Vitamine gehört. 
Es war Christiaan Eijkman, das zuerst eine Substanz in der 
Reishaut unterstrich, die später war, als Vitamin B1 bekannt. 
Für dieses und für seine neuen Methoden des Nachforschens, 
sowie für die Methoden pflegte er, die Krankheiten zu steuern, die 
durch Vitaminmangel verursacht wurden, wurde Eijkman den Nobelpreis 
1929 in der Physiologie oder in der Medizin zugesprochen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jouez un jeu et découvrez au sujet d'une 
découverte ou d'un travail attribuée de prix Nobel ! Avant le 
20ème siècle, personne n'avaient entendu parler des vitamines. 
C'était Christiaan Eijkman qui a précisé la première fois 
une substance dans la peau de riz, qui était plus tardive pour être 
connue comme vitamine B1. Pour ceci, et pour ses nouvelles voies
de l'investigation, comme pour les méthodes il avait l'habitude de 
contrôler les maladies provoquées par insuffisance de vitamine, 
Eijkman a été attribué le prix 1929 Nobel dans la physiologie ou la
médecine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogue um jogo e encontre-o para fora sobre uma 
descoberta ou um trabalho concedido do prêmio de nobel! Antes 
do 20o século, ninguém tinham-se ouvido das vitaminas. Era 
Christiaan Eijkman que indicou primeiramente uma substância na pele 
do arroz, que estava mais atrasada ser sabida como a vitamina B1. 
Para esta, e para suas maneiras novas de investigar, assim como 
para os métodos usou-se controlar as doenças causadas pela 
deficiência da vitamina, Eijkman foi concedido o prêmio 1929 de 
nobel no physiology ou na medicina.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gioc un gioco e scopra circa una scoperta o un 
lavoro ricevuta del premio Nobel! Prima del ventesimo secolo, 
nessuno avevano sentito parlare le vitamine. Era Christiaan 
Eijkman che in primo luogo ha precisato una sostanza nella pelle del 
riso, che era successivamente essere conosciuta come vitamina B1. 
Per questa e per i suoi nuovi modi di studio, come pure per i 
metodi ha usato gestire le malattie causate dalla mancanza della 
vitamina, Eijkman ha ricevuto il premio 1929 Nobel nella fisiologia o 
nella medicina.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παίξτε ένα παιχνίδι και ανακαλύψτε για μια 
απονεμημένη βραβείο ανακάλυψη ή μια εργασία Νόμπελ! Πριν 
από το 20ό αιώνα, κανένας είχε ακούσει για τις βιταμίνες. 
Ήταν Christiaan Eijkman που επισήμανε αρχικά μια ουσία
στο δέρμα ρυζιού, το οποίο επρόκειτο αργότερα να μαθευτεί ως 
βιταμίνη B1. Για αυτό, και για τους νέους τρόπους του, 
καθώς επίσης και για τις μεθόδους που χρησιμοποίησε για να 
ελέγξει τις ασθένειες που προκλήθηκαν από την ανεπάρκεια 
βιταμινών, Eijkman απονεμήθηκε το βραβείο Νόμπελ του 1929 
στη φυσιολογία ή την ιατρική.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Juegue un juego y descubra sobre un 
descubrimiento o un trabajo concedido del premio Nobel! Antes 
del vigésimo siglo, nadie habían oído hablar de las vitaminas. 
Era Christiaan Eijkman que primero precisó una sustancia en la 
piel del arroz, que era más adelante ser conocida como vitamina B1. 
Para esto, y para sus nuevas maneras de investigar, tan bien 
como para los métodos él controlaba las enfermedades causadas por 
deficiencia de la vitamina, Eijkman fue concedido el premio 1929 Nobel
en fisiología o medicina.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973942</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108420</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/medicine-games-fight-beriberi</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
