<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108371</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108371</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203343</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Inquiry into High Resolution Ice Core and Marine Sediment Records: Archives of Suborbital (Millennial) Oscillations in Climate</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Anfrage über hohen Zerlegung-Eis-Kern und 
Marinesediment-Sätze: Archive Suborbital (Millennial) der 
Pendelbewegungen in Klima</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Enquête dans le noyau de haute résolution de 
glace et les enregistrements marins de sédiment : Archives des 
oscillations (Millénaires) Suborbitales dans le climat</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Inquérito no núcleo de alta resolução do gelo 
e em registros marinhos do sedimento: Arquivos de oscilações 
de Suborbital (Millennial) no clima</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Inchiesta nel nucleo di alta risoluzione del 
ghiaccio e nei record marini del sedimento: Archivi delle 
oscillazioni di Suborbital (Millennial) nel clima</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Έρευνα στον πυρήνα πάγου υψηλού ψηφίσματος και τα 
θαλάσσια αρχεία ιζημάτων: Αρχεία των suborbital 
(χιλιετών) ταλαντώσεων στο κλίμα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Pregunta en base de alta resolución del hielo y 
expedientes marinas del sedimento: Archivos de las oscilaciones 
de Suborbital (Millennial) en clima</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Joint Oceanographic Institutions activity (PDF) provides questions related to interpreting paleoclimate (climate in the past) data. Questions inquire about characteristics that make sites favorable for paleoclimate records, locating sites using a map, finding patterns and correlations in the data, and implications for these records. Figures are provided to answer the questions and are from various sources that, in most cases, are hyperlinked to the original source.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese gemeinsame ozeanographische Anstalten 
Aktivität (pdf) liefert die Fragen, die auf der Deutung paleoclimate 
in Verbindung gestanden werden (Klima in der Vergangenheit) von von 
Daten. Fragen erkundigen sich nach Eigenschaften, die Sites 
vorteilhaft für paleoclimate Sätze bilden und Sites mit einer Karte 
lokalisieren und Muster und Wechselbeziehungen in den Daten finden, 
und Implikationen für diese Sätze. Abbildungen werden zur 
Verfügung gestellt, um die Fragen zu beantworten und sind von den 
verschiedenen Quellen, die in den meisten Fällen hyperlinked zur 
ursprünglichen Quelle sind.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette activité océanographique commune 
d'établissements (pdf) fournit des questions liées à interpréter 
des données du paleoclimate (climat dans le passé). Les 
questions s'enquièrent au sujet des caractéristiques qui rendent des
sites favorables pour des enregistrements de paleoclimate, localisant 
des sites en utilisant une carte, trouvant des configurations et des 
corrélations dans les données, et des implications pour ces 
enregistrements. Des figures sont fournies pour répondre aux 
questions et sont des diverses sources qui, dans la plupart des cas, 
sont hyperlinked à la source initiale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta atividade oceanographic comum das 
instituições (pdf) fornece as perguntas relacionadas a interpretar 
dados do paleoclimate (clima no passado). As perguntas inquirem 
sobre as características que fazem locais favoráveis para registros 
do paleoclimate, encontrando locais usando um mapa, encontrando testes
padrões e correlações nos dados, e as implicações para estes 
registros. As figuras são fornecidas para responder às 
perguntas e são das várias fontes que, em a maioria de casos, são 
hyperlinked à fonte original.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa attività oceanografica unita delle 
istituzioni (pdf) fornisce le domande relative ad interpretare i dati 
del paleoclimate (clima nel passato). Le domande domandano circa
le caratteristiche che rendono i luoghi favorevoli per i record del 
paleoclimate, individuando i luoghi usando un programma, trovando i 
modelli e le correlazioni nei dati e le implicazioni per questi 
record. Le figure sono fornite per rispondere alle domande e 
provengono dalle varie sorgenti che, nella maggior parte dei casi, 
sono hyperlinked alla sorgente originale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η κοινή ωκεανογραφική δραστηριότητα 
Οργάνων (PDF) παρέχει τις ερωτήσεις σχετικές με την 
ερμηνεία paleoclimate (κλίμα από μπροστά) των στοιχείων. 
Οι ερωτήσεις ερευνούν για τα χαρακτηριστικά που καθιστούν 
τις περιοχές ευνοϊκές για paleoclimate τα αρχεία, εντοπίζοντας
τις περιοχές χρησιμοποιώντας έναν χάρτη, βρίσκοντας τα πρότυπα 
και τους συσχετισμούς στα στοιχεία, και τις επιπτώσεις σε αυτά τα 
αρχεία. Οι αριθμοί παρέχονται για να απαντήσουν στις 
ερωτήσεις και είναι από τις διάφορες πηγές που, στις 
περισσότερες περιπτώσεις, είναι στην αρχική πηγή.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta actividad oceanográfica común de las 
instituciones (pdf) proporciona a las preguntas relacionadas con 
interpretar datos del paleoclimate (clima en el pasado). Las 
preguntas investigan sobre las características que hacen sitios 
favorables para los expedientes del paleoclimate, localizando sitios 
usando una correspondencia, encontrando modelos y correlaciones en los
datos, y las implicaciones para estos expedientes. Las figuras 
se proporcionan para contestar a las preguntas y son de las varias 
fuentes que, en la mayoría de los casos, son hyperlinked a la fuente 
original.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:KRISTEN ST. JOHN
FN:KRISTEN ST. JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MARK LECKIE
FN:MARK LECKIE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JOINT OCEANOGRAPHIC INSTITUTIONS; THE SCHOOL OF ROCK EXPEDITION
FN:JOINT OCEANOGRAPHIC INSTITUTIONS; THE SCHOOL OF ROCK EXPEDITION
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203343</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108371</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/inquiry-into-high-resolution-ice-core-and-marine-sediment-records-archives-of-suborbital-millennial-oscillations-in-climate</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
