<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108649</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108649</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086232</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Hello, Mama. We're makin' history."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Hallo, Mutter. Wir sind makin ' 
Geschichte."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Bonjour, Maman. Nous sommes makin 
'histoire."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Hello, Mama. Nós somos makin ' history."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Ciao, Mama. Siamo makin 'storia."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Γειάσου, μαμά. Είμαστεmakin "ιστορία."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Hola, Mama. Somos makin ' historia."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">When the United Automobile Workers won a six week sit-down strike in 1937 against General Motors, the largest corporation in the United States, a fever of organization and a sense of empowerment spread throughout working-class communities in the Northeast and Midwest. That year, 5 million workers took part in some kind of industrial action, and nearly 3 million joined a union. Denys Wortman's cartoon in the March 25, 1937  New York World-Telegram  captures the excitement and sense of power felt by many working men and working women when they participated in militant labor action.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Als die vereinigten Automobil-Arbeiter einen sechs Woche 
sit-down Schlag 1937 gegen General Motors, die größte Korporation in
den Vereinigten Staaten gewannen, ein Fieber der Organisation und eine
Richtung der Ermächtigung verbritten während der 
Arbeiterklassegemeinschaften im Nordosten und im Mittelwesten. 
Daß Jahr, 5 Million Arbeiter an irgendeiner Art 
gewerkschaftliche Kampfmassnahme und fast 3 an Million teilnahmen, 
verbanden einen Anschluß. Denys Wortmans Karikatur im März 25,
1937 New York Welt-Telegramm erfaßt die Aufregung und die Richtung 
der Energie geglaubt von vielen Funktion Männern und von Funktion 
Frauen, als sie an der militanten Arbeitstätigkeit teilnahmen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Quand les ouvriers unis d'automobile ont gagné une grève
sur le tas de six semaines en 1937 contre General Motors, la plus 
grande société aux Etats-Unis, une fièvre d'organisation et un sens
d'habilitation écarté dans toutes les communautés de classe 
ouvrière dans le nord-est et le Midwest. Qu'année, 5 millions 
d'ouvriers ont participé à un certain genre d'action industrielle, 
et à presque 3 millions a joint une union. Le dessin animé de 
Denys Wortman en 25 mars 1937 Monde-Télégramme de New York capture 
l'excitation et le sens de la puissance sentis par beaucoup d'ouvriers
et travailleuses actives quand ils ont participé à l'action de 
travail de militant.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quando os trabalhadores unidos do automóvel ganharam uma 
batida sit-down de seis semanas em 1937 de encontro a General Motors, 
o corporation o maior nos estados unidos, em uma febre da 
organização e em um sentido do empowerment espalhado durante todo 
comunidades do working-class no nordeste e no Midwest. Que ano, 
5 milhão trabalhadores fizeram exame da parte em algum tipo da ação
industrial, e de quase 3 milhões juntou uma união. O cartoon 
de Denys Wortman março no 25, 1937 Mundo-Telegrama de New York 
captura o excitamento e o sentido da potência sentidos por muitos 
homens de funcionamento e mulheres de funcionamento quando 
participaram na ação labor militant.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Quando gli operai uniti dell'automobile hanno vinto un 
colpo sit-down di sei settimane in 1937 contro General Motors, la più
grande società in unito Dichiara, una febbre 
dell'organizzazione e un senso di empowerment sparso durante le 
Comunità della classe operaia nel nordest e nel Midwest. Che 
anno, 5 milione operai hanno partecipato in certo genere di azione 
industriale e quasi 3 milioni ha unito un'unione. Il fumetto di 
Denys Wortman in 25 marzo 1937 Mondo-Telegramma de New York blocca 
l'eccitamento ed il senso di potenza ritenuti da molti uomini di 
funzionamento e donne lavorarici quando hanno partecipato all'azione 
di lavoro del militante.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Όταν οι ενωμένοι αυτοκινητικοί εργαζόμενοι κέρδισαν 
μια έξι εβδομάδα κάθομαι-κατεβάστε την απεργία το 1937 
ενάντια σε General Motors, τη μεγαλύτερη εταιρία στις 
Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες, έναν πυρετό της οργάνωσης και μια αίσθηση 
της ενδυνάμωσης που διαδίδεται σε όλες κοινότητα εργατικών 
τάξεων στα βορειοανατολικά και midwest. Εκείνο το έτος, 5
εκατομμύριο εργαζόμενοι συμμετείχαν στην κάποια βιομηχανική 
ενέργεια, και σχεδόν 3 εκατομμύρια ένωσαν μια ένωση. Τα 
κινούμενα σχέδια Wortman Denys τις 25 Μαρτίου 
κόσμος-τηλεγράφημα ..1937 Νέας Υόρκης συλλαμβάνουν τον 
ενθουσιασμό και την αίσθηση της δύναμης που γίνονται αισθητό από
πολλούς εργαζόμενους άνδρες και εργαζόμενες γυναίκες όταν 
συμμετείχαν στη στρατευμένη ενέργεια εργασίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cuando los trabajadores unidos del automóvil ganaron una 
huelga sit-down de seis semanas en 1937 contra General Motors, la 
corporación más grande de los Estados Unidos, una fiebre de la 
organización y un sentido del empowerment separado a través de 
comunidades de la clase obrera en el noreste y el Cercano oeste. 
Que año, 5 millones de trabajadores participaron en una cierta 
clase de acción industrial, y casi 3 millones ensambló una unión. 
La historieta de Denys Wortman en de marcha la 25 de 1937 
Mundo-Telegrama de Nueva York captura el entusiasmo y el sentido de la
potencia sentidos por muchos hombres de funcionamiento y mujeres de 
funcionamiento cuando participaron en la acción del trabajo del 
militante.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086232</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108649</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/hello-mama-were-makin-history</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
