<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106654</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106654</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213205</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">WISE - The Web-Based Inquiry Science Environment</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">KLUG - Die Web-Gegründete Anfrage-Wissenschaft 
Umgebung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">SAGE - l'Environnement de la Science d'Enquête De
Web-based</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">SÁBIO - O Ambiente Web-Baseado Da Ciência Do 
Inquérito</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">SAGGIO - L'Ambiente Web-Basato Di Scienza Di 
Inchiesta</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ΣΟΦΟΣ - το βασισμένο στο WEB περιβάλλον επιστήμης 
έρευνας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">SABIO - El Ambiente De la Ciencia De la Pregunta 
De Web-based</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Web-based Inquiry Science Environment (WISE) is a free on-line science learning environment for students in grades 4-12. In WISE, students work on exciting inquiry projects on topics such as genetically modified foods, earthquake prediction, and the deformed frogs mystery. Students learn about and respond to contemporary scientific controversies through designing, debating, and critiquing solutions, all via the internet. Curriculum projects are complete and ready to use in the classroom. The projects are designed to meet standards and complement existing science curricula. The Teacher Area lets instructors explore new projects and grade students' work on the web, as well as to collaborate with other teachers and researchers.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Web-gegründete Anfrage-Wissenschaft Umgebung 
(KLUG) ist eine freie Onlinewissenschaft erlernenumgebung für 
Kursteilnehmer in den Graden 4-12. In KLUGEM arbeiten 
Kursteilnehmer auf aufregenden Anfrageprojekten auf Themen wie 
genetisch geänderten Nahrungsmitteln, Erdbebenvorhersage und dem 
verformten Froschgeheimnis. Kursteilnehmer erlernen über und 
reagieren auf zeitgenössische wissenschaftliche Kontroversen durch 
das Konzipieren, das Debattieren und die critiquing Lösungen, alle 
über das Internet. Lehrplanprojekte sind komplett und 
betriebsbereit, im Klassenzimmer zu verwenden. Die Projekte sind
konzipiert, um Standards zu entsprechen und vorhandene Wissenschaft 
Lehrpläne ergäzunzen. Der Lehrer-Bereich läßt Ausbilder neue
Projekte und Arbeit der Gradkursteilnehmer über das Web, sowie 
erforschen, um mit anderen Lehrern und Forschern zusammenzuarbeiten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'environnement de la Science d'enquête de 
Web-based (SAGE) est un environnement d'étude de la science en 
ligne libre pour des étudiants dans les catégories 4-12. Dans 
SAGE, les étudiants travaillent sur des projets passionnants 
d'enquête sur des sujets tels que les nourritures génétiquement 
modifiées, la prévision de tremblement de terre, et le mystère 
déformé de grenouilles. Les étudiants se renseignent sur et 
répondent aux polémiques scientifiques contemporaines en concevant, 
la discussion, et les solutions critiquing, toutes par 
l'intermédiaire de l'Internet. Les projets de programme 
d'études sont complets et prêts à utiliser dans la salle de classe.
Les projets sont conçus pour répondre à des normes et pour 
compléter des programmes d'études existants de la science. La 
région de professeur laisse des instructeurs explorer de nouveaux 
projets et travail des étudiants de catégorie sur le Web, aussi bien
que pour collaborer avec d'autres professeurs et chercheurs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O ambiente Web-baseado da ciência do inquérito 
(SÁBIO) é um ambiente de aprendizagem da ciência em linha livre 
para estudantes nas classes 4-12. Em SÁBIO, os estudantes 
trabalham em projetos emocionantes do inquérito em tópicos tais como
alimentos genetically modificados, predição do terremoto, e o 
mistério deformado das râs. Os estudantes aprendem sobre e 
respondem às controvérsias científicas contemporary através do 
projeto, de debater, e das soluções critiquing, tudo através do 
Internet. Os projetos do curriculum estão completos e prontos 
para usar-se na sala de aula. Os projetos são projetados 
encontrar-se com padrões e complementar curricula existentes da 
ciência. A área do professor deixa instrutores explorar 
projetos novos e trabalho dos estudantes da classe no Web, as.well.as 
para collaborate com outros professores e investigadores.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'ambiente Web-basato di scienza di inchiesta 
(SAGGIO) è un ambiente imparante di scienza in linea libera per gli 
allievi nei gradi 4-12. In SAGGIO, gli allievi lavorano ai 
progetti emozionanti di inchiesta sui soggetti quali gli alimenti 
geneticamente modificati, la previsione di terremoto ed il mistero 
deforme delle rane. Gli allievi imparano circa e rispondono alle
polemiche scientifiche contemporanee attraverso la progettazione, 
dibattere e le soluzioni critiquing, tutte via il Internet. I 
progetti di programma di studi sono completi e aspettano per 
usare nell'aula. I progetti sono destinati per rispondere agli 
standard e complementare i programmi di studi attuali di scienza. 
La zona dell'insegnante lascia gli istruttori esplorare i nuovi 
progetti ed il lavoro degli allievi del grado sul Web, così come per 
collaborare con altri insegnanti e ricercatori.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το βασισμένο στο WEB περιβάλλον επιστήμης έρευνας 
(ΣΟΦΟ) είναι ένα ελεύθερο σε απευθείας σύνδεση μαθησιακό 
περιβάλλον επιστήμης για τους σπουδαστές στους βαθμούς 4-12. 
Σε ΣΟΦΟ, οι σπουδαστές εργάζονται στη διέγερση των 
προγραμμάτων έρευνας για τα θέματα όπως τα γενετικά 
τροποποιημένα τρόφιμα, η πρόβλεψη σεισμού, και το παραμορφωμένο 
μυστήριο βατράχων. Οι σπουδαστές μαθαίνουν για και 
αποκρίνονται στις σύγχρονες επιστημονικές διαμάχες μέσω του 
σχεδιασμού, της συζήτησης, και των critiquing λύσεων, όλες 
μέσω του Διαδικτύου. Τα προγράμματα προγράμματος σπουδών 
είναι πλήρη και αναμένουνε για να χρησιμοποιήσουν στην τάξη. 
Τα προγράμματα έχουν ως σκοπό να ανταποκριθούν στα πρότυπα 
και να συμπληρώσουν τα υπάρχοντα προγράμματα σπουδών επιστήμης. 
Η περιοχή δασκάλων αφήνει την εργασία εκπαιδευτικών να 
ερευνήσει τα νέα προγράμματα και των σπουδαστών βαθμού για τον 
Ιστό, καθώς επίσης και για να συνεργαστεί με άλλους δασκάλους 
και ερευνητές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El ambiente de la ciencia de la pregunta de 
Web-based (SABIO) es un ambiente que aprende de la ciencia en 
línea libre para los estudiantes en grados 4-12. En SABIO, los 
estudiantes trabajan en proyectos emocionantes de la pregunta sobre 
asuntos tales como alimentos genético modificados, predicción del 
terremoto, y el misterio deformido de las ranas. Los estudiantes
aprenden sobre y responden a las controversias científicas 
contemporáneas a través de diseñar, de discutir, y de las 
soluciones critiquing, todas vía el Internet. Los proyectos del
plan de estudios son completos y listos utilizar en la sala de clase. 
Los proyectos se diseñan para resolver estándares y para 
complementar planes de estudios existentes de la ciencia. El 
área del profesor deja a instructores explorar nuevos proyectos y el 
trabajo de los estudiantes del grado sobre el Web, así como para 
colaborar con otros profesores e investigadores.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213205</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106654</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/wise-the-web-based-inquiry-science-environment</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
