<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106267</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106267</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206763</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Smithsonian Source: Colonial America</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Smithsonian Quelle: Kolonialamerika</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Source Smithsonienne : l'Amérique 
Coloniale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fonte Smithsonian: América Colonial</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sorgente Smithsonian: L'America Coloniale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σμιθσονιτική πηγή: Αποικιακή Αμερική</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fuente Smithsonian: América Colonial</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">offers primary sources and tools for using them in the classroom. Watch an anthropologist examine skeletons for clues to daily life in Jamestown. Find lessons on the Boston Massacre, Stamp Act, patriot women, Pocahontas, and money. Use questions -- built around primary documents -- to explore the clashing views of revolutionary colonists and loyalist colonists. Examine the political, religious, economic, and social reasons for the Revolution.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Angebotprimärquellen und -hilfsmittel für das 
Verwenden sie im Klassenzimmer. Überwachen Sie einen 
Anthropologen, Skelette für Anhaltspunkte zur täglichen Lebensdauer 
in Jamestown zu überprüfen. Finden Sie Lektionen auf dem 
Boston Blutbad, der Stempel-Tat, den Patriotfrauen, dem Pocahontas und
dem Geld. Gebrauchfragen -- aufgebaut um Primärdokumente -- zum
der zusammenstoßenden Ansichten der revolutionären Kolonisten und 
der loyalist Kolonisten zu erforschen. Überprüfen Sie die 
politischen, frommen, ökonomischen und Sozialgründe für die 
Umdrehung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">sources primaires et outils d'offres pour l'usage 
d'elles dans la salle de classe. Observez un anthropologue 
examiner des squelettes pour des indices à la vie quotidienne dans 
Jamestown. Trouvez les leçons sur le Massacre de Boston, 
l'acte de timbre, les femmes de patriote, le Pocahontas, et l'argent. 
Questions d'utilisation -- établies autour des documents 
primaires -- pour explorer les vues s'opposantes des colons 
révolutionnaires et des colons loyalistes. Examinez les raisons
politiques, religieuses, économiques, et sociales de la révolution.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fontes preliminares e ferramentas das ofertas para
usá-los na sala de aula. Preste atenção a um antropólogo 
examinar os esqueletos para indícios à vida diária em Jamestown. 
Encontre lições no massacre de Boston, no ato do selo, nas 
mulheres do patriot, no Pocahontas, e no dinheiro. Perguntas do 
uso -- construídas em torno dos originais preliminares -- para 
explorar as opiniões clashing colonos revolucionários e colonos 
loyalist. Examine as razões políticas, religiosas, 
econômicas, e sociais para a volta.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">sorgenti primarie e strumenti di offerte per 
usando nell'aula. Guardi un antropologo esaminare gli scheletri 
per gli indizii a vita quotidiana in Jamestown. Trovi le lezioni
sul massacre de Boston, sulla Legge del bollo, sulle donne del 
patriot, sul Pocahontas e sui soldi. Domande di uso -- 
sviluppate intorno ai documenti primari -- per esplorare i punti di 
vista clashing dei colonizzatori rivoluzionari e dei colonizzatori 
loyalist. Esamini i motivi politici, religiosi, economici e 
sociali per la rivoluzione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">πηγές και εργαλεία προσφορών αρχικές για τους στην 
τάξη. Προσέξτε έναν ανθρωπολόγο εξετάζει τους σκελετούς 
για τις ενδείξεις στην καθημερινή ζωή σε Jamestown. 
Βρείτε τα μαθήματα στη σφαγή της Βοστώνης, το νόμο 
γραμματοσήμων, τις γυναίκες πατριωτών, το Pocahontas, και τα 
χρήματα. Ερωτήσεις χρήσης -- που χτίζονται γύρω από τα 
αρχικά έγγραφα -- για να ερευνήσει τις διαφωνώντας όψεις των 
επαναστατικών αποίκων και των αποίκων loyalist. Εξετάστε 
τους πολιτικούς, θρησκευτικούς, οικονομικούς, και κοινωνικούς 
λόγους για την επανάσταση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">fuentes primarias y herramientas de las ofertas 
para usarla en la sala de clase. Mire a antropólogo examinar 
los esqueletos para las pistas a la vida de cada día en Jamestown. 
Encuentre las lecciones en la Masacre de Boston, el acto del 
sello, las mujeres del patriota, el Pocahontas, y el dinero. 
Preguntas del uso -- construidas alrededor de documentos 
primarios -- para explorar las opiniones clashing colonos 
revolucionarios y colonos leales. Examine las razones 
políticas, religiosas, económicas, y sociales de la revolución.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206763</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106267</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/smithsonian-source-colonial-america</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
