<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104536</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104536</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206117</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Molecular Workbench Project</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Molekulares Werktisch-Projekt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Projet Moléculaire D'Établi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Projeto Molecular Da Bancada</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Progetto Molecolare Della Stazione di lavoro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μοριακό πρόγραμμα πάγκων εργασίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Proyecto Molecular Del Banco de trabajo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">offers tools for visualizing and computing the motion of atoms and molecules. See simulations of diffusion, dissolution, distillation, chemical reactions, chain reactions, equilibrium, catalysis, self-assembly, x-ray diffraction, light-matter interactions, DNA hybridization, nano machinery, Maxwell's law of speed distribution, Archimedes' principle of buoyancy, Pascal's principle, ideal gas laws, and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Angebothilfsmittel für das Sichtbar machen und 
das Berechnen der Bewegung der Atome und der Moleküle. Sehen 
Sie Simulationen der Diffusion (Zerstäubung), Auflösung, 
Destillation, chemische Reaktionen, Kettenreaktionen, Gleichgewicht, 
Katalyse, Selbst-Versammlung, Röntgenstrahlbeugung, Licht-Stoff 
Interaktionen, DNA Hybridation, nano Maschinerie, Gesetz des Maxwells 
Geschwindigkeit Verteilung, Grundregel Archimedes des Tragvermögens, 
der Grundregel des Pascal, der idealen Gasgesetze und mehr.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">outils d'offres pour visualiser et calculer le 
mouvement des atomes et des molécules. Voir les simulations de 
la diffusion, dissolution, distillation, réactions chimiques, 
réactions en chaîne, équilibre, la catalyse, art de l'auto-portrait-assembly, 
diffraction de rayon X, interactions de lumière-matière, hybridation
d'ADN, machines de nano, la loi du maxwell's de distribution de
vitesse, le principe d'Archimède de la flottabilité, du principe du 
Pascal, des lois idéales de gaz, et de plus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">ferramentas das ofertas para visualizar e computar
o movimento dos átomos e das moléculas. Veja simulações da 
difusão, dissolução, distillation, reações químicas, reações 
chain, equilíbrio, catalysis, self-conjunto, diffraction de raio X, 
interações da luz-matéria, hybridization do DNA, maquinaria do 
nano, lei do maxwell da distribuição da velocidade, princípio de 
Archimedes' do buoyancy, do princípio do Pascal, de leis ideais do 
gás, e de mais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">strumenti di offerte per prevedere e la 
computazione del movimento degli atomi e delle molecole. Veda le
simulazioni di diffusione, la dissoluzione, la distillazione, le 
reazioni chimiche, le reazioni a catena, l'equilibrio, la catalisi, il
auto-complessivo, la diffrazione di raggi X, le interazioni della 
luce-materia, l'ibridazione del DNA, il macchinario di nano, legge del
maxwell di distribuzione di velocità, principio del Archimedes di 
galleggiabilità, del principio del Pascal, delle leggi ideali del gas
e di più.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εργαλεία προσφορών για και την κίνηση των ατόμων και 
των μορίων. Δείτε τις προσομοιώσεις της διάχυσης, 
της διάλυσης, της απόσταξης, των χημικών αντιδράσεων, των 
αλυσιδωτών αντιδράσεων, της ισορροπίας, της κατάλυσης, της 
μόνος-συμβολικής γλώσσας, της των ακτίνων X διάθλασης, των 
αλληλεπιδράσεων ελαφρύς-θέματος, της υβριδοποίησης DNA, των 
νανο μηχανημάτων, του νόμου Maxwell της διανομής ταχύτητας, της
αρχής του Αρχιμήδη της πλευστότητας, της αρχής PASCAL, των 
ιδανικών αέριο νόμων, και περισσότεροι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">herramientas de las ofertas para visualizar y 
computar el movimiento de átomos y de moléculas. Vea las 
simulaciones de la difusión, disolución, destilación, reacciones 
químicas, reacciones en cadena, equilibrio, catálisis, uno 
mismo-ensamblaje, difracción de radiografía, interacciones de la 
luz-materia, hibridación de la DNA, maquinaria del nano, ley del 
maxwell de distribución de la velocidad, principio de Archimedes de 
la flotabilidad, del principio del PASCAL, de los leyes ideales del 
gas, y más.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206117</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104536</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/molecular-workbench-project</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
