<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103752</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103752</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1879158212</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Audio and Speaker Electronics</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Audio-und Lautsprecher-Elektronik</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'électronique d'acoustique et de haut-parleur</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Eletrônica do áudio e do altofalante</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Elettronica dell'altoparlante e dell'audio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ήχος και ηλεκτρονική ομιλητών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Electrónica del audio y del altavoz</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Take a hands-on ride through the fundamentals of electronics and acoustics, and the process of loudspeaker design and construction. Learn about the engineering and art involved throughout music/movie recording and playback, the design and application of everything from microphones to DACs, amplifiers, and speakers. With the aid of computer assisted audio measuring equipment at the MIT Edgerton Center, analyze the frequency response and distortion of speaker drivers, and understand their effect on what we hear. Design your own speakers - driver selection, crossover networks, and enclosure design - and build them in class!</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nehmen Sie eine Blindeinschub Fahrt durch die 
Grundlagen von Elektronik und von Akustik und den Prozeß des 
Lautsprecherdesigns und -aufbaus. Erlernen Sie über die Technik
und die kunst, die während der music/movie Aufnahme und Playback mit 
einbezogen werden, das Design und Anwendung von alles von Mikrophone 
zu DACs, Verstärker und Lautsprecher. Mit dem Hilfsmittel der 
Computer unterstützten messenden Audioausrüstung in der MIT Edgerton
Mitte, analysieren Sie den Frequenzgang und die Verzerrung der 
Lautsprechertreiber, und verstehen Sie ihren Effekt auf, was wir 
hören. Konzipieren Sie Ihre eigenen Lautsprecher - 
Treiberauswahl, Überkreuzungsnetze und Einschließung Design - und 
bauen Sie sie in der Kategorie auf!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Prenez un tour à commande manuelle par les 
principes fondamentaux de l'électronique et des acoustiques, et le 
processus de la conception et de la construction de haut-parleur. 
Renseignez-vous sur l'ingénierie et l'art impliqués dans tout 
l'enregistrement et le playback de music/movie, la conception et 
application de tout des microphones à DACs, à amplificateurs, et à 
haut-parleurs. À l'aide de l'appareillage de mesure sonore 
aidé par ordinateur au centre de MIT Edgerton, analysez la réponse 
en fr3quence et la déformation des gestionnaires de haut-parleur, et 
comprenez leur effet sur ce que nous entendons. Concevez vos 
propres haut-parleurs - sélection de gestionnaire, réseaux de 
croisement, et conception de rubrique de description - et 
construisez-les dans la classe !</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Faça exame de um passeio hands-on com os 
fundamentos da eletrônica e das acústicas, e do processo do projeto 
e da construção do loudspeaker. Aprenda sobre a engenharia e a
arte envolvidas durante todo a gravação e o playback de music/movie,
o projeto e aplicação de tudo dos microfones a DACs, a 
amplificadores, e a altofalantes. Com o dae (dispositivo 
automático de entrada) do equipamento de medição audio ajudado 
computador no centro do MIT Edgerton, analise a resposta de 
freqüência e a distorção de excitadores do altofalante, e 
compreenda seu efeito em o que nós nos ouvimos. Projete seus 
próprios altofalantes - seleção do excitador, redes do cruzamento, 
e projeto do cerco - e construa-os na classe!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Prenda un giro hands-on con i fondamenti di 
elettronica e dell'acustica ed il processo della progettazione e della
costruzione dell'altoparlante. Impari circa l'ingegneria e 
l'arte addette durante la registrazione e playback di music/film,
il disegno ed applicazione di tutto dai microfoni a DACs, agli 
amplificatori ed agli altoparlanti. Con l'aiuto di attrezzatura 
di misura audio aiutata calcolatore al centro del MIT Edgerton, 
analizzi la risposta di frequenza e la distorsione dei driver 
dell'altoparlante e capisca il loro effetto su che cosa ci sentiamo. 
Progetti i vostri propri altoparlanti - selezione del driver, 
reti dell'incrocio e disegno di recinzione - e costruiscali nel codice
categoria!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πάρτε έναν εμπράγματο γύρο μέσω των βασικών αρχών 
της ηλεκτρονικής και της ακουστικής, και τη διαδικασία του σχεδίου
και της κατασκευής μεγάφωνων. Μάθετε για την εφαρμοσμένη 
μηχανική και την τέχνη που περιλαμβάνονται σε όλη τη μουσική/την 
καταγραφή και την ακρόαση κινηματογράφων, το σχέδιο και την 
εφαρμογή όλων από τα μικρόφωνα σε DACs, τους ενισχυτές, και 
τους ομιλητές. Με την ενίσχυση των με υπολογιστή ηχητικών 
οργάνων μέτρησης στο κέντρο MIT Edgerton, αναλύστε την 
απάντηση συχνότητας και τη διαστρέβλωση των οδηγών ομιλητών, και 
καταλάβετε την επίδρασή τους σε αυτό που ακούμε. Σχεδιάστε
τους ομιλητές σας - επιλογή οδηγών, δίκτυα διασταυρώσεων, και 
σχέδιο περιφράξεων - και τους χτίστε στην κλάση!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Tome un paseo con manos con los fundamentales de 
la electrónica y de la acústica, y el proceso del diseño y de la 
construcción del altavoz. Aprenda sobre la ingeniería y el 
arte implicados a través de la grabación y aparato de lectura de 
music/movie, el diseño y aplicación de todo de los micrófonos a 
DACs, a los amplificadores, y a los altavoces. Con la ayuda del 
equipo que mide audio asistido ordenador en el centro del MIT 
Edgerton, analice la respuesta de frecuencia y la distorsión de los 
programas pilotos del altavoz, y entienda su efecto sobre lo que 
oímos. ¡Diseñe sus propios altavoces - selección del programa
piloto, redes de la cruce, y diseño del recinto - y constrúyalos en 
clase!</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PRICE, MICHAEL
FN:PRICE, MICHAEL
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1879158212</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103752</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/audio-and-speaker-electronics</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
