<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107461</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107461</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205928</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">First Person Narratives of the American South, 1860-1920</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erste Person-Darstellungen des amerikanischen 
Südens, 1860-1920</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Premiers récits de personne des Sud 
américains, 1860-1920</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Primeiras narrativas da pessoa do sul americano, 
1860-1920</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Prime descrizioni della persona del sud americano,
1860-1920</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πρώτα αφηγήματα προσώπων του αμερικανικού νότου, 
1860-1920</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Primeras narrativas de la persona del sur 
americano, 1860-1920</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">documents the culture of the 19th century American South from the viewpoint of Southerners. It includes diaries, autobiographies, memoirs, ex-slave narratives, and travel accounts of women, African Americans, enlisted men, Native Americans, laborers, and prominent individuals. The site features 140 titles, including some published before 1860.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">dokumentiert die Kultur des 19. Jahrhundert 
amerikanischen Südens von der Veranschaulichung von Southerners. 
Es schließt Tagebücher, Autobiographien, Abhandlungen, 
Exsklave Darstellungen und Spielraumkonten der Frauen, der 
afrikanischen Amerikaner, der eingetragenen Männer, der gebürtigen 
Amerikaner, der Arbeiter und der vorstehenden Einzelpersonen ein. 
Die Situationsmerkmale 140 Namen, einschließlich einiges 
veröffentlicht vor 1860.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">documente la culture des Sud américains 
du 19ème siècle du point de vue des Habitants du sud. Il inclut 
des agendas, des autobiographies, des mémoires, des récits 
d'ex-slave, et des comptes de voyage des femmes, des Américains 
africains, des hommes enrôlés, des Américains indigènes, des 
travailleurs, et des individus en avant. Les dispositifs de site
140 titres, y compris certains édités avant 1860.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">documenta a cultura do sul americano do 1ø 
século do viewpoint de Southerners. Inclui diários, 
autobiographies, memoirs, narrativas do ex-escravo, e clientes do 
curso das mulheres, de americanos africanos, de homens alistados, de 
americanos nativos, de laborers, e de indivíduos proeminentes. 
As características de local 140 títulos, including algum 
publicado antes de 1860.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">documenta la coltura del sud americano di 
diciannovesimo secolo dal punto di vista di Southerners. Include
i diari, i autobiographies, le memorie, le descrizioni dello 
ex-schiavo ed i clienti di corsa delle donne, degli Americani 
africani, degli uomini arruolati, degli Americani natali, dei 
lavoratori e degli individui prominenti. Le caratteristiche di 
luogo 140 titoli, compreso alcuno pubblicato prima di 1860.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">τεκμηριώνει τον πολιτισμό του αμερικανικού νότου του 
19$ου αιώνα από την άποψη των νοτίων. Περιλαμβάνει τα 
ημερολόγια, τις αυτοβιογραφίες, τα απομνημονεύματα, τα αφηγήματα 
πρώην-σκλάβων, και τους απολογισμούς ταξιδιού των γυναικών, 
αφρικανικών Αμερικανών, των στρατολογημένων ανδρών, εγγενών 
Αμερικανών, των laborers, και των προεξεχόντων ατόμων. Η 
περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει 140 τίτλους, συμπεριλαμβανομένων μερικών 
που δημοσιεύονται πριν από 1860.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">documenta la cultura del sur americano del 
diecinueveavo siglo del punto de vista de Southerners. Incluye 
los diarios, las autobiografías, las memorias, las narrativas del 
ex-esclavo, y las cuentas del recorrido de mujeres, de americanos 
africanos, de hombres alistados, de americanos nativos, de 
trabajadores, y de individuos prominentes. Las características 
de sitio 140 títulos, incluyendo alguno publicado antes de 1860.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205928</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107461</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/first-person-narratives-of-the-american-south-1860-1920</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
