<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103590</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103590</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204319</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">To Kill A Mockingbird role-play: A Maycomb pig pickin'</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zum Abbruch spielen eine Spottdrossel Rolle: 
Ein Maycomb Schwein pickin '</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">À la mise à mort un moqueur jouent un rôle : 
Un pickin de porc de Maycomb '</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">À matança um mockingbird role-play: Um 
pickin do porco de Maycomb '</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">All'uccisione un mockingbird si atteggia: Un 
pickin del maiale di Maycomb '</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Για να σκοτώσει ένα ρόλος-παιχνίδι Mockingbird: 
Ένας χοίρος Maycomb pickin "</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">A la matanza un mockingbird actúa en papel: 
Un pickin del cerdo de Maycomb '</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Somewhere near the middle of reading the novel, students start to become confused about characters. This fun role-play activity works especially well just after Chapter 21 and allows students to get to know characters beyond Jem and Scout. It also can be a springboard into further discussions of point of view, theme, and stereotypes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Irgendwo nahe der Mitte des Ablesens des Romans, 
Kursteilnehmeranfang, um über Zeichen konfus zu werden. Dieser 
Spaß spielen Aktivität Arbeiten besonders gut gleich nach Kapitel 21
Rolle und erlauben Kursteilnehmern zu erhalten, Zeichen über Jem 
hinaus zu kennen und zu kundschaften. Es kann ein Sprungbrett
in weitere Diskussionen über Gesichtspunkt, Thema und Stereotypen 
auch sein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Quelque part près du milieu de lire le roman, 
début d'étudiants pour devenir confus au sujet des caractères. 
Cet amusement jouent un rôle des travaux d'activité 
spécialement bien juste aprés le chapitre 21 et permettent à des 
étudiants de connaître des caractères au delà de Jem et pour 
surveiller. Ce peut également être un tremplin dans d'autres 
discussions de point de vue, de thème, et de stéréotypes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em algum lugar perto do meio de ler a novela, 
começo dos estudantes para tornar-se confused sobre caráteres. 
Este divertimento role-play trabalhos da atividade especial bem 
imediatamente depois do capítulo 21 e permite que os estudantes 
comecem saber caráteres além de Jem e scout. Também pode ser 
um trampolim em umas discussões mais adicionais do ponto da vista, do
tema, e dos stereotypes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In qualche luogo vicino alla metà di lettura del 
romanzo, inizio degli allievi per essere confuso circa i caratteri. 
Questo divertimento si atteggia specialmente bene impianti di 
attività subito dopo il capitolo 21 e che permette che gli allievi 
ottengano conoscere i caratteri oltre Jem ed esplorare. Anche 
può essere uno springboard in ulteriori discussioni sul punto di 
vista, sul tema e sugli stereotipi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κάπου κοντά στη μέση της ανάγνωσης του 
μυθιστορήματος, οι σπουδαστές αρχίζουν να γίνονται ταραγμένοι για
τους χαρακτήρες. Αυτή η δραστηριότητα ρόλος-παιχνιδιού 
διασκέδασης λειτουργεί ιδιαίτερα καλά αμέσως μετά από το 
κεφάλαιο 21 και επιτρέπει στους σπουδαστές για να γνωρίσει να 
ξέρει τους χαρακτήρες πέρα από Jem και την ανίχνευση. 
Μπορεί επίσης να είναι μια αφετηρία στις περαιτέρω 
συζητήσεις της άποψης, του θέματος, και των στερεοτύπων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En alguna parte cerca del centro de leer la novela,
comienzo de los estudiantes para llegar a ser confuso sobre 
caracteres. Esta diversión actúa en papel los trabajos de la 
actividad especialmente bien enseguida después del capítulo 21 y 
permite que los estudiantes consigan saber caracteres más allá de 
Jem y explorar. También puede ser un trampolín en otras 
discusiones del punto de vista, del tema, y de estereotipos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:DAVID ANSBACHER
FN:DAVID ANSBACHER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204319</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103590</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/to-kill-a-mockingbird-role-play-a-maycomb-pig-pickin</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
