<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102860</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102860</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087445</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Born in Sin, Nurtured in Crime": The Children of New York City's Notorious Five Points, 1854</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"getragen in der Sünde, ernährt im Verbrechen": 
Die Kinder notorischer fünf Punkte der New York Stadt, 1854</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"soutenu dans le péché, consolidé dans le crime"
: Les enfants points notoires de la ville de New York des cinq, 
1854</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"carregado no sin, nurtured no crime": As 
crianças pontos notorious da cidade de New York dos cinco, 1854</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"sopportato nel sin, consolidato nel crimine": 
I bambini punti rinomati della città de New York dei cinque, 
1854</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Γεννημένος στην αμαρτία, που παγιοποιείται στο 
έγκλημα": Τα παιδιά πασίγνωστων πέντε σημείων της πόλης 
της Νέας Υόρκης, 1854</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"llevado en el pecado, consolidado en crimen": 
Los niños puntas notorias de la ciudad de Nueva York de las 
cinco, 1854</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Five Points was a notorious mid-nineteenth century New York City slum. Located just east of the fashionable stores, columned banks, and well-dressed crowds of Broadway, its squalor served to remind New Yorkers of the destitution that so closely underlay the city's surging wealth. The neighborhood included the infamous "Old Brewery," which had once been a real brewery but by mid-century had degenerated into a miserable tenement dwelling for the very poor. In the early 1850s the New York Ladies Home Missionary Society of the Methodist Episcopal Church purchased the "Old Brewery," demolished it, and built a mission on the site. The women of the Home Missionary Society made children their first concern, as, increasingly, did many other reformers of this period. While in this selection these Protestant missionary women showcase the children's gratitude, many Irish-Catholic immigrant families resented the missionaries' assumption of superiority and regarded their proselytizing as antagonistic to their own desire to pass on their religious beliefs to their children.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die fünf Punkte waren ein notorisches 
mittler-19.jahrhundert New York City Elendsviertel. Gefunden 
gerade östlich der modernen Speicher, columned Bänke und 
gut-kleidete die Massen von Broadway, sein Squalor gedient, um neues 
Yorkers an die Bedürftigkeit zu erinnern, die so nah der schwankenden
Fülle der Stadt zugrunde lag. Die Nachbarschaft enthielt die 
unbeliebte "alte Brauerei,", die einmal eine reale Brauerei aber 
gewesen war, bis zum Mid-century war degeneriert in eine miserable 
Wohnungwohnung für das sehr schlechte. Im frühen 1850s kaufte 
die New York Dame-Hauptmissionarsgesellschaft der methodistischen 
episkopalen Kirche die "alte Brauerei," demolierte sie und baute eine 
Mission auf der Site auf. Die Frauen der 
Hauptmissionarsgesellschaft, die Kinder ihr erstes Interesse, AS 
gebildet wurde taten in zunehmendem Maße viele andere Reformer 
dieser Periode. Während in dieser Auswahl diese protestierenden
Missionarsfrauen die Dankbarkeit der Kinder zur Schau stellen, nahmen 
viele Irisch-Katholische einwandernde Familien die Annahme der 
Missionare der Überlegenheit übel und betrachteten ihr proselytizing
als entgegenwirkend zu ihrem eigenen Wunsch, ihren frommen Glauben an 
ihre Kinder weiterzuleiten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les cinq points étaient mi-dix-neuvième taudis 
notoire de New York City de siècle. Situé juste à l'est des 
mémoires à la mode, des banques à colonnes, et des foules 
bien-habillées de Broadway, sa misère noire a servi à rappeler 
nouveau Yorkers le dénuement qui était à la base tellement 
étroitement de la richesse d'augmentation de la ville. Le 
voisinage a inclus la "vieille brasserie infâme," qui avait par le 
passé été une vraie brasserie mais par la moitié du siècle 
s'était dégénéré dans un logement malheureux d'appartement pour 
très le pauvre. Dans le 1850s tôt la société à la maison de
missionnaire de dames de New York de l'église épiscopale méthodiste
a acheté la "vieille brasserie," l'a démolie, et a établi une 
mission sur le site. Les femmes de la société à la maison de 
missionnaire faite des enfants leur premier souci, as, de plus en 
plus, ont fait beaucoup d'autres réformateurs de cette période. 
Tandis que dans cette sélection ces femmes protestantes de 
missionnaire présentent la gratitude des enfants, beaucoup de 
familles immigrées Irlandais-Catholiques étaient offensées par 
l'acceptation des missionnaires de la supériorité et ont considéré
leur convertir comme antagonique à leur propre désir de transmettre 
leur croyance religieuse à leurs enfants.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os cinco pontos eram um mid-décimo nono slum 
notorious de New York City do século. Localizado apenas leste 
das lojas fashionable, columned bancos, e bem-vestiu as multidões de 
Broadway, seu squalor servidas lembrar Yorkers novo do destitution que
underlay assim pròxima a riqueza surging da cidade. A 
vizinhança incluiu "o brewery velho infamous," que tinha sido uma vez
um brewery real mas pelo mid-century degenerated em uma moradia 
miserável do tenement para o muito deficiente. No 1850s 
adiantado a sociedade home do missionário das senhoras de New York da
igreja episcopal methodist comprou "o brewery velho," demolished o, e 
construiu uma missão no local. As mulheres da sociedade home do
missionário feita crianças seu primeiro interesse, as, cada vez 
mais, fizeram muitos outros reformers deste período. Quando 
nesta seleção estas mulheres protestant do missionário showcase a 
gratitude das crianças, muitas famílias immigrant 
Irish-irish-Catholic ressentiram-se pela suposição dos missionários
do superiority e consideraram-se seu proselytizing como antagonistic a
seu próprio desejo passar sobre sua opinião religiosa a suas 
crianças.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I cinque punti erano metà di-diciannovesimo slum 
rinomato de New York City di secolo. Individuato appena ad est 
dei depositi alla moda, columned la banca e bene-avuto vestito 
le folle di Broadway, il relativo squalor servite per ricordare a 
nuovo Yorkers del destitution che ha stato alla base così molto 
attentamente della ricchezza agitata della città. La vicinanza 
ha incluso "la vecchia fabbrica di birra malfamata," che era stata una
volta una fabbrica di birra reale ma entro la metà del secolo aveva 
degenerato in una dimora misera dell'appartamento per il povero 
stesso. Nel 1850s iniziale la società domestica di Missionario 
delle signore de New York della chiesa episcopal methodist ha comprato
"la vecchia fabbrica di birra," la ha demolita ed ha sviluppato una 
missione sul luogo. Le donne della società domestica di 
Missionario resa a bambini la loro prima preoccupazione, asse, sempre 
più, hanno fatto molti altri reformers di questo periodo. 
Mentre in questa selezione queste donne protestanti di 
missionario montrano il ringraziamento dei bambini, molte 
famiglie immigrate Irlandese-Cattoliche si sono risentite presupposto 
di missionari 'di superiorità ed hanno considerare loro 
proselytizing antagonistico al loro proprio desiderio passare sopra la
loro credenza religiosa ai loro bambini.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα πέντε σημεία ήταν μια πασίγνωστη τρώγλη πόλεων 
της Νέας Υόρκης του μέσος-δέκατου έννατου αιώνα. Η 
τοποθετημένη ακριβώς ανατολή των μοντέρνων καταστημάτων, των 
περίστυλων τραπεζών, και των καλά-ντυμένων πληθών Broadway, το
squalor της χρησίμευσε να υπενθυμίσει σε Νεοϋρκέζους την 
ένδεια που τόσο πολύ κρύφτηκε κάτω από τον ξεχυμένος σαν 
θάλασσα πλούτο της πόλης. Η γειτονιά περιέλαβε το κακόφημο
"παλαιό ζυθοποιείο," που ήταν μιά φορά ένα πραγματικό 
ζυθοποιείο αλλά μέχρι mid-century είχε εκφυλιστεί σε μια 
άθλια κατοικία κατοικιών για πολύ το φτωχό. Στο πρόωρο 
1850s η ιεραποστολική κοινωνία γυναικείων "Οικιαών της Νέας 
Υόρκης της μεθοδιστούς επισκοπικής εκκλησίας αγόρασε το" παλαιό 
ζυθοποιείο, "το κατεδάφισε, και στηρίχτηκε μια αποστολή στην 
περιοχή. Οι γυναίκες της ιεραποστολικής κοινωνίας "Οικιαών 
που γίνεται τα παιδιά την πρώτη ανησυχία τους, όπως, όλο και 
περισσότερο, έκανε πολλούς άλλους μεταρρυθμιστές αυτής της 
περιόδου. Ενώ σε αυτήν την επιλογή αυτές οι προτεσταντικές
ιεραποστολικές γυναίκες επιδεικνύουν την ευγνωμοσύνη των παιδιών,
πολλές ιρλανδικός-καθολικές που έχουν μεταναστεύσει οικογένειες 
αγανάκτησαν με την υπόθεση των ιεραποστόλων της ανωτερότητας και 
θεώρησαν το προσυλητισμό τους όπως ανταγωνιστικό στην επιθυμία 
τους να δώσουν τις θρησκευτικές πεποιθήσεις τους στα παιδιά τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las cinco puntas eran mediados de-diecinueveavo 
tugurios notorios de New York City del siglo. Localizado apenas 
al este de los almacenes de moda, columned las baterías, y 
bien-vistio' a muchedumbres de Broadway, su mugre servidas para 
recordar Yorkers nuevo la destitución que fue la base tan de cerca de
la abundancia que se aflojaba de la ciudad. La vecindad incluyó
la "vieja cervecería infame," que había sido una vez una cervecería
verdadera pero por mediados de siglo había degenerado en una vivienda
desgraciada de la vivienda para el muy pobre. En el 1850s 
temprano la sociedad casera del misionario de las señoras de Nueva 
York de la iglesia episcopal methodist compró la "vieja cervecería,"
la demolió, y construyó una misión en el sitio. Las mujeres 
de la sociedad casera del misionario hecha los niños su primera 
preocupación, as, hicieron cada vez más a muchos otros reformadores 
de este período. Mientras que en esta selección estas mujeres 
protestantes del misionario showcase la gratitud de los niños, muchas
familias inmigrantes Irlande's-Cato'licas se resentían la asunción 
de los misionarios de la superioridad y miraron su ganar prosélitos 
como antagónico a su propio deseo de pasar encendido su creencia 
religiosa a sus niños.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087445</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102860</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/born-in-sin-nurtured-in-crime-the-children-of-new-york-citys-notorious-five-points-1854</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
