<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107978</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107978</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087351</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A Word of Warning: A Former Slave  Urges Constitutional Caution</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Wort von WARNING: Ein Ehemaliger Sklave 
Drängt Auf Konstitutionelle Vorsicht</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un mot de l'avertissement : Une Attention 
Constitutionnelle d'Anciens Recommander Slaves</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uma palavra do aviso: Um Escravo Anterior 
Incita O Cuidado Constitutional</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Una parola di avvertimento: Uno Schiavo 
Precedente Sollecita L'Attenzione Costituzionale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Word της προειδοποίησης: Ένας προηγούμενος 
σκλάβος ωθεί τη συνταγματική προσοχή</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una palabra de la alerta: Un Esclavo 
Anterior Impulsa La Precaución Constitucional</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The South Carolina Constitutional Convention of 1895 completed the process of disenfranchising African-Americans (and many poor whites). The state's restrictive policies began with the election law of 1882 that used an intricate system of eight ballot boxes to discourage illiterate white and black residents from voting. The 1895 convention added a poll tax and literacy test, thereby ensuring that a coalition of remaining black voters and disaffected whites could not unite to challenge Democratic Party rule in South Carolina. Black delegates to the Convention raised their voices against this disenfranchisement, among them Civil War hero Robert Smalls. Born a slave in South Carolina, Smalls became a Congressman during Reconstruction and the leading political figure in Edgefield County, South Carolina. Although disenfranchisement destroyed his local political machine, he remained a prominent figure through federal patronage, serving as the customs collector for the port of Beaufort for many years.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Südcarolina konstitutionelle Vereinbarung von
1895 führte den Prozeß des Entrechtens der Afrikanisch-Amerikaner 
durch (und vielen schlechten Weiß). Die einschränkende Politik
des Zustandes fing mit dem Wahlgesetz von 1882 an, das ein schwieriges
System von acht Wahlurneen benutzte, um unwissende weiße und schwarze
Bewohner vom Wählen zu entmutigen. Die Versammlung 1895 fügte 
eine Gemeindeabgabe hinzu und der Bildungsgradtest, dadurch 
ersicherstellt ersicherstellt daß eine Koalition der restlichen 
schwarzen Wähler und disaffected Weiß könnte nicht vereinigen, um 
demokratische Parteirichtlinie in Südcarolina herauszufordern. 
Schwarzdelegierte zur Versammlung warfen ihre Stimmen gegen 
dieses disenfranchisement, unter ihnen Bürgerkriegheld Robert Smalls 
auf. Einem Sklaven in Südcarolina, Smalls wurden ein 
Kongreßabgeordnetes während der Rekonstruktion und die führende 
politische Abbildung in der Edgefield Grafschaft, Südcarolina 
getragen. Obgleich disenfranchisement seine lokale politische 
Maschine zerstörte, blieb er eine vorstehende Abbildung durch das 
Bundespatronat und diente als der Gewohnheiten Kollektor für den 
Kanal von Beaufort für viele Jahre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La convention constitutionnelle du sud de la
Caroline de 1895 a complété le processus de priver des droits 
civiques des Afro-Américains (et beaucoup de blancs pâles). Les 
politiques restrictives de l'état ont commencé par la loi 
d'élection de 1882 qui a employé un système complexe de huit urnes 
de vote pour décourager les résidants blancs et noirs illettrés du 
vote. La convention 1895 a ajouté un essai d'impôt local et 
d'instruction, s'assurant de ce fait qu'une coalition des électeurs 
noirs restants et des blancs mécontents ne pourrait pas unir pour 
défier la règle de parti démocratique en Caroline du sud. 
Les délégués de noir à la convention ont élevé leurs voix 
contre ce disenfranchisement, parmi elles des Sous-vêtements de Robert 
de héros de guerre civile. Soutenu un slave en Caroline 
Du sud, Sous-vêtements sont devenus un membre du Congrès pendant 
la reconstruction et la principale figure politique dans le comté 
d'Edgefield, Caroline du sud. Bien que le 
disenfranchisement ait détruit sa machine politique locale, il est 
resté une figure en avant par le patronage fédéral, servant de 
collecteur de douane au port de Beaufort pendant beaucoup d'années.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A convenção constitutional sul de carolina de 
1895 terminou o processo de disenfranchising Africano-Americanos (e 
muitos brancos deficientes). As políticas restritivas do estado
começaram com a lei da eleição de 1882 que usou um sistema 
intricado de oito caixas de cédula desanimar residentes brancos e 
pretos illiterate de votar. A convenção 1895 adicionou um 
imposto de votação e o teste do literacy, assegurando-se de desse 
modo que um coalition de eleitores pretos restantes e disaffected 
brancos não poderia unir-se para desafiar a régua do partido 
democrático em carolina sul. Os delegados do preto à 
convenção levantaram suas vozes de encontro a este 
disenfranchisement, entre elas herói Robert Smalls da guerra civil. 
Carregado um escravo em carolina sul, Smalls tornaram-se um 
congressista durante o reconstruction e a figura política principal 
no condado de Edgefield, carolina sul. Embora o 
disenfranchisement destruísse sua máquina política local, 
remanesceu uma figura proeminente com o patronage federal, servindo 
como o coletor dos costumes para a porta de Beaufort por muitos anos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La convenzione costituzionale della Carolina del 
Sud di 1895 ha realizzato il processo di disenfranchising gli 
Africano-Americani (e molti poveri bianchi). Le politiche 
restrittive di dichiarare hanno cominciato con la legge di elezione 
di 1882 che ha usato un sistema complicato di otto caselle di scheda 
elettorale per scoraggiare i residenti bianchi e neri illetterati dal 
voto. La convenzione 1895 ha aggiunto una tassa di scrutinio e 
la prova di literacy, quindi accertantesi che una coalizione degli 
elettori neri restanti e disaffected i bianchi non potrebbe unire per 
sfidare la regola del partito democratico in Carolina del Sud. I
delegati di nero alla convenzione hanno alzato le loro voci contro 
questo disenfranchisement, fra loro hero Robert Smalls di guerra 
civile. Sopportato uno schiavo in Carolina del Sud, Smalls sono 
stato un membro del Congresso durante la ricostruzione e la figura 
politica principale nella contea di Edgefield, Carolina del Sud. 
Anche se il disenfranchisement ha distrutto la sua 
macchina politica locale, è rimasto una figura prominente con 
patronato federale, servente da collettore di dogana per la porta di 
Beaufort per molti anni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η συνταγματική Συνθήκη της νότιας Καρολίνας 1895 
ολοκλήρωσε τη διαδικασία αφρικανικός-Αμερικανοί (και πολλά φτωχά
λευκά). Οι κρατικές περιοριστικές πολιτικές άρχισαν με το 
νόμο εκλογής 1882 που χρησιμοποίησε ένα περίπλοκο σύστημα 
οκτώ κιβωτίων ψήφου για να αποθαρρύνει τους αναλφάβητους λευκούς
και μαύρους κατοίκους από την ψηφοφορία. Η σύμβαση 1895 
πρόσθεσε μια δοκιμή κεφαλικού φόρου και βασικής εκπαίδευσης, με 
αυτόν τον τρόπο εξασφαλίζοντας ότι ένας συνασπισμός της 
παραμονής μαύροι ψηφοφόροι και δυσαρεστημένα λευκά δεν θα 
μπορούσε να ενώσει για να προκαλέσει το δημοκρατικό κανόνα 
συμβαλλόμενου μέρους στη νότια Καρολίνα. Οι μαύροι 
εκπρόσωποι στη Συνθήκη αύξησαν τις φωνές τους ενάντια σε αυτό το
disenfranchisement, μεταξύ τους ήρωας Robert Smalls 
εμφύλιου πολέμου. Γεννημένος ένας σκλάβος στη νότια 
Καρολίνα, smalls έγινε μέλος του Κογκρέσσου κατά τη διάρκεια 
της αναδημιουργίας και του κύριου πολιτικού αριθμού Edgefield 
στο νομό, νότια Καρολίνα. Αν και το disenfranchisement 
κατέστρεψε την τοπική πολιτική μηχανή του, παρέμεινε ένας 
προεξέχων αριθμός μέσω της ομοσπονδιακής προστασίας, που 
χρησιμεύει ως ο τελωνειακός συλλέκτης για το λιμένα Beaufort 
για πολλά έτη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La convención constitucional de Carolina del Sur 
de 1895 terminó el proceso de disenfranchising Africano-Americanos (y
muchos blancos pobres). Las políticas restrictivas del estado 
comenzaron con la ley de la elección de 1882 que utilizó un sistema 
intrincado de ocho rectángulos de balota para desalentar a residentes
blancos y negros analfabetos de la votación. La convención 
1895 agregó un impuesto de encuesta y la prueba de la instrucción, 
de tal modo asegurándose de que una coalición de votantes negros 
restantes y disaffected blancos no podría unir para desafiar regla 
del partido democrático en Carolina del Sur. Los delegados del 
negro a la convención levantaron sus voces contra este 
disenfranchisement, entre ellas héroe Roberto Smalls de la guerra 
civil. Se llevaron un esclavo en Carolina del Sur, Smalls un 
miembro del Congreso durante la reconstrucción y la figura política 
principal en el condado de Edgefield, Carolina del Sur. Aunque 
el disenfranchisement destruyó su máquina política local, él 
seguía siendo una figura prominente con el patrocinio federal, 
sirviendo como el colector de los costumbres para el acceso de 
Beaufort por muchos años.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087351</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107978</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-word-of-warning-a-former-slave-urges-constitutional-caution</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
