<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103986</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103986</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086318</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I'm Going to Fight Like Hell"Anna Taffler and the Unemployed Councils of the 1930s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ich werde wie Hell"Anna Taffler und die 
arbeitslosen Räte kämpfen von den dreißiger Jahren</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"je vais combattre comme Hell"Anna Taffler et les 
Conseils sans emploi des années 30</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"eu estou indo lutar como Hell"Anna Taffler e 
conselhos unemployed dos 1930s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"sto andando combattere come Inferno Taffler 
ed i Consigli disoccupati dei 1930s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Πρόκειται να παλεψω όπως Hell"Anna Taffler και τα
άνεργα Συμβούλια της δεκαετίας του '30</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"voy a luchar como Hell"Anna Taffler y los 
consejos parados de los años 30</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Communist-led Unemployed Councils mobilized jobless men and women in hundreds of local communities to demand jobs and better treatment from relief authorities. In these excerpts from a recorded interview, Anna Taffler, a Communist activist and a Russian Jewish immigrant, described how her own experience of facing eviction pushed her into organizing the unemployed. She also talked about the focus of local councils on issues like fighting for more relief and stopping evictions.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Kommunistisch-führenden arbeitslosen Räte 
mobilisierten arbeitslose Männer und Frauen in den Hunderten der 
lokalen Gemeinschaften, um Jobs und bessere Behandlung von den 
Entlastung Behörden zu verlangen. In diesen Excerpts von einem 
gespeicherten Interview, von Anna Taffler, von einem kommunistischen 
Aktivisten und von einem russischen jüdischen Immigranten, 
beschrieben, wie ihre eigene Erfahrung der Einfassungvertreibung sie 
in das Organisieren der Arbeitslosen drückte. Sie befaßte auch
sich dem mit Fokus der lokalen Räte auf Ausgaben wie dem Kämpfen 
für mehr Entlastung und dem Stoppen von von Vertreibungen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Conseils sans emploi Communiste-menés ont 
mobilisé les hommes et les femmes sans emploi dans les centaines de 
communautés locales pour exiger les travaux et un meilleur traitement
des autorités de soulagement. Dans ces extraits d'une entrevue 
enregistrée, d'Anna Taffler, d'un activiste communiste et d'un 
immigré juif russe, décrits comment sa propre expérience 
d'expulsion de revêtements l'a poussée dans organiser les chômeurs.
Elle a également parlé du centre des conseils locaux sur des 
questions comme le combat pour plus de soulagement et arrêter des 
expulsions.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os conselhos unemployed Comunista-conduzidos 
mobilized homens e mulheres jobless nas centenas de comunidades locais
para exijir trabalhos e o tratamento melhor das autoridades do relevo.
Nestes excerpts de uma entrevista gravada, de Anna Taffler, de 
uma activista comunista e de um immigrant jewish russian, descritos 
como sua própria experiência do eviction dos revestimentos a 
introduziu em organizar os desempregados. Falou também sobre o 
foco de conselhos locais em edições como a luta por mais relevo e a 
parada de evictions.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I Consigli disoccupati Comunista-condotti hanno 
mobilitato gli uomini e le donne senza lavoro nei centinaia delle 
Comunità locali per richiedere i lavori ed il trattamento migliore 
dalle autorità di rilievo. In questi brani da un'intervista 
registrata, da Anna Taffler, da un attivista comunista e da un 
immigrante ebreo russo, descritti come la sua propria esperienza in 
eviction dei rivestimenti la ha spinta nell'organizzazione dei 
disoccupati. Egualmente ha parlato del fuoco dei consigli locali
sulle edizioni come combattimento per più rilievo ed evictions di 
arresto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα κομμουνιστικός-οδηγημένα άνεργα Συμβούλια 
κινητοποίησαν τους άνεργους άνδρες και τις γυναίκες στις 
εκατοντάδες των τοπικών κοινοτήτων για να απαιτήσουν τις εργασίες
και την καλύτερη επεξεργασία από τις αρχές ανακούφισης. Σε 
αυτά τα αποσπάσματα από μια καταγραμμένη συνέντευξη, Anna 
Taffler, ένα κομμουνιστικό ενεργό στέλεχος και ένας ρωσικός 
εβραϊκός μετανάστης, περιέγραψαν πώς η εμπειρία της το 
απέλαση την ώθησε στην οργάνωση των ανέργων. Μίλησε 
επίσης για την εστίαση των τοπικών συμβουλίων σχετικά με τα 
ζητήματα όπως την πάλη για περισσότερη ανακούφιση και την παύση 
των απέλαση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los consejos parados Comunista-conducidos 
movilizaron a hombres y a mujeres desempleados en centenares de 
comunidades locales para exigir trabajos y un tratamiento mejor de 
autoridades de la relevación. En estos extractos de una 
entrevista registrada, de Ana Taffler, de un activista comunista y de 
un inmigrante judío ruso, descritos cómo su propia experiencia del 
desahucio de los revestimientos la empujó en la ordenación de los 
parados. Ella también habló del foco de consejos locales sobre
ediciones como luchar para más relevación y parar desahucios.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086318</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103986</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/im-going-to-fight-like-hell-anna-taffler-and-the-unemployed-councils-of-the-1930s</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
