<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107936</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107936</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201371</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Earth Exploration Toolbook Chapter: When is Dinner Served? Predicting the Spring Phytoplankton Bloom in the Gulf of Maine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Masse Erforschung Toolbook Kapitel: Wann 
wird Abendessen gedient? Voraussagen der Frühling 
Phytoplankton-Blüte im Golf von Maine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Chapitre de Toolbook d'Exploration de la Terre : 
Quand le dîner est-il servi ? Prévision de la fleur de 
phytoplancton de ressort dans le Golfe du Maine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Capítulo De Toolbook Da Exploração Da Terra: 
Quando o jantar é servido? Predizendo a flor do 
phytoplankton da mola no golfo de Maine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Capitolo Di Toolbook Di Esplorazione Della Terra: 
Quando il pranzo è servito? Predizione della fioritura 
del fitoplancton della molla nel golfo della Maine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κεφάλαιο Toolbook γήινης εξερεύνησης: Πότε το
γεύμα εξυπηρετείται; Πρόβλεψη της άνθισης φυτοπλαγκτόντων 
ανοίξεων στον κόλπο του Maine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Capítulo De Toolbook De la Exploración De la 
Tierra: ¿Cuándo se sirve la cena? Predecir la floración 
del phytoplankton del resorte en el golfo de Maine</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this activity, users learn about the variables that influence the abundance of phytoplankton, the microscopic plants that form the base of the marine food chain. Users apply this knowledge to make predictions about the timing of the spring phytoplankton bloom in the Gulf of Maine. They obtain and graph data from buoy monitoring stations and interpret them to make their predictions. They check their predictions by examining chlorophyll concentration data at each buoy. Users also compare their predictions with reality by obtaining and examining MODIS satellite images to view the full extent of the bloom over time.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In dieser Aktivität erlernen Benutzer über die 
Variablen, die den Überfluß am Phytoplankton beeinflussen, die 
mikroskopischen Betriebe, die die Unterseite der 
Marinenahrungsmittelkette bilden. Benutzer wenden dieses Wissen 
an, um Vorhersagen über die Zeitbegrenzung der Frühling 
Phytoplanktonblüte im Golf von Maine zu bilden. Sie erreichen 
und Diagrammdaten von der Boje, die Stationen überwacht und deuten 
sie, um ihre Vorhersagen zu bilden. Sie überprüfen ihre 
Vorhersagen, indem sie Chlorophyllkonzentration Daten an jeder Boje 
überprüfen. Benutzer vergleichen auch ihre Vorhersagen mit 
Wirklichkeit, indem sie MODIS Satellitenbilder erhalten und 
überprüfen, um den vollen Umfang einer Blüte über Zeit anzusehen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cette activité, les utilisateurs se 
renseignent sur les variables qui influencent l'abondance du 
phytoplancton, les usines microscopiques qui forment la base de la 
chaîne alimentaire marine. Les utilisateurs appliquent cette 
connaissance pour faire des prévisions au sujet de la synchronisation
de la fleur de phytoplancton de ressort dans le Golfe du Maine. 
Eux obtiennent et les données de graphique de la bouée 
surveillant des stations et les interprètent pour faire leurs 
prévisions. Ils contrôlent leurs prévisions en examinant des 
données de concentration en chlorophylle à chaque bouée. Les 
utilisateurs comparent également leurs prévisions à la réalité en
obtenant et en examinant des images satellites de MODIS pour 
visualiser la pleine ampleur de la fleur avec le temps.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta atividade, os usuários aprendem sobre as 
variáveis que influenciam a abundância de phytoplankton, as plantas 
microscópicas que dão forma à base da corrente de alimento marinha.
Os usuários aplicam este conhecimento para fazer predições 
sobre o sincronismo da flor do phytoplankton da mola no golfo de 
Maine. Obtêm e os dados do gráfico da bóia que monitora 
estações e interpretam-nas para fazer suas predições. 
Verificam suas predições examinando dados da concentração do
chlorophyll em cada bóia. Os usuários comparam também suas 
predições com a realidade obtendo e examinando imagens satellite de 
MODIS para ver a extensão cheia da flor sobre o tempo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questa attività, gli utenti imparano circa le 
variabili che influenzano l'abbondanza del fitoplancton, le piante 
microscopiche che formano la base del ciclo alimentare marino. 
Gli utenti applicano questa conoscenza per fare le previsioni 
circa la sincronizzazione della fioritura del fitoplancton della molla
nel golfo della Maine. si verificano ed i dati del grafico 
dalla boa che controlla le stazioni e le interpretano per fare le loro
previsioni. Controllano le loro previsioni esaminando i dati di 
concentrazione nella clorofilla ad ogni boa. Gli utenti 
egualmente paragonano le loro previsioni alla realtà ottenendo ed 
esaminando le immagini satelliti di MODIS per osservare il limite 
completo della fioritura col tempo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτήν την δραστηριότητα, οι χρήστες μαθαίνουν για 
τις μεταβλητές που επηρεάζουν την αφθονία φυτοπλαγκτόντος, οι 
μικροσκοπικές εγκαταστάσεις που διαμορφώνουν τη βάση της 
θαλάσσιας τροφικής αλυσίδας. Οι χρήστες εφαρμόζουν αυτήν 
την γνώση για να κάνουν τις προβλέψεις για το συγχρονισμό της 
άνθισης φυτοπλαγκτόντων άνοιξη στον κόλπο του Maine. 
Λαμβάνουν και στοιχεία γραφικών παραστάσεων από τους 
σταθμούς ελέγχου σημαντήρων και τους ερμηνεύουν για να κάνουν τις
προβλέψεις τους. Ελέγχουν τις προβλέψεις τους με την εξέταση
των στοιχείων συγκέντρωσης χλωροφύλλης σε κάθε σημαντήρα. 
Οι χρήστες συγκρίνουν επίσης τις προβλέψεις τους με την 
πραγματικότητα με τη λήψη και την εξέταση των δορυφορικών εικόνων
MODIS για να εμφανίσουν την πλήρη έκταση της άνθισης κατά τη 
διάρκεια του χρόνου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta actividad, los utilizadores aprenden sobre
las variables que influencian la abundancia del phytoplankton, las 
plantas microscópicas que forman la base del encadenamiento de 
alimento marina. Los utilizadores aplican este conocimiento para
hacer predicciones sobre la sincronización de la floración del 
phytoplankton del resorte en el golfo de Maine. Ellos obtienen y
los datos del gráfico de la boya que vigila estaciones y las 
interpretan para hacer sus predicciones. Controlan sus 
predicciones examinando datos de la concentración de la clorofila en 
cada boya. Los utilizadores también comparan sus predicciones 
con realidad obteniendo y examinando imágenes basadas en los 
satélites de MODIS para visión el fragmento completo de la 
floración en un cierto plazo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:DENISE BLAHA
FN:DENISE BLAHA
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:AMY CLINE
FN:AMY CLINE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201371</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107936</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/earth-exploration-toolbook-chapter-when-is-dinner-served-predicting-the-spring-phytoplankton-bloom-in-the-gulf-of-maine</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
