<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106417</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106417</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206146</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Geology at the U.S. Geological Survey</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geologie an der VEREINIGTE STAATEN geologischen 
Übersicht</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Géologie à l'enquête géologique des 
ETATS-UNIS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Geologia no exame geological de ESTADOS UNIDOS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Geologia all'indagine geologica degli STATI UNITI</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γεωλογία στην ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ γεωλογική έρευνα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Geología en la encuesta sobre geológica ESTADOS 
UNIDOS</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">provides resource collections and maps for studying earthquakes, hurricanes, floods, wildfires, and other natural disasters, as well as rocks and minerals, plate tectonics, earth's interior, fossils, coastal wetlands, deserts, the carbon cycle, climate change, and the solar system. Learn about the San Andreas fault system, the life cycle of a mineral deposit, fire ecology research, big floods in the U.S., and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt Hilfsmittelansammlungen zur Verfügung und 
Karten für das Studieren der Erdbeben, Hurrikane, Fluten, wildfires 
und andere Naturkatastrophen, sowie Felsen und Mineralien, 
Plattentektonik, bedeckten Inneren, Fossilien, KüstenSumpfgebiete, 
Wüsten, die Carbonschleife, Klimaänderung und das Solarsystem mit 
Erde. Erlernen Sie über das San Andreas Störung System, den 
Lebenszyklus einer Mineralablagerung, Feuerökologieforschung, grosse 
Fluten in den VEREINIGTEN STAATEN und mehr.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fournit des collections de ressource et les cartes
pour étudier les tremblements de terre, ouragans, inondations, 
feux de forêt, et d'autres désastres normaux, aussi bien que des 
roches et des minerais, tectonique de plat, ont mis à la terre 
l'intérieur, les fossiles, les marécages côtiers, les déserts, 
le cycle de carbone, le changement de climat, et le système solaire. 
Renseignez-vous sur le système de défaut de San Andreas, le 
cycle de vie d'un dépôt de minérai, la recherche en matière 
d'écologie du feu, les grandes inondations aux ETATS-UNIS, et plus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fornece coleções do recurso e os mapas para 
estudar os terremotos, furacões, inundações, wildfires, e outros 
disastres naturais, as.well.as rochas e minerais, tectonics de placa, 
ligaram à terra o interior, os fossils, wetlands litorais, desertos, 
o ciclo de carbono, a mudança do clima, e o sistema solar. 
Aprenda sobre o sistema da falha do San Andreas, o ciclo de vida
de um depósito mineral, a pesquisa do ecology do fogo, inundações 
grandes nos ESTADOS UNIDOS, e mais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fornisce le collezioni delle risorse ed i 
programmi per studiare i terremoti, uragani, inondazioni, wildfires ed
altri disastri naturali, così come le roccie ed i minerali, la 
tettonica di piastra, hanno interrato l'interiore, i fossili, i 
wetlands litoranei, i deserti, il ciclo di carbonio, il cambiamento di
clima ed il sistema solare. Impari circa il sistema del difetto 
di San Andreas, il ciclo di vita di un giacimento minerario, la 
ricerca in ecologia del fuoco, gli inondazioni grandi negli STATI 
UNITI e più.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρέχει τις συλλογές και τους χάρτες των στοιχείων 
συμπεριφοράς για τη μελέτη των σεισμών, των τυφώνων, των 
πλημμυρών, των πυρκαγιών, και άλλων φυσικών καταστροφών, καθώς 
επίσης και των βράχων και των μεταλλευμάτων, της τεκτονικής 
πιάτων, του γήινου εσωτερικού, των απολιθωμάτων, των παράκτιων 
υγρότοπων, των ερήμων, του κύκλου άνθρακα, της αλλαγής κλίματος,
και του ηλιακού συστήματος. Μάθετε για το σύστημα βλαβών 
SAN Ανδρέας, τον κύκλο ζωής ενός ορυκτού αποθέματος, την 
έρευνα οικολογίας πυρκαγιάς, τις μεγάλες πλημμύρες στις ΗΠΑ, και 
περισσότερους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">proporciona a colecciones del recurso y las 
correspondencias para estudiar los terremotos, huracanes, 
inundaciones, wildfires, y otros desastres naturales, así como las 
rocas y los minerales, tectónica de placa, conectaron a tierra el 
interior, fósiles, wetlands costeros, los desiertos, el ciclo de 
carbón, el cambio del clima, y la Sistema Solar. Aprenda sobre 
el sistema del incidente del San Andreas, el ciclo vital de un 
depósito mineral, la investigación de la ecología del fuego, 
inundaciones grandes en los ESTADOS UNIDOS, y más.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206146</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106417</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/geology-at-the-u-s-geological-survey</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
