<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104074</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104074</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207227</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Emerald Necklace: Boston's Green Connection</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Smaragdhalskette: Bostons Grüner 
Anschluß</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Collier Vert : La Connexion Verte de 
Boston</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Necklace Emerald: Conexão Verde De 
Boston</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Necklace Verde smeraldo: Collegamento 
Verde De Boston</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το σμαραγδένιο περιδέραιο: Πράσινη σύνδεση της 
Βοστώνης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Collar Esmeralda: Conexión Verde De 
Boston</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">recounts the creation of a series of parks in Boston in the 1880s. At that time, Boston was crammed with buildings and people. It was overcrowded, noisy, and dirty. City officials, concerned about the health and well-being of Bostonians, hired Frederick Law Olmsted, who had designed Central Park in New York, to create a park system that wove together a series of small parks?gardens, waterways, meadows, tree museums, and others?into what became known as Boston's Emerald Necklace.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">zählt die Kreation einer Reihe Parks in Boston im
1880s nach. Zu dieser Zeit crammed Boston mit Gebäuden und 
Leuten. Es war überfüllt schmutzig, laut, und. Die 
Stadtbeamten, betroffen über die Gesundheit und das Wohl von 
Bostonians, stellten Frederick Gesetz Olmsted, das Central Park in New
York konzipiert hatte an, um ein Parksystem zu erstellen, das eine 
Reihe kleine zusammen parks?gardens, Wassern-Strasse, Wiesen, 
Baummuseen und others?into spann, was als Bostons Smaragdhalskette 
bekannt wurde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">raconte la création d'une série de parcs à 
Boston dans le 1880s. À ce moment-là, Boston a été fourré 
des bâtiments et des personnes. Il était surchargé, bruyant, 
et modifié. Les fonctionnaires de ville, préoccupés par la 
santé et le bien-être de Bostonians, ont loué la loi Olmsted de 
Frederick, qui avait conçu le parc central à New York, pour créer 
un système de parc qui a tissé ensemble une série de petits 
parks?gardens, voies d'eau, prés, musées d'arbre, et others?into ce 
qui est devenu notoire comme collier vert de Boston.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">recounts a criação de uma série dos parques em 
Boston no 1880s. Nesse tempo, Boston crammed com os edifícios e
os povos. Estava overcrowded, ruidosa, e suja. Os oficiais
da cidade, concernidos sobre a saúde e o bem estar de Bostonians, 
empregaram a lei Olmsted de Frederick, que tinha projetado Central 
Park em New York, para criar um sistema do parque que tecesse junto 
uma série dos parks?gardens, de canais, de prados, de museus da 
árvore, e do others?into pequenos o que se tornou sabido como o 
necklace emerald de Boston.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">racconta la creazione di una serie di parchi a 
Boston nel 1880s. A quel tempo, Boston crammed con le 
costruzioni e la gente. Era sovraccaricata, rumorosa e sporca. 
I funzionari della città, interessati circa la salute ed il 
benessere di Bostonians, hanno assunto la legge Olmsted di Frederick, 
che aveva progettato Central Park a New York, per creare un sistema 
del parco che ha tessuto insieme una serie di piccoli parks?gardens, 
canali navigabili, prati, musei dell'albero ed others?into che cosa è
stato conosciuto come il necklace verde smeraldo de Boston.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξιστορεί τη δημιουργία μιας σειράς πάρκων στη 
Βοστώνη στο 1880s. Εκείνη την περίοδο, η Βοστώνη 
γεμίστηκε με τα κτήρια και τους ανθρώπους. Ήταν 
επιβαρυνμένο, θορυβώδες, και βρώμικο. Ανώτεροι υπάλληλοι 
πόλεων, ενδιαφερόμενοι για την υγεία και την ευημερία 
Bostonians, μισθωμένος Frederick νόμος Olmsted, που είχε 
σχεδιάσει το κεντρικό πάρκο στη Νέα Υόρκη, για να δημιουργήσει 
ένα σύστημα πάρκων που ύφανε μαζί μια σειρά μικρών 
parks?gardens, υδάτινων οδών, λιβαδιών, μουσείων δέντρων, και 
others?into αυτό που έγινε γνωστό ως σμαραγδένιο περιδέραιο 
της Βοστώνης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">contó de nuevo la creación de una serie de 
parques en Boston en el 1880s. En aquella 'epoca, Boston fue 
abarrotada con los edificios y la gente. Era atestada, ruidosa, 
y sucia. Los funcionarios de la ciudad, referidos sobre la salud
y el bienestar de Bostonians, emplearon la ley Olmsted de Frederick, 
que había diseñado el parque central en Nueva York, para crear un 
sistema del parque que tejió juntos una serie de parks?gardens, de 
canales, de prados, de museos del árbol, y de others?into pequeños 
qué se conocía como collar esmeralda de Boston.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207227</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104074</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-emerald-necklace-bostons-green-connection</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
