<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105346</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105346</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202705</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Bouncing Ball Experiment</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Aufprallen Des Kugel-Experimentes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Rebondissement de l'Expérience de Boule</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Saltando A Experiência Da Esfera</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Rimbalzo Dell'Esperimento Della Sfera</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πείραμα σφαιρών αναπήδησης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Despedir El Experimento De la Bola</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this experiment students should be in groups of 3. Students will drop a ball from different heights and measure the corresponding bounce. Since each group will use a different ball, they will generate different sets of data. They will be asked to discuss and compare their linear function with that of their classmates. They should practice measuring the ball bounce before they begin to collect data.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In diesem Experiment sollten Kursteilnehmer in den
Gruppen von 3 sein. Kursteilnehmer lassen eine Kugel von den 
unterschiedlichen Höhen fallen und messen den entsprechenden Schlag. 
Da jede Gruppe eine andere Kugel benutzt, legen sie 
unterschiedliche Sets Daten fest. Sie werden gebeten, ihre 
lineare Funktion mit der ihrer Mitschüler zu behandeln und zu 
vergleichen. Sie sollten den, Kugelschlag zu messen üben, bevor
sie anfangen, Daten zu sammeln.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cette expérience les étudiants devraient 
être dans les groupes de 3. Les étudiants relâcheront une 
boule de différentes tailles et mesureront le rebond correspondant. 
Puisque chaque groupe utilisera une boule différente, ils 
produiront de différents ensembles de données. Ils seront 
invités à discuter et comparer leur fonction linéaire à celle de 
leurs camarades de classe. Ils devraient pratiquer mesurer le 
rebond de boule avant qu'ils commencent à rassembler des données.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta experiência os estudantes devem estar nos 
grupos de 3. Os estudantes deixarão cair uma esfera das alturas
diferentes e medirão o salto correspondente. Desde que cada 
grupo usará uma esfera diferente, gerarão jogos diferentes dos 
dados. Serão pedidos para discutir e comparar sua função 
linear com a aquela de seus classmates. Devem praticar medir o 
salto da esfera antes que comecem a coletar dados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questo esperimento allievi dovrebbero essere 
nei gruppi di 3. Gli allievi cadranno una sfera dalle altezze 
differenti e misureranno il rimbalzo corrispondente. Poiché 
ogni gruppo userà una sfera differente, genereranno gli insiemi 
differenti dei dati. Saranno chiesti di discutere e paragonare 
la loro funzione lineare a quella dei loro classmates. 
Dovrebbero esercitarsi in misurare il rimbalzo della sfera prima
che comincino a raccogliere i dati.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτό το πείραμα οι σπουδαστές πρέπει να είναι στις
ομάδες 3. σπουδαστών θα ρίξουν μια σφαίρα από τα διαφορετικά 
ύψη και θα μετρήσουν την αντίστοιχη αναπήδηση. Δεδομένου 
ότι κάθε ομάδα θα χρησιμοποιήσει μια διαφορετική σφαίρα, θα 
παραγάγουν τα διαφορετικά σύνολα στοιχείων. Θα κληθούν να 
συζητήσουν και να συγκρίνουν τη γραμμική λειτουργία τους με αυτήν
των συμμαθητών τους. Πρέπει να ασκήσουν την αναπήδηση 
σφαιρών προτού να αρχίσουν να συλλέγουν τα στοιχεία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En este experimento los estudiantes deben estar en
grupos de 3. Los estudiantes caerán una bola de diversas 
alturas y medirán la despedida correspondiente. Puesto que cada
grupo utilizará una diversa bola, generarán diversos conjuntos de 
datos. Les pedirán discutir y comparar su función linear con 
la de sus classmates. Deben practicar el medir de la despedida 
de la bola antes de que comiencen a recoger datos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ALICIA JONES
FN:ALICIA JONES
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202705</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105346</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/bouncing-ball-experiment</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
