<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107785</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107785</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087650</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">High School Human Genome Project</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">High School Menschliches Genom-Projekt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Projet Humain de Génome de Lycée</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Projeto Humano Do Genome Da High School</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Progetto Umano Del Genome Della High School</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρώπινο πρόγραμμα γονιδιώματος γυμνασίου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Proyecto Humano Del Genoma De la High School 
Secundaria</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The High School Human Genome Program allows high school students to sequence DNA in their classrooms and to contribute their data to the Human Genome Project. The program was developed jointly by scientists from the University of Washington's Department of Molecular Biotechnology and high school teachers from the Puget Sound region. The goals of the program are to promote a better understanding of DNA research among students by enabling them, under the guidance of their teachers, to sequence portions of the human genome; to stimulate students interest in the ethical, legal and social implications of genome research; and to interest students in careers in science.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das High School menschliche Genom-Programm erlaubt
High School Kursteilnehmern, DNA in ihren Klassenzimmern sequentiell 
zu ordnen und ihre Daten zum menschlichen Genom-Projekt beizutragen. 
Das Programm wurde gemeinsam von den Wissenschaftlern von der 
Universität von Abteilung Washingtons der Lehrer der molekularen 
Biotechnologie und der High School von der Puget Soundregion 
entwickelt. Die Ziele des Programms sind, ein besseres 
Verständnis der DNA Forschung unter Kursteilnehmern zu fördern, 
indem sie sie, unter der Anleitung ihrer Lehrer aktivieren, Teile des 
menschlichen Genoms sequentiell zu ordnen; 
Kursteilnehmerinteresse an den ethischen, zugelassenen und 
Sozialimplikationen der Genomforschung anregen; und 
Kursteilnehmer für Karrieren in der Wissenschaft interessieren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le programme humain de génome de lycée permet à
des étudiants de lycée d'ordonnancer l'ADN dans leurs salles de 
classe et de contribuer leurs données au projet humain de génome. 
Le programme a été développé conjointement par des 
scientifiques de l'université du service de Washington des 
professeurs de biotechnologie moléculaire et de lycée de la région 
de bruit de Puget. Les buts du programme sont de favoriser un 
meilleur arrangement de recherche d'ADN parmi des étudiants en leur 
permettant, sous les conseils de leurs professeurs, d'ordonnancer des 
parties du génome humain ; pour stimuler l'intérêt 
d'étudiants pour les implications morales, légales et sociales de la
recherche de génome ; et pour intéresser des étudiants dans 
les carrières en science.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O programa humano do genome da High School permite
que os estudantes da High School arranjem em seqüência o DNA em suas
salas de aula e contribuam seus dados ao projeto humano do genome. 
O programa foi desenvolvido conjuntamente por cientistas da 
universidade do departamento de Washington de professores do 
biotechnology molecular e da High School da região do som de Puget. 
Os objetivos do programa são promover uma compreensão melhor 
da pesquisa do DNA entre estudantes permitindo os, sob a orientação 
de seus professores, de arranjar em seqüência parcelas do genome 
humano; para estimular o interesse dos estudantes nas 
implicações éticas, legais e sociais da pesquisa do genome; e
para interessar estudantes nas carreiras na ciência.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il programma umano del genome della High School 
permette che gli allievi della High School ordinino il DNA in serie 
nelle loro aule e forniscano i loro dati al progetto umano del genome.
Il programma è stato sviluppato insieme dagli scienziati 
dall'università di reparto de Washington degli insegnanti della High 
School e di biotecnologia molecolare dalla regione del suono di Puget.
Gli obiettivi del programma sono di promuovere una comprensione 
migliore della ricerca del DNA fra gli allievi permettendo loro, sotto
il consiglio dei loro insegnanti, di ordinare le parti in serie del 
genome umano; per stimolare interesse degli allievi nelle 
implicazioni etiche, legali e sociali di ricerca del genome; e 
per interessare gli allievi alle carriere nella scienza.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το ανθρώπινο πρόγραμμα γονιδιώματος γυμνασίου 
επιτρέπει στους σπουδαστές γυμνασίου στο DNA ακολουθίας στις 
τάξεις τους και για να συμβάλει τα στοιχεία τους στο ανθρώπινο 
έργο γονιδιώματος. Το πρόγραμμα αναπτύχθηκε από κοινού 
από τους επιστήμονες από το πανεπιστήμιο του τμήματος της 
Ουάσιγκτον μοριακών δασκάλων βιοτεχνολογίας και γυμνασίου από 
την υγιή περιοχή Puget. Οι στόχοι του προγράμματος είναι
να προωθηθεί μια καλύτερη κατανόηση της έρευνας DNA μεταξύ των
σπουδαστών με τη διευκόλυνση τους, κάτω από την καθοδήγηση των 
δασκάλων τους, στις μερίδες ακολουθίας του ανθρώπινου 
γονιδιώματος  για να υποκινήσετε τους σπουδαστές ενδιαφέρετε
για τις ηθικές, νομικές και κοινωνικές επιπτώσεις της έρευνας 
γονιδιώματος  και στους σπουδαστές ενδιαφέροντος στις 
σταδιοδρομίες στην επιστήμη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El programa humano del Genoma de la High 
School secundaria permite que los estudiantes de la High School 
secundaria ordenen la DNA en sus salas de clase y contribuyan sus 
datos al proyecto humano del Genoma. El programa fue 
desarrollado en común por los científicos de la universidad del 
departamento de Washington de los profesores de la biotecnología 
molecular y de la High School secundaria de la región del sonido de 
Puget. Las metas del programa son promover una comprensión 
mejor de la investigación de la DNA entre estudiantes 
permitiéndoles, bajo dirección de sus profesores, ordenar porciones 
del genoma humano; para estimular interés de los 
estudiantes en las implicaciones éticas, legales y sociales de la 
investigación del genoma; y para interesar a estudiantes en
carreras en ciencia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087650</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107785</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/matters/high-school-human-genome-project</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
