<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104702</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104702</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086697</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Only Thing We Have to Fear Is Fear Itself": FDR's First Inaugural Address</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"nur Sache, die wir uns fürchten müssen, ist 
Furcht selbst": Eröffnungsadresse FDR Ersten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"seulement la chose que nous devons craindre est 
la crainte elle-même" : l'Adresse Inaugurale de FDR Premier</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"somente a coisa que nós temos que temer é o 
medo próprio": Endereço Inaugural Do FDR Primeiro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"soltanto la cosa che dobbiamo temere è timore in
se": Indirizzo Inaugurale Del FDR Primo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Μόνο πράγμα πρέπει να φοβηθούμε ότι είναι ο ίδιος 
φόβοσ": Πρώτη εναρκτήρια διεύθυνση FDR</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"solamente la cosa que tenemos que temer es el 
miedo sí mismo": Direccionamiento Inaugural Del FDR Primer</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Franklin D. Roosevelt had campaigned against Herbert Hoover in the 1932 presidential election by saying as little as possible about what he might do if elected. Through even the closest working relationships, none of the president-elect's most intimate associates felt they knew him well, with the exception perhaps of his wife, Eleanor. The affable, witty Roosevelt used his great personal charm to keep most people at a distance. In campaign speeches, he favored a buoyant, optimistic, gently paternal tone spiced with humor. But his first inaugural address took on an unusually solemn, religious quality. And for good reason--by 1933 the depression had reached its depth. Roosevelt's first inaugural address outlined in broad terms how he hoped to govern and reminded Americans that the nation's "common difficulties" concerned "only material things."  Please note that the audio is an excerpt from the full address.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Franklin D. Roosevelt hatte gegen Herbert 
Staubsauger in der Präsidentenwahl 1932 geworben, indem er so wenig 
wie möglich sagte über, was er tun konnte, wenn es gewählt wird. 
Durch gleichmäßiges deuten die nähsten Arbeitsverhältnisse, 
keines des gewählten Präsidenten am meisten Teilnehmer glaubten an, 
daß sie ihn gut, mit der Ausnahme möglicherweise seiner Frau, 
Eleanor kannten. Das leutselige, witty Roosevelt verwendete 
seinen großen persönlichen Charme, um die meisten Leute in einem 
Abstand zu halten. In den Wahlreden beehrte er einen 
schwimmenden, optimistischen, leicht väterlichen Ton, der mit 
Stimmung gewürzt wurde. Aber seine erste Eröffnungsadresse 
nahm auf einer ungewöhnlich ernsten, frommen Qualität. Und aus
triftigem Grund -- durch 1933 hatte der Tiefstand seine Tiefe 
erreicht. Roosevelts erste Eröffnungsadresse umriß grob 
ausgedrückt, wie er hoffte zu regeln und erinnerte Amerikaner, denen 
die "geläufigen Schwierigkeiten" der Nation betrafen "nur materielle 
Sachen." Beachten Sie bitte, daß der Audio ein Excerpt von der 
vollen Adresse ist.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Franklin D. Roosevelt avait fait campagne contre 
l'aspirateur d'Herbert dans l'élection 1932 présidentielle en disant
le moins possible au sujet de ce qu'il pourrait faire si élu. 
Par même les relations de travail les plus étroites, rien le 
président désigné suggèrent plus des associés ont jugé qu'elles 
l'ont bien connu, à l'exception peut-être de son épouse, Eleanor. 
Le Roosevelt affable et plein d'esprit a employé son grand 
charme personnel pour garder la plupart des personnes à une distance.
Dans des discours de campagne, il a favorisé une tonalité 
flottable, optimiste, doucement paternelle épicée avec l'humeur. 
Mais sa première adresse inaugurale a pris une qualité 
exceptionnellement solennelle et religieuse. Et pour la bonne 
raison -- par 1933 la dépression avait atteint sa profondeur. 
La première adresse inaugurale de Roosevelt tracée les grandes
lignes de façon générale comment il a espéré régir et a rappelé
les Américains que difficultés les "communes" de la nation sont 
concernées "seulement des choses matérielles." Veuillez noter 
que l'acoustique est un extrait de la pleine adresse.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Franklin D. Roosevelt tinha feito campanha de 
encontro ao hoover de Herbert na eleição 1932 presidencial dizendo o
menos possível sobre o que pôde fazer se eleito. Com uniforme 
os relacionamentos de funcionamento os mais próximos, nenhum do 
president-elect intimate mais associados sentiram que o conheceram 
bem, com a exceção talvez de sua esposa, Eleanor. O Roosevelt 
affable, witty usou seu encanto pessoal grande manter a maioria de 
povos em uma distância. Em discursos de campanha, favoreceu um 
tom flutuante, optimistic, delicadamente paternal spiced com o humor. 
Mas seu primeiro endereço inaugural fêz exame em uma qualidade
raramente solemn, religiosa. E para a razão boa -- por 1933 o 
depression tinha alcançado sua profundidade. O primeiro 
endereço inaugural de Roosevelt esboçado em termos largos como 
esperou governar e lembrou os americanos que as dificuldades "comuns" 
da nação concerniram "somente coisas materiais." Anote por 
favor que o áudio é um excerpt do endereço cheio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Franklin D. Roosevelt aveva fatto una campagna 
contro il hoover del Herbert nell'elezione presidenziale 1932 dicendo 
il meno possibile circa che cosa potrebbe fare se scelto. Con 
persino le relazioni di lavoro più vicine, nessuna del presidente 
eletto più intimate i soci hanno ritenuto che lo hanno conosciuto 
bene, con l'eccezione forse della sua moglie, Eleanor. Il 
Roosevelt affable e witty ha usato il suo fascino personale grande per
mantenere la maggior parte della gente ad una distanza. Nei 
discorsi di campagna, ha favorito un tono capace di galleggiare, 
ottimista, delicatamente paterno aromatizzato con umore. Ma il 
suo primo indirizzo inaugurale ha intrapreso una qualità 
insolitamente solenne e religiosa. E per buon motivo -- da 1933 
la depressione aveva raggiunto la relativa profondità. Il primo
indirizzo inaugurale del Roosevelt descritto in generale come ha 
sperato di governare ed ha ricordato agli Americani che le difficoltà
"comuni" della nazione hanno interessato "soltanto le cose materiali."
Noti prego che l'audio è un brano dall'indirizzo completo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Franklin Δ. Roosevelt είχε κάνει εκστρατεία 
ενάντια σε Herbert Hoover στην προεδρική εκλογή του 1932 
με να πει το λιγότερο δυνατόν για αυτό που να κάνει εάν 
εκλέγεται. Μέσω ακόμη και των στενότερων εργασιακών 
σχέσεων, κανένας από τους president-elect οικειότερους 
συνεταίρους δεν αισθάνθηκε ότι τον ήξεραν καλά, με την εξαίρεση 
ίσως της συζύγου του, Eleanor. Το ευπροσήγορο, 
πνευματώδες Roosevelt χρησιμοποίησε τη μεγάλη προσωπική 
γοητεία του για να κρατήσει τους περισσότερους ανθρώπους σε μια 
απόσταση. Στις ομιλίες εκστρατείας, ευνόησε έναν 
επιπλέοντα, αισιόδοξο, ήπια πατρικό τόνο που καρυκεύτηκε με το 
χιούμορ. Αλλά η πρώτη εναρκτήρια διεύθυνσή του πήρε μια 
κατ'ασυνήθιστο τρόπο σοβαρή, θρησκευτική ποιότητα. Και για 
τον καλό λόγο -- μέχρι το 1933 η κατάθλιψη είχε φθάσει στο 
βάθος της. Η πρώτη εναρκτήρια διεύθυνση του Roosevelt 
περιέγραψε γενικά πώς ήλπισε να κυβερνήσει και υπενθύμισε σε 
Αμερικανούς ότι οι "κοινές δυσκολίεσ" του έθνους αφορούσαν 
"μόνο τα υλικά πράγματα." Παρακαλώ σημειώστε ότι ο ήχος 
είναι ένα απόσπασμα από την πλήρη διεύθυνση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Franklin D. Roosevelt había hecho campaña contra
la aspiradora de Herberto en la elección presidencial 1932 diciendo 
lo menos posible sobre lo que él puede ser que haga si estuvo 
elegido. Con uniforme los lazos de funcionamiento más cercanos,
ningunos de los asociados más íntimos del presidente electo se 
sentían que le conocían bien, con la anomalía quizás de su esposa,
Eleanor. El Roosevelt afable, ingenioso utilizó su gran encanto
personal para guardar a la mayoría de gente en una distancia. 
En discursos de campaña, él favoreció un tono boyante, 
optimista, suavemente paternal condimentado con humor. Pero su 
primer direccionamiento inaugural adquirió una calidad inusualmente 
solemne, religiosa. Y por buena razón -- por 1933 la depresión
había alcanzado su profundidad. El primer direccionamiento 
inaugural de Roosevelt contorneado en amplios términos cómo él 
esperaba gobernar y recordó a americanos que las dificultades 
"comunes" de la nación se refirieron "solamente a cosas materiales." 
Observe por favor que el audio es un extracto del 
direccionamiento completo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086697</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104702</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/only-thing-we-have-to-fear-is-fear-itself-fdrs-first-inaugural-address</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
