<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104164</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104164</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087326</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"A Perfect Hailstorm of Bullets": A Black Sergeant Remembers the Battle of San Juan Hill in 1899</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ein vollkommenes Hailstorm der Gewehrkugeln": 
Ein schwarzer Sergeant erinnert sich die an Schlacht San 
Juan des Hügels 1899</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"un Hailstorm parfait des balles" : Un 
Sergent noir se rappelle la bataille de la colline de San 
Juan en 1899</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"um Hailstorm perfeito das balas": Um 
sergeant preto Recordar a batalha do monte do San Juan em 1899</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"un Hailstorm perfetto delle pallottole": Un
sergeant nero Remembers la battaglia della collina di San Juan in 
1899</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ένα τέλειο Hailstorm των σφαιρών": Ένας 
μαύρος λοχίας θυμάται τη μάχη του SAN Juan Hill το 
1899</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"un Hailstorm perfecto de puntos negros": Un
sargento negro Remembers la batalla de la colina del San Juan en 1899</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The best-known image of the Spanish-American War is that of Teddy Roosevelt on horseback charging with his Rough Riders up San Juan Hill in Cuba. But not only was the role of the Rough Riders exaggerated, it also displaced attention from the black soldiers who made up almost 25 percent of the U. S. force in Cuba. Indeed, the Spanish troops, who called the black soldiers "smoked Yankees," were often more respectful of the black troops than were the white officers who commanded them. Here Sergeant-Major Frank W. Pullen, Jr. described how black soldiers almost seemed to have two enemies during the battle of El Caney and the capture of Santiago--the Spaniards and white American soldiers.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das bekannteste Bild des Spanisch-Amerikanischen 
Krieges ist das von Teddy Roosevelt auf mit seinen rauhen Mitfahrern 
herauf San Juan Hügel in Kuba zu Pferde aufladen. Aber war 
nicht nur die Rolle der rauhen übertriebenen Mitfahrer, es verlegte 
auch Aufmerksamkeit von den schwarzen Soldaten, die fast 25 Prozent 
der USKRAFT in Kuba bildeten. In der Tat rauchten die spanischen
Truppen, die die schwarzen Soldaten "anriefen, Yankees," waren häufig
respektvoller von den schwarzen Truppen, als die weißen waren 
Offiziere, die sie befahlen. Hier beschrieb Sergeant-major 
aufrichtiges W. Pullen, jr., wie schwarze Soldaten fast schienen, zwei
Feinde während der Schlacht von EL Caney und die Sicherung von 
Santiago -- die Spaniards und die weißen amerikanischen Soldaten zu 
haben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'image la plus connue de la guerre 
Espagnol-Américaine est celle du nounours Roosevelt chargeant à 
cheval de ses cavaliers approximatifs vers le haut de colline de San 
Juan au Cuba. Mais était non seulement le rôle des 
cavaliers approximatifs exagérés, il a également déplacé 
l'attention des soldats noirs qui ont composé presque une force des 
États-Unis de 25 pour cent au Cuba. En effet, les troupes 
espagnoles, qui ont appelé les soldats noirs "ont fumé Yankees," 
étaient souvent plus respectueuses des troupes noires que n'étaient 
les officiers blancs qui les ont commandées. Ici 
sergent-major W. Pullen franc, Jr. a décrit comment les soldats 
noirs ont presque semblé avoir deux ennemis pendant la bataille du EL
Caney et la saisie de Santiago -- les Espagnols et les soldats 
américains blancs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A imagem a mais best-known da guerra 
Espanhol-Americana é aquela do teddy Roosevelt horseback em carregar 
com seus cavaleiros ásperos acima do monte do San Juan em Cuba. 
Mas era não somente o papel dos cavaleiros ásperos 
exaggerated, ele deslocou também a atenção dos soldados pretos que 
compuseram quase 25 por cento da força dos E. U. em Cuba. 
Certamente, as tropas espanholas, que chamaram os soldados 
pretos "fumaram Yankees," eram frequentemente mais respectful das 
tropas pretas do que eram os oficiais brancos que as comandaram. 
W. frank aqui Sergeant-Principal Pullen, Jr. descreveu como os 
soldados pretos pareceram quase ter dois inimigos durante a batalha do
EL Caney e a captação de Santiago -- os spaniards e soldados 
americanos brancos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'immagine più nota della guerra 
Spagnolo-Americana è quella del teddy Roosevelt a cavallo sul 
caricarsi dei suoi riders approssimativi sulla collina di San Juan in 
Cuba. Ma era non soltanto il ruolo dei riders approssimativi 
esagerati, esso egualmente ha spostato l'attenzione dai soldati neri 
che hanno composto quasi 25 per cento della forza degli Stati Uniti in
Cuba. Effettivamente, le truppe spagnole, che hanno chiamato i 
soldati neri "hanno fumato Yankees," erano spesso più rispettose 
delle truppe nere degli ufficiali bianchi che le hanno comandate. 
W. Pullen franco qui Sergeant-Principale, Jr. ha descritto come 
i soldati neri quasi hanno sembrato avere due nemici durante la 
battaglia del EL Caney ed il bloccaggio di Santiago -- gli spaniards 
ed i soldati americani bianchi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η πιό γνωστή εικόνα του spanish-American πολέμου 
είναι αυτή Teddy Roosevelt στην πλάτη αλόγου που χρεώνει με
τους τραχιούς αναβάτες του επάνω στο SAN Juan Hill στην 
Κούβα. Αλλά όχι μόνο ο ρόλος των τραχιών αναβατών 
υπερβλήθηκε, μετατόπισε επίσης την προσοχή από τους μαύρους 
στρατιώτες που αποτέλεσαν σχεδόν 25 τοις εκατό της δύναμης του
Θ*u. Θ*ς. στην Κούβα. Πράγματι, τα ισπανικά στρατεύματα, που
καπνισμένοι Αμερικανοί κάλεσαν των μαύρων στρατιωτών "," ήταν 
συχνά πιό πλήρη σεβασμού των μαύρων στρατευμάτων από ήταν οι 
λευκοί ανώτεροι υπάλληλοι που τα διέταξαν. Εδώ 
Sergeant-Major Frank Θ*Ω. Pullen, νεώτερος περιέγραψε πώς 
οι μαύροι στρατιώτες φάνηκαν σχεδόν να έχουν δύο εχθρούς κατά 
τη διάρκεια της μάχης της EL Caney και της σύλληψης του 
Σαντιάγο -- οι Ισπανοί και οι λευκοί αμερικανικοί στρατιώτες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La imagen más conocida de la guerra 
Español-Americana es la del teddy Roosevelt en a caballo la carga con
sus jinetes ásperos encima de la colina del San Juan en Cuba. 
Pero estaba no solamente el papel de los jinetes ásperos 
exagerados, él también desplazó la atención de los soldados negros
que compusieron casi de 25 por ciento una fuerza de los E.E.U.U. en 
Cuba. De hecho, las tropas españolas, que llamaron a soldados 
negros "fumaron Yankees," eran a menudo más respetuosas de las tropas
negras que los oficiales blancos que las ordenaron. W. franco 
aquí Sargento-Principal Pullen, Jr. describió cómo los soldados 
negros casi se parecían tener dos enemigos durante la batalla del EL 
Caney y la captura de Santiago -- los españoles y los soldados 
americanos blancos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087326</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104164</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-perfect-hailstorm-of-bullets-a-black-sergeant-remembers-the-battle-of-san-juan-hill-in-1899</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
