<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108055</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108055</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087312</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A Labor Newspaper Derides the Myth of the Self-Made Man</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Arbeitszeitung verhöhnt den Mythus des 
Selbst-Gebildeten Mannes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un journal de travail moque du mythe de l'homme de
art de l'auto-portrait-made</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um jornal labor derides o mito do homem 
Self-Feito</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un giornale Di lavoro derides il mito dell'uomo 
Auto-Fatto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια εφημερίδα Derides εργασίας ο μύθος του 
μόνος-γίνονταυ ατόμου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un periódico de trabajo derides el mito del 
hombre Uno mismo-Hecho</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">One of the prime frustrations of labor organizers in the late 1800s was the powerful myth that every American could attain untold riches if sufficiently hardworking and ambitious. The faith that some workers had in this mythology of the "self-made man" inhibited unionization and the spread of radical ideology. The anonymous writer of this 1877 editorial in the  Labor Standard  took aim at the national obsession with making money at any cost .</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine der Hauptfrustrationen der 
Gewerkschaftsorganisatoren im späten 1800s war der leistungsfähige 
Mythus, dem jeder Amerikaner untold riches erreichen könnte, wenn 
genug fleißig und ehrgeizig. Der Glaube, den einige Arbeiter in
dieser Mythologie des "hatten, Selbst--bildete Mann" gehemmten 
Unionization und in der Verbreitung der radikalen Ideologie. Der
anonyme Verfasser von diesen 1877, die Leitartikel in der Richtlinie 
für angemessene Arbeitsbedingungen nahm, streben die nationale 
Obsession mit dem Verdienen des Geldes an allen möglichen Kosten an.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un des anéantissements principaux des 
propagandistes vers la fin de 1800s était le mythe puissant que 
chaque Américain pourrait atteindre la richesse incalculable si 
suffisamment assidu et ambitieux. La foi que quelques ouvriers 
ont eue en cette mythologie du l'"homme de art de l'auto-portrait-made" a empêché 
la syndicalisation et la diffusion de l'idéologie radicale. 
L'auteur anonyme de ces 1877 que l'éditorial dans la norme de 
travail a pris visent l'hantise nationale avec faire l'argent à 
n'importe quel coût.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uma das frustrações principais de organizers 
labor no 1800s atrasado era o mito poderoso que cada americano poderia
alcançar riches do untold se suficientemente hardworking e ambicioso.
A fé que alguns trabalhadores tiveram neste mythology 
"self-fêz do unionization inibido do homem" e na propagação do 
ideology radical. O escritor anonymous destes 1877 que o 
editorial no padrão labor fêz exame visa o obsession nacional com 
fazer o dinheiro em todo o custo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Una delle frustrazioni principali degli 
organizzatori di lavoro verso la fine di 1800s era il mito potente 
che ogni americano potrebbe raggiungere i riches del untold se 
sufficiente hardworking ed ambizioso. La fede che alcuni operai 
hanno avuti in questa mitologia "auto-ha fatto del unionization 
inibito dell'uomo" e nella diffusione dell'ideologia radicale. 
Il produttore anonimo di questi 1877 che editoriale nello 
standard Di lavoro ha preso punta sull'ossessione nazionale con 
fare i soldi a tutto il costo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια από τις πρωταρχικές απογοητεύσεις των διοργανωτών 
εργασίας προς το τέλος 1800s ήταν ο ισχυρός μύθος ότι κάθε 
Αμερικανός θα μπορούσε να επιτύχει τους ανεξιστόρητους πλούτους 
εάν αρκετά εργατικός και φιλόδοξος. Η πίστη που μερικοί 
εργαζόμενοι είχαν σε αυτήν την μυθολογία του "μόνος-γίνονταυ 
ατόμου" εμπόδισε τη συνδικαλικοποίηση και τη διάδοση της ριζικής 
ιδεολογίας. Ο ανώνυμος συγγραφέας αυτού του κύριου άρθρου 
1877 στα πρότυπα εργασίας πήρε το στόχο στην εθνική ιδεοληψία
με την παραγωγή των χρημάτων με οποιοδήποτε κόστος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una de las frustraciones primeras de organizadores
de trabajo en el último 1800s era el mito de gran alcance que cada 
americano podría lograr riquezas del untold si suficientemente es 
trabajador y ambicioso. La fe que algunos trabajadores tenían 
en esta mitología "uno mismo-hizo de la sindicalización inhibida a 
hombre" y la extensión de la ideología radical. El programa de
escritura anónimo de estos 1877 que el editorial en el estándar de 
trabajo tomó tiene como objetivo la obsesión nacional con la 
fabricación del dinero en cualquier coste.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087312</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108055</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-labor-newspaper-derides-the-myth-of-the-self-made-man</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
