<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104774</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104774</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209759</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Psychology In Everyday Life: The Psych Files podcast</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Psychologie In der Täglichen Lebensdauer: 
Das Psych archiviert podcast</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Psychologie Dans La Vie Quotidienne : Le 
Psych classe le podcast</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Psychology Na Vida Diária: O Psych arquiva 
o podcast</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Psicologia Nella Vita di tutti i giorni: Lo 
Psych archivia il podcast</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ψυχολογία στην καθημερινή ζωή: Το Psych 
αρχειοθετεί podcast</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Psicología En Vida Diaria: El Psych 
clasifía el podcast</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Psych Files is a blog and podcast written and hosted by an experienced psychology teacher and elearning specialist.  The content is designed for anyone interested in a variety of topics one would find in an introductory psychology course.   Upbeat and engaging podcasts are supported by links to websites and suggested classroom and student activities.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Psych Dateien ist ein blog und ein podcast, 
die von einem erfahrenen Psychologielehrer und von einem elearning 
Fachmann geschrieben werden und bewirtet sind. Der Inhalt ist 
für jedermann bestimmt, das an einer Vielzahl von Themen man 
interessiert wird, würde finden in einem einleitenden 
Psychologiekurs. Positive und engagierende podcasts werden 
durch Links zu den Web site und zu vorgeschlagenen Klassenzimmer- und 
Kursteilnehmeraktivitäten unterstützt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les fichiers de Psych est un blog et un podcast 
écrits et accueillis par un professeur expérimenté de psychologie 
et un spécialiste elearning. Le contenu est conçu pour 
n'importe qui intéressé à une variété des sujets un trouverait 
dans un cours préliminaire de psychologie. Des podcasts 
optimistes et s'engageants sont supportés par des liens aux sites 
Web et aux activités suggérées de salle de classe et d'étudiant.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As limas de Psych são um blog e um podcast 
escritos e hospedados por um professor experiente do psychology e por 
um specialist elearning. O índice é projetado para qualquer um
interessado em uma variedade dos tópicos um encontraria em um curso 
introdutório do psychology. Upbeat e os podcasts acoplando são
suportados pelas ligações aos Web site e às atividades sugeridas da
sala de aula e do estudante.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli archivi di Psych è un blog e un podcast 
scritti ed ospitati da un insegnante con esperienza di psicologia e da
un esperto elearning. Il soddisfare è progettato per chiunque 
interessato ad una varietà di soggetti uno troverebbe in un corso 
introduttivo di psicologia. I podcasts ottimistici e d'agganci 
sono sostenuti dai collegamenti ai Web site ed alle attività 
suggerite dell'allievo e dell'aula.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα αρχεία Psych είναι ένα blog και podcast 
γραπτός και φιλοξενημένος από έναν πεπειραμένο δάσκαλο 
ψυχολογίας και έναν elearning ειδικό. Το περιεχόμενο 
σχεδιάζεται για καθένα ενδιαφερόμενο σε ποικίλα θέματα που 
κάποιος θα έβρισκε σε μια εισαγωγική σειρά μαθημάτων ψυχολογίας.
Οπτιμιστής και δεσμεύοντας podcasts υποστηρίζεται από τις
συνδέσεις με τους ιστοχώρους και τις προτεινόμενες δραστηριότητες 
τάξεων και σπουδαστών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los ficheros de Psych son un blog y un podcast 
escritos y recibidos por un profesor experimentado de la psicología y
un especialista elearning. El contenido se diseña para 
cualquier persona interesada en una variedad de los asuntos uno 
encontraría en un curso introductorio de la psicología. Upbeat
y los podcasts de acoplamiento son utilizados por conexiones a los Web
site y a las actividades sugeridas de la sala de clase y del 
estudiante.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MICHAEL A. BRITT, PH.D.
FN:MICHAEL A. BRITT, PH.D.
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209759</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104774</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/psychology-in-everyday-life-the-psych-files-podcast</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
