<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107837</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107837</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086039</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Statistics Online Computational Resource for Education and Research</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Statistik-Onlineberechnungshilfsmittel für 
Ausbildung und Forschung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ressource de calcul en ligne de statistiques pour 
l'éducation et la recherche</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Recurso computacional em linha dos statistics para
a instrução e a pesquisa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Risorsa di calcolo in linea di statistiche per 
formazione e ricerca</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε απευθείας σύνδεση υπολογιστικό στοιχείο 
συμπεριφοράς στατιστικών για την εκπαίδευση και την έρευνα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Recurso de cómputo en línea de la estadística 
para la educación y la investigación</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The goals of the Statistics Online Computational Resource (www.SOCR.ucla.edu) are to design, validate and freely disseminate knowledge. Specifically, SOCR provides portable online aids for probability and statistics education, technology based instruction and statistical computing. SOCR tools and resources include a repository of interactive applets, computational and graphing tools, instructional and course materials.

The core SOCR educational and computational components include: Distributions (interactive graphs and calculators), Experiments (virtual computer-generated analogs of popular games and processes), Analyses (collection of common web-accessible tools for statistical data analysis), Games (interfaces and simulations to real-life processes), Modeler (tools for distribution, polynomial and spectral model-fitting and simulation), Graphs, Plots and Charts (comprehensive web-based tools for exploratory data analysis), Additional Tools (other statistical tools and resources), SOCR Wiki (collaborative Wiki resource), Educational Materials and Hands-on Activities (varieties of SOCR educational materials), SOCR Statistical Consulting and Statistical Computing Libraries.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Ziele des 
Statistik-Onlineberechnungshilfsmittels (www.SOCR.ucla.edu) sind zu 
konzipieren, validieren und verbreiten frei Wissen. Spezifisch 
stellt SOCR bewegliche Onlinehilfsmittel für Wahrscheinlichkeit und 
Statistikausbildung, Technologie gegründete Anweisung und das 
statistische Rechnen zur Verfügung. SOCR Hilfsmittel und 
Betriebsmittel enthalten einen Behälter der interaktiven applet, 
rechnerisch und Hilfsmittel graphisch darstellend, schließen 
anweisender und des Kurses materials.The Kern SOCR pädagogische und 
Berechnungsbestandteile ein: Verteilungen (interaktive Diagramme
und Rechner), Experimente (virtuelle computererzeugte Entsprechungen 
der populären Spiele und der Prozesse), Analysen (Ansammlung 
geläufige Web-zugängliche Hilfsmittel für statistische 
Datenanalyse), Spiele (Schnittstellen und Simulationen zu den 
real-life Prozessen), Modellierer (Hilfsmittel für Verteilung, 
polynomische und spektrale Modell-Befestigung und Simulation), stellt,
Plots und Diagramme (komplette Web-gegründete Hilfsmittel für 
forschende Datenanalyse), zusätzliche Hilfsmittel (andere 
statistische Hilfsmittel und Betriebsmittel), SOCR Wiki 
(gemeinschaftliches Wiki Hilfsmittel), pädagogische Materialien und 
Blindeinschub Aktivitäten (Vielzahl SOCR der pädagogischen 
Materialien), SOCR statistisches Beraten und statistische rechnende 
Bibliotheken graphisch dar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les buts de la ressource de calcul en ligne de 
statistiques (www.SOCR.ucla.edu) sont de concevoir, valident et 
diffusent librement la connaissance. Spécifiquement, SOCR 
fournit les aides en ligne portatives pour la probabilité et 
l'éducation de statistiques, l'instruction basée par technologie et 
le calcul statistique. Les outils et les ressources de SOCR 
incluent un dépôt des applet interactifs, de calcul et représentant
graphiquement des outils, le noyau les composants éducatifs et de 
calcul de SOCR d'instruction et du cours materials.The incluent : 
Les distributions (graphiques et calculatrices interactifs), les
expériences (analogues générés par ordinateur virtuels des jeux et
les processus populaires), les analyses (collection d'outils 
Web-accessibles communs pour l'analyse de données statistique), jeux 
(des interfaces et des simulations aux processus réels), le modeleur 
(outils pour la distribution, le modèle-ajustage de précision 
polynôme et spectral et la simulation), représente graphiquement, 
des traçages et des diagrammes (outils Web-basés complets pour 
l'analyse de données exploratoire), des outils supplémentaires 
(d'autres outils et ressources statistiques), SOCR Wiki (ressource de 
collaboration de Wiki), matériaux éducatifs et activités à 
commande manuelle (variétés de matériaux éducatifs de SOCR), 
consultation statistique de SOCR et bibliothèques de calcul 
statistiques.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os objetivos do recurso computacional em linha dos
statistics (www.SOCR.ucla.edu) são projetar, validam e disseminate 
livremente o conhecimento. Especificamente, SOCR fornece dae 
(dispositivo automático de entrada) em linha portáteis para a 
probabilidade e a instrução dos statistics, a instrução baseada 
tecnologia e computar estatístico. As ferramentas e os recursos
de SOCR incluem um repositório de applet interativos, computacional e
representando graficamente ferramentas, o núcleo componentes 
educacionais e computacionais de SOCR instrutivo e do curso 
materials.The inclui: As distribuições (gráficos e 
calculadoras interativos), experiências (analogs computer-generated 
virtuais de jogos e processos populares), análises (coleção de 
ferramentas Web-acessíveis comuns para a análise de dados 
estatística), jogos (relações e simulações aos processos 
real-life), modeler (ferramentas para a distribuição, modelo-encaixe
polynomial e spectral e simulação), representam graficamente, lotes 
e cartas (ferramentas Web-baseadas detalhadas para a análise de dados
exploratory), ferramentas adicionais (outros ferramentas e recursos 
estatísticos), SOCR Wiki (recurso collaborative de Wiki), materiais 
educacionais e atividades hands-on (variedades de materiais 
educacionais de SOCR), consultar estatístico de SOCR e bibliotecas 
computando estatísticas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli obiettivi della risorsa di calcolo in linea di
statistiche (www.SOCR.ucla.edu) sono di progettare, convalidano e 
liberamente diffondono la conoscenza. Specificamente, SOCR 
fornisce i sussidi in linea portatili per la probabilità e la 
formazione di statistiche, l'istruzione basata tecnologia e la 
computazione statistica. Gli strumenti e le risorse di SOCR 
includono un deposito dei applet interattivi, di calcolo e 
rappresentando graficamente gli strumenti, il nucleo componenti 
educativi e di calcolo di SOCR di corso e didattico materials.The 
include: Le distribuzioni (grafici e calcolatori interattivi), 
esperimenti (analoghi generati da calcolatore virtuali dei giochi e 
processi popolari), analisi (accumulazione degli strumenti 
Web-accessibili comuni per analisi di dati statistica), giochi 
(interfacce e simulazioni ai processi in vivo), modeler (strumenti per
distribuzione, modello-montaggio polinomiale e spettrale e 
simulazione), rappresenta graficamente, diagrammi e tabelle (strumenti
Web-basati completi per analisi di dati esplorativa), strumenti 
supplementari (altri strumenti e risorse statistici), SOCR Wiki 
(risorsa di collaborazione di Wiki), materiali educativi ed attività 
hands-on (varietà di materiali educativi di SOCR), consulto 
statistico di SOCR e librerie di calcolo statistiche.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι στόχοι του σε απευθείας σύνδεση υπολογιστικού 
στοιχείου συμπεριφοράς στατιστικών (www.SOCR.ucla.edu) είναι να
σχεδιαστεί, να επικυρωθεί και να διαδοθεί ελεύθερα η γνώση. 
Συγκεκριμένα, SOCR παρέχει τις φορητές σε απευθείας 
σύνδεση ενισχύσεις για την πιθανότητα και την εκπαίδευση 
στατιστικών, βασισμένη στην τεχνολογία οδηγία και στατιστικός 
υπολογισμός. Τα εργαλεία SOCR και τα στοιχεία 
συμπεριφοράς περιλαμβάνουν μια αποθήκη των διαλογικών applets, 
των υπολογιστικών και δίνοντας με γραφική παράσταση εργαλείων, 
των εκπαιδευτικών και υλικών σειράς μαθημάτων Τα 
εκπαιδευτικά και υπολογιστικά τμήματα πυρήνων SOCR 
περιλαμβάνουν: Διανομές (διαλογικοί γραφικές παραστάσεις 
και υπολογιστές), πειράματα (εικονικά παραγόμενα από υπολογιστή 
ανάλογα των δημοφιλών παιχνιδιών και των διαδικασιών), αναλύσεις 
(συλλογή των κοινών Ιστός-προσιτών εργαλείων για την ανάλυση 
στατιστικών στοιχείων), παιχνίδια (διαπροσωπείες και 
προσομοιώσεις στις πραγματικές διαδικασίες), Modeler (εργαλεία 
για τη διανομή, την πολυωνυμική και φασματική 
πρότυπος-συναρμολόγηση και την προσομοίωση), γραφικές 
παραστάσεις, πλοκές και διαγράμματα (περιεκτικά βασισμένα στο 
WEB εργαλεία για τη διερευνητική ανάλυση στοιχείων), πρόσθετα 
εργαλεία (άλλα στατιστικά εργαλεία και στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς), 
SOCR Wiki (συνεργάσιμο στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς Wiki), 
εκπαιδευτικά υλικά και εμπράγματες δραστηριότητες (ποικιλίες των 
εκπαιδευτικών υλικών SOCR), στατιστική διαβούλευση SOCR και 
στατιστικές βιβλιοθήκες υπολογισμού.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las metas del recurso de cómputo en línea de la 
estadística (www.SOCR.ucla.edu) son diseñar, validan y diseminan 
libremente conocimiento. Específicamente, SOCR proporciona a 
las ayudas en línea portables para la probabilidad y la educación de
la estadística, a la instrucción basada tecnología y a computar 
estadístico. Las herramientas y los recursos de SOCR incluyen 
un depósito de applet interactivos, de cómputo y representando las 
herramientas gra'ficamente, la base educacional y del curso los 
componentes educativos y de cómputo de SOCR materials.The incluye: 
Las distribuciones (gráficos y calculadoras interactivos), 
experimentos (análogos originados en ordenador virtuales de juegos y 
los procesos populares), análisis (colección de las herramientas 
Web-accesibles comunes para el análisis de datos estadístico), 
juegos (los interfaces y las simulaciones a los procesos de la vida 
real), modeler (herramientas para la distribución, modelo-guarnicio'n
polinómica y espectral y simulación), representan gra'ficamente, los
diagramas y las cartas (herramientas Web-basadas comprensivas para el 
análisis de datos exploratorio), las herramientas adicionales (otras 
herramientas y recursos estadísticos), SOCR Wiki (recurso de 
colaboración de Wiki), materiales educativos y actividades con manos 
(variedades de materiales educativos de SOCR), el consultar 
estadístico de SOCR y bibliotecas que computan estadísticas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:IVO D. DINOV, PHD
FN:IVO D. DINOV, PHD
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:NICOLAS CHRISTOU, PHD
FN:NICOLAS CHRISTOU, PHD
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086039</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">GNU Free Documentation License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107837</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/statistics-online-computational-resource-for-education-and-research</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
