<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105273</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105273</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200399</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">All Creatures Microscopically Small</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Alle Geschöpfe Mikroskopisch Klein</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Toutes les Créatures Au microscope Petites</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Todas as Criaturas Microscopically Pequenas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Tutte le Creature Microscopicamente Piccole</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Όλα τα πλάσματα μικροσκοπικά μικρά</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Todas las Criaturas Microscópico Pequeñas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This lesson is part of the New York Times Learning Network, a service in which lesson plans are created to accompany newspaper articles. In this lesson, students investigate the physical and behavioral characteristics of different microbes and create research- based 'Microbe Biographies.' Students then visually compare microbe sizes and examine how the size of a microbe relates to its physical and behavioral characteristics. The lesson includes an overview, time allowance, objectives, list of resources/materials, activities/procedures, questions for discussion, evaluation/assessment, vocabulary, extension activities, interdisciplinary connections, links to information on the web, and academic content standards with links to access a database of each state's standards. The site also includes links to related articles and the lesson plan archives.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Lektion ist ein Teil der New York Zeiten, 
die Netz, einen Service erlernen, in dem Lektionpläne erstellt 
werden, um Zeitungsartikel zu begleiten. In dieser Lektion 
forschen Kursteilnehmer die körperlichen und Verhaltenseigenschaften 
der unterschiedlichen Mikroben nach und erstellen Forschung 
gegründete ' Mikrobe Biographien.' Kursteilnehmer dann 
vergleichen sichtlich Mikrobe Größen und überprüfen, wie die 
Größe einer Mikrobe auf seinen körperlichen und 
Verhaltenseigenschaften in Verbindung steht. Die Lektion 
schließt einen Überblick, Pufferzeit, Lernziele, Liste von 
resources/materials, activities/procedures, Fragen für Diskussion, 
evaluation/assessment, Wortschatz, Extension Aktivitäten, 
interdisziplinäre Anschlüsse, Links zu den Informationen über das 
Web und akademische zufriedene Standards mit Links ein, um auf eine 
Datenbank der Standards jedes Zustandes zuzugreifen. Die Site 
schließt auch Links zu in Verbindung stehenden Artikeln und zu den 
Lektionplanarchiven ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette leçon fait partie des temps de New York 
apprenant le réseau, un service dans lequel des plans de leçon sont 
créés pour accompagner des articles de journal. Dans cette 
leçon, les étudiants étudient les caractéristiques physiques et 
comportementales de différents microbes et créent des 'biographies 
de microbe basées par recherche.' Les étudiants comparent 
alors visuellement des tailles de microbe et examinent comment la 
taille d'un microbe associe à ses caractéristiques physiques et 
comportementales. La leçon inclut une vue d'ensemble, 
l'allocation de temps, les objectifs, la liste de resources/materials,
l'activities/procedures, les questions pour la discussion, 
l'evaluation/assessment, le vocabulaire, les activités d'extension, 
les connexions interdisciplinaires, les liens à l'information sur le 
Web, et les normes contentes d'universitaire avec des liens pour 
accéder à une base de données des normes de chaque état. Le 
site inclut également des liens aux articles relatifs et aux archives
de plan de leçon.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta lição é parte dos tempos de New York que 
aprendem a rede, um serviço em que as plantas da lição são criadas
para acompanhar artigos de jornal. Nesta lição, os estudantes 
investigam as características físicas e behavioral de micróbios 
diferentes e críam ' biografias baseadas pesquisa do micróbio.' 
Os estudantes então comparam visualmente tamanhos do micróbio 
e examinam como o tamanho de um micróbio se relaciona a suas 
características físicas e behavioral. A lição inclui uma 
vista geral, a permissão de tempo, os objetivos, a lista de 
resources/materials, o activities/procedures, as perguntas para a 
discussão, o evaluation/assessment, o vocabulário, as atividades da 
extensão, conexões interdisciplinary, ligações à informação no 
Web, e padrões satisfeitos academic com ligações para alcançar uma
base de dados de padrões de cada estado. O local inclui também
as ligações aos artigos relacionados e aos arquivos da planta da 
lição.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa lezione fa parte dei tempi de New York che 
imparano la rete, un servizio in cui i programmi di lezione sono 
creati per accompagnare gli articoli di stampa. In questa 
lezione, gli allievi studiano le caratteristiche fisiche e del 
comportamento dei microbi differenti e creano 'le biografie del 
microbo basate ricerca.' Gli allievi allora confrontano 
visivamente i formati del microbo ed esaminano come il formato di un 
microbo si riferisce alle relative caratteristiche fisiche e del 
comportamento. La lezione include una descrizione, il permesso 
di tempo, gli obiettivi, lista di resources/materials, 
activities/procedures, domande per la discussione, 
evaluation/assessment, il vocabolario, le attività di estensione, i 
collegamenti interdisciplinari, collegamenti alle informazioni sul Web
e gli standard soddisfatti accademici con i collegamenti per accedere 
ad una base di dati di ciascuno dichiarano gli standard. Il
luogo egualmente include i collegamenti agli articoli relativi ed agli
archivi di programma di lezione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το μάθημα είναι μέρος του δικτύου εκμάθησης 
New York Times, μια υπηρεσία στην οποία τα σχέδια 
μαθήματος δημιουργούνται για να συνοδεύσουν τα άρθρα εφημερίδων. 
Σε αυτό το μάθημα, οι σπουδαστές ερευνούν τα φυσικά και 
συμπεριφοριστικά χαρακτηριστικά των διαφορετικών μικροβίων και 
δημιουργούν την έρευνα - βασισμένες "βιογραφίες μικροβίων." 
Οι σπουδαστές έπειτα οπτικά συγκρίνουν τα μεγέθη μικροβίων
και εξετάζουν πώς το μέγεθος ενός μικροβίου αφορά τα φυσικά και
συμπεριφοριστικά χαρακτηριστικά του. Το μάθημα περιλαμβάνει 
μια επισκόπηση, χρονικό επίδομα, στόχοι, κατάλογος στοιχείων 
συμπεριφοράς/υλικών, δραστηριοτήτων/διαδικασιών, ερωτήσεις για τη
συζήτηση, την αξιολόγηση/την αξιολόγηση, το λεξιλόγιο, τις 
δραστηριότητες επέκτασης, τις διεπιστημονικές συνδέσεις, τις 
συνδέσεις με τις πληροφορίες για τον Ιστό, και τα ακαδημαϊκά 
ικανοποιημένα πρότυπα με τις συνδέσεις για να έχει πρόσβαση σε 
μια βάση δεδομένων των προτύπων κάθε κράτους. Η περιοχή 
περιλαμβάνει επίσης τις συνδέσεις με τα σχετικά άρθρα και τα 
αρχεία σχεδίων μαθήματος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta lección es parte de los tiempos de Nueva 
York que aprenden la red, un servicio en el cual los planes de la 
lección se creen para acompañar los artículos periodísticos. 
En esta lección, los estudiantes investigan las 
características físicas y del comportamiento de diversos microbios y
crean ' biografías basadas investigación del microbio.' Los 
estudiantes entonces comparan visualmente tallas del microbio y 
examinan cómo la talla de un microbio se relaciona con sus 
características físicas y del comportamiento. La lección 
incluye una descripción, el permiso de tiempo, objetivos, la lista de
resources/materials, activities/procedures, las preguntas para la 
discusión, evaluation/assessment, vocabulario, actividades de la 
extensión, conexiones interdisciplinarias, conexiones a la 
información sobre el Web, y estándares contentos académicos con 
conexiones para tener acceso a una base de datos de los estándares de
cada estado. El sitio también incluye conexiones a los 
artículos relacionados y a los archivos del plan de la lección.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ALISON ZIMBALIST
FN:ALISON ZIMBALIST
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:THE NEW YORK TIMES LEARNING NETWORK
FN:THE NEW YORK TIMES LEARNING NETWORK
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200399</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105273</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/all-creatures-microscopically-small</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
