<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106975</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106975</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087393</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">An NAACP Official Calls for Censorship of  The Birth of a Nation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein NAACP Beamt-Aufrufe für Zensur der Geburt 
einer Nation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Appels d'un fonctionnaire de NAACP pour la censure
de la naissance d'une nation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Atendimentos de um oficial de NAACP para a censura
do nascimento de uma nação</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Richieste del funzionario di NAACP per censura 
della nascita di una nazione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επίσημες κλήσεις ένα NAACP για τη λογοκρισία της 
γέννησης ενός έθνους</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Llamadas de un funcionario de NAACP para la 
censura del nacimiento de una nación</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Birth of a Nation , which opened in March 1915, was simultaneously a landmark in the history of American cinema and a landmark in American racism. The film depicted the South, following the assassination of President Lincoln, as ruled by rapacious African Americans, who by the film's end were heroically overthrown from power by the Ku Klux Klan. The National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP) attempted to mount boycott of the film, but it failed to stir significant white opposition. The NAACP changed its tactics; this April 17, 1915, letter from NAACP national secretary Mary Childs Nerney described the organization's efforts, largely in vain, to get local film censors to remove particularly racist scenes .  The NAACP's ongoing national campaign to censor the film produced decidedly mixed results. Despite success in Boston and Chicago in securing several minor cuts in the film's release print, by year's end distributors could show  The Birth of a Nation  almost anywhere in the country.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Geburt einer Nation, die im März 1915 sich 
öffnete, war gleichzeitig ein Grenzstein in der Geschichte des 
amerikanischen Kinos und ein Grenzstein im amerikanischen Rassismus. 
Der Film stellte das Süd bildlich dar und folgte der Ermordung 
des Präsidenten Lincoln, wie von den rapacious afrikanischen 
Amerikanern angeordnet, die durch das Ende des Filmes heroisch von der
Energie durch das Ku Klux Klan besiegt wurden. Die nationale 
Verbindung für die Zuführung der Farbiger (NAACP) versuchte, Boykott
des Filmes, aber ihn einzuhängen nicht konnte bedeutende weiße 
Opposition rühren. Das NAACP änderte seine Taktiken; 
dieser April 17, 1915, Zeichen NAACP von der nationalen 
Sekretärin Mary Childs Nerney beschrieb die Bemühungen der 
Organisation, groß in nichtigem, lokale Filmzensoren zu veranlassen, 
besonders rassistische Szenen zu löschen. Die NAACP's 
fortwährende nationale Kampagne, zum des Filmes zu zensieren 
produzierte entschieden Mischresultate. Trotz des Erfolges in 
Boston und Chicagos, wenn, einige geringe sichernd, schneidet den 
Freigabedruck des Filmes, durch Verteiler Ende des Jahres könnte die 
Geburt einer Nation im Land fast überall zeigen ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La naissance d'une nation, qui s'est ouverte en 
mars 1915, était simultanément une borne limite dans l'histoire du 
cinéma américain et une borne limite dans le racisme américain. 
Le film a dépeint le du sud, suivant l'assassinat du 
Président Lincoln, comme régné par les Américains africains 
rapaces, qui par l'extrémité du film ont été héroïquement 
renversés de la puissance par le Ku Klux Klan. L'association 
nationale pour l'avancement des personnes de couleur (NAACP) a essayé
de monter le boycott du film, mais lui n'a pas remué l'opposition 
blanche significative. Le NAACP a changé sa tactique ; 
cet 17 avril 1915, lettre de secrétaire national Mary Childs 
Nerney de NAACP a décrit les efforts de l'organisation, en grande 
partie dans vain, d'obliger les censeurs locaux de film à retirer en 
particulier des scènes racistes. La campagne nationale continue
de NAACP's pour censurer le film a produit des résultats décidément
mélangés. En dépit du succès à Boston et de la Chicago en 
fixant plusieurs mineurs coupe dedans la copie de la version du film, 
par les distributeurs de l'extrémité de l'année pourrait montrer la
naissance d'une nation presque n'importe où dans le pays.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O nascimento de uma nação, que abrisse em março
1915, era simultaneamente um marco no history do cinema americano e um
marco no racism americano. A película descreveu o sul, seguindo
o assassination do presidente Lincoln, como governado pelos americanos
africanos rapacious, que pela extremidade da película overthrown 
heroically da potência pelo Ku Klux Klan. A associação 
nacional para o avanço dos povos coloridos (NAACP) tentou montá-la o
boycott da película, mas não agitou a oposição branca 
significativa. O NAACP mudou suas táticas; este abril 17,
1915, letra da secretária nacional Mary Childs Nerney de NAACP 
descreveu os esforços da organização, pela maior parte em vão, 
começar censores locais da película remover particularmente as cenas
racist. A campanha nacional ongoing de NAACP's para censor a 
película produziu resultados decidedly misturados. Apesar do 
sucesso em Boston e da Chicago em fixar diversos menores corta dentro 
a cópia da liberação da película, por distribuidores da 
extremidade do ano poderia mostrar o nascimento de uma nação quase 
em qualquer lugar no país.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La nascita di una nazione, che si è aperta nel 
mese di marzo del 1915, era simultaneamente un limite nella storia del
cinematografo americano e un limite nel razzismo americano. La 
pellicola ha descritto il del sud, seguendo l'assassinio del 
presidente Lincoln, come regolato dagli Americani africani rapacious, 
che dall'estremità della pellicola eroico overthrown da potenza dal 
Ku Klux Klan. L'associazione nazionale per l'avanzamento della 
gente colorata (NAACP) ha tentato di montarla il boicottaggio della 
pellicola, ma non è riuscito a mescolare l'opposizione bianca 
significativa. Il NAACP ha cambiato le relative tattiche; 
questo 17 aprile 1915, lettera dalla segretaria nazionale Mary 
Childs Nerney di NAACP ha descritto gli sforzi dell'organizzazione, in
gran parte in inutile, convincere i censori locali della pellicola a 
rimuovere specialmente le scene razziste. La campagna nazionale 
continua di NAACP's per censurare la pellicola ha fornito i risultati 
decisamente mixed. Malgrado successo a Boston e Chicago nel 
fissaggio dei parecchi secondari taglia dentro la stampa della 
versione della pellicola, dai distributori dell'estremità dell'anno 
potrebbe mostrare la nascita di una nazione quasi dovunque nel paese.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η γέννηση ενός έθνους, που άνοιξε τον Μάρτιο του 
1915, ήταν ταυτόχρονα ένα ορόσημο στην ιστορία του 
αμερικανικού κινηματογράφου και ένα ορόσημο στον αμερικανικό 
ρατσισμό. Η ταινία απεικόνισε το νότο, μετά από τη 
δολοφονία του Προέδρου Lincoln, όπως κυβερνιέται από 
αρπακτικούς αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς, οι οποίοι από το τέλος της
ταινίας νικήθηκαν ηρωικά από τη δύναμη από το Ku Klux 
Klan. Η εθνική ένωση για την πρόοδο των έγχρωμων 
ανθρώπων (NAACP) προσπάθησε να επικολλήσει το μποϊκοτάρισμα 
της ταινίας, αλλά απέτυχε να ανακατώσει τη σημαντική άσπρη 
αντίθεση. Το NAACP άλλαξε την τακτική του  αυτού 
του 17 Απριλίου ..1915, επιστολή από NAACP τον εθνικό 
γραμματέα Mary Childs Nerney περιέγραψε τις προσπάθειες 
της οργάνωσης, κατά ένα μεγάλο μέρος μάταια, για να πάρει τους 
τοπικούς λογοκριτές ταινιών για να αφαιρέσει ιδιαίτερα τις 
ρατσιστικές σκηνές. Η τρέχουσα εθνική εκστρατεία του 
NAACP για να λογοκρίνει την ταινία παρήγαγε τα οριστικά μικτά 
αποτελέσματα. Παρά την επιτυχία στη Βοστώνη και το Σικάγο 
στην εξασφάλιση διάφορων δευτερευουσών αποκοπών στην τυπωμένη 
ύλη έκδοσης της ταινίας, από το τέλος του χρόνου οι διανομείς 
θα μπορούσαν να εμφανίσουν τη γέννηση ενός έθνους σχεδόν 
οπουδήποτε στη χώρα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El nacimiento de una nación, que se abrió en 
marcha de 1915, era simultáneamente una señal en la historia del 
cine americano y una señal en racismo americano. La película 
representó el del sur, siguiendo el asesinato de presidente Lincoln, 
según lo gobernado por los americanos africanos rapaces, que por el 
extremo de la película heroico fueron derrocados de potencia por el 
Ku Klux Klan. La asociación nacional para el adelanto de la 
gente coloreada (NAACP) procuró montar el boicoteo de la película, 
pero la no pudo revolver la oposición blanca significativa. El 
NAACP cambió sus táctica; este 17 de abril de 1915, carta 
de la secretaria nacional Maria Childs Nerney de NAACP describió los 
esfuerzos de la organización, en gran parte en inútil, de conseguir 
a censores locales de la película quitar determinado escenas racist. 
La campaña nacional en curso de NAACP's para censurar la 
película produjo resultados decididamente mezclados. A pesar de
éxito en Boston y Chicago en asegurar varios de menor importancia 
corta adentro la impresión del desbloquear de la película, por las 
distribuidores del extremo del año podría mostrar el nacimiento de 
una nación casi dondequiera en el país.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087393</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106975</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/an-naacp-official-calls-for-censorship-of-the-birth-of-a-nation</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
