<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108406</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108406</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213110</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Weather Underground: Midwest Temperature</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wetter Unterirdisch: Mittelwesten 
Temperatur</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Survivez à à souterrain : La 
Température de Midwest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Tempo Subterrâneo: Temperatura De Midwest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Tempo Sotterraneo: Temperatura Del Midwest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Καιρός υπόγεια: Midwest θερμοκρασία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Tiempo Subterráneo: Temperatura De Cercano 
oeste</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This commercial website offers weather data from throughout the country. This section focuses on Midwest Temperature. Users can click on weather contour maps and find local weather forecasts. Data also includes wind-chill, humidity, dew point, visibility, snow, jet stream and visible satellite maps. Health maps, UV forecast, flu activity and air quality are also available. From this site users can link to different regions of the United State and individual states and access weather information for those regions and states. This is an excellent site for finding local and regional weather data.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese kommerziellen Web site Angebot-Wetterdaten 
aus in dem Land. Dieses Kapitel konzentriert auf Mittelwesten 
Temperatur. Benutzer können an klicken verwittern 
Höhenlinienkarten und finden lokale Wettervorhersagen. Daten 
enthalten auch Wind-Schauer, Feuchtigkeit, Taupunkt, Sicht, Schnee, 
Strahl Strom und sichtbare Satellitenkarten. Gesundheit Karten, 
UVPROGNOSE, Grippeaktivität und Luftqualität sind auch vorhanden. 
Von dieser Site können Benutzer mit unterschiedlichen Regionen 
des vereinigten Zustandes und der einzelnen Zustände binden und auf 
Wetterinformationen für jene Regionen und Zustände zugreifen. 
Dieses ist eine ausgezeichnete Site für das Finden der lokalen 
und regionalen Wetterdaten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les offres commerciales de ce site Web 
survivent à à des données de dans tout le pays. Cette 
section se concentre sur la température de Midwest. Les 
utilisateurs peuvent cliquer en fonction survivent à à 
des cartes de découpe et les gens du pays de trouvaille 
survivent à à des prévisions. Les données également 
incluent le vent-froid, humidité, point de condensation, visibilité,
neige, voyagent en jet le jet et les cartes satellites visibles. 
Les cartes de santé, la prévision UV, l'activité de grippe et
la qualité d'air sont également disponibles. De ce site les 
utilisateurs peuvent joindre à différentes régions de l'état uni 
et les états et l'accès individuels survivent à à l'information
pour ces régions et états. C'est un excellent site pour la 
conclusion local et régional survivez à aux données.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Estes dados comerciais do tempo das ofertas do Web
site durante todo do país. Esta seção focaliza na temperatura
de Midwest. Os usuários podem estalar sobre resistem a mapas de
contorno e encontram previsões de tempo locais. Os dados 
incluem também o vento-frio, a umidade, o ponto de orvalho, a 
visibilidade, a neve, o córrego do jato e mapas satellite visíveis. 
Os mapas da saúde, a previsão UV, a atividade do flu e a 
qualidade do ar estão também disponíveis. Deste local os 
usuários podem ligar às regiões diferentes do estado unido e dos 
estados individuais e alcançar a informação do tempo para aqueles 
regiões e estados. Este é um local excelente para encontrar 
dados locais e regionais do tempo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questi dati commerciali del tempo di offerte di 
Web site durante dal paese. Questa sezione mette a fuoco sulla 
temperatura del Midwest. Gli utenti possono scattarsi sopra 
espongono all'aria i programmi di profilo e trovano i bollettini 
meteorologici locali. I dati egualmente includono il 
vento-freddo, l'umidità, il punto di rugiada, la visibilità, la 
neve, il flusso del getto ed i programmi satelliti visibili. I 
programmi di salute, la previsione UV, l'attività di flu e la 
qualità dell'aria sono egualmente disponibili. Da questo luogo 
utenti possono collegarsi alle regioni differenti del unito 
Dichiarano e l'individuo dichiara e le informazioni del 
tempo di accesso per quelle regioni e dichiara. Ciò è 
un luogo eccellente per l'individuazione dei dati locali e regionali 
del tempo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το εμπορικό καιρικό στοιχείο προσφορών 
ιστοχώρου από σε όλη τη χώρα. Αυτό το τμήμα εστιάζει 
midwest στη θερμοκρασία. Οι χρήστες μπορούν να χτυπήσουν 
στους χάρτες καιρικού περιγράμματος και να βρούν τις τοπικές 
καιρικές προβλέψεις. Το στοιχείο περιλαμβάνει επίσης την 
αέρας-ψύχρα, την υγρασία, το σημείο δροσιάς, τη διαφάνεια, το 
χιόνι, το αεριωθούμενο ρεύμα και τους ορατούς δορυφορικούς 
χάρτες. Οι χάρτες υγείας, η UV πρόβλεψη, η δραστηριότητα
γρίπης και η ατμοσφαιρική ποιότητα είναι επίσης διαθέσιμοι. 
Από αυτήν την περιοχή οι χρήστες μπορούν να συνδέσουν με 
τις διαφορετικές περιοχές του ενωμένου κράτους και των 
μεμονωμένων κρατών και καιρικών των πληροφοριών πρόσβασης για 
εκείνα τα περιοχές και κράτη. Αυτό είναι μια άριστη 
περιοχή για την εύρεση των τοπικών και περιφερειακών καιρικών 
στοιχείων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Estos datos comerciales del tiempo de las ofertas 
del Web site a través del país. Esta sección se centra en la 
temperatura de Cercano oeste. Los utilizadores pueden hacer clic
encendido resisten a correspondencias de contorno y encuentran partes 
meteorológicos locales. Los datos también incluyen 
viento-frialdad, humedad, el punto de condensación, la visibilidad, 
la nieve, la secuencia del jet y correspondencias basadas en los 
satélites visibles. Las correspondencias de la salud, el 
pronóstico UV, la actividad de la gripe y la calidad del aire están 
también disponibles. De este sitio los utilizadores pueden 
conectar a diversas regiones del estado unido y de los estados 
individuales y tener acceso a la información del tiempo para esas 
regiones y estados. Esto es un sitio excelente para encontrar 
datos locales y regionales del tiempo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213110</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108406</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/weather-underground-midwest-temperature</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
