<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103744</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103744</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086739</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Plessy  v.  Ferguson : Justice Harlan Dissents</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Plessy V. Ferguson: Gerechtigkeit Harlan 
Stimmt Nicht überein</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Plessy v. Ferguson : Le Juge Harlan Diffère
d'opinion</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Plessy v. Ferguson: A Justiça Harlan 
Dissents</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Plessy v. Ferguson: La Giustizia Harlan 
Dissents</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Plessy V. Ferguson: Διαφωνίες Harlan 
δικαιοσύνης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Plessy v. Ferguson: La Justicia Harlan 
Dissents</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1890, Louisiana passed a law compelling railways to "provide equal but separate accommodations for the white, and colored, races," joining several southern states that had already passed similar laws. African Americans in New Orleans fought the new law in several ways, including a legal challenge. In 1892, they arranged for Homer Adolph Plessy to be arrested on an East Louisiana Railway train for refusing to move to the car designated for "colored passengers." The case eventually reached the U.S. Supreme Court in 1896 as  Plessy v. Ferguson  (named for the judge who first ruled against Plessy). The Supreme Court decision argued that as long as racially separate facilities were equal, they did not violate the Fourteenth Amendment's guarantees of equal protection of the law. The lone dissenter was Justice John Marshall Harlan, himself a former slaveholder from Kentucky. While Harlan had opposed the Thirteenth Amendment (which abolished slavery), the experience of seeing brutal attacks on African Americans in the immediate post-Civil War years apparently changed him. In his  Plessy  dissent, he insisted that "all citizens are equal before the law" and correctly predicted that upholding the Louisiana law would lead to the passage of even more laws segregating African Americans. Not until 1954 did the Supreme Court accept Harlan's arguments, when it reversed  Plessy v. Ferguson  with its  Brown v. Board of Education  decision.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1890 stellen Louisiana geführte unwiderstehliche 
Gleise eines Gesetzes "Gleichgestelltes aber unterschiedliche 
Anpassungen für das Weiß zur Verfügung, und gefärbt, Rennen,", 
einige südliche Zustände verbinden, die bereits ähnliche Gesetze 
verabschiedet hatten. Afrikanische Amerikaner in New-Orleans 
kämpften das neue Gesetz in einigen Methoden, einschließlich eine 
zugelassene Herausforderung. 1892 ordneten sie für Homer Adolph
auf einer Ostlouisiana Bahnserie festgehalten zu werden Plessy,, damit
das Ablehnen auf das Auto bewegt, das gekennzeichnet wird für 
"farbige Passagiere." Der Fall erreichte schließlich das 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Höchste Gericht in 1896 als Plessy V. Ferguson 
(benannt für den Richter, der zuerst gegen Plessy anordnete). 
Die Gerichtentscheidung argumentierte, daß solange rassisch 
unterschiedliche Teildienste gleich waren, sie verletzte nicht die 
Garantien der vierzehnten Änderung des gleichen Schutzes des 
Gesetzes. Der einsame Abweichler war Gerechtigkeit-John 
Marschall Harlan, selbst ein ehemaliges slaveholder von Kentucky. 
Während Harlan der dreizehnten Änderung entgegengesetzt hatte 
(der Sklaverei abschuf), änderte die Erfahrung des Sehens der 
brutalen Angriffe auf afrikanischen Amerikanern in den sofortigen 
PfostenZivilkriegsjahren ihn anscheinend. In seiner Plessy 
Meinungsverschiedenheit beharrte er, daß "alle Bürger vor dem 
Gesetz" und daß das Unterstützen gleich sind des Louisiana Gesetzes 
richtig vorausgesagt, zu den Durchgang von sogar mehr Gesetzen führen
würde, die afrikanische Amerikaner trennen. Nicht bis 1954 das 
Höchste Gericht taten, nehmen Sie Argumente Harlans an, als es Plessy
V. Ferguson mit seinem braunen v. Brett der Ausbildung Entscheidung 
aufhob.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1890, la Louisiane les chemins de fer 
contraignants passés d'une loi "fournissent l'égale mais le logement
séparé pour le blanc, et coloré, des courses," joignant plusieurs 
déclarer méridionaux qui avaient déjà passé les lois semblables. 
Les Américains africains à la Nouvelle-Orléans ont combattu 
la nouvelle loi de plusieurs voies, y compris un défi légal. 
En 1892, ils ont assuré Homer Adolph Plessy à arrêter sur un 
train ferroviaire est de la Louisiane pour que refuser se déplace à 
la voiture indiquée pour "les passagers colorés." Le cas a par
la suite atteint la cour suprême des ETATS-UNIS dans 1896 comme 
Plessy v. Ferguson (nommé pour le juge qui a régné la première 
fois contre Plessy). La décision de cour suprême a argué du 
fait qu'aussi longtemps que les équipements racial séparés étaient
égaux, ils n'a pas violé les garanties de quatorzième amendement de
la protection égale de la loi. Le seul dissident était 
maréchal Harlan, lui-même de John de justice un ancien slaveholder 
du Kentucky. Tandis que Harlan s'était opposé au treizième 
amendement (qui a supprimé l'esclavage), l'expérience de voir des 
attaques brutales sur les Américains africains en années de guerre 
poteau-Civiles immédiates l'a apparemment changé. Dans sa 
dissidence de Plessy, il a insisté sur le fait que "tous les citoyens
sont égaux avant la loi" et correctement prévu que la confirmation 
de la loi de la Louisiane mènerait au passage de bien plus de lois 
isolant les Américains africains. Pas jusqu'à ce que 1954 ont 
fait la cour suprême recevez les arguments de Harlan, quand elle a 
renversé Plessy v. Ferguson avec son panneau brun de v. de décision 
d'éducation.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1890, Louisiana estradas de ferro compelindo 
passadas de uma lei "fornece o igual mas acomodações separadas para 
o branco, e colorido, raças," juntando diversos estados do sul que 
tinham passado já leis similares. Os americanos africanos em 
Nova Orleães lutaram a lei nova em diversas maneiras, including um 
desafio legal. Em 1892, arranjaram para Homer Adolph Plessy a 
ser prendido em um trem railway do leste de Louisiana para que recusar
mova-se para o carro designado para "passageiros coloridos." O 
caso alcançou eventualmente a corte suprema de ESTADOS UNIDOS em 1896
como Plessy v. Ferguson (nomeado para o juiz que governou 
primeiramente de encontro a Plessy). A decisão da corte suprema
discutiu que tão por muito tempo quanto facilidades racial separadas 
eram igual, eles não violate as garantias de décima quarta emenda da
proteção igual da lei. O dissenter solitário era marshall 
Harlan de John da justiça, ele mesmo um slaveholder anterior de 
Kentucky. Quando Harlan tinha oposto a décima terceira emenda 
(que abolished o slavery), a experiência de ver ataques brutais em 
americanos africanos nos anos de guerra borne-Civis imediatos mudou-o 
aparentemente. Em seu dissent de Plessy, insistiu que "todos os 
cidadãos são iguais antes da lei" e predito corretamente que 
upholding a lei de Louisiana conduziria à passagem de mesmo mais leis
que segregam americanos africanos. Não até que 1954 fizeram a 
corte suprema aceite argumentos de Harlan, quando inverteu Plessy v. 
Ferguson com sua placa marrom do v. da decisão da instrução.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1890, la Luisiana ferrovie costringenti passate
di legge "fornisce il uguale ma le sistemazioni separate per il bianco
e colorato, le corse," unendo parecchi del sud dichiara che 
leggi simili già approvate avute. Gli Americani africani a New 
Orleans hanno combattuto la nuova legge in parecchi modi, compreso una
contestazione. In 1892, hanno assicurato Homer Adolph Plessy da 
arrestare su un treno ferroviario orientale della Luisiana affinchè 
rifiutare si muovano verso l'automobile indicato per "i passeggeri 
colorati." Il caso finalmente ha raggiunto la Corte suprema 
degli STATI UNITI in 1896 come Plessy v. Ferguson (chiamato per il 
giudice che in primo luogo ha regolato contro Plessy). La 
decisione della Corte suprema ha sostenuto che finchè le attrezzature
razziale separate erano uguale, non ha violato le garanzie della 
fourteenth correzione di protezione uguale della legge. Il 
dissenter solo era marshall Harlan, egli stesso del John della 
giustizia uno slaveholder precedente dal Kentucky. Mentre Harlan
aveva opposto la tredicesima correzione (che ha abolito lo slavery), 
l'esperienza in vedere gli attacchi brutali agli Americani africani 
durante gli anni di guerra alberino-Civili immediati lo ha cambiato 
apparentemente. Nel suo dissenso di Plessy, ha insistito che 
"tutti i cittadini sono uguali prima della legge" e predetto 
correttamente che sostenere la legge della Luisiana condurrebbe al 
passaggio di ancor più leggi che segregano gli Americani africani. 
Non fino a che 1954 non facciano la Corte suprema accetti gli 
argomenti del Harlan, quando ha invertito Plessy v. Ferguson con il 
relativo Bordo marrone del v. della decisione di formazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1890, η Λουιζιάνα πέρασε τους αναγκάζοντας 
σιδηροδρόμους ενός νόμου για "να παρέχει τις ίσες αλλά χωριστές
στεγάσεις για το λευκό, και χρωμάτισε, φυλές," προσχωρώντας σε 
διάφορα νότια κράτη που είχαν περάσει ήδη τους παρόμοιους 
νόμους. Αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί στη Νέα Ορλεάνη πάλεψαν το 
νέο νόμο με διάφορους τρόπους, συμπεριλαμβανομένης μιας νομικής 
πρόκλησης. Το 1892, τακτοποίησαν για Όμηρο Adolph 
Plessy που συλλαμβάνεται σε ένα τραίνο σιδηροδρόμων της 
ανατολικής Λουιζιάνας για την άρνηση να κινηθούν προς το 
αυτοκίνητο που υποδείχθηκε για τους "έγχρωμους επιβάτες." Η 
υπόθεση έφθασε τελικά στο ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ ανώτατο δικαστήριο το 
1896 ως Plessy V. Ferguson (που ονομάζεται για το 
δικαστή που κυβέρνησε αρχικά ενάντια σε Plessy). Η 
απόφαση ανώτατου δικαστηρίου υποστήριξε ότι εφ' όσον racially
οι χωριστές εγκαταστάσεις ήταν ίσες, δεν παραβίασαν τις 
εγγυήσεις της δέκατης τέταρτης τροποποίησης της ίσης προστασίας 
του νόμου. Ο απομονωμένος αποστάτης ήταν δικαιοσύνη John
Marshall Harlan, ο ίδιος ένα προηγούμενο slaveholder από 
το Κεντάκυ. Ενώ Harlan είχε αντιτάξει τη δέκατη τρίτη 
τροποποίηση (που κατάργησε τη σκλαβιά), η εμπειρία τις βάναυσες 
επιθέσεις σε αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς στα άμεσα μετα-αστικά 
πολεμικά έτη τον άλλαξε προφανώς. Στη διαφωνία Plessy 
του, επέμεινε ότι "όλοι οι πολίτες είναι ίσοι πριν από το 
νόμο" και σωστά πρόβλεψε ότι η υποστήριξη του νόμου της 
Λουιζιάνας θα οδηγούσε στη μετάβαση ακόμη και περισσότερων νόμων
που διαχωρίζει αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς. Μέχρι που το 
1954 έκανε το ανώτατο δικαστήριο αποδεχθείτε τα ορίσματα 
Harlan, όταν αντέστρεψε Plessy V. Ferguson με Brown 
του V. Board απόφασης εκπαίδευσης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1890, Luisiana los ferrocarriles que obligan 
pasados de una ley "proporciona al igual pero a las comodidades 
separadas para el blanco, y coloreado, las razas," ensamblando varios 
estados meridionales que habían aprobado ya leyes similares. 
Los americanos africanos en New Orleans lucharon la nueva ley de
varias maneras, incluyendo un desafío legal. En 1892, 
arreglaron para Homer Adolph Plessy que se arrestará en un tren 
ferroviario del este de Luisiana para que el rechazo se traslade al 
coche señalado para los "pasajeros coloreados." El caso 
alcanzó eventual el Tribunal Supremo de ESTADOS UNIDOS en 1896 como 
Plessy v. Ferguson (nombrado para el juez que primero gobernó contra 
Plessy). La decisión del Tribunal Supremo discutió que como 
recursos racial separados fueran tan de largo igual, ellos no violó 
las garantías de la catorcena enmienda de la protección igual de la 
ley. El dissenter solitario era ordenar Harlan, sí mismo de 
Juan de la justicia un slaveholder anterior de Kentucky. 
Mientras que Harlan había opuesto la décimotercera enmienda 
(que suprimió esclavitud), la experiencia de considerar ataques 
brutales contra americanos africanos en los años de guerra 
poste-Civiles inmediatos lo cambió al parecer. En su disensión
de Plessy, él insistió que "todos los ciudadanos son iguales antes 
de la ley" y predicho correctamente que mantener la ley de Luisiana 
conduciría al paso de aún más leyes que segregan a americanos 
africanos. No hasta que 1954 hicieron el Tribunal Supremo valide
los argumentos de Harlan, cuando invirtió Plessy v. Ferguson con su 
tarjeta marrón del v. de la decisión de la educación.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086739</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103744</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/plessy-v-ferguson-justice-harlan-dissents</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
