<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104535</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104535</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087356</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Actions speak louder than words.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Tätigkeiten sprechen louder als Wörter.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les actions parlent plus fort que des mots.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As ações falam mais ruidosamente do que 
palavras.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le azioni parlano più alto delle parole.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι ενέργειες μιλούν δυνατότερο από τις λέξεις.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las acciones hablan más ruidosamente que 
palabras.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">"The Land of Liberty" was the ironic title of this cartoon published in an 1847 edition of the British satirical weekly  Punch . As the cartoon suggests, Americans faced a number of dilemmas and crises that came to revolve around the institution of slavery and its expansion into the West. As slavery became more entrenched in Southern social and economic life, the war against Mexico, the forced removal of Native Americans from the Southeastern United States, and conflicts between rich and poor whites all highlighted the conflicts within Southern society and between the North and South about the place of slavery in a rapidly expanding republic.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"das Land der Freiheit" war der ironische Titel dieser 
Karikatur, die in einer Ausgabe 1847 des britischen satirical 
wöchentlichen Lochers veröffentlicht wurde. Da die Karikatur 
vorschlägt, stellten Amerikaner eine Anzahl von Dilemmas und Krisen 
gegenüber, die kamen, um die Anstalt der Sklaverei und seiner 
Expansion in den Westen zu rotieren. Während Sklaverei im 
südlichen Sozial- und Wirtschaftsleben befestigter wurde, markierten 
der Krieg gegen Mexiko, der vorverlegte Abbau der gebürtigen 
Amerikaner von den südöstlichen Vereinigten Staaten und die 
$überschneidungen zwischen reichem und schlechtem Weiß ganz die 
$überschneidungen innerhalb der südlichen Gesellschaft und zwischen 
dem Norden und dem Süden über den Ort der Sklaverei in einer schnell
erweiternrepublik.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"la terre de la liberté" était le titre ironique de ce 
dessin animé édité dans une édition 1847 du perforateur 
hebdomadaire satirique britannique. Car le dessin animé 
suggère, les Américains ont fait face à un certain nombre de 
dilemmes et de crises qui sont venus pour tourner autour de 
l'établissement de l'esclavage et de son expansion dans l'ouest. 
Pendant que l'esclavage devenait plus indélogeable dans la vie 
sociale et économique méridionale, la guerre contre le Mexique, le 
déplacement obligatoire des Américains indigènes des états unis du
sud-est, et des conflits entre les blancs riches et pâles ont tout 
mis en valeur les conflits chez la société méridionale et entre le 
nord et les Sud au sujet de l'endroit de l'esclavage 
dans une république rapidement d'extension.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"a terra da liberdade" era o título ironic deste cartoon 
publicado em uma edição 1847 do perfurador semanal satirical 
britânico. Porque o cartoon sugere, os americanos enfrentaram 
um número dilemmas e de crises que vieram revolver em torno da 
instituição do slavery e da sua expansão no oeste. Enquanto o
slavery se tornou mais entrenched na vida social e econômica do sul, 
a guerra de encontro a México, a remoção forçada de americanos 
nativos dos estados unidos do sudeste, e dos conflitos entre brancos 
ricos e deficientes destacaram toda os conflitos dentro da sociedade 
do sul e entre o norte e o sul sobre o lugar do slavery em uma 
república ràpidamente de expansão.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la terra della libertà" era il titolo ironico di questo 
fumetto pubblicato in un'edizione 1847 del punzone settimanale 
satirical britannico. Poichè il fumetto suggerisce, gli 
Americani hanno affrontato un certo numero di dilemmi e di crisi che 
sono venuto girare intorno all'istituzione di slavery e della relativa
espansione nell'ovest. Poichè lo slavery è diventato più 
entrenched in sociale del sud e vita economica, la guerra contro il 
Messico, la rimozione forzata degli Americani natali dal del sud-est 
unito Dichiara ed è in conflitto fra ricco ed i poveri 
bianchi interamente ha evidenziato i conflitti presso la società del 
sud e fra il nord ed il sud circa il posto di slavery in una 
repubblica velocemente d'espansione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Το έδαφος της ελευθερίασ" ήταν ο ειρωνικός τίτλος 
αυτών των κινούμενων σχεδίων που δημοσιεύθηκαν σε μια έκδοση 
1847 της βρετανικής σατυρικής εβδομαδιαίας διάτρησης. 
Όπως τα κινούμενα σχέδια προτείνουν, Αμερικανοί 
αντιμετώπισαν διάφορες διλήμματα και κρίσεις που ήρθαν να 
περιστραφούν γύρω από το όργανο της σκλαβιάς και την 
επέκτασή του στη δύση. Δεδομένου ότι η σκλαβιά έγινε 
περισσότερο περιχαρακωμένη στη νότια κοινωνική και οικονομική 
ζωή, ο πόλεμος ενάντια στο Μεξικό, η αναγκασμένη απομάκρυνση 
εγγενών Αμερικανών από τις νοτιοανατολικές Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες, 
και των συγκρούσεων μεταξύ των πλούσιων και φτωχών λευκών όλες 
έδωσαν έμφαση στις συγκρούσεις μέσα στη νότια κοινωνία και 
μεταξύ του Βορρά και του νότου για τη θέση σκλαβιά σε μια 
γρήγορα επεκτειμένος δημοκρατία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"la pista de la libertad" era el título irónico de esta 
historieta publicada en una edición 1847 del sacador semanal 
satírico británico. Pues la historieta sugiere, los americanos
hicieron frente a un número de dilemas y de crisis que vinieron girar
alrededor de la institución de la esclavitud y de su extensión en el
oeste. Mientras que la esclavitud llegó a ser más atrincherada
en vida social y económica meridional, la guerra contra México, el 
retiro forzado de americanos nativos de los Estados Unidos del 
sudeste, y los conflictos entre los blancos ricos y pobres destacaron 
todo los conflictos dentro de la sociedad meridional y entre el norte 
y el sur sobre el lugar de la esclavitud en una república 
rápidamente que se ampliaba.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087356</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104535</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/actions-speak-louder-than-words</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
