<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103048</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103048</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086411</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Like a Thick Wall": Blocking Farm Auctions in Iowa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"wie eine starke Wand": Bauernhof blockend, 
Versteigert in Iowa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"comme un mur épais" : Blocage des 
enchères de ferme en Iowa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"como uma parede grossa": Obstruindo 
auctions da fazenda em Iowa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"come una parete spessa": Ostruire le aste 
dell'azienda agricola nello Iowa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Όπως έναν παχύ τοίχο": Φράξιμο των αγροτικών 
δημοπρασιών στο Iowa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"como una pared gruesa": Bloqueo de subastas
de la granja en Iowa</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Some may think of farmers as conservative, but that view ignores a long tradition of rural radicalism in the United States. In the early years of the Great Depression, that radicalism found powerful expression in the subverting of farm foreclosures and tax sales. The technique was simple--when a farm was foreclosed for overdue taxes or failure to meet mortgage payments, neighbors would show up at the auction and intimidate any potential buyers. Then the farm and equipment would be purchased at a token price and returned to the original owner.  Nation  magazine reporter Ferner Nuhn witnessed such an auction sale in Iowa and described this practice in March 1933. These efforts saved the livelihood of many South Dakota and Iowa farmers who were devastated by the depression, but they were not enough. Between 1930 and 1935, about 750,000 farms were lost through foreclosure and bankruptcy sales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Einige können an Landwirte als Konservatives 
denken, aber diese Ansicht ignoriert eine lange Tradition der 
landwirtschaftlichen Radikalismus in den Vereinigten Staaten. 
In den frühen Jahren des großen Tiefstands, dieses 
Radikalismus gefundenen leistungsfähigen Ausdruckes im Umstürzen 
der Bauernhofgerichtlicher Verfallserklärungen und der 
Zwangsverkäufe wegen Steuerrückständen. Die Technik war 
einfach -- als ein Bauernhof ausgeschlossen wurde, damit überfällige
Steuern oder Störung Hypothek Zahlungen trifft, würden Nachbarn oben
an versteigerte darstellen und alle möglichen Kunden einschüchtern. 
Dann würden der Bauernhof und die Ausrüstung zu einem 
Scheinpreis gekauft und zurückgebracht zum ursprünglichen Inhaber. 
Nationzeitschrift Reporter Ferner Nuhn zeugte solch einen 
versteigernverkauf in Iowa und beschrieb diese Praxis im März 1933. 
Diese Bemühungen sicherten den Lebensunterhalt von vielen South
Dakota und Iowa Landwirte, die durch den Tiefstand verwüstet wurden, 
aber sie waren nicht genug. Zwischen 1930 und 1935 waren 
ungefähr 750.000 Bauernhöfe durch Verfallserklärung- und 
Bankrottverkäufe verloren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Certains peuvent penser aux fermiers en tant que 
conservateur, mais cette vue ignore une longue tradition de radicalisme
rural aux Etats-Unis. En premières années de la grande 
dépression, de cette expression puissante trouvée par radicalisme 
dans le renversement des forclusions de ferme et des ventes d'impôts.
La technique était simple -- quand une ferme a été empêchée
pour que des impôts ou le manque en retard rencontre des paiements 
d'hypothèque, les voisins révéleraient à l'enchère et 
intimideraient tous les acheteurs potentiels. Puis la ferme et 
le matériel seraient achetés à un prix symbolique et retournés au 
propriétaire initial. Le journaliste Ferner Nuhn de magasin de 
nation était témoin d'une telle vente d'enchère en Iowa et a 
décrit cette pratique en mars 1933. Ces efforts ont sauvegardé
la vie des beaucoup de les fermiers du sud du Dakota et de l'Iowa
qui ont été dévastés par la dépression, mais ils n'étaient pas 
assez. Entre 1930 et 1935, environ 750.000 fermes ont été 
détruites par des ventes de forclusion et de faillite.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Alguns podem pensar dos fazendeiros como o 
conservador, mas essa vista ignora uma tradição longa do radicalism 
rural nos estados unidos. Nos anos adiantados do depression 
grande, dessa expressão poderosa encontrada radicalism no subverting 
de foreclosures da fazenda e de vendas de imposto. A técnica 
era simples -- quando uma fazenda foreclosed para que impostos ou a 
falha overdue se encontre com pagamentos de mortgage, os vizinhos 
mostrariam acima no auction e intimidate todos os compradores 
potenciais. Então a fazenda e o equipamento seriam comprados em
um preço simbólico e retornados ao proprietário original. O 
repórter Ferner Nuhn do compartimento da nação testemunhou tal 
venda do auction em Iowa e descreveu esta prática em março 1933. 
Estes esforços conservaram os meios de subsistência de muitos 
os fazendeiros sul de Dakota e de Iowa que devastated pelo depression,
mas não eram bastantes. Entre 1930 e 1935, aproximadamente 
750.000 fazendas foram perdidas com as vendas do foreclosure e da 
bancarrota.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Alcuni possono pensare ai coltivatori come 
conservatore, ma quella vista ignora una tradizione lunga del 
radicalism rurale in unito Dichiara. Durante i primi anni
della depressione grande, di quell'espressione potente trovata 
radicalism nel subverting dei preclusioni dell'azienda agricola e 
delle vendite di imposta. La tecnica era semplice -- quando un 
podere è stato precluso affinchè le tasse o l'omissione in ritardo 
venisse a contatto dei pagamenti ipotecari, i vicinoi rivelerebbero 
all'asta ed intimidirebbero tutti i compratori potenziali. 
Allora il podere e l'apparecchiatura sarebbero comprati ad un 
prezzo simbolico e sono stati restituiti al proprietario originale. 
Il reporter Ferner Nuhn dello scomparto di nazione ha 
testimoniato una tal vendita dell'asta nello Iowa ed ha descritto 
questa pratica nel mese di marzo del 1933. Questi sforzi hanno 
salvato la vita dei molti coltivatori dello Iowa e del Dakota del Sud 
che sono stati devastati dalla depressione, ma non erano abbastanza. 
Fra 1930 e 1935, circa 750.000 poderi sono stati persi con le 
vendite di fallimento e di preclusione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μερικοί μπορούν να σκεφτούν τους αγρότες όπως 
συντηρητικός, αλλά εκείνη η όψη αγνοεί μια μακροχρόνια παράδοση
αγροτική ριζοσπαστισμός στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες. Τα πρώτα 
έτη της μεγάλης οικονομικής κρίσης, εκείνη η ριζοσπαστισμός 
βρήκε την ισχυρή έκφραση στην υπονόμευση των αγροτικών 
αποκλεισμών και των φορολογικών πωλήσεων. Η τεχνική ήταν 
απλή -- όταν αποκλείθηκε ένα αγρόκτημα για τους υπερήμερους 
φόρους ή την αποτυχία να συναντηθούν οι πληρωμές υποθηκών, οι 
γείτονες θα παρουσίαζαν στη δημοπρασία και θα εκφόβιζαν 
οποιουσδήποτε πιθανούς αγοραστές. Κατόπιν το αγρόκτημα και 
ο εξοπλισμός θα αγοράζονταν σε μια συμβολική τιμή και θα 
επιστρέφονταν στον αρχικό ιδιοκτήτη. Ο δημοσιογράφος 
Ferner Nuhn περιοδικών έθνους βεβαίωσε μια τέτοια πώληση 
δημοπρασίας στο Iowa και περιέγραψε αυτήν την πρακτική τον 
Μάρτιο του 1933. Αυτές οι προσπάθειες έσωσαν στους 
οικονομικούς πόρους πολλές τους αγρότες της νότιων Ντακότας και 
του Iowa που καταστράφηκαν από την κατάθλιψη, αλλά δεν ήταν 
αρκετές. Μεταξύ 1930 και 1935, περίπου 750.000 
αγροκτήματα χάθηκαν μέσω των πωλήσεων αποκλεισμού και πτώχευσης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Algunos pueden pensar en granjeros como 
conservador, pero esa visión no hace caso de una tradición larga del
radicalismo rural en los Estados Unidos. En los años de la gran 
depresión, de esa expresión de gran alcance encontrada radicalismo en
el derribo de las ejecuciones de una hipoteca de la granja y de las 
ventas de impuesto. La técnica era simple -- cuando una granja 
fue excluida para que los impuestos o el incidente atrasados resuelvan
pagos de hipoteca, los vecinos mostrarían para arriba en la subasta e
intimidarían a cualquier comprador potencial. Entonces la 
granja y el equipo serían comprados en un precio simbólico y vueltos
al propietario original. El reportero Ferner Nuhn del 
compartimiento de la nación atestiguó tal venta de la subasta en 
Iowa y describió esta práctica en marcha de 1933. Estos 
esfuerzos salvaron el sustento de muchos los granjeros de Dakota del 
Sur y de Iowa que fueron devastados por la depresión, pero no eran 
bastantes. Entre 1930 y 1935, cerca de 750.000 granjas fueron 
perdidas con ventas de la ejecución de una hipoteca y de la 
bancarrota.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086411</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103048</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/like-a-thick-wall-blocking-farm-auctions-in-iowa</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
