<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108685</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108685</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206316</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Martin Luther King, Jr., National Historic Site</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Martin Luther König, Jr., Nationale Historische 
Site</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Roi de Martin Luther, Jr., Site Historique 
National</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Rei De Martin Luther, Jr., Local Historic 
Nacional</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Re Del Martin Luther, Jr., Luogo Storico 
Nazionale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θ*Μαρτην Luther King, νεώτερος, εθνική ιστορική 
περιοχή</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Rey De Martin Luther, Jr., Sitio Histórico 
Nacional</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features Atlanta's Auburn Avenue, the neighborhood where the civil rights leader was born and raised. Sweet Auburn, as it came to be called, became the center of African American life in Atlanta between 1910 and 1930. Photos and maps of the neighborhood are provided. King's role in the civil rights movement is also examined.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">kennzeichnet Atlantas Auburn Allee, die 
Nachbarschaft, in der der Zivilrechtführer geboren und angehoben war.
Süsses Auburn, während es kam benannt zu werden, wurde die 
Mitte der afrikanischen amerikanischen Lebensdauer in Atlanta zwischen
1910 und 1930. Fotos und Karten der Nachbarschaft werden zur 
Verfügung gestellt. Rolle des Königs in der Zivilrechtbewegung
wird auch überprüft.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">comporte l'avenue auburn d'Atlanta, le voisinage 
où l'amorce de droits civiques est née et a été élevée. 
Auburn doux, pendant qu'il venait pour s'appeler, est devenu le 
centre de la vie américaine africaine à Atlanta entre 1910 et 1930. 
Des photos et les cartes du voisinage sont fournies. Le 
rôle du roi dans le mouvement de droits civiques est également 
examiné.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">caracteriza a avenida auburn de Atlanta, a 
vizinhança onde chefes dos direitos civis foi carregado e levantado. 
Auburn doce, enquanto veio ser chamado, transformou-se o centro 
da vida americana africana em Atlanta entre 1910 e 1930. As 
fotos e os mapas da vizinhança são fornecidos. O papel do rei 
no movimento das direitas civis é examinado também.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">caratterizza il viale auburn de Atlanta, la 
vicinanza in cui il capo di diritti civili è stato sopportato 
ed alzato stato. Auburn dolce, mentre è venuto essere chiamato,
si è transformato in nel centro di vita americana africana a Atlanta 
fra 1910 e 1930. Le foto ed i programmi della vicinanza sono 
forniti. Il ruolo del re nel movimento di diritti civili 
egualmente è esaminato.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χαρακτηρίζει την πυρόξανθη λεωφόρο της Ατλάντας, η 
γειτονιά όπου ο ηγέτης αστικών δικαιωμάτων ήταν γεννημένος και 
αυξημένος. Γλυκός πυρόξανθος, καθώς ήρθε να κληθεί, έγινε
το κέντρο της αφρικανικής αμερικανικής ζωής στην Ατλάντα μεταξύ 
1910 και 1930, φωτογραφίες και χάρτες της γειτονιάς 
παρέχονται. Ο ρόλος του βασιλιά στη μετακίνηση αστικών 
δικαιωμάτων εξετάζεται επίσης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece la avenida castaña de Atlanta, la vecindad
donde el arranque de cinta de las derechas civiles nació y fue 
levantado. Castaño dulce, mientras que vino ser llamada, se 
convirtió en el centro de la vida americana africana en Atlanta entre
1910 y 1930. Las fotos y las correspondencias de la vecindad se 
proporcionan. El papel del rey en el movimiento de las derechas 
civiles también se examina.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206316</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108685</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/martin-luther-king-jr-national-historic-site</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
