<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108517</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108517</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206110</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Before and After the Great Earthquake and Fire, 1897-1916</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Vorher und nachher das große Erdbeben und das 
Feuer, 1897-1916</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Avant et après le grands tremblement de terre et feu,
1897-1916</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Before.and.after o terremoto e o fogo grandes, 
1897-1916</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Prima e dopo il terremoto ed il fuoco grandi, 
1897-1916</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πριν και μετά από το μεγάλους σεισμό και την 
πυρκαγιά, 1897-1916</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Antes y después el grandes terremoto y fuego, 
1897-1916</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">provides 26 films of San Francisco from before and after the Great Earthquake and Fire. The earthquake struck on April 18, 1906, along the San Andreas Fault, damaging most central California cities and killing more than 3,000 people. These films show Market Street, Chinatown, a parade, San Francisco viewed from a balloon, and vast devastation from the 8.3 magnitude earthquake and 3-day fire.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt 26 Filme San Francisco vorher und nachher 
vom großen Erdbeben und vom Feuer zur Verfügung. Das Erdbeben 
schlug an April 18, 1906, entlang der San Andreas Störung an, 
beschädigte die meisten zentralen Kalifornien Städte und beendet 
mehr als 3.000 Leute. Diese Filme zeigen Markt-Straße, 
Chinatown, eine Parade, San Francisco, das von einem Ballon und von 
der beträchtlichen Verwüstung vom 8.3 Größe Erdbeben und von 
3tägigen Feuer angesehen wird.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fournit 26 films de San Francisco avant et après du 
grands tremblement de terre et feu. Le tremblement de terre a 
frappé 18 avril 1906, le long du défaut de San Andreas, 
endommageant la plupart des villes centrales de la Californie et 
détruisant plus de 3.000 personnes. Ces films montrent la rue 
du marché, le Chinatown, un défilé, un San Francisco visualisé 
d'un ballon, et la vaste dévastation du tremblement de terre de 8.3 
grandeurs et du feu de trois jours.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fornece 26 películas de San Francisco 
before.and.after do terremoto e do fogo grandes. O terremoto 
golpeou abril em 18, 1906, ao longo da falha do San Andreas, 
danificando a maioria de cidades centrais de Califórnia e matando 
mais de 3.000 povos. Estas películas mostram a rua do mercado, 
o Chinatown, uma parada, um San Francisco visto de um balão, e o 
devastation vasto do terremoto de 8.3 valores e do fogo 3-day.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fornisce 26 pellicole di San Francisco prima e 
dopo dal terremoto e dal fuoco grandi. Il terremoto ha colpito 
il 18 aprile 1906, lungo il difetto di San Andreas, danneggiante la 
maggior parte delle città centrali della California e mortale più di
3.000 genti. Queste pellicole mostrano la via del mercato, 
Chinatown, una parata, San Francisco osservata da un aerostato e da 
una devastazione ampia dal terremoto di 8.3 grandezze e dal fuoco di 
tre giorni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρέχει 26 ταινίες του Σαν Φρανσίσκο από πριν και 
μετά από το μεγάλους σεισμό και την πυρκαγιά. Ο σεισμός 
χτύπησε στις 18 Απριλίου ..1906, κατά μήκος του SAN 
Ανδρέας Fault, που βλάπτει τις περισσότερες κεντρικές πόλεις 
Καλιφόρνιας και που σκοτώνει περισσότερους από 3.000 
ανθρώπους. Αυτές οι ταινίες εμφανίζουν οδό αγοράς, 
Chinatown, μια παρέλαση, Σαν Φρανσίσκο που εμφανίζεται από ένα
μπαλόνι, και την απέραντη ερήμωση από το σεισμό 8,3 μεγέθους 
και την τριών ημερών πυρκαγιά.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">proporciona a 26 películas de San Francisco antes
y después del grandes terremoto y fuego. El terremoto pulso de 
abril el 18 de 1906, a lo largo del incidente del San Andreas, 
dañando la mayoría de las ciudades centrales de California y matando
a más de 3.000 personas. Estas películas muestran la calle del
mercado, Chinatown, un desfile, San Francisco visto de un globo, y de 
la devastación extensa del terremoto de 8.3 magnitudes y del fuego de
tres días.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206110</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108517</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/before-and-after-the-great-earthquake-and-fire-1897-1916</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
