<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106005</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106005</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086187</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Gender Bender: Mary Masquerades as Murray</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geschlecht-Bieger: Mary Maskeraden als 
Murray</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cintreuse de Genre : Mascarades de Mary comme
Murray</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Dobrador Do Gender: Masquerades de Mary como 
Murray</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Piegatrice Di Genere: Masquerades della Mary 
come Murray</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πένσα γένους: Θ*Μαρυ Masquerades ως Murray</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Doblador Del Género: Masquerades de Maria 
como Murray</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Most people have a clear stereotype of the urban political boss of the early 20th century, and in many ways Murray Hall, a leader of New York City's notorious "Tammany Hall," was its embodiment. Hall was known as a poker-playing, cigar-chomping, whiskey-drinking, "man about town." But in one significant way, Hall departed from the stereotype: she was actually a woman (by the name of Mary Anderson) who "passed" as a man for more than a quarter century. Tragically, Hall died of untreated breast cancer and her deception was only discovered at her death in 1901. "Passing" was a strategy that some lesbians (a term that was not in use at that time) used both to avoid public condemnation and to increase their earnings so that they could live independently. It could also be an assertion of political independence--Hall managed to vote and serve as a political leader in an era when women were denied the franchise.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die meisten Leute haben einen freien Stereotypen 
des städtischen politischen Chefs des frühen 20. Jahrhunderts, und 
in vielen Methoden Murray Hall, ein Führer von notorischem "Tammany 
Hall der New York Stadt," war seine Verkörperung. Hall bekannt 
als Schürhaken-playing, die Zigarre-chomping und Whisky-trank, "Mann 
über Stadt." Aber in einer bedeutenden Möglichkeit, reiste 
Hall vom Stereotypen ab: sie war wirklich eine Frau (durch den 
Namen von Mary Anderson) die als Mann für mehr als ein 
Vierteljahrhundert "führte". Tragisch wurde Hall, der an 
unbehandeltem Brustkrebs und an ihrer Täuschung gestorben wurde, nur 
an ihrem Tod 1901 entdeckt. "das Überschreiten" war eine 
Strategie, daß einige Lesbier (eine Bezeichnung, die nicht innen 
Gebrauch zu dieser Zeit war), allgemeine Verurteilung zu vermeiden 
pflegten und ihr Einkommen zu erhöhen, damit sie unabhängig leben 
konnten. Es könnte eine Behauptung der politischen 
Unabhängigkeit auch sein -- Hall, der gehandhabt wurde, um als 
politischer Führer in einer Ära zu wählen und zu dienen, als Frauen
das Vorrecht verweigert wurden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La plupart des personnes ont un stéréotype clair 
du patron politique urbain du début du 20ème siècle, et de beaucoup
de voies Murray Hall, une amorce Tammany hall notoire de la ville de 
New York de "," était son incorporation. Hall a été connu en 
tant que tisonnier-jeu, cigare-chomping, whiskey-buvant, "homme au 
sujet de ville." Mais d'une voie significative, Hall s'est 
écarté du stéréotype : elle était réellement une femme 
(par le nom de Mary Anderson) que "a passée" en tant qu'homme pour 
plus qu'un siècle quart. Tragiquement, Hall mort du cancer de 
sein non traité et de sa déception a été seulement découvert à 
sa mort en 1901. le "dépassement" était une stratégie que 
quelques lesbiennes (une limite qui n'était pas en service à ce 
moment-là) avaient l'habitude d'éviter la condamnation publique et 
d'augmenter leurs revenus de sorte qu'elles aient pu vivre 
indépendamment. Ce pourrait également être une affirmation de
l'indépendance politique -- Hall parvenu pour voter et servir 
d'amorce politique dans une ère où des femmes ont été niées la 
concession.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A maioria de povos têm um stereotype desobstruído
da saliência política urbana do 20o século adiantado, e em muitas 
maneiras Murray Salão, um líder Tammany notorious salão da cidade 
de New York de "," estava sua incorporação. Salão foi sabido 
como poker-jogar, charuto-chomping, whiskey-bebendo, "homem sobre a 
cidade." Mas em uma maneira significativa, Salão partiu do 
stereotype: era realmente uma mulher (pelo nome de Mary 
Anderson) que "passasse" como um homem para mais do que um século de 
um quarto. Tràgica, Salão morrido de cancer de peito untreated
e de seu deception foi descoberto somente em sua morte em 1901. 
"passar" era uma estratégia que alguns lesbians (um termo que 
não fosse dentro uso nesse tempo) se usaram  evitar o condemnation 
público e aumentar seu salário de modo que pudessem viver 
independentemente. Poderia também ser uma afirmação da 
independência política -- Salão controlado votar e servir como um 
líder político em uma era em que as mulheres fossem negadas o 
franchise.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La maggior parte della gente ha uno stereotipo 
libero della sporgenza politica urbana di inizio del 20esimo secolo ed
in molti modi Murray Corridoio, un capo di Tammany corridoio 
rinomato della città de New York "," era il relativo incorporamento. 
Corridoio è stato conosciuto come un mazza-gioco, 
sigaro-chomping, whisky-bevente, "uomo circa la città." Ma in 
un modo significativo, Corridoio ha partito dallo stereotipo: 
era realmente una donna (dal nome di Mary Anderson) che "ha 
passato" come uomo per più di un secolo quarto. Tragicamente, 
Corridoio morto del cancro di seno non trattato e del suo inganno è 
stato scoperto soltanto alla sua morte in 1901. "passare" era 
una strategia che alcune lesbiche (un termine che non era in uso a 
quel tempo) hanno usato sia evitare la condanna pubblica che aumentare
i loro guadagni in modo che potessero vivere indipendentemente. 
Potrebbe anche essere un'asserzione di indipendenza politica -- 
Corridoio riuscito per votare e servire da capo politico in 
un'era in cui le donne sono state negate la concessione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι περισσότεροι άνθρωποι έχουν ένα σαφές στερεότυπο 
του αστικού πολιτικού προϊσταμένου του πρόωρου 20ού αιώνα, και 
από πολλές απόψεις Murray η αίθουσα, ένας ηγέτης της 
πασίγνωστης "αίθουσας Tammany της πόλης της Νέας Υόρκης," 
ήταν η ενσωμάτωσή της. Η αίθουσα ήταν γνωστή ως 
πόκερ-παιχνίδι, πούρο-, ουίσκυ-που πίνει, "άτομο για την πόλη."
Αλλά με έναν σημαντικό τρόπο, η αίθουσα αναχώρησε από το 
στερεότυπο: ήταν πραγματικά γυναίκα (από το όνομα Mary 
Αντερσον) που "πέρασε" ως άνδρα για έναν περισσότερο από αιώνα 
τετάρτων. Τραγικά, η αίθουσα πέθανε του μη επεξεργασμένου 
καρκίνου του μαστού και η εξαπάτησή της ανακαλύφθηκε μόνο στο 
θάνατό της το 1901. "Η διάβαση" ήταν μια στρατηγική που 
μερικές λεσβίες (ένας όρος που δεν ήταν σε χρήση εκείνη την 
περίοδο) χρησιμοποίησαν και για να αποφύγουν τη δημόσια καταδίκη 
και για να αυξήσουν τις αποδοχές τους έτσι ώστε να μπορούν να 
ζήσουν ανεξάρτητα. Θα μπορούσε επίσης να είναι ένας 
ισχυρισμός της πολιτικής ανεξαρτησίας -- αίθουσα διοικούμενη για 
να ψηφίσει και να χρησιμεύσει ως ένας πολιτικός ηγέτης σε μια 
εποχή όταν αμφισβητήθηκαν οι γυναίκες το προνόμιο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La mayoría de la gente tiene un estereotipo claro 
del jefe político urbano del vigésimo siglo temprano, y de muchas 
maneras Murray Pasillo, arranque de cinta Tammany notorio pasillo de 
la ciudad de Nueva York de "," estaba su encarnación. Conocían
a Pasillo como po'ker-jugar, cigarro-chomping, whisky-bebiendo, 
"hombre sobre ciudad." Pero de una manera significativa, Pasillo
salió del estereotipo: ella era realmente una mujer (por el 
nombre de Maria Anderson) a que "pasó" como hombre para más que un 
siglo cuarto. Trágico, descubrieron a Pasillo muerto de cáncer
de pecho untreated y de su engaño solamente en su muerte en 1901. 
el "pasar" era una estrategia que algunas lesbianas (un término
que no era adentro uso en aquella 'epoca) utilizaron evitar la 
condenación pública y aumentar sus ganancias de modo que pudieran 
vivir independientemente. Podría también ser una aserción de 
la independencia política -- Pasillo manejado para votar y para 
servir como arranque de cinta político en una era en que negaron las 
mujeres la licencia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086187</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106005</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/gender-bender-mary-masquerades-as-murray</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
