<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104242</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104242</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1221201389</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Module Five: Employability Skills</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Modul Fünf: Verwendbarkeit-Fähigkeiten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Module Cinq : Qualifications 
d'Employabilité</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Módulo Cinco: Habilidades Do Employability</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Modulo Cinque: Abilità Di Idoneità al 
lavoro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ενότητα πέντε: Δεξιότητες καταλληλότητας για 
απασχόληση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Módulo Cinco: Habilidades De la Posibilidad 
de empleo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">If you are thinking of looking for a job now or in the future, this module will be of great interest to you. It is designed to illustrate the importance of understanding what it takes to get prepared for the world of work, to look for and secure that job that you need so much in life. It is intended to give you skills and competences that you need to be a successful job searcher. It explores, for example, essential job search skills and approaches that will help you to compete in the changing labour market where the recruitment and selection process is becoming more and more complex. Another feature of this module is a unit telling you about the pros and cons of becoming self-employed.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Business</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wenn Sie an nach einem Job jetzt oder zukünftig 
suchen denken, ist dieses Modul vom großen Interesse zu Ihnen. 
Es ist konzipiert, um zu veranschaulichen den Wert des 
Verstehens, was es nimmt, um vorbereitet für die Welt der Arbeit zu 
erhalten, um nach diesem Job zu suchen und zu sichern, den Sie soviel 
im Leben benötigen. Es soll Ihnen Fähigkeiten und Kompetenzen 
geben, daß Sie ein erfolgreicher Jobforscher sein müssen. Es 
erforscht z.B. wesentliche Jobsuchfähigkeiten und -annäherungen, die
Ihnen helfen, im ändernden Arbeitsmarkt zu konkurrieren, in dem die 
Verstärkung und das Auswahlverfahren immer komplizierter wird. 
Ein anderes Merkmal dieses Moduls ist eine Maßeinheit, die 
Ihnen über das Pro und die Cons des Werdens selbständig erklärt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Si vous pensez à rechercher un travail maintenant 
ou à l'avenir, ce module sera de grand intérêt à vous. Il 
est conçu pour illustrer l'importance de l'arrangement ce qu'il prend
pour obtenir préparé pour le monde du travail, de rechercher et 
fixer ce travail dont vous avez besoin tellement dans la vie. On
le destine pour vous donner des qualifications et des compétences que
vous devez être un chercheur réussi du travail. Il explore, 
par exemple, les qualifications et les approches essentielles de 
recherche du travail qui vous aideront à concurrencer sur le marché 
du travail changeant où le processus de recrutement et de sélection 
devient de plus en plus plus complexe. Un autre dispositif de ce
module est une unité vous indiquant au sujet du pour et du contre de 
art de l'auto-portrait-employed devenant.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Se você estiver pensando de procurar um trabalho 
agora ou no futuro, este módulo será do interesse grande a você. 
É projetado ilustrar a importância de compreender o que faz 
exame para começar preparado para o mundo do trabalho, para procurar 
e fixar esse trabalho que você necessita assim muito na vida. 
Pretende-se dar-lhe habilidades e competences que você 
necessita ser um searcher bem sucedido do trabalho. Explora, 
para o exemplo, as habilidades da busca do trabalho e as 
aproximações essenciais que lhe ajudarão competir no mercado labour
em mudança onde o processo do recruitment e de seleção se está 
tornando mais e mais complexo. Uma outra característica deste 
módulo é uma unidade que diz o sobre os pros e os cons de tornar-se 
self-employed.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Se state pensando a cercare un lavoro ora o in 
avvenire, questo modulo sarà di interesse grande a voi. È 
destinato per illustrare l'importanza di capire che cosa prende per 
ottenere preparato per il mondo di lavoro, per cercare ed assicurare 
quel lavoro di che avete bisogno così tanto nella vita. È 
inteso per darvi le abilità e le competenze che dovete essere un 
ricercatore riuscito di lavoro. Esplora, per esempio, le 
abilità ed i metodi essenziali di ricerca di lavoro che li aiuteranno
a competere nel mercato cambiante di lavoro in cui il 
reclutamento e la procedura di selezione sta diventando più e più 
complessi. Un'altra caratteristica di questo modulo è un'unità
vi che dice circa i pro ed il contro di diventare non retribuiti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εάν σκέφτεστε να αναζητήσετε μια θέση εργασίας τώρα 
ή στο μέλλον, αυτή η ενότητα θα παρουσιάσει μεγάλο ενδιαφέρον 
για σας. Έχει ως σκοπό να επεξηγήσει τη σημασία τι παίρνει 
για να πάρει προετοιμασμένο για τον κόσμο της εργασίας, για να 
αναζητήσει και να εξασφαλίσει εκείνη την θέση εργασίας ότι 
χρειάζεστε τόσο μεγάλο μέρος στη ζωή. Προορίζεται να σας 
δοθούν οι δεξιότητες και οι ειδικότητες που χρειάζεστε για να 
είστε επιτυχής ερευνητής εργασίας. Ερευνά, παραδείγματος 
χάριν, τις ουσιαστικές δεξιότητες και τις προσεγγίσεις αναζήτησης
εργασίας που θα σας βοηθήσουν για να ανταγωνιστούν στη 
μεταβαλλόμενη αγορά εργασίας όπου η διαδικασία στρατολόγησης και
επιλογής γίνεται όλο και περισσότερο σύνθετη. Ένα άλλο 
χαρακτηριστικό γνώρισμα αυτής της ενότητας είναι μια μονάδα 
λέγοντας σας για τα πλεονεκτήματα και τα μειονεκτήματα να γίνει 
αυτοαπασχολούμενα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Si usted está pensando en buscar un trabajo ahora 
o en el futuro, este módulo estará de gran interés a usted. 
Se diseña para ilustrar la importancia de entender lo que toma 
para conseguir preparado para el mundo del trabajo, para buscar y para
asegurar ese trabajo que usted necesite tanto en vida. Se piensa
para darle habilidades y capacidades que usted necesita ser 
investigador acertado del trabajo. Explora, por ejemplo, las 
habilidades y los acercamientos esenciales de la búsqueda del trabajo
que le ayudarán a competir en el mercado de trabajo que cambia donde 
el proceso del reclutamiento y de selección está llegando a ser más
y más complejo. Otra característica de este módulo es una 
unidad que le dice sobre los pros y el contra de convertirse 
independientes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geschäft</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Affaires</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Negócio</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Commercio</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιχείρηση</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Negocio</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1221201389</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104242</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/module-five-employability-skills</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
