<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107537</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107537</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206441</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Wayfinders: A Pacific Odyssey</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wayfinders: Eine Pazifische Odyssee</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Wayfinders : Une Odyssée Pacifique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Wayfinders: Um Odyssey Pacífico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Wayfinders: Un Odyssey Pacifico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Wayfinders: Μια ειρηνική οδύσσεια</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Wayfinders: Una Odisea Pacífica</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is the companion website for a film that features a community of Pacific Islanders as they build sailing canoes and follow the stars on a 2,000-mile voyage across the ocean in the wake of their ancestors. The site includes a wayfinder game, an essay on navigating without instruments, an interview with a wayfinding expert, and a history of the Polynesian people.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist die Begleiterweb site für einen Film, der 
eine Gemeinschaft der pazifischen Inselbewohner kennzeichnet, während
sie das Segeln der Kanus aufbauen und den Sternen auf einer 
Reise 2,000-mile über dem Ozean unmittelbar nach ihren Vorfahren 
folgen. Die Site schließt ein wayfinder Spiel, einen Versuch 
auf dem Steuern ohne Instrumente, ein Interview mit einem wayfinding 
Experten und eine Geschichte der polynesischen Leute ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est le site Web de compagnon pour un film qui 
comporte une communauté des insulaires Pacifiques pendant qu'elles 
établissent naviguer des canoës et suivent tient le premier rôle sur un 
voyage 2,000-mile à travers l'océan à la suite de leurs ancêtres. 
Le site inclut un jeu de wayfinder, un essai sur diriger sans 
instruments, une entrevue avec un expert wayfinding, et une histoire 
des personnes polynésiennes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é o Web site do companheiro para uma película 
que caracterize uma comunidade de islanders pacíficos enquanto 
constroem sailing canoes e seguem as estrelas em uma viagem 2,000-mile
através do oceano na vigília de seus antepassados. O local 
inclui um jogo do wayfinder, um essay em navigating sem instrumentos, 
uma entrevista com um perito wayfinding, e um history dos povos 
polynesian.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è il Web site del compagno per una pellicola che 
caratterizza una Comunità dei islanders pacifici mentre sviluppano la
navigazione dei canoes e seguono le stelle su un viaggio 2,000-mile 
attraverso l'oceano come conseguenza dei loro antenati. Il luogo
include un gioco del wayfinder, un saggio sulla navigazione senza 
strumenti, un'intervista con un esperto wayfinding e una storia della 
gente polynesian.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι ο ιστοχώρος συντρόφων για μια ταινία που 
χαρακτηρίζει μια κοινότητα των ειρηνικών Islander δεδομένου 
ότι χτίζουν τα πλέοντας κανό και ακολουθούν τα αστέρια σε ένα 
ταξίδι 2.000-μιλίου πέρα από τον ωκεανό αμέσως μετά τους 
προγόνους τους. Η περιοχή περιλαμβάνει ένα παιχνίδι 
wayfinder, ένα δοκίμιο στην πλοήγηση χωρίς όργανα, μια 
συνέντευξη με έναν wayfinding εμπειρογνώμονα, και μια ιστορία 
των πολυνησιακών ανθρώπων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es el Web site del compañero para una película 
que ofrezca a comunidad de isleños pacíficos mientras que ella 
construye la navegación de las canoas y sigue las estrellas en un 
viaje 2,000-mile a través del océano en la estela de sus 
antepasados. El sitio incluye un juego del wayfinder, un ensayo 
en la navegación sin los instrumentos, una entrevista con un experto 
wayfinding, y una historia de la gente polynesian.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206441</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107537</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/wayfinders-a-pacific-odyssey</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
