<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105083</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105083</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086266</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Always Had Pads with Me": A G.I. Artist's Sketchpad, 1943-1944</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ich hatte immer Auflagen mit mir": G.I. 
Artists Sketchpad, 1943-1944</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"j'ai toujours eu des garnitures avec moi" : 
Sketchpad de G.I. Artist's, 1943-1944</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"eu tive sempre almofadas com mim": Bloco de
notas de G.I. Um Artista, 1943-1944</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"mi ho avuto sempre rilievi con": Sketchpad 
del G.I. Un Artist, 1943-1944</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"είχα πάντα τα μαξιλάρια με με": Το Sketchpad 
ενός G.I. καλλιτέχνη, 1943-1944</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"tenía siempre pistas con mí": Sketchpad 
de G.I. Artist's, 1943-1944</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the wake of the attack on Pearl Harbor and the declaration of war, thousands of Americans enlisted in the U.S. armed forces. Among them was twenty-year-old Bronx resident Ben Hurwitz. Like many of the men and women who entered military service, Hurwitz (who changed his name to Brown after the war) kept a record of his experiences. But his "journal" was a sketchpad, and, during his two years in North Africa and Italy, Corporal Hurwitz drew and painted at every opportunity. Hurwitz's pictures are accompanied by the artist's commentary transcribed by historian Joshua Brown in November 1996. Sketches used with permission of Eleanor A. Brown.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Unmittelbar nach dem Angriff auf Pearl Harbor und 
der Erklärung des Krieges, trugen Tausenden Amerikaner in den 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN bewaffneten Kräften ein. Unter ihnen war 
Zwanzig-Jahr-altes Bronx Residentben Hurwitz. Wie viele der 
Männer und der Frauen, die militärischen Service eintrugen, hielt 
Hurwitz (wer seinen Namen zum Braun nach dem Krieg änderte), einen 
Satz seiner Erfahrungen. Aber sein "Journal" war ein Sketchpad, 
und, während seiner zwei Jahre in Nordafrika und in Italien, 
physisches Hurwitz zeichnete und malte an jeder Gelegenheit. 
Abbildungen Hurwitzs werden vom Kommentar des Künstlers 
begleitet, der durch Historiker Joshua Braun im November 1996 
übertragen wird. Skizzen verwendet mit Erlaubnis von Eleanor A.
Brown.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">À la suite de l'attaque sur le port de perle et 
de la déclaration de la guerre, les milliers d'Américains ont 
enrôlé dans les forces armées par ETATS-UNIS. Parmi eux 
était vingt-année-vieux Bronx Ben résident Hurwitz. Comme 
plusieurs des hommes et des femmes qui ont écrit le service 
militaire, Hurwitz (qui a changé son nom en brun après la guerre) a 
gardé un enregistrement de ses expériences. Mais son "journal"
était un cahier de croquis, et, pendant ses deux années en Afrique 
du nord et en Italie, Hurwitz corporel a dessiné et a peint à 
chaque occasion. Les images de Hurwitz sont accompagnées du 
commentaire de l'artiste transcrit par brun de Joshua d'historien en 
novembre 1996. Croquis utilisés avec la permission d'Eleanor A.
Brown.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Na vigília do ataque no porto de pérola e da 
declaração da guerra, os milhares dos americanos alistaram-se nas 
forças armadas ESTADOS UNIDOS. Entre eles era Bronx 
vinte-ano-velho Ben residente Hurwitz. Como muitas dos homens e 
das mulheres que incorporaram o serviço militar, Hurwitz (quem mudou 
seu nome ao marrom após a guerra) manteve um registro de suas 
experiências. Mas seu "jornal" era um bloco de notas, e, 
durante seus dois anos em África norte e em Italy, Hurwitz corporal 
desenhou e pintou em cada oportunidade. Os retratos de Hurwitz 
são acompanhados pelo commentary do artista transcrito pelo marrom de
Joshua do historian em novembro 1996. Esboços usados com 
permissão de Eleanor A. Marrom.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Come conseguenza dell'attacco al porto di perla e 
della dichiarazione della guerra, i migliaia degli Americani hanno 
arruolato nelle forze munite gli STATI UNITI. Fra loro era 
venti-anno-vecchio Bronx Ben residente Hurwitz. Come molte degli
uomini e delle donne che hanno entrato nel servizio militare, Hurwitz 
(chi ha cambiato il suo nome a colore marrone dopo la guerra) ha 
mantenuto un record delle sue esperienze. Ma il suo "giornale" 
era un blocchetto per schizzi e, durante i suoi due anni in Africa del
nord ed in Italia, Hurwitz corporale ha dissipato e verniciato ad ogni
occasione. Le immagini del Hurwitz sono accompagnate dal 
commento dell'artista trascritto da colore marrone di Joshua dello 
storico nel mese di novembre del 1996. Abbozzi usati con 
permesso di Eleanor A. Brown.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αμέσως μετά την επίθεση στο λιμάνι μαργαριταριών και 
τη δήλωση του πολέμου, χιλιάδες Αμερικανοί που στρατολογούνται 
στις ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΕΣ οπλισμένες δυνάμεις. Μεταξύ τους ήταν 
είκοσι-χρονών Bronx εδρεύον Ben Hurwitz. 
Όπως πολλούς από τους άνδρες και τις γυναίκες που 
εισήγαγαν τη στρατιωτική θητεία, Hurwitz (που άλλαξε το όνομά
του σε καφετή μετά από τον πόλεμο) εδιατήρησε ένα αρχείο της 
εμπειρίας του. Αλλά "το περιοδικό του" ήταν ένα 
sketchpad, και, κατά τη διάρκεια δύο ετών του στη βόρειες 
Αφρική και την Ιταλία, σωματικό Hurwitz έσυρε και χρωμάτισε σε
κάθε ευκαιρία. Οι εικόνες του Hurwitz συνοδεύονται από 
τα σχόλια του καλλιτέχνη από τον ιστορικό Joshua καφετί το 
Νοέμβριο 1996, σκίτσα που χρησιμοποιούνται που μεταγράφονται με
τη δικαιοδοσία Eleanor Α. Brown.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En la estela del ataque contra puerto de perla y 
del declaración de la guerra, los millares de americanos alistaron en
las fuerzas armadas ESTADOS UNIDOS. Entre ellos estaba 
veinte-año-viejo Bronx Ben residente Hurwitz. Como muchas de 
los hombres y de las mujeres que incorporaron servicio militar, 
Hurwitz (quién cambió su nombre al marrón después de la guerra) 
guardó un expediente de sus experiencias. Pero su "diario" era 
un bloc de bocetos, y, durante sus dos años en África del norte e 
Italia, Hurwitz corporal trazó y pintó en cada oportunidad. 
Los cuadros de Hurwitz son acompañados por el comentario del 
artista transcrito por el marrón de Joshua del historiador en 
noviembre de 1996. Bosquejos usados con el permiso de Eleanor A.
Brown.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086266</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105083</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-always-had-pads-with-me-a-g-i-artists-sketchpad-1943-1944</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
