<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107972</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107972</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087474</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Caught in the middle.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Abgefangen in der Mitte.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Attrapé au milieu.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Travado no meio.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Interferito nella metà.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πιασμένος στη μέση.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cogido en el centro.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">After the Civil War began, slaves were sometimes seized from their masters and forced into service for the Confederate army. This illustration from a May 1862 issue of  Harper's Weekly  depicted one way that the institution of slavery contributed to the Confederacy's war effort. According to the caption, the northern newspaper artist observed this struggle between two Negroes and a rebel captain" through a telescope. The captain "insisted upon their loading a cannon within range of [Union] Sharpshooters. . . . [He] succeeded in forcing the Negroes to expose themselves</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nachdem der Bürgerkrieg anfing, wurden Sklaven manchmal 
von ihren Meistern ergriffen und erzwungen in Service für die 
verbündete Armee. Diese Abbildung a Mai 1862 von der Ausgabe 
von Wochenzeitung Harpers stellte One-way bildlich dar, den die 
Anstalt der Sklaverei zur Kriegbemühung der Konföderation beitrug. 
Entsprechend dem Untertitel beobachtete der Nordzeitung 
Künstler diesen Kampf zwischen zwei Schwarzen und einem rebellischen 
Kapitän "durch ein Teleskop. Der Kapitän "beharrte nach ihrem 
Laden eine Kanone innerhalb des Bereiches [ Anschluß] der 
Sharpshooters.. . . [ er ] gefolgt, mit, die 
Schwarzen zu erzwingen, sich herauszustellen</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Après que la guerre civile ait commencé, des esclaves 
ont été parfois saisis de leurs maîtres et forcés en service pour 
l'armée confédérée. Cette illustration d'issue de a mai 1862
de l'hebdomadaire de Harper a dépeint l'one-way que l'établissement 
de l'esclavage a contribué à l'effort de la guerre de la 
confédération. Selon la légende, l'artiste nordique de 
journal a observé cette lutte entre deux nègres et un capitaine 
rebelle "par un télescope. Le capitaine "a exigé sur leur 
chargement un canon dans la marge [ des tireurs d'élite des syndicats
]. . . [ il ] réussi en vigueur des nègres 
s'exposer</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Depois que a guerra civil começou, os escravos às vezes 
foram apreendidos de seus mestres e forçados no serviço para o 
exército confederate. Esta ilustração da introdução de a 
maio 1862 do semanário de Harper descreveu o one-way que a 
instituição do slavery contribuiu ao esforço da guerra do 
confederacy. De acordo com o subtítulo, o artista do norte do 
jornal observou este esforço entre dois negroes e um capitão rebel 
"através de um telescópio. O capitão "insistiu em cima de seu
carregamento um canhão dentro da escala de sharpshooters. [ da união
]. . . [ ele ] sucedido em forçar os negroes a 
expo</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dopo che la guerra civile cominci, gli schiavi a volte 
sono stati grippati dai loro supervisori e sono stati forzati in 
servizio per l'esercito confederato. Questa illustrazione 
dall'emissione di a maggio 1862 del settimanale del Harper ha 
descritto il one-way che l'istituzione di slavery ha contribuito allo 
sforzo di guerra del confederacy. Secondo il titolo, l'artista 
nordico del giornale ha osservato questa lotta fra due negroes e un 
capitano ribelle "tramite un telescopio. Il capitano "ha 
insistito sul loro caricamento un cannone all'interno di gamma di 
sharpshooters. [ del sindacato ]. . . [ lui ] 
riuscito a forzare i negroes esporrsi</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αφότου άρχισε ο εμφύλιος πόλεμος, οι σκλάβοι 
αρπάχτηκαν μερικές φορές από τους κυρίους τους και αναγκάστηκαν 
στην υπηρεσία για τον ομόσπονδο στρατό. Αυτή η απεικόνιση 
από έναν Μάιος 1862 ζήτημα της εβδομαδιαίας έκδοσης 
Harper απεικόνισε έναν τρόπο που το όργανο της 
σκλαβιάς συνέβαλε στην πολεμική προσπάθεια της συνομοσπονδίας. 
Σύμφωνα με τον τίτλο, ο βόρειος καλλιτέχνης εφημερίδων 
παρατήρησε αυτήν την προσπάθεια μεταξύ δύο νέγρων και ενός 
επαναστατικού καπετάνιου "μέσω ενός τηλεσκοπίου. Ο 
καπετάνιος "επέμεινε επάνω στη φόρτωσή τους ένα πυροβόλο μέσα 
στη σειρά [ των άριστων σκοπευτών ένωσης ]. .. [ Αυτός ] πετυχημένος στον καταναγκασμό των νέγρων για να 
εκτεθεί</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Después de que la guerra civil comenzara, los esclavos 
fueron agarrados de sus amos y forzados a veces en el servicio para el
ejército confederado. Esta ilustración de la aplicación de a 
mayo 1862 el semanario de Harper representó una forma que la 
institución de la esclavitud contribuyó al esfuerzo de la guerra del
confederacy. Según el encabezamiento, el artista norteño del 
periódico observó esta lucha entre dos negros y un capitán rebelde 
"a través de un telescopio. El capitán "insistió sobre su 
cargamento un cañón dentro del rango de los tiradores de primera [ 
de la unión ]. . . [ él ] tenido éxito en vigor a
los negros exponerse</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087474</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107972</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/caught-in-the-middle</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
