<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108617</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108617</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086355</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"It Was Vital Not to Lose Vietnam by Force to Communism": Leslie Gelb Analyzes the Roots of U.S. Involvement in Vietnam</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"es war lebenswichtig, Vietnam nicht durch Force 
zum Kommunismus zu verlieren": Leslie Gelb analysiert die 
Wurzeln der VEREINIGTE STAATEN Miteinbeziehung in Vietnam</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"il était essentiel de ne pas détruire le 
Vietnam par Force au communisme" : Leslie Gelb analyse les 
racines de l'intervention des ETATS-UNIS au Vietnam</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"era vital não perder Vietnam por Força ao 
communism": Leslie Gelb analisa as raizes da participação de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS em Vietnam</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"era vitale non perdere il Vietnam da Force a 
comunismo": Leslie Gelb analizza le radici della partecipazione 
degli STATI UNITI nel Vietnam</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ήταν ζωτικής σημασίας να μην χαθεί το Βιετνάμ από 
τη δύναμη στον κομμουνισμό": Θ*Λεσληε Gelb Analyzes οι 
ρίζες της ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ συμμετοχής στο Βιετνάμ</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"era vital no perder Vietnam de Force al 
comunismo": Leslie Gelb analiza las raíces de la implicación 
de ESTADOS UNIDOS en Vietnam</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">During World War II, the U.S. collaborated with the resistance group the Vietminh and their leader, Ho Chi Minh, in their fight against Japan. In the postwar period, however, the U.S. feared Communist expansion into Southeast Asia. In 1954, as France withdrew its forces in defeat, the Geneva Accords established the countries of Laos, Cambodia, and Vietnam. Vietnam was partitioned into north and south sectors until elections to be held by 1956. Fearing a victory by Ho Chi Minh, the Eisenhower administration collaborated with the South Vietnam leadership to prevent elections and subsequently sent military aid and advisors. Under President John F. Kennedy, the number of "advisors" increased to more than 16,000, some of whom engaged in counterinsurgency efforts and actual combat. Although Kennedy opposed large scale U.S. involvement, his successor, Lyndon Johnson, began regular bombings and escalated troops to more than 500,000 by 1967. Johnson's successor, Richard Nixon, scaled back to 39,000 U.S. troops in Vietnam by September 1972, but initiated bombing raids into Cambodia in 1969 and sent ground troops there in 1970. The U.S. and North Vietnam reached a cease-fire agreement in January 1973, and the South Vietnamese regime fell in April 1975. More than one million people died during the war, including an estimated 925,000 North Vietnamese, 184,000 South Vietnamese, and 57,000 American soldiers. In the following excerpt, Leslie Gelb, a State Department official during the Vietnam War and Defense Department official afterward, offered an insider's appraisal to a Senate committee of the reasons for the U.S. involvement.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während des Zweiten Weltkrieges arbeiteten die 
VEREINIGTEN STAATEN mit der Widerstand Gruppe das Vietminh und ihr 
Führer, Ho Chi Minh, in ihrem Kampf gegen Japan zusammen. In 
der Nachkriegszeit jedoch fürchteten die VEREINIGTEN STAATEN 
kommunistische Expansion in Südostasien. 1954 da Frankreich 
seine Kräfte in der Niederlage entnahm, stellten die Genf 
Übereinstimmungen die Länder von Laos, von Kambodscha und von 
Vietnam her. Vietnam wurde in die Nord- und Südsektoren bis die
bis zum verteilt 1956 angehalten zu werden Wahlen. Einen Sieg 
durch Ho Chi Minh fürchtend, arbeitete die Eisenhower Leitung mit der
Südvietnam Führung zusammen, um Wahlen zu verhindern und sendete 
nachher militärisches Helfer und Berater. Unter Präsidenten 
John F. Kennedy, erhöhte sich die Zahl "Beratern" bis mehr als 
16.000, einiges von, engagierte sich wem in den 
Gegenaufstandbemühungen und im tatsächlichen Kampf. Obgleich 
Kennedy große Skala VEREINIGTE STAATEN Miteinbeziehung 
entgegensetzte, fing sein Nachfolger, Lyndon Johnson, regelmäßige 
Bombardierungen an und entwickelte sich Truppen bis mehr als 500.000 
bis zum 1967. Nachfolger Johnsons, Richard Nixon, dort 
eingestuft zurück zu 39.000 VEREINIGTE STAATEN Truppen in Vietnam von
September 1972, aber von initialisierten Bombardierungüberfällen in 
Kambodscha 1969 und von gesendeten Grundtruppen 1970. Die 
VEREINIGTEN STAATEN und das Nordvietnam erreichten eine 
Waffenstillstandvereinbarung im Januar 1973, und das vietnamesische 
Südregime fiel im April 1975. Mehr als eine Million Leute 
starben während des Krieges, einschließlich einen geschätzten 
925.000 Nordvietnamesen, 184.000 Südvietnamesen und 57.000 
amerikanischer Soldaten. Im folgenden Excerpt boten Leslie Gelb,
ein Zustand-Abteilung Beamter während des Vietnam Krieges und 
Verteidigung-Abteilung Beamter danach, die Schätzung eines 
Eingeweihten einem Senatausschuß der Gründe für die VEREINIGTE 
STAATEN Miteinbeziehung an.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant la deuxième guerre mondiale, les 
ETATS-UNIS ont collaboré avec le groupe de résistance le Vietminh et
leur amorce, chi Minh de Ho, dans leur combat contre le Japon. 
Dans l'après-guerre, cependant, les ETATS-UNIS ont craint 
l'expansion communiste en l'Asie du Sud-Est. En 1954, car la 
France a retiré ses forces dans la défaite, les ententes de Genève 
ont établi les pays du Laos, du Cambodge, et du Vietnam. Le 
Vietnam a été divisé dans les secteurs du nord et du sud 
jusqu'à ce que des élections à tenir d'ici 1956. Craignant 
une victoire par Ho Chi Minh, la gestion d'Eisenhower a collaboré 
avec la conduite du sud du Vietnam pour empêcher des élections 
et a ultérieurement envoyé l'aide et les conseillers militaires. 
Sous le Président John F. Kennedy, le nombre de 
"conseillers" a grimpé jusqu'plus de à 16.000, une partie de qui 
s'est engagé dans des efforts de contre-insurrection et le combat 
réel. Bien que Kennedy se soit opposé à l'intervention des
ETATS-UNIS à grande échelle, son successeur, Lyndon Johnson, a 
commencé les bombardements réguliers et a escaladé des troupes plus
de à 500.000 d'ici 1967. Le successeur de Johnson, Richard 
Nixon, mesuré de nouveau à 39.000 troupes des ETATS-UNIS au Vietnam 
par septembre 1972, mais incursions lancées de bombardement en le 
Cambodge en 1969 et troupes moulues envoyées là en 1970. Les 
ETATS-UNIS et le nord Vietnam ont conclu un accord de 
cessez-le-feu en janvier 1973, et le régime vietnamien du sud est
tombé en avril 1975. Plus d'un million de personnes sont mortes
pendant la guerre, y compris des 925.000 vietnamiens du nord 
environ, 184.000 Vietnamiens du sud, et 57.000 soldats 
américains. Dans l'extrait suivant, Leslie Gelb, un 
fonctionnaire de service d'état pendant la guerre de Vietnam et le 
fonctionnaire de service de la défense après, ont offert 
l'évaluation d'un initié à un comité de sénat des raisons de 
l'intervention des ETATS-UNIS.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Durante a segunda guerra mundial, os ESTADOS 
UNIDOS collaborated com o grupo da resistência o Vietminh e seu 
líder, chi Minh de Ho, em sua luta de encontro a Japão. No 
período postwar, entretanto, os ESTADOS UNIDOS temeram a expansão 
comunista em Ásia do sudeste. Em 1954, porque France retirou 
suas forças na derrota, os acordos de Genebra estabeleceram os 
países de Laos, de Cambodia, e de Vietnam. Vietnam estêve 
dividido nos setores nortes e sul até que as eleições a ser 
prendidas por 1956. Temendo uma vitória por Ho Chi Minh, a 
administração de Eisenhower collaborated com a liderança sul de 
Vietnam para impedir eleições e emitiu subseqüentemente o dae 
(dispositivo automático de entrada) e conselheiros militares. 
Sob o presidente John F. Kennedy, o número de "conselheiros" 
aumentou mais a de 16.000, algum de quem acoplou em esforços do 
counterinsurgency e no combate real. Embora Kennedy opusesse a 
participação de ESTADOS UNIDOS da escala grande, seu sucessor, 
Lyndon Johnson, começou bombardeios regulares e escalou tropas mais a
de 500.000 por 1967. Sucessor de Johnson, Richard Nixon, 
escalado para trás a 39.000 tropas de ESTADOS UNIDOS em Vietnam por 
setembro 1972, mas por invasões iniciadas do bombardeio em Cambodia 
em 1969 e por tropas à terra emitidas lá em 1970. Os ESTADOS 
UNIDOS e o Vietnam norte alcançaram um acordo do cease-fire em 
janeiro 1973, e o regime vietnamese sul caiu em abril 1975. Mais
de um milhão povos morreram durante a guerra, including uns 925.000 
vietnamese nortes estimado, 184.000 vietnamese sul, e 57.000 soldados 
americanos. No seguinte excerpt, Leslie Gelb, um oficial do 
departamento do estado durante a guerra de Vietnam e o oficial do 
departamento da defesa mais tarde, ofereceram o appraisal de um 
insider a um comitê do senate das razões para a participação de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Durante la seconda guerra mondiale, gli STATI 
UNITI hanno collaborato con il gruppo di resistenza il Vietminh ed il 
loro capo, il "chi" Minh di Ho, nella loro lotta contro il 
Giappone. Nel periodo, tuttavia, gli STATI UNITI hanno temuto 
l'espansione comunista in Asia sudorientale. In 1954, poichè la
Francia ha ritirato le relative forze nella sconfitta, gli accordi de 
Ginevra hanno stabilito i paesi del Laos, della Cambogia e del 
Vietnam. Dividere il Vietnam nei settori del nord e del sud fino
a elezioni da tenere entro 1956. Temendo una vittoria da Ho Chi 
Minh, la gestione di Eisenhower ha collaborato con la direzione del 
sud del Vietnam per impedire le elezioni e successivamente ha 
trasmesso il sussidio ed i consiglieri militari. Sotto il 
presidente John F. Kennedy, il numero "di consiglieri" è aumentato 
più di a 16.000, alcuno di chi si è agganciato negli sforzi del 
counterinsurgency e nel combattimento reale. Anche se Kennedy ha
opposto la partecipazione degli STATI UNITI della grande scala, il suo
successore, Lyndon Johnson, ha cominciato i bombardamenti normali ed 
ha intensificato le truppe più di 500.000 entro 1967. 
Successore del Johnson, Richard Nixon, regolato di nuovo a 
39.000 truppe degli STATI UNITI nel Vietnam da settembre del 1972, ma 
dalle incursioni iniziate del bombardamento in Cambogia in 1969 e 
dalle truppe a terra trasmesse là in 1970. Gli STATI UNITI ed 
il Vietnam del nord hanno raggiunto un accordo del cessate il fuoco nel 
mese di gennaio del 1973 ed il regime vietnamita del sud è caduto nel
mese di aprile del 1975. Più di un milione di genti sono morto 
durante la guerra, compreso i 925.000 vietnamiti del nord valutato, 
184.000 vietnamiti del sud ed i 57.000 soldati americani. Nel 
seguente brano, Leslie Gelb, un funzionario di State Department durante la 
guerra di Vietnam ed il funzionario di reparto della difesa in 
seguito, hanno offerto la valutazione del membro ad un comitato del 
senato dei motivi per la partecipazione degli STATI UNITI.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ, οι ΗΠΑ 
συνεργάστηκαν με την ομάδα αντίστασης το Vietminh και ο ηγέτης 
τους, Ho chi Minh, στην πάλη τους ενάντια στην Ιαπωνία. 
Στη μεταπολεμική περίοδο, εντούτοις, η ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ 
φοβισμένη κομμουνιστική επέκταση στη Νοτιοανατολική Ασία. 
Το 1954, καθώς η Γαλλία απέσυρε τις δυνάμεις της στην 
ήττα, οι συμφωνίες της Γενεύης καθιέρωσαν τις χώρες του Λάος, 
της Καμπότζης, και του Βιετνάμ. Το Βιετνάμ χωρίστηκε στους 
τομείς του Βορρά και νότου μέχρι τις εκλογές που 
πραγματοποιούνται από 1956, φοσμένος μια νίκη από Ho Chi
Minh, η κυβέρνηση Eisenhower συνεργάστηκε με την ηγεσία του 
νότιου Βιετνάμ να αποτρέψει τις εκλογές και έστειλε στη συνέχεια
τη στρατιωτική ενίσχυση και τους συμβούλους. Κάτω από τον 
Πρόεδρο John F. Kennedy, ο αριθμός "συμβούλων" αυξήθηκε 
σε περισσότερο από 16.000, μερικά από τα οποία συμμετείχαν 
στις προσπάθειες αντιεξέγερσης και τον πραγματικό αγώνα. Αν 
και Kennedy αντέταξε την ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ συμμετοχή μεγάλης 
κλίμακας, ο διάδοχός του, Lyndon Johnson, άρχισε τους 
κανονικούς βομβαρδισμούς και κλιμάκωσε τα στρατεύματα σε 
περισσότερο από 500.000 από 1967, διάδοχο Johnson, 
Richard Nixon, που ξελεπιάστηκε πίσω σε 39.000 ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΑ 
στρατεύματα στο Βιετνάμ μέχρι τον Σεπτέμβριο του 1972, αλλά οι
αρχισμένες επιδρομές βομβαρδισμού στην Καμπότζη το 1969 και το 
σταλμένο έδαφος συγκεντρώνονται εκεί το 1970. Οι ΗΠΑ και 
το βόρειο Βιετνάμ επέτυχαν μια συμφωνία εκεχειρίας τον Ιανουάριο
του 1973, και το νότιο βιετναμέζικο καθεστώς ενέπεσε τις 
1975, Απριλίου Περισσότεροι του ενός εκατομμύρες 
άνθρωποι πέθαναν κατά τη διάρκεια του πολέμου, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένου του κατ' εκτίμηση 925.000 Βορρά 
βιετναμέζικα, 184.000 νότος βιετναμέζικα, και 57.000 
αμερικανικοί στρατιώτες. Στο ακόλουθο απόσπασμα, η Leslie
Gelb, ένας ανώτερος υπάλληλος υπουργείου εξωτερικών κατά τη 
διάρκεια του πολέμου του Βιετνάμ και ο ανώτερος υπάλληλος 
αμυντικού τμήματος κατόπιν, πρόσφεραν την αξιολόγηση ενός 
μέλους σε μια επιτροπή Συγκλήτου των λόγων για την ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ 
συμμετοχή.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Durante la Segunda Guerra Mundial, los ESTADOS 
UNIDOS colaboraron con el grupo de la resistencia el Vietminh y su 
arranque de cinta, chi Minh de Ho, en su lucha contra Japón. En
la posguerra, sin embargo, los ESTADOS UNIDOS temieron la extensión 
comunista en Asia suroriental. En 1954, como Francia retiró sus
fuerzas en derrota, los acuerdos de Ginebra establecieron los países 
de Laos, de Camboya, y de Vietnam. Vietnam fue repartido en los 
sectores del norte y del sur hasta que las elecciones que se 
sostendrán antes de 1956. Temiendo una victoria de Ho Chi Minh,
la administración de Eisenhower colaboró con la dirección del sur 
de Vietnam para prevenir elecciones y envió posteriormente al 
asistente y a consejeros militares. Bajo presidente John F. 
Kennedy, el número de "consejeros" aumentó más a de 16.000, algunos
de quién enganchó a esfuerzos del counterinsurgency y a combate 
real. Aunque Kennedy opuso la implicación de ESTADOS UNIDOS de 
la escala grande, su sucesor, Lyndon Johnson, comenzó bombardeos 
regulares y extendió a tropas más a de 500.000 antes de 1967. 
Sucesor de Johnson, Richard Nixon, escalado de nuevo a 39.000 
tropas de ESTADOS UNIDOS en Vietnam antes de septiembre de de 1972, 
pero incursiones iniciadas del bombardeo en Camboya en 1969 y tropas 
de tierra enviadas allí en 1970. Los ESTADOS UNIDOS y el 
Vietnam del norte alcanzaron un acuerdo del alto el fuego en enero de 
1973, y el régimen vietnamita del sur bajó en abril de 1975. 
Más de un millón personas murieron durante la guerra, 
incluyendo 925.000 vietnamitas del norte estimado, 184.000 vietnamitas
del sur, y 57.000 soldados americanos. En el extracto siguiente,
Leslie Gelb, un funcionario del departamento del estado durante la 
guerra de Vietnam y el funcionario del departamento de la defensa 
luego, ofrecieron la valoración de un iniciado a un comité del 
senado de las razones de la implicación de ESTADOS UNIDOS.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086355</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108617</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/it-was-vital-not-to-lose-vietnam-by-force-to-communism-leslie-gelb-analyzes-the-roots-of-u-s-involvement-in-vietnam</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
