<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108062</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108062</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086971</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The I.W.W. and the other features that go with it."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die I.W.W. und die anderen Merkmale, die gehören
zu ihm."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Les I.W.W. et les autres dispositifs qui sont 
assortis à lui."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Os I.W.W. e as outras características que vão 
com ele."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"I I.W.W. e le altre caratteristiche che vanno con
esso."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Το I.W.W. και τα άλλα χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα που
πηγαίνουν με το."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Los I.W.W. y las otras características que van 
con él."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">During World War I, government at all levels subjected the Industrial Workers of the World (IWW), a radical labor union, to repression in the name of wartime security. IWW organizers were repeatedly arrested, and strikers were beaten or shot by police and hired thugs. In September, 1917, federal agents raided every IWW office in the country, arresting some 300 leaders on charges of espionage and sedition. Within six months, two thousand IWW members, known as Wobblies, were in jail and awaiting trial. Most were eventually convicted of violating wartime statutes and sentenced to long prison terms. The organization never recovered from these wartime setbacks. This 1917 cartoon from the  New York Globe  newspaper uses the acronym IWW" in place of the features of Kaiser Wilhelm of Germany</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während des Ersten Weltkrieges unterwarf Regierung auf 
allen Stufen die industriellen Arbeiter der Welt (IWW), ein radikaler 
Arbeiterverband, Unterdrückung im Namen der Kriegsicherheit. 
IWW Organisatoren wurden wiederholt festgehalten, und 
Schlaggeräte wurden oder Schuß von der Polizei und von angestellten 
Schurkeen geschlagen. Im September 1917, überfielen 
Bundesmittel jedes IWW Büro im Land und hielten ca. 300 Führer auf 
Ladungen von Spionage und von Sedition fest. Innerhalb sechs 
Monate waren zwei tausend IWW Bauteile, bekannt als Wobblies, im 
Gefängnis und Erwartenversuch. Die meisten wurden schließlich 
des Verletzens der Krieggesetze überführt und verurteilt, um sich zu
sehnen Gefängnisbezeichnungen. Die Organisation erholte nie von
diesen Krieghindernissen. Diese Karikatur 1917 von der New York 
Kugelzeitung verwendet das Akronym IWW "anstatt der Merkmale von 
Kaiser Wilhelm von Deutschland</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant la Première Guerre Mondiale, le gouvernement à 
tous les niveaux a soumis les ouvriers industriels du monde (IWW), un 
syndicat radical, à la répression au nom de la sécurité de temps 
de guerre. Des organisateurs d'IWW ont été à plusieurs 
reprises arrêtés, et des butées ont été battues ou projectile par
la police et les gangsters loués. En septembre, 1917, les 
agents fédéraux ont pillé chaque bureau d'IWW dans le pays, 
arrêtant environ 300 amorces sur des frais de l'espionnage et du 
sedition. Dans les six mois, deux mille membres d'IWW, connus 
sous le nom de Wobblies, étaient en prison et épreuve d'attente. 
Les la plupart ont été par la suite condamnées de violer des 
statuts de temps de guerre et condamnées pour désirer ardemment des 
limites de prison. L'organisation n'a jamais récupéré de ces 
reculs de temps de guerre. Ce dessin animé 1917 du journal de 
globe de New York utilise l'acronyme IWW "au lieu des dispositifs de 
Kaiser Wilhelm de l'Allemagne</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Durante o world.war.i, o governo em todos os níveis 
sujeitou os trabalhadores industriais do mundo (IWW), uma união labor
radical, ao repression no nome da segurança do wartime. Os 
organizers de IWW foram prendidos repetidamente, e os grevistas foram 
batidos ou tiro por polícias e por thugs empregados. Em 
setembro, 1917, os agentes federais invadiram cada escritório de IWW 
no país, prendendo uns 300 líderes em cargas de espionage e de 
sedition. Dentro de seis meses, dois mil membros de IWW, sabidos
como Wobblies, estavam na cadeia e experimentação esperar. A 
maioria convicted de violating statutes do wartime e foram 
sentenciados eventualmente para long termos da prisão. A 
organização nunca recuperou destes setbacks do wartime. Este 
cartoon 1917 do jornal do globo de New York usa o acrônimo IWW "no 
lugar das características de Kaiser Wilhelm de Germany</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Durante il world.war.i, il governo a tutti i livelli ha 
sottoposto i lavoratori dell'industria del mondo (IWW), un'unione 
di lavoro radicale, a repressione in nome di sicurezza di wartime. 
Gli organizzatori di IWW sono stati arrestati ripetutamente ed i
percussori sono stati battuti o colpo dalla polizia e dai thugs 
assunti. In settembre, del 1917, gli agenti federali raided ogni
ufficio di IWW nel paese, arrestante circa 300 capi sulle spese
di spionaggio e di sedition. Entro sei mesi, due mila membri di 
IWW, conosciuti come Wobblies, erano in prigione e prova attendere. 
La maggior parte finalmente sono stati condannati di violazione 
degli statuti di wartime e sono stati sentenziati per desiderare 
termini della prigione. L'organizzazione non ha recuperato mai 
da queste battute d'arresto di wartime. Questo fumetto 1917 dal 
giornale del globo de New York usa l'acronimo IWW "al posto delle 
caratteristiche di Kaiser Wilhelm della Germania</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου Ι, η 
κυβέρνηση σε όλα τα επίπεδα υπέβαλε τους βιομηχανικούς εργάτες 
του κόσμου (IWW), ένα ριζικό εργατικό συνδικάτο, στην 
καταστολή στο όνομα της εν καιρώ πολέμου ασφάλειας. Οι 
διοργανωτές IWW συλλήφθηκαν επανειλημμένα, και οι απεργοί 
κτυπήθηκαν ή πυροβολήθηκαν από την αστυνομία και τους 
μισθωμένους κακοποιούς. Τον Σεπτέμβριο, του 1917, οι 
ομοσπονδιακοί πράκτορες επιτέθηκαν κάθε γραφείο IWW στη χώρα,
που συλλαμβάνει περίπου 300 ηγέτες στις δαπάνες της 
κατασκοπείας και του στασιασμού. Μέσα σε έξι μήνες, δύο 
χιλιάες μέλη IWW, γνωστά ως wobblies, ήταν στη φυλακή και 
αναμονή της δοκιμής. Οι περισσότεροι καταδικάστηκαν τελικά 
της παραβίασης των εν καιρώ πολέμου καταστατικών και 
καταδικάστηκαν στους μακροχρόνιους όρους φυλακών. Η 
οργάνωση δεν ανάκτησε ποτέ από αυτές τις εν καιρώ πολέμου 
οπισθοδρομήσεις. Αυτά τα κινούμενα σχέδια του 1917 από 
την εφημερίδα σφαιρών της Νέας Υόρκης χρησιμοποιούν το 
αρκτικόλεξο IWW "αντί των χαρακτηριστικών γνωρισμάτων Kaiser
Wilhelm της Γερμανίας</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Durante Primera Guerra Mundial, el gobierno en todos los 
niveles sujetó a trabajadores industriales del mundo (IWW), un 
sindicato radical, a la represión en el nombre de la seguridad del 
tiempo de guerra. Arrestaron a los organizadores de IWW en 
varias ocasiones, y los huelguistas fueron batidos o tiro por el 
policía y los gamberros empleados. En septiembre de 1917, los 
agentes federales atacaron cada oficina de IWW en el país, arrestando
a unos 300 arranques de cinta en cargas de espionaje y de sedición. 
En el plazo de seis meses, dos mil miembros de IWW, conocidos 
como Wobblies, estaban en cárcel y ensayo el aguardar. La 
mayoría fueron condenadas por la violación de los estatutos del 
tiempo de guerra y condenadas eventual para desear los términos de la
prisión. La organización nunca se recuperó de estos reveses 
del tiempo de guerra. Esta historieta 1917 del periódico del 
globo de Nueva York utiliza las siglas IWW "en lugar de las 
características de Kaiser Wilhelm de Alemania</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086971</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108062</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-i-w-w-and-the-other-features-that-go-with-it</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
