<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105865</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105865</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086773</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Ran off.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Deaktiviert.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Coulé.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Funcionou fora.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Colato.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τρεγμένος.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Escurr.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The September 18, 1762 edition of the  South Carolina Gazette  included notices of stray animals, runaway wives, and escaped slaves. Along with breaking tools, feigning illness, and slowing work, running away, individually or in groups, was a common form of resistance to slavery. Most of those who ran away did so for short periods, often to visit spouses or relatives on other farms, or to escape punishment. Chances were slim for permanent escape, and most of those who ran away were eventually reenslaved. Still, some escaped slaves found refuge with Native American groups or in small, isolated maroon colonies.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der September 18, 1762 enthielt Ausgabe der Südcarolina 
Zeitung Begriffe der Streutiere, Durchgehenfrauen und entging Sklaven.
Zusammen mit dem Brechen der Hilfsmittel, der vortäuschenden 
Krankheit und des Verlangsamens der Arbeit, weg, einzeln laufen oder 
in den Gruppen, war ein geläufiges Formular des Widerstandes zur 
Sklaverei. Die meisten denen, die weg liefen, taten so für 
kurze Perioden, um Gatten oder Verwandte auf anderen Bauernhöfen 
häufig zu besuchen, oder Bestrafung zu entgehen. 
Wahrscheinlichkeiten waren für permanentes Entweichen dünn, 
und die meisten denen, die weg liefen, waren reenslaved schließlich. 
Noch fanden einige entgangene Sklaven Schutz mit gebürtigen 
amerikanischen Gruppen oder in den kleinen, lokalisierten 
kastanienbraunen Kolonien.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">18 septembre 1762 l'édition de la gazette du sud 
de la Caroline a inclus des notifications des animaux parasites, 
épouses d'emballement, et a échappé à des esclaves. Avec 
casser des outils, la maladie de simulation, et ralentir le travail, 
l'exécution loin, individuellement ou dans les groupes, était une 
forme commune de résistance à l'esclavage. Les la plupart de 
ceux qui ont fonctionné loin ont fait ainsi pendant des périodes 
courtes, pour rendre visite souvent à des conjoints ou à des parents
à d'autres fermes, ou pour échapper à la punition. Les 
chances étaient minces pour l'évasion permanente, et les la plupart 
de ceux qui ont fonctionné loin étaient reenslaved par la suite. 
Toujours, quelques esclaves échappés ont trouvé le refuge 
avec les groupes américains indigènes ou dans de petites, 
d'isolement colonies marron.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Setembro o 18, 1762 a edição do gazette de carolina sul 
incluiu observações de animais dispersos, esposas do runaway, e 
escapou de escravos. Junto com quebrar ferramentas, a doença 
fingindo, e retardar o trabalho, funcionar afastado, individualmente 
ou nos grupos, estava um formulário comum da resistência ao slavery.
A maioria daquelas que funcionaram afastado fêz assim por 
períodos curtos, para visitar frequentemente esposos ou parentes em 
outras fazendas, ou para escapar da punição. As possibilidades
eram slim para o escape permanente, e a maioria daquelas que 
funcionaram afastado era reenslaved eventualmente. Ainda, alguns
escravos escapados encontraram o refúgio com grupos americanos 
nativos ou em colônias marrons pequenas, isoladas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">18 settembre 1762 l'edizione del gazette della Carolina 
del Sud ha incluso gli avvisi degli animali esterni, mogli di 
instabilità ed ha fuoriuscito gli schiavi. Con rompere gli 
strumenti, la malattia fingente e ritardare il lavoro, funzionare via,
individualmente o nei gruppi, era una forma comune di resistenza a 
slavery. La maggior parte di coloro che ha funzionato via hanno 
fatto così in breve i periodi, per visitare spesso gli sposi o i 
parenti su altri poderi, o per fuoriuscire la punizione. Le 
probabilità erano sottili per la fuga permanente e la maggior parte 
di coloro che ha funzionato via erano finalmente reenslaved. 
Eppure, alcuni schiavi fuoriusciti hanno trovato il rifugio con 
i gruppi americani natali o nelle piccole, colonie marrone rossiccio 
isolate.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">18 Σεπτεμβρίου έκδοση ..1762 της εφημερίδας της 
νότιας Καρολίνας περιέλαβε τις ειδοποιήσεις των περιπλανώμενων 
ζώων, σύζυγοι δραπέτη, και δραπέτευσε τους σκλάβους. Μαζί 
με το σπάσιμο των εργαλείων, feigning η ασθένεια, και την 
επιβράδυνση της εργασίας, που τρέχει μακριά, χωριστά ή κατά 
ομάδες, ήταν μια κοινή μορφή της αντίστασης στη σκλαβιά. 
Οι περισσότεροι από εκείνους που έτρεξαν μακριά έκαναν 
έτσι για τις μικρές χρονικές περιόδους, συχνά για να επισκεφτούν
τους συζύγους ή τους συγγενείς σε άλλα αγροκτήματα, ή για να 
δραπετεύσουν την τιμωρία. Οι πιθανότητες ήταν λεπτές για τη
μόνιμη διαφυγή, και οι περισσότεροι από εκείνους που έτρεξαν 
μακριά ήταν τελικά. Ακόμα, μερικοί δραπετευμένοι σκλάβοι 
βρήκαν το καταφύγιο με τις εγγενείς αμερικανικές ομάδες ή στις 
μικρές, απομονωμένες καφέ αποικίες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">18 de septiembre de 1762 la edición de la gaceta de 
Carolina del Sur incluyó los avisos de los animales perdidos, esposas
del fugitivo, y escapó esclavos. Junto con romper las 
herramientas, enfermedad que fingía, y retardar el trabajo, 
ejecutarse lejos, individualmente o en grupos, estaba una forma común
de resistencia a la esclavitud. La mayoría de los que se 
ejecutaron lejos hicieron tan por períodos cortos, para visitar a 
menudo esposos o a parientes en otras granjas, o para escapar el 
castigo. Las ocasiones eran delgadas para el escape permanente, 
y la mayoría de los que se ejecutaron lejos eran reenslaved eventual.
No obstante, algunos esclavos escapados encontraron el refugio 
con los grupos americanos nativos o en colonias marrón pequeñas, 
aisladas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086773</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105865</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/ran-off</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
