<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108121</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108121</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206297</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">NeMO Explorer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">NeMO Forscher</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Explorateur de NeMO</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Explorador De NeMO</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Esploratore Di NeMO</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">NeMO εξερευνητής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Explorador De NeMO</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">allows students to explore a seafloor observatory geographically or by topic. Learn about seafloor animals, hydrothermal vents, mid-ocean ridges, axial volcano, lava flow, and technology and tools. Operate (remotely) a vehicle that takes you to the seafloor near an active submarine volcano. Explore black smoker vents, new lava flows, and unusual life forms.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erlaubt Kursteilnehmern, eine seafloor Sternwarte 
Thema geographisch oder durch zu erforschen. Erlernen Sie über 
seafloor Tiere, hydrothermale Entlüftungsöffnungen, Mittlerozean 
Kanten, axialer Vulkan, Lavafluß und Technologie und Hilfsmittel. 
Lassen Sie (entfernt) einen Träger laufen, der Nehmen Sie zum 
seafloor nahe einem aktiven Unterwasservulkan. Erforschen Sie 
schwarze Raucherentlüftungsöffnungen, neue Lavaflüsse und 
ungewöhnliche Lebensformen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">permet à des étudiants d'explorer un 
observatoire de seafloor géographiquement ou par sujet. 
Renseignez-vous sur des animaux de seafloor, des évents 
hydrothermiques, des arêtes de mi-océan, volcan axial, écoulement 
de lave, et technologie et des outils. Actionnez (à distance) 
un véhicule qui des prises vous au seafloor près d'un volcan 
submersible actif. Explorez les évents noirs de fumeur, les 
nouveaux écoulements de lave, et les formes de vie peu communes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">permite que os estudantes explorem um obervatório
do seafloor geogràfica ou pelo tópico. Aprenda sobre animais 
do seafloor, respiradouros hydrothermal, cumes do mid-oceano, vulcão 
axial, fluxo da lava, e tecnologia e ferramentas. Opere 
(remotamente) um veículo que tomadas você ao seafloor perto de um 
vulcão submarino ativo. Explore respiradouros pretos do smoker,
fluxos novos da lava, e formulários de vida incomuns.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">permette che gli allievi esplorino un osservatorio
di seafloor geograficamente o dal soggetto. Impari circa gli 
animali di seafloor, sfiati idrotermali, creste dell'metà di-oceano, 
vulcano assiale, flusso della lava e tecnologia e strumenti. 
Faccia funzionare (a distanza) un veicolo che introiti voi al 
seafloor vicino ad un vulcano sottomarino attivo. Esplori gli 
sfiati neri del fumatore, i nuovi flussi della lava e le forme di vita
insolite.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">επιτρέπει στους σπουδαστές για να εξερευνήσει ένα 
παρατηρητήριο θαλάσσιου πυθμένα γεωγραφικά ή από το θέμα. 
Μάθετε για τα ζώα θαλάσσιου πυθμένα, τις υδροθερμικές 
διεξόδους, τις mid-ocean κορυφογραμμές, το αξονικό ηφαίστειο, 
τη ροή λάβας, και την τεχνολογία και τα εργαλεία. 
Ενεργοποιήστε (μακρινά) ένα όχημα που σας παίρνει στο 
θαλάσσιο πυθμένα κοντά σε ένα ενεργό υποβρύχιο ηφαίστειο. 
Ερευνήστε τις μαύρες διεξόδους καπνιστών, τις νέες ροές 
λάβας, και τις ασυνήθιστες μορφές ζωής.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">permite que los estudiantes exploren un 
observatorio del seafloor geográficamente o por asunto. Aprenda
sobre animales del seafloor, los respiraderos hidrotérmicos, los 
cantos del mediados de-oce'ano, volcán axial, flujo de la lava, y 
tecnología y las herramientas. Funcione (remotamente) un 
vehículo que las tomas usted al seafloor cerca de un volcán 
submarino activo. Explore los respiraderos negros del fumador, 
los nuevos flujos de la lava, y las formas de vida inusuales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206297</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108121</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/nemo-explorer</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
