<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103230</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103230</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086875</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">T-Bone Slim Pens "The Lumberjack's Prayer"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">T-Knochen Dünn Federn "Das Gebet Des 
Holzfällers"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">T-Os Mince Crayons lecteurs "La Prière du 
Bûcheron"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">T-Osso Slim Penas "O Prayer Do Lumberjack"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">T-Osso Sottile Penne "La Preghiera Del 
Lumberjack"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">T-Bone λεπτές πέννες "η προσευχή του υλοτόμου"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">T-Hueso Delgado Plumas "El Rezo Del Lumberjack"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Lumberjacks often worked twelve hours a day, seven days a week, faced incredible dangers on the job, and lived under horrendous conditions. They were one of the most abused groups of workers in the early 20th century. The Industrial Workers of the World (IWW) was the only labor organization to pay any attention to workers in the lumber camps of the South and the Pacific Northwest. Although humorous in tone, the poem "The Lumberjack's Prayer" captured the grueling conditions that most lumbermen faced on and off the job. "The Lumberjack's Prayer" was written by T-Bone Slim and circulated on small colored cards that the IWW (also known as the "Wobblies") sold to raise money. T-Bone Slim (born Matt Valentine Huhta) was a popular Wobbly writer. The nickname "Slim" was often used by hoboes, perhaps because they tended to be skinny from lack of food. In Wobbly publications, Christ was sometimes called "Jerusalem Slim."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Holzfäller bearbeiteten häufig zwölf Stunden 
pro Tag, sieben Tage ein Woche, gegenübergestellte unglaubliche 
Gefahren auf dem Job, und gelebt unter horrenden Bedingungen. 
Sie waren eine der mißbrauchten Gruppen der Arbeiter im frühen
20. Jahrhundert. Die industriellen Arbeiter der Welt (IWW) waren
die einzige Gewerkschaft, zum jeder möglicher Aufmerksamkeit auf 
Arbeiter in den Bauholzlagern des Süd- und pazifischen Nordwestens zu
lenken. Obgleich humorvoll im Ton, erfaßte das Gedicht "das 
Gebet des Holzfällers" die anstrengenden Bedingungen, denen die 
meisten Holzfäller auf und weg vom Job gegenüberstellten. "das
Gebet des Holzfällers" wurde von T-T-Bone Slim geschrieben und 
verteilte auf kleinen farbigen Karten, denen das IWW (alias das 
"Wobblies") verkaufte, um Geld anzuheben. Der dünne T-Knochen 
(getragenes mattes Valentine Huhta) war ein populärer Wobbly 
Verfasser. Der "dünne" Spitzname wurde häufig durch hoboes, 
möglicherweise verwendet, weil sie neigten, vom Mangel an Nahrung 
dünn zu sein. In den Wobbly Publikationen wurde Christ genannt 
manchmal "dünnes Jerusalem."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les bûcherons ont souvent travaillé douze heures
par jour, sept jours par semaine, dangers incroyables faits face sur 
le travail, et vécu dans des conditions affreuses. Ils étaient
l'un des groupes d'ouvriers les plus maltraités en début du 20ème 
siècle. Les ouvriers industriels du monde (IWW) étaient la 
seule organisation de travail pour prêter n'importe quelle attention 
aux ouvriers dans les camps de bois de charpente du nord-ouest 
Du sud et Pacifique. Bien que plein d'humour dans la 
tonalité, la poésie "la prière du bûcheron" a capturé les 
conditions épuisantes que la plupart des bûcherons ont fait face en 
marche et en arrêt au travail. "la prière du bûcheron" a 
été écrite par T-T-Bone Slim et a circulé sur les petites cartes 
colorées que l'IWW (également connu sous le nom de "Wobblies") s'est
vendu pour soulever l'argent. Le T-Os mince (Valentine mat 
soutenu Huhta) était un auteur wobbly populaire. Le surnom 
"mince" a été souvent employé par des hoboes, peut-être parce 
qu'ils ont tendu à être maigres du manque de nourriture. En 
publications wobbly, le Christ s'est parfois appelé "Jérusalem 
mince."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os lumberjacks trabalharam frequentemente doze 
horas um o dia, sete dias uma semana, perigos incredible enfrentados 
no trabalho, e vivido sob circunstâncias horrendous. Eram um 
dos grupos os mais abusados dos trabalhadores no 20o século 
adiantado. Os trabalhadores industriais do mundo (IWW) eram a 
única organização labor para pagar toda a atenção aos 
trabalhadores nos acampamentos da madeira serrada do noroeste sul e 
pacífico. Embora humorous no tom, o prayer o poema "do 
lumberjack" capturou as circunstâncias grueling em que a maioria de 
lumbermen enfrentaram e fora do trabalho. "o prayer do 
lumberjack" foi escrito por T-Osso Slim e circulou nos cartões 
coloridos pequenos que o IWW (sabido também como o "Wobblies") vendeu
para levantar o dinheiro. O T-Osso slim (Valentine matt 
carregado Huhta) era um escritor wobbly popular. O nickname 
"slim" foi usado frequentemente por hoboes, talvez porque tenderam a 
ser skinny da falta do alimento. Em publicações wobbly, Christ
foi chamado às vezes "Jerusalem slim."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I lumberjacks hanno lavorato spesso dodici ore al 
giorno, sette giorni un la settimana, pericoli incredibili affrontati 
sul lavoro e vivo nelle circostanze horrendous. Erano uno dei 
gruppi degli operai abusati nell'inizio del 20esimo secolo. I 
lavoratori dell'industria del mondo (IWW) erano l'unica organizzazione
di lavoro per prestare tutta l'attenzione agli operai negli 
accampamenti del legname del nord-ovest del sud e pacifico. 
Anche se divertente nel tono, la preghiera il poem "del 
lumberjack" ha bloccato le circostanze faticose che la maggior parte 
dei tagliaboschi hanno affrontato in funzione e a riposo il lavoro. 
"la preghiera del lumberjack" è stata scritta da T-T-Bone Slim 
ed ha circolato sulle piccole schedi colorate che il IWW (anche 
conosciuto come "il Wobblies") ha venduto per alzare i soldi. 
L'T-Osso sottile (Valentine opaco sopportato Huhta) era un 
produttore wobbly popolare. Il nickname "sottile" è stato usato
spesso dai hoboes, forse perché hanno teso ad essere skinny da 
mancanza di alimento. In pubblicazioni wobbly, Christ a volte è
stato chiamato "Gerusalemme sottile."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι υλοτόμοι που εργάστηκαν συχνά δώδεκα ώρες 
ημερησίως, επτά ημέρες εβδομαδιαίως, αντιμετώπισαν τους 
απίστευτους κινδύνους στην εργασία, και έζησαν υπό τους φρικτούς
όρους. Ήταν μια από τις πιό κακομεταχειρισμένες ομάδες 
εργαζομένων στις αρχές του 20ού αιώνα. Οι βιομηχανικοί 
εργάτες του κόσμου (IWW) ήταν η μόνη οργάνωση εργασίας για να
δώσουν οποιαδήποτε προσοχή στους εργαζομένους στα στρατόπεδα 
ξυλείας του νότου και των ειρηνικών βορειοδυτικών. Αν και 
χιουμοριστικό στον τόνο, το ποίημα "η προσευχή του υλοτόμου" 
συνέλαβε τους εξαντλητικούς όρους εκείνους τους τα περισσότερα 
lumbermen που αντιμετωπίστηκαν σε και από την εργασία. 
"Την προσευχή του υλοτόμου" γράφτηκε από t-Bone λεπτό 
και κυκλοφόρησαν στις μικρές χρωματισμένες κάρτες ότι το IWW 
(επίσης γνωστό ως "wobblies") πώλησε για να συγκεντρώσει τα 
χρήματα. T-Bone λεπτό (γεννημένος ματ βαλεντίνος 
Huhta) ήταν δημοφιλής wobbly συγγραφέας. Το παρωνύμιο 
"λεπτό" χρησιμοποιήθηκε συχνά από τα hoboes, ίσως επειδή 
έτειναν να είναι μεμβρανοειδή από την έλλειψη τροφίμων. 
Στις wobbly δημοσιεύσεις, Χριστός κλήθηκε μερικές φορές 
"Ιερουσαλήμ λεπτή."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los lumberjacks trabajaron a menudo doce horas al 
día, siete días una semana, peligros increíbles hechos frente en el
trabajo, y vivido bajo condiciones horrendas. Eran uno de los 
grupos abusados de trabajadores en el vigésimo siglo temprano. 
Los trabajadores industriales del mundo (IWW) eran la única 
organización de trabajo para prestar cualquier atención a los 
trabajadores en los campos de la madera de construcción del noroeste 
del sur y pacífico. Aunque es chistoso en tono, el rezo el 
poema "del lumberjack" capturó las condiciones grueling que la 
mayoría de los lañadores hicieron frente por intervalos al trabajo. 
"el rezo del lumberjack" fue escrito por T-T-Bone Slim y 
circuló en las tarjetas coloreadas pequeñas que el IWW (también 
conocido como el "Wobblies") vendió para levantar el dinero. El
T-Hueso delgado (Valentine mate llevado Huhta) era programa de 
escritura wobbly popular. El apodo "delgado" fue utilizado a 
menudo por los hoboes, quizás porque tendieron para ser flacos de la 
carencia del alimento. En publicaciones wobbly, llamaron Cristo 
a veces "Jerusalén delgada."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086875</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103230</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/t-bone-slim-pens-the-lumberjacks-prayer</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
