<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107452</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107452</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087238</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Why Did We Have to Win It Twice?": A Physicist Remembers His Work on the First Atomic Bomb</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"warum wir ihn zweimal gewinnen mußten?": 
Ein Physiker erinnert sich an seine Arbeit über die erste 
Atombombe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"pourquoi nous avons dû le gagner deux fois?" : 
Un physicien se rappelle son travail sur la première panne 
atomique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"porque nós tivemos que o ganhar duas vezes?": 
Um físico recorda seu trabalho na primeira bomba atômica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"perchè abbiamo dovuto vincerli due volte?": 
Un fisico si ricorda del suo lavoro sulla prima bomba atomica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Γιατί πρέπει να το κερδίσουμε δύο φορές;": 
Ένας φυσικός θυμάται την εργασία του για την πρώτη ατομική
βόμβα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"porqué tuvimos que ganarla dos veces?": Un
físico recuerda su trabajo sobre la primera bomba atómica</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Those who built the atomic bomb at the secret Los Alamos, New Mexico, facility understood very well the potential for destruction and death they had created, though individual reactions of the scientists varied widely. Some argued that America needed to develop nuclear weapons before the Germans did. Others argued that a war against fascism demanded the most lethal measures. Still others, as they witnessed the blast on July 16, 1945, were appalled at what they had unleashed. In this excerpt from a 1980 interview, Bernard Feld recalled his work as a graduate student at Los Alamos. While he had few reservations about the bomb's development and its first use at Hiroshima, he had profound reservations about using the second bomb against Nagasaki.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die, die die Atombombe beim geheimen Los Alamos 
aufbauten, New-Mexico, Teildienst verstanden sehr gut das Potential 
für Zerstörung und Tod, die sie erstellt hatten, zwar einzelne 
Reaktionen von den Wissenschaftlern, die weit verändert wurden. 
Einige argumentierten, daß Amerika Kernwaffen entwickeln 
mußte, bevor die Deutschen. Andere argumentierten, daß ein 
Krieg gegen Faschismus die lebensgefährlichsten Masse verlangte. 
Noch andere, während sie den Knall an Juli 16 zeugten, 1945, 
wurden entsetzt an, was sie unleashed. In diesem Excerpt von 
einem Interview 1980, erinnerte an Bernard Feld seine Arbeit als 
Schulabgänger bei Los Alamos. Während er wenige Vorbehalte 
bezüglich der der Entwicklung und seines ersten Gebrauches Bombe in 
Hiroschima hatte, hatte er profunde Vorbehalte bezüglich des 
Verwendens der zweiten Bombe gegen Nagasaki.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ceux qui ont construit la panne atomique chez le 
Los Alamos secret, Nouveau-Mexique, service ont compris très bien le 
potentiel pour la destruction et la mort qu'elles avaient créée, 
cependant différentes réactions des scientifiques changés 
considérablement. Certains ont argué du fait que l'Amérique a
dû développer les armes nucléaires avant que les Allemands . 
D'autres ont argué du fait qu'une guerre contre le fascisme a 
exigé les mesures les plus mortelles. Encore d'autres, pendant 
qu'elles étaient témoin du souffle 16 juillet 1945, appalled à ce 
qu'elles avaient lâché. Dans cet extrait d'une entrevue 1980, 
Bernard Feld a rappelé son travail en tant qu'étudiant gradué chez 
Los Alamos. Tandis qu'il avait peu de réservations au sujet de 
sa première utilisation de la panne du développement et à 
Hiroshima, il a eu des réservations profondes au sujet d'utiliser la 
deuxième panne contre Nagasaki.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Aqueles que construíram a bomba atômica no Los 
Alamos secreto, Novo México, facilidade compreenderam muito bem o 
potencial para a destruição e a morte que tinham criado, though 
reações individuais dos cientistas variados extensamente. 
Alguns discutiram que América necessitou desenvolver armas 
nucleares antes que os alemães . Outros discutiram que uma 
guerra de encontro ao fascism exijiu as medidas as mais letais. 
Ainda outros, enquanto testemunharam a explosão julho em 16, 
1945, appalled em o que tinham desencadeado. Neste excerpt de 
uma entrevista 1980, Bernard Feld recordou seu trabalho como um 
estudante graduado em Los Alamos. Quando teve poucos 
reservations sobre seu primeiro uso da bomba o desenvolvimento e em 
Hiroshima, teve reservations profundos sobre usar a segunda bomba de 
encontro a Nagasaki.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Coloro che ha costruito la bomba atomica al Los 
Alamos segreto, Nuovo Messico, funzione hanno capito molto bene il 
potenziale per distruzione e la morte che avevano creato, comunque 
diverse reazioni degli scienziati variati ampiamente. Alcuni 
hanno sostenuto che l'America ha dovuto sviluppare le armi nucleari 
prima che i tedeschi. Altri hanno sostenuto che una guerra 
contro fascismo ha richiesto le misure più mortali. Ancora 
altri, mentre hanno testimoniato lo scoppio il 16 luglio 1945, 
appalled a che cosa avevano liberato. In questo brano da 
un'intervista 1980, Bernard Feld ha ricordato il suo lavoro come 
allievo laureato a Los Alamos. Mentre ha avuto poche 
prenotazioni circa il relativo primo uso della bomba lo sviluppo ed a 
Hiroshima, ha avuto prenotazioni profonde circa usando la seconda 
bomba contro Nagasaki.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εκείνοι που έχτισαν την ατομική βόμβα στο μυστικό 
Los Alamos, New Mexico, δυνατότητα κατάλαβαν πολύ καλά
τη δυνατότητα για την καταστροφή και το θάνατο που είχαν 
δημιουργήσει, αν και οι μεμονωμένες αντιδράσεις των επιστημόνων 
ποίκιλαν ευρέως. Μερικοί υποστήριξαν ότι η Αμερική έπρεπε
να αναπτύξει τα πυρηνικά όπλα προτού οι Γερμανοί. Αλλοι 
υποστήριξαν ότι ένας πόλεμος ενάντια στο φασισμό απαίτησε τα 
πιό θανατηφόρα μέτρα. Ακόμα άλλοι, δεδομένου ότι 
βεβαίωσαν το φύσημα στις 16 Ιουλίου ..1945, ήταν σε αυτό 
που είχαν εξαπολύσει. Σε αυτό το απόσπασμα από μια 
συνέντευξη του 1980, Bernard Feld υπενθύμισε την εργασία του 
ως διαβαθμισμένο σπουδαστή στο Los Alamos. Ενώ είχε 
λίγες επιφυλάξεις για την ανάπτυξη της βόμβας και την πρώτη 
χρήση του στη Χιροσίμα, είχε τις βαθιές επιφυλάξεις για τη 
χρησιμοποίηση της δεύτερης βόμβας ενάντια στο Ναγκασάκι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los que construyeron la bomba atómica en el Los 
Alamos secreto, New México, recurso entendían muy bien el potencial 
para la destrucción y la muerte que habían creado, aunque reacciones
individuales de los científicos variados extensamente. Algunos 
discutieron que América necesitara desarrollar las armas nucleares 
antes de que lo hicieran los alemanes. Otros discutieron que una
guerra contra fascismo exigiera las medidas más mortales. 
Todavía otros, pues atestiguaron la ráfaga 16 de julio de 
1945, eran aterrados en lo que habían destraillado. En este 
extracto de una entrevista an o 80, Bernard Feld recordó su trabajo 
como estudiante graduado en Los Alamos. Mientras que él tenía 
pocas reservas sobre su primer uso de la bomba el desarrollo y en 
Hiroshima, él tenía reservas profundas sobre usar la segunda bomba 
contra Nagasaki.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087238</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107452</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/why-did-we-have-to-win-it-twice-a-physicist-remembers-his-work-on-the-first-atomic-bomb</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
