<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108345</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108345</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206280</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Environmental Explorers' Club</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Verein Der Klimaforscher</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Club des Explorateurs Environnementaux</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Clube Dos Exploradores Ambientais</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Randello Degli Esploratori Ambientali</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Λέσχη των περιβαλλοντικών εξερευνητών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Club De los Exploradores Ambientales</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a place where kids can learn about the environment and the Environmental Protection Agency. It features plants and animals, air, water, people and the environment, recycling, and a clubhouse area containing art, a game room, a science room, and a trophy room listing the winners of the President's Environmental Youth Award.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist ein Platz, in dem Zicklein über die Umgebung 
und die Behörde für Umweltschutz erlernen können. Er 
kennzeichnet Betriebe und Tiere, Luft, Wasser, Leute und die Umgebung,
Wiederverwertung und ein Klubhausbereich, der kunst, einen Spielraum, 
einen Wissenschaft Raum und einen Trophäeraum ausdruckt die Sieger 
von Environmental Youth Award des Präsidenten enthält.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est un endroit où les gosses peuvent se 
renseigner sur l'environnement et l'agence de protection de 
l'environnement. Il comporte des usines et des animaux, air, 
l'eau, les gens et l'environnement, réutilisation, et une zone de 
pavillion contenant l'art, une salle de jeu, une salle de la science, 
et une salle de trophée énumérant les gagnants de Environmental 
Youth Award du Président.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é um lugar onde os miúdos possam aprender sobre 
o ambiente e a agência de proteção ambiental. Caracteriza 
plantas e animais, ar, água, povos e o ambiente, recycling, e uma 
área do clubhouse que contem a arte, um quarto do jogo, um quarto da 
ciência, e um quarto do trophy que alista os vencedores de Ambiental 
Jovem Conceder do presidente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è un posto in cui i capretti possono imparare 
circa l'ambiente e l'ente per la salvaguardia dell'ambiente. 
Caratterizza le piante ed animali, aria, acqua, la gente e 
l'ambiente, riciclare e una zona del clubhouse che contiene l'arte, 
una stanza del gioco, una stanza di scienza e una stanza del trophy 
che elenca i vincitori dell'Environmental la Youth Award del 
presidente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι μια θέση όπου τα κατσίκια μπορούν να μάθουν 
για το περιβάλλον και την αντιπροσωπεία προστασίας του 
περιβάλλοντος. Χαρακτηρίζει τα φυτά και τα ζώα, τον αέρα, 
το ύδωρ, τους ανθρώπους και το περιβάλλον, την ανακύκλωση, και μια
περιοχή clubhouse που περιέχει την τέχνη, ένα δωμάτιο 
παιχνιδιών, ένα δωμάτιο επιστήμης, και ένα δωμάτιο τροπαίων που
εμφανίζει λίστα τους νικητές του περιβαλλοντικού βραβείου 
νεολαίας του Προέδρου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es un lugar en donde los cabritos pueden aprender 
sobre el ambiente y la agencia de protección del medio ambiente. 
Ofrece las plantas y los animales, aire, agua, gente y el 
ambiente, reciclaje, y un área del clubhouse que contiene arte, un 
cuarto del juego, un cuarto de la ciencia, y un cuarto del trofeo que 
enumera a los ganadores de Environmental Youth Award del presidente.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206280</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108345</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/environmental-explorers-club</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
