<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105839</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105839</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206886</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Memories of Montpelier: Home of James and Dolley Madison</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Speicher von Montpelier: Haus von James und 
von Dolley Madison</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mémoires de Montpelier : Maison de 
James et de Dolley Madison</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Memórias de Montpelier: HOME de James e de 
Dolley Madison</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Memorie di Montpelier: Sede di James e di 
Dolley Madison</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μνήμες Montpelier: "Οικία" james και 
Dolley Μάντισον</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Memorias de Montpelier: Hogar de James y de 
Dolley Madison</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">describes the setting, main house, and grounds of the home of our fourth President and the father of the Constitution. It also provides insights into daily life in the 19th century in a home located on a 5,000-acre plantation in the Piedmont of Virginia. The Madisons received many visitors; in fact, it was not uncommon for them to have as many as 25 guests requiring both room and board.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">beschreibt die Einstellung, das Haupthaus und den 
Boden des Hauses unseres vierten Präsidenten und des Vaters der 
Beschaffenheit. Sie stellt auch Einblicke in tägliche 
Lebensdauer im 19. Jahrhundert in einem Haus zur Verfügung, das auf 
einer Plantage 5,000-acre im Piedmont von Virginia gelegen ist. 
Das Madisons empfing viele Besucher; tatsächlich war es 
nicht selten für sie, bis zu wie 25 Gäste zu haben, die Raum und 
Brett benötigen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">décrit la configuration, la maison principale, et
les raisons de la maison de notre quatrième président et du père de
la constitution. Elle fournit également des perspicacités dans
la vie quotidienne au 19ème siècle dans une maison située sur une 
plantation 5,000-acre dans le Piémont de la Virginie. Le 
Madisons a reçu beaucoup de visiteurs ; en fait, il n'était 
pas rare que ils aient l'autant d'en tant que 25 invités ayant besoin
de la pièce et du panneau.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">descreve o ajuste, a casa principal, e as terras 
da HOME de nosso quarto presidente e do pai do constitution. 
Fornece também introspecções na vida diária no 1ø século 
em uma HOME situada em uma plantação 5,000-acre no Piedmont de 
Virgínia. O Madisons recebeu muitos visitantes; no fato, 
não era uncommon para eles ter o tanto como como 25 convidados que 
requerem  o quarto e a placa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">descrive la regolazione, la casa principale ed i 
motivi della sede del nostro presidente di quarto e del padre 
della costituzione. Egualmente fornisce le comprensioni in vita 
quotidiana nel diciannovesimo secolo in una sede situata su una 
piantagione 5,000-acre nel Piemonte della Virginia. Il Madisons 
ha ricevuto molti ospiti; infatti, per loro non era raro avere 
altretanto come 25 ospiti che richiedono sia la stanza che il 
bordo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">περιγράφει την τιμή τών παραμέτρων, το βασικό σπίτι,
και τους λόγους του σπιτιού του τέταρτου Προέδρου μας και του 
πατέρα του συντάγματος. Παρέχει επίσης τις ιδέες στην 
καθημερινή ζωή στο 19$ο αιώνα σε ένα σπίτι που βρίσκεται σε μια 
φυτεία 5.000-στρέμματος piedmont της Βιρτζίνια. Το 
Madisons έλαβε πολλούς επισκέπτες  στην πραγματικότητα, 
δεν ήταν ασυνήθιστο για τους να έχουν τουλάχιστον 25 
φιλοξενουμένους που απαιτούν και το δωμάτιο και τον πίνακα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">describe la configuración, la casa principal, y 
los argumentos del hogar de nuestro cuarto presidente y del padre de 
la constitución. También proporciona a penetraciones en vida 
de cada día en el diecinueveavo siglo en un hogar situado en una 
plantación 5,000-acre en el Piedmont de Virginia. El Madisons 
recibió a muchos visitantes; en hecho, no era infrecuente que 
tengan tanto como 25 huéspedes que requerían el sitio y a tarjeta.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206886</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105839</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/memories-of-montpelier-home-of-james-and-dolley-madison</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
