<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106748</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106748</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206814</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Civil War Maps</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bürgerkrieg-Karten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cartes de Guerre Civile</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Mapas Da Guerra Civil</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Programmi Di Guerra Civile</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Χάρτες εμφύλιου πολέμου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Correspondencias De la Guerra Civil</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features detailed battle maps made by Major Jedediah Hotchkiss for General Lee and General Sherman, and maps taken from diaries, scrapbooks, and manuscripts -- all available for the first time in one place. An essay, History of Mapping the Civil War, looks at Union maps, Confederate maps, battlefield maps, commercial maps, and others.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Merkmale schilderten die Schlachtkarten genau, die
von Major Jedediah Hotchkiss für allgemeine Schutze und General 
Sherman gebildet wurden, und die Karten, die zum ersten Mal von den 
Tagebüchern, von den Scrapbooks genommen wurden, und von den 
Manuskripten -- ganz vorhanden in einem Platz. Ein Versuch, 
Geschichte des Diagramms des Bürgerkrieges, Blicke auf 
Anschlußkarten, verbündete Karten, Schlachtfeld Karten, kommerzielle
Karten und andere.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les dispositifs ont détaillé des cartes de 
bataille faites par Major Jedediah Hotchkiss pour la lie et le 
Général généraux Sherman, et des cartes prises à partir des 
agendas, des albums, et des manuscrits -- tout disponibles pour la 
première fois dans un endroit. Un essai, histoire de tracer la 
guerre civile, regards aux cartes des syndicats, aux cartes 
confédérées, aux cartes de champ de bataille, aux cartes 
commerciales, et à d'autres.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">as características detalharam os mapas da batalha
feitos por Principal Jedediah Hotchkiss para lee e o general gerais 
Sherman, e os mapas feitos exame dos diários, dos scrapbooks, e dos 
manuscritos -- toda disponíveis para a primeira vez em um lugar. 
Um essay, history de traçar a guerra civil, olhares em mapas da
união, em mapas confederate, em mapas do campo de batalha, em mapas 
comerciais, e em outros.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">le caratteristiche hanno dettagliato i programmi 
di battaglia fatti da Major Jedediah Hotchkiss per i rifugi ed il 
General generali Sherman ed i programmi presi per la prima volta dai 
diari, dagli album e dai manoscritti -- tutto il disponibili in un 
posto. Un saggio, storia di tracciato della guerra civile, 
sguardi ai programmi del sindacato, ai programmi confederati, ai 
programmi del campo di battaglia, ai programmi commerciali e ad altri.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">τα χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα απαρίθμησαν τους χάρτες 
μάχης που έγιναν από σημαντικό Jedediah Hotchkiss για το 
στρατηγό Lee και το στρατηγό Sherman, και τους χάρτες που 
λήφθηκαν από τα ημερολόγια, τα λευκώματα αποκομμάτων, και τα 
χειρόγραφα -- όλα διαθέσιμα για πρώτη φορά σε μια θέση. 
Ένα δοκίμιο, ιστορία της χαρτογράφησης του εμφύλιου 
πολέμου, εξετάζει τους χάρτες ένωσης, τους ομόσπονδους χάρτες, 
τους χάρτες πεδίων μαχών, τους εμπορικούς χάρτες, και άλλους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">las características detallaron las 
correspondencias de la batalla hechas por Major Jedediah Hotchkiss 
para las heces y general generales Sherman, y las correspondencias 
tomadas de los diarios, de los libros de recuerdos, y de los 
manuscritos -- todo disponibles para la primera vez en un lugar. 
Un ensayo, historia de asociar la guerra civil, miradas en las 
correspondencias de la unión, las correspondencias confederadas, las 
correspondencias del campo de batalla, las correspondencias 
comerciales, y otras.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206814</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106748</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/civil-war-maps</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
