<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104391</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104391</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203572</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Just-in-Time Teaching (JiTT) WarmUp Activity: Marine Archaeology and Technology</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gerade-in-Zeit Unterricht (JiTT) Vorwärmung 
Aktivität: Marinearchäologie und Technologie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Activité De Préchauffage d'Enseignement de 
Juste-dans-Temps (JiTT) : Archéologie et technologie marines</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Atividade Do WarmUp Do Ensino Do Apenas-em-Tempo 
(JiTT): Archaeology e tecnologia marinhos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Attività Di Preriscaldamento Di Insegnamento Di 
Appena-in-Tempo (JiTT): Archaeology e tecnologia marini</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πάνω στην ώρα δραστηριότητα WarmUp διδασκαλίας 
(JiTT): Θαλάσσιες αρχαιολογία και τεχνολογία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Actividad Del Calentamiento De la Enseñanza Del 
Apenas-en-Tiempo (JiTT): Archaeology y tecnología marinas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site from SERC details Just-in-Time Teaching (JiTT) warm up questions about marine archeology and technology. The questions examine how technology has helped and hurt marine archeology, costs of using technology in marine archeology, and various aspects of Bob Ballard's 1999 Ashkelon expedition. Assessment tips and related resources are provided.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site von SERC schildert Gerade-in-Zeit 
Unterricht (JiTT) Vorwärmung Fragen über Marinearchäologie und 
Technologie genau. Die Fragen überprüfen, wie Technologie und 
verletzte Marinearchäologie, Kosten der verwendenden Technologie in 
der Marinearchäologie und verschiedene Aspekte von Bob Ballards 
Ashkelon Expedition 1999 geholfen hat. Einschätzung neigt und 
in Verbindung stehende Betriebsmittel werden zur Verfügung gestellt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site de SERC détaille des questions de 
préchauffage d'enseignement de Juste-dans-Temps (JiTT) au sujet de 
l'archéologie et de la technologie marines. Les questions 
examinent comment la technologie a aidé et archéologie marine 
blessée, coûts de technologie d'utilisation en archéologie marine, 
et divers aspects en expédition 1999 d'Ashkelon de Bob Ballard. 
L'évaluation incline et des ressources relatives sont fournies.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local do ensino do Apenas-em-Tempo dos 
detalhes de SERC (JiTT) aquece acima perguntas sobre o archeology e a 
tecnologia marinhos. As perguntas examinam como a tecnologia 
ajudou e archeology marinho ferido, custos da tecnologia se usando no 
archeology marinho, e vários aspectos da expedição 1999 de Ashkelon
de Bob Ballard. A avaliação derruba e os recursos relacionados
são fornecidos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo da SERC dettaglia le domande di 
preriscaldamento di insegnamento di Appena-in-Tempo (JiTT) circa 
l'archeologia e la tecnologia marine. Le domande esaminano come 
la tecnologia ha aiutato e l'archeologia marina danneggiata, spese per
tecnologia di utilizzazione in archeologia marina e varie funzioni 
della spedizione 1999 di Ashkelon del Bob Ballard. La 
valutazione si capovolge e le risorse relative sono fornite.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή από SERC απαριθμεί τις πάνω στην 
ώρα ερωτήσεις προθέρμανσης διδασκαλίας (JiTT) για τη θαλάσσιες
αρχαιολογία και την τεχνολογία. Οι ερωτήσεις εξετάζουν πώς 
η τεχνολογία έχει βοηθήσει και έχει βλάψει θαλάσσια την 
αρχαιολογία, δαπάνες της χρησιμοποιώντας τεχνολογίας στη θαλάσσια
αρχαιολογία, και διάφορες πτυχές της αποστολής Ashkelon του 
1999 Ballard βαριδιών. Οι άκρες αξιολόγησης και τα 
σχετικά στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς παρέχονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio de SERC detalla preguntas del 
calentamiento de la enseñanza del Apenas-en-Tiempo (JiTT) sobre la 
arqueología y la tecnología marinas. Las preguntas examinan 
cómo la tecnología ha ayudado y arqueología marina lastimada, los 
costes de tecnología que usaba en arqueología marina, y los varios 
aspectos de la expedición 1999 de Ashkelon de Bob Ballard. El 
gravamen inclina y se proporcionan los recursos relacionados.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:LAURA GUERTIN
FN:LAURA GUERTIN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CATHY MANDUCA
FN:CATHY MANDUCA
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203572</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104391</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/just-in-time-teaching-jitt-warmup-activity-marine-archaeology-and-technology</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
