<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106958</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106958</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087052</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The South's Recovery: Who Paid the Price of Success?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Südwiederanlauf: Wer zahlte den Preis 
des Erfolges?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Reprise des Sud : Qui a payé le 
prix du succès ?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A Recuperação Sul: Quem pagou o preço do 
sucesso?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Recupero Del sud: Chi ha pagato il prezzo
di successo?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η νότια αποκατάσταση: Ποιος κατέβαλε την τιμή 
της επιτυχίας;</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Recuperación Del sur: ¿Quién pagó el 
precio del éxito?</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Beginning in the late 1870s, white southern landowners, entrepreneurs, and newspaper editors heralded a vision of a "New South" with a modern, industrial economic system. The defeat of the Confederacy, the abolition of racial slavery, and the demise of the plantation economy provided the South with opportunities to build factories and turn its raw materials into finished products: cotton into cloth, tobacco into cigarettes, coal and iron ore into steel. But mill workers, small farmers, and agricultural tenants and sharecroppers in the "New South" suffered decades of long hours, low pay, unsafe working conditions, and deplorable living situations. These anonymous comments made by cotton mill hands and farmers in 1887 and 1889 to agents of the North Carolina Bureau of Labor Statistics challenged the arguments of the "New South" boosters and illustrated the grim price workers paid for the region's embrace of the much-touted new industrial order.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Anfangend im späten 1870s, kündigten weiße südliche 
Grundbesitzer, Unternehmer und Zeitungsverleger einen Anblick eines 
"neuen Südens" mit einem modernen, industriellen Wirtschaftssystem 
an. Die Niederlage der Konföderation, die Aufhebung der 
rassischen Sklaverei und das Ende der Plantagewirtschaft versahen den 
Süden mit Gelegenheiten, Fabriken aufzubauen und seine Rohstoffe zu 
Fertigwaren zu machen: Baumwolle in Tuch, Tabak in Zigaretten, 
Kohle und Eisenerz in Stahl. Aber Tausendstelarbeiter, kleine 
Landwirte und landwirtschaftliche Pächter und sharecroppers im "neuen
Süden" erlitten Dekaden der langen Stunden, der niedrigen Bezahlung, 
der unsicheren Arbeitsbedingungen und der bedauernswerten lebenden 
Situationen. Dieser anonyme Kommentar, der von den 
Baumwollspinnereihänden und -landwirten 1887 und 1889 zu den Mitteln 
des Nord-Carolina Büros von Arbeitsstatistiken gebildet wurde, 
forderte die Argumente der "neuen Süd" Verstärker heraus und 
veranschaulichte die grimmigen Preisarbeiter, die für die Region 
gezahlt wurden, umfaßt von der much-kündigte neuen industriellen 
Ordnung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Commençant vers la fin de 1870s, les propriétaires 
fonciers, les entrepreneurs, et les éditeurs de journal méridionaux 
blancs ont annoncé une vision d'un "nouveau Sud" avec un 
système économique moderne et industriel. La défaite de la 
confédération, l'abolition de l'esclavage racial, et la cession de 
l'économie de plantation ont fourni aux Sud des occasions de
construire des usines et de transformer ses matières premières 
premières en produits finis : coton dans le tissu, tabac dans 
le minerai de cigarettes, de charbon et de fer dans l'acier. 
Mais les ouvriers de moulin, les petits fermiers, et les 
locataires et les métayers agricoles dans les "nouveaux 
Sud" ont souffert des décennies de longues heures, de bas 
salaire, de conditions de travail peu sûres, et de situations 
vivantes déplorables. Ces commentaires anonymes faits par des 
mains et des fermiers de filature de coton en 1887 et 1889 aux agents 
du bureau du nord de la Caroline des statistiques de travail ont 
défié les arguments des "nouveaux" propulseurs du sud et ont 
illustré les ouvriers sinistres des prix payés la région embrassent
de la nouvelle commande industrielle de much-espionner.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Começando no 1870s atrasado, os latifundiários, os 
empreendedores, e os editores de jornal do sul brancos heralded uma 
visão "de um sul novo" com um sistema econômico moderno, industrial.
A derrota do confederacy, o abolition do slavery racial, e o 
demise da economia da plantação forneceram o sul com as 
oportunidades de construir fábricas e girar seus materiais crus em 
produtos terminados: algodão no pano, tabaco no minério dos 
cigarros, do carvão e de ferro no aço. Mas os trabalhadores do
moinho, os fazendeiros pequenos, e os tenants e os sharecroppers 
agriculturais "no sul novo" sofreram décadas de horas longas, do 
pagamento baixo, de condições de funcionamento inseguras, e de 
situações vivas deplorable. Estes comentários anonymous 
feitos pelas mãos e pelos fazendeiros do moinho de algodão em 1887 e
em 1889 aos agentes do departamento de North.carolina de statistics 
labor desafiaram os argumentos dos impulsionadores "sul" novos e 
ilustraram os trabalhadores grim do preço pagos pela região embrace 
da ordem industrial nova muito-much-touted.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Cominciando verso la fine di 1870s, i latifondisti, gli 
imprenditori e gli editori di giornale del sud bianchi hanno 
annunziato una visione "di nuovo sud" con un sistema economico moderno
e industriale. La sconfitta del confederacy, l'abolizione di 
slavery razziale ed il demise dell'economia della piantagione hanno 
fornito il sud le occasioni costruire le fabbriche e trasformare nelle
relative materie prime i prodotti finiti: cotone nel panno, 
tabacco nelle sigarette, carbone e minerale ferroso in acciaio. 
Ma gli operai del laminatoio, i piccoli coltivatori e gli 
inquilini e gli sharecroppers agricoli "nel nuovo sud" hanno sofferto 
le decadi delle ore lunghe, della paga bassa, delle condizioni di 
lavoro pericolose e delle situazioni viventi deplorable. Queste 
osservazioni anonime formulate dalle mani e dai coltivatori del 
cotonificio in 1887 ed in 1889 agli agenti dell'ufficio del 
North.carolina delle statistiche Di lavoro hanno sfidato gli 
argomenti "di nuovi" ripetitori del sud ed hanno illustrato gli operai
torvi di prezzi pagati la regione abbracciano di nuovo ordine 
industriale molto-much-touted.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αρχίζοντας προς το τέλος 1870s, τα λευκά νότια 
landowners, οι επιχειρηματίες, και οι επεξεργαστές εφημερίδων 
ανακοίνωσαν ένα όραμα ενός "νέου νότου" με ένα σύγχρονο, 
βιομηχανικό οικονομικό σύστημα. Η ήττα της συνομοσπονδίας, 
η κατάργηση της φυλετικής σκλαβιάς, και η μεταβίβαση της 
οικονομίας φυτειών παρείχαν στο νότο τις ευκαιρίες να χτιστούν 
τα εργοστάσια και να μετατραπούν οι πρώτες ύλες της σε 
ολοκληρωμένα προϊόντα: βαμβάκι στο ύφασμα, καπνός στα 
τσιγάρα, μετάλλευμα άνθρακα και σιδήρου στο χάλυβα. Αλλά 
οι εργαζόμενοι μύλων, οι μικροί αγρότες, και οι γεωργικοί 
μισθωτές και οι επίμορτοι καλλιεργητές στο "νέο νότο" υπέστησαν 
τις δεκαετίες πολλών ωρών, χαμηλής αμοιβής, επισφαλών συνθηκών 
εργασίας, και λυπηρών καταστάσεων διαβίωσης. Αυτά τα 
ανώνυμα σχόλια που έγιναν από τα χέρια και τους αγρότες μύλων 
βαμβακιού το 1887 και το 1889 στους πράκτορες του γραφείου 
της βόρειας Καρολίνας των στατιστικών εργασίας προκάλεσαν τα 
ορίσματα των ενισχυτών "νέου νότου" και επεξήγησαν τους 
απαίσιους εργαζομένους τιμών που πληρώθηκαν για τον εναγκαλισμό 
της περιοχής της πολύς-κρμίας νέας βιομηχανικής κατάταξης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Comenzando en el último 1870s, los terratenientes, los 
empresarios, y los redactores meridionales blancos anunciaron una 
visión de un "nuevo sur" con un sistema económico moderno, 
industrial. La derrota del confederacy, la abolición de la 
esclavitud racial, y el fallecimiento de la economía de la 
plantación proveieron del sur oportunidades de construir fábricas y 
de dar vuelta a sus materias primas en productos acabados: 
algodón en el paño, tabaco en el mineral de los cigarrillos, 
del carbón y de hierro en el acero. Pero los trabajadores del 
molino, los granjeros pequeños, y los arrendatarios y los 
sharecroppers agrícolas en el "nuevo sur" sufrieron décadas de 
largases horas, de la paga baja, de condiciones de trabajo inseguras, 
y de situaciones vivas deplorables. Estos comentarios anónimos 
hechos por las manos y los granjeros de la fábrica de algodón en 
1887 y 1889 a los agentes de la oficina de Carolina del Norte de la 
estadística de trabajo desafiaron los argumentos de los aumentadores 
de presión "del sur" nuevos e ilustraron a trabajadores severos del 
precio pagados la región abrazan de la nueva orden industrial 
mucho-much-touted.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087052</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106958</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-souths-recovery-who-paid-the-price-of-success</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
