<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105838</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105838</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087011</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The "One Best Way" to Wash: A Home Economist Explains</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die "eine beste Methode" zu waschen: Ein 
Hauptwirtschaftswissenschaftler Erklärt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'"une meilleure voie" de laver : Un 
Économiste À la maison Explique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A "uma mais melhor maneira" lavar-se: Um 
Economista Home Explica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"l'un modo migliore" lavarsi: Un Economista 
Domestico Spiega</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο "ένας καλύτερος τρόποσ" να πλύνει: Ένας 
οικονομολόγος "Οικιαών εξηγεί</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La "una mejor manera" de lavarse: Un 
Economista Casero Explica</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the early 20th century, new household technology was both accomplished and inspired by the tremendous increase in American industrial production. As in industry, mechanization and scientific management were part of a larger reorganization of work. And as in industry, efficient housekeeping was partially a response to labor unrest--both the "servant problem" and the growing disquiet of middle-class wives. A major proponent of the new housekeeping, Christine Frederick was consulting household editor for  Ladies Home Journal  from 1912 to 1919 and the author of numerous books and pamphlets on scientific management in the home. Frederick's pamphlet,  You and Your Laundry  (1922), instructed women in the daunting complexities of washing clothes--a process comprising fifteen different steps.  You and Your Laundry  also illustrated the close alliance between scientific housework and consumption. Written under the sponsorship of the Hurley Machine Company, Frederick's pamphlet frequently invoked its brand name and products. The pamphlet ended with a pitch for buying on installment, a payment plan that helped to spur consumption.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im frühen 20. Jahrhundert wurde neue Haushalt 
Technologie durch die enorme Zunahme der amerikanischen industriellen 
Industrieproduktion vollendet und angespornt. Wie in der 
Industrie, waren Mechanisierung und wissenschaftliche 
Unternehmensführung ein Teil einer größeren Reorganisierung der 
Arbeit. Und wie in der Industrie, war leistungsfähige 
Haushaltung teilweise eine Antwort zur Arbeitsruhelosigkeit -- das 
"Bedienstetproblem" und die wachsende Besorgnis der 
Mittelklassefrauen. Ein Hauptantragsteller der neuen 
Haushaltung, Christine Frederick beriet Haushalt Herausgeber für 
Dame-Hauptjournal von 1912 bis 1919 und den Autor der zahlreichen 
Bücher und der Flugschriften auf wissenschaftlicher 
Unternehmensführung im Haus. Flugschrift Fredericks, Sie und 
Ihre Laundry (1922), angewiesene Frauen in den erschreckenden 
Kompliziertheiten des Waschens kleidet -- einen Prozeß, der fünfzehn
unterschiedliche Jobsteps enthält. Sie und Ihre Wäscherei 
veranschaulichten auch das enge Bündnis zwischen wissenschaftlicher 
Hausarbeit und Verbrauch. Geschrieben unter die Förderung 
Hurley Machine Company, Flugschrift Fredericks rief häufig seinen 
Markennamen und Produkte hervor. Die Flugschrift beendete mit 
einem Taktabstand für das Kaufen auf Ratenzahlung, ein Zahlung Plan, 
der half, Verbrauch anzutreiben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En début du 20ème siècle, la nouvelle 
technologie de ménage a été accomplie et inspirée par 
l'augmentation énorme de la production industrielle américaine. 
Comme dans l'industrie, la mécanisation et la gestion 
scientifique faisaient partie d'une plus grande réorganisation de 
travail. Et comme dans l'industrie, le ménage efficace était 
partiellement une réponse au malaise ouvrier -- le "problème 
d'domestique" et l'inquiétude croissante des épouses de classe 
moyenne. Un partisan important du nouveau ménage, Christine 
Frederick consultait l'éditeur de ménage pour le journal à la 
maison de dames de 1912 à 1919 et l'auteur de nombreux livres et 
brochures sur la gestion scientifique dans la maison. La 
brochure de Frederick, vous et votre Laundry (1922), les femmes 
instruites dans les complexités intimidantes du lavage vêtx -- un 
processus comportant quinze étapes différentes. Vous et votre 
blanchisserie avez également illustré l'alliance étroite entre les 
travaux domestiques et la consommation scientifiques. Écrit 
sous le patronage de Hurley Machine Company, la brochure de Frederick 
a fréquemment appelé son nom et produits de marque. La 
brochure a terminé avec un lancement pour acheter sur l'acompte, un 
plan de paiement qui a aidé à stimuler la consommation.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No 20o século adiantado, a tecnologia nova da 
casa  foi realizada e inspirada pelo aumento tremendo na produção 
industrial americana. Como na indústria, o mechanization e a 
gerência científica eram parte de um reorganization maior do 
trabalho. E como na indústria, as tarefas domésticas 
eficientes eram parcialmente uma resposta ao unrest labor --  do "o 
problema empregado" e o disquiet crescente de esposas do middle-class.
Um proponent principal das tarefas domésticas novas, Christine 
Frederick consultava o editor da casa para o jornal home das senhoras 
de 1912 a 1919 e o autor de livros e de panfletos numerosos na 
gerência científica na HOME. O panfleto de Frederick, você e 
sua Lavanderia (1922), mulheres instruídas nas complexidades daunting
do lavagem vestem -- um processo que compreende quinze etapas 
diferentes. Você e sua lavanderia ilustraram também o alliance
próximo entre o housework e o consumo científicos. Escrito sob
o sponsorship do Hurley Máquina Companhia, panfleto de Frederick 
invocou freqüentemente seus nome e produtos de tipo. O panfleto
terminou com um passo para comprar na prestação, uma planta do 
pagamento que ajudasse spur o consumo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nell'inizio del 20esimo secolo, la nuova 
tecnologia della famiglia sia è stata compiuta che ispirato stata 
tramite l'incremento tremendo della produzione industriale americana. 
Come nell'industria, la meccanizzazione e la gestione 
scientifica facevano parte di più grande riorganizzazione di lavoro. 
E come nell'industria, il governo della casa efficiente era 
parzialmente una risposta ad agitazione di lavoro -- sia "il 
problema del servo" che l'inquietudine crescente delle mogli della 
classe media. Un fautore importante di nuovo governo della casa,
Christine Frederick stava consultando l'editore della famiglia per il 
giornale domestico delle signore da 1912 a 1919 e l'autore dei libri e
degli opuscoli numerosi sulla gestione scientifica nella sede. 
L'opuscolo del Frederick, voi e la vostra Laundry (1922), donne 
insegnate a nelle complessità scoraggianti di lavaggio copre -- un 
processo che contiene quindici punti differenti. Voi e la vostra
lavanderia egualmente avete illustrato l'alleanza vicina fra lavori 
domestici e consumo scientifici. Scritto sotto il patrocinio del
Hurley Machine Company, opuscolo del Frederick ha invocato 
frequentemente la relativi marca e prodotti. L'opuscolo si è 
concluso con un passo per l'acquisto sulla rata, un programma di 
pagamento che ha contribuito a stimolare il consumo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στις αρχές του 20ού αιώνα, η νέα οικιακή τεχνολογία 
και ολοκληρώθηκε και εμπνεύστηκε από την τεράστια αύξηση στην 
αμερικανική βιομηχανική παραγωγή. Όπως στη βιομηχανία, η 
μηχανοποίηση και η επιστημονική διαχείριση ήταν μέρος μιας 
μεγαλύτερης αναδιοργάνωσης της εργασίας. Και όπως στη 
βιομηχανία, η αποδοτική οικοκυρική ήταν μερικώς μια απάντηση 
στην ανησυχία εργασίας -- και το "πρόβλημα υπαλλήλων" και η 
αυξανόμενη ανησυχία των συζύγων μεσαίων τάξεων. Ένας 
σημαντικός υπερασπιστής της νέας οικοκυρικής, Christine 
Frederick συμβουλευόταν τον οικιακό επεξεργαστή για το 
περιοδικό γυναικείων "Οικιαών από το 1912 ως το 1919 και το 
συντάκτη των πολυάριθμων βιβλίων και των τευχών για την 
επιστημονική διαχείριση στο σπίτι. Το τεύχος του 
Frederick, εσείς και το πλυντήριό σας (1922), καθοδηγημένες 
γυναίκες στις αποθαρρυντικές περιπλοκές της πλύσης ντύνει -- μια 
διαδικασία περιλαμβάνοντας δεκαπέντε διαφορετικά στάδια. 
Εσείς και το πλυντήριό σας επεξηγήσατε επίσης τη στενή 
συμμαχία μεταξύ των επιστημονικών οικιακών και της κατανάλωσης. 
Γραπτός κάτω από την εγγυοδοσία Hurley Machine 
Company, τεύχος Frederick κάλεσε συχνά το εμπορικό σήμα και
τα προϊόντα του. Το τεύχος τελείωσε με μια πίσσα για την 
αγορά στη δόση, ένα σχέδιο πληρωμής που βοήθησε να κεντρίσει 
την κατανάλωση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En el vigésimo siglo temprano, la nueva 
tecnología de la casa fue lograda e inspirada por el enorme aumento 
en la producción industrial americana. Como en industria, la 
mecanización y la gerencia científica eran parte de una 
reorganización más grande del trabajo. Y como en industria, 
las operacíones de entretenimiento eficientes eran parcialmente una 
respuesta al malestar de trabajo -- el "problema del criado" y la 
inquietud cada vez mayor de las esposas de la clase media. Un 
autor importante de las nuevas operacíones de entretenimiento, 
Christine Frederick consultaba el editor de la casa para el diario 
casero de las señoras a partir de 1912 a 1919 y el autor de libros y 
de folletos numerosos en la gerencia científica en el hogar. El
folleto de Frederick, usted y su Laundry (1922), las mujeres mandadas 
en las complejidades desalentadoras de lavarse arropa -- un proceso 
que abarca quince diversos pasos de progresión. Usted y su 
lavadero también ilustraron la alianza cercana entre el quehacer 
doméstico y la consumición científicos. Escrito bajo 
patrocinio del Hurley Machine Company, folleto de Frederick invocó 
con frecuencia su marca y productos. El folleto terminó con una
echada para comprar en la instalación, un plan del pago que ayudó a 
estimular la consumición.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087011</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105838</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-one-best-way-to-wash-a-home-economist-explains</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
