<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106378</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106378</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207214</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Vanderbilt Mansion National Historic Site: Monument to the Gilded Age</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Vanderbilt Villennationale Historische Site: 
Denkmal zum vergoldeten Alter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Site Historique National de Manoir de Vanderbilt :
Monument à l'âge doré</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Local Historic Nacional Do Mansion De Vanderbilt: 
Monumento à idade gilded</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Luogo Storico Nazionale Del Mansion Di Vanderbilt:
Monumento all'età gilded</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εθνική ιστορική περιοχή μεγάρων Vanderbilt: 
Μνημείο στην επιχρυσωμένη ηλικία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sitio Histórico Nacional De la Mansión De 
Vanderbilt: Monumento a la edad dorada</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">describes this Hyde Park estate that includes a palatial Beaux-Arts mansion, stunning views of the Hudson River and Catskill Mountains, and over 600 acres of landscaped property. The mansion was built in 1895-8 by Frederick Vanderbilt, an heir of the fortune created by Cornelius Commodore Vanderbilt. Cornelius, at the age of 16, borrowed $100 from his parents, purchased a periauger (a flat-bottomed sailing barge), and began a ferry service now known as the Staten Island Ferry.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">beschreibt diesen Hyde Park Zustand, der eine 
palatial Galan-Künste Villa, erstaunliche Ansichten des Hudson 
Flusses und Catskill Berge enthält, und über 600 Morgen der 
landschaftlich verschönerten Eigenschaft. Die Villa wurde 
1895-8 von Frederick Vanderbilt, ein Erbe des Vermögens aufgebaut, 
das von Cornelius Flottenadmiral Vanderbilt erstellt wurde. 
Cornelius, am Alter von 16, borgte $100 von seinen Eltern, 
gekauft einem periauger (einem flat-bottomed segelnden Lastkahn) und 
fing einen Fährbetrieb an, der jetzt als die Staten- Islandfähre 
bekannt ist.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">décrit ce domaine de Hyde Park qui inclut un 
manoir somptueux de Beau-Arts, des vues renversantes du fleuve de 
Hudson et des montagnes de Catskill, et plus de 600 acres de 
propriété aménagée en parc. Le manoir a été construit en 
1895-8 par Frederick Vanderbilt, un héritier de la fortune créée 
par Cornelius Commodore Vanderbilt. Cornelius, à l'âge de 16, 
a emprunté $100 à ses parents, achetés un periauger (un chaland de 
navigation à fond plat), et a commencé un service de bac maintenant 
connu sous le nom de bac d'île de Staten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">descreve esta propriedade de Hyde Park que inclui 
um mansion palatial das Beaux-Artes, umas vistas stunning do rio de 
Hudson e umas montanhas de Catskill, e sobre 600 acres da propriedade 
ajardinada. O mansion foi construído em 1895-8 por Frederick 
Vanderbilt, um heir da fortuna criada por Cornelius Commodore 
Vanderbilt. Cornelius, na idade de 16, pediu $100 de seus pais, 
comprados um periauger (uma barca sailing flat-bottomed), e começou 
um serviço de balsa sabido agora como a balsa do console de Staten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">descrive questa proprietà del Hyde Park che 
include un mansion palatial di Beaux-Arti, lle viste sbalorditive del 
fiume di Hudson e lle montagne di Catskill ed oltre 600 acri di 
proprietà modificata il terreno. Il mansion è stato costruito 
in 1895-8 da Frederick Vanderbilt, un erede della fortuna creata da 
Cornelius Commodore Vanderbilt. Cornelius, all'età di 16, ha 
preso in prestito $100 dai suoi genitori, comprati un periauger (una 
chiatta di navigazione flat-bottomed) ed ha cominciato un servizio di 
traghetto ora conosciuto come il traghetto dell'isola di Staten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">περιγράφει αυτό το κτήμα πάρκων Hyde που 
περιλαμβάνει ένα ανακτορικό μέγαρο ψεαuξ-τεχνών, που ζαλίζει 
όψεις του ποταμού Hudson και των βουνών Catskill, και πάνω 
από 600 στρέμματα της εξωραϊσμένης ιδιοκτησίας. Το 
μέγαρο χτίστηκε το 1895-8 από Frederick Vanderbilt, ένας 
κληρονόμος της τύχης που δημιουργήθηκε από τον Cornelius 
Commodore Vanderbilt. Ο Cornelius, στην ηλικία 16, 
δανείστηκε $100 από τους γονείς του, αγόρασε ένα periauger 
(μια με επίπεδο πυθμένα πλέοντας φορτηγίδα), και άρχισε μια 
υπηρεσία πορθμείων γνωστή τώρα ως πορθμείο νησιών Staten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">describe este estado de Hyde Park que incluya una 
mansión palatial de los Beaux-Artes, vistas imponentes del río de 
Hudson y montañas de Catskill, y sobre 600 acres de la 
característica ajardinada. La mansión fue construida en 1895-8
por Frederick Vanderbilt, heredero de la fortuna creada por Cornelius 
Comodoro Vanderbilt. Cornelius, en la edad de 16, pidió 
prestados $100 de sus padres, comprados un periauger (una lancha a 
remolque navegante flat-bottomed), y comenzó un servicio del 
balsear ahora sabido como la isla de Staten Balsea.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207214</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106378</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/vanderbilt-mansion-national-historic-site-monument-to-the-gilded-age</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
