<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104978</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104978</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213239</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">X-Ray Vision, Crystallography</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Röntgenstrahl-Anblick, Kristallographie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Vision de Rayon X, Cristallographie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Visão Do Raio X, Crystallography</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Visione Dei Raggi X, Cristallografia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Των ακτίνων X όραμα, κρυσταλλογραφία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Visión De la Radiografía, Cristalografía</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site features a tutorial designed to allow students to gain an appreciation of how X-ray crystallography works. Using X-ray diffraction patterns to determine the arrangement of atoms in a molecule requires sophisticated mathematics. This activity depends only on light from an overhead projector passing through a ball-and-stick molecular model placed on the stage of the projector, making it an ideal introduction to x-ray diffraction.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Situationsmerkmale, die ein Tutorial 
konzipierte, Kursteilnehmern zu erlauben, zu gewinnen eine Anerkennung
von, wie Röntgenstrahlkristallographie arbeitet. Das Verwenden 
der Röntgenstrahlbeugungmuster, um die Anordnung für Atome in einem 
Molekül festzustellen benötigt hoch entwickelte Mathematik. 
Diese Aktivität hängt nur vom Licht von einem 
Tageslichtprojektor ab, der durch ein Kugel-und-Stock molekulares 
Modell überschreitet, das auf das Stadium des Projektors plaziert 
wird und bildet es eine ideale Einleitung zur Röntgenstrahlbeugung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dispositifs de ce site que un cours d'instruction 
a conçu pour permettre à des étudiants de gagner une appréciation 
de la façon dont la cristallographie de rayon X fonctionne. 
L'utilisation des diagrammes diffraction de rayon X pour 
déterminer l'agencement des atomes dans une molécule exige des 
mathématiques sophistiquées. Cette activité dépend seulement
de la lumière d'un rétroprojecteur passant par un modèle 
moléculaire de boule-et-bâton placé sur l'étape du projecteur, lui
faisant une introduction idéale à la diffraction de rayon X.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Características que deste local um tutorial 
projetou permitir que os estudantes ganhem uma apreciação de como o 
crystallography do raio X trabalha. Usar testes padrões de 
diffraction do raio X determinar o arranjo dos átomos em uma 
molécula requer a matemática sofisticada. Esta atividade 
depende somente da luz de um projetor aéreo que passa através de um 
modelo molecular da esfera-e-vara colocado no estágio do projetor, 
fazendo lhe uma introdução ideal ao diffraction de raio X.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Caratteristiche di questo luogo una lezione 
privata ha progettato permettere che gli allievi guadagnino un 
apprezzamento di come la cristallografia dei raggi X funziona. 
Usando i modelli di diffrazione che dei raggi X per determinare 
la disposizione degli atomi in una molecola richiede la matematica 
specializzata. Questa attività dipende soltanto da luce da un 
proiettore ambientale che passa attraverso un modello molecolare del 
sfera-e-bastone disposto sulla fase del proiettore, rendentegli 
un'introduzione ideale alla diffrazione di raggi X.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει ένα σεμινάριο με σκοπό 
να επιτρέψει στους σπουδαστές για να κερδίσει μια εκτίμηση για το 
πώς η των ακτίνων X κρυσταλλογραφία λειτουργεί. Η 
χρησιμοποίηση των των ακτίνων X προτύπων διάθλασης για να 
καθορίσει τη ρύθμιση των ατόμων σε ένα μόριο απαιτεί τα 
περίπλοκα μαθηματικά. Αυτή η δραστηριότητα εξαρτάται μόνο 
από το φως από έναν υπερυψωμένο προβολέα που περνά μέσω ενός 
μοριακού μοντέλου σφαίρα-και-ραβδιών που τοποθετείται στο στάδιο
του προβολέα, που κάνει το μια ιδανική εισαγωγή στην των ακτίνων 
X διάθλαση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Características de este sitio que una guía 
diseñó permitir que los estudiantes ganen un aprecio de cómo la 
cristalografía de la radiografía trabaja. Usar modelos de 
difracción de radiografía para determinar el arreglo de átomos en 
una molécula requiere matemáticas sofisticadas. Esta actividad
depende solamente de luz de un proyector de arriba que pasa a través 
de un modelo molecular del bola-y-palillo puesto en la etapa del 
proyector, haciéndole una introducción ideal a la difracción de 
radiografía.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213239</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104978</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/x-ray-vision-crystallography</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
