<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105733</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105733</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202710</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Sequential Vocabulary: Lesson I</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sequentieller Wortschatz: Lektion I</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Vocabulaire Séquentiel : Leçon I</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Vocabulário Seqüencial: Lição I</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Vocabolario Sequenziale: Lezione I</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διαδοχικό λεξιλόγιο: Μάθημα Ι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Vocabulario Secuencial: Lección I</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Understanding words is necessary for success in every discipline. Learning to identify and define word parts empowers a student to unlock the meaning of unfamiliar words. This process teaches a life skill rather than memorization of definitions. Sequential Vocabulary: Lesson I is designed to be taught with Sequential Vocabulary: Lessons II, III, and IV.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wörter zu verstehen ist für Erfolg in jeder 
Disziplin notwendig. Das Lernen, Wortteile zu kennzeichnen und 
zu definieren bevollmächtigt einen Kursteilnehmer, um die Bedeutung 
der nicht vertrauten Wörter zu entsperren. Dieser Prozeß 
unterrichtet eine Lebenfähigkeit anstatt Memorieren von Definitionen.
Sequentieller Wortschatz: Lektion I ist konzipiert, mit 
sequentiellem Wortschatz unterrichtet zu werden: Lektionen II, 
III und IV.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les mots d'arrangement est nécessaire pour le 
succès dans chaque discipline. L'étude pour identifier et 
définir des pièces de mot autorise un étudiant pour déverrouiller 
la signification des mots peu familiers. Ce processus enseigne 
une technique de la vie plutôt que la mémorisation des définitions.
Vocabulaire Séquentiel : La leçon I est conçue pour 
être enseignée avec le vocabulaire séquentiel : Leçons II, 
III, et IV.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Compreender palavras é necessária para o sucesso
em cada disciplina. Aprender identificar e definir as peças da 
palavra empowers um estudante para destravar o meaning de palavras 
estranhas. Este processo ensina uma habilidade da vida melhor 
que o memorization das definições. Vocabulário Seqüencial: 
A lição I é projetada ser ensinada com vocabulário 
seqüencial: Lições II, III, e IV.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Capire le parole è necessario per successo in 
ogni disciplina. Imparare identificare e definire le parti di 
parola autorizza un allievo per sbloccare il significato delle parole 
non pratiche. Questo processo insegna una tecnica di vita 
piuttosto che la memorizzazione delle definizioni. Vocabolario 
Sequenziale: La lezione I è destinata per essere insegnata con 
vocabolario sequenziale: Lezioni II, III e dispositivo di 
venipunzione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η κατανόηση των λέξεων είναι απαραίτητη για την 
επιτυχία σε κάθε πειθαρχία. Η εκμάθηση να προσδιορίζονται 
και να καθορίζονται τα μέρη λέξης εξουσιοδοτεί έναν σπουδαστή 
για να ξεκλειδώσει την έννοια των άγνωστων λέξεων. Αυτή η 
διαδικασία διδάσκει μια ικανότητα ζωής παρά την αποστήθιση των 
ορισμών. Διαδοχικό λεξιλόγιο: Το μάθημα Ι έχει ως 
σκοπό να διδαχθεί με το διαδοχικό λεξιλόγιο: Μαθήματα ΙΙ, 
ΙΙΙ, και IV.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Entender palabras es necesario para el éxito en 
cada disciplina. El aprender identificar y definir piezas de la 
palabra autoriza a estudiante para abrir el significado de palabras 
desconocedoras. Este proceso enseña una habilidad de la vida 
más bien que la memorización de definiciones. Vocabulario 
Secuencial: La lección I se diseña para ser enseñada con 
vocabulario secuencial: Lecciones II, III, e intravenoso.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:VALERIE HENDRICKS
FN:VALERIE HENDRICKS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202710</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105733</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/sequential-vocabulary-lesson-i</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
