<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105505</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105505</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086376</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Just before the firing started.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kurz bevor die Zündung begann.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Juste avant que la mise à feu ait commencé.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Imediatamente antes que o despedimento começou.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Appena prima che l'infornamento ha cominciato.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αμέσως πριν από την πυρκαγιά που αρχίζει.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Momentos antes que la despedida comenzó.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">After long accepting low pay, long hours, and dangerous working conditions, Polish oil refinery workers in Bayonne, New Jersey, walked off the job in 1915. Virtually the entire Polish immigrant community supported them, and only police violence and hired thugs succeeded in breaking the strike. In this photograph, striking workers confront company guards outside the Standard Oil Works moments before the private police opened fire. Five strikers were killed by gunfire, but workers elected to strike again the next year.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nachdem sie lang niedrige Bezahlung, lange Stunden und 
gefährliche Arbeitsbedingungen angenommen hatten, gingen polnische 
Ölraffineriearbeiter in Bayonne, Neu-Jersey, weg vom Job 1915. 
Praktisch unterstützte die gesamte polnische einwandernde 
Gemeinschaft sie und nur Polizeigewalttätigkeit und stellte die 
Schurkeen an, die mit den, Schlag zu brechen gefolgt wurden. In 
dieser Fotographie konfrontieren auffallende Arbeiter Firmaschutz 
außerhalb der Standardöl-Arbeiten Momente vor dem private Polizei 
geöffneten Feuer. Fünf Schlaggeräte wurden vom 
Maschinengewehr, aber von den Arbeitern, die gewählt wurden, um das 
folgende Jahr wieder anzuschlagen beendet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Après avoir longtemps reçu le bas salaire, de longues 
heures, et conditions de travail dangereuses, les ouvriers polonais de
raffinerie de pétrole dans Bayonne, New Jersey, ont marché outre du 
travail en 1915. Pratiquement la communauté immigrée polonaise
entière a supporté eux, et seulement la violence de police et a 
loué des gangsters réussis à casser la grève. En cette 
photographie, les ouvriers saisissants confrontent des gardes de 
compagnie en dehors des travaux standard d'huile des moments avant le 
feu ouvert par police privée. Cinq butées ont été détruites
par le tir, mais les ouvriers choisis pour frapper encore l'année 
suivante.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Após por muito tempo ter aceitado o pagamento baixo, 
horas longas, e condições de funcionamento perigosas, os 
trabalhadores poloneses em Bayonne, Novo-Jersey da refinaria de óleo,
andaram fora do trabalho em 1915. Virtualmente a comunidade 
immigrant polonesa inteira suportou os, e somente a violência das 
polícias e empregou os thugs sucedidos em quebrar a batida. 
Nesta fotografia, os trabalhadores impressionantes confrontam 
protetores da companhia fora dos trabalhos padrão do óleo momentos 
antes polícias confidenciais do fogo aberto. Cinco grevistas 
foram matados pelo gunfire, mas pelos trabalhadores eleitos para 
golpear outra vez o ano seguinte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dopo lungamente avere accettato la paga bassa, ore lunghe 
e condizioni di lavoro pericolose, gli operai polacchi in Bayonne, 
Nuovo-Jersey della raffineria di petrolio, hanno camminato fuori del 
lavoro in 1915. Virtualmente l'intera Comunità immigrata 
polacca ha sostenuto loro e soltanto la violenza della polizia ed ha 
assunto i thugs riusciti a rompere il colpo. In questa 
fotografia, gli operai notevoli confrontano le protezioni dell'azienda
fuori degli impianti standard dell'olio momenti prima del fuoco aperto
polizia riservata. Cinque percussori sono stati uccisi da 
colpi di arma di fuoco, ma dagli operai scelti per colpire ancora l'anno 
successivo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μετά από πολύ να αποδεχθεί χαμηλή πληρώστε, πολλές 
ώρες, και επικίνδυνες συνθήκες εργασίας, πολωνικοί εργαζόμενοι 
εγκαταστάσεων καθαρισμού πετρελαίου σε Bayonne, Νιου Τζέρσεϋ, 
που περπατιέται από την εργασία σε 1915, Ουσιαστικά η 
ολόκληρη πολωνική που έχουν μεταναστεύσει κοινότητα υποστήριξε 
τους, και μόνο τη βία αστυνομίας και μίσθωσε τους κακοποιούς που 
πέτυχαν στο σπάσιμο της απεργίας. Σε αυτήν την φωτογραφία, 
οι απεργοί εργαζόμενοι αντιμετωπίζουν τις φρουρές επιχείρησης 
έξω από τις πρότυπες στιγμές εργοστασίων πετρελαίου προτού να 
ανοίξει η ιδιωτική αστυνομία την πυρκαγιά. Πέντε απεργοί 
σκοτώθηκαν από τον πυροβολισμό, αλλά οι εργαζόμενοι εξέλεξαν να 
χτυπήσουν πάλι το επόμενο έτος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Después de largo de validar paga baja, las largases 
horas, y las condiciones de trabajo peligrosas, los trabajadores 
polacos en Bayonne, Nuevo-Jersey de la refinería de petróleo, 
recorrieron del trabajo en 1915. La comunidad inmigrante polaca 
entera utilizó virtualmente los, y solamente violencia del policía y
empleó a gamberros tenidos éxito en romper la huelga. En esta 
fotografía, los trabajadores llamativos enfrentan a protectores de la
compañía fuera de los trabajos estándares del aceite los momentos 
antes del fuego abierto policía privado. Cinco huelguistas 
fueron matados por el fuego, pero los trabajadores elegidos para pulso
otra vez el año próximo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086376</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105505</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/just-before-the-firing-started</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
