<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108711</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108711</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087459</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Cal Noyce Describes Merging Union, Gay, and Lesbian Organizing</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Cal Noyce beschreibt, Anschluß, Homosexuelles und
das lesbische Organisieren zu mergen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Eao Noyce décrit fusionner l'union, le gay, et 
l'organisation lesbienne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Cal Noyce descreve fundir a união, o gay, e 
organizar lesbian</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La caloria Noyce descrive fondere l'unione, il 
Gay e l'organizzazione lesbica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η θερμ. Noyce περιγράφει τη συγχωνεύοντας ένωση, τον
ομοφυλόφιλο, και τη λεσβιακή οργάνωση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La caloría Noyce describe el combinar de la 
unión, del Gay, y de la ordenación lesbiana</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An officer of the Communications Workers of America Local 7704 in Salt Lake City and an out gay man, Cal Noyce began to raise issues of gay, lesbian, and bisexual equity within the union during the early 1990's. By forming an organization of gay trade unionists in Utah, as well as the national gay, lesbian, and bisexual group Pride at Work, Noyce joined a larger push to link the gay rights movement to the labor movement. Noyce and his associates won the support of Utah AFL-CIO president Ed Mayne, who, like many, recognized the organization as important way for organized labor to reach out to gay and lesbian communities and bring gay men and lesbians into the labor movement as motivated activists.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Offizier der Kommunikationen Arbeiter von 
Amerika Einheimischem 7704 in Salt Lake City und in einem 
homosexuellen Mann des Heraus, cal Noyce fing an, Ausgaben der 
homosexuellen, lesbischen und bisexual Billigkeit innerhalb des 
Anschlußes während der frühen neunziger Jahre anzuheben. 
Indem er eine Organisation der homosexuellen Gewerkschaftler in 
Utah, sowie das nationale Homosexuelle, den Lesbier und bisexual den 
Gruppe Stolz an der Arbeit bildete, verband Noyce einen größeren 
Stoß, um die Homosexuellrechtbewegung zur Arbeiterbewegung zu binden.
Noyce und seine Teilnehmer gewannen den Support Utah AFL-CIO des
Präsidenten ED Mayne, der, wie viele, die Organisation während 
wichtige Methode erkannte, damit organisierte Arbeit heraus zu den 
homosexuellen und lesbischen Gemeinschaften erreicht und homosexuelle 
Männer und Lesbier in die Arbeiterbewegung als motivierte Aktivisten 
holt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un officier des ouvriers de transmissions des gens
du pays 7704 de l'Amérique à Salt Lake City et un homme gai de 
sortie, Eao Noyce a commencé à soulever des questions des capitaux 
propres gais, lesbiens, et bisexuels dans l'union pendant le début 
des années 90. En formant une organisation des syndicalistes 
gais en Utah, aussi bien que le gay national, la lesbienne, et la 
fierté bisexuelle de groupe au travail, Noyce a joint une plus 
grande poussée pour joindre le mouvement de droits de gay au 
mouvement de travail. Noyce et ses associés ont gagné le 
support du Président ED Mayne de l'Utah AFL-CIO, qui, comme beaucoup,
a identifié l'organisation pendant que voie importante pour que le 
travail organisé atteigne dehors aux communautés gaies et lesbiennes
et d'introduit les hommes et les lesbiennes gais dans le mouvement de 
travail en tant qu'activistes motivés.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um oficial dos trabalhadores das comunicações do
local 7704 de América na cidade de lago salt e em um homem gay da 
saída, Cal Noyce começou a levantar introduções da equidade gay, 
lesbian, e bisexual dentro da união durante os 1990's adiantados. 
Dando forma a uma organização de unionists de comércio gay em
Utá, as.well.as o gay nacional, o lesbian, e o orgulho bisexual do 
grupo no trabalho, Noyce juntou um impulso maior para ligar o 
movimento das direitas do gay ao movimento labor. Noyce e seus 
associados ganharam a sustentação do presidente Ed Mayne de Utá 
AFL-CIO, que, como muitos, reconheceu a organização enquanto maneira
importante para que o trabalho organizado alcance para fora às 
comunidades gay e lesbian e traga homens e lesbians gay no movimento 
labor como activistas motivated.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un ufficiale degli operai di comunicazioni del 
local 7704 dell'America a Salt Lake City e un uomo di gay di 
out, la caloria Noyce ha cominciato a sollevare le emissioni del 
gay, della lesbica e dell'equità bisexual all'interno 
dell'unione durante l'inizio degli anni 90. Formando 
un'organizzazione dei sindacalisti di gay nell'Utah, così 
come il gay nazionale, la lesbica e l'orgoglio bisexual del 
gruppo sul lavoro, Noyce ha unito una più grande spinta per collegare
il movimento di diritti di gay al movimento di lavoro. 
Noyce ed i suoi soci hanno vinto il supporto del presidente Ed 
Mayne dell'Utah AFL-CIO, che, come molti, ha riconosciuto 
l'organizzazione come modo importante affinchè il lavoro 
organizzato raggiungesse fuori alle Comunità della lesbica e di 
gay ed introdurre gli uomini e le lesbiche di gay 
nel movimento di lavoro come attivisti motivati.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένας ανώτερος υπάλληλος των εργαζομένων επικοινωνιών 
της Αμερικής τοπικά 7704 στη Σωλτ Λέικ Σίτυ και ένα έξω 
ομοφυλοφιλικό άτομο, θερμ. Noyce άρχισε να προκύπτει τα 
ζητήματα του ομοφυλόφιλου, της λεσβίας, και της αμφίφυλης 
δικαιοσύνης εντός της ένωσης κατά τη διάρκεια της πρόωρης 
δεκαετίας του '90. Από τη διαμόρφωση μιας οργάνωσης των 
ομοφυλοφιλικών συνδικαλιστών στο Utah, καθώς επίσης και τον 
εθνικό ομοφυλόφιλο, τη λεσβία, και την αμφίφυλη υπερηφάνεια 
ομάδας στην εργασία, Noyce ένωσε μια μεγαλύτερη ώθηση να 
συνδεθεί η ομοφυλοφιλική μετακίνηση δικαιωμάτων με τη μετακίνηση 
εργασίας. Το Noyce και οι συνεταίροι του κέρδισαν την 
υποστήριξη του Utah αφλ- CIO Πρόεδρος ΕΔ Mayne, ο οποίος, 
όπως πολλούς, αναγνώρισε την οργάνωση ως σημαντικό τρόπο για την
οργανωμένη εργασία να φτάσει στις ομοφυλοφιλικές και λεσβιακές 
κοινότητες και να φέρει τα ομοφυλοφιλικές άτομα και τις λεσβίες 
στη μετακίνηση εργασίας ως παρακινημένα ενεργά στελέχη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un oficial de los trabajadores de las 
comunicaciones del local 7704 de América en la ciudad de lago salt y 
un hombre gay de la salida, caloría Noyce comenzó a plantear 
aplicaciones el gay, la lesbiana, y la equidad bisexual dentro 
de la unión durante los años 90 tempranos. Formando una 
organización de unionistas comerciales gays en Utah, así 
como el gay nacional, la lesbiana, y el orgullo bisexual del 
grupo en el trabajo, Noyce ensambló un empuje más grande para 
conectar el movimiento de las derechas del gay al movimiento de
trabajo. Noyce y sus asociados ganaron la ayuda del presidente 
Ed Mayne de Utah AFL-CIO, que, como muchos, reconoció la 
organización mientras que manera importante para que el trabajo 
ordenado alcance hacia fuera a las comunidades gays y 
lesbianas y traiga hombres gays y a lesbianas en el movimiento
de trabajo como activistas motivados.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087459</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108711</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/cal-noyce-describes-merging-union-gay-and-lesbian-organizing</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
