<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108804</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108804</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206748</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Vote: The Machinery of Democracy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Stimme: Die Maschinerie der Demokratie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Voix : Les machines de la démocratie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Voto: A maquinaria da democracia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Voto: Il macchinario della democrazia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ψηφοφορία: Τα μηχανήματα της δημοκρατίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Voto: La maquinaria de la democracia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">looks at the history and variety of voting methods in the U.S. -- the voice vote, party ticket (paper ballots listing candidates from just one party), Australian ballot, gear and lever machine, and others. Voting reforms of the early 1900s, when the U.S. electorate doubled, are described. Kinds of voting equipment used in counties across the U.S. are shown on a map. Innovative design improvements are discussed.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Blicke auf die Geschichte und die Vielzahl der 
wählenden Methoden in den US. -- die Sprachstimme, die 
Parteikarte (Papierstimmzettel, die Anwärter von gerade einer 
Partei ausdrucken), australische der Stimmzettel, das Zahnrad 
und die Hebelmaschine und die anderen. Wählende Verbesserungen 
der frühen 1900s, wenn die geverdoppelten VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Wählerschaften, werden beschrieben. Die Arten der wählenden 
Ausrüstung verwendet in den Grafschaften über den VEREINIGTEN 
STAATEN werden auf einer Karte gezeigt. Erfinderische 
Designverbesserungen werden behandelt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">regards à l'histoire et à la variété de 
méthodes de vote aux États-Unis. -- la voix de voix, le billet
de partie (votes de papier énumérant des candidats de juste une 
partie), le vote, la vitesse et la machine de levier, et les autres 
australiens. Des réformes de vote des années 1900 tôt, quand 
l'électorat des ETATS-UNIS doublé, sont décrites. Des genres 
de matériel de vote utilisés dans les comtés à travers les 
ETATS-UNIS sont montrés sur une carte. Des améliorations 
innovatrices de conception sont discutées.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">olhares no history e na variedade de métodos 
votando nos E. U.. -- o voto da voz, o bilhete do partido 
(cédulas de papel que alistam candidatos de apenas um partido), a 
cédula, a engrenagem e a máquina da alavanca, e a outra australian. 
As reformas votando dos 1900s adiantados, quando o eleitorado de
ESTADOS UNIDOS dobrado, forem descritas. Os tipos do equipamento
votando usados nos condados através dos ESTADOS UNIDOS são mostrados
em um mapa. As melhorias inovativas do projeto são discutidas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">sguardi alla storia ed alla varietà di metodi di 
voto negli Stati Uniti. -- il voto di voce, il biglietto del 
partito (schede elettorali di carta che elencano i candidati da appena
un partito), la scheda elettorale, l'ingranaggio e la macchina della 
leva e le altre australiani. Le riforme di voto dei 1900s in 
anticipo, quando l'elettorato degli STATI UNITI raddoppiato, sono 
descritte. I generi di apparecchiatura di voto usati in contee 
attraverso gli STATI UNITI sono indicati su un programma. I 
miglioramenti innovatori di disegno sono discussi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει την ιστορία και την ποικιλία της ψηφοφορίας 
των μεθόδων στις ΗΠΑ -- η ψηφοφορία φωνής, το εισιτήριο 
συμβαλλόμενων μερών (υποψήφιοι λιστών ψήφων εγγράφου από μόνο 
ένα συμβαλλόμενο μέρος), η αυστραλιανή ψήφος, η μηχανή 
εργαλείων και μοχλών, και άλλα. Οι μεταρρυθμίσεις 
ψηφοφορίας των πρόωρων δεκαετιών του 20ου αιώνα, όταν 
διπλασιάστηκε το ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ εκλογικό σώμα, περιγράφονται. 
Τα είδη ψηφοφορίας του εξοπλισμού που χρησιμοποιούνται στους
νομούς στις ΗΠΑ εμφανίζονται σε έναν χάρτη. Οι καινοτόμες 
βελτιώσεις σχεδίου συζητούνται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">miradas en la historia y la variedad de métodos 
de votación en los E.E.U.U.. -- el voto de la voz, el boleto 
del partido (balotas de papel que enumeran a candidatos de apenas un 
partido), la balota, el engranaje y la máquina de la palanca, y las 
otras australianos. Las reformas de votación de los 1900s 
tempranos, cuando el electorado de ESTADOS UNIDOS doblado, se 
describen. Las clases de equipo de votación usadas en condados 
a través de los ESTADOS UNIDOS se muestran en una correspondencia. 
Se discuten las mejoras innovadoras del diseño.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206748</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108804</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/vote-the-machinery-of-democracy</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
