<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104565</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104565</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204179</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Automatic Door Opener</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Automatischer Tür-Öffner</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ouvreur Automatique de Porte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Opener Automático Da Porta</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Apri Automatico Del Portello</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτόματο ανοιχτήρι πορτών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Abrelatas Automático De la Puerta</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The engineering design process involves many steps. Not only must an engineer be able to devise a solution to a problem, he or she must also be ready to test and evaluate that solution to reach the best result. To successfully complete the design process, an engineer must be able to identify design flaws and learn from his or her mistakes. In this video segment adapted from ZOOM, learn about the design process as cast members create automatic door openers that enable them to open their bedroom doors while lying on their beds. For grades 3-8.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Technikdesignprozeß bezieht viele Jobsteps 
mit ein. Muß ein Ingenieur nicht nur können, eine Lösung zu 
einem Problem zu planen, müssen er oder sie betriebsbereit auch sein,
diese Lösung zu prüfen und auszuwerten, um das beste Resultat zu 
erreichen. Um den Designprozeß erfolgreich durchzuführen, muß
ein Ingenieur können Konstruktionsfehler zu kennzeichnen und von 
seinen oder Fehlern zu erlernen. In diesem Bildschirm paßte 
sich Segment vom ZOOM, erlernen über den Designprozeß an, wie 
geworfene Bauteile automatische Türöffner herstellen, die sie 
aktivieren, ihre Schlafzimmertüren beim Lügen zu öffnen auf ihren 
Betten. Für Grade 3-8.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le processus de conception d'ingénierie implique 
beaucoup d'étapes. Non seulement doit un ingénieur pouvoir 
concevoir une solution à un problème, lui ou elle doit également 
être prête à tester et évaluer cette solution pour atteindre le 
meilleur résultat. Pour compléter avec succès le processus de
conception, un ingénieur doit pouvoir identifier des imperfections de
conception et apprendre de ses erreurs. Dans ce vidéo le 
segment s'est adapté du ZOOM, se renseignent sur le processus de 
conception comme les membres moulés créent les ouvreurs automatiques
de porte qui leur permettent d'ouvrir leurs portes de chambre à 
coucher tout en se trouvant sur leurs lits. Pour des catégories
3-8.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O processo do projeto da engenharia envolve muitas
etapas. Não somente deve um coordenador poder  planejar uma 
solução a um problema, ou devem também estar pronto para testar e 
avaliar essa solução para alcançar o mais melhor resultado. 
Para terminar com sucesso o processo do projeto, um coordenador 
deve poder  identificar falhas de projeto e aprendê-las do seu ou 
dela erros. Neste vídeo o segmento adaptou-se do ZOOM, aprende 
sobre o processo do projeto como os membros moldados críam os openers
automáticos da porta que os permitem de abrir suas portas do bedroom 
ao se encontrar em suas camas. Para classes 3-8.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il processo di disegno di ingegneria coinvolge 
molti punti. Non soltanto deve un assistente tecnico potere 
inventare una soluzione ad un problema, lui o lei deve anche essere 
aspetta per verificare e valutare quella soluzione per 
raggiungere il risultato migliore. Realizzare con successo il 
processo di disegno, un assistente tecnico deve potere identificare i 
difetti di disegno ed imparare dai suoi errori. In questo video 
segmento si è adattato dallo ZOOM, impara circa il processo di 
disegno come i membri fusi creano gli apri automatici del portello che
permettono loro di aprire i loro portelli della camera da letto mentre
si trovano sulle loro basi. Per i gradi 3-8.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η διαδικασία σχεδίου εφαρμοσμένης μηχανικής 
περιλαμβάνει πολλά βήματα. Όχι μόνο πρέπει ένας 
μηχανικός να είναι σε θέση να επινοήσει μια λύση σε ένα 
πρόβλημα, πρέπει επίσης να είναι αναμένει για να εξετάσει 
και να αξιολογήσει ότι λύση για να φθάσει στο καλύτερο 
αποτέλεσμα. Για να ολοκληρώνει επιτυχώς τη διαδικασία 
σχεδίου, ένας μηχανικός πρέπει να είναι ικανός να προσδιορίσει 
τις ρωγμές σχεδίου και να μάθει από τα λάθη του ή της. Σε 
αυτό το τηλεοπτικό τμήμα μνήμης που προσαρμόζεται από το ΖΟΥΜ, 
μάθετε για τη διαδικασία σχεδίου όπως τα χυτά μέλη δημιουργούν 
τα αυτόματα ανοιχτήρια πορτών που επιτρέπουν σε τους για να 
ανοίξουν τις πόρτες κρεβατοκάμαρών τους στα κρεβάτια τους. 
Για τους βαθμούς 3-8.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El proceso del diseño de la ingeniería implica 
muchos pasos de progresión. No solamente debe un ingeniero 
poder idear una solución a un problema, él o ella debe también ser 
lista probar y evaluar esa solución para alcanzar el mejor resultado.
Terminar con éxito el proceso del diseño, un ingeniero debe 
poder identificar defectos de diseño y aprender de su o de ella los 
errores. En este vídeo el segmento se adaptó de ZOOM, aprende 
sobre el proceso del diseño como los miembros echados crean los 
abrelatas automáticos de la puerta que les permiten abrir sus puertas
del dormitorio mientras que mienten en sus camas. Para los 
grados 3-8.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204179</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104565</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/automatic-door-opener</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
