<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107270</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107270</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207251</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The American Presidency: A Glorious Burden</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Amerikanische Vorsitz: Eine Prachtvolle 
Belastung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Présidence Américaine : Un Fardeau 
Glorieux</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Presidency Americano: Um Burden Glorious</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Presidenza Americana: Una Difficoltà 
Glorious</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η αμερικανική προεδρία: Ένα λαμπρό φορτίο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Presidencia Americana: Una Carga 
Gloriosa</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">examines the job of a president, the balance of power with the Supreme Court and Congress, and ways presidents have communicated with the public. Features include the battle sword of George Washington, the lap desk on which Thomas Jefferson wrote the Declaration of Independence, and the top hat worn by Abraham Lincoln the night he was assassinated.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">überprüft den Job eines Präsidenten, die 
Balance der Energie mit dem Höchsten Gericht und Kongreß, und 
Methoden Präsidenten haben mit der Öffentlichkeit geverständigt. 
Merkmale enthalten die Schlachtklinge von George Washington, auf
dem der Schoßschreibtisch Thomas Jefferson die 
Unabhängigkeitserklärung schrieb, und den oberen Hut, der von 
Abraham Lincoln die Nacht getragen wird, die er ermordet wurde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">examine le travail d'un président, l'equilibre 
des forces avec la cour suprême et le congrès, et les présidents de
voies ont communiqué avec le public. Les dispositifs incluent 
l'épée de bataille de George Washington, le bureau de 
recouvrement sur lequel Thomas Jefferson a écrit la déclaration de 
l'indépendance, et le chapeau supérieur porté par Abraham Lincoln 
la nuit où il a été assassiné.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">examina o trabalho de um presidente, o contrapeso 
de potência com a corte suprema e o congress, e os presidentes das 
maneiras comunicaram-se com o público. As características 
incluem a espada da batalha de George Washington, a mesa do regaço em
que Thomas Jefferson escreveu a declaração de independência, e o 
chapéu superior desgastado por Abraham Lincoln a noite onde 
assassinated.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esamina il lavoro di un presidente, l'equilibrio 
di forze con la Corte suprema ed il congresso ed i presidenti di modi 
hanno comunicato con il pubblico. Le caratteristiche includono 
la spada di battaglia di George Washington, lo scrittorio del giro su 
che Thomas Jefferson ha scritto la dichiarazione di indipendenza ed il
cappello superiore portato da Abraham Lincoln la notte che è stato 
assassinato.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει την εργασία ενός Προέδρου, η ισορροπία της 
δύναμης με το ανώτατο δικαστήριο και το συνέδριο, και οι Πρόεδροι
τρόπων έχουν επικοινωνήσει με το κοινό. Τα χαρακτηριστικά 
γνωρίσματα περιλαμβάνουν το ξίφος μάχης George Ουάσιγκτον, το 
γραφείο περιτυλίξεων στο οποίο ο Thomas Jefferson έγραψε τη 
Διακήρυξη της ανεξαρτησίας, και το κορυφαίο καπέλο που φορέθηκε 
από τον Abraham Λίνκολν η νύχτα δολοφονήθηκε.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">examina al trabajo de un presidente, al equilibrio
de la potencia con el Tribunal Supremo y a congreso, y los presidentes
de las maneras se han comunicado con el público. Las 
características incluyen la espada de la batalla de George 
Washington, el escritorio del regazo en que Thomas Jefferson escribió
el declaración de la independencia, y el sombrero superior desgastado
por Abraham Lincoln la noche que lo asesinaron.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207251</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107270</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-american-presidency-a-glorious-burden</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
