<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105232</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105232</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086371</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Journalists Pay Homage to Babe Ruth and the House That He Built</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Journalist-Bezahlung Ehrerbietung zum Baby Ruth 
und zum Haus, die er aufbaute</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Hommage de salaire de journalistes au bébé 
Ruth et à la Chambre qu'il a construits</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Homage do pagamento dos journalists ao babe Ruth e
à casa que construiu</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Omaggio di paga dei giornalisti al babe Ruth ed 
alla Camera che ha costruito</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι δημοσιογράφοι πληρώνουν το σεβασμό σε Babe 
Ruth και το σπίτι που έχτισε</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Homenaje de la paga de los periodistas al bebé 
Ruth y a la casa a que él construyó</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Baseball's growing popularity in the 1920s can be measured by structural and cultural changes that helped transform the game, including the building of commodious new ballparks; the emergence of sports pages in daily urban newspapers; and the enormous popularity of radio broadcasts of baseball games. But baseball's grip on the American popular imagination also was fueled by the emergence in the 1920s of the game's most dominant player, George Herman "Babe" Ruth. Ruth's rise to stardom in these years was an essential part of an era when celebrities came to dominate the various forms of American popular culture: sports, especially baseball; radio; and the movies. In these short articles that appeared in the  Literary Digest  in 1921 and 1923, two baseball writers described the importance of the Ruthian home run and the majesty of Yankee Stadium, the new temple that Yankee management built in 1923 to accommodate the Babe.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wachsende Popularität des Baseballs in den 
zwanziger Jahren kann durch die strukturellen und kulturellen 
Änderungen, die das halfen, Spiel umzuwandeln, einschließlich das 
Gebäude der commodious neuen Baseballstadion gemessen werden; 
das Hervortreten der Sportseiten in den täglichen städtischen 
Zeitungen; und die enorme Popularität der Radiosendungen der 
Baseballspiele. Aber Griff des Baseballs auf der amerikanischen 
populären Phantasie auch wurde durch das Hervortreten in den 
zwanziger Jahren des dominierendsten Spielers des Spiels, George 
Herman "Baby" Ruth getankt. Anstieg Ruths zum stardom in diesen 
Jahren war ein wesentliches Teil einer Ära, als Berühmtheiten kamen,
die verschiedenen Formulare der amerikanischen populären Kultur zu 
beherrschen: Sport, besonders Baseball; Radio; und 
die Filme. In diesen kurzen Artikeln, die in der literarischen 
Auswahl 1921 und 1923 erschienen, beschrieben zwei Baseballverfasser 
den Wert des Ruthian Ausgangsdurchlaufes und der Majestät von Yankee 
Stadium, der neue Bügel, dem Yankee Management 1923 aufbaute, um das 
Baby anzupassen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La popularité croissante du base-ball dans les 
années 20 peut être mesurée par les changements structuraux et 
culturels qui ont aidé à transformer le jeu, y compris le bâtiment 
de nouveaux ballparks spacieux ; l'apparition des pages de 
sports en journaux urbains quotidiens ; et l'énorme popularité
des émissions par radio des jeux de base-ball. Mais la poignée
du base-ball sur l'imagination populaire américaine également a 
été remplie de combustible par l'apparition dans les années 20 du 
joueur le plus dominant du jeu, George Herman "bébé" Ruth.
L'élévation de Ruth au stardom en ces années était une
partie essentielle d'une ère où les célébrités sont venues pour 
dominer les diverses formes de la culture populaire américaine : 
sports, particulièrement base-ball ; radio ; et les
films. En ces articles courts qui sont parus dans le sommaire 
littéraire en 1921 et 1923, deux auteurs de base-ball ont décrit 
l'importance du passage de maison de Ruthian et de la majesté du 
stade de Yankee, le nouveau temple que la gestion de Yankee a 
construit en 1923 pour faciliter le bébé.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A popularidade crescente do baseball nos 1920s 
pode ser medida pelas mudanças estruturais e cultural que ajudaram 
transformar o jogo, including o edifício de ballparks novos 
commodious; o emergence de páginas dos esportes em jornais 
urbanos diários; e a popularidade enorme das transmissões de 
rádio de jogos do baseball. Mas o aperto do baseball na 
imaginação popular americana foi abastecido também pelo emergence 
nos 1920s do jogador o mais dominante do jogo, George Herman "babe" 
Ruth. A ascensão de Ruth ao stardom nestes anos era uma parte 
essencial de uma era em que as celebridades viessem dominar os vários
formulários da cultura popular americana: esportes, especial 
baseball; rádio; e os filmes. Nestes artigos curtos
que se publicaram no sumário literário em 1921 e em 1923, dois 
escritores do baseball descreveram a importância do funcionamento da 
HOME de Ruthian e do majesty do stadium de Yankee, o temple novo que a
gerência de Yankee construiu em 1923 para acomodar o babe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La popolarità crescente del baseball negli anni 
20 può essere misurata dai cambiamenti strutturali e culturali che 
hanno contribuito a trasformare il gioco, compreso la costruzione di 
nuovi ballparks commodious; l'emersione delle pagine di sport in
giornali urbani quotidiani; e popolarità enorme delle 
radiodiffusioni radiofoniche dei giochi di baseball. Ma la presa
del baseball sull'immaginazione popolare americana egualmente è stata
rifornita tramite l'emersione negli anni 20 del giocatore più 
dominante del gioco, George Herman "il babe" Ruth. L'aumento del
Ruth allo stardom durante questi anni era una parte essenziale di 
un'era in cui i celebrities sono venuto dominare le varie forme di 
coltura popolare americana: sport, particolarmente baseball; 
radio; ed i film. In questi articoli corti 
che sono stato publicati nella raccolta letteraria in 1921 ed in 1923,
due produttori di baseball hanno descritto l'importanza del 
funzionamento della sede di Ruthian e del majesty dello stadio di 
Yankee, il nuovo tempiale che la gestione di Yankee ha costruito in 
1923 per accomodare il babe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η αυξανόμενη δημοτικότητα του μπέιζ-μπώλ στη δεκαετία
του '20 μπορεί να μετρηθεί από τις δομικές και πολιτιστικές 
αλλαγές που βοήθησαν να μετασχηματίσουν το παιχνίδι, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένης της οικοδόμησης των ευρύχωρων νέων 
εξεδρών  η εμφάνιση των αθλητικών σελίδων στις 
καθημερινές αστικές εφημερίδες  και η τεράστια δημοτικότητα
των ραδιο ραδιοφωνικών μεταδόσεων των παιχνιδιών μπέιζ-μπώλ. 
Αλλά το πιάσιμο του μπέιζ-μπώλ στην αμερικανική δημοφιλή 
φαντασία επίσης τροφοδοτήθηκε από την εμφάνιση στη δεκαετία του 
'20 του πιό κυρίαρχου παίκτη του παιχνιδιού, George Herman 
"Babe" Ruth. Η άνοδος της Ruth στο stardom σε αυτά
τα έτη ήταν ένα ουσιαστικό μέρος μιας εποχής όταν ήρθαν να 
εξουσιάσουν οι προσωπικότητες τις διάφορες μορφές του 
αμερικανικού δημοφιλούς πολιτισμού: αθλητισμός, ειδικά 
μπέιζ-μπώλ  ραδιόφωνο  και οι κινηματογράφοι. Σε
αυτά τα σύντομα άρθρα που εμφανίστηκαν στη λογοτεχνική αφομοίωση
το 1921 και το 1923, δύο συγγραφείς μπέιζ-μπώλ περιέγραψαν 
τη σημασία του βασικού Ruthian τρεξίματος και της μεγαλειότητας
του σταδίου Αμερικανού, ο νέος ναός ότι η διαχείριση Αμερικανού
ενσωμάτωσε το 1923 για να προσαρμόσει το Babe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El renombre cada vez mayor del béisbol en los 
años 20 se puede medir por los cambios estructurales y culturales que
ayudaron a transformar el juego, incluyendo el edificio de estadios de béisbol
nuevos commodious; la aparición de las paginaciones de los 
deportes en periódicos urbanos diarios; y el renombre enorme de
las difusiones de radio de los juegos del béisbol. Pero el 
apretón del béisbol en la imaginación popular americana también 
fue aprovisionado de combustible por la aparición en los años 20 del
jugador más dominante del juego, George Herman "bebé" Ruth. La
subida de Ruth al stardom en estos años era una parte esencial de una
era en que las celebridades vinieron dominar las varias formas de 
cultura popular americana: deportes, especialmente béisbol; 
radio; y las películas. En estos artículos cortos 
que aparecieron en el resumen literario en 1921 y 1923, dos programas 
de escritura del béisbol describieron la importancia del 
funcionamiento y de la majestad del estadio de Yankee, el templo nuevo
del hogar de Ruthian que la gerencia de Yankee construyó en 1923 para
acomodar al bebé.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086371</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105232</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/journalists-pay-homage-to-babe-ruth-and-the-house-that-he-built</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
