<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106244</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106244</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086811</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Separate But Equal: The  Plessy  v. &lt;/&gt;Ferguson  Case</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Trennen Sie sich, Aber Entsprechen Sie: 
Plessy V. &lt;/&gt; Ferguson Fall</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Séparez Mais Égalez : &lt; de Plessy v./&gt; cas 
de Ferguson</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Separe Mas Iguale: &lt; de Plessy v./&gt; caso de 
Ferguson</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Separi Ma Sia uguale: &lt;/&gt; di Plessy v. caso 
di Ferguson</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Χωριστός αλλά ίσος: Plessy V. &lt;/&gt; 
περίπτωση Ferguson</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sepárese Pero Iguale: &lt;/&gt; de Plessy v. caso 
de Ferguson</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1887, Florida passed the first law requiring railways to provide "equal but separate accommodations for the white, and colored, races," and Mississippi, Texas, and other states soon followed suit. When Louisiana passed such a law in 1890, African Americans in New Orleans resisted in several ways, including mounting a legal challenge to it. In 1892 they arranged for Homer Adolph Plessy (who was one-eighth black and could have readily "passed" for white) to be arrested on an East Louisiana Railway train for refusing to move to the car designated for "colored passengers." The case eventually reached the U.S. Supreme Court in 1896 as  Plessy v. Ferguson  (named for the New Orleans Criminal District Court Judge who first ruled against Plessy). The  Plessy  decision, excerpted below, was written by Justice Henry Billings Brown. Brown argued that as long as racially separate facilities were equal they did not violate the Fourteenth Amendment's guarantees of equal protection of the law. All of the justices but one (John Marshall Hylan) agreed with Brown's arguments. The  Plessy  ruling provided legal justification for segregation in transportation, public accommodations, and schools until the Supreme Court effectively overruled it in the 1954  Brown v. Board of Education  decision.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1887 verabschiedete Florida das erste Gesetz, das 
Gleise benötigt, "Gleichgestelltes aber unterschiedliche Anpassungen 
zur Verfügung zu stellen für das Weiß und färbte, Rennen," und 
Mississippi, Texas und andere gefolgte Klage der Zustände bald. 
Als Louisiana solch ein Gesetz 1890 verabschiedete, widerstanden
afrikanische Amerikaner in New-Orleans in einigen Methoden, 
einschließlich die Montierung einer zugelassenen Herausforderung zu 
ihr. In 1892 ordneten sie für Homer Adolph auf einer 
Ostlouisiana Bahnserie festgehalten zu werden Plessy (wer one-eighth 
Schwarzes war und "betriebsbereit überschritten haben könnte" zum 
Weiß), damit das Ablehnen auf das Auto bewegt, das gekennzeichnet 
wird für "farbige Passagiere." Der Fall erreichte schließlich 
das VEREINIGTE STAATEN Höchste Gericht in 1896 als Plessy V. Ferguson
(benannt für den New-Orleans kriminellen Amtsgericht-Richter, der 
zuerst gegen Plessy anordnete). Die Plessy Entscheidung, unten 
excerptiert, wurde durch Justice Henry Gebührenzählungen Braun 
geschrieben. Braun argumentierte, daß solange rassisch 
unterschiedliche Teildienste Gleichgestelltes waren, das sie nicht die
Garantien der vierzehnten Änderung des gleichen Schutzes des Gesetzes
verletzten. Die ganze von aber von eine (John Marschall Hylan) 
stimmten mit Argumenten des Brauns überein. Das Plessy Anordnen
stellte zugelassene Rechtfertigung für Abtrennung im Transport, in 
den allgemeinen Anpassungen und in den Schulen zur Verfügung, bis das
Höchste Gericht ihn effektiv im braunen v. 1954 Brett der Ausbildung 
Entscheidung überlagerte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1887, la Floride a passé la première loi 
exigeant des chemins de fer de fournir l'"égale mais le logement 
séparé pour le blanc, et l'a coloré, les courses," et le 
Mississippi, le Texas, et tout autre mouvement bientôt suivi 
d'états. Quand la Louisiane a passé une telle loi en 1890, les
Américains africains à la Nouvelle-Orléans ont résisté de 
plusieurs voies, y compris monter un défi légal à lui. Dans 
1892 ils ont assuré Homer Adolph Plessy (qui était un huitième 
noirs et pourrait aisément "avoir passé" pour le blanc) à arrêter 
sur un train ferroviaire est de la Louisiane pour que refuser se 
déplace à la voiture indiquée pour "les passagers colorés." 
Le cas a par la suite atteint la cour suprême des ETATS-UNIS 
dans 1896 comme Plessy v. Ferguson (nommé pour le juge criminel de 
cour de zone de la Nouvelle-Orléans qui a régné la première fois 
contre Plessy). La décision de Plessy, extraite ci-dessous, a 
été écrite par brun de facturations de Justice Henry. Le brun
a argué du fait qu'aussi longtemps que les équipements racial 
séparés étaient l'égale qu'ils n'ont pas violé les garanties de 
quatorzième amendement de la protection égale de la loi. Tous 
les justices mais une (maréchal Hylan de John) étaient conformes aux
arguments du brun. Régner de Plessy a fourni la justification 
légale pour la ségrégation dans le transport, le logement public, 
et les écoles jusqu'à ce que la cour suprême l'ait pertinemment 
outrepassé dans le conseil brun de v. 1954 de la décision 
d'éducation.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1887, Florida passou a primeira lei que requer 
estradas de ferro fornecer o "igual mas acomodações separadas para o
branco, e coloriu-a, raças," e Mississippi, Texas, e o outro terno 
logo seguido dos estados. Quando Louisiana passou tal lei em 
1890, os americanos africanos em Nova Orleães resistiram em diversas 
maneiras, including a montagem de um desafio legal a ele. Em 
1892 arranjaram para Homer Adolph Plessy (quem era one-eighth pretos e
podia prontamente "ter passado" para o branco) a ser prendido em um 
trem railway do leste de Louisiana para que recusar mova-se para o 
carro designado para "passageiros coloridos." O caso alcançou 
eventualmente a corte suprema de ESTADOS UNIDOS em 1896 como Plessy v.
Ferguson (nomeado para o juiz criminal da corte de distrito de Nova 
Orleães que governou primeiramente de encontro a Plessy). A 
decisão de Plessy, excerpted abaixo, foi escrita pelo marrom dos 
faturamentos de Justiça Henry. O marrom discutiu que tão por 
muito tempo quanto facilidades racial separadas era o igual que não 
violate as garantias de décima quarta emenda da proteção igual da 
lei. Toda a justiças mas uma (marshall Hylan de John) concordou
com os argumentos do marrom. Governar de Plessy forneceu a 
justificação legal para o segregation no transporte, em 
acomodações públicas, e em escolas até que a corte suprema 
overruled eficazmente o na placa marrom do v. 1954 da decisão da 
instrução.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1887, Florida ha approvato la prima legge che 
richiede le ferrovie fornire "il uguale ma le sistemazioni separate 
per il bianco ed ha colorato, corse," ed il Mississippi, il Texas ed 
altro dichiara il vestito presto seguito. Quando la 
Luisiana ha approvato una tal legge in 1890, gli Americani africani a 
New Orleans hanno resistito a in parecchi modi, compreso il montaggio 
della contestazione ad esso. In 1892 hanno assicurato Homer 
Adolph Plessy (chi era one-eighth neri e potrebbe "passare 
prontamente" per il bianco) da arrestare su un treno ferroviario 
orientale della Luisiana affinchè rifiutare si muovano verso 
l'automobile indicato per "i passeggeri colorati." Il caso 
finalmente ha raggiunto la Corte suprema degli STATI UNITI in 1896 
come Plessy v. Ferguson (chiamato per il giudice criminale della corte
del distretto de New Orleans che in primo luogo ha regolato contro 
Plessy). La decisione di Plessy, stralciata sotto, è stata 
scritta da colore marrone di fatturazioni della Justice Henry. 
Il colore marrone ha sostenuto che finchè le attrezzature 
razziale separate era il uguale che non hanno violato le garanzie 
della fourteenth correzione di protezione uguale della legge. 
Tutto il giustizie ma una (marshall Hylan del John) ha 
accosentito con gli argomenti del colore marrone. Il 
regolamento di Plessy ha fornito la giustificazione legale per la 
segregazione nel trasporto, nelle sistemazioni pubbliche ed in scuole 
fino a che la Corte suprema non lo oltrepassasse efficacemente nel 
Bordo marrone del v. 1954 della decisione di formazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1887, η Φλώριδα πέρασε τον πρώτο νόμο που 
απαιτεί τους σιδηροδρόμους για να παρέχει τις "ίσες αλλά 
χωριστές στεγάσεις για το λευκό, και χρωμάτισε, φυλές," και 
Μισισιπής, Τέξας, και άλλο κρατικό σύντομα ακολουθούμενο 
κοστούμι. Όταν η Λουιζιάνα πέρασε έναν τέτοιο νόμο το 
1890, αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί στη Νέα Ορλεάνη αντιστάθηκαν με 
διάφορους τρόπους, συμπεριλαμβανομένης της επικόλλησης μιας 
νομικής πρόκλησης σε τον. Το 1892 τακτοποίησαν για Όμηρο 
Adolph Plessy (που ήταν ένας-όγδοος μαύρος και θα μπορούσε 
εύκολα "να έχει περάσει" για το λευκό) που συλλαμβάνεται σε ένα 
τραίνο σιδηροδρόμων της ανατολικής Λουιζιάνας για την άρνηση να 
κινηθούν προς το αυτοκίνητο που υποδείχθηκε για τους "έγχρωμους 
επιβάτες." Η υπόθεση έφθασε τελικά στο ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ ανώτατο 
δικαστήριο το 1896 ως Plessy V. Ferguson (που ονομάζεται
για τον εγκληματικό δικαστή περιφερειακού δικαστηρίου της Νέας 
Ορλεάνης που κυβέρνησε αρχικά ενάντια σε Plessy). Η 
απόφαση Plessy, κατωτέρω, γράφτηκε από τη δικαιοσύνη Henry 
Billings καφετί. Καφετής που υποστηρίζεται ότι εφ' όσον 
racially οι χωριστές εγκαταστάσεις ήταν ίσες δεν παραβίασαν 
τις εγγυήσεις της δέκατης τέταρτης τροποποίησης της ίσης 
προστασίας του νόμου. Όλα τα justices αλλά το ένα 
(John Marshall Hylan) συμφώνησαν με τα καφέ ορίσματα. 
Το Plessy που κυβερνά την παρεχόμενη νομική στοίχιση για 
το διαχωρισμό στη μεταφορά, τις δημόσιες στεγάσεις, και τα 
σχολεία μέχρι το ανώτατο δικαστήριο τον ξεπέρασε αποτελεσματικά 
το 1954 Brown V. Board της απόφασης εκπαίδευσης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1887, la Florida aprobó la primera ley que 
requería ferrocarriles proporcionar al "igual pero las comodidades 
separadas para el blanco, y la coloreó, las razas," y el Mississippi,
el Tejas, y el otro juego pronto seguido de los estados. Cuando 
Luisiana aprobó tal ley en 1890, los americanos africanos en New 
Orleans se opusieron de varias maneras, incluyendo montar un desafío 
legal a él. En 1892 arreglaron para Homer Adolph Plessy (quién
era one-eighth negros y habría podido "pasar fácilmente" para el 
blanco) que se arrestará en un tren ferroviario del este de Luisiana 
para que el rechazo se traslade al coche señalado para los "pasajeros
coloreados." El caso alcanzó eventual el Tribunal Supremo de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS en 1896 como Plessy v. Ferguson (nombrado para el juez 
criminal de la corte de districto de New Orleans que primero gobernó 
contra Plessy). La decisión de Plessy, extractada abajo, fue 
escrita por marrón de las facturas de Justice Henry. El marrón
discutió que como recursos racial separados estuviera tan de largo el
igual que no violaron las garantías de la catorcena enmienda de la 
protección igual de la ley. Todo el justicias pero una (ordenar
Hylan de Juan) convino con los argumentos del marrón. La 
decisión de Plessy proporcionó a la alineación legal para la 
segregación en el transporte, comodidades públicas, y escuelas hasta
que el Tribunal Supremo lo invalidó con eficacia en la tarjeta 
marrón del v. 1954 de la decisión de la educación.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086811</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106244</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/separate-but-equal-the-plessy-v-ferguson-case</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
