<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106214</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106214</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087397</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Anacostia flats and flames.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Anacostia Ebenen und Flammen.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Appartements et flammes d'Anacostia.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Planos e flamas de Anacostia.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Appartamenti e fiamme di Anacostia.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επίπεδα και φλόγες Anacostia.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Planos y llamas de Anacostia.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Bonus March was one of several grassroots movements of the unemployed during the Great Depression that galvanized thousands of men and women and helped focus attention on the role of the federal government in alleviating economic hardship. Twenty thousand World War I veterans marched to Washington to demand the immediate release of promised cash bonuses and set up camp until their demands were met. With President Herbert Hoover's authorization, federal troops, armed with tanks and cavalry, attacked the homeless veterans and burned their encampment. When images like this photograph, which shows the Bonus Marchers' shantytown burning down in sight of the Capitol on the afternoon of July 28, 1932, reached the public, Hoover's image was permanently tarnished.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Prämie März war eine einiger Basisbewegungen 
der Arbeitslosen während des großen Tiefstands, der Tausenden 
Männer und Frauen und geholfene Fokusaufmerksamkeit auf der Rolle der
Bundesregierung galvanisierte, wenn es ökonomische Härte 
verminderte. Zwanzig tausend Weltkriegveterane grenzten nach 
Washington, um die sofortige Freigabe der versprochenen 
Barvergütungen zu verlangen und aufzustellen kampieren Sie, bis ihre 
Nachfragen befriedigt waren. Wenn Präsident Herbert Hoovers der
Ermächtigung, Bundestruppen, bewaffnet mit Behältern und Kavallerie,
angegriffen den heimatlosen Veteranen und gebrannt sind, ihrem Lager. 
Wenn Bilder diese Fotographie mögen, die das shantytown des 
Prämie Marchers' zeigt, das unten im Anblick des Kapitols am 
Nachmittag von Juli 28 brennt, 1932, erreichte die Öffentlichkeit, 
Bild des Staubsaugers wurde getrübt permanent.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La bonification mars était l'un de plusieurs mouvements 
de bases des chômeurs pendant la grande dépression qui a galvanisé 
des milliers des hommes et de femmes et l'attention aidée de foyer 
sur le rôle du gouvernement fédéral en allégeant des difficultés 
économiques. Vingt mille vétérans de Première Guerre 
Mondiale ont marché à Washington pour exiger la version immédiate 
des gratifications en espèces et du camp promis d'installation 
jusqu'à ce que leurs demandes aient été satisfaites. 
L'autorisation du Président Herbert Hoover's, les troupes 
fédérales, armées avec les réservoirs et la cavalerie, attaquées 
les vétérans sans foyer et étant brûlées leur campement. 
Quand les images aiment cette photographie, qui montre le 
bidonville du Marchers de bonification brûlant vers le bas en vue du 
capitol l'après-midi juillet de 28, 1932, a atteint le public, 
l'image de l'aspirateur a été de manière permanente terni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O bônus março era um de diversos movimentos dos 
grassroots dos desempregados durante o depression grande que 
galvanized milhares dos homens e das mulheres e a atenção ajudada do
foco no papel do governo federal em aliviar o hardship econômico. 
Vinte mil veterans do world.war.i marcharam a Washington para 
exijir a liberação imediata de bônus de dinheiro prometidos e para 
ajustar-se acima acampe até que suas demandas estiveram encontradas 
com. Com a autorização do presidente Herbert Hoover, as tropas
federais, armadas com os tanques e a cavalaria, atacadas os veterans 
desabrigados e queimadas seu encampment. Quando as imagens 
gostam desta fotografia, que mostra o shantytown do Marchers' do 
bônus que se queima para baixo na vista do capitol na tarde julho de 
28, 1932, alcançou o público, imagem do hoover tarnished 
permanentemente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'indennità marzo era uno di parecchi movimenti dei 
grassroots dei disoccupati durante la depressione grande che ha 
galvanizzato i migliaia degli uomini e delle donne e l'attenzione 
aiutata del fuoco sul ruolo del governo federale nell'alleviazione 
delle difficoltà economiche. Venti mila veterani di world.war.i
hanno marciato a Washington per richiedere la versione immediata delle
indennità di contanti e dell'accampamento promessi di messa a punto 
fino a rispondere le loro esigenze. Con autorizzazione del 
presidente Herbert Hoover, le truppe federali, munite con i 
carri armati ed il cavalry, attacate i veterani senza casa e bruciate 
il loro encampment. Quando le immagini gradiscono questa 
fotografia, che mostra lo shantytown del Marchers di indennità che si
brucia giù in vista del capitol sul pomeriggio de 28 luglio 1932, ha 
raggiunto il pubblico, immagine del hoover permanente è stato 
appannato.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το επίδομα Μάρτιος ήταν μια από διάφορες κυκλοφορίες
σε επίπεδο βάσης των ανέργων κατά τη διάρκεια της μεγάλης 
οικονομικής κρίσης που γαλβάνισε χιλιάδες άνδρες και γυναίκες 
και βοήθησε να στρέψει την προσοχή στο ρόλο της ομοσπονδιακής 
κυβέρνησης στην ανακούφιση της οικονομικής δυσκολίας. Ο 
παγκόσμιος πόλεμος Ι είκοσι χιλιάδων παλαίμαχοι βάδισε στην 
Ουάσιγκτον για να απαιτήσει την άμεση έκδοση των υποσχεμένων 
επιδομάτων μετρητών και να οργανώσει το στρατόπεδο έως ότου 
ικανοποιήθηκαν οι απαιτήσεις τους. Με την έγκριση Προέδρου 
Herbert Hoover's, τα ομοσπονδιακά στρατεύματα, που οπλίστηκαν
με τις δεξαμενές και το ιππικό, επιτέθηκαν στους άστεγους 
παλαιμάχους και έκαψαν τη στρατοπέδευσή τους. Όταν οι 
εικόνες όπως αυτήν την φωτογραφία, που εμφανίζει φτωχογειτονιά 
του Marchers επιδομάτων που καίει ολοσχερώς στη θέα του 
Capitol στο απόγευμα της 28ης Ιουλίου ..1932, έφθασαν στο 
κοινό, η εικόνα Hoover ήταν μόνιμα αμαυρωμένη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La prima marcha era uno de varios movimientos de los 
pueblos de los parados durante la gran depresión que galvanizó 
millares de hombres y de mujeres y la atención ayudada del foco en el
papel del gobierno federal en aliviar dificultad económica. 
Veinte mil veteranos de la Primera Guerra Mundial marcharon a 
Washington para exigir el desbloquear inmediato de las primas de 
efectivo prometidas e instalar acampe hasta que sus demandas fueron 
resueltas. Con la autorización de presidente Herberto Hoover's,
las tropas federales, armadas con los tanques y la caballería, 
atacadas los veteranos sin hogar y quemadas su campamento. 
Cuando las imágenes tienen gusto de esta fotografía, que 
muestra el shantytown del Marchers de la prima que se quema abajo en 
la vista del capitol en la tarde del de julio 28 de 1932, alcanzó el 
público, imagen de la aspiradora fue deslustrado permanentemente.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087397</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106214</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/anacostia-flats-and-flames</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
