<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107841</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107841</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087109</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"This Is Not What It Sounds Like On TV:" Carol Mirman on the 1970 Kent State Shootings</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Dieses Ist Nicht, Was Es Klingt Wie Auf 
Fernsehapparat:" Lied Mirman auf dem Kent Zustand 1970 
Shootings</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Ce N'est pas Ce qui Ressemble Cela À de Sur la 
TV :" Hymne de louange Mirman sur l'état 1970 de Kent 
Shootings</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Este Não é O que Soa Como na Tevê:" 
Carol Mirman no estado 1970 de Kent Shootings</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Questo Non è Che cosa Suona Come sulla TV:" 
Il carol Mirman sulla Risonanza 1970 Dichiara Shootings</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Αυτό δεν είναι αυτό που ηχεί όπως στην TV:" 
Θ*Θαρολ Mirman στους κρατικούς πυροβολισμούς του Κεντ του 
1970</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Esto No es Lo que Suena Como En la TV:" 
Carol Mirman en el estado 1970 de Kent Shootings</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">When the United States invaded Cambodia in 1970, college campuses around the country erupted in the most violent, disruptive set of antiwar demonstrations of the entire Vietnam period. The FBI listed 1,785 student demonstrations and 313 building occupations during the 1969-1970 school year. At Kent State University in Ohio, four undergraduates were killed on May 4, 1970 when the National Guard opened fire at an antiwar rally. Carol Mirman was a senior at Kent State in 1970, preparing to graduate with a degree in Fine Arts. Like other students, she was outraged that National Guard troops were stationed on campus. She took part in the rally on May 4, and witnessed, to her horror, the shooting deaths of her fellow students.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Als die Vereinigten Staaten Kambodscha 1970 
eindrangen, brachen Hochschulcampus um das Land im heftigsten, 
Unterbrechungsset von Antikriegsdemonstrationen der gesamten Vietnam 
Periode aus. Das FBI druckte 1.785 Kursteilnehmerdemonstrationen
und 313 aufbauende Besetzungen während des 1969-1970 Schuljahres aus.
An der Kent Landesuniversität in Ohio, wurden vier 
Nichtgraduierte an Mai 4, 1970 beendet, als der nationale Schutz Feuer
an einer Antikriegssammlung öffnete. Lied Mirman war ein 
Älteres am Kent Zustand 1970 und bereitete vor sich, mit einem Grad 
in den feinen künsten zu graduieren. Wie andere Kursteilnehmer 
wurde sie verletzt, die Truppen des nationalen Schutzes auf Campus 
stationiert wurden. Sie nahm an der Sammlung an Mai 4 teil und 
zeugte, zu ihrer Grausigkeit, die schießenden Todesfälle ihrer 
Mitkursteilnehmer.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Quand les Etats-Unis ont envahi le Cambodge en 
1970, les campus d'université dans le pays ont éclaté dans 
l'ensemble le plus violent et le plus disruptif de démonstrations 
pacifistes de la période entière du Vietnam. Le FBI a 
énuméré 1.785 démonstrations d'étudiant et 313 métiers de 
construction pendant l'année 1969-1970 scolaire. À 
l'université de l'Etat de Kent en Ohio, quatre étudiants préparant 
une licence ont été détruits 4 mai 1970 où la garde nationale a 
ouvert le feu à un rassemblement pacifiste. La hymne de louange
Mirman était un aîné à l'état de Kent en 1970, préparant pour 
recevoir un diplôme avec un degré dans des arts fins. Comme 
d'autres étudiants, on l'a outragé que des troupes de garde 
nationale ont été postée sur le campus. Elle a participé au 
rassemblement mai 4, et était témoin, à son horreur, des décès de
tir de ses étudiants de camarade.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quando os estados unidos invadiram Cambodia em 
1970, os campuses da faculdade em torno do país erupted no jogo o 
mais violento, o mais disruptivo de demonstrações antiwar do 
período inteiro de Vietnam. O FBI alistou 1.785 demonstrações
do estudante e 313 ocupações construindo durante o ano de escola 
1969-1970. Na universidade de estado de Kent em Ohio, quatro 
undergraduates foram matados maio em 4, 1970 em que o protetor 
nacional abriu o fogo em um rally antiwar. O carol Mirman era um
sénior no estado de Kent em 1970, preparando-se para graduar-se com 
um grau em artes finas. Como outros estudantes, foi ultrajada 
que as tropas do protetor nacional foram postadas no campus. 
Fêz exame da parte no rally maio em 4, e testemunhou, a seu 
horror, as mortes disparando de seus estudantes do companheiro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Quando unito Dichiara la Cambogia invasa in
1970, le città universitarie dell'università intorno al paese hanno 
scoppiato nell'insieme più violento e più disgregativo delle 
dimostrazioni pacifiste di intero periodo del Vietnam. Il FBI ha
elencato 1.785 dimostrazione dell'allievo e 313 occupazioni di 
costruzione durante l'anno scolastico 1969-1970. A Risonanza 
Dichiari l'università nell'Ohio, quattro studenti non 
laureati sono stati uccisi maggio su 4, 1970 in cui la protezione 
nazionale ha aperto il fuoco ad un raduno pacifista. Il carol 
Mirman era un anziano a Risonanza Dichiara in 1970, 
preparandosi per laurearsi con un grado nelle arti fini. Come 
altri allievi, è stata oltraggiata che le truppe della protezione 
nazionale sono state disposte sulla città universitaria. Ha 
partecipato al raduno maggio su 4 ed ha testimoniato, al suo orrore, 
le morti di fucilazione dei suoi allievi del collega.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Όταν οι Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες εισέβαλαν στην Καμπότζη το
1970, οι πανεπιστημιουπόλεις κολλεγίων γύρω από τη χώρα 
εξερράγησαν στο βιαιότερο, αποδιοργανωτικό σύνολο αντιπολεμικές 
επίδειξη της ολόκληρης περιόδου του Βιετνάμ. Η FBI 
εμφάνισε λίστα 1.785 επιδείξεις σπουδαστών και 313 
επαγγέλματα οικοδόμησης κατά τη διάρκεια του σχολικού έτους του 
1969-1970. Κρατικό πανεπιστήμιο του Κεντ στο Οχάιο, 
τέσσερις προπτυχιακοί φοιτητές σκοτώθηκαν σε Μάιος 4 
..1970 όταν άνοιξε η εθνική φρουρά την πυρκαγιά σε μια 
αντιπολεμική συνάθροιση. Η Carol Mirman ήταν 
πρεσβύτερος στο κράτος του Κεντ το 1970, που προετοιμάζεται να 
βαθμολογήσει με έναν βαθμό στις καλές τέχνες. Όπως άλλους
σπουδαστές, προσβλήθηκε ότι τα εθνικά στρατεύματα φρουράς 
τοποθετήθηκαν στην πανεπιστημιούπολη. Συμμετείχε στη 
συνάθροιση σε Μάιος 4, και βεβαίωσε, στη φρίκη της, τους 
πυροβολισμός θανάτους των συμφοιτητών της.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cuando los Estados Unidos invadieron Camboya en 
1970, los campus de la universidad alrededor del país entraron en 
erupción en el conjunto más violento, más quebrantador de 
demostraciones pacifistas del período entero de Vietnam. El FBI
enumeró 1.785 demostraciones del estudiante y 313 ocupaciones 
constructivas durante el año escolar 1969-1970. En la 
universidad de estado de Kent en Ohio, mataron a cuatro estudiantes de
mayo el 4 de 1970 en que el protector nacional abrió el fuego en una 
reunión pacifista. El carol Mirman era un mayor en el estado de
Kent en 1970, preparándose para graduar con un grado en artes finos. 
Como otros estudiantes, la ultrajaron a que colocaron las tropas
del protector nacional en campus. Ella participó en la reunión
de mayo el 4, y atestiguó, a su horror, las muertes que tiraban de 
sus estudiantes del compañero.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087109</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107841</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/this-is-not-what-it-sounds-like-on-tv-carol-mirman-on-the-1970-kent-state-shootings</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
