<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108465</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108465</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086118</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Elsie Johnson McDougald on "The Double Task: The Struggle of Negro Women for Sex and Race Emancipation"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Elsie Johnson McDougald auf "der doppelten 
Aufgabe: Der Kampf der Schwarze-Frauen für Geschlecht-und 
Rennen-Emanzipation "</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Elsie Johnson McDougald sur "le double 
Chargent : La lutte des femmes de nègre pour 
l'émancipation de sexe et de course "</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Elsie Johnson McDougald "na tarefa dobro: O 
esforço de mulheres do negro para o emancipation do sexo e da raça 
"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Elsie Johnson McDougald "sulla doppia operazione: 
La lotta delle donne del negro per emancipazione della razza e 
del sesso "</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Elsie Johnson McDougald "στη διπλή στοιχειώδη 
εργασία: Η προσπάθεια των γυναικών νέγρων για την 
Χειραφέτηση φύλων και φυλών "</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Elsie Johnson McDougald en "la tarea doble: 
La lucha de las mujeres del negro para la emancipación del sexo
y de la raza "</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Through a range of political, social, and organizational venues, African-American women struggled to participate in the racial awareness and pride that characterized the "New Negro" movement of the 1920s. Alain Locke's important 1925 compilation of Harlem Renaissance writings,  The New Negro , included an essay by Elise Johnson McDougald, a prominent black educator, social investigator, and journalist. McDougald's essay, originally published in the  Survey , employed socioeconomic analysis to explore the particular problems, as well as contributions to society, of four groups of black women, from wealthy to working-class. Seeking to repudiate the monolithic way in which black women were perceived and represented by white America, McDougald not only focused on economics but also challenged stereotypical representations of blacks in the arts and advertising, as well as those surrounding black women's sexuality.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Durch eine Strecke politischen, kämpften Sozial- 
und organisatorische Schauplätze, Afrikanisch-Amerikanische Frauen, 
um am rassischen Bewußtsein teilzunehmen und Stolz, der die Bewegung 
"des neuen Schwarzen" des zwanziger Jahre Alain Lockes wichtigen der 
Kompilation 1925 der Harlem Renaissanceschreiben kennzeichnete, der 
neue Schwarze, schloß einen Versuch durch Elise Johnson McDougald, 
ein vorstehender schwarzer Erzieher, Sozialforscher und Journalist 
ein. Versuch McDougalds, ursprünglich veröffentlicht in der 
Übersicht, eingesetzte sozioökonomische Analyse, um die bestimmten 
Probleme, sowie Beiträge zur Gesellschaft, von vier Gruppen der 
schwarzen Frauen, von wohlhabendem zur Arbeiterklasse zu erforschen. 
Das Suchen, die monolithische Methode, in der schwarze Frauen 
durch weißes Amerika, wahrgenommen und dargestellt wurden McDougald 
abzulehnen konzentrierte nicht nur, auf Volkswirtschaft aber forderte 
auch stereotypische Darstellungen von Schwarzen in den künsten und im
Bekanntmachen, sowie Sexualität jener umgebende schwarzen Frauen 
heraus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Par un intervalle de politique, les rendez-vous 
sociaux et et d'organisation, les femmes afro-américaines ont lutté pour
participer à la conscience raciale et la fierté qui a caractérisé 
le mouvement de "nouveau nègre" de la compilation 1925 importante 
d'Alain le Locke des années 20 des écritures de la Renaissance de 
Harlem, le nouveau nègre, a inclus un essai par Elise Johnson 
McDougald, un éducateur noir en avant, investigateur social, et 
journaliste. L'essai de McDougald, initialement édité dans 
l'étude, analyse socio-économique utilisée pour explorer les 
problèmes particuliers, aussi bien que des contributions à la 
société, de quatre groupes de femmes noires, de riche au classe 
ouvrier. Rechercher à nier la voie monolithique dont des femmes
noires ont été perçues et représentées par l'Amérique blanche, 
McDougald s'est non seulement concentré sur des sciences économiques
mais a également défié les représentations stéréotypées des 
noirs dans les arts et la publicité, aussi bien que la sexualité 
environnante de ces femmes noires.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Através de uma escala de político, os venues 
sociais, e organizational, mulheres Africano-Americanas esforçaram-se
para participar na consciência racial e o orgulho que caracterizou "o
movimento do negro novo" da compilação 1925 importante de Alain o 
Locke dos 1920s. de escritas do renascimento de Harlem, negro novo, 
incluiu um essay por Elise Johnson McDougald, um educador preto 
proeminente, investigator social, e journalist. Essay de 
McDougald, publicado originalmente no exame, análise socioeconomic 
empregada para explorar os problemas particulares, as.well.as 
contribuições à sociedade, de quatro grupos de mulheres pretas, de 
rico ao working-class. Procurar repudiate a maneira monolítica 
em que as mulheres pretas foram percebidas e representadas por 
América branca, McDougald focalizado não somente na economia mas 
desafiou também respresentações stereotypical dos pretos nas artes 
e em anunciar, as.well.as sexuality circunvizinho daquelas mulheres 
pretas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Attraverso una gamma di politico, le sedi della 
riunione sociali e ed organizzative, donne Africano-Americane hanno 
lottato per partecipare alla consapevolezza razziale e l'orgoglio che 
ha caratterizzato "il movimento del nuovo negro" della compilazione 
importante 1925 di Alain il Locke degli anni 20 delle scritture di 
rinascita di Harlem, il nuovo negro, ha incluso un saggio da Elise 
Johnson McDougald, un educatore nero prominente, ricercatore sociale e
giornalista. Saggio del McDougald, originalmente pubblicato 
nell'indagine, analisi socioeconomica impiegata per esplorare i 
problemi particolari, così come i contributi alla società, di 
quattro gruppi delle donne nere, da ricco alla classe operaia. 
La ricerca rinnegare il modo monolitico in cui le donne nere 
sono state percepite e rappresentato state dall'America bianca, 
McDougald messo a fuoco non soltanto su economia ma egualmente ha 
sfidato le rappresentazioni stereotypical dei neri nelle arti e nella 
pubblicità, così come il sexuality circostante di quelle donne nere.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μέσω μιας σειράς των πολιτικών, κοινωνικών, και 
οργανωτικών τόπων συναντήσεως, οι αφρικανικός-αμερικανικές 
γυναίκες αγωνίστηκαν να συμμετέχουν στη φυλετική συνειδητοποίηση 
και η υπερηφάνεια που χαρακτήρισε τη μετακίνηση "νέων νέγρων" της
σημαντικής μεταγλώττισης του 1925 του Alain Locke's της 
δεκαετίας του '20 των γραφών αναγέννησης Harlem, ο νέος 
νέγρος, περιέλαβε ένα δοκίμιο από Elise Johnson 
McDougald, έναν προεξέχοντα μαύρο εκπαιδευτικό, έναν 
κοινωνικό ανακριτή, και έναν δημοσιογράφο. McDougald's 
δοκίμιο, που δημοσιεύεται αρχικά στην έρευνα, υιοθετημένη 
κοινωνικοοικονομική ανάλυση για να ερευνήσει τα ιδιαίτερα 
προβλήματα, καθώς επίσης και τις συνεισφορές στην κοινωνία, 
τεσσάρων ομάδων μαύρων γυναικών, από πλούσιο στην εργατική 
τάξη. Επιδιώκον να αποκηρύξει το μονολιθικό τρόπο με τον 
οποίο οι μαύρες γυναίκες έγιναν αντιληπτές και αντιπροσωπεύθηκαν
από τη λευκιά Αμερική, McDougald όχι μόνο εστίασε στα 
οικονομικά αλλά και προκάλεσε τις stereotypical 
αντιπροσωπεύσεις των Μαύρων στις τέχνες και τη διαφήμιση, καθώς 
επίσης και τη σεξουαλικότητα εκείνων των να περιβάλει μαύρων 
γυναικών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">A través de un rango de político, los lugares 
sociales, y de organización, las mujeres Africano-Americanas lucharon
para participar en el conocimiento racial y el orgullo que 
caracterizó el movimiento del "nuevo negro" de la compilación 
importante 1925 de Alain el Locke de los años 20 de las escrituras 
del renacimiento de Harlem, el nuevo negro, incluyó un ensayo de 
Elise Johnson McDougald, educador negro prominente, investigador 
social, y periodista. Ensayo de McDougald, publicado 
originalmente en la encuesta, análisis socioeconómico empleado para 
explorar los problemas determinados, así como contribuciones a la 
sociedad, de cuatro grupos de mujeres negras, de rico a la clase 
obrera. El intentar negar la manera monolítica de la cual 
América blanca percibieron y fueron representadas a las mujeres 
negras, McDougald centrado no solamente en la economía pero también 
desafió representaciones stereotypical de negros en los artes y la 
publicidad, así como la sexualidad circundante de esas mujeres 
negras.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086118</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108465</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/elsie-johnson-mcdougald-on-the-double-task-the-struggle-of-negro-women-for-sex-and-race-emancipation</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
