<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105072</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105072</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211160</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Vectors: Grade 10</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Vektoren: Grad 10</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Vecteurs : Catégorie 10</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Vetores: Classe 10</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Vettori: Grado 10</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διανύσματα: Βαθμός 10</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Vectores: Grado 10</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Grade 10: Vectors. Are vectors physics? No, vectors themselves are not physics. Physics is just a description of the world around us. To describe something we need to use a language. The most common language used to describe physics is mathematics. Vectors form a very important part of the mathematical description of physics, so much so that it is absolutely essential to master the use of vectors.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">Africa</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Grad 10: Vektoren. Sind Vektoren 
Physik? Nr., vectors sind nicht Physik. Physik ist eine 
Beschreibung der Welt um uns gerecht. Etwas beschreiben, das wir
eine Sprache verwenden müssen. Die Standardsprache verwendete, 
Physik zu beschreiben ist Mathematik. Vectors Formular ein sehr 
wichtiges Teil der mathematischen Beschreibung von Physik, soviel, 
damit es absolut wesentlich ist, den Gebrauch von Vektoren zu 
erarbeiten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Catégorie 10 : Vecteurs. Les vecteurs
sont-ils de la physique ? Le non, se dirige ne sont pas 
physique. La physique est juste une description du monde autour 
de nous. Pour décrire quelque chose que nous devons nous servir
d'un langage. Le langage le plus commun décrivait la physique 
est des mathématiques. Dirige la forme par partie très 
importante de la description mathématique de la physique, tellement 
de sorte qu'il soit absolument essentiel de maîtriser l'utilisation 
des vecteurs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Classe 10: Vetores. São os vetores 
física? O No., vectors não é física. A física é 
justa uma descrição do mundo em torno de nós. Para descrever 
algo que nós necessitamos usar uma língua. A língua a mais 
comum usou-se descrever a física é matemática. Vectors o 
formulário um a parte muito importante da descrição matemática da 
física, assim muito de modo que seja absolutamente essencial dominar 
o uso dos vetores.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Grado 10: Vettori. Sono i vettori la 
fisica? No, vectors non è la fisica. La fisica è giusta 
una descrizione del mondo intorno noi. Per descrivere qualcosa 
che dobbiamo usare un linguaggio. Il linguaggio più comune ha 
usato descrivere la fisica è la matematica. Vectors la forma un
la parte molto importante della descrizione matematica della fisica, 
così tanto in modo che sia assolutamente essenziale per acquistare 
padronanza dell'uso dei vettori.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βαθμός 10: Διανύσματα. Είναι τα διανύσματα
φυσική; Όχι, διανύσματα οι ίδιοι δεν είναι φυσική. Η
φυσική είναι ακριβώς μια περιγραφή του κόσμου γύρω από μας. 
Για να περιγράψουμε κάτι πρέπει να χρησιμοποιήσουμε μια 
γλώσσα. Η πιό κοινή γλώσσα που χρησιμοποιείται για να 
περιγράψει τη φυσική είναι μαθηματικά. Τα διανύσματα 
αποτελούν ένα πολύ σημαντικό μέρος της μαθηματικής περιγραφής 
της φυσικής, τόσο πολύ έτσι ώστε είναι απολύτως ουσιαστικό να 
κυριαρχηθεί η χρήση των διανυσμάτων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Grado 10: Vectores. ¿Son los vectores 
física? No, vectors no es física. La física es justa 
una descripción del mundo alrededor de nosotros. Para describir
algo que necesitamos utilizar un lenguaje. El lenguaje más 
común describía la física es matemáticas. Vectors la forma a
la parte muy importante de la descripción matemática de la física, 
tanto de modo que sea absolutamente esencial dominar el uso de 
vectores.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211160</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105072</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/vectors-grade-10</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
