<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105481</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105481</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206331</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Teacher's Guide to the Occupational Outlook Handbook</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Anleitung des Lehrers zum beruflichen 
Aussicht-Handbuch</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le guide du professeur du manuel professionnel de
perspectives</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Guia do professor ao manual ocupacional do 
outlook</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Guida dell'insegnante al manuale professionale di
prospettiva</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οδηγός δασκάλου για το επαγγελματικό εγχειρίδιο 
προοπτικής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Guía del profesor al manual ocupacional de la 
perspectiva</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">describes hundreds of jobs. For each job, it tells what workers do, working conditions, the training and education needed, earnings, and expected job prospects. Job search tips, information about the job market in each state, articles about specific occupations and industries, and additional career information are included.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">beschreibt Hunderte Jobs. Für jeden Job 
erklärt es welche Arbeiter tun, Arbeitsbedingungen, das Training und 
die Ausbildung, die benötigt werden, Einkommen und erwartete 
Jobaussichten. Jobsuche neigt, Informationen über den 
Stellenmarkt in jedem Zustand, Artikel über spezifische Besetzungen 
und Industrien, und zusätzliche Karriereinformationen sind enthalten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">décrit des centaines de travaux. Pour 
chaque travail, il indique quels ouvriers font, des conditions de 
travail, la formation et l'éducation requises, des revenus, et s'est 
attendu à des perspectives du travail. La recherche du travail 
incline, des informations sur le marché du travail dans chaque état,
des articles concernant des métiers spécifiques et des industries, 
et l'information supplémentaire de carrière sont incluse.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">descreve centenas dos trabalhos. Para cada 
trabalho, diz que trabalhadores fazem, condições de funcionamento, o
treinamento e a instrução necessitados, salário, e esperou 
prospetos do trabalho. A busca do trabalho derruba, informação
sobre o mercado de trabalho em cada estado, artigos sobre ocupações 
específicas e indústrias, e a informação adicional da carreira é 
incluída.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">descrive le centinaia dei lavori. Per ogni 
lavoro, dice al che operai fanno, condizioni di lavoro, la formazione 
e l'istruzione state necessaria, guadagni ed ha previsto i prospetti 
di lavoro. La ricerca di lavoro si capovolge, le informazioni 
sul mercato di lavoro in ciascuno dichiarano, articoli sulle 
occupazioni specifiche ed industrie e le informazioni supplementari 
di carriera sono incluse.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">περιγράφει τις εκατοντάδες των εργασιών. _ για 
κάθε εργασία, αυτός λέω ποιος εργαζόμενος, εργασία συνθήκη, ο 
εκπαιδεύω και εκπαίδευση χρειάζομαι, αποδοχή, και ανα:μένω 
εργασία προοπτική. Οι συμβουλές αναζήτησης εργασίας, οι 
πληροφορίες για την αγορά εργασίας σε κάθε κράτος, τα άρθρα για 
τα συγκεκριμένες επαγγέλματα και τις βιομηχανίες, και οι πρόσθετες
πληροφορίες σταδιοδρομίας συμπεριλαμβάνονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">describe centenares de trabajos. Para cada 
trabajo, dice qué trabajadores hacen, las condiciones de trabajo, el 
entrenamiento y la educación necesitados, las ganancias, y contaba 
con perspectivas del trabajo. La búsqueda del trabajo inclina, 
información sobre el mercado de trabajo en cada estado, los 
artículos acerca de ocupaciones específicas y las industrias, y la 
información adicional de la carrera es incluida.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206331</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105481</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/teachers-guide-to-the-occupational-outlook-handbook</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
