<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103173</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103173</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086299</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Was a Very Apt Scholar in This Kind of Street Etiquette": William Otter Brawls His Way Through New York City, 1830s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ich war ein sehr passender Gelehrter in dieser 
Art der Straße Etikette": William Otter Keift Seine Methode 
Durch New York City, 1830s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"j'étais un disciple très convenable dans ce 
genre d'étiquette de rue" : La Loutre de William Se bagarre Sa 
Voie Par New York City, 1830s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"eu era um scholar muito apt neste tipo do 
etiquette da rua": A Lontra De William Brawls Sua Maneira 
Através De New York City, 1830s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"ero un erudito molto adatto in questo genere di 
etiquette della via": La Lontra Del William Brawls Il Suo Modo 
Attraverso New York City, 1830s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"ήμουν πολύ ικανός μελετητής σε αυτό το είδος 
εθιμοτυπίας οδών": Θ*Ωηλληαμ Otter Brawls His Way 
μέσω της πόλης της Νέας Υόρκης, 1830s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"era un erudito muy conveniente en esta clase de 
Etiqueta de la calle": La Nutria De Guillermo Se pelea Su 
Manera A través De New York City, 1830s</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">While most working-class autobiographers followed the example of Benjamin Franklin and portrayed the "industrious apprentice," William Otter showed another side of plebian life. Otter took his readers into the world of heavy drinking and nativist violence of antebellum urban life. Cities increasingly became unruly places to govern in the decades before the Civil War with their rapid population growth and jostling of immigrant and native born. Competition for jobs and just plain scapegoating led to brawls between native-born, foreign, and African-Americans workers. Otter participated in the urban diversions made possible by the new commercial culture such as boxing, baseball and other sports, or games at local taverns, along with the competitions between rival militia companies and neighborhood street gangs. All of these boisterous activities could turn violent. Otter was born in England and impressed into the British navy. He jumped ship and came to New York in 1831. While apprenticed as a plasterer, he entered a world of masculine culture that he colorfully displayed in his  History of My Own Times  (1835).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während die meisten Arbeiterklasseautobiographen 
dem Beispiel von Benjamin Franklin folgten und den "industrious 
Lehrling schilderten," zeigte William Otter eine andere Seite der 
plebian Lebensdauer. Otter nahm seine Leser in die Welt des 
schweren Trinkens und der nativist Gewalttätigkeit der antebellum 
städtischen Lebensdauer. Städte wurden in zunehmendem Maße 
die unruly Plätze, zum in den Dekaden vor dem Bürgerkrieg mit ihrem 
schnellen Bevölkerung Wachstum und Drängeln von einwanderndem und 
von Eingeborenem zu regeln geboren. Konkurrenz für Jobs und 
normales gerade scapegoating führten zu Lärm zwischen den 
gebürtig-getragenen, fremden und Afrikanisch-Amerikaner Arbeitern. 
Otter nahm an den städtischen Ablenkungen teil gebildet, die 
durch die neue kommerzielle Kultur so als Verpacken, Baseball und 
anderer Sport oder Spiele an den lokalen Taverns, entlang mit den 
Konkurrenzen zwischen rivalisierenden Milizfirmen und Nachbarschaft 
Straße Gruppen möglich sind. Alle diese stürmischen 
Aktivitäten konnten heftig sich drehen. Otter wurde in England 
getragen und beeindruckt in die britische Marine. Er sprang 
Schiff und kam nach New York 1831. Während es als Plasterer in 
die Lehre gegeben wird, betrat er eine Welt der männlichen Kultur, 
die er bunt in seiner Geschichte meiner eigenen Zeiten (1835) 
anzeigte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Tandis que la plupart des autobiographes de classe
ouvrier suivaient l'exemple de Benjamin Franklin et dépeignaient 
"l'apprenti travailleur," la loutre de William a montré un autre 
côté de la vie plebian. La loutre a pris ses lecteurs dans le 
monde du boire lourd et de la violence nativiste de la vie urbaine 
d'avant-guerre. Les villes sont de plus en plus devenues les 
endroits indisciplinés à régir dans les décennies avant la guerre 
civile avec leur croissance de population et bousculer rapides 
d'immigré et de l'indigène nés. La concurrence pour les 
travaux et juste scapegoating ordinaire ont mené aux bagarres entre 
les ouvriers indigène-soutenu, étrangers, et d'Afro-Américains. 
La loutre a participé aux transferts urbains possibles par la 
nouvelle culture commerciale telle que la boxe, le base-ball et 
d'autres sports, ou les jeux aux tavernes locales, avec les concours 
entre les compagnies de milice et les troupes rivales de rue de 
voisinage. Toutes ces activités bruyantes ont pu tourner 
violent. La loutre a été soutenue en Angleterre et 
impressionnée dans la marine britannique. Il a sauté le bateau
et est venu à New York en 1831. Tandis que mis en apprentissage
en tant que plâtrier, il est entré dans un monde de culture 
masculine qu'il a coloré affiché dans son histoire de mes propres 
périodes (1835).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quando a maioria de autobiógrafos do 
working-class seguiram o exemplo de Benjamin Franklin e portrayed "o 
aprendiz industrious," a lontra de William mostrou um outro lado da 
vida plebian. A lontra fêz exame de seus leitores no mundo de 
beber pesado e de violência nativist da vida urbana antebellum. 
As cidades transformaram-se cada vez mais lugares unruly a 
governar nas décadas antes da guerra civil com seus crescimento da 
população e jostling rápidos de immigrant e do nativo carregados. 
A competição para trabalhos e apenas scapegoating liso 
conduziram aos brawls entre trabalhadores nativo-carregado, 
extrangeiros, e dos Africano-Americanos. A lontra participou nas
diversões urbanas feitas possíveis pela cultura comercial nova tal 
como o boxing, o baseball e os outros esportes, ou os jogos em taverns
locais, junto com as competições entre as companhias da milícia e 
os grupos rivais da rua da vizinhança. Todas estas atividades 
boisterous podiam girar violento. A lontra foi carregada em 
Inglaterra e imprimida na marinha britânica. Saltou o navio e 
veio a New York em 1831. Quando colocado como um plasterer, 
entrou em um mundo da cultura masculine que indicasse colorida em seu 
history de minhas próprias épocas (1835).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Mentre la maggior parte dei autobiografi della 
classe operaia hanno seguito l'esempio di Benjamin Franklin ed hanno
ritratto "l'apprendista industrious," la lontra del William ha 
mostrato un altro lato di vita plebian. La lontra ha preso i 
suoi lettori nel mondo bere pesante e della violenza nativist di vita 
urbana antebellum. Le città sempre più si sono transformate in
in posti unruly da governare nelle decadi prima della guerra civile 
con il loro sviluppo della popolazione e jostling veloci di immigrato 
e del nativo sopportati. La concorrenza per i lavori ed appena 
scapegoating normale hanno condotto ai brawls fra gli operai 
natale-sopportato, straniero e degli Africano-Americani. La 
lontra ha partecipato alle diversioni urbane permesse dalla nuova 
coltura commerciale quali boxing, baseball ed altri sport, o giochi 
alle locande locali, con i concorsi fra le aziende della milizia ed i 
gruppi rivali della via della vicinanza. Tutte queste attività 
boisterous hanno potuto girare violento. La lontra è stata 
sopportata in Inghilterra ed è stata impressionata nel blu marino 
britannico. Ha saltato la nave ed è venuto a New York in 1831. 
Mentre collocato come plasterer, ha entrato in un mondo di 
coltura maschile che colorfully ha visualizzato nella sua storia dei 
miei propri periodi (1835).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ενώ τα περισσότερα autobiographers εργατικών τάξεων
ακολούθησαν το παράδειγμα Benjamin Franklin και απεικόνισαν 
το "εργατικό μαθητευόμενο," William Otter εμφάνισε μια άλλη 
πλευρά της plebian ζωής. Η ενυδρίδα πήρε τους αναγνώστες
του στον κόσμο της βαριάς βίας κατανάλωσης και nativist της 
προπολεμικής αστικής ζωής. Οι πόλεις έγιναν όλο και 
περισσότερο απείθαρχες θέσεις που κυβερνούν στις δεκαετίες πριν 
από τον εμφύλιο πόλεμο με την ταχέα ανάπτυξη πληθυσμών και το 
σπρώξιμό τους μετανάστη και ντόπιου γεννημένων. Ο 
ανταγωνισμός για τις εργασίες και ακριβώς σαφή οδήγησαν στις 
φιλονικίες μεταξύ εγγενής-γεννημένου, ξένος, και των εργαζομένων
αφρικανικός-Αμερικανοί. Η ενυδρίδα συμμετείχε στις αστικές 
παρεκτροπές που έγιναν πιθανές από το νέο εμπορικό πολιτισμό 
όπως ο εγκιβωτισμός, το μπέιζ-μπώλ και άλλος αθλητισμός, ή τα 
παιχνίδια στις τοπικές ταβέρνες, μαζί με τους ανταγωνισμούς 
μεταξύ των αντίπαλων επιχειρήσεων πολιτοφυλακών και των συμμοριών
των δρόμων γειτονιάς. Όλες αυτές οι άγριες δραστηριότητες 
θα μπορούσαν να γίνουν βίαιες. Η ενυδρίδα γεννήθηκε στην 
Αγγλία και εντυπωσίασε στο βρετανικό ναυτικό. Πήδησε το 
σκάφος και ήρθε στη Νέα Υόρκη το 1831. Ενώ τοποθετείται
ως μαθητευόμενο ως γυψαδόρος, εισήγαγε έναν κόσμο του αρσενικού 
πολιτισμού που παρουσίασε colorfully στην ιστορία χρόνων μου 
του (1835).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mientras que la mayoría de los autobiógrafos de 
la clase obrera siguieron el ejemplo de Benjamin Franklin y retrataron
a "aprendiz industrious," la nutria de Guillermo mostró otra cara de 
la vida plebian. La nutria tomó a sus programas de lectura en 
el mundo de beber pesado y de la violencia nativista de la vida urbana
antebellum. Las ciudades se convirtieron en cada vez más 
lugares ingobernables a gobernar en las décadas antes de la guerra 
civil con su crecimiento de la población y empujar rápidos 
de inmigrante y del natural llevados. La competición para los 
trabajos y apenas el scapegoating llano condujeron a las reyertas 
entre los trabajadores nativo-llevado, no nativo, y de los 
Africano-Americanos. La nutria participó en las diversiones 
urbanas hechas posibles por la nueva cultura comercial tal como boxeo,
béisbol y otros deportes, o los juegos en las tabernas locales, junto
con las competiciones entre las compañías de la milicia y las 
cuadrillas rivales de la calle de la vecindad. Todas estas 
actividades bulliciosas podían dar vuelta violento. La nutria 
fue llevada en Inglaterra e impresionada en la marina de guerra británica. 
Él saltó la nave y vino a Nueva York en 1831. Mientras 
que estaba puesto de aprendiz como yesero, él entró en un mundo de 
la cultura masculina que él colorido visualizó en su historia de mis
propias épocas (1835).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086299</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103173</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-was-a-very-apt-scholar-in-this-kind-of-street-etiquette-william-otter-brawls-his-way-through-new-york-city-1830s</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
