<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104050</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104050</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202717</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">One, Two, Three...Go POE!</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein, Zwei, Drei... Gehen POE!</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">On, Deux, Trois... Vont POE !</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uns, Dois, Três... Vai POE!</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Uno, Due, Tre... Va POE!</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το ένα, δύο, τρία... πηγαίνει σημείο εισόδου!</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Uno, Dos, Tres... Va POE!</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this lesson, students will be able to compare and contrast three short stories they have read by Edgar Allan Poe. The assignment will be divided into three parts: (1) They will have read and discussed or completed other classroom activities on each of the three stories. (2) They will work in small groups to brainstorm and create comparison/contrast charts that will be shared with the class. (3) Students will create their own graphic organizers based on the ideas shared in step two and then create a draft and final paper.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In dieser Lektion können Kursteilnehmer, drei kurze 
Geschichten zu vergleichen und zu kontrastieren, die sie durch Edgar 
Allan Poe gelesen haben. Die Anweisung wird in drei Teile 
geteilt: (1) haben sie und behandelt oder andere 
Klassenzimmeraktivitäten durchgeführt auf jeder der drei Geschichten
gelesen. (2) arbeiten sie in den kleinen Gruppen, um gedanklich 
zu lösen und comparison/contrast Diagramme zu erstellen, die mit der 
Kategorie geteilt werden. (3) stellen Kursteilnehmer ihre 
eigenen graphischen Organisatoren her, die auf den Ideen basieren, die
in Jobstep zwei geteilt werden und stellen dann einen Entwurf und ein 
abschließendes Papier her.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cette leçon, les étudiants pourront comparer et 
contraster trois histoires courtes qu'ils ont lues par Edgar Allan 
Poe. L'affectation sera divisée en trois parts : (1) ils 
auront lu et discuté ou terminé d'autres activités de salle de 
classe sur chacune des trois histoires. (2) ils travailleront 
dans de petits groupes pour faire un brainstorm et pour créer les 
diagrammes de comparison/contrast qui seront partagés avec la classe.
(3) les étudiants créeront leurs propres organisateurs 
graphiques basés sur les idées partagées dans l'étape deux et puis
créeront une ébauche et un papier final.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta lição, os estudantes poderão  comparar e 
contrastar três histórias que curtas leram por Edgar Allan Poe. 
A atribuição será dividida em três porções: (1) 
terão lido e discutido ou terminado outras atividades da sala de aula
em cada uma das três histórias. (2) trabalharão em grupos 
pequenos para brainstorm e criar as cartas de comparison/contrast que 
serão compartilhadas com a classe. (3) os estudantes criarão 
seus próprios organizers gráficos baseados nas idéias 
compartilhadas em etapa dois e criarão então um esboço e um papel 
final.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questa lezione, gli allievi potranno confrontare e 
contrapporre tre storia che corte hanno letto da Edgar Allan Poe. 
L'assegnazione sarà divisa in tre parti: (1) avranno 
letto e discusso o completato altre attività dell'aula su ciascuna 
delle tre storia. (2) lavoreranno nei piccoli gruppi per 
brainstorm e creare le tabelle di comparison/contrast che saranno 
ripartite con il codice categoria. (3) gli allievi creeranno i 
loro propri organizzatori grafici basati sulle idee compartecipi a 
punto due ed allora creeranno una brutta copia e una carta finale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτό το μάθημα, οι σπουδαστές θα είναι σε θέση να 
συγκρίνουν και να αντιπαραβάλουν τρεις σύντομες ιστορίες που 
έχουν διαβάσει από τον Edgar Allan Poe. Η ανάθεση 
θα διαιρεθεί σε τρία μέρη: (1) Θα έχουν διαβάσει και θα 
έχουν συζητήσει ή θα έχουν ολοκληρώσει άλλες δραστηριότητες 
τάξεων σε κάθε μια από τις τρεις ιστορίες. (2) Θα 
λειτουργήσουν στις μικρές ομάδες στον καταιγισμό ιδεών και θα 
δημιουργήσουν τα διαγράμματα σύγκρισης/αντίθεσης που θα 
μοιραστούν με την κλάση. (3) Οι σπουδαστές θα δημιουργήσουν 
τους γραφικούς διοργανωτές τους βασισμένους στις ιδέες κοινές στο
βήμα δύο και θα δημιουργήσουν έπειτα ένα σχέδιο και ένα τελικό
έγγραφο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta lección, los estudiantes podrán comparar y poner
en contraste tres historias cortas que han leído por Edgar Allan Poe.
La asignación será dividida en tres porciones: (1) 
habrán leído y discutido o terminado otras actividades de la sala de
clase en cada uno de las tres historias. (2) trabajarán en 
grupos pequeños para inspirarse y para crear las cartas de 
comparison/contrast que serán compartidas con la clase. (3) los
estudiantes crearán a sus propios organizadores gráficos basados en 
las ideas compartidas en el paso de progresión dos y después 
crearán un bosquejo y un papel final.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JANIE PEAK
FN:JANIE PEAK
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202717</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104050</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/one-two-three-go-poe</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
