<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/18071053</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>18071053</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>20101533</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Time Dilation Video</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zeit-Ausdehnung-Bildschirm</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Vidéo de Dilatation de Temps</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Vídeo Do Dilation Do Tempo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Video Di Dilatazione Di Tempo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βίντεο χρονικής διαστολής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Vídeo De la Dilatación Del Tiempo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Is time different to observers moving at different speeds? For more information, see the World Year of Physics 2005 feature.

Video Transcript: Two spaceships are traveling together through the galaxy at close to the speed of light. Mounted on one ship is a laser that can fire pulses of light, and on the other, a mirror. The pilot of the first ship fires a pulse at the mirror, and watches as it is reflected back. A clock on board measures how long the round trip takes.

But now suppose that he does this as the ships are passing an observer on a nearby asteroid. According to relativity theory, this observer sees the pulse moving through space at exactly the same speed that the pilot does -- namely, the speed of light. But he also sees the pulse traveling a longer distance, because from his perspective, he must add the forward motion of the ships to the motion of the pulse between them. So he measures a longer time interval for the round trip than the pilot does, because he is watching the pulse go farther without going any faster. This effect is called time dilation: if one observer is moving with respect to another, each perceives that the other's time is flowing more slowly.

General Restrictions:Images and other media in the National Science Foundation Multimedia Gallery are available for use in print and electronic material by NSF employees, members of the media, university staff, teachers and the general public. All media in the gallery are intended for personal, educational and nonprofit/non-commercial use only.

Images credited to the National Science Foundation, a federal agency, are in the public domain. The images were created by employees of the United States Government as part of their official duties or prepared by contractors as "works for hire" for NSF. You may freely use NSF-credited images and, at your discretion, credit NSF with a "Courtesy: National Science Foundation" notation. Additional information about general usage can be found in Conditions.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bewegt die Zeit, die von Beobachtern mit 
unterschiedlichen Geschwindigkeiten verschieden ist? Zu mehr 
Information sehen Sie das Weltjahr der Abschrift der Physik-2005 
feature.Video: Zwei Raumschiffe reisen zusammen durch die 
Galaxie mit nah an der Lichtgeschwindigkeit. An einem Schiff 
gehangen ein Laser, der Impulse des Lichtes abfeuern kann, und auf dem
anderen, ein Spiegel ein. Der Pilot des ersten Schiffs feuert 
einen Impuls am Spiegel und an den Uhren ab, während es zurück 
reflektiert wird. Ein Taktgeber an Bord der Masse, wie sich 
sehnen Sie, die runde Reise takes.But nehmen jetzt an, daß er dies 
tut, während die Schiffe einen Beobachter auf einem nahe gelegenen 
Planetoid führen. Entsprechend Relativität Theorie sieht 
dieser Beobachter den Impuls, durch Platz mit der gleichen 
Geschwindigkeit genau zu bewegen, die der Pilot -- nämlich, die 
Lichtgeschwindigkeit. Aber er sieht auch den Impuls, zu reisen 
ein längerer Abstand, weil von seiner Perspektive, er die 
Vorwärtsbewegung der Schiffe der Bewegung des Impulses zwischen ihnen
hinzufügen muß. So mißt er einen längeren Zeitabstand für 
die runde Reise, als der Pilot, weil er den Impuls geht weit 
überwacht, ohne irgendwie schneller zu gehen. Dieser Effekt 
wird Zeitausdehnung genannt: wenn ein Beobachter in Bezug auf 
andere umzieht, nimmt jeder wahr, daß die andere Zeit mehr 
slowly.General Restrictions:Images fließt und andere Media in der 
National- Science Foundationmultimedia-Galerie für Gebrauch im Druck 
und im elektronischen Material durch NSF Angestellte, Bauteile der 
Media, Universitätspersonal, Lehrer und die Öffentlichkeit vorhanden
sind. Alle Media in der Galerie sind für persönliches 
bestimmt, pädagogisch und der nonprofit/non-commercial Gebrauch 
only.Images, der zum National Science Foundation, ein Bundesamt 
gutgeschrieben wird, ist im public domain. Die Bilder wurden von
den Angestellten der Vereinigte Staaten Regierung als Teil ihrer 
Dienstpflichten erstellt oder vorbereitet durch Fremdfirmen, wie "für
Miete" für NSF arbeitet. Sie können an NSF-GUTGESCHRIEBENEN 
Bildern und, an Ihrer Rücksicht, Gutschrift NSF frei üben mit einer 
"Höflichkeit: National Science Foundation"Darstellung. 
Zusätzliche Informationen über allgemeinen Verbrauch können 
in den Bedingungen gefunden werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le temps différent aux observateurs se 
déplace-t-il à différentes vitesses ? Pour plus 
d'information, voyez l'année du monde de la transcription de la 
physique 2005 feature.Video : Deux vaisseaux spatiaux voyagent 
ensemble par la galaxie à près de la vitesse de la lumière. 
Monté sur un bateau est un laser qui peut mettre le feu à des 
impulsions de lumière, et de l'autre, un miroir. Le pilote du 
premier bateau met le feu à une impulsion au miroir, et aux montres 
pendant qu'on le reflète en arrière. Une horloge à bord des 
mesures combien de temps le voyage rond takes.But supposent maintenant
qu'il fait ceci pendant que les bateaux passent un observateur sur un 
asteroïde voisin. Selon la théorie de relativité, cet 
observateur voit l'impulsion se déplacer par l'espace exactement à 
la même vitesse que le pilote  -- notamment, la vitesse de la 
lumière. Mais il voit également l'impulsion voyager une plus 
longue distance, parce que de sa perspective, il doit ajouter la 
marche avant des bateaux au mouvement de l'impulsion entre eux. 
Ainsi il mesure un plus long intervalle de temps pour le voyage 
rond que le pilote , parce qu'il observe l'impulsion vont plus loin 
sans aller  plus rapidement. Cet effet s'appelle la dilatation 
de temps : si un observateur se déplace en ce qui concerne des 
autres, chacun perçoit que l'autre temps coule plus de slowly.General
Restrictions:Images et d'autres medias dans la galerie de multimédia 
de National Science Foundation sont disponibles pour l'usage en copie 
et matériel électronique par des employés de NSF, des membres des 
medias, le personnel d'université, des professeurs et le grand 
public. Tous les medias dans la galerie sont destinés pour 
personnel, éducatif et l'utilisation only.Images de 
nonprofit/non-commercial créditée au National Science Foundation, 
une agence fédérale, sont dans le public domain. Les images 
ont été créées par des employés du gouvernement des Etats-Unis en
tant qu'élément de leurs fonctions officielles ou préparées par 
des entrepreneurs comme "travaille pour la location" pour le NSF. 
Vous pouvez librement utiliser les images NSF-CRÉDITÉES et, à
votre discrétion, NSF de degré de solvabilité avec une "courtoisie : 
Notation de National Science Foundation ". Des 
informations supplémentaires sur l'utilisation générale peuvent 
être trouvées en conditions.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O tempo diferente aos observadores está 
movendo-se em velocidades diferentes? Para mais informação, 
veja o ano do mundo do transcript da física 2005 feature.Video: 
Duas naves espaciais estão viajando junto através da galáxia 
perto da velocidade de luz. É montado em um navio um laser que 
possa atear fogo a pulsos de luz, e no outro, um espelho. O 
piloto do primeiro navio ateia fogo a um pulso no espelho, e em 
relógios enquanto se reflete para trás. Um pulso de disparo em
medidas de placa quanto tempo o desengate redondo takes.But supõe 
agora que faz este enquanto os navios estão passando um observador em
um asteroid próximo. De acordo com a teoria do relativity, este
observador vê o pulso mover-se através do espaço exatamente na 
mesma velocidade que o piloto  -- a saber, a velocidade de luz. 
Mas vê também o pulso viajar a uma distância mais longa, 
porque de seu perspective, deve adicionar o movimento para diante dos 
navios ao movimento do pulso entre eles. Assim mede um intervalo
mais longo do tempo para o desengate redondo do que o piloto , porque 
está prestando atenção ao pulso vai mais distante sem ir  mais 
rapidamente. Este efeito é chamado dilation do tempo: se 
um observador se estiver movendo com respeito a outro, cada um percebe
que outro tempo está fluindo mais slowly.General Restrictions:Images 
e outros media na galeria dos multimedia do National Science 
Foundation estão disponíveis para o uso na cópia e no material 
eletrônico por empregados de NSF, por membros dos media, por equipe 
de funcionários da universidade, por professores e pelo público 
geral. Todos os media na galeria são pretendidos para pessoal, 
educacional e o uso only.Images de nonprofit/non-commercial creditado 
ao National Science Foundation, uma agência federal, está no public 
domain. As imagens foram criadas por empregados do governo unido
dos estados como a parte de seus deveres oficiais ou preparadas por 
contratantes como "trabalha para o hire" para o NSF. Você pode 
livremente usar as imagens NSF-CREDITADAS e, na sua discreção, NSF 
do crédito com uma "cortesia: Notação do National Science 
Foundation ". A informação adicional sobre o uso geral pode 
ser encontrada nas circunstâncias.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il tempo differente agli osservatori sta 
muovendosi alle velocità differenti? Per le più informazioni, 
veda l'anno del mondo della trascrizione di fisica 2005 feature.Video:
Due navi spaziali stanno attraversando insieme through la 
galassia vicino alla velocità di luce. È montato su una nave 
un laser che può infornare gli impulsi di luce e d'altro canto, uno 
specchio. Il pilota della prima nave inforna un impulso allo 
specchio ed alle vigilanze mentre è riflesso indietro. Un 
orologio a bordo misura quanto tempo il viaggio rotondo takes.But 
ora suppone che fa questo mentre le navi stanno passando un 
osservatore ad un su un asteroide vicino. Secondo la teoria di 
relatività, questo osservatore vede l'impulso muoversi attraverso lo 
spazio esattamente alla stessa velocità che il pilota -- cioè, la 
velocità di luce. Ma inoltre vede l'impulso viaggiare una 
distanza più lunga, perché dalla sua prospettiva, deve aggiungere il
movimento di andata delle navi al movimento dell'impulso fra loro. 
Così misura un intervallo più lungo di tempo per il viaggio 
rotondo che il pilota, perché sta guardando l'impulso va più lontano
senza andare affatto più velocemente. Questo effetto è 
chiamato la dilatazione di tempo: se un osservatore sta 
muovendosi riguardo ad un altro, ciascuno percepisce che l'altro tempo
sta fluendo più slowly.General Restrictions:Images ed altri media 
nella galleria di multimedia di National Science Foundation sono 
disponibili per uso in stampa e materiale elettronico dagli impiegati 
del NSF, dai membri dei media, dal personale dell'università, dagli 
insegnanti e dal grande pubblico. Tutti i media nella galleria 
sono intesi per personale, educativo e l'uso only.Images di 
nonprofit/non-commercial accreditato al National Science Foundation, 
un ente federale, è nel public domain. Le immagini sono state 
create dagli impiegati del unito Dichiara il governo come 
componente delle loro funzioni ufficiali o preparato dagli appaltatori
come "funziona per noleggio" per il NSF. Potete usare 
liberamente le immagini NSF-ACCREDITATE e, alla vostra discrezione, 
NSF di accreditamento con "una cortesia: Notazione di National 
Science Foundation ". Le informazioni supplementari su uso 
generale possono essere trovate nelle circostanze.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο χρόνος διαφορετικός στους παρατηρητές κινείται με 
τις διαφορετικές ταχύτητες; Για περισσότερες πληροφορίες, 
δείτε το παγκόσμιο έτος τηλεοπτικού αντιγράφου 
χαρακτηριστικών γνωρισμάτων φυσικής το 2005: Δύο 
spaceships ταξιδεύουν μαζί μέσω του γαλαξία στον περίβολο στην
ταχύτητα του φωτός. Επικολλιέται σε ένα σκάφος ένα λέιζερ
που μπορεί να βάλει φωτιά στους σφυγμούς του φωτός, και σε άλλο,
ένας καθρέφτης. Ο πιλότος του πρώτου σκάφους βάζει φωτιά 
σε έναν σφυγμό στον καθρέφτη, και τα ρολόγια όπως απεικονίζεται 
πίσω. Ένα ρολόι στα μέτρα πόσο καιρό πολύ το στρογγυλό 
ταξίδι παίρνει αλλά τώρα υποθέτει ότι κάνει αυτό δεδομένου 
ότι τα σκάφη περνούν έναν παρατηρητή κοντινό asteroid. 
Σύμφωνα με τη θεωρία σχετικότητας, αυτός ο παρατηρητής 
βλέπει το σφυγμό μέσω του διαστήματος με ακριβώς την 
ίδια ταχύτητα ότι ο πιλότος -- συγκεκριμένα, η ταχύτητα του 
φωτός. Αλλά βλέπει επίσης το σφυγμό μια μεγαλύτερη
απόσταση, επειδή από την προοπτική του, πρέπει να προσθέσει την 
μπροστινή κίνηση των σκαφών στην κίνηση του σφυγμού μεταξύ τους.
Έτσι μετρά ένα πιό μακροχρόνιο χρονικό διάστημα για το 
στρογγυλό ταξίδι από ο πιλότος, επειδή προσέχει το σφυγμό 
πηγαίνει μακρύτερα χωρίς να πάει καθόλου γρηγορότερα. 
Αυτή η επίδραση καλείται χρονική διαστολή: εάν ένας
παρατηρητής κινείται όσον αφορά άλλο, κάθε ένας αντιλαμβάνεται
ότι ο άλλος χρόνος είναι ρέοντας πιό αργά γενικό 
Restrictions:Images και άλλα μέσα στην εθνική στοά πολυμέσων 
ιδρύματος επιστήμης είναι διαθέσιμα για τη χρήση στην τυπωμένη 
ύλη και το ηλεκτρονικό υλικό από NSF τους υπαλλήλους, τα μέλη
των μέσων, το πανεπιστημιακό προσωπικό, τους δασκάλους και το 
ευρύ κοινό. Όλα τα μέσα στη στοά προορίζονται για 
προσωπικό, εκπαιδευτικός και οι μη κερδοσκοπικές/μη εμπορικές 
εικόνες χρήσης μόνο που πιστώνονται στο εθνικό ίδρυμα 
επιστήμης, μια ομοσπονδιακή αντιπροσωπεία, είναι στο δημόσιο 
τομέα. Οι εικόνες δημιουργήθηκαν από τους υπαλλήλους της 
Ηνωμένης κυβέρνησης ως τμήμα των επίσημων καθηκόντων τους ή 
προετοιμάστηκαν από τους αναδόχους ως "εργασίες για μίσθωση" για 
NSF. Μπορείτε ελεύθερα να χρησιμοποιήσετε τις 
νσφ-πιστωμένες εικόνες και, κατά την κρίση σας, την πίστωση 
NSF με μια "ευγένεια: Σημείωση εθνικού ιδρύματος 
επιστήμης ". Οι πρόσθετες πληροφορίες για τη γενική χρήση 
μπορούν να βρεθούν στους όρους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿El tiempo diferente a los observadores se está 
moviendo a diversas velocidades? Para más información, vea el 
año del mundo de la transcripción de la física 2005 feature.Video: 
Dos naves espaciales están viajando juntas a través de la 
galaxia cerca de la velocidad de la luz. Se monta en una nave un
laser que puede encender pulsos de luz, y en la otra, un espejo. 
El piloto de la primera nave enciende un pulso en el espejo, y 
los relojes mientras que se refleja detrás. Un reloj a bordo de
medidas cuánto tiempo el viaje redondo takes.But ahora supone que él
hace esto mientras que las naves están pasando a observador en un 
asteroide próximo. Según teoría de la relatividad, este 
observador ve el pulso el moverse a través de espacio exactamente a 
la misma velocidad que lo hace el piloto -- es decir, la velocidad de 
la luz. Pero él también ve el pulso el viajar una larga 
distancia, porque de su perspectiva, él debe agregar el movimiento 
delantero de las naves al movimiento del pulso entre ellas. Él 
mide tan un intervalo más largo del tiempo para el viaje redondo que 
lo hace el piloto, porque él está mirando el pulso va más lejos sin
ir ninguno más rápidamente. Este efecto se llama dilatación 
del tiempo: si un observador se está moviendo con respecto a 
otro, cada uno percibe que está fluyendo el otro tiempo más 
slowly.General Restrictions:Images y otros media en la galería de las
Multimedias del National Science Foundation están disponibles para el
uso en la impresión y el material electrónico de los empleados de 
NSF, de los miembros de los media, del personal de la universidad, de 
los profesores y del público en general. Todos los media en la 
galería se piensan para personal, educativo y el uso only.Images de 
nonprofit/non-commercial acreditado al National Science Foundation, 
una agencia federal, está en el public domain. Las imágenes 
fueron creadas por los empleados del gobierno de Estados Unidos como 
parte de sus deberes oficiales o preparadas por los contratistas como 
"trabaja para el hire" para el NSF. Usted puede utilizar 
libremente las imágenes NSF-ACREDITADAS y, en su discreción, NSF del
crédito con una "cortesía: Notación del National Science 
Foundation ". La información adicional sobre uso general se 
puede encontrar en condiciones.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:NSF
FN:NSF
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>20101533</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>18071053</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/time-dilation-video</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
