<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105918</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105918</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200363</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Advances in Neurotechnology</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Rückt in Neurotechnology vor</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Avance dans Neurotechnology</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Avança em Neurotechnology</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Avanza in Neurotechnology</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πρόοδοι σε Neurotechnology</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Avanza en Neurotechnology</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Our brains control every movement we make. Most of us take for granted our ability to pick up a cup or change the television station. However, for people who have lost a limb or become paralyzed, the inability to do these things means a loss of freedom and independence. This video segment from Greater Boston describes how neuroscientists and bioengineers have teamed up to create a system that allows people who have lost motor functions to control electronic devices through their thoughts alone. Grades 6-12</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Unsere Gehirne steuern jede Bewegung, die wir 
bilden. Die meisten uns Nehmen für bewilligten unsere 
Fähigkeit, ein Cup aufzuheben oder die Fernsehenstation zu ändern. 
Jedoch für Leute, die haben ein Glied verloren oder werden 
gelähmt, bedeutet die Unfähigkeit, diese Sachen zu tun einen 
Verlust der Freiheit und der Unabhängigkeit. Dieses 
videosegment von grösserem Boston beschreibt, wie Neurologen und 
bioengineers teamed erstellen bis ein System haben, das Leute erlaubt,
die Bewegungsfunktionen verloren haben, um elektronische Einheiten 
durch ihre Gedanken alleine zu steuern. Grade 6-12</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Nos cerveaux contrôlent chaque mouvement que nous
faisons. La plupart d'entre nous prise pour a accordé notre 
capacité de prendre une tasse ou de changer la station de 
télévision. Cependant, pour les personnes qui ont détruit un 
membre ou deviennent paralysées, l'incapacité de faire ces choses 
signifie une perte de liberté et d'indépendance. Ce segment 
visuel de plus grand Boston décrit comment les neurologistes et les 
bioengineers ont teamed créent jusqu'à un système qui permet les 
personnes qui ont détruit des fonctions de moteur pour contrôler les
dispositifs électroniques par leurs seules pensées. 
Catégories 6-12</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nossos cérebros controlam cada movimento que nós
fazemos. A maioria de nós tomada para concederam nossa 
abilidade de escolher acima um copo ou de mudar a estação da 
televisão. Entretanto, para os povos que perderam um membro ou 
se tornam paralizados, a inabilidade fazer estas coisas significa uma 
perda da liberdade e da independência. Este segmento video de 
uma Boston mais grande descreve como os neuroscientists e os 
bioengineers têm teamed críam até um sistema que permita os povos 
que perderam funções do motor para controlar dispositivos 
eletrônicos com seus pensamentos sozinho. Classes 6-12</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I nostri cervelli gestiscono ogni movimento che 
facciamo. La maggior parte di noi introito per hanno assegnato 
la nostra capacità di prendere una tazza o di cambiare la stazione 
della televisione. Tuttavia, per la gente che ha perso un membro
o è paralizzata, l'incapacità di fare queste cose significa una 
perdita della libertà e dell'indipendenza. Questo video 
segmento da Boston più grande descrive come i neuroscenziati ed i 
bioengineers hanno teamed fino a creano un sistema che permette la 
gente che ha perso le funzioni del motore per gestire i dispositivi 
elettronici con i loro pensieri da solo. Gradi 6-12</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι εγκέφαλοί μας ελέγχουν κάθε μετακίνηση που 
κάνουμε. Οι περισσότεροι από μας παίρνουν για χορήγησαν τη 
δυνατότητά μας να πάρουμε ένα φλυτζάνι ή να αλλάξουμε τον 
τηλεοπτικό σταθμό. Εντούτοις, για τους ανθρώπους που έχουν 
χάσει ένα άκρο ή έχουν γίνει παραλυμένοι, η ανικανότητα να 
γίνουν αυτά τα πράγματα σημαίνει μια απώλεια ελευθερίας και 
ανεξαρτησίας. Αυτό το τηλεοπτικό τμήμα μνήμης από τη 
μεγαλύτερη Βοστώνη περιγράφει πώς οι επιστήμονες νευρολογίας και
τα bioengineers έχουν συνεργαστεί για να δημιουργήσουν ένα 
σύστημα που επιτρέπει στους ανθρώπους που έχουν χάσει τις 
λειτουργίες μηχανών για να ελέγξουν τις ηλεκτρονικές συσκευές 
μέσω των σκέψεών τους μόνο. Βαθμοί 6-12</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Nuestros cerebros controlan cada movimiento que 
hacemos. La mayoría de nosotros toma para concedieron nuestra 
capacidad de tomar una taza o de cambiar la estación de la 
televisión. Sin embargo, para la gente que ha perdido un 
miembro o se paraliza, la inhabilidad de hacer estas cosas significa 
una pérdida de libertad y de independencia. Este segmento video
de mayor Boston describe cómo los neurólogos y los bioengineers 
tienen teamed hasta crean un sistema que permita a gente que ha 
perdido funciones del motor para controlar los dispositivos 
electrónicos con sus pensamientos solamente. Grados 6-12</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:WGBH EDUCATIONAL FOUNDATION
FN:WGBH EDUCATIONAL FOUNDATION
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200363</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105918</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/advances-in-neurotechnology</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
