<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104352</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104352</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202634</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Ya se; lo que hiciste el verano pasado! Using the Preterite Indicative Tense</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ya SE; niedriges que hiciste EL verano 
pasado! Verwenden des Preterite hinweisenden Tempus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Expert en logiciel de Ya ; bas pasado de 
verano de EL de hiciste de que ! Utilisation du temps indicatif 
de Preterite</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">SE de Ya; pasado baixo do verano do EL do 
hiciste do que! Usando o tempo indicativo de Preterite</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Esperto in informatica di Ya; pasado basso 
di verano di EL del hiciste del que! Usando il tempo indicativo 
di Preterite</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">SE Ya  lo que hiciste pasado 
verano EL! Χρησιμοποίηση του ενδεικτικού χρόνου 
Preterite</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">SE de Ya; ¡pasado bajo del verano del EL del
hiciste del que! Usar el tiempo indicativo de Preterite</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This lesson focuses on the uses of the preterite indicative tense and vocabulary related to travel. The students will read various selections that demonstrate the use of the preterite. and draw pictures to illustrate their understanding. Students will demonstrate their understanding by creating a time line of their life Social Sciences and sharing it with the class. The lesson culminates with students writing a composition entitled, "I know what you did last summer" and presenting it to the class in the target language.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Lektion konzentriert auf die Gebräuche von 
dem preterite hinweisenden Tempus und dem Wortschatz, die auf 
Spielraum in Verbindung gestanden werden. Die Kursteilnehmer 
lesen verschiedene Anwählungen, die den Gebrauch des preterite. 
zeigen und Abbildungen zeichnen, um ihr Verständnis zu 
veranschaulichen. Kursteilnehmer demonstrieren ihr Verständnis,
indem sie eine Zeitzeile ihrer Leben Sozialwissenschaften erstellen 
und sie mit der Kategorie teilen. Die Lektion kulminiert mit den
Kursteilnehmern, die einen erlaubten Aufbau schreiben, "ich weiß, was
Sie letzten Sommer" und das Darstellen es der Kategorie in der 
Zielsprache taten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette leçon se concentre sur les utilisations du 
temps et du vocabulaire indicatifs de preterite liés au voyage. 
Les étudiants liront les diverses sélections qui démontrent 
l'utilisation du preterite. et dessinent des images pour illustrer 
leur arrangement. Les étudiants démontreront leur arrangement
en créant une ligne de temps de leurs sciences sociales de la vie et 
en la partageant avec la classe. La leçon culmine avec des 
étudiants écrivant une composition autorisée, "je sais ce que vous 
avez fait l'été passé" et le présenter à la classe dans la langue
cible.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta lição focaliza nos usos do tempo e do 
vocabulário indicativos do preterite relacionados ao curso. Os 
estudantes lerão as várias seleções que demonstram o uso do 
preterite. e desenham retratos para ilustrar sua compreensão. 
Os estudantes demonstrarão sua compreensão criando uma linha 
do tempo de suas ciências sociais da vida e compartilhando d com a 
classe. A lição culmina com os estudantes que escrevem uma 
composição intitulada, "eu sei o que você fêz o último verão" e 
o apresentar à classe na língua de alvo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa lezione mette a fuoco sugli usi del tempo e
del vocabolario indicativi del preterite relativi alla corsa. 
Gli allievi leggeranno le varie selezioni che dimostrano l'uso 
del preterite. e dissipano le immagini per illustrare la loro 
comprensione. Gli allievi dimostreranno la loro comprensione 
creando una linea di tempo le loro scienze sociali di vita e 
ripartendola con il codice categoria. La lezione culmina con gli
allievi che scrivono una composizione avente diritto, "conosco che 
cosa avete fatto l'ultima estate" e presentarlo al codice categoria 
nella lingua di arrivo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το μάθημα εστιάζει στις χρήσεις του ενδεικτικών 
χρόνου και του λεξιλογίου preterite σχετικών με το ταξίδι. 
Οι σπουδαστές θα διαβάσουν τις διάφορες επιλογές που 
καταδεικνύουν τη χρήση του preterite. και σύρουν τις εικόνες 
για να επεξηγήσουν την κατανόησή τους. Οι σπουδαστές θα 
καταδείξουν την κατανόησή τους με τη δημιουργία μιας χρονικής 
γραμμής κοινωνικών επιστημών ζωής τους και τη διανομή της με την 
κλάση. Το μάθημα καταλήγει με τους σπουδαστές που γράφουν 
μια σύνθεση έχουσα το δικαίωμα, "ξέρω τι το περασμένο καλοκαίρι"
και παρουσιάζοντας την στην κλάση στη γλώσσα στόχο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta lección se centra en las aplicaciones del 
tiempo y del vocabulario indicativos del preterite relacionados con el
recorrido. Los estudiantes leerán las varias selecciones que 
demuestran el uso del preterite. y trazan cuadros para ilustrar su 
comprensión. Los estudiantes demostrarán su comprensión 
creando una línea del tiempo de sus ciencias sociales de la vida y 
compartiéndola con la clase. La lección culmina con los 
estudiantes que escriben una composición titulada, "sé lo que usted 
hizo el verano pasado" y la presentación de él a la clase en la 
lengua objetivo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CAROLINA THOMSON
FN:CAROLINA THOMSON
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:RONDA HATCHER
FN:RONDA HATCHER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202634</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104352</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/ya-se-lo-que-hiciste-el-verano-pasado-using-the-preterite-indicative-tense</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
