<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105383</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105383</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086677</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Not Only Ridiculous, but Dangerous":  Collier's  Objects to Joseph McCarthy's Attacks on the Press</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"nicht nur lächerlich, aber gefährlich": 
Nachrichten des Colliers Joseph McCarthys zu den Angriffen auf 
der Presse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"non seulement ridicule, mais dangereux" : 
Les objets de Collier aux attaques de Joseph McCarthy sur la 
presse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"não somente ridiculous, mas perigoso": 
Objetos do collier aos ataques de Joseph McCarthy na imprensa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"non soltanto ridiculous, ma pericoloso": 
Oggetti del collier agli attacchi del Joseph McCarthy alla 
pressa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Όχι μόνο γελοίος, αλλά επικίνδυνοσ": 
Αντικείμενα ανθρακωρύχου σε Joseph McCarthy's Attacks
στον Τύπο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"no sólo ridículo, sino peligroso": 
Objetos del collier a los ataques de José McCarthy contra la 
prensa</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Anticommunist crusader Senator Joseph R. McCarthy stepped into national prominence on February 9, 1950, when he mounted an attack on President Truman's foreign policy agenda. McCarthy charged that the State Department and its Secretary, Dean Acheson, harbored "traitorous" Communists. McCarthy's apocalyptic rhetoric--he portrayed the Cold War conflict as "a final, all-out battle between communistic atheism and Christianity"--made critics hesitate before challenging him, as his purported lists of Communist conspirators multiplied to include employees in government agencies, the broadcasting and defense industries, universities, the United Nations, and the military. Most of those accused by McCarthy were helpless to defend their ruined reputations and faced loss of employment, damaged careers, and in many cases, broken lives. The following editorial from the popular magazine  Collier's  sharply criticized McCarthy's tactic of trying to scare away advertisers from a magazine that had publicly criticized him.  Collier's  made sure, however, to announce to its readers--some of whom responded in letters included below--their own solemn concern about "Communist infiltration in government."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Anticommunist Kreuzfahrer Senator Joseph R. 
McCarthy trat in nationalen Vorsprung an Februar 9, 1950, als er einen
Angriff auf Präsident Trumans Tagesordnung der fremden Politik 
einhing. McCarthy lud auf, daß die Zustand-Abteilung und seine 
Sekretärin, Dekan Acheson, "traitorous" Kommunisten beherbargen. 
McCarthys apokalyptische Rhetorik -- er schilderte die 
$überschneidung des kalten Krieges als "abschließende, all-out 
Schlacht zwischen communistic Atheismus und Christentum" -- 
gebildete Kritiker zögern vor schwierigem er, als seine behauptete 
Listen der kommunistischen Verschwörer, die multipliziert werden, um 
Angestellte in den Regierungsagenturen zu enthalten, die Sendung und 
Verteidigungindustrien, Universitäten, die Nationen und das Militär.
Die meisten denen, die von McCarthy beschuldigt wurden, waren 
hilflos, ihre ruinierten Renommees zu verteidigen und stellten Verlust
der Beschäftigung gegenüber, beschädigten die Karrieren und in 
vielen Fällen, gebrochen Leben. Der folgende Leitartikel von 
der populären des Zeitschrift Taktik scharf kritisierten McCarthys 
Colliers des Versuchens, weginserenten von einer Zeitschrift zu 
erschrecken, die ihn öffentlich kritisiert hatte. Colliers 
sichergestellt jedoch um zu seinen Lesern zu verkünden -- einiger 
von, reagierten wem in den Zeichen, die unten eingeschlossen waren -- 
ihr eigenes ernstes Interesse über "kommunistische Infiltration in 
der Regierung."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le sénateur Joseph R. McCarthy de croisé 
d'Anticommunist a fait un pas dans la proéminence nationale février 
9, 1950, quand il a monté une attaque à l'ordre du jour de politique
étrangère du Président Truman's. McCarthy a chargé que le 
service d'état et son secrétaire, doyen Acheson, ont hébergé les 
communistes "déloyaux". La rhétorique apocalyptique de 
McCarthy -- il a dépeint le conflit de guerre froide comme "bataille 
entre l'athéisme communisant et christianisme finals et globaux" -- 
les critiques faits hésitent avant provocant il, en tant que sien les
listes prétendues de conspirateurs communistes multipliés pour 
inclure des employés aux organismes gouvernementaux, les industries 
de radiodiffusion et de défense, des universités, les Nations Unies,
et les militaires. Les la plupart de ceux accusées par McCarthy
étaient délaissées pour défendre leurs réputations ruinées et 
ont fait face à la perte d'emploi, ont endommagé des carrières, et 
dans beaucoup de cas, cassées les vies. L'éditorial suivant de
la tactique populaire de McCarthy vivement critiqué de Collier de 
magasin de l'essai d'effrayer les annonceurs partis d'un magasin qui
l'avait publiquement critiqué Collier veillé, cependant, pour 
annoncer à ses lecteurs -- une partie de qui ont répondu dans les 
lettres incluses ci-dessous -- leur propre souci solennel concernant 
"l'infiltration communiste dans le gouvernement."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O senator Joseph R. McCarthy do cruzado de 
Anticommunist pisou no prominence nacional fevereiro em 9, 1950, 
quando montou um ataque na agenda da política extrangeira do 
presidente Truman. McCarthy carregou que o departamento do 
estado e sua secretária, decano Acheson, abrigaram comunistas 
"traitorous". O rhetoric apocalyptic de McCarthy -- portrayed o 
conflito da guerra fria como "uma batalha entre o atheism communistic 
e um christianity finais, all-out" -- críticos feitos hesitate antes 
de challenging ele, como his listas purported dos conspirators 
comunistas multiplicados para incluir empregados em agências de 
governo, as indústrias da transmissão e da defesa, universidades, as
nações unidas, e as forças armadas. A maioria daquelas 
acusadas por McCarthy era helpless defender suas reputações 
arruinadas e enfrentava a perda do emprego, carreiras danificadas, e 
em muitas caixas, quebradas vidas. O seguinte editorial da 
tática de McCarthy agudamente criticado do collier popular do 
compartimento de tentar scare publicitários ausentes de um 
compartimento que o criticasse publicamente. Collier 
certificado, entretanto, anunciar a seus leitores -- algum de quem 
responderam nas letras incluídas abaixo -- seu próprio interesse 
solemn sobre "o infiltration comunista no governo."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il senatore Joseph R. McCarthy del crociato di 
Anticommunist ha fatto un passo nella protuberanza nazionale il 9 
febbraio 1950, quando ha montato un attacco all'ordine del giorno di 
politica straniera del presidente Truman. McCarthy si è 
caricato che State Department e la relativa segretaria, il decano Acheson, 
harbored i comunisti "traitorous". La retorica apocalyptic del 
McCarthy -- ha ritratto il conflitto di guerra fredda come "una 
battaglia fra atheism communistic e christianity finali e con tutti i mezzi a disposizione"
-- critici fatti esita prima di challenging lui, come sua liste 
pretese dei conspirators comunisti moltiplicati per includere gli 
impiegati negli enti governativi, le industrie della difesa e di 
broadcasting, università, le Nazioni Unite ed i militari. La 
maggior parte di quelli accusati da McCarthy erano helpless difendere 
le loro reputazioni rovinate ed hanno affrontato la perdita di 
occupazione, hanno danneggiato le carriere ed in molti casi, rotte 
vite. Il seguente editoriale dalla tattica del McCarthy 
acutamente criticato del collier popolare dello scomparto di provare a
spaventare i advertisers assenti da uno scomparto che lo aveva 
criticato pubblicamente. Collier assicurato, tuttavia, per 
annunciare ai relativi lettori -- alcuno di chi hanno risposto nelle 
lettere incluse sotto -- la loro propria preoccupazione solenne circa 
"infiltrazione comunista nel governo."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο αντικομμουνιστής σταυροφόρος γερουσιαστής Joseph 
R. McCarthy περπάτησε στην εθνική προεξοχή στις 9 
Φεβρουαρίου ..1950, όταν επικόλλησε μια επίθεση στην ημερήσια 
διάταξη εξωτερικής πολιτικής Προέδρου Truman's. McCarthy χρέωσε ότι το υπουργείο εξωτερικών και ο γραμματέας 
του, Dean Acheson, οι "προδοτικοί" κομμουνιστές. McCarthy's η αποκαλυπτική ρητορική -- απεικόνισε τη σύγκρουση 
ψυχρού πολέμου ως "τελική, ενθουσιώδη μάχη μεταξύ του 
κομμουνιστικού αθεϊσμού και χριστιανισμό" -- γίνονται κριτικοί 
διστάζει πρίν προκαλεί τον, όπως ισχυρισμένους καταλόγους 
κομμουνιστικών συνωμοτών του που πολλαπλασιάζονται για να 
περιλάβουν τους υπαλλήλους στις κυβερνητικές αντιπροσωπείες, τις 
βιομηχανίες ραδιοφωνικής αναμετάδοσης και υπεράσπισης, τα 
πανεπιστήμια, τα Ηνωμένα Έθνη, και τους στρατιωτικούς. Οι 
περισσότεροι από εκείνους που κατηγορήθηκαν από McCarthy ήταν
ανίσχυροι για να υπερασπίσουν τις φήμες τους και αντιμετώπισαν την
απώλεια απασχόλησης, έβλαψαν τις σταδιοδρομίες, και σε πολλές 
περιπτώσεις, που έσπασαν ζωές. Το ακόλουθο κύριο άρθρο 
από την επικριμένη του δημοφιλούς ανθρακωρύχου περιοδικών 
αισθητά τακτική McCarthy's της προσπάθειας να φοβηθούν μακριά 
οι δηαφημιστές από ένα περιοδικό που τον είχε επικρίνει 
δημόσια. Ανθρακωρύχου που σιγουρεύεται, εντούτοις, για να 
αναγγείλει στους αναγνώστες του -- μερικοί των οποίων αποκρίθηκε 
στις επιστολές περιέλαβε κατωτέρω -- η σοβαρή ανησυχία τους για 
τη "κομμουνιστική διήθηση στην κυβέρνηση."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Senador José R. McCarthy del cruzado de 
Anticommunist caminó en prominencia nacional 9 de febrero de 1950,
cuando él montó un ataque contra agenda de la política no nativa de
presidente Truman. McCarthy cargó que el departamento y su 
secretaria, decano Acheson del estado, abrigaran comunistas 
"traidores". El retórico apocalíptico de McCarthy -- él 
retrató el conflicto de la guerra fría como "una batalla entre el 
ateismo comunista y cristianismo finales, totales" -- los 
críticos hechos vacila antes de desafiador él, como el suyo las 
listas pretendidas de los conspirators comunistas multiplicados para 
incluir a empleados en agencias de estatal, las industrias de la 
difusión y de la defensa, las universidades, los Naciones Unidas, y 
los militares. La mayoría de ésos acusados por McCarthy eran 
desamparados defender sus reputaciones arruinadas e hicieron frente a 
la pérdida de empleo, dañaron las carreras, y en muchos casos, rotas
las vidas. El editorial siguiente de la táctica de McCarthy 
sostenidamente criticado del collier popular del compartimiento de 
intentar asustar a publicistas ausentes de un compartimiento que lo 
había criticado público. Collier cerciorado de, sin embargo, 
para anunciar a sus programas de lectura -- algunos de quién 
respondieron en las cartas incluidas abajo -- su propia preocupación 
solemne por la "infiltración comunista en el gobierno."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086677</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105383</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/not-only-ridiculous-but-dangerous-colliers-objects-to-joseph-mccarthys-attacks-on-the-press</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
