<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106553</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106553</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203212</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Human Health and Ecological Risk</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschliche Gesundheit und ökologische Gefahr</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Santé humaine et risque écologique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Saúde humana e risco ecological</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Salute umana e rischio ecologico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρώπινη υγεία και οικολογικός κίνδυνος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Salud humana y riesgo ecológico</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This EPA site provides information about health and safety issues concerning Superfund sites. It features links to information about the hazards related to contaminant exposure, emergency response programs, guidelines for pollution prevention, safety tips for environmental cleanup, risk assessment, reporting hazardous substance releases, and other environmental and human health related sites.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese EPA Site liefert Informationen über 
Gesundheit und Sicherheit die Ausgaben hinsichtlich sind der Superfund
Sites. Sie kennzeichnet Links zu den Informationen über die 
Gefahren, die auf Verschmutzerberührung, 
Dringlichkeitswarteprogramme, Korrekturlinien für Verunreinigung 
Verhinderung, Sicherheit Spitzen für Klimareinigung, 
Risikobeurteilung in Verbindung gestanden werden und berichtet 
gefährliche Substanzfreigaben und über andere Klima- und menschliche
Gesundheit in Verbindung gestandene Sites.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site d'EPA fournit des informations au sujet 
des issues de salubrité et de sûreté au sujet des sites de 
Superfund. Il comporte des liens aux informations sur les 
risques liés à l'exposition de contaminant, les programmes de 
réponse de secours, les directives pour l'empêchement de pollution, 
extrémités de sûreté pour le nettoyage environnemental, 
évaluation des risques, enregistrant les versions dangereuses de 
substance, et d'autres sites associés de santé environnementale et 
humaine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local de EPA fornece a informação sobre as 
edições de saúde e de segurança a respeito dos locais de 
Superfund. Caracteriza as ligações à informação sobre os 
perigos relacionados à exposição do contaminador, programas da 
resposta da emergência, guidelines para a prevenção da poluição, 
pontas de segurança para o cleanup ambiental, avaliação de risco, 
relatando liberações perigosas da substância, e outros locais 
relacionados da saúde ambiental e humana.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo di EPA fornisce le informazioni sulle
edizioni di sanità e sicurezza riguardo ai luoghi di Superfund. 
Caratterizza i collegamenti alle informazioni sui rischi 
relativi ad esposizione dell'agente inquinante, programmi di risposta 
di emergenza, guida di riferimento per la prevenzione di inquinamento,
punte di sicurezza per pulizia ambientale, valutazione di rischio, 
segnalando le versioni pericolose della sostanza ed altri luoghi 
riferiti di salute ambientale ed umana.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή EPA παρέχει τις πληροφορίες για τα 
ζητήματα υγείας και ασφάλειας σχετικά με τις περιοχές 
Superfund. Χαρακτηρίζει τις συνδέσεις με τις πληροφορίες 
για τους κινδύνους σχετικούς με την έκθεση μολυσματικών 
παραγόντων, προγράμματα απάντησης έκτακτης ανάγκης, οδηγίες για 
την πρόληψη ρύπανσης, άκρες ασφάλειας για τον περιβαλλοντικό 
καθαρισμό, αξιολόγηση του κινδύνου, που εκθέτει τις επικίνδυνες 
εκδόσεις ουσιών, και άλλες περιβαλλοντικές και ανθρώπινες 
σχετικές με την υγεία περιοχές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio de EPA proporciona a la información 
sobre ediciones de salud y de seguridad referentes a los sitios de 
Superfund. Ofrece conexiones a la información sobre los 
peligros relacionados con la exposición del contaminante, programas 
de la respuesta de la emergencia, guías de consulta para la 
prevención de la contaminación, extremidades de seguridad para la 
limpieza ambiental, gravamen de riesgo, señalando desbloquear 
peligrosos de la sustancia, y otros sitios relacionados de la salud 
ambiental y humana.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203212</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106553</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/human-health-and-ecological-risk</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
