<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107524</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107524</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086117</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Elevate Us to a Free and Independent Position": William J. Brown Looks for Work, 1831</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"erhöhen Sie uns in eine freie und unabhängige 
Position": William J. Brown sucht nach Arbeit, 1831</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"élevez-nous dans une position libre et 
indépendante" : William J. Brown recherche le travail, 1831</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"elevate nos a uma posição livre e 
independente": William J. Marrom procura o trabalho, 1831</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"elevili ad una posizione libera ed indipendente":
William J. Brown cerca il lavoro, 1831</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Μας ανυψώστε σε μια ελεύθερη και ανεξάρτητη θέση": 
Θ*Ωηλληαμ J. Brown ψάχνει την εργασία, 1831</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"elévenos a una posición libre y Independiente": 
Guillermo J. Brown busca el trabajo, 1831</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">After the War for Independence, the northern states slowly abolished slavery. However, the rising population of northern free blacks still faced significant obstacles in their struggle to achieve economic and social liberty. African Americans in New England remained concentrated in the seaport cities, often clustered in low-paying jobs. Successful entrepreneurs and skilled traders still faced discrimination as well as opposition from white wageworkers. William J. Brown had been born in 1814 into a free black family in Providence, Rhode Island. His father was a sailor and laborer and his mother was the daughter of an African-American slave and Narragansett Indian woman. William became an artisan and leader in Providence's African-American community. But he described his uphill struggle to find work and obtain respect from his fellow New Englanders in his autobiography  Life of William J. Brown of Providence  (1883).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nach dem Krieg für Unabhängigkeit, schufen die 
Nordzustände langsam Sklaverei ab. Jedoch stellte die steigende
Bevölkerung der freien Nordschwarzer noch bedeutende Hindernisse in 
ihrem Kampf gegenüber, ökonomische und Sozialfreiheit zu erzielen. 
Afrikanische Amerikaner in Neu-England blieben in den 
Seehafenstädte konzentriert, häufig gebündelt in niedrig-zahlenden 
Jobs. Erfolgreiche Unternehmer und erfahrene Händler stellten 
noch Unterscheidung sowie Opposition von den weißen Wageworkers 
gegenüber. William J. Brown war 1814 in eine freie schwarze 
Familie in der Vorsehung, Rhode-Insel geboren gewesen. Sein 
Vater war ein Seemann und Hilfsarbeiter und seine Mutter waren die 
Tochter eines Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Sklaven und der Narragansett 
Inderfrau. William stand einem Handwerker und einem Führer in 
der Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Gemeinschaft der Vorsehung. Aber 
er beschrieb seins ansteigender Kampf, um Arbeit zu finden und Respekt
von seinen Gefährteneuen Engländern in seiner Autobiographie 
Lebensdauer von William J. Brown der Vorsehung (1883) zu erreichen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Après la guerre pour l'indépendance, les états 
nordiques ont lentement supprimé l'esclavage. Cependant, la 
population se levante des noirs libres nordiques faisait face toujours
à des obstacles significatifs dans leur lutte de réaliser la 
liberté économique et sociale. Les Américains africains en 
Nouvelle Angleterre sont restés concentrés dans les villes de port 
maritime, souvent groupées dans les travaux depaiement. Les 
entrepreneurs réussis et les commerçants habiles faisaient face 
toujours à la discrimination aussi bien que l'opposition des 
salariés blancs. William J. Brown avait été né en 1814 dans 
une famille noire libre dans la providence, île de Rhode. Son 
père était un marin et le travailleur et sa mère étaient la fille 
d'une femme afro-américaine slave et de Narragansett d'Indien. 
William est allé bien à un artisan et à une amorce dans la 
communauté afro-américaine de la providence. Mais il a décrit le 
sien lutte ascendante pour trouver le travail et pour obtenir le 
respect de ses nouveaux Anglais de camarade dans son vie 
d'autobiographie de William J. Brown de la providence (1883).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Após a guerra para a independência, os estados 
do norte abolished lentamente o slavery. Entretanto, a 
população levantando-se de pretos livres do norte enfrentou ainda 
obstáculos significativos em seu esforço conseguir a liberdade 
econômica e social. Os americanos africanos em Nova Inglaterra 
remanesceram concentrados nas cidades do seaport, aglomeradas 
frequentemente em trabalhos baixo-pagando. Os empreendedores bem
sucedidos e os comerciantes hábeis enfrentaram ainda a 
discriminação as.well.as a oposição dos wageworkers brancos. 
William J. Marrom tinha sido nascido em 1814 em uma família 
preta livre no providence, console de Rhode. Seu pai era um 
sailor e o laborer e sua matriz eram a filha de um escravo e de uma 
mulher Africano-Americanos do indian de Narragansett. William 
assentou bem em um artisan e em um líder na comunidade 
Africano-Americana do providence. Mas descreveu his esforço 
uphill para encontrar o trabalho e obter o respeito de seus englanders
novos do companheiro em sua vida do autobiography de William J. Marrom
do providence (1883).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dopo la guerra per indipendenza, il nordico 
dichiara lo slavery lentamente abolito. Tuttavia, la 
popolazione aumentante dei neri liberi nordici ancora ha affrontato 
gli ostacoli significativi nella loro lotta realizzare la libertà 
economica e sociale. Gli Americani africani in Nuova Inghilterra
sono rimasto concentrati nelle città del porto marittimo, ragruppate 
spesso nei lavori dipagamento. Gli imprenditori riusciti ed in 
commercianti esperti ancora hanno affrontato la distinzione così come
opposizione dai wageworkers bianchi. William J. Brown era stato 
nato in 1814 in una famiglia nera libera nel providence, Rhode-isola. 
Il suo padre era un marinaio ed il laborer e la sua madre erano 
la figlia di uno schiavo e di una donna Africano-Americani 
dell'indiano di Narragansett. William ha stato bene ad un 
artigianale e ad un capo nella Comunità Africano-Americana del
providence. Ma ha descritto suo lotta in salita per trovare il 
lavoro ed ottenere il rispetto dai suoi nuovi englanders del collega 
nella sua durata del autobiography di William J. Brown di providence 
(1883).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μετά από τον πόλεμο για την ανεξαρτησία, τα βόρεια 
κράτη κατάργησαν αργά τη σκλαβιά. Εντούτοις, ο αυξανόμενος
πληθυσμός των βόρειων ελεύθερων Μαύρων αντιμετώπισε ακόμα τα 
σημαντικά εμπόδια στην προσπάθειά τους να επιτύχουν την 
οικονομική και κοινωνική ελευθερία. Αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί 
στη Νέα Αγγλία παρέμειναν συγκεντρωμένοι στις πόλεις θαλάσσιων 
λιμένων, που συγκεντρώθηκαν συχνά στην χαμηλός-πληρωμή των 
εργασιών. Οι επιτυχείς επιχειρηματίες και οι ειδικευμένοι 
έμποροι αντιμετώπισαν ακόμα τη διάκριση καθώς επίσης και την 
αντίθεση από τα άσπρα wageworkers. Θ*Ωηλληαμ J. 
Brown είχε γεννηθεί το 1814 σε μια ελεύθερη οικογένεια 
μαύρων στην πρόνοια, Ρόδος. Ο πατέρας του ήταν ναυτικός 
και laborer και η μητέρα του ήταν η κόρη ενός 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικού σκλάβου και μιας ινδικής γυναίκας 
Narragansett. Θ*Ωηλληαμ έγινε ένας χειροτεχνικός και 
ηγέτης στην αφρικανικός-αμερικανική κοινότητα της πρόνοιας. 
Αλλά περιέγραψε την ανηφορική προσπάθειά του να βρεί την 
εργασία και να λάβει το σεβασμό από το συντροφικό νέο 
Englanders του στη ζωή αυτοβιογραφιών William του J. 
Brown της πρόνοιας (1883).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Después de la guerra para la independencia, los 
estados norteños suprimieron lentamente esclavitud. Sin 
embargo, la población de levantamiento de negros libres norteños 
todavía hizo frente a obstáculos significativos en su lucha de 
alcanzar libertad económica y social. Los americanos africanos 
en Nueva Inglaterra seguían concentrados en las ciudades del puerto, 
arracimadas a menudo en trabajos bajo-que pagaban. Los 
empresarios acertados y los comerciantes expertos todavía hicieron 
frente a la discriminación así como la oposición de los wageworkers
blancos. Guillermo J. Brown había sido nato en 1814 en una 
familia negra libre en providence, Rhode-isla. Su padre era 
marinero y el laborer y su madre eran la hija de un esclavo y de una 
mujer Africano-Americanos del indio de Narragansett. Guillermo 
sintió bien a un artesano y a un arranque de cinta en la comunidad 
Africano-Americana del providence. Pero él describió el suyo 
lucha ascendente para encontrar el trabajo y para obtener respecto de 
sus nuevos ingleses del compañero en su vida de la autobiografía de 
Guillermo J. Brown del providence (1883).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086117</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107524</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/elevate-us-to-a-free-and-independent-position-william-j-brown-looks-for-work-1831</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
