<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105319</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105319</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206588</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Inside the Cell</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Innerhalb der Zelle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">À l'intérieur de la cellule</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Dentro da pilha</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">All'interno della cellula</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μέσα στο κύτταρο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Dentro de la célula</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">explores the smallest form of life: the cell. Discover what's happening inside your body. See basic structures that let your cells accomplish their tasks. Learn about functions shared by virtually all cells: making fuel and proteins, transporting materials, and disposing of wastes. Find out how cells specialize to get their unique jobs done -- and how cells reproduce, age, and die.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erforscht das kleinste Formular des Lebens: 
die Zelle. Entdecken Sie, was innerhalb Ihres Körpers 
geschieht. Sehen Sie grundlegende Strukturen, die Ihre Zellen 
ihre Aufgaben vollenden lassen. Erlernen Sie über die 
Funktionen, die durch praktisch alle Zellen geteilt werden: 
Kraftstoff und Proteine bilden, Materialien und das Entledigen 
der Vergeudungen transportierend. Finden Sie, wie Zellen sich 
spezialisieren, um ihre eindeutigen Arbeiten zu erhalten erledigt -- 
heraus und wie Zellen reproduzieren, altern und sterben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">explore la plus petite forme de la vie : la 
cellule. Découvrez ce qui se produit à l'intérieur de votre 
corps. Voyez que structures de base qui laissent vos cellules 
accomplir le leur charge. Renseignez-vous sur des 
fonctions partagées par pratiquement toutes les cellules : 
faisant le carburant et des protéines, transportant des 
matériaux, et avoir des pertes. Découvrez comment les cellules
se spécialisent pour obtenir leurs seuls travaux faits -- et comment 
les cellules se reproduisent, vieillissent, et meurent.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">explora o formulário o menor da vida: a 
pilha. Descubra o que está acontecendo dentro de seu corpo. 
Veja as estruturas básicas que deixam suas pilhas realizar suas
tarefas. Aprenda sobre as funções compartilhadas por 
virtualmente todas as pilhas: fazendo o combustível e as 
proteínas, transportando materiais, e dispôr de desperdícios. 
Encontre para fora como as pilhas se especializam para começar 
seus trabalhos originais feitos -- e como as pilhas reproduzem, 
envelhecem, e morrem.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esplora la più piccola forma di vita: la 
cellula. Scopra che cosa sta accadendo all'interno del vostro 
corpo. Veda le strutture di base che lasciano le vostre cellule 
compire le loro mansioni. Impari circa le funzioni compartecipi 
da virtualmente tutte le cellule: facendo combustibile e le 
proteine, trasportando i materiali ed avere gli sprechi. Scopra 
come le cellule si specializzano per ottenere i loro lavori unici 
fatti -- e come le cellule riproducono, invecchiano e muoiono.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ερευνά τη μικρότερη μορφή της ζωής: το κύτταρο.
Ανακαλύψτε τι να συμβεί μέσα στο σώμα σας. 
Δείτε τις βασικές δομές που αφήνουν τα κύτταρά 
σας να ολοκληρώσουν τις στοιχειώδεις εργασίες τους. Μάθετε 
για τις λειτουργίες κοινές σε ουσιαστικά όλα τα κύτταρα: η 
παραγωγή τροφοδοτεί με καύσιμα και πρωτεϊ'νες, μεταφορά των 
υλικών, και διάθεση των αποβλήτων. Ανακαλύψτε πώς τα 
κύτταρα ειδικεύονται για να πάρουν τις μοναδικές εργασίες τους 
γίνοντες -- και πώς τα κύτταρα αναπαράγουν, γερνούν, και κύβος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">explora la forma más pequeña de vida: la 
célula. Descubra qué está sucediendo dentro de su cuerpo. 
Vea las estructuras básicas que dejan sus células lograr sus 
tareas. Aprenda sobre las funciones compartidas por virtualmente
todas las células: haciendo el combustible y las proteínas, 
transportando los materiales, y disponer de basuras. Descubra 
cómo las células se especializan para conseguir sus trabajos únicos
hechos -- y cómo las células se reproducen, envejecen, y mueren.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206588</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105319</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/inside-the-cell</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
