<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106617</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106617</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086667</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"No One Ever Hurried During 'Cake-time": Work and Leisure a New York Shipyard, 1835</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Niemand Beeilten Überhaupt Sich Während ' Der 
Zusammenbacken-Zeit": Arbeit und Freizeit eine neue York Werft, 
1835</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Personne Ne se sont jamais dépêchés Pendant Le
'Durcir-temps" : Travail et loisirs un chantier naval de New 
York, 1835</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Ninguém Apressaram-se Sempre Durante ' O 
Endureç-tempo": Trabalho e lazer um shipyard de New York, 1835</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Nessuno Hanno affrettato Mai Durante 'Il 
Raggrum-tempo": Lavoro e svago un cantiere navale de New York, 
1835</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Κανένας πάντα εσπευσμένος κατά τη διάρκεια" του 
κέικ-χρόνου ": Εργασία και ελεύθερος χρόνος ένα ναυπηγείο
της Νέας Υόρκης, 1835</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Nadie Se apresuraron Siempre Durante ' 
Apelmazar-tiempo": Trabajo y ocio un astillero de Nueva York, 
1835</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Early nineteenth-century workers followed traditional workshop practices with a limited pace and intensity to their labor. Breaks for drink and food punctuated the workday in these recollections of a ship's captain of a New York City shipyard from 1835 (published in George McNeill's late nineteenth-century history of the labor movement). However, employers challenged these customs with the goal of obtaining greater efficiency and profit. Mechanics and artisans responded collectively by organized strikes or "turnouts." Despite the obstacles of planning these early collective actions, the ship carpenters 'strike for a ten-hour day proved successful in the mid-1830s. Even as new manufacturing complexes rose in Lowell and other factory towns, work patterns remained irregular in many trades; some craftsmen faced a growing division of labor and accompanying loss of independence. Irregular hours and unemployment always loomed, while cold winters would thrust many of those working outdoors out of work for the harshest season.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Frühe 19.-Jahrhundert Arbeiter folgten 
traditioneller Werkstattpraxis mit einem begrenzten Schritt und einer 
Intensität zu ihrer Arbeit. Brüche für Getränk und Nahrung 
interpunktierten den Arbeitstag in diesen Erinnerungen des Kapitäns 
eines Schiffs einer New York City Werft von 1835 (veröffentlicht 
George McNeills in der späten 19.-Jahrhundert Geschichte der 
Arbeiterbewegung). Jedoch forderten Arbeitgeber diese 
Gewohnheiten mit dem Ziel des Erreichens der grösseren 
Leistungsfähigkeit und des Profites heraus. Mechaniker und 
Handwerker reagierten zusammen durch organisierte Schläge oder 
"Beteiligungen." Trotz der Hindernisse der Planung dieser 
frühen Kollektivtätigkeiten, schlagen die Schiff Tischler ' für ein
Zehnstundentag nachgewiesenes erfolgreiches im mid-1830s an. 
Selbst als neue herstellenkomplexe in Lowell und in andere 
Fabrikstädte stiegen, blieben Arbeit Muster in vielem Handel 
unregelmäßig; einige Handwerker stellten eine wachsende 
Arbeitsteilung und Begleitenverlust von Unabhängigkeit gegenüber. 
Unregelmäßige Stunden und Arbeitslosigkeit tauchten immer auf,
während kalte Winter viele von denen stoßen würden, die draußen 
aus Arbeit während der rauhesten Jahreszeit heraus arbeiten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les premiers ouvriers de dix-neuvième-siècle ont
suivi des pratiques en matière traditionnelles d'atelier avec un pas 
et une intensité limités à leur travail. Les ruptures pour la
boisson et la nourriture ont ponctué le jour ouvrable dans ces 
souvenirs du capitaine d'un bateau d'un chantier naval de New York 
City de 1835 (édité dans l'histoire en retard de 
dix-neuvième-siècle de George McNeill du mouvement de travail). 
Cependant, les employeurs ont défié ces coutumes avec le but 
d'obtenir une plus grande efficacité et un bénéfice. La 
mécanique et les artisans ont répondu collectivement par des grèves
organisées ou des "assemblées." En dépit des obstacles de 
projeter ces actions collectives tôt, les charpentiers de bateau 
'frappent pour un réussi prouvé par jour de dix heures dans le 
mid-1830s. Même pendant que les nouveaux complexes de 
fabrication montaient à Lowell et d'autres villes d'usine, les 
configurations de travail sont demeurées irrégulières dans beaucoup
de commerces ; quelques artisans ont fait face à une division 
de travail croissante et perte d'accompagnement de l'indépendance. 
Les heures et le chômage irréguliers ont toujours apparu 
indistinctement, alors que les hivers froids pousseraient beaucoup de 
ceux fonctionnant dehors sans emploi pour la saison la plus dure.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os trabalhadores adiantados de décimo-século 
seguiram práticas tradicionais da oficina com um ritmo e uma 
intensidade limitados a seu trabalho. As rupturas para a bebida 
e o alimento punctuated o workday nestes recollections do capitão de 
um navio de um shipyard de New York City de 1835 (publicado em um 
history atrasado de décimo-século de George McNeill do movimento 
labor). Entretanto, os empregadores desafiaram estes costumes 
com o objetivo de obter uma eficiência mais grande e um lucro. 
Os mecânicos e os artisans responderam coletivamente por 
batidas organizadas ou por "turnouts." Apesar dos obstáculos de
planear estas ações coletivas adiantadas, os carpinteiros do navio '
golpeiam para dia ten-hour um bem sucedido provado no mid-1830s. 
Mesmo enquanto os complexos manufaturando novos se levantaram em
Lowell e em outras cidades da fábrica, os testes padrões de trabalho
remanesceram irregulares em muitos comércios; alguns artesãos 
enfrentaram uma divisão de trabalho crescente e perda acompanhar da 
independência. As horas e o desemprego irregulares apareceram 
sempre, quando os invernos frios empurrariam muita daqueles que 
trabalham ao ar livre fora do trabalho para a estação a mais 
áspera.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli operai in anticipo di diciannovesimo-secolo 
hanno seguito le pratiche tradizionali del workshop con un passo e 
un'intensità limitati al loro lavoro. Le rotture per la 
bevanda e l'alimento hanno punteggiato il workday in questi ricordi 
del capitano della nave di un cantiere navale de New York City da 1835
(pubblicato nella storia ritardata di diciannovesimo-secolo di George 
McNeill del movimento di lavoro). Tuttavia, i datori di lavoro
hanno sfidato queste abitudini con l'obiettivo di ottenere il 
risparmio di temi più grande ed il profitto. I meccanici e gli 
artigianale hanno risposto collettivamente dai colpi organizzati o 
"dalle affluenze." Malgrado gli ostacoli di progettazione delle 
queste azioni collettive iniziali, i carpentieri della nave 
'colpiscono per un riuscito provato giorno di dieci ore nel mid-1830s.
Proprio mentre i nuovi complessi di produzione sono aumentato a 
Lowell ed altre città della fabbrica, gli schemi di lavoro sono 
rimasto irregolari in molti commerci; alcuni artigiani hanno 
affrontato una divisione crescente del lavoro e perdita 
accompagnare di indipendenza. Le ore e la disoccupazione 
irregolari hanno apparso in lontananza sempre, mentre gli inverni 
freddi spingerebbero molti di quelli che funzionano all'aperto senza 
lavoro per la stagione più dura.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι πρώτοι εργαζόμενοι δέκατος-αιώνα ακολούθησαν τις 
παραδοσιακές πρακτικές εργαστηρίων με έναν περιορισμένο ρυθμό 
και την ένταση στην εργασία τους. Τα σπασίματα για το ποτό 
και τα τρόφιμα έβαλαν σημεία στίξης την εργάσιμη ημέρα σε αυτές
τις αναμνήσεις του καπετάνιου ενός σκάφους ενός ναυπηγείου 
πόλεων της Νέας Υόρκης από 1835 (δημοσιευμένος στην πρόσφατη 
ιστορία δέκατος-αιώνα George McNeill's της μετακίνησης 
εργασίας). Εντούτοις, οι εργοδότες προκάλεσαν αυτό το 
τελωνείο με το στόχο τη μεγαλύτερα αποδοτικότητα και το κέρδος. 
Μηχανικοί και artisans αποκριμένος συλλογικά από τις 
οργανωμένες απεργίες ή "τις συγκεντρώσεις." Παρά τα 
εμπόδια του προγραμματισμού αυτών των πρόωρων συλλογικών 
ενεργειών, οι ξυλουργοί σκαφών "χτυπούν για μια δέκα ωρών ημέρα
αποδεδειγμένη επιτυχή στα μέσα της 1830s. Ακόμη και ως 
νέα κατασκευή τα συγκροτήματα αυξήθηκαν στο Lowell και άλλες 
πόλεις εργοστασίων, πρότυπα εργασίας παρέμειναν ανώμαλες σε 
πολλά εμπόρια  μερικοί βιοτέχνες απασχόλησαν ένα 
αυξανόμενο τμήμα της εργασίας και τη συνοδευτική απώλεια 
ανεξαρτησίας. Οι ακανόνιστες ώρες και η ανεργία 
εμφανίστηκαν πάντα, ενώ οι κρύοι χειμώνες θα ωθούσαν πολλές 
από εκείνη την εργασία υπαίθρια άνεργη για την πιό σκληρή 
εποχή.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los trabajadores tempranos del diecinueveavo-siglo
siguieron prácticas tradicionales del taller con un paso y una 
intensidad limitados a su trabajo. Las roturas para la bebida y 
el alimento puntuaron el día laborable en estos recuerdos del 
capitán de una nave de un astillero de New York City a partir de 1835
(publicado en la última historia del diecinueveavo-siglo de George 
McNeill del movimiento de trabajo). Sin embargo, los patrones 
desafiaron estos costumbres con la meta de obtener mayor eficacia y 
beneficio. Los mecánicos y los artesanos respondieron 
colectivamente por huelgas ordenadas o "séquitos." A pesar de 
los obstáculos de planear estas acciones colectivas tempranas, los 
carpinteros de la nave ' pulso para un acertado probada día de diez 
horas en el mid-1830s. Incluso mientras que los nuevos complejos
de fabricación se levantaron en Lowell y otras ciudades de la 
fábrica, los modelos de trabajo seguían siendo irregulares en muchos
comercios; algunos artesanos hicieron frente a una división del
trabajo cada vez mayor y pérdida del acompañamiento de 
independencia. Las horas y el desempleo irregulares asomaron 
siempre, mientras que los inviernos fríos empujarían muchos de ésos
que trabajan al aire libre sin trabajo para la estación más áspera.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086667</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106617</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/no-one-ever-hurried-during-cake-time-work-and-leisure-a-new-york-shipyard-1835</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
