<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108122</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108122</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207178</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Figuring Somepin 'Bout the Great Depression</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Berechnen Somepin ' Zeitraum der große Tiefstand</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Accès figure Somepin 'la grande dépression</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Figurando bout de Somepin ' o depression grande</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Calcolando periodo di Somepin 'la depressione 
grande</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Λογαριάζοντας "περίοδος Somepin η μεγάλη οικονομική
κρίση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Calculando combate de Somepin ' la gran 
depresión</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a lesson in which students examine songs, interviews, and photos of migrant farm workers in California during the Great Depression and then create a scrapbook from the point of view of a migrant worker. Students use photos and recordings of migrant workers to create captions, letters, and songs. This lesson can be particularly useful when students are learning about the Great Depression or reading The Grapes of Wrath.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist eine Lektion, in der Kursteilnehmer Liede, 
Interviews und Fotos der Wander- Landarbeiter in Kalifornien während 
des großen Tiefstands überprüfen und dann einen Scrapbook vom 
Gesichtspunkt eines Gastarbeiters herstellen. 
Kursteilnehmergebrauchfotos und Aufnahmen der Gastarbeiter, zum 
von von Untertitelen, von von Zeichen und von von Lieden zu erstellen.
Diese Lektion kann besonders nützlich sein, wenn Kursteilnehmer
über den großen Tiefstand erlernen oder die Trauben des 
Zorns lesen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est une leçon dans laquelle les étudiants 
examinent des chansons, des entrevues, et des photos des ouvriers 
migrateurs de ferme en Californie pendant la grande dépression et 
puis créent un album du point de vue d'un travailleur migrant. 
Photos d'utilisation d'étudiants et enregistrements des 
travailleurs migrants pour créer des légendes, des lettres, et des 
chansons. Cette leçon peut être particulièrement utile quand 
les étudiants se renseignent sur la grande dépression ou lisent les 
raisins de la colère.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é uma lição em que os estudantes examinam 
canções, entrevistas, e fotos de trabalhadores de fazenda emigrantes
em Califórnia durante o depression grande e críam então um 
scrapbook do ponto da opinião um trabalhador emigrante. Fotos 
do uso dos estudantes e gravações dos trabalhadores emigrantes para 
criar subtítulos, letras, e canções. Esta lição pode ser 
particularmente útil quando os estudantes estão aprendendo sobre o 
depression grande ou estão lendo as uvas do wrath.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è una lezione in cui gli allievi esaminano le 
canzoni, le interviste e le foto della manodopera agricola migratore 
nella California durante la depressione grande ed allora creano un 
album dal punto di vista di un lavoratore migrante. Foto di uso 
degli allievi e registrazioni dei lavoratori migranti per creare i 
titoli, le lettere e le canzoni. Questa lezione può essere 
particolarmente utile quando gli allievi stanno imparando circa la 
depressione grande o stanno leggendo l'uva di wrath.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι ένα μάθημα στο οποίο οι σπουδαστές εξετάζουν 
τα τραγούδια, τις συνεντεύξεις, και τις φωτογραφίες των 
αποδημητικών αγροτών σε Καλιφόρνια κατά τη διάρκεια της μεγάλης 
οικονομικής κρίσης και δημιουργούν έπειτα ένα λεύκωμα 
αποκομμάτων από την άποψη ενός διακινούμενου εργαζομένου. 
Οι σπουδαστές χρησιμοποιούν τις φωτογραφίες και τις 
καταγραφές των διακινούμενων εργαζομένων για να δημιουργήσουν τους
τίτλους, τις επιστολές, και τα τραγούδια. Αυτό το μάθημα 
μπορεί να είναι ιδιαίτερα χρήσιμο όταν μαθαίνουν οι σπουδαστές 
για τη μεγάλη οικονομική κρίση ή διαβάζουν τα σταφύλια της 
οργής.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es una lección en la cual los estudiantes 
examinan canciones, entrevistas, y las fotos de los trabajadores de 
granja migratorios en California durante la gran depresión y después
crean un libro de recuerdos desde el punto de vista de una trabajador 
emigrante. Fotos del uso de los estudiantes y grabaciones de las
trabajadores emigrantes para crear encabezamientos, cartas, y 
canciones. Esta lección puede ser determinado útil cuando los 
estudiantes están aprendiendo sobre la gran depresión o están 
leyendo las uvas de la cólera.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207178</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108122</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/figuring-somepin-bout-the-great-depression</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
