<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105664</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105664</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086795</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Run Old Jeremiah": Echoes of the Ring Shout</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Lassen Sie Alten Jeremias" Laufen: Echos 
des Ringshout</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Exécutez Vieux Jérémie" : Échos du cri 
de boucle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Funcione Jeremiah Velho": Ecos do shout do 
anel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Faccia funzionare Jeremiah Anziano": Echi 
del grido dell'anello</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Τρέξιμο παλαιό Jeremiah": Ηχώ της κραυγής 
δαχτυλιδιών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Ejecute A Viejo Jeremiah": Generaciones de 
eco del grito del anillo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Spirituals and work songs, rooted in both the slavery era and the West African societies from which most African-American slaves were originally taken, provided cultural sustenance to African Americans in the midst of intense racial oppression. Folklorists first began collecting traditional southern music in the late-19th century. By the 1920s and 1930s, John and Alan Lomax were recording southern musicians (African-American, white, and Mexican-American) for the Library of Congress. "Run, Old Jeremiah," sung by Joe Washington Brown and Austin Coleman in Jennings, Louisiana, in 1934, was a ring-shout, a religious song using a West African dance pattern, where the performers shuffled single file, clapping out a complex counter-rhythm. The ring-shout was common during slavery and remained popular well into the 20th century as a means of emotional and physical release during religious worship. The lyrics of the ring-shout spoke of escape from the travails of the present.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Angelegenheiten- und Arbeitsliede, verwurzelt in 
der Sklavereiära und in den afrikanischen Westgesellschaften, von 
denen die meisten Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Sklaven ursprünglich 
genommen wurden, zur Verfügung gestelltes kulturelles sustenance zu 
den afrikanischen Amerikanern in der Mitte der intensiven rassischen 
Unterdrückung. Folkloristen fingen zuerst an, traditionelle 
südliche Musik im des späten 19. jahrhunderts Jahrhundert zu 
sammeln. Bis zum den zwanziger Jahren und den dreißiger Jahren 
speicherten John und Alan Lomax südliche Musiker 
(Afrikanisch-Amerikanisch, weiß und Mexikanisch-Amerikanisch) für 
die Bibliothek des Kongresses. "laufen Sie, alter Jeremias," 
gesungen durch Joe Washington Braun und Austin Coleman in Jennings, 
Louisiana, 1934, war Ring-schreien, ein frommes Lied mit einem 
afrikanischen Tanzwestmuster, in dem die Ausführenden einzelne Datei 
schlurften und klatschte aus einem komplizierten 
Kostenzähler-Rhythmus. Ring-schreien Sie war geläufig während
der Sklaverei und geblieben populär gut in das 20. Jahrhundert als 
Mittel der emotionalen und körperlichen Freigabe während der frommen
Anbetung. Die Lyriken von Ring-schreien Speiche des 
Entweichens von den travails des Geschenkes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Chansons de chant religieux et de travail, 
enracinées dans l'ère d'esclavage et les sociétés africaines 
occidentales desquelles la plupart des esclaves afro-américains ont 
été initialement pris, sustentation culturelle fournie aux 
Américains africains au milieu de l'oppression raciale intense. 
Les folkloristes ont commencé la première fois à rassembler 
la musique méridionale traditionnelle en fin du 19me siècle. 
Par les années 20 et les années 30, John et Alan Lomax
enregistraient les musiciens méridionaux (Afro-Américain, blanc, et 
Mexicain-Américain) pour la bibliothèque du congrès. 
"exécutez, vieux Jérémie," chanté par brun de Joe Washington
et Austin Coleman dans Jennings, Louisiane, en 1934, était 
boucle-crient, une chanson religieuse en utilisant une configuration 
africaine occidentale de danse, où les interprètes ont brouillé le 
fichier simple, battant hors d'un compteur-rythme complexe. 
Boucle-criez était commun pendant l'esclavage et a été bien 
resté populaire dans le 20ème siècle en tant que des moyens de 
version émotive et physique pendant le culte religieux. Le 
lyrique du boucle-crie rai d'évasion des travails du présent.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Canções do espiritual e do trabalho, enraizadas
  na era do slavery e nas sociedades africanas ocidentais de que a 
maioria de escravos Africano-Americanos foram feitos exame 
originalmente, sustenance cultural fornecido aos americanos africanos 
no meio do oppression racial intenso. Os folklorists começaram 
primeiramente a coletar a música do sul tradicional no século 
late-19th. Pelos 1920s e pelos 1930s, John e Alan Lomax gravavam
músicos do sul (Africano-Americano, branco, e Mexicano-Americano) 
para a biblioteca do congress. "funcione, Jeremiah velho," 
cantado pelo marrom de Joe Washington e Austin Coleman em Jennings, 
Louisiana, em 1934, era anel-ring-shout, uma canção religiosa usando
um teste padrão africano ocidental da dança, onde os performers 
baralhassem a única lima, clapping para fora de um contador-ritmo 
complexo. Anel-ring-shout era comum durante o slavery e foi 
remanescido popular bem no 20o século como meios da liberação 
emocional e física durante a adoração religiosa. Os lyrics do
anel-ring-shout raio do escape dos travails do presente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Canzoni del lavoro e dello spiritual, sradicate 
sia nell'era di slavery che nelle società africane ad ovest da cui la
maggior parte dei schiavi Africano-Americani originalmente sono stati 
presi, sustenance culturale fornito al oppression razziale in mezzo a
intenso africano degli Americani. I folklorists in primo luogo 
hanno cominciato a raccogliere la musica del sud tradizionale nel fine
del 19esimo secolo. Entro gli anni 20 ed i 1930s, John ed Alan 
Lomax stavano registrando i musicisti del sud (Africano-Americano, 
bianco e messicano-american) per la libreria del congresso. 
"funzioni, Jeremiah anziano," cantato da colore marrone del Joe 
Washington ed Austin Coleman in Jennings, Luisiana, in 1934, era 
anello-grida, una canzone religiosa usando un modello africano ad 
ovest di ballo, in cui gli esecutori hanno mescolareato il singolo 
archivio, applaudente verso l'esterno un contatore-ritmo complesso. 
Anello-gridi era comune durante lo slavery ed è stato rimasto 
popolare facilmente per il ventesimo secolo come mezzi di versione 
impressionabile e fisica durante il culto religioso. I lyrics 
del anello-gridano spoke della fuga dai travails del presente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τραγούδια Spirituals και εργασίας, που ριζοβολούν 
και στην εποχή σκλαβιάς και στις δυτικές αφρικανικές κοινωνίες 
από τις οποίες οι περισσότεροι αφρικανικός-αμερικανικοί σκλάβοι 
λήφθηκαν αρχικά, παρεχόμενο πολιτιστικό μέσο συντήρησης σε 
αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς στη μέση της έντονης φυλετικής κατοχής.
Folklorists άρχισαν αρχικά την παραδοσιακή νότια 
μουσική στο late-19th αιώνα. Μέχρι τη δεκαετία του '20 
και τη δεκαετία του '30, John και ο Alan Lomax κατέγραφαν 
τους νότιους μουσικούς (αφρικανικός-Αμερικανός, λευκό, και 
Μεξικανοαμερικάνος) για τη βιβλιοθήκη του συνεδρίου. "Το 
τρέξιμο, παλαιό Jeremiah," τραγουδημένος από Joe Ουάσιγκτον
καφετιά και το Ώστιν Coleman σε Jennings, Λουιζιάνα, το 
1934, ήταν μια δαχτυλίδι-κραυγή, ένα θρησκευτικό τραγούδι που
χρησιμοποιεί ένα πρότυπο δυτικού αφρικανικό χορού, όπου οι 
εκτελεστές μετάθεσαν το ενιαίο αρχείο, χτυπώντας έξω έναν 
σύνθετο αντίθετος-ρυθμό. Η δαχτυλίδι-κραυγή ήταν κοινή 
κατά τη διάρκεια της σκλαβιάς και παρέμεινε δημοφιλής καλά στο 
20ό αιώνα ως μέσο συναισθηματικής και φυσικής έκδοσης κατά τη 
διάρκεια της θρησκευτικής λατρείας. Τα λυρικά ποιήματα της 
δαχτυλίδι-κραυγής μίλησαν για τη διαφυγή από τα travails του 
παρόντος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Canciones del espiritual y del trabajo, arraigadas
en la era y las sociedades africanas del oeste de las cuales la 
mayoría de los esclavos Africano-Americanos fueron tomados 
originalmente, sustenance cultural proporcionado de la esclavitud a 
los americanos africanos en el medio de la opresión racial intensa. 
Los folklorists primero comenzaron a recoger música meridional 
tradicional en el siglo de fines del siglo diecinueve. Por los 
años 20 y los años 30, Juan y Alan Lomax registraban a músicos 
meridionales (Africano-Americano, blanco, y Mexicano-Americano) para 
la biblioteca del congreso. "ejecútese, viejo Jeremiah," 
cantado por el marrón de Joe Washington y Austin Coleman en Jennings,
Luisiana, en 1934, era anillo-grita, una canción religiosa usando un 
modelo africano del oeste de la danza, donde los ejecutantes mezclaron
el solo fichero, aplaudiendo fuera de un contador-ritmo complejo. 
Anillo-grite era común durante esclavitud y era seguido siendo 
popular bien en el vigésimo siglo como los medios del desbloquear 
emocional y físico durante la adoración religiosa. Las 
líricas del anillo-gritan rayo del escape de los travails del 
presente.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086795</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105664</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/run-old-jeremiah-echoes-of-the-ring-shout</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
