<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106452</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106452</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087224</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"What I Tell My Child About Color": Black and White Fathers in Atlanta Try to Explain Race Relations to Their Sons</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Was Ich Meinem Kind Über Farbe" Erkläre: 
Schwarze und weiße Väter in Atlanta versuchen, 
Rennen-Relationen ihren Söhnen zu erklären</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Ce qui Je Dis Mon Enfant Au sujet de Couleur" : 
Les pères noirs et blancs à Atlanta essayent d'expliquer des 
relations inter-raciales à leurs fils</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"O que Eu Digo Minha Criança Sobre A Cor": 
Os pais pretos e brancos em Atlanta tentam explicar relações 
de raça a seus filhos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Che cosa Dico Al Mio Bambino Circa Colore": 
I padri neri e bianchi a Atlanta provano a spiegare i rapporti 
di corsa ai loro figli</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Τι λέω στο παιδί μου για το χρώμα": Οι μαύροι 
και λευκοί πατέρες στην Ατλάντα προσπαθούν να εξηγήσουν τις 
φυλετικές σχέσεις με τους γιους τους</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Qué Digo A Mi Niño Sobre Color": Los 
padres negros y blancos en Atlanta intentan explicar relaciones de 
raza a sus hijos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1954, the unanimous U.S. Supreme Court ruling in Brown v. Board of Education dramatically changed American society.    The Court reversed the 1896 Plessy v. Ferguson decision that racially segregated public facilities were not inherently discriminatory. After the 1954 ruling, states could no longer apply "separate but equal" to public schools, in part because of segregation's psychological effects on children. Chief Justice Earl Warren wrote in the Court's decision that the separation of Negro children "from others of similar age and qualifications solely because of their race generates a feeling of inferiority as to their status in the community that may affect their hearts and minds in a way unlikely ever to be undone." In 1955, the Court ordained that desegregation of public schools should proceed "with all deliberate speed." As the South reacted to these rulings, two Atlanta fathers, both professionals, related for a popular magazine their experiences discussing race relations with their young sons.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1954 änderte das einmütige VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Höchste Gericht, das im braunen v. Brett der Ausbildung anordnet 
drastisch, amerikanische Gesellschaft. Das Gericht hob die 
Plessy V. Ferguson Entscheidung 1896 auf, die rassisch allgemeine 
Teildienste waren nicht in sich selbst diskriminierend trennte. 
Nach 1954 anordnend, konnten Zustände nicht mehr zutreffen 
"sich trennen aber Gleichgestelltes" zu den allgemeinen Schulen, im 
Teil wegen der psychologischen Effekte der Abtrennung auf Kinder. 
Oberrichter Graf Warren schrieb in die Entscheidung des 
Gerichtes, daß die Trennung der Schwarzekinder "von anderen von 
ähnlichem Alter und von Qualifikationen nur wegen ihres Rennens ein 
Gefühl der Unterlegenheit hinsichtlich ihres Status in der 
Gemeinschaft festlegt, die ihre Inneren und Verstand in einer Methode 
überhaupt beeinflussen kann, die unwahrscheinlich ist 
annuliert zu werden." 1955 ordinierte das Gericht, daß 
desegregation der allgemeinen Schulen "mit allen fortfahren sollte 
überlegte Geschwindigkeit." Wie der Süden zu diesen Regelungen
reagierte, zwei Atlanta Väter, beide Fachleute, für eine populäre 
Zeitschrift ihre Erfahrungen in Verbindung gestanden Rennenrelationen 
mit ihren jungen Söhnen behandelnd.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1954, la cour suprême unanime des ETATS-UNIS 
régnant dans le panneau brun de v. de l'éducation a excessivement 
changé la société américaine. La cour a renversé la 
décision 1896 de Plessy v. Ferguson qui a racial isolé les 
équipements publics n'étaient pas en soi discriminatoire. 
Après le 1954 régnant, les états ont pu plus ne s'appliquer 
"séparent mais égale" aux écoles d'Etat, en partie en raison des 
effets psychologiques de la ségrégation sur des enfants. Le 
comte Warren de justice en chef a écrit dans la décision de la cour 
que la séparation des enfants de nègre "de d'autres d'âge et de 
qualifications semblables seulement en raison de leur course produit 
d'un sentiment d'infériorité quant à leur mode dans la communauté 
qui peut affecter leurs coeurs et esprits d'une voie peu susceptible 
jamais d'être défait." En 1955, la cour a ordonné que la 
déségrégation des écoles d'Etat devrait se poursuivre "par tous vitesse 
délibérée." Comme les Sud ont réagi à ces actes, 
deux pères d'Atlanta, les deux professionnels, associés pour un 
magasin populaire leurs expériences discutant des relations 
inter-raciales avec leurs jeunes fils.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1954, a corte suprema unânime de ESTADOS UNIDOS
que governa na placa marrom do v. da instrução mudou dramàtica a 
sociedade americana. A corte inverteu a decisão 1896 de Plessy 
v. Ferguson que segregou racial facilidades públicas não era 
inerente discriminatory. Após o 1954 que governam, os estados 
podiam não mais por muito tempo aplicar-se "separam mas igual" às 
escolas públicas, na parte por causa dos efeitos psicológicos do 
segregation em crianças. O earl Warren da justiça principal 
escreveu na decisão da corte que a separação de crianças do negro 
"de outras da idade e de qualificações similares unicamente por 
causa de sua raça gera um sentimento do inferiority a respeito de seu
status na comunidade que pode afetar seus corações e mentes em uma 
maneira improvável sempre undone." Em 1955, a corte ordained 
que o desegregation de escolas públicas deve proseguir "com tudo 
velocidade deliberada." Como o sul reagiu a estes rulings, dois 
pais de Atlanta, ambos os profissionais, relacionados para um 
compartimento popular suas experiências discutindo relações de 
raça com seus filhos novos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1954, la Corte suprema unanime degli STATI UNITI
che regola nel Bordo marrone del v. di formazione ha cambiato 
drammaticamente la società americana. La corte ha invertito la 
decisione 1896 di Plessy v. Ferguson che razziale ha segregato le 
attrezzature pubbliche non era inerentemente discriminatoria. 
Dopo il 1954 che regola, dichiara potrebbe più non 
applicarsi "separano ma uguale" alle "public school", in parte a causa
degli effetti psicologici della segregazione sui bambini. Il 
earl Warren della giustizia principale ha scritto nella decisione 
della corte che la separazione dei bambini del negro "da altre 
dell'età e delle qualificazioni simili a causa della loro corsa 
genera solamente una sensibilità del inferiority quanto alla loro 
condizione nella Comunità che può interessare mai i loro cuori e 
menti in un modo improbabile undone." In 1955, la corte ordained
che il desegregation delle "public school" dovrebbe procedere "a tutti
velocità intenzionale." Come il sud ha reagito a queste 
decisioni, due padri de Atlanta, entrambi i professionisti, 
riguardanti per uno scomparto popolare le loro esperienze discutenti i
rapporti di corsa con i loro figli giovani.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1954, η ομόφωνη απόφαση του ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΥ ανώτατου
δικαστηρίου Brown V. Board της εκπαίδευσης άλλαξε 
εντυπωσιακά την αμερικανική κοινωνία. Το δικαστήριο 
αντέστρεψε τη 1896 Plessy V. Ferguson απόφαση που 
διαχώρισε racially τις δημόσιες εγκαταστάσεις δεν ήταν εγγενώς
μεροληπτική. Μετά από το 1954 που κυβερνά, τα κράτη δεν 
θα μπορούσαν πλέον να εφαρμόσουν "χωριστός αλλά ίσοσ" με τα 
δημόσια σχολεία, εν μέρει λόγω των ψυχολογικών αποτελεσμάτων του
διαχωρισμού στα παιδιά. Προϊστάμενος η δικαιοσύνη κόμης 
Warren έγραψε στην απόφαση του δικαστηρίου ότι ο χωρισμός των 
παιδιών νέγρων "από άλλες της παρόμοιων ηλικίας και των 
προσόντων απλώς λόγω της φυλής τους παράγει ένα συναίσθημα της 
κατωτερότητας ως προς τη θέση τους στην κοινότητα που μπορεί να 
έχει επιπτώσεις στις καρδιές και τα μυαλά τους με έναν τρόπο 
απίθανο πάντα να ανατρεφθεί." Το 1955, το δικαστήριο 
ορισμένος ότι ο διαχωρισμός των δημόσιων σχολείων πρέπει να 
συνεχίσει "με όλη τη σκόπιμη ταχύτητα." Δεδομένου ότι ο 
νότος αντέδρασε σε αυτές τις αποφάσεις, δύο πατέρες της 
Ατλάντας, και οι δύο επαγγελματίες, σχετικοί για ένα δημοφιλές 
περιοδικό η εμπειρία τους που συζητά τις φυλετικές σχέσεις με 
τους νέους γιους τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1954, el Tribunal Supremo unánime de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS que gobernaba en la tarjeta marrón del v. de la educación 
cambió dramáticamente a sociedad americana. La corte invirtió
la decisión 1896 de Plessy v. Ferguson que racial segregó recursos 
públicos no era intrínsecamente discriminatoria. Después del 
1954 que gobernaba, los estados podían aplicarse no más de largo "se
separan solamente igual" a las escuelas públicas, en parte debido a 
los efectos psicologicos de la segregación sobre niños. El 
earl Warren de la principal justicia escribió en la decisión de la 
corte que la separación de los niños del negro "de otras de edad y 
de calificaciones similares debido a su raza genera solamente una 
sensación de la inferioridad en cuanto a su estatus en la comunidad 
que puede afectar sus corazones y mentes de una manera poco probable 
siempre ser deshecho." En 1955, la corte ordained que el 
desegregation de escuelas públicas debe proceder "con todos velocidad
deliberada." Como el sur reaccionó a estos actos, dos padres de
Atlanta, ambos profesionales, relacionados para un compartimiento 
popular sus experiencias discutiendo relaciones de raza con sus hijos 
jóvenes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087224</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106452</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/what-i-tell-my-child-about-color-black-and-white-fathers-in-atlanta-try-to-explain-race-relations-to-their-sons</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
