<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103022</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103022</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087006</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The New Middle-Class Housekeeping: "How I Keep House without a Maid"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Neue Mittler-Kategorie Haushaltung: "wie
ich Haus ohne ein Mädchen halte"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Nouveau Ménage de Moyen-Classe : 
"comment je garde la Chambre sans bonne"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As Tarefas domésticas Novas Da Médio-Classe: 
"como eu mantenho a casa sem uma empregada doméstica"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nuovo Governo della casa Del Centrale-Codice 
categoria: "come mantengo la Camera senza una domestica"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η νέα οικοκυρική μεσαίας τάξης: "Πώς κρατώ το 
σπίτι χωρίς ένα κορίτσι"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las Nuevas Operacíones de entretenimiento De la 
Medio-Clase: "cómo guardo la casa sin una criada"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">As immigration dropped sharply during World War I and many native-born women left domestic service for wartime jobs, middle-class women lamented the shortage of domestic workers. New experts offered their advice to the middle-class woman who decided to tackle housework without the assistance of paid help. Gladys Hutton Chase  ,  writing in  Good Housekeeping  in 1918, explained the new middle-class housekeeping. Chase celebrated her newfound freedom from the "work and worry" of employing domestic workers. Notably, her solution was doing her own work with the help of a professional home economics course, rather than getting other household members to pitch in. And even as she enthused about the efficiency of her new methods, Chase revealed the escalating standards that expanded and complicated middle-class housekeeping.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Da die Immigration, die scharf während des Ersten
Weltkrieges und vieler gebürtig-getragene Frauen fallengelassen 
wurde, inländischen Service für Kriegjobs ließ, bejammerten 
Mittelklassefrauen den Mangel an inländische Arbeiter. Neue 
Experten boten ihren Rat der Mittelklassefrau an, die entschied, 
Hausarbeit ohne die Unterstützung der zahlenden Hilfe anzupacken. 
Gladys Hutton die Verfolgung, schreibend in gute Haushaltung 
1918, erklärte die neue Mittelklassehaushaltung. Verfolgung 
feierte ihre neuentdeckte Freiheit von der "Arbeit und von der Sorge" 
der Beschäftigung der inländischen Arbeiter. Vornehmlich 
erledigte ihre Lösung ihre eigene Arbeit mit Hilfe eines 
professionellen Hauswirtschaftkurses, anstatt veranließ andere 
Haushalt Bauteile, innen zu werfen. Und selbst als sie über die
Leistungsfähigkeit ihrer neuen Methoden enthused, deckte Verfolgung 
die entwickelnden Standards auf, die Mittelklassehaushaltung 
erweiterten und erschwerten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Car l'immigration abandonnée brusquement pendant 
la Première Guerre Mondiale et les beaucoup les femmes 
indigène-soutenues a laissé le service domestique pour les travaux 
de temps de guerre, les femmes de classe moyen ont déploré le manque
d'ouvriers domestiques. Les nouveaux experts ont offert leur 
conseil à la femme de classe moyenne qui a décidé d'aborder les
travaux domestiques sans aide d'aide payée. La chasse de Gladys
Hutton, écrivant dans le bon ménage en 1918, a expliqué le 
nouveau ménage de classe moyenne. La chasse a célébré sa 
absence récemment découverte du "travail et du souci" d'employer les
ouvriers domestiques. Notamment, sa solution effectuait son 
propre travail avec l'aide d'un cours professionnel d'économie 
ménagère, plutôt que d'oblige d'autres membres de ménage à lancer
dedans. Et même pendant qu'elle enthused au sujet de 
l'efficacité de ses nouvelles méthodes, la chasse a indiqué les 
normes d'escalade qui ont augmenté et ont compliqué le ménage de 
classe moyen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Porque o immigration deixado cair agudamente 
durante o world.war.i e os muitos mulheres nativo-carregadas deixou o 
serviço doméstico para trabalhos do wartime, as mulheres do 
middle-class lamented a falta de trabalhadores domésticos. Os 
peritos novos ofereceram seu conselho à mulher do middle-class que se
decidiu tackle o housework sem o auxílio de ajuda paga. A 
perseguição de Gladys Hutton, escrevendo em tarefas domésticas boas
em 1918, explicou as tarefas domésticas novas do middle-class. 
A perseguição comemorou sua liberdade newfound do "trabalho e 
da preocupação" de empregar trabalhadores domésticos. 
Notàvelmente, sua solução fazia seu próprio trabalho com a 
ajuda de um curso profissional da economia home, melhor que começava 
outros membros da casa lançar dentro. E nivele como enthused 
sobre a eficiência de seus métodos novos, perseguição revelou os 
padrões escalando que expandiram e complicaram tarefas domésticas do
middle-class.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Poichè l'immigrazione caduta acutamente durante 
il world.war.i ed i molti donne natale-sopportate ha lasciato il 
servizio domestico per i lavori di wartime, le donne della classe 
media hanno deplorato la scarsità degli operai domestici. I 
nuovi esperti hanno offerto il loro consiglio alla donna della classe 
media che ha deciso affrontare i lavori domestici senza l'assistenza 
di aiuto paid. L'inseguimento di Gladys Hutton, scrivente nel 
buon governo della casa in 1918, ha spiegato il nuovo governo della 
casa della classe media. L'inseguimento ha celebrato la sua 
libertà newfound "dal lavoro e dalla preoccupazione" di impiegare gli
operai domestici. Considerevolmente, la sua soluzione stava 
facendo il suo proprio lavoro con l'aiuto di un corso professionale di
economia domestica, piuttosto che stava convincendo altri membri della
famiglia a lanciare dentro. E proprio mentre enthused circa il 
risparmio di temi dei suoi nuovi metodi, l'inseguimento ha rivelato 
gli standard crescenti che hanno espanso e complicato il governo della
casa della classe media.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σαν μετανάστευση που έπεσαν αισθητά κατά τη διάρκεια 
του παγκόσμιου πολέμου Ι και πολλές εγγενής-γεννημένες γυναίκες 
που αφέθηκαν την εσωτερική υπηρεσία για τις εν καιρώ πολέμου 
εργασίες, οι γυναίκες μεσαίων τάξεων θρήνησαν την έλλειψη των 
εσωτερικών εργαζομένων. Οι νέοι εμπειρογνώμονες πρόσφεραν 
τις συμβουλές τους στη γυναίκα μεσαίων τάξεων που αποφάσισε να 
αντιμετωπίσει τα οικιακά χωρίς τη βοήθεια των πληρωμένων 
οδηγιών. Hutton Gladys το αυλάκωμα, που γράφει στην 
καλή οικοκυρική το 1918, εξήγησε τη νέα οικοκυρική μεσαίων 
τάξεων. Το αυλάκωμα γιόρτασε την προσφάτως ανευρεθείσα 
ελευθερία της από τη "εργασία και την ανησυχία" της απασχόλησης 
των εσωτερικών εργαζομένων. Ειδικότερα, η λύση της έκανε 
την εργασία της με τη βοήθεια μιας επαγγελματικής σειράς 
μαθημάτων βασικών οικονομικών, παρά να πάρει άλλα οικιακά μέλη
για να ρίξει μέσα. Και ακόμη και όπως για την αποδοτικότητα
των νέων μεθόδων της, το αυλάκωμα αποκάλυψε τα κλιμακώνοντας 
πρότυπα που επέκτειναν και περιέπλεξαν την οικοκυρική μεσαίων 
τάξεων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Pues la inmigración caída sostenidamente durante
Primera Guerra Mundial y muchas las mujeres nativo-llevadas dejó el 
servicio doméstico para los trabajos del tiempo de guerra, las 
mujeres de la clase media lamentaron de la escasez de trabajadores 
domésticos. Los nuevos expertos ofrecieron su consejo a la 
mujer de la clase media que decidía abordar el quehacer doméstico 
sin la ayuda de la ayuda pagada. La persecución de Gladys 
Hutton, escribiendo en buenas operacíones de entretenimiento en 1918,
explicó las nuevas operacíones de entretenimiento de la clase media.
La persecución celebró su libertad newfound del "trabajo y de 
la preocupación" de emplear a trabajadores domésticos. 
Notablemente, su solución hacía su propio trabajo con la ayuda
de un curso profesional de la economía doméstica, más bien que 
conseguía a otros miembros de la casa echar adentro. E iguale 
como ella enthused sobre la eficacia de sus nuevos métodos, 
persecución reveló los estándares de extensión que ampliaron y 
complicaron operacíones de entretenimiento de la clase media.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087006</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103022</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-new-middle-class-housekeeping-how-i-keep-house-without-a-maid</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
