<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106105</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106105</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086408</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Let's Have a Meeting:" Cathy Wilkerson on SDS Organizing</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"lassen Sie uns eine Sitzung haben:" Cathy 
Wilkerson auf SDS dem Organisieren</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"ayons une réunion :" Cathy Wilkerson sur 
l'organisation de SDS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"deixe-nos ter uma reunião:" Cathy 
Wilkerson em organizar do SDS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"abbiamo una riunione:" Cathy Wilkerson 
sull'organizzazione di SDS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Διοργανώνει μια συνεδρίαση:" Θ*Θατχυ Wilkerson
στην οργάνωση SDS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"tengamos una reunión:" Cathy Wilkerson en 
la ordenación del SDS</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Student organizers from groups such as Students for Democratic Society (SDS) traveled to college campuses around the country to build student opposition to the Vietnam War. Cathy Wilkerson, who worked in the SDS national office and edited the SDS paper,  New Left Notes,  described how SDS organizers used campus politics to build the movement. By getting students involved in conflicts over university governance, defense research taking place at their universities, or local civil rights issues, SDS engaged thousands of students who had not previously thought of themselves as political. The ability of SDS organizers to make the issues real to students by getting them to take risks and be confrontational on these local issues was, to Wilkerson, the key to SDS's organizing success. [The material in brackets was added to the transcript shortly after the recorded interview.]</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kursteilnehmerorganisatoren von den Gruppen wie 
Kursteilnehmern für demokratische Gesellschaft (SDS) reisten zu den 
Hochschulcampus um das Land zur Baukursteilnehmeropposition zum 
Vietnam Krieg Cathy Wilkerson, der im SDS nationalen Büro arbeitete 
und das SDS Papier bearbeitete, die neuen linken Anmerkungen, 
beschrieben, wie SDS Organisatoren Campuspolitiken verwendeten, um die
Bewegung aufzubauen. Indem es Kursteilnehmer gewesen mit 
$überschneidungen über Universitätsregierungsgewalt, der 
Verteidigungforschung, die an ihren Universitäten stattfinden, oder 
den lokalen Zivilrechtausgaben erhielt, engagierte sich SDS Tausenden 
Kursteilnehmer, die nicht dachten vorher an selbst hatten, wie 
politisch. Die Fähigkeit der SDS Organisatoren, die Ausgaben 
real zu bilden zu den Kursteilnehmern, indem sie sie veranließ, 
Gefahren zu nehmen und confrontational zu diesen lokalen Punkten zu 
sein, war, zu Wilkerson, die Taste zu organisierendem Erfolg SDSs. 
[ das Material in den Haltewinkeln wurde der Abschrift kurz nach
dem gespeicherten Interview. hinzugefügt ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les organisateurs d'étudiant des groupes tels que
des étudiants pour la société démocratique (SDS) ont voyagé aux 
campus d'université dans le pays à l'opposition d'étudiant de 
construction à la guerre de Vietnam Cathy Wilkerson, qui a 
fonctionné dans le bureau national de SDS et a édité le papier de 
SDS, de nouvelles notes gauches, décrites comment les organisateurs 
de SDS avaient l'habitude la politique de campus pour établir le 
mouvement. En obtenant des étudiants impliqués dans les 
conflits au-dessus du gouvernement d'université, de la recherche de 
la défense ayant lieu à leurs universités, ou des issues locales de
droits civiques, le SDS a engagé des milliers d'étudiants qui n'ont 
pas eu ont précédemment pensé à eux-mêmes comme politique. 
La capacité des organisateurs de SDS de rendre les issues 
vraies aux étudiants en les obligeant à prendre des risques et à 
être conflictuels sur ces questions locales était, à Wilkerson, la 
clé au succès d'organisation du SDS. [ le matériel entre 
parenthèses a été ajouté à la transcription peu de temps après 
l'entrevue enregistrée. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os organizers do estudante dos grupos tais como 
estudantes para a sociedade democrática (SDS) viajaram aos campuses 
da faculdade em torno do país à oposição do estudante da 
configuração à guerra de Vietnam Cathy Wilkerson, que trabalhou no 
escritório nacional do SDS e editou o papel do SDS, as notas 
esquerdas novas, descritas como os organizers do SDS usaram a 
política do campus construir o movimento. Começando estudantes
envolvidos nos conflitos sobre o governance da universidade, a 
pesquisa da defesa que ocorrem em suas universidades, ou edições 
locais das direitas civis, o SDS acoplou milhares dos estudantes que 
não tiveram pensaram previamente dse como político. A 
abilidade de organizers do SDS de fazer as edições reais aos 
estudantes começando os fazer exame de riscos e ser confrontational 
nestas edições locais era, a Wilkerson, a chave ao sucesso 
organizando do SDS. [ o material nos suportes foi adicionado ao 
transcript logo depois que a entrevista gravada. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli organizzatori dell'allievo dai gruppi quali 
gli allievi per la società democratica (SDS) hanno viaggiato alle 
città universitarie dell'università intorno al paese ad opposizione 
dell'allievo di configurazione alla guerra di Vietnam Cathy Wilkerson,
che ha lavorato nell'ufficio nazionale di SDS ed ha stampato la carta 
da SDS, nuove note di sinistra, descritte come gli organizzatori di 
SDS hanno usato le politiche della città universitaria per sviluppare
il movimento. Ottenendo gli allievi addetti ai conflitti sopra 
controllo dell'università, ricerca della difesa che avviene alle loro
università, o le edizioni locali di diritti civili, lo SDS ha 
agganciato i migliaia degli allievi che non hanno avuti 
precedentemente hanno pensato se stesso come politico. La 
capacità degli organizzatori di SDS di rendere le edizioni reali agli
allievi convincendoli a assumersi le responsabilità ed essere 
confrontational su queste edizioni locali era, a Wilkerson, il tasto a
successo d'organizzazione dello SDS. [ il materiale tra 
parentesi è stato aggiunto alla trascrizione subito dopo l'intervista
registrata. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι διοργανωτές σπουδαστών από τις ομάδες όπως οι 
σπουδαστές για τη δημοκρατική κοινωνία (SDS) ταξίδεψαν στις 
πανεπιστημιουπόλεις κολλεγίων γύρω από τη χώρα για να χτίσουν 
την αντίθεση σπουδαστών στον πόλεμο του Βιετνάμ. Η Cathy 
Wilkerson, που εργάστηκε στο εθνικό γραφείο SDS και 
επιμελήθηκε το έγγραφο SDS, νέες αριστερές σημειώσεις, 
περιέγραψε πώς οι διοργανωτές SDS χρησιμοποίησαν την πολιτική 
πανεπιστημιουπόλεων για να χτίσουν τη μετακίνηση. Με να 
πάρει τους σπουδαστές περιλήφθείτυς σε σύγκρουση πέρα από την 
πανεπιστημιακή διακυβέρνηση, την αμυντική έρευνα που 
πραγματοποιούνται στα πανεπιστήμιά τους, ή τα τοπικά ζητήματα 
αστικών δικαιωμάτων, SDS δέσμευσε χιλιάδες σπουδαστές που δεν 
είχαν σκεφτεί προηγουμένως τους όπως πολιτικός. Η 
δυνατότητα των διοργανωτών SDS να καταστήσουν τα ζητήματα 
πραγματικά στους σπουδαστές με να πάρει τους για να διατρεχτούν οι
κίνδυνοι και να είναι αντιπαραθετικούς σε αυτά τα τοπικά 
ζητήματα ήταν, σε Wilkerson, το πλήκτρο στην επιτυχία 
οργάνωσης SDS. [ Το υλικό εντός παρενθέσεως 
προστέθηκε στο αντίγραφο αμέσως μετά από την καταγραμμένη 
συνέντευξη. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los organizadores del estudiante de grupos tales 
como estudiantes para la sociedad democrática (SDS) viajaron a los 
campus de la universidad alrededor del país a la oposición del 
estudiante de la estructura a la guerra de Vietnam Cathy Wilkerson, 
que trabajó en la oficina nacional del SDS y corrigió el papel del 
SDS, las nuevas notas izquierdas, descritas cómo los organizadores 
del SDS utilizaron políticas del campus para construir el movimiento.
Consiguiendo estudiantes implicados en conflictos sobre gobierno
de la universidad, la investigación de la defensa que ocurría en sus
universidades, o ediciones locales de las derechas civiles, el SDS 
contrató a millares de estudiantes que no tenían pensaron 
previamente en sí mismos como político. La capacidad de los 
organizadores del SDS de hacer las ediciones verdaderas a los 
estudiantes consiguiéndolos tomar riesgos y ser confrontational en 
estas ediciones locales era, a Wilkerson, el clave al éxito de 
ordenación del SDS. [ el material en corchetes fue agregado a 
la transcripción poco después la entrevista registrada. ]</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086408</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106105</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/lets-have-a-meeting-cathy-wilkerson-on-sds-organizing</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
