<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107477</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107477</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086365</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Jim Vacarella Describes Avoiding the Draft During the Vietnam War</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Jim Vacarella beschreibt, den Entwurf während des
Vietnam Krieges zu vermeiden</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jim Vacarella décrit éviter l'ébauche pendant 
la guerre de Vietnam</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jim Vacarella descreve evitar o esboço durante a 
guerra de Vietnam</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Jim Vacarella descrive evitare la brutta copia 
durante la guerra di Vietnam</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Jim Vacarella Describes Avoiding το σχέδιο 
κατά τη διάρκεια του πολέμου του Βιετνάμ</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Jim Vacarella describe el evitar del bosquejo 
durante la guerra de Vietnam</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">For young men like Jim Vacarella, the draft stood as the prime symbol of the war in Vietnam. Millions of young men tried to evade the draft: some fled to Canada; many feigned physical or mental illness, others used family connections to gain safe positions in the National Guard. For some, resisting the draft became an important way of protesting the war, and a few thousand men took public stands as draft resistors, burning their draft cards and challenging the government to imprison them. Jim Vacarella was one of those who burned his draft card, although he was lucky enough to avoid prison.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Für junge Männer mögen Sie Jim Vacarella, der 
Entwurf, der als das Hauptsymbol des Krieges in Vietnam gestanden 
wird. Millionen der jungen Männer versuchten, dem Entwurf 
auszuweichen: einige flohen nach Kanada; viel körperliche
oder Geistesscheinkrankheit, andere benutzte Familie Anschlüsse, um 
sichere Positionen im nationalen Schutz zu gewinnen. Für 
einiges dem Entwurf wurde zu widerstehen eine wichtige Methode des 
Protestierens des Krieges, und einige tausend Männer nahmen 
allgemeine Standplätze als Entwurfwiderstände und brannten ihre 
Entwurfkarten und schwierig die Regierung, um sie einzusperren. 
Jim Vacarella war eins von denen, die seine Entwurfkarte 
brannten, obgleich er genug glücklich war, Gefängnis zu vermeiden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pour de jeunes hommes aimez Jim Vacarella, 
l'ébauche tenue comme symbole principal de la guerre au Vietnam. 
Les millions de jeunes hommes ont essayé d'éluder l'ébauche :
certains se sont sauvés au Canada ; beaucoup de maladie 
physique ou mentale simulée, d'autres a employé des connexions de 
famille pour gagner des positions sûres dans la garde nationale. 
Pour certains, la résistance de l'ébauche est devenue une voie
importante de protester la guerre, et quelques mille hommes ont pris 
les stands publics comme résistances d'ébauche, brûlant leurs 
cartes d'ébauche et provocant le gouvernement pour les emprisonner. 
Jim Vacarella était l'un de ceux qui ont brûlé son carte 
d'ébauche, bien qu'il ait été assez chanceux pour éviter la 
prison.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Para homens novos goste de Jim Vacarella, o 
esboço estado como o símbolo principal da guerra em Vietnam. 
Os milhões de homens novos tentaram evade o esboço: 
alguns fujiram a Canadá; muita doença física ou mental 
feigned, outra usou conexões da família ganhar posições seguras no
protetor nacional. Para algum, resistir o esboço transformou-se
uma maneira importante de protestar a guerra, e alguns mil homens 
fizeram exame de carrinhos públicos como os resistores do esboço, 
queimando seus cartões do esboço e challenging o governo para 
imprison os. Jim Vacarella era um daqueles que queimaram seu 
cartão do esboço, embora fosse afortunado bastante evitar a prisão.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Per i giovani gradisca Jim Vacarella, la brutta 
copia partecipata come il simbolo principale della guerra nel Vietnam.
Milioni di giovani hanno provato ad eludere la brutta copia: 
alcuni sono fuggito nel Canada; molta malattia fisica o 
mentale finta, altre ha usato i collegamenti della famiglia per 
guadagnare le posizioni sicuri nella protezione nazionale. Per 
alcuno, resistere alla brutta copia si è transformata in in un modo 
importante della protesta della guerra ed alcuni mille uomini hanno 
testimoniato pubblici come resistori della brutta copia, brucianti le 
loro schedi della brutta copia e challenging il governo per imprison. 
Jim Vacarella era uno di coloro che ha bruciato la sua scheda 
della brutta copia, anche se era abbastanza fortunato evitare la 
prigione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Για τους νεαρούς άνδρες όπως jim Vacarella, το 
σχέδιο στάθηκε ως πρωταρχικό σύμβολο του πολέμου στο Βιετνάμ. 
Τα εκατομμύρια των νεαρών άνδρων προσπάθησαν να αποφύγουν 
το σχέδιο: μερικοί που στον Καναδά  πολλοί υποκριτική
φυσική ή διανοητική ασθένεια, άλλες χρησιμοποιημένες 
οικογενειακές συνδέσεις για να κερδίσει τις ασφαλείς θέσεις στην 
εθνική φρουρά. Για μερικούς, που αντιστέκονται το σχέδιο 
έγινε ένας σημαντικός τρόπος τον πόλεμο, και μερικές χιλιάες 
άτομα υιοθέτησαν τις δημόσιες στάσεις ως αντιστάτες σχεδίων, που
καίνε τις κάρτες σχεδίων τους και που προκαλούν την κυβέρνηση για
να τις φυλακίσουν. Jim Vacarella ήταν ένας από 
εκείνους που έκαψαν την κάρτα σχεδίων του, αν και ήταν αρκετά 
τυχερός να αποφύγει τη φυλακή.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Para los hombres jóvenes tenga gusto de Jim 
Vacarella, el bosquejo parado como el símbolo primero de la guerra en
Vietnam. Millones de hombres jóvenes intentaron evadir el 
bosquejo: algunos huyeron a Canadá; mucha enfermedad 
física o mental fingida, otras utilizó conexiones de la familia para
ganar posiciones seguras en el protector nacional. Para alguno, 
resistir el bosquejo se convirtió en una manera importante de 
protestar la guerra, y algunos mil hombres tomaron soportes públicos 
como resistores del bosquejo, quemándose sus tarjetas del bosquejo y 
desafiador el gobierno para encarcelarlas. Jim Vacarella era uno
de los que se quemaron su tarjeta del bosquejo, aunque él era 
bastante afortunado evitar la prisión.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086365</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107477</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/jim-vacarella-describes-avoiding-the-draft-during-the-vietnam-war</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
