<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107453</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107453</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206352</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Pipestone, Minnesota -- National Register of Historic Places Travel Itinerary</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Pipestone, Minnesota -- Einwohnermeldeliste des 
historischen Platz-Spielraum-Reisewegs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pipestone, Minnesota -- registre national 
d'itinéraire historique de voyage d'endroits</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Pipestone, Minnesota -- registo nacional do 
itinerary historic do curso dos lugares</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Pipestone, Minnesota -- registro nazionale 
dell'itinerario storico di corsa dei posti</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Pipestone, Μινεσότα -- εθνικός κατάλογος της 
ιστορικής περιήγησης ταξιδιού θέσεων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Pipestone, Minnesota -- registro nacional del 
itinerario histórico del recorrido de los lugares</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features an area in the southwest corner of Minnesota that reflects a rich history of American Indian quarrying, prosperity brought by the railroad and mining enterprises, and a distinctive natural landscape. This National Register of Historic Places Travel itinerary highlights 30 historic places, including buildings constructed with beautiful local red stone and land still sacred to American Indians.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">kennzeichnet einen Bereich in der Südwestecke von
Minnesota, das eine reiche Geschichte des indianischen Abbauens, den 
Wohlstand, der durch die Eisenbahn geholt werden und die 
gewinnenunternehmen reflektiert, und von unterscheidender natürlicher
Landschaft. Diese Einwohnermeldeliste des historischen 
Platz-Spielraumreisewegs markiert 30 historische Plätze, 
einschließlich die Gebäude, die mit schönem lokalem rotem Stein 
konstruiert werden und landet noch heiliges zu den Indianern.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">comporte une zone dans le coin de sud-ouest du 
Minnesota qui reflète une histoire riche de l'extraction en carrière
indienne, la prospérité apportée par le chemin de fer et les 
entreprises d'extraction, et d'un horizontal normal distinctif. 
Ce registre national d'itinéraire historique de voyage 
d'endroits met en valeur 30 endroits historiques, y compris des 
bâtiments construits avec la belle pierre rouge locale et débarque 
encore sacré aux Indiens d'Amerique.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">caracteriza uma área no canto do sudoeste de 
Minnesota que reflete um history rico de quarrying indian americano, a
prosperidade trazida pela estrada de ferro e empresas minando, e de 
uma paisagem natural distintiva. Este registo nacional do 
itinerary historic do curso dos lugares destaca 30 lugares historic, 
including os edifícios construídos com a pedra vermelha local bonita
e aterra ainda sacred aos indians americanos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">caratterizza una zona nel angolo di sud-ovest del 
Minnesota che riflette una storia ricca di estrazione indiana 
americana, la prosperità portata dalla ferrovia e le imprese 
estraenti e di un paesaggio naturale distintivo. Questo registro
nazionale dell'itinerario storico di corsa dei posti evidenzia 30 
posti storici, compreso le costruzioni costruite con la pietra rossa 
locale bella ed atterra ancora sacred agli indiani americani.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χαρακτηρίζει μια περιοχή στη νοτιοδυτική γωνία 
Μινεσότας που απεικονίζει μια πλούσια ιστορία της αμερικανικής 
εξόρυξης Ινδού, της ευημερίας φέρνω από το σιδηρόδρομο και τις 
εξάγοντας επιχειρήσεις, και ενός διακριτικού φυσικού τοπίου. 
Αυτός ο εθνικός κατάλογος της ιστορικής περιήγησης 
ταξιδιού θέσεων δίνει έμφαση σε 30 ιστορικές θέσεις, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένων των κτηρίων που κατασκευάζονται με την όμορφα 
τοπικά κόκκινα πέτρα και το έδαφος ακόμα ιερές σε αμερικανικούς
Ινδούς.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece un área en la esquina del sudoeste de 
Minnesota que refleje una historia rica de sacar indio americano, la 
prosperidad traída por el ferrocarril y las empresas que minan, y de 
un paisaje natural distintivo. Este registro nacional del 
itinerario histórico del recorrido de los lugares destaca 30 lugares 
históricos, incluyendo los edificios construidos con la piedra roja 
local hermosa y todavía aterriza sagrado a los indios americanos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206352</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107453</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/pipestone-minnesota-national-register-of-historic-places-travel-itinerary</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
