<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107337</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107337</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086233</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Hello, You Fighting Orphans": "Tokyo Rose" Woos U.S. Sailors and Marines</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Hallo, Sie Kämpfende Orphans": "Tokyo 
Rose" fleht VEREINIGTE STAATEN Seeleute und Marinen an</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Bonjour, Vous Orphelins de Combat" : "Tokyo
Rose" courtise des marins et des soldats de marine des ETATS-UNIS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Hello, Você Orphans De combate": "Tokyo 
Rosa" woos sailors e fuzileiros navais de ESTADOS UNIDOS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Ciao, Voi Orphans Di Combattimento": "Tokyo 
Rosa" corteggia i marinai ed i fanti di marina degli STATI UNITI</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Γειάσου, εσείς παλεύοντας ορφανοί": "Το Τόκιο 
αυξήθηκε" επιζητά τους ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΥΣ ναυτικούς και τα ναυτικά</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Hola, Usted Huérfanos Que luchan": "Tokio 
Rose" corteja a los marineros y a infantes de marina de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">During World War II, a dozen female broadcasters, collectively dubbed "Tokyo Rose" by U.S. troops, provided a diversion from the horrors of war. Set up by the Japanese military and using the powerful signal of Radio Tokyo, these Tokyo Roses were on the air nightly, broadcasting English-language shows designed to make American soldiers and sailors nostalgic and homesick. One such Tokyo Rose, U.S. citizen Iva Ikuki Toguri D'Aquino, described her August 14, 1944, broadcast as "sweet propaganda" and played tunes whose titles (for example, "My Resistance Is Low") were designed to demoralize her listeners. Although some soldiers and sailors may have felt the occasional twinge of homesickness while listening to Tokyo Rose's broadcasts, most simply ignored the propaganda and insults while hoping to hear their favorite popular songs.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während des Zweiten Weltkrieges Rundfunkstationen
einer Dutzend Frau, zusammen betiteltes "Tokyo Rose" durch VEREINIGTE 
STAATEN Truppen, vorausgesetzt eine Ablenkung von den Grausigkeiten 
des Krieges. Aufgestellt, indem das japanische militärische und
das Verwenden das leistungsfähige Signal von Radiotokyo, sprachen 
übertrugen diese Tokyo Rosen im Rundfunk allabendlich und die 
englischsprachigen Erscheinen, die konzipiert waren, um amerikanische 
Soldaten und Seeleute zu bilden Nostalgiker und homesick. Ein 
solches Tokyo Rose, VEREINIGTE STAATEN Bürger Iva Ikuki Toguri 
D'Aquino, beschrieben ihr August 14, 1944, Sendung als "süsse 
Propaganda" und gespielte Melodien deren Namen (zum Beispiel, "mein 
Widerstand ist" niedrig) konzipiert waren, ihre Zuhörer zu 
demoralisieren. Obgleich einige Soldaten und Seeleute dem 
gelegentlichen Twinge von Homesickness beim Hören geglaubt haben 
können Tokyo Rose zu den Sendungen, einfach ignoriert worden der 
Propaganda und den Beleidigungen während hoffend, ihre populären 
Lieblingsliede zu hören.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant la deuxième guerre mondiale, des douzaine
radiodiffuseurs femelles, "Tokyo collectivement doublée Rose" par des
troupes des ETATS-UNIS, si un transfert des horreurs de la guerre. 
L'installation le militaire japonais et en utilisant le signal 
puissant de Tokyo par radio, ces roses de Tokyo étaient sur l'air de 
nuit, annonçant les expositions de langue anglaise conçues pour 
faire les soldats et les marins américains nostalgique et 
nostalgique. Une telle Tokyo Rose, citoyen Iva Ikuki Toguri 
d'Aquino des ETATS-UNIS, décrit son 14 août 1944, émission en tant
que "propagande douce" et airs joués dont les titres (par exemple, 
"ma résistance est basse") ont été conçus pour démoraliser ses 
auditeurs. Bien que quelques soldats et marins aient pu avoir 
senti l'élancement occasionnel du mal du pays tout en écoutant des 
émissions de Tokyo Rose, le plus simplement ignoré la propagande et 
les insultes tout en espérant entendre leurs chansons populaires 
préférées.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Durante a segunda guerra mundial, radiodifusores 
de umas dúzia fêmeas, "Tokyo coletivamente dubbed Rosa" por tropas 
de ESTADOS UNIDOS, desde que uma diversão dos horrors da guerra. 
Ajustado acima o militar japonês e usando o sinal poderoso de 
Tokyo de rádio, estas rosas de Tokyo estavam no ar nightly, 
transmitindo as mostras english-language projetadas fazer soldados e 
sailors americanos nostálgico e homesick. Um tal Tokyo Rosa, 
cidadão Iva Ikuki Toguri D'Aquino de ESTADOS UNIDOS, descrito seu 
agosto 14, 1944, transmissão como "o propaganda doce" e tunes jogados
cujos títulos (para o exemplo, "minha resistência é baixa") foram 
projetados demoralize seus ouvintes. Embora alguns soldados e 
sailors possam ter sentido o twinge ocasional do homesickness ao 
escutar transmissões de Tokyo Rosa, ignorado o mais simplesmente o 
propaganda e os insultos ao esperar ouvir suas canções populares 
favoritas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Durante la seconda guerra mondiale, distributori a
spaglio delle dozzina femmine, "Tokyo collettivamente dubbed Rosa" 
dalle truppe degli STATI UNITI, se una diversione dagli orrori della 
guerra. La messa a punto il militare giapponese ed usando il 
segnale potente di Tokyo radiofonica, queste rose de Tokyo era nightly
sull'aria, trasmettendo per radio le esposizioni english-language 
destinate per fare i soldati ed i marinai americani nostalgico e 
homesick. Una tale Tokyo Rosa, cittadino Iva Ikuki Toguri 
D'Aquino degli STATI UNITI, descritto suo 14 agosto 1944, 
radiodiffusione come "propaganda dolce" ed arie giocate di cui titoli 
(per esempio, "la mia resistenza è bassa") sono stati destinati a 
demoralizzare i suoi ascoltatori. Anche se alcuni soldati e 
marinai possono ritenere il twinge occasionale di homesickness mentre 
ascoltano le radiodiffusioni de Tokyo Rosa, il più semplicemente 
ignorato la propaganda e gli insulti mentre sperano di sentire le loro
canzoni popolari favorite.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ, δωδεκάδι 
θηλυκοί εκφωνητές, που μεταγλωττίστηκαν συλλογικά "το Τόκιο 
αυξήθηκαν" από τα ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΑ στρατεύματα, υπό τον όρο ότι μια 
παρεκτροπή από τις φρίκες του πολέμου. Ιδρυθείτε από 
ιαπωνικό το στρατιωτικό και χρησιμοποίηση του ισχυρού σήματος του
ραδιο Τόκιο, αυτά τα τριαντάφυλλα του Τόκιο ήταν στον αέρα κάθε
βράδυ, η ραδιοφωνική αναμετάδοση της αγγλικής γλώσσας εμφανίζει 
σχεδιασμένος για να καταστήσει τους αμερικανικούς στρατιώτες και 
τους ναυτικούς νοσταλγικούς και homesick. Ένα τέτοιο 
Τόκιο αυξήθηκε, ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΣ πολίτης Iva Ikuki Toguri 
D'Aquino, περιέγραψε τις 14 του Αυγούστου της ..1944, η 
ραδιοφωνική μετάδοση ως "γλυκιά προπαγάνδα" και παιγμένος 
συντονίζει οι της οποίας τίτλοι (παραδείγματος χάριν, "η 
αντίστασή μου είναι χαμηλή") είχαν ως σκοπό να διαφθείρουν τους
ακροατές της. Αν και μερικοί στρατιώτες και ναυτικοί μπορεί
να είχαν αισθανθεί τον περιστασιακό πόνο της νοσταλγίας για την 
πατρίδα ακούοντας τις ροδαλές ραδιοφωνικές μεταδόσεις του Τόκιο,
ο απλούστερα αγνόησε την προπαγάνδα και τις προσβολές ελπίζοντας 
να ακούσει τα αγαπημένα δημοφιλή τραγούδια τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Durante la Segunda Guerra Mundial, locutores de 
las docena hembras, "Tokio colectivamente doblada Rose" por las tropas
de ESTADOS UNIDOS, con tal que una diversión de los horrores de la 
guerra. Instalado el militar japonés y usando la señal de gran
alcance de Tokio de radio, estas rosas de Tokio estaban en el aire 
cada noche, difundiendo las demostraciones de lengua inglesa 
diseñadas para hacer soldados y a marineros americanos nostálgico y 
nostálgico. Una tal Tokio Rose, ciudadano Iva Ikuki Toguri 
D'Aquino de ESTADOS UNIDOS, descrito su 14 de agosto de 1944, 
difusión como "propaganda dulce" y consonancias jugadas que títulos 
(por ejemplo, "mi resistencia es baja") fueron diseñados desmoralizar
a sus módulos de escucha. Aunque algunos soldados y marineros 
pudieron haber sentido la punzada ocasional de la nostalgia mientras 
que escuchan las difusiones de Tokio Rose, lo más simplemente posible
no hecha caso la propaganda y los insultos mientras que esperan oír 
sus canciones populares preferidas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086233</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107337</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/hello-you-fighting-orphans-tokyo-rose-woos-u-s-sailors-and-marines</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
