<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107701</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107701</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206232</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Cosmic and Heliospheric Learning Center</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kosmische und Heliospheric erlernenmitte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Centre d'étude cosmique et de Heliospheric</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Centro de aprendizagem cosmic e de Heliospheric</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Centro imparante di Heliospheric e cosmico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοσμικός και κέντρο εκμάθησης Heliospheric</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Centro que aprende cósmico y de Heliospheric</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">explores the universe through interactive activities and learning resources such as the question and answer service, Ask a Physicist. Students can also learn astrophysics basics, or find out the history of cosmic ray studies beginning with the Mesopotamian and Egyptian astronomers mapping the heavens, and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erforscht das Universum durch interaktive 
Aktivitäten und erlernenbetriebsmittel wie der Frage und 
Antwortservice, fragen einen Physiker. Kursteilnehmer können 
Astrophysikgrundlagen auch erlernen, oder finden Sie die Geschichte 
der Studien des kosmischen Strahls heraus, die mit dem Mesopotamian 
und den ägyptischen Astronomen abbilden die Himmel anfangen, und 
mehr.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">explore l'univers par des activités interactives 
et les ressources d'étude telles que le service de question et de 
réponse, demandent à un physicien. Les étudiants peuvent 
également apprendre des fondations d'astrophysique, ou découvrez 
l'histoire des études de rayon cosmique commençant par le 
Mesopotamian et les astronomes égyptiens traçant les cieux, et plus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">explora o universo com as atividades interativas e
os recursos de aprendizagem tais como o serviço da pergunta e da 
resposta, perguntam a um físico. Os estudantes podem também 
aprender princípios da astrofísica, ou encontre para fora o history 
dos estudos do raio cosmic que começam com o Mesopotamian e os 
astrónomos egyptian que traçam os heavens, e mais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esplora l'universo con le attività interattive e 
le risorse imparanti quale il servizio di risposta e di domanda, 
chiedono ad un fisico. Gli allievi possono anche imparare i 
principi fondamentali di astrofisica, o scopra la storia degli studi 
del raggio cosmico che cominciano con il Mesopotamian e gli astronomi 
egiziani che tracciano il cielo e più.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ερευνά τον κόσμο μέσω των διαλογικών δραστηριοτήτων 
και τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς εκμάθησης όπως η υπηρεσία 
ερωταποκρίσεων, ρωτούν έναν φυσικό. Οι σπουδαστές μπορούν 
επίσης να μάθουν τα βασικά αστροφυσικής, ή να ανακαλύψουν την 
ιστορία των μελετών κοσμικών ακτίνων αρχίζοντας με τους 
μεσοποτάμιους και αιγυπτιακούς αστρονόμους που χαρτογραφούν τους 
ουρανούς, και περισσότερων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">explora el universo con actividades interactivas y
los recursos que aprenden tales como el servicio de la pregunta y de 
la respuesta, preguntan a físico. Los estudiantes pueden 
también aprender fundamentos de la astrofísica, o descubra la 
historia de los estudios del rayo cósmico que comienzan con el 
Mesopotamian y los astrónomos egipcios que asocian los cielos, y 
más.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206232</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107701</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/cosmic-and-heliospheric-learning-center</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
