<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107939</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107939</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087126</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"To Have Our Own Lawyers Fight Our Own Cases": The Origins of the Mexican American Legal Defense and Educational Fund</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">", Unsere Eigenen Rechtsanwälte Zu haben Kämpfen
Sie Unsere Eigenen Fälle": Die Ursprung der mexikanischen 
amerikanischen zugelassenen Verteidigung und der pädagogischen 
Kapitals</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Pour Avoir Nos Propres Avocats Défendez Nos 
Propres Causes" : Les origines de la défense légale 
américaine mexicaine et des fonds éducatifs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Para ter Nossos Próprios Advogados Lute Nossos 
Próprios Casos": As origens da defesa legal americana mexicana 
e do fundo educacional</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Per avere Nostri Propri Avvocati Combatti I 
Nostri Propri Casi": Le origini della difesa legale americana 
messicana e del fondo monetario educativo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Για να έχουν τους δικηγόρους μας να παλεψουν τις 
περιπτώσεις μασ": Η προέλευση της μεξικάνικης αμερικανικής 
νομικής υπεράσπισης και του εκπαιδευτικού Ταμείου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Para tener Nuestros Propios Abogados Luche 
Nuestros Propios Casos": Los orígenes de la defensa legal 
americana mexicana y del fondo educativo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the following interview, Pete Tijerina, the first executive director of the Mexican American Legal Defense and Educational Fund (MALDEF), discussed the origins of the organization. A trial lawyer with experience handling discrimination cases and encouraging organized political participation among Mexican Americans, Tijerina had been a State Civil Rights Chairman for the League of United Latin American Citizens (LULAC), an organization he joined in 1946. Because his efforts with LULAC were limited by funding and the demand for aid to individuals in localized cases, Tijerina and others realized the need for broad legal precedents to successfully erase widespread discriminatory practices and implement social and economic changes. MALDEF, with a $2.2 million grant in 1968 from the Ford Foundation (including $250,000 for the education of Mexican American lawyers), was set up initially in five southwestern states. It was patterned after the NAACP Legal Defense and Educational Fund (LDF), formed in 1940 by Thurgood Marshall to pursue initiatives in the courts to gain opportunities long denied to African Americans. MALDEF successfully argued in court for inclusion of Mexican Americans on Texas juries, integration of schools, bilingual and bicultural educational programs, equal opportunity in employment, and amendments to the Voting Rights Act.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im folgenden Interview behandelten Peter Tijerina,
der erste Executivdirektor der mexikanischen amerikanischen 
zugelassenen Verteidigung und der pädagogischen Kapitals (MALDEF), 
die Ursprung der Organisation. _ ein Probe-Rechtsanwalt mit 
Erfahrung handhaben Unterscheidungder Fall und anregen organisieren 
politisch Teilnahme unter mexikanisch Amerikaner, Tijerina haben sein 
ein ein ZustandZivil-RechtVorsitzend für die d Liga von der 
vereinigen lateinamerikanisch Bürger (LULAC), eine ein Organisation 
er anschliessen in 1946. Weil seine Bemühungen mit LULAC durch 
die Finanzierung und die Nachfrage nach Hilfsmittel für 
Einzelpersonen in beschränkten Fällen begrenzt wurden, 
verwirklichten Tijerina und andere die Notwendigkeit an den 
ausgedehnten zugelassenen Präzedenzfällen, weitverbreitete 
diskriminierende Praxis erfolgreich zu löschen und die Sozial- und 
ökonomischen Änderungen einzuführen. MALDEF, mit einer 
Bewilligung $2.2 Million 1968 von der Ford Grundlage (einschließlich 
$250.000 für die Ausbildung der mexikanischen amerikanischen 
Rechtsanwälte), wurde zuerst in fünf südwestliche Zustände 
aufgestellt. Es patterned nachdem die NAACP zugelassene 
Verteidigung und die pädagogische Kapital (LDF), gebildet 1940 von 
Thurgood Marshall, um Initiativen in den Gerichten auszuüben, um die 
Gelegenheiten zu gewinnen, die lang den afrikanischen Amerikanern 
verweigert wurden. MALDEF argumentierte erfolgreich bei Gericht 
für Einbeziehung der mexikanischen Amerikaner auf Texas Jurys, 
Integration der Schulen, zweisprachig und bikulturelle pädagogische 
Programme, gleiche Gelegenheit in der Beschäftigung und Änderungen 
rechts wählenden fungieren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans l'entrevue suivante, Peter Tijerina, le 
premier directeur exécutif de la défense légale américaine 
mexicaine et des fonds éducatifs (MALDEF), ont discuté les origines 
de l'organisation. Un avocat d'essai avec une expérience 
manipulant des cas de discrimination et les encourageant a organisé 
la participation politique parmi les Américains mexicains, Tijerina 
avait été un Président de droits civiques d'état pour la ligue des
citoyens latino-américains unis (LULAC), une organisation qu'il s'est
associée à 1946. Puisque ses efforts avec LULAC ont été 
limités par le placement et la demande de l'aide aux individus dans 
des cas localisés, Tijerina et d'autres ont réalisé le besoin de 
larges précédents légaux d'effacer avec succès des pratiques 
discriminatoires répandues et de mettre en application les 
changements sociaux et économiques. MALDEF, avec une concession
$2.2 millions en 1968 de la base de Ford ($250.000 y compris pour 
l'éducation des avocats américains mexicains), a été installé au 
commencement dans cinq états du sud-ouest. Il a été modelé 
après que la défense légale de NAACP et les fonds éducatifs (LDF),
formés en 1940 par Thurgood Marshall pour poursuivre des initiatives 
dans les cours pour gagner des occasions longtemps refusées aux 
Américains africains. MALDEF avec succès a plaidé devant le 
tribunal pour l'inclusion des Américains mexicains sur des jurys du 
Texas, intégration des écoles, bilingue et les programmes éducatifs
biculturels, la égalité des chances dans l'emploi, et les 
amendements vers le droit de vote agissent.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Na seguinte entrevista, Pete Tijerina, o primeiro 
diretor executivo da defesa legal americana mexicana e do fundo 
educacional (MALDEF), discutiram as origens da organização. Um
advogado experimental com a experiência que segura casos da 
discriminação e que incentiva organizou a participação política 
entre americanos mexicanos, Tijerina tinha sido um presidente das 
direitas civis do estado para a liga dos cidadãos americanos latin 
unidos (LULAC), uma organização que juntou em 1946. Porque 
seus esforços com LULAC foram limitados financiar e pela demanda para
o dae (dispositivo automático de entrada) aos indivíduos em casos 
localizados, Tijerina e outro realizaram a necessidade para precedents
legais largos apagar com sucesso práticas discriminatory difundidas e
executar mudanças sociais e econômicas. MALDEF, com uma 
concessão $2.2 milhões em 1968 da fundação de Ford ($250.000 
including para a instrução de advogados americanos mexicanos), foi 
ajustado acima inicialmente em cinco estados do sudoeste. Foi 
modelado depois que a defesa legal de NAACP e o fundo educacional 
(LDF), dados forma em 1940 por Thurgood Marshall para perseguir 
iniciativas nas cortes para ganhar as oportunidades negadas por muito 
tempo aos americanos africanos. MALDEF discutiu com sucesso na 
corte para o inclusion de americanos mexicanos em júris de Texas, 
integração das escolas, bilíngüe e os programas educacionais 
bicultural, a oportunidade igual no emprego, e as emendas às direita 
votando agem.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nella seguente intervista, Pete Tijerina, il primo
direttore esecutivo della difesa legale americana messicana e del 
fondo monetario educativo (MALDEF), hanno discusso le origini 
dell'organizzazione. Un avvocato di prova con esperienza che 
maneggia i casi di distinzione e che consiglia ha organizzato la 
partecipazione politica fra gli Americani messicani, Tijerina era 
stato un presidente di diritti civili di Dichiarare per la lega dei 
cittadini dell'America latina uniti (LULAC), un'organizzazione che si 
è associato a 1946. Poiché i suoi sforzi con LULAC sono stati 
limitati costituendo un fondo per e dalla domanda del sussidio agli 
individui nei casi localizzati, Tijerina ed altri hanno realizzato la 
necessità per i vasti precedenti legali di cancellare con successo le
pratiche discriminatorie diffuse e di effettuare i cambiamenti sociali
ed economici. MALDEF, con una concessione $2.2 milioni in 1968 
dal fondamento del Ford ($250.000 compresi per la formazione degli 
avvocati americani messicani), è stato installato inizialmente in 
cinque del sud-ovest dichiara. È stato modellato dopo 
che la difesa legale di NAACP ed il fondo monetario educativo (LDF), 
formati in 1940 da Thurgood Marshall per perseguire le iniziative 
nelle corti per guadagnare le occasioni lungamente rifiutate agli 
Americani africani. MALDEF ha parlato con successo in tribunale 
a favore dell'inclusione degli Americani messicani sulle giurie del 
Texas, integrazione delle scuole, bilingue ed i programmi educativi 
biculturali, l'occasione uguale nell'occupazione e le correzioni ai 
diritti di voto si comportano.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στην ακόλουθη συνέντευξη, pete Tijerina, ο πρώτος
εκτελεστικός σκηνοθέτης της μεξικάνικης αμερικανικής νομικής 
υπεράσπισης και του εκπαιδευτικού Ταμείου (MALDEF), συζήτησαν 
την προέλευση της οργάνωσης. Ένας δοκιμαστικός δικηγόρος με
τις διαχειριζόμενες περιπτώσεις και την ενθάρρυνση διάκρισης 
εμπειρίας της οργανωμένης πολιτικής συμμετοχής μεταξύ 
μεξικάνικων Αμερικανών, Tijerina ήταν πρόεδρος κρατικών 
αστικών δικαιωμάτων για την ένωση των ενωμένων λατινοαμερικανικών
πολιτών (LULAC), μια οργάνωση που προσχώρησε το 1946. 
Επειδή οι προσπάθειές του με LULAC περιορίστηκαν από τη 
χρηματοδότηση και την απαίτηση για την ενίσχυση στα άτομα σε 
εντοπισμένες περιπτώσεις, Tijerina και άλλα πραγματοποίησαν την
ανάγκη για τα ευρέα νομικά προηγούμενα για να σβήσουν επιτυχώς 
τις διαδεδομένες μεροληπτικές πρακτικές και να εφαρμόσουν τις 
κοινωνικές και οικονομικές αλλαγές. MALDEF, με μια 
επιχορήγηση $2,2 εκατομμυρίων το 1968 από το ίδρυμα 
διάβασης (συμπεριλαμβανομένων $250.000 για την εκπαίδευση των 
μεξικάνικων αμερικανικών δικηγόρων), ιδρύθηκε αρχικά σε πέντε 
νοτιοδυτικά κράτη. Διαμορφώθηκε μετά από τη νομική 
υπεράσπιση NAACP και το εκπαιδευτικό Ταμείο (LDF), που 
διαμορφώθηκε το 1940 από Thurgood Marshall για να 
ακολουθήσει τις πρωτοβουλίες στα δικαστήρια να κερδηθούν οι 
ευκαιρίες που αμφισβητήθηκαν πολύ σε αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς. 
MALDEF υποστήριξε επιτυχώς στο δικαστήριο το 
συνυπολογισμό μεξικάνικων Αμερικανών στις κριτικές επιτροπές του 
Τέξας, ολοκλήρωση των σχολείων, των δίγλωσσων και διπολιτιστικών 
εκπαιδευτικών προγραμμάτων, της ίσης ευκαιρίας στην απασχόληση, 
και των τροποποιήσεων στο νόμο δικαιωμάτων ψήφου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En la entrevista siguiente, Pete Tijerina, el 
primer director ejecutivo de la defensa legal americana mexicana y del
fondo educativo (MALDEF), discutieron los orígenes de la 
organización. Un abogado de ensayo con la experiencia que 
manejaba casos de la discriminación y que los animaba ordenó la 
participación política entre americanos mexicanos, Tijerina había 
sido presidente de las derechas civiles del estado para la liga de los
ciudadanos americanos latinos unidos (LULAC), una organización que 
él ensambló en 1946. Porque sus esfuerzos con LULAC fueron 
limitados por el financiamiento y la demanda para la ayuda a los 
individuos en casos localizados, Tijerina y otros realizaron la 
necesidad de amplios precedentes legales de borrar con éxito 
prácticas discriminatorias extensas y de poner cambios en ejecucio'n 
sociales y económicos. MALDEF, con una concesión $2.2 millones
en 1968 de la fundación de Ford ($250.000 incluyendo para la 
educación de abogados americanos mexicanos), fue instalado 
inicialmente en cinco estados al sudoeste. Fue modelado después
de que la defensa legal y el fondo educativo (LDF) de NAACP, formados 
en 1940 por Thurgood Marshall para perseguir iniciativas en las cortes
para ganar las oportunidades negadas de largo a los americanos 
africanos. MALDEF discutió con éxito en la corte para la 
inclusión de americanos mexicanos en los jurados de Tejas, 
integración de escuelas, bilingüe y los programas educativos 
biculturales, la oportunidad igual en el empleo, y las enmiendas a los
derechos al voto actúan.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087126</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107939</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/to-have-our-own-lawyers-fight-our-own-cases-the-origins-of-the-mexican-american-legal-defense-and-educational-fund</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
