<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103829</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103829</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201155</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">CyanoBase</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">CyanoBase</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">CyanoBase</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">CyanoBase</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">CyanoBase</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">CyanoBase</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">CyanoBase</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This information database provides an easy way of accessing the sequences and all-inclusive annotation data on the structures of the cyanobacterial genomes. Cyanobacteria carry a complete set of genes for oxygenic photosynthesis, and are believed to be the ancient ancestors of chloroplast. Maintained by the Kazusa DNA Research Institute, Cyanobase contains information and sequences for Synechocystis, Anabaena, Thermosynechococcus elongatus, Gloeobacter violaceus, Prochlorococcus marinus, Synechococcus, Chlorobium tepidum, and Rhodopseudomonas palustris. It also includes links to CyanoMutants, a database depository of published and unpublished functional and genetic data on Synechocystis 6803 mutants with known mutations, and CyanoGenes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Informationen Datenbank stellt eine einfache
Methode des Zugreifens die Reihenfolgen und Sammelauf die anmerkung 
Daten auf den Strukturen der cyanobacterial Genome zur Verfügung. 
Cyanobacteria tragen ein komplettes Set Gene für oxygenic 
Fotosynthese und werden geglaubt, um die alten Vorfahren des 
Chloroplasts zu sein. Beibehalten durch das Kazusa DNA 
Forschungsinstitut, enthält Cyanobase Informationen und Reihenfolgen 
für Synechocystis, Anabaena, Thermosynechococcus elongatus, 
Gloeobacter violaceus, Prochlorococcus marinus, Synechococcus, 
Chlorobium tepidum und Rhodopseudomonas palustris. Es schließt 
auch Links zu CyanoMutants, einen Datenbankverwahrungsort erschienene 
und unveröffentlichte Funktions- und genetische Daten bezüglich 
Synechocystis 6803 Durch Mutation entstehende Variationen mit 
bekannten Veränderungen und zu CyanoGenes ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette base de données de l'information fournit 
une voie facile d'accéder aux ordres et aux données inclusives 
d'annotation sur les structures des génomes cyanobacterial. 
Cyanobacteria portent un ensemble complet de gènes pour la 
photosynthèse oxygenic, et sont censés pour être les ancêtres 
antiques du chloroplaste. Mis à jour par l'institut de 
recherche de recherche d'ADN de Kazusa, Cyanobase contient 
l'information et des ordres pour l'elongatus de Synechocystis, 
d'anabaena, de Thermosynechococcus, le violaceus de Gloeobacter, le 
marinus de Prochlorococcus, le tepidum de Synechococcus, de 
Chlorobium, et les palustris de rhodopseudomonas. Il inclut 
également les liens à CyanoMutants, un dépôt de base de données 
de données fonctionnelles et génétiques éditées et non publiées 
sur Synechocystis 6803 mutants avec des mutations connues, et à 
CyanoGenes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta base de dados da informação fornece uma 
maneira fácil de alcançar as seqüências e os dados inclusivos da 
anotação nas estruturas dos genomes cyanobacterial. 
Cyanobacteria carrega um jogo completo dos genes para a 
fotossíntese oxygenic, e é acreditado para ser os antepassados 
antigos do chloroplast. Mantido pelo instituto de pesquisa do 
DNA de Kazusa, Cyanobase contem a informação e as seqüências para 
o elongatus de Synechocystis, de anabaena, de Thermosynechococcus, o 
violaceus de Gloeobacter, o marinus de Prochlorococcus, o tepidum de 
Synechococcus, de Chlorobium, e os palustris dos rhodopseudomonas. 
Inclui também as ligações a CyanoMutants, um depository da 
base de dados de dados funcionais e genetic publicados e unpublished 
em Synechocystis 6803 mutants com mutations sabidos, e a CyanoGenes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa base di dati delle informazioni fornisce un
modo facile di accesso alle sequenze ed a dei dati inclusivi di 
annotazione sulle strutture dei genomes cyanobacterial. 
Cyanobacteria trasporta un insieme completo dei geni per la 
fotosintesi oxygenic e si crede per essere gli antenati antichi del 
cloroplasto. Effettuato dall'istituto di ricerca del DNA di 
Kazusa, Cyanobase contiene le informazioni e le sequenze per il 
elongatus di Synechocystis, del anabaena, di Thermosynechococcus, il 
violaceus di Gloeobacter, il marinus di Prochlorococcus, il tepidum di
Chlorobium, di Synechococcus ed i palustris delle rodopseudomone. 
Egualmente include i collegamenti a CyanoMutants, un depository 
della base di dati dei dati funzionali e genetici pubblicati e non 
pubblicati su Synechocystis 6803 mutanti con le mutazioni conosciute 
ed a CyanoGenes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η βάση δεδομένων πληροφοριών παρέχει έναν 
εύκολο τρόπο στις ακολουθίες και τα όλος-συμπεριλαμβάνοντα 
στοιχεία σχολιασμών όσον αφορά τις δομές των cyanobacterial 
γονιδιωμάτων. Το Cyanobacteria φέρνει ένα πλήρες σύνολο 
γονιδίων για την oxygenic φωτοσύνθεση, και θεωρείται οι αρχαίοι
πρόγονοι του χλωροπλάστη. Διατηρημένο από το ερευνητικό 
ίδρυμα DNA Kazusa, Cyanobase περιέχει τις πληροφορίες και 
τις ακολουθίες για το elongatus Synechocystis, Anabaena, 
Thermosynechococcus, το violaceus Gloeobacter, το tepidum 
Prochlorococcus Marinus, Synechococcus, Chlorobium, και 
rhodopseudomonas τα palustris. Περιλαμβάνει επίσης τις 
συνδέσεις με CyanoMutants, ένας χώρος καταθέσεων βάσεων 
δεδομένων των δημοσιευμένων και αδημοσίευτων λειτουργικών και 
γενετικών στοιχείων όσον αφορά Synechocystis 6803 
μεταλλάξεις με τις γνωστές μεταλλαγές, και CyanoGenes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta base de datos de la información proporciona 
a una manera fácil de tener acceso a las secuencias y a los datos 
inclusivos de la anotación en las estructuras de los genomas 
cyanobacterial. Cyanobacteria lleva un conjunto completo de los 
genes para la fotosíntesis oxygenic, y se cree para ser los 
antepasados antiguos del cloroplasto. Mantenido por el instituto
de investigación de la DNA de Kazusa, Cyanobase contiene la 
información y las secuencias para el elongatus de Synechocystis, del 
anabaena, de Thermosynechococcus, el violaceus de Gloeobacter, el 
marinus de Prochlorococcus, el tepidum de Synechococcus, de 
Chlorobium, y los palustris de los rhodopseudomonas. También 
incluye las conexiones a CyanoMutants, un almacén de la base de datos
de datos funcionales y genéticos publicados e inéditos sobre 
Synechocystis 6803 mutantes con mutaciones sabidas, y a CyanoGenes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:YASUKAZU NAKAMURA
FN:YASUKAZU NAKAMURA
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MAKOTO HIROSAWA
FN:MAKOTO HIROSAWA
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:TAKAKAZU KANEKO
FN:TAKAKAZU KANEKO
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:SATOSHI TABATA
FN:SATOSHI TABATA
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:KAZUSA DNA RESEARCH INSTITUTE
FN:KAZUSA DNA RESEARCH INSTITUTE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201155</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103829</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/cyanobase</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
