<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107678</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107678</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207198</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Coca-Cola Television Advertisements</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Coca-Cola Fernsehen-Reklameanzeigen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Annonces de Télévision de Coca-Cola</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Propagandas Da Televisão Da Coca-Cola</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Pubblicità Della Televisione Della Coca-Cola</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τηλεοπτικές διαφημίσεις κόκα κόλα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Anuncios De la Televisión De la Coca-Cola</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">presents TV commercials, never-broadcast outtakes, and experimental footage that together reflect the historical development of TV advertising for a major product. Ads include the 1971 Hilltop commercial with an international group of young people on an Italian hilltop singing I'd Like to Buy the World a Coke; the first Polar Bear commercial from 1993; the Snowflake commercial from 1999; and First Experience, an international commercial filmed in Morocco in 1999.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt Fernsehapparat Werbungen dar, 
nie-überträgt outtakes und experimentelle Gesamtlänge, die zusammen
ist die historische Entwicklung von Fernsehapparat bekanntmachend für
ein Hauptprodukt reflektieren. ADS schließen die Gipfelwerbung 
1971 mit einer internationalen Gruppe jungen Leuten auf einem 
italienischen Gipfel ein, singend, das ich die Welt kaufen möchte 
einen Koks; die erste polarer Bär Werbung von 1993; die 
Schneeflockewerbung von 1999; und erste Erfahrung, eine 
internationale Werbung gefilmet in Marokko 1999.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">présente des films publicitaires de TV, 
jamais-annonce les outtakes, et la longueur expérimentale qui 
reflètent ensemble le développement historique de la TV annonçant 
pour un produit important. L'ADS incluent le film publicitaire 
1971 de sommet avec un groupe international de jeunes sur un sommet 
italien chantant que je voudrais acheter le monde un coke ; le 
premier film publicitaire d'ours blanc de 1993 ; le film 
publicitaire de flocon de neige de 1999 ; et première 
expérience, un film publicitaire international filmé au Maroc en 
1999.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">apresenta comerciais da tevê, nunca-transmitem os
outtakes, e o footage experimental que refletem junto o 
desenvolvimento histórico da tevê que anuncia para um produto 
principal. O Ads inclui o comercial 1971 do hilltop com um grupo
internacional de povos novos em um hilltop italiano cantando que eu 
gostaria de comprar o mundo um coke; o primeiro comercial do 
urso polar de 1993; o comercial do snowflake de 1999; e 
primeira experiência, um comercial internacional filmado em Marrocos 
em 1999.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">presenta gli annunci pubblicitari della TV, 
mai-trasmettono per radio i outtakes ed il metraggio sperimentale che 
riflettono insieme lo sviluppo storico della TV che fa pubblicità per
un prodotto importante. Il Ads include l'annuncio pubblicitario 
1971 del hilltop con un gruppo internazionale dei giovani su un 
hilltop italiano cantando che vorrei comprare il mondo un coke; 
il primo annuncio pubblicitario dell'orso polare da 1993; 
l'annuncio pubblicitario del fiocco di neve da 1999; e 
prima esperienza, un annuncio pubblicitario internazionale filmato nel
Marocco in 1999.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρουσιάζει τους αντιπροσώπους TV, την 
ποτέ-ραδιοφωνική μετάδοση outtakes, και το πειραματικό μήκος 
σε πόδηα που απεικονίζουν μαζί την ιστορική ανάπτυξη της 
διαφήμισης TV για ένα σημαντικό προϊόν. Οι αγγελίες 
περιλαμβάνουν την κορυφή υψώματος του 1971 εμπορική με μια 
διεθνή ομάδα νέων σε μια ιταλική κορυφή υψώματος που τραγουδά 
εγώ θα επιθυμούσαν να αγοράσουν τον κόσμο ένα κοκ  η πρώτη
πολική αρκούδα εμπορική από το 1993  snowflake 
εμπορικό από το 1999  και η πρώτη εμπειρία, ένας 
διεθνής αντιπρόσωπος στο Μαρόκο το 1999.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">presenta los anuncios de la TV, nunca-difunde los 
outtakes, y la cantidad experimental que junto reflejan el desarrollo 
histórico de la TV que anuncia para un producto importante. El 
Ads incluye el anuncio 1971 del hilltop con un grupo internacional de 
gente joven en un hilltop italiano cantando que quisiera comprar el 
mundo un coque; el primer anuncio del oso polar a partir de 
1993; el anuncio del copo de nieve a partir de 1999; y 
primera experiencia, un anuncio internacional filmado en Marruecos en 
1999.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207198</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107678</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/coca-cola-television-advertisements</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
