<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103026</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103026</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205837</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Arts for the Nation: American Sheet Arts, 1870-1885</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste für die Nation: Amerikanische 
Blatt-Künste, 1870-1885</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts pour la nation : Arts Américains de 
Feuille, 1870-1885</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes para a nação: Artes Americanas Da 
Folha, 1870-1885</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti per la nazione: Arti Americane Del 
Foglio, 1870-1885</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες για το έθνος: Αμερικανικές τέχνες 
φύλλων, 1870-1885</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes para la nación: Artes Americanos De 
la Hoja, 1870-1885</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">consists of tens of thousands of pieces of sheet music registered for copyright during the post-Civil War era. Included are popular songs, piano music, sacred music and secular choral music, solo instrumental music, method books and instructional materials, and music for band and orchestra. This first release of the online collection consists of over 22,000 musical compositions registered for copyright during the years 1870 to 1879.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">besteht aus 10 Tausenden Stücken Blattmusik 
registriert für copyright während der PfostenZivilkriegära. 
Ist populäre Liede, Klaviermusik, heilige Musik und weltliche 
choral Musik, solo instrumentelle Musik, Methode Bücher und 
Unterrichtsmaterialien und Musik für Band und Orchester enthalten. 
Diese erste Freigabe der Onlineansammlung besteht aus über 
22.000 musikalischem Aufbau, der für copyright während der Jahre 
1870 bis 1879 registriert wird.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">se compose des dizaines de milliers de morceaux de
musique de feuille inscrits à copyright pendant l'ère poteau-Civile 
de guerre. Incluses sont les chansons populaires, la musique de 
piano, la musique sacrée et la musique chorale séculaire, la musique
instrumentale soloe, les livres de méthode et le matériel 
didactique, et la musique pour la bande et l'orchestre. Cette 
première version de la collection en ligne se compose plus de 22.000 
compositions musicales inscrites à copyright pendant les années 1870
à 1879.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">consiste em dez dos milhares das partes de música
da folha registadas para o copyright durante a era borne-Civil da 
guerra. Incluídas são as canções populares, a música do 
piano, a música sacred e a música choral secular, a música 
instrumental de solo, os livros do método e os materiais instrutivos,
e a música para a faixa e o orchestra. Esta primeira 
liberação da coleção em linha consiste sobre 22.000 composições 
musicais registadas para o copyright durante os anos 1870 a 1879.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">consiste dei dieci delle migliaia delle parti di 
musica del foglio registrate per il copyright durante l'era 
alberino-Civile di guerra. Incluse sono le canzoni popolari, la 
musica del piano, la musica sacred e la musica choral secolare, la 
musica strumentale sola, i libri di metodo ed il materiale didattico e
la musica per la fascia e l'orchestra. Questa prima versione 
dell'accumulazione in linea consiste di oltre 22.000 composizioni 
musicali registrate per il copyright durante gli anni 1870 - 1879.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">αποτελείται από τις δεκάδες χιλιάδων κομμάτια της 
μουσικής φύλλων που καταχωρείται για τα πνευματικά δικαιώματα 
κατά τη διάρκεια της μετα-αστικής πολεμικής εποχής. 
Περιλαμβάνονται τα δημοφιλή τραγούδια, η μουσική πιάνων, η 
ιερή μουσική και η κοσμική χορωδιακή μουσική, σόλο η οργανική 
μουσική, τα βιβλία μεθόδου και τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, και η 
μουσική για τη ζώνη και την ορχήστρα. Αυτή η πρώτη έκδοση 
της σε απευθείας σύνδεση συλλογής αποτελείται από πάνω από 
22.000 μουσικές συνθέσεις που καταχωρούνται για τα πνευματικά 
δικαιώματα κατά τη διάρκεια των ετών 1870 έως 1879.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">consiste en diez de millares de pedazos de música
de la hoja registrados para el copyright durante la era poste-Civil de
la guerra. Incluidas son las canciones populares, la música del
piano, la música sagrada y la música coral secular, la música 
instrumental a solas, los libros del método y los materiales de 
instrucción, y la música para la venda y la orquesta. Este 
primer desbloquear de la colección en línea consiste en sobre 22.000
composiciones musicales registradas para el copyright durante los 
años 1870 a 1879.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205837</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103026</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/arts-for-the-nation-american-sheet-arts-1870-1885</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
