<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105882</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105882</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206075</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Global Volcanism Program (GVP)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Globale Vulkanismus-Programm (GVP)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Programme Global de Volcanisme (GVP)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Programa Global Do Volcanism (GVP)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Programma Globale Di Volcanism (GVP)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το σφαιρικό volcanism πρόγραμμα (GVP)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Programa Global Del Volcanismo (GVP)</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">presents documentation of the eruptions of all volcanoes during the past 10,000 years. Visitors can review volcanic activity reports, view geographic and geologic information for all Holocene volcanoes (those with known activity during the last 10,000 years), and order research and publications by Smithsonian volcanologists and their colleagues.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt Unterlagen der Eruptionen aller Vulkane 
während der letzten 10.000 Jahre dar. Besucher können 
vulkanische Tätigkeitsberichte, geographische und geologische 
Informationen der Ansicht für alle Holocene Vulkane (die mit 
bekannter Aktivität während der letzten 10.000 Jahre) und Ordnung 
Forschung und Publikationen durch Smithsonian volcanologists und ihre 
Kollegen wiederholen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">présente la documentation des éruptions de tous 
les volcans pendant les 10.000 dernières années. Les visiteurs
peuvent passer en revue des rapports d'activité volcaniques, 
l'information géographique et géologique de vue pour tous les 
volcans holocènes (ceux avec l'activité connue pendant les 10.000 
dernières années), et recherche et publications de commande par des 
volcanologues de Smithsonian et leurs collègues.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">apresenta a documentação dos eruptions de todos 
os vulcões durante os 10.000 anos passados. Os visitantes podem
rever relatórios de atividade vulcânicos, informação geográfica e
geologic da vista para todos os vulcões holocene (aqueles com 
atividade sabida durante os últimos 10.000 anos), e pesquisa e 
publicações da ordem por volcanologists de Smithsonian e por seus 
colegas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">presenta la documentazione dei eruptions di tutti 
i vulcani durante i 10.000 anni scorsi. Gli ospiti possono 
rivedere i rapporti d'attività vulcanici, le informazioni geografiche
e geologiche di vista per tutti i vulcani holocene (quelli con 
attività conosciuta durante i 10.000 anni ultimi) e ricerca e 
pubblicazioni di ordine dai volcanologists dello Smithsonian e dai 
loro colleghe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρουσιάζει την τεκμηρίωση των εκρήξεων όλων των 
ηφαιστείων κατά τη διάρκεια των προηγούμενων 10.000 ετών. 
Οι επισκέπτες μπορούν να αναθεωρήσουν τις ηφαιστειακές 
εκθέσεις δραστηριότητας, τις γεωγραφικές και γεωλογικές 
πληροφορίες όψης για όλα τα ολόκενα ηφαίστεια (εκείνοι με τη 
γνωστή δραστηριότητα κατά τη διάρκεια των τελευταίων 10.000 
ετών), και την έρευνα και τις δημοσιεύσεις κατάταξης από τα 
σμιθσονιτικά volcanologists και τους συναδέλφους τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">presenta la documentación de las erupciones de 
todos los volcanes durante los últimos 10.000 años. Los 
visitantes pueden repasar informes de actividad volcánicos, 
información geográfica y geológica de la visión para todos los 
volcanes holocene (ésos con actividad sabida durante los 10.000 años
pasados), e investigación y las publicaciones de la orden de los 
volcanologists de Smithsonian y de sus colegas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206075</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105882</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-global-volcanism-program-gvp</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
