<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105302</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105302</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087423</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Beginning of the End: Chapter One of Sinclair's The Jungle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Anfang des Endes: Kapitel eins Sinclairs vom
Dschungel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Début de l'extrémité : Chapitre un de la 
jungle de Sinclair</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Começo da extremidade: Capítulo um da 
selva de Sinclair</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Inizio dell'estremità: Capitolo uno della 
giungla del Sinclair</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αρχή του τέλους: Κεφάλαιο μια ζούγκλας 
Sinclair της</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Principio del extremo: Capítulo uno de la 
selva de Sinclair</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1904, socialist writer Upton Sinclair spent two months in Chicago's "Packingtown" observing a bitter stockyard strike. He turned the wealth of material he found there into his best-selling 1905 novel,  The Jungle . The book is best known for revealing the unsanitary process by which animals became meat products, and its revelations were an important factor in the 1906 passage of the federal Pure Food and Drug and Meat Inspection Act. Yet Sinclair's primary concern was not with the goods that were produced but with the workers who produced them. He described, with great accuracy, the horrifying physical conditions under which immigrant packing plant workers and their families worked and lived, portraying the collapse of immigrant culture under the relentless pressure of industrial capitalism. Despite his sympathies, as a middle-class reformer Sinclair was oblivious to the vibrancy of immigrant communities beyond the reach of bosses, where immigrants found solidarity and hope. In the opening chapter of  The Jungle , the immigrant hero and heroine, Juris and Ona Rudkus, celebrate their nuptials and the start of their new lives in Chicago.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1904 verbrachte sozialistischer Verfasser Upton 
Sinclair zwei Monate in Chicagos "Packingtown", das einen bitteren 
Stockyardschlag beobachtet. Er drehte die Fülle des Materials, 
das er dort in seinen fand, der Roman 1905 gut-verkauft, den 
Dschungel. Das Buch ist bekannt für das Aufdecken des 
unhygienischen Prozesses bestes, durch den Tiere Fleischprodukte 
wurden, und seine Enthüllung waren ein wichtiger Faktor im Durchgang 
1906 der reinen Nahrungsmittel-und Droge-und Fleisch-Kontrolle 
föderativtat, noch Sinclairs war- Primärinteresse nicht mit den 
Waren, die produziert wurden, aber mit den Arbeitern, die sie 
produzierten. Er beschrieb, mit großer Genauigkeit, die 
erschreckenden körperlichen Bedingungen, unter denen einwandernde 
Verpackung Betriebsarbeiter und ihre Familien arbeiteten und lebten 
und schilderte den Einsturz der einwandernden Kultur unter dem 
unnachgiebigen Druck des industriellen Kapitalismus. Trotz 
seiner Sympathien als MittelklasseReformer Sinclair zum vibrancy
der einwandernden Gemeinschaften über der Reichweite der Chefs 
hinaus, in denen Immigranten gefundene solidarität und Hoffnung 
weltvergessen waren-. Im Öffnung Kapitel des Dschungels, feiern
der einwandernde Held und die Heldin, Juris und Ona Rudkus, ihre 
nuptials und den Anfang ihrer neuen Lebensdauern in Chicago.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1904, l'auteur socialiste Upton Sinclair a 
passé deux mois dans "Packingtown" de Chicago observant une grève 
amère de parc à matériau. Il a tourné la richesse du 
matériel qu'il a trouvé là dans le sien meilleur-vendant le roman 
1905, la jungle. Le livre est meilleur connu pour indiquer le 
processus antihygiénique par lequel les animaux sont devenus des 
produits à base de viande, et ses révélations étaient un facteur 
important dans le passage 1906 de l'acte pur fédéral d'inspection de
nourriture et de drogue et de viande. Pourtant le souci primaire
de Sinclair n'était pas avec les marchandises qui ont été produites
mais avec les ouvriers qui les ont produits. Il a décrit, avec 
la grande exactitude, les conditions physiques horrifiantes dans 
lesquelles les ouvriers immigrés d'usine d'emballage et leurs 
familles ont travaillé et ont vécu, dépeignant l'effondrement de la
culture immigrée sous la pression implacable du capitalisme 
industriel. En dépit de ses sympathies, en tant que réformateur
Sinclair de classe moyenne étaient inconsciente à la vibration des
communautés immigrées au delà de l'extension des patrons, où la 
solidarité et l'espoir trouvés par immigrés. Dans le chapitre
d'ouverture de la jungle, le héros et la héroïne immigrée, Juris 
et ARO Rudkus, célèbrent leurs nuptials et le début de leurs 
nouvelles vies Chicago.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1904, o escritor socialist Upton Sinclair 
gastou dois meses em "Packingtown" de Chicago que observa uma batida 
amarga do stockyard. Girou a riqueza do material que encontrou 
lá em his quevende a novela 1905, a selva. O livro é o mais 
melhor sabido revelando o processo unsanitary por que os animais se 
transformaram produtos de carne, e seus revelations eram um fator 
importante na passagem 1906 do ato puro federal da inspeção do 
alimento e da droga e da carne contudo o interesse preliminar de 
Sinclair não era com os bens que foram produzidos mas com os 
trabalhadores que os produziram. Descreveu, com exatidão 
grande, as circunstâncias físicas horrorizando sob que os 
trabalhadores immigrant da planta da embalagem e suas famílias 
trabalharam e viveram, portraying o colapso da cultura immigrant sob a
pressão relentless do capitalismo industrial. Apesar de seus 
sympathies, como um reformer Sinclair do middle-class eram oblivious 
ao vibrancy de comunidades immigrant além do alcance das saliências,
onde o solidarity e a esperança encontrados immigrants. No 
capítulo da abertura da selva, o herói e o heroine immigrant, Juris 
e o Ona Rudkus, comemoram seus nuptials e o começo de suas vidas 
novas em Chicago.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1904, il produttore socialista Upton Sinclair 
ha speso due mesi "in Packingtown" del Chicago che osserva 
un colpo amaro del recinto per il bestiame. Ha girato la 
ricchezza di materiale che ha trovato là in suo chevende il romanzo 
1905, la giungla. Il libro è la cosa migliore conosciuto per 
rivelare il processo antigienico tramite cui gli animali si sono 
transformati in in prodotti a base di carne e le relative rivelazioni 
erano un fattore importante nel passaggio 1906 della Legge pura 
federale di controllo dell'alimento e della droga e della carne 
tuttavia la preoccupazione primaria del Sinclair non era con le merci 
che sono state prodotte ma con gli operai che li hanno prodotti. 
Ha descritto, con esattezza grande, le circostanze fisiche 
sconvolgenti in cui gli operai immigrati della pianta dell'imballaggio
e le loro famiglie hanno lavorato e vissuto, ritraenti il crollo di 
coltura immigrata sotto la pressione relentless del capitalismo 
industriale. Malgrado le sue compassione, come reformer Sinclair
della classe media erano oblivious al vibrancy delle Comunità 
immigrate oltre l'estensione delle sporgenze, in cui la solidarietà e
la speranza trovate immigranti. Nel capitolo di apertura della 
giungla, il hero ed il heroine immigrato, Juris ed il Ona Rudkus, 
celebrano i loro nuptials e l'inizio delle loro nuove vite in Chicago.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1904, σοσιαλιστικός συγγραφέας Upton 
Sinclair που ξοδεύεται δύο μήνες σε "Packingtown" του 
Σικάγου που παρατηρεί μια πικρή απεργία μαντρών. Γύρισε 
τον πλούτο του υλικού που βρήκε εκεί στο με εμπορική επιτυχία 
μυθιστόρημα του 1905 του, η ζούγκλα. Το βιβλίο είναι 
καλύτερα γνωστό για την αποκάλυψη της unsanitary διαδικασίας 
από την οποία τα ζώα έγιναν προϊόντα κρέατος, και οι 
αποκαλύψεις της ήταν ένας σημαντικός παράγοντας στη μετάβαση του
1906 του ομοσπονδιακού καθαρού νόμου επιθεώρησης τροφίμων και 
φαρμάκων και κρέατος. Ακόμα η αρχική ανησυχία Sinclair 
δεν ήταν με τα αγαθά που παρήχθησαν αλλά με τους εργαζομένους που
τα παρήγαγαν. Περιέγραψε, με τη μεγάλη ακρίβεια, τις 
τρομάζοντας φυσικές καταστάσεις κάτω από τις οποίες οι που 
έχουν μεταναστεύσει εργαζόμενοι εγκαταστάσεων συσκευασίας και οι 
οικογένειές τους εργάστηκαν και έζησαν, απεικονίζοντας την 
κατάρρευση του που έχουν μεταναστεύσει πολιτισμού διά την ανηλεή
πίεση της βιομηχανικής κεφαλαιοκρατίας. Παρά τις 
συμπόνοιές του, ως μεσαία τάξη ένας μεταρρυθμιστής Sinclair 
ήταν μη ενθυμούμενος στη δονητικότητα των που έχουν μεταναστεύσει
κοινοτήτων πέρα από την προσιτότητα των προϊσταμένων, όπου οι 
μετανάστες βρήκαν την αλληλεγγύη και την ελπίδα. Στο 
ανοίγοντας κεφάλαιο της ζούγκλας, ο που έχουν μεταναστεύσει 
ήρωας και η ηρωϊ'δα, Juris και Ona Rudkus, γιορτάζουν τα 
nuptials τους και την έναρξη των νέων ζωών τους στο Σικάγο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1904, el programa de escritura socialista Upton
Sinclair pasó dos meses en "Packingtown" de Chicago que observaba una
huelga amarga del corral. Él dio vuelta a la abundancia del 
material que él encontró allí en el suyo mejor-que vendi'a la 
novela 1905, la selva. El libro es el mejor sabido para revelar 
el proceso antihigiénico por el cual los animales se convirtieron en 
productos de carne, y sus revelaciones eran un factor importante en el
paso 1906 del acto puro federal del examen del alimento y de la droga 
y de la carne con todo la preocupación primaria de Sinclair no estaba
con las mercancías que fueron producidas pero con los trabajadores 
que los produjeron. Él describió, con gran exactitud, las 
condiciones físicas que horrorizaban bajo las cuales los trabajadores
inmigrantes de la planta del embalaje y sus familias trabajaron y 
vivieron, retratando el derrumbamiento de la cultura inmigrante bajo 
presión implacable del capitalismo industrial. A pesar de sus 
condolencias, como reformador Sinclair de la clase media al vibrancy 
de comunidades inmigrantes más allá del alcance de jefes, donde 
estaban olvidadiza la solidaridad y la esperanza encontradas los 
inmigrantes. En el capítulo de la apertura de la selva, el 
héroe y la heroína inmigrante, Juris y el Ona Rudkus, celebran sus
nuptials y el comienzo de sus nuevas vidas en Chicago.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087423</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105302</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/beginning-of-the-end-chapter-one-of-sinclairs-the-jungle</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
