<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108019</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108019</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086058</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Date With Destiny: The Gonzales Diary</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Datum Mit Schicksal: Das Gonzales Tagebuch</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Date Avec Le Destin : l'Agenda de Gonzales</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Data Com Destiny: O Diário De Gonzales</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Data Con Il Destino: Il Diario Di Gonzales</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ημερομηνία με το πεπρωμένο: Το ημερολόγιο 
Gonzales</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fecha Con Destino: El Diario De Gonzales</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The best-known image of America's 1898 war with Spain is that of Teddy Roosevelt on horseback charging with his Rough Riders up San Juan Hill in Cuba. While the Rough Riders fired the first shot in the war and were the first to raise the U.S. flag in Cuba, their exploits were greatly mythologized. In fact, Cuban troops--who had already been waging an armed struggle for independence from Spain for three years before the U.S. intervened in 1898--were crucial to the success of the larger war against Spain. Some sense of their importance can be gleaned from this account by N. G. Gonzales, the American editor of a pro-Cuban newspaper. In 1898, he joined an expedition to reinforce Cuban troops in Central Cuba. Cuban cigarmakers from Key West and Tampa (centers of Cuban-American trade union and socialist sentiment) dominated the expedition, though at least fifty black troops from the 10th Cavalry also participated. Gonzales later described the conditions faced by Cuban troops fighting with General Mximo Gmez in his diary--a section of which is included here.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das bekannteste Bild von Amerikas 1898 Krieg mit 
Spanien ist das von Teddy Roosevelt auf mit seinen rauhen Mitfahrern 
herauf San Juan Hügel in Kuba zu Pferde aufladen. Während die 
rauhen Mitfahrer den ersten Schuß im Krieg abfeuerten und die ersten 
waren, zum der VEREINIGTEN STAATEN anzuheben kennzeichnen in Kuba, 
waren ihre Großtaten mythologized groß. Unternommen hatte 
für, tatsächlich waren kubanische Truppen -- wem bereits einen 
bewaffneten Kampf für Unabhängigkeit von Spanien drei Jahre bevor 
die VEREINIGTEN STAATEN 1898 eingriffen -- zum Erfolg des größeren 
Krieges gegen Spanien entscheidend. Etwas Richtung ihres Wertes 
kann von diesem Konto von N. G. Gonzales, der amerikanische 
Herausgeber aufgelesen werden einer Pro-Kubaner Zeitung. 1898 
verband er eine Expedition, um kubanische Truppen in zentralem Kuba zu
verstärken. Kubanische cigarmakers vom Schlüsselwesten und von
Tampa (Mitten der Kubaner-Amerikanischen Gewerkschaft und des 
sozialistischen Gefühls) beherrschten die Expedition, obwohl 
mindestens fünfzig schwarze Truppen von der 10. Kavallerie auch 
teilnahmen. Gonzales beschrieb später die Bedingungen, die von 
den Cuban Truppen gegenübergestellt wurden, die mit General Mximo 
Gmez in seinem Tagebuch -- ein Kapitel kämpfen, von dem hier 
eingeschlossen ist.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'image la plus connue de la guerre de l'Amérique
1898 avec l'Espagne est celle du nounours Roosevelt chargeant à 
cheval de ses cavaliers approximatifs vers le haut de colline de San 
Juan au Cuba. Tandis que les cavaliers approximatifs 
mettaient le feu au premier projectile dans la guerre et étaient les 
premiers pour soulever les ETATS-UNIS diminuent au Cuba, leurs 
exploits étaient mythologized considérablement. En fait, les 
troupes cubaines -- pour qui avait déjà fait une lutte armée pour 
l'indépendance d'Espagne trois ans avant que les ETATS-UNIS sont 
intervenus en 1898 -- étaient cruciales au succès de la guerre plus 
grande contre l'Espagne. Un certain sens de leur importance peut
être glané de ce compte par N. G. Gonzales, l'éditeur américain 
d'un journal de pro-Cubain. En 1898, il a joint une expédition 
pour renforcer les troupes cubaines au Cuba central. Les 
cigarmakers cubains de l'ouest principal et de Tampa (centres de 
syndicat Cubain-Américain et de sentiment socialiste) ont dominé 
l'expédition, bien qu'au moins cinquante troupes noires de la 10ème 
cavalerie aient également participé. Gonzales plus tard a 
décrit les conditions faites face par des troupes de Cuban combattant
avec le Général Mximo Gmez en son agenda -- une section dont est 
inclus ici.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A imagem a mais best-known da guerra de América 
1898 com o Spain é aquela do teddy Roosevelt horseback em carregar 
com seus cavaleiros ásperos acima do monte do San Juan em Cuba. 
Quando os cavaleiros ásperos atearam fogo ao primeiro tiro na 
guerra e foram os primeiros para levantar os ESTADOS UNIDOS 
embandeiram em Cuba, suas façanhas eram mythologized extremamente. 
No fato, as tropas cuban -- quem tem empreendido já um esforço
armado para a independência de Spain para três anos antes que os 
ESTADOS UNIDOS intervieram em 1898 -- foram cruciais ao sucesso da 
guerra maior de encontro a Spain. Algum sentido de sua 
importância pode ser recolhido deste cliente por N. G. Gonzales, 
editor americano de um jornal do pro-Cubano. Em 1898, juntou uma
expedição para reforçar tropas cuban em Cuba central. Os 
cigarmakers cuban do oeste chave e do Tampa (centros da união de 
comércio Cubano-Americana e do sentiment socialist) dominaram a 
expedição, embora ao menos cinqüênta tropas pretas da 10o 
cavalaria participaram também. Gonzales descreveu mais tarde as
circunstâncias enfrentadas pelas tropas de Cubano que lutam com 
general Mximo Gmez em seu diário -- uma seção de que é incluído 
aqui.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'immagine più nota della guerra dell'America 
1898 con la Spagna è quella del teddy Roosevelt a cavallo sul 
caricarsi dei suoi riders approssimativi sulla collina di San Juan in 
Cuba. Mentre i riders approssimativi hanno infornato il primo 
colpo nella guerra ed erano i primi per alzare gli STATI UNITI 
diminuiscono in Cuba, le loro imprese erano notevolmente mythologized.
Infatti, le truppe cuban -- chi già stava intraprendendo una 
lotta munita per indipendenza dalla Spagna per tre anni prima che gli 
STATI UNITI intervenissero in 1898 -- erano cruciali al successo di 
più grande guerra contro la Spagna. Un certo senso della loro 
importanza può essere spigolato da questo cliente da N. G. Gonzales, 
l'editore americano di un giornale del pro-Cubano. In 1898, ha 
unito una spedizione per rinforzare le truppe cuban in Cuba centrale. 
I cigarmakers cuban dall'ovest chiave e da Tampa (centri del 
sindacato Cubano-Americano e del sentimento socialista) hanno dominato
la spedizione, benchè almeno cinquanta truppe nere dal decimo cavalry
egualmente partecipassero. Gonzales più successivamente ha 
descritto le circostanze affrontate da combattimento delle truppe del 
Cuban con il General Mximo Gmez in suo diario -- una sezione di cui è
incluso qui.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η πιό γνωστή εικόνα του πολέμου 1898 της Αμερικής 
με την Ισπανία είναι αυτή Teddy Roosevelt στην πλάτη αλόγου
που χρεώνει με τους τραχιούς αναβάτες του επάνω στο SAN Juan
Hill στην Κούβα. Ενώ οι τραχιοί αναβάτες έβαλαν φωτιά 
στο πρώτο πλάνο στον πόλεμο και ήταν το πρώτο για να αυξήσουν 
την ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ σημαία στην Κούβα, οι άθλοι τους ήταν πολύ. 
Στην πραγματικότητα, κουβανικά στρατεύματα -- ποιοι ήδη μια 
οπλισμένη προσπάθεια για την ανεξαρτησία από την Ισπανία για 
τρία έτη προτού να επεμβουν οι ΗΠΑ το 1898 -- ήταν κρίσιμος 
για την επιτυχία του μεγαλύτερου πολέμου ενάντια στην Ισπανία. 
Κάποια αίσθηση σπουδαιότητάς τους μπορεί να σταχυολογηθεί 
από αυτόν τον απολογισμό από Ν. Γ. Gonzales, ο αμερικανικός 
επεξεργαστής μιας υπέρ-κουβανικής εφημερίδας. Το 1898, 
ένωσε μια αποστολή για να ενισχύσει τα κουβανικά στρατεύματα στην
κεντρική Κούβα. Τα κουβανικά cigarmakers από τη βασική 
δύση και την Τάμπα (κέντρα του κουβανικός-αμερικανικού 
συνδικάτου και του σοσιαλιστικού συναισθήματος) εξουσίασαν την 
αποστολή, αν και τουλάχιστον πενήντα μαύρα στρατεύματα από το 
10ο ιππικό συμμετείχαν επίσης. Το Gonzales περιέγραψε 
αργότερα τους όρους που αντιμετωπίστηκαν από τα κουβανικά 
στρατεύματα που παλεύουν με το στρατηγό Mximo Gmez στο 
ημερολόγιό του -- ένα τμήμα του οποίου συμπεριλαμβάνεται εδώ.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La imagen más conocida de la guerra de América 
1898 con España es la del teddy Roosevelt en a caballo la carga con 
sus jinetes ásperos encima de la colina del San Juan en Cuba. 
Mientras que los jinetes ásperos encendieron el primer tiro en 
la guerra y eran los primeros para levantar los ESTADOS UNIDOS 
señalan por medio de una bandera en Cuba, sus hazañas eran 
mythologized grandemente. En hecho, las tropas cubanos -- para 
quiénes había estado emprendiendo ya una lucha armada para la 
independencia de España tres años antes de que los ESTADOS UNIDOS 
intervinieron en 1898 -- eran cruciales al éxito de la guerra más 
grande contra España. Un cierto sentido de su importancia se 
puede espigar de esta cuenta por N. G. Gonzales, el editor americano 
de un periódico del favorable-Cubano. En 1898, él ensambló a 
expedición para reforzar a tropas cubanos en Cuba central. Los 
cigarmakers cubanos del oeste dominante y de Tampa (centros del 
sindicato Cubano-Americano y del sentimiento socialista) dominaron a 
expedición, aunque por lo menos participaron cincuenta tropas negras 
de la 10ma caballería también. Gonzales describió más 
adelante las condiciones hechas frente por las tropas de cuban que 
luchaban con general Mximo Gmez en su diario -- una sección de la 
cual se incluye aquí.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086058</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108019</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/date-with-destiny-the-gonzales-diary</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
