<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108327</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108327</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207022</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology of Mental Illness</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie der Geisteskrankheit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie de maladie mentale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia da doença mental</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia della malattia mentale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία της διανοητικής ασθένειας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología de la enfermedad mental</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site provides six lessons that help students understand what mental illnesses are. PET images show changes in the brain and how treatment can change activity levels and restore functioning. Case studies and other activities explore differences among illnesses, risk factors, and treatment plan goals. Students develop a brochure to inform people about mental illness.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site liefert sechs Lektionen, die 
Kursteilnehmern helfen, zu verstehen, was Geisteskrankheiten sind. 
HAUSTIER-Bilder zeigen Änderungen im Gehirn und wie Behandlung 
Bewegungsstufen ändern und das Arbeiten wiederherstellen kann. 
Fallstudien und andere Aktivitäten erforschen Unterschiede 
unter Krankheiten, Gefahr Faktoren und Behandlungplanzielen. 
Kursteilnehmer entwickeln eine Broschüre, um Leute über 
Geisteskrankheit zu informieren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site fournit six leçons qui aident des 
étudiants à comprendre ce que sont les maladies mentales. Les 
images d'ANIMAL DE COMPAGNIE montrent des changements du cerveau et 
comment le traitement peut changer des niveaux d'activité et 
restaurer le fonctionnement. Les études de cas et d'autres 
activités explorent des différences parmi des maladies, des facteurs
de risque, et des buts de plan de traitement. Les étudiants 
développent une brochure pour informer des personnes au sujet de 
maladie mentale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local fornece seis lições que ajudam a 
estudantes compreender o que as doenças mentais são. As 
imagens do ANIMAL DE ESTIMAÇÃO mostram mudanças no cérebro e como 
o tratamento pode mudar níveis de atividade e restaurar funcionar. 
Os estudos de caso e outras atividades exploram diferenças 
entre doenças, fatores de risco, e objetivos da planta do tratamento.
Os estudantes desenvolvem um folheto para informar povos sobre a
doença mental.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo fornisce sei lezioni che aiutano gli 
allievi a capire che cosa le malattie mentali sono. Le immagini 
dell'ANIMALE DOMESTICO mostrano i cambiamenti nel cervello e come il 
trattamento può cambiare i livelli di attività e ristabilire il 
funzionamento. Le inchieste ed altre attività esplorano le 
differenze fra le malattie, i fattori di rischio e gli obiettivi di 
programma di trattamento. Gli allievi sviluppano un opuscolo per
informare la gente circa la malattia mentale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή παρέχει έξι μαθήματα που βοηθούν τους
σπουδαστές να καταλάβουν τι οι διανοητικές ασθένειες είναι. 
Οι εικόνες PET εμφανίζουν αλλαγές στον εγκέφαλο και πώς 
η επεξεργασία μπορεί να αλλάξει τα επίπεδα δραστηριότητας και να 
αποκαταστήσει τη λειτουργία. Οι περιπτωσιολογικές μελέτες 
και άλλες δραστηριότητες ερευνούν τις διαφορές μεταξύ των 
ασθενειών, των παραγόντων κινδύνου, και των στόχων σχεδίων 
επεξεργασίας. Οι σπουδαστές αναπτύσσουν ένα φυλλάδιο για να
ενημερώσουν τους ανθρώπους για τη διανοητική ασθένεια.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio proporciona a seis lecciones que ayuden
a estudiantes a entender cuáles son las enfermedades mentales. 
Las imágenes del ANIMAL DOMÉSTICO muestran cambios en el 
cerebro y cómo el tratamiento puede cambiar niveles de actividad y 
restablecer el funcionamiento. Los estudios de caso y otras 
actividades exploran diferencias entre enfermedades, factores de 
riesgo, y metas del plan del tratamiento. Los estudiantes 
desarrollan un folleto para informar a la gente sobre enfermedad 
mental.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207022</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108327</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/science-and-technology-of-mental-illness</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
