<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104089</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104089</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200411</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">American Museum of Natural History-Resources for Learning</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Amerikanisches Museum der natürlichen 
Geschichte-Hilfsmittel für das Lernen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Musée américain des Histoire-Ressources normales
pour l'étude</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Museu americano de History-Recursos naturais para 
aprender</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Museo americano delle Storia-Risorse naturali per 
imparare</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αμερικανικό μουσείο των φυσικών ιστορία-στοιχείων 
συμπεριφοράς για την εκμάθηση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Museo americano de los Historia-Recursos naturales
para aprender</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site presents a collection of scientific learning resources for educators, parents, kids, after-school coordinators, informal learning center staff, and anyone else interested in teaching or learning about science. The site provides a searchable database of resource materials, including activities (computer based and otherwise), curriculum materials, articles, evidence and analytical tools and procedures, exhibition materials, reference lists, and special collections of resources organized around a particular theme. Users can browse resources by topic, sub-topic, grade level, or resource type. Each resource is displayed with a concise description that includes the title, resource type, grade level, and key concepts. Clicking the icon next to the title displays the full resource description. If available, other icons link to the resource in print format, Web format, or both.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site stellt eine Ansammlung 
wissenschaftliche erlernenbetriebsmittel für die Erzieher, Eltern, 
Zicklein, Nachschule Koordinatoren, formlosen erlernenden 
Mittelpersonal und jedermann dar, die, sonst an dem Unterrichten oder 
dem Lernen über Wissenschaft interessiert werden. Die Site 
liefert eine auffindbare Datenbank der Hilfsmittelmaterialien, 
einschließlich die Aktivitäten (rechnergestützt und anders), der 
Lehrplanmaterialien, der Artikel, des Beweises und der analytischen 
Hilfsmittel und der Prozeduren, der Ausstellungmaterialien, der 
Bezugslisten und der speziellen Ansammlungen Betriebsmittel, die um 
ein bestimmtes Thema organisiert werden. Benutzer können 
Betriebsmittel durch Thema, Abschnitt, Gradstufe oder Hilfsmitteltypen
durchstöbern. Jedes Hilfsmittel wird mit einer kurzen 
Beschreibung angezeigt, die den Namen, den Hilfsmitteltypen, die 
Gradstufe und die Tastekonzepte einschließt. Das Anklicken der 
Ikone nahe bei dem Namen zeigt die volle Hilfsmittelbeschreibung an. 
Wenn vorhanden, binden andere Ikonen mit dem Hilfsmittel im 
Druckformat, im Web-Format oder in beiden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site présente une collection de ressources 
d'étude scientifiques pour des éducateurs, des parents, des gosses, 
des coordonnateurs d'après-école, le personnel central d'étude sans
cérémonie, et n'importe qui autrement intéressés à l'enseignement
ou à se renseigner sur la science. Le site fournit une base de 
données rechercheable des matériaux de ressource, y compris des 
activités (sur ordinateur et autrement), des matériaux de programme 
d'études, des articles, évidence et des outils analytiques et des 
procédures, des matériaux d'exposition, des listes de référence, 
et des collections spéciales de ressources organisées autour d'un 
thème particulier. Les utilisateurs peuvent parcourir des 
ressources par sujet, note sensible, niveau de catégorie, ou type de 
ressource. Chaque ressource est affichée avec une description 
concise qui inclut le titre, le type de ressource, le niveau de 
catégorie, et les concepts de clé. Cliquer le 
graphisme à côté du titre affiche la description complète de 
ressource. Si disponibles, d'autres graphismes joignent à la 
ressource dans le format d'impression, le format de Web, ou 
tous les deux.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local apresenta uma coleção de recursos de 
aprendizagem científicos para os educadores, os pais, os miúdos, os 
coordenadores da após-escola, a equipe de funcionários center de 
aprendizagem informal, e a qualquer um interessados mais em ensinar ou
na aprender sobre a ciência. O local fornece uma base de dados 
searchable de materiais do recurso, including atividades (computador 
baseado e de outra maneira), materiais do curriculum, artigos, 
evidência e ferramentas analíticas e procedimentos, materiais de 
exhibition, listas de referência, e coleções especiais dos recursos
organizados em torno de um tema particular. Os usuários podem 
browse recursos pelo tópico, pelo sub-topic, pelo nível da classe, 
ou pelo tipo do recurso. Cada recurso é indicado com uma 
descrição concisa que inclua o título, o tipo do recurso, o nível 
da classe, e os conceitos da chave. Estalar o ícone ao lado do 
título indica a descrição cheia do recurso. Se disponíveis, 
outros ícones ligam ao recurso no formato da cópia, no formato do 
Web, ou em ambos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo presenta una collezione di risorse 
imparanti scientifiche per gli educatori, i genitori, i capretti, i 
coordinatori della dopo-scuola, il personale concentr imparante 
informale e chiunque altrimenti interessati all'istruzione o ad 
imparare circa la scienza. Il luogo fornisce una base di dati 
reperibile dei materiali delle risorse, compreso le attività 
(computerizzate ed al contrario), materiali di programma di studi, 
articoli, prova e strumenti analitici e procedure, materiali per 
esposizioni, gli indici bibliografici e collezioni speciali di risorse
organizzate intorno ad un tema particolare. Gli utenti possono 
passare in rassegna le risorse dal soggetto, dal sub-topic, dal 
livello del grado, o dal tipo delle risorse. Ogni risorsa è 
visualizzata con una descrizione concisa che include il titolo, il 
tipo delle risorse, il livello del grado ed i concetti di tasto. 
Scattare l'icona vicino al titolo visualizza la descrizione 
completa delle risorse. Se disponibili, altre icone si collegano
alla risorsa nel formato della stampa, nel formato di Web, o in 
entrambi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή παρουσιάζει μια συλλογή των 
επιστημονικών στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς εκμάθησης για τους 
εκπαιδευτικούς, τους γονείς, τα κατσίκια, τους μετά 
από-σχολικούς συντονιστές, το άτυπο προσωπικό κέντρων 
εκμάθησης, και οποιοδήποτε άλλοδήποτε ενδιαφερόμενο στη 
διδασκαλία ή την εκμάθηση για την επιστήμη. Η περιοχή 
παρέχει μια εξερευνήσιμη βάση δεδομένων των υλικών των στοιχείων
συμπεριφοράς, συμπεριλαμβανομένων των δραστηριοτήτων (βασισμένων 
σε υπολογιστή και ειδάλλως), των υλικών προγράμματος σπουδών, των
άρθρων, των στοιχείων και των αναλυτικών εργαλείων και των 
διαδικασιών, των υλικών έκθεσης, των καταλόγων αναφοράς, και των 
ειδικών συλλογών των στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς που οργανώνονται 
γύρω από ένα ιδιαίτερο θέμα. Οι χρήστες μπορούν να 
περιοδεύσουν τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς από το θέμα, το επιμέρους 
θέμα, το επίπεδο βαθμού, ή τον τύπο των στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς.
Κάθε στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς παρουσιάζεται με μια συνοπτική 
περιγραφή που περιλαμβάνει τον τίτλο, τον τύπο των στοιχείων 
συμπεριφοράς, το επίπεδο βαθμού, και τις βασικές έννοιες. Ο
κρότος του εικονιδίου δίπλα στον τίτλο παρουσιάζει την πλήρη 
περιγραφή των στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς. Εάν διαθέσιμα, άλλα 
εικονίδια συνδέουν με το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς και με τη μορφή 
τυπωμένων υλών, τη μορφή Ιστού, ή τις δύο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio presenta una colección de los recursos
que aprenden científicos para los educadores, los padres, los 
cabritos, los coordinadores de la despue's-escuela, el personal de 
centro que aprende informal, y cualquier persona  interesados en la 
enseñanza o aprender sobre ciencia. El sitio proporciona a una 
base de datos investigable de los materiales del recurso, incluyendo 
las actividades (computarizadas y de otra manera), los materiales del 
plan de estudios, los artículos, evidencia y las herramientas 
analíticas y los procedimientos, los materiales de exposición, las 
listas de referencia, y las colecciones especiales de recursos 
ordenados alrededor de un tema determinado. Los utilizadores 
pueden hojear recursos por asunto, subtema, el nivel del grado, o el 
tipo del recurso. Cada recurso se visualiza con una descripción
sucinta que incluya el título, el tipo del recurso, el nivel del 
grado, y los conceptos del clave. Hacer clic el icono al lado 
del título visualiza la descripción completa del recurso. Si 
esta'n disponibles, otros iconos conectan al recurso en formato de la 
impresión, formato del Web, o ambos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200411</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104089</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/american-museum-of-natural-history-resources-for-learning</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
