<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105722</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105722</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212584</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Grand Canyon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Grand Canyon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Gorge Grande</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A Garganta Grande</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Grande Canyon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το μεγάλο φαράγγι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Barranca Magnífica</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Over the course of several lessons, this lesson plan deals with the consequences of damming in the Grand Canyon area. Students act as scientists investigating the damming of the Colorado River by the Glen Canyon dam and experimental flooding that took place in 1996. They then write a proposal as to whether or not more experimental flooding should be done on the area considering the ecological effects. This topic has great potential for an Earth Systems Science class, as the consequences of damming affect climate, ecosystems, sedimentation/erosion, and water quality. On this Starting Point page, users can find learning goals, teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment hints and references and resources dealing with this exercise. It also describes the context in which the lesson is best used.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Über dem Kurs einiger Lektionen, beschäftigt 
dieser Lektionplan die Konsequenzen des Stauens im Grand 
Canyonbereich. Kursteilnehmer dienen als die Wissenschaftler, 
die das Stauen des Kolorado Flusses durch die Glen-Schluchtverdammung 
und die experimentelle Überschwemmung, die, nachforschen 1996 
stattfanden. Sie schreiben dann einen Antrag, ob oder nicht 
experimentellere Überschwemmung auf dem Bereich erfolgt werden 
sollte, der die ökologischen Effekte betrachtet. Dieses Thema 
hat großes Potential für eine Masse Systeme Wissenschaft Kategorie, 
da die Konsequenzen des Stauens Klima, Oekosysteme, 
sedimentation/erosion und Wasserqualität beeinflussen. Auf 
dieser Ausgangspunktseite können Benutzer die erlernenziele, 
unterrichtende Anmerkungen und Spitzen, Lehrmittel, Einschätzung Tips
und Referenzen und Betriebsmittel beschäftigend diese Übung finden. 
Sie beschreibt auch den Kontext, in dem die Lektion gut 
verwendet wird.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Au-dessus du cours de plusieurs leçons, ce plan 
de leçon traite les conséquences du barrage dans la région de gorge
grande. Les étudiants agissent en tant que scientifiques 
étudiant le barrage du fleuve du Colorado par le barrage de gorge de 
gorge et l'inondation expérimentale qui ont eu lieu en 1996. 
Ils écrivent alors une proposition de savoir si ou une 
inondation plus expérimentale devrait être faite sur la zone 
considérant les effets écologiques. Ce sujet a le grand 
potentiel pour une classe de la Science de systèmes de la terre, car 
les conséquences du barrage affectent le climat, les écosystèmes, 
le sedimentation/erosion, et la qualité de l'eau. À cette page
de point de départ, les utilisateurs peuvent trouver des buts 
d'étude, des notes et des extrémités d'enseignement, matériel 
didactique, des conseils d'évaluation et des références et des 
ressources traitant cet exercice. Il décrit également le 
contexte dans lequel la leçon mieux est utilisée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Sobre o curso de diversas lições, esta planta da
lição trata das conseqüências de represar na área da garganta 
grande. Os estudantes agem como os cientistas que investigam 
represar do rio de Colorado pela represa da garganta do glen e pelo 
flooding experimental que ocorreram em 1996. Escrevem então uma
proposta a respeito de se ou um flooding mais experimental deve ser 
feito na área que considera os efeitos ecological. Este tópico
tem o potencial grande para uma classe da ciência dos sistemas da 
terra, porque as conseqüências de represar afetam o clima, os 
ecosystems, o sedimentation/erosion, e a qualidade de água. 
Nesta página do ponto começar, os usuários podem encontrar os
objetivos de aprendizagem, as notas e as pontas ensinando, os 
materiais de ensino, as sugestões da avaliação e as referências e 
os recursos tratando deste exercício. Descreve também o 
contexto em que a lição é usada melhor.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sopra il corso di parecchie lezioni, questo 
programma di lezione si occupa delle conseguenze di arginare nella 
zona del grande canyon. Gli allievi fungono da scienziati che 
studiano arginare del fiume del Colorado tramite la diga del canyon 
del glen ed il flooding sperimentale che hanno avvenuto in 1996. 
Allora scrivono una proposta se o il flooding più sperimentale 
dovrebbe essere fatto sulla zona che considera gli effetti ecologici. 
Questo soggetto ha potenziale grande per un codice categoria di 
scienza dei sistemi della terra, poichè le conseguenze di arginare 
interessano il clima, gli ecosistemi, sedimentation/erosion e la 
qualità dell'acqua. A questa pagina del punto di partenza, gli 
utenti possono trovare gli obiettivi imparanti, note e punte 
d'istruzione, materiali didattici, suggerimenti di valutazione e 
riferimenti e risorse occupantesi di questa esercitazione. 
Egualmente descrive il contesto in cui la lezione è usata il 
più bene.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατά τη διάρκεια διάφορων μαθημάτων, αυτό το σχέδιο 
μαθήματος εξετάζει τις συνέπειες να φράξει στη μεγάλη περιοχή 
φαραγγιών. Οι σπουδαστές ενεργούν ως επιστήμονες που να 
φράξουν του ποταμού του Κολοράντο από το φράγμα φαραγγιών 
Glen και η πειραματική πλημμύρα που πραγματοποιήθηκαν το 
1996. Συντάσσουν έπειτα μια πρόταση ως προς το εάν η πιό
πειραματική πλημμύρα πρέπει να γίνει στην περιοχή εξετάζοντας τα
οικολογικά αποτελέσματα. Αυτό το θέμα έχει τη μεγάλη 
δυνατότητα για μια κλάση επιστήμης γήινων συστημάτων, δεδομένου 
ότι οι συνέπειες να φράξουν έχουν επιπτώσεις στο κλίμα, τα 
οικοσυστήματα, την ιζηματογένεση/τη διάβρωση, και την ποιότητα 
νερού. Σε αυτήν την σελίδα αφετηρίας, οι χρήστες μπορούν 
να βρούν τους στόχους εκμάθησης, τις σημειώσεις και τις άκρες 
διδασκαλίας, τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, τους υπαινιγμούς αξιολόγησης 
και τις αναφορές και τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς εξετάζοντας αυτήν 
την άσκηση. Περιγράφει επίσης το πλαίσιο στο οποίο το 
μάθημα χρησιμοποιείται καλύτερα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sobre el curso de varias lecciones, este plan de 
la lección se ocupa de las consecuencias de contener en el área de 
la barranca magnífica. Los estudiantes actúan como 
científicos que investigan contener del río de Colorado por la presa
de la barranca de la cañada y el flooding experimental que ocurrieron
en 1996. Entonces escriben una oferta si o un flooding más 
experimental se debe hacer en el área que considera los efectos 
ecológicos. Este asunto tiene gran potencial para una clase de 
la ciencia de los sistemas de la tierra, pues las consecuencias de 
contener afectan clima, ecosistemas, sedimentation/erosion, y calidad 
del agua. En esta paginación del punto de partida, los 
utilizadores pueden encontrar las metas que aprenden, las notas y las 
extremidades de enseñanza, los materiales didácticos, las indirectas
del gravamen y las referencias y los recursos ocupándose de este 
ejercicio. También describe el contexto en el cual la lección 
se utiliza lo más mejor posible.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212584</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105722</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-grand-canyon</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
