<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104214</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104214</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086932</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Evil Shadow of Slavery No Longer Hangs Over Them": Charlotte Forten Describes Her Experiences Teaching on the South Carolina Sea Islands, 1862</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"der schlechte Schatten der Sklaverei hängt nicht
mehr über ihr": Charlotte Forten beschreibt sie die 
Erfahrungen, die auf den Südcarolina Seeinseln, 1862 unterrichten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"l'ombre mauvaise de l'esclavage ne s'arrête plus
au-dessus d'elles" : Charlotte Forten la décrit les 
expériences enseignant sur les îles du sud de mer de la 
Caroline, 1862</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"a sombra evil do slavery pendura não mais por 
muito tempo sobre eles": Charlotte Forten descreve-a as 
experiências que ensinam nos consoles do mar de carolina sul, 1862</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"l'ombra diabolica di slavery più non appende 
sopra loro": Charlotte Forten la descrive esperienze che 
insegnano sulle isole del mare della Carolina del Sud, 1862</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η κακή σκιά της σκλαβιάς δεν κρεμά πλέον πέρα από 
τουσ": Το Σαρλόττα Forten περιγράφει την εμπειρία της 
διδασκαλικός στα νησιά θάλασσας της νότιας Καρολίνας, 1862</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"la sombra malvada de la esclavitud cuelga no más
de largo sobre ella": Charlotte Forten la describe las 
experiencias que enseñan en las islas del mar de Carolina del Sur, 
1862</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">During the Civil War, when Union forces occupied the South Carolina sea islands of St. Helena and Port Royal, white slaveowners fled but their slaves remained. It was here, in October 1862, that Charlotte Forten arrived under the auspices of the Philadelphia Port Royal Relief Association to teach the newly liberated slaves. Forten (later Charlotte Forten Grimke) was born in Philadelphia in 1837 into a family of well-to-do, free blacks who were active in the abolitionist movement. Forten was a teacher and a writer, known today for her extensive diaries and her articles. An educated woman and a product of free black society, Forten hovered uneasily between the worlds of blacks and whites. In this article for a white audience she expressed her jubilation about the freedom her students were newly experiencing. She also revealed her ambivalence about these people who were similar to herself, yet at the same time so different.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während des Bürgerkrieges als Anschlußkräfte 
die Südcarolina Seeinseln von St. Helena und von Kanal besetzten, die
königlich sind, flohen weiße slaveowners, aber ihre Sklaven blieben.
Es war hier, im Oktober 1862, daß Charlotte Forten unter den 
Auspizienn der Philadelphia königlichen Entlastung Portverbindung 
ankam, um die eben befreiten Sklaven zu unterrichten. Forten 
(neueres Charlotte Forten Grimke) wurde in Philadelphia 1837 in eine 
Familie von gut-zu-, freie Schwarze getragen, die in der abolitionist 
Bewegung aktiv waren. Forten war ein Lehrer und ein Verfasser, 
heute bekannt für ihre umfangreichen Tagebücher und ihre Artikel. 
Eine gebildete Frau und ein Produkt der freien schwarzen 
Gesellschaft, Forten schwoben unbehaglich zwischen den Welten von 
Schwarzen und Weiß. In diesem Artikel für ein weißes Publikum
drückte sie ihr jubilation über die Freiheit aus, die ihre 
Kursteilnehmer eben erfuhren. Sie deckte auch ihre ambivalenz 
über diese Leute, die ähnlich waren, dennoch gleichzeitig so 
unterschiedlich auf.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant la guerre civile, quand les forces des 
syndicats ont occupé les îles du sud de mer de la Caroline de 
la Ste.Hélène et du port royaux, les slaveowners blancs se sont 
sauvés mais leurs esclaves sont restés. Elle était ici, en 
octobre 1862, que Charlotte Forten est arrivé sous les auspices de 
l'association royale gauche de soulagement de Philadelphie pour 
enseigner les esclaves nouvellement libérés. Forten (plus 
défunt Charlotte Forten Grimke) a été soutenu à Philadelphie en 
1837 dans une famille de bien-à-, les noirs libres qui étaient en 
activité dans le mouvement d'abolitionniste. Forten était un 
professeur et un auteur, connus aujourd'hui pour ses agendas étendus 
et ses articles. Une femme instruite et un produit de la 
société noire libre, Forten ont plané avec difficulté entre les 
mondes des noirs et les blancs. En cet article pour une 
assistance blanche elle a exprimé sa jubilation au sujet de la 
liberté que ses étudiants éprouvaient nouvellement. Elle a 
également indiqué son ambivalence au sujet de ces personnes qui 
étaient semblables à elle-même, pourtant en même temps si 
différent.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Durante a guerra civil, quando as forças da 
união ocuparam os consoles do mar de carolina sul de St. Helena e 
porta reais, os slaveowners brancos fujiram mas seus escravos 
remanesceram. Estava aqui, em outubro 1862, que Charlotte Forten
chegou sob os auspices da associação real portuária do relevo de 
Filadélfia para ensinar os escravos recentemente liberated. 
Forten (Charlotte mais atrasado Forten Grimke) foi carregado em 
Filadélfia em 1837 em uma família de bem-à-, os pretos livres que 
eram ativos no movimento do abolitionist. Forten era um 
professor e um escritor, conhecidos hoje para seus diários extensivos
e seus artigos. Uma mulher educada e um produto da sociedade 
preta livre, Forten pairaram inquieta entre os mundos dos pretos e 
brancos. Neste artigo para uma audiência branca expressou seu 
jubilation sobre a liberdade que seus estudantes experimentavam 
recentemente. Revelou também seu ambivalence sobre estes povos 
que eram similares a herself, contudo ao mesmo tempo assim diferente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Durante la guerra civile, quando le forze del 
sindacato hanno occupato le isole del mare della Carolina del Sud 
della Sant'Elena e della porta reali, gli slaveowners bianchi sono 
fuggito ma i loro schiavi sono rimasto. Era qui, nel mese di 
ottobre del 1862, che Charlotte Forten è arrivato sotto gli auspici 
dell'associazione reale port di rilievo de Filadelfia per insegnare 
gli schiavi recentemente liberati. Forten (Charlotte successiva 
Forten Grimke) è stato sopportato a Filadelfia in 1837 in una 
famiglia di bene-$$$-, neri liberi che erano attivi nel movimento di 
abolitionist. Forten era un insegnante e un produttore, 
conosciuti oggi per i suoi vasti diari ed i suoi articoli. Una 
donna istruita e un prodotto della società nera libera, Forten si 
sono librati uneasily fra i mondi dei neri ed i bianchi. In 
questo articolo per un pubblico bianco ha espresso il suo jubilation 
circa la libertà che i suoi allievi recentemente stavano 
sperimentando. Egualmente ha rivelato la sua ambivalenza circa 
questa gente che era simile a sè, tuttavia allo stesso tempo così 
differente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατά τη διάρκεια του εμφύλιου πολέμου, όταν 
κατέλαβαν οι δυνάμεις ένωσης τα νησιά θάλασσας της νότιας 
Καρολίνας των βασιλικών, άσπρων slaveowners της Σάντα Έλενα 
και λιμένων τρεπόμενων σε φυγή αλλά των σκλάβων τους παρέμεινε. 
Ήταν εδώ, τον Οκτώβριο του 1862, ότι το Σαρλόττα 
Forten έφθασε υπό την αιγίδα της βασιλικής ένωσης ανακούφισης
λιμένων της Φιλαδέλφειας για να διδάξει τους πρόσφατα 
ελευθερωμένους σκλάβους. Το Forten (πιό πρόσφατο 
Σαρλόττα Forten Grimke) γεννήθηκε στη Φιλαδέλφεια το 1837 
σε μια οικογένεια των ευκατάστατων, ελεύθερων Μαύρων που 
δραστηριοποιήθηκαν στη μετακίνηση ρεφορμιστών. Το Forten 
ήταν ένας δάσκαλος και ένας συγγραφέας, που ήταν γνωστός 
σήμερα για τα εκτενή ημερολόγιά της και τα άρθρα της. Μια 
μορφωμένη γυναίκα και ένα προϊόν της ελεύθερης μαύρης 
κοινωνίας, Forten αιωρήθηκαν ανήσυχα μεταξύ των κόσμων των 
Μαύρων και των λευκών. Σε αυτό το άρθρο για ένα άσπρο 
ακροατήριο εξέφρασε την αγαλλίασή της για την ελευθερία οι 
σπουδαστές που της δοκίμαζαν πρόσφατα. Αποκάλυψε επίσης την
αμφιθυμία της για αυτούς τους ανθρώπους που ήταν παρόμοιοι με 
την, όμως συγχρόνως τόσο διαφορετικοί.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Durante la guerra civil, cuando las fuerzas de la 
unión ocuparon las islas del mar de Carolina del Sur de St. Helena y 
del acceso reales, los slaveowners blancos huyeron pero sus esclavos 
permanecían. Estaba aquí, en octubre de 1862, que Charlotte 
Forten llegó bajo auspicios de la asociación real portuaria de la 
relevación de Philadelphia para enseñar a los esclavos nuevamente 
liberados. Forten (una Charlotte más última Forten Grimke) fue
llevado en Philadelphia en 1837 en una familia de bien-a-, los negros 
libres que eran activos en el movimiento del abolitionist. 
Forten era profesor y programa de escritura, conocidos hoy para 
sus diarios extensos y sus artículos. Una mujer educada y un 
producto de la sociedad negra libre, Forten asomaron inquieto entre 
los mundos de negros y los blancos. En este artículo para una 
audiencia blanca ella expresó su jubilation sobre la libertad que sus
estudiantes experimentaban nuevamente. Ella también reveló su 
ambivalencia sobre esta gente que era similar a se, con todo en el 
mismo tiempo tan diferente.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086932</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104214</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-evil-shadow-of-slavery-no-longer-hangs-over-them-charlotte-forten-describes-her-experiences-teaching-on-the-south-carolina-sea-islands-1862</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
