<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106923</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106923</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206210</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">National Atlas of the United States</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nationaler Atlas der Vereinigten Staaten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Atlas national des Etats-Unis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Atlas nacional dos estados unidos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'atlante nazionale del unito Dichiara</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εθνικός άτλαντας των Ηνωμένων Πολιτειών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Atlas nacional de los Estados Unidos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a primary source of U.S. maps and geographic information. Zoom in on your state and make your own map by selecting features to display: cities and counties, roads and rivers, population and 109th congressional districts, crops and livestock, amphibians and butterflies, air and water quality, earthquakes and land cover, forest types, and more. Print a U.S. map (with or without names of states and capitals). Find an aerial photo of your neighborhood.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist eine Primärquelle der VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Karten und der geographischen Informationen. Zoom innen auf 
Ihren Zustand und bilden Sie Ihre eigene Karte, indem Sie Merkmale 
auswählen, um anzuzeigen: Städte und Grafschaften, Straßen 
und Flüsse, Bevölkerung und 109. Kongreßbezirke, Getreide und Vieh,
Amphibien und Basisrecheneinheiten, Luft- und Wasserqualität, 
Erdbeben und Landabdeckung, Waldtypen und mehr. Drucken Sie eine
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Karte (mit oder ohne Namen der Zustände und der 
Kapitalien). Finden Sie ein Luftfoto Ihrer Nachbarschaft.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est une source primaire de cartes des ETATS-UNIS 
et information géographique. Bourdonnez dedans sur votre état 
et faites votre propre carte en choisissant des dispositifs pour 
afficher : villes et comtés, routes et fleuves, population et 
109th zones congressionnelles, collectes et bétail, amphibies et 
papillons, qualité d'air et de l'eau, tremblements de terre et 
couverture de terre, types de forêt, et plus. Imprimez une 
carte des ETATS-UNIS (avec ou sans des noms des états et des 
capitaux). Trouvez une photo aérienne de votre voisinage.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é uma fonte preliminar de mapas de ESTADOS UNIDOS
e da informação geográfica. Zumba dentro em seu estado e 
faça seu próprio mapa selecionando características para indicar: 
cidades e condados, estradas e rios, população e 109th 
distritos congressionais, colheitas e animais domésticos, anfíbios e
borboletas, qualidade do ar e de água, terremotos e tampa de terra, 
tipos da floresta, e mais. Imprima um mapa de ESTADOS UNIDOS 
(com ou sem nomes dos estados e dos capitais). Encontre uma foto
aérea de sua vizinhança.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è una sorgente primaria dei programmi degli STATI
UNITI e delle informazioni geografiche. Zumi dentro sul vostro 
dichiarano e fanno il vostro proprio programma selezionando le 
caratteristiche per visualizzare: città e contee, strade e 
fiumi, popolazione e 109th distretti congressuali, raccolti e 
bestiame, anfibi e farfalle, qualità dell'acqua e dell'aria, 
terremoti e tipi di terreno, tipi della foresta e più. Stampi 
un programma degli STATI UNITI (con o senza i nomi di dichiara 
e capitali). Trovi una foto aerea della vostra vicinanza.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι μια αρχική πηγή ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΩΝ χαρτών και 
γεωγραφικών πληροφοριών. Το ζουμ μέσα στο κράτος σας και 
κάνει το χάρτη σας με την επιλογή των χαρακτηριστικών γνωρισμάτων
που παρουσιάζουν: πόλεις και νομοί, δρόμοι και ποταμοί, 
πληθυσμός και 109th του Κογκρέσου περιοχές, συγκομιδές και 
ζωικό κεφάλαιο, αμφίβια και πεταλούδες, αέρας και ποιότητα 
νερού, σεισμοί και κάλυψη εδάφους, δασικοί τύποι, και 
περισσότεροι. Τυπώστε έναν ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ χάρτη (με ή χωρίς 
ονόματα των κρατών και των κεφαλαίων). Βρείτε μια εναέρια 
φωτογραφία της γειτονιάς σας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es una fuente primaria de las correspondencias de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS y de la información geográfica. Enfoque adentro
en su estado y haga su propia correspondencia seleccionando 
características para visualizar: ciudades y condados, caminos y
ríos, población y 10øs districtos del congreso, cosechas y ganado, 
anfibios y mariposas, calidad del aire y del agua, terremotos y 
cubierta de pista, tipos del bosque, y más. Imprima una 
correspondencia de ESTADOS UNIDOS (con o sin nombres de estados y de 
capitales). Encuentre una foto aérea de su vecindad.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206210</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106923</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/nationalatlas.gov</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
