<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108003</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108003</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087163</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Victory on the Menu: Recipes and Rationing</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sieg auf dem Menü: Rezepte und Rationieren</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Victoire sur le menu : Recettes et 
rationnement</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Vitória no menu: Receitas e racionar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Vittoria sul menu: Ricette e razionare</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Νίκη στον κατάλογο επιλογής: Συνταγές και 
διανομή με δελτίο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Victoria en el menú: Recetas y el racionar</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">With U.S. entry into World War I, President Woodrow Wilson appointed Herbert Hoover to head the newly created U.S. Food Administration. A mining engineer who had successfully organized the massive effort to get food to Belgium's citizens after the German army's sweep through that country in 1914, Hoover was now charged with managing domestic agriculture and conservation in order to feed the U.S. Army and assist Allied armies and civilians. "Food Will Win the War," declared the Food Administration through its ubiquitous posters and publicity efforts. Planting gardens, observing voluntary rationing, avoiding waste--these efforts at food conservation all came to be known as "Hooverizing." Women's magazines also took up the home conservation crusade.  Good Housekeeping  printed menus, offering housewives directions for preparing tasty meals that met conservation standards. Contributed by readers, this "month's worth of recipes" printed in August 1917 demonstrated conservation in action, as well as women's ingenuity in redesigning menus to observe rationing guidelines.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mit VEREINIGTE STAATEN Eintrag in den Ersten 
Weltkrieg, ernannte Präsident Woodrow Wilson Herbert Staubsauger, um 
die eben erstellte VEREINIGTE STAATEN Nahrungsmittelleitung 
voranzugehen. Ein Mineningenieur, der erfolgreich die massive 
Bemühung organisiert hatte, Nahrung an Bürger Belgiens nach der 
deutschen Schleife der Armee durch dieses Land 1914 zu gelangen, 
Staubsauger wurde jetzt mit dem Handhaben der inländischen 
Landwirtschaft und der Erhaltung, um die VEREINIGTE STAATEN Armee 
einzuziehen und verbündete Armeen und Zivilisten zu unterstützen 
aufgeladen. "Nahrung gewinnt den Krieg," erklärte die 
Nahrungsmittelleitung durch seine überall vorhandenen Plakate und 
Werbebemühungen. Gärten errichten, das freiwillige Rationieren
beobachtend und vermeiden Vergeudung -- diese Bemühungen an der 
Nahrungsmittelerhaltung alle kamen, als "Hooverizing bekannt." 
Zeitschriften der Frauen nahmen auch den Haupterhaltung Kreuzzug
auf. Gute Haushaltung druckte die Menüs und bot Hausfrauen 
Richtungen für das Vorbereiten der geschmackvollen Mahlzeiten an, die
Erhaltung Standards entsprachen. Beigetragen durch Leser, 
druckte Wert dieses "Monats von Rezepten" im August 1917 demonstrierte
Erhaltung in der Tätigkeit, sowie Scharfsinn der Frauen in neu 
entwerfenden Menüs, um das Rationieren der Korrekturlinien zu 
beobachten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Avec l'entrée des ETATS-UNIS dans la Première 
Guerre Mondiale, le Président Woodrow Wilson a nommé l'aspirateur 
d'Herbert pour diriger la gestion nouvellement créée de nourriture 
des ETATS-UNIS. Un ingénieur des mines qui avait avec succès 
organisé l'effort massif d'obtenir la nourriture aux citoyens de la 
Belgique après le champ de l'armée allemande par ce pays en 1914, 
aspirateur a été maintenant chargé de parvenir l'agriculture et 
l'économie domestiques afin d'alimenter l'armée des ETATS-UNIS et 
aider les armées et les civils alliés. la "nourriture gagnera 
la guerre," a déclaré la gestion de nourriture par ses affiches et 
efforts omniprésents de publicité. Plantant des jardins, 
observant le rationnement volontaire, évitant la perte -- ces efforts
à l'économie de nourriture tous sont venus pour être connus en tant
que "Hooverizing." Les magazines des femmes ont également pris 
la croisade à la maison d'économie. Le bon ménage a imprimé 
des menus, offrant à des femmes au foyer des directions pour 
préparer les repas savoureux qui ont répondu à des normes 
d'économie. Contribué par des lecteurs, valeur de ce la "mois 
des recettes" a imprimé en août 1917 a démontré l'économie dans 
l'action, aussi bien que l'ingéniosité des femmes dans les menus de 
remodelage pour observer rationner des directives.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Com entrada de ESTADOS UNIDOS no world.war.i, o 
presidente Woodrow Wilson apontou o hoover de Herbert para dirigir a 
administração recentemente criada do alimento de ESTADOS UNIDOS. 
Um coordenador de mineração que organizasse com sucesso o 
esforço maciço começar o alimento aos cidadãos de Bélgica após a
varredura do exército alemão através desse país em 1914, hoover 
foi carregado agora com controlar a agricultura e o conservation 
domésticos a fim alimentar o exército de ESTADOS UNIDOS e ajudar a 
exércitos e a civis aliados. o "alimento ganhará a guerra," 
declarou a administração do alimento com seus posteres e esforços 
ubiquitous do publicity. Plantando jardins, observando racionar 
voluntário, evitando o desperdício -- estes esforços no 
conservation do alimento todos vieram ser sabidos como "Hooverizing." 
Os compartimentos das mulheres fizeram exame também acima do 
crusade home do conservation. As tarefas domésticas boas 
imprimiram os menus, oferecendo a housewives sentidos para preparar as
refeições tasty que se encontraram com padrões do conservation. 
Contribuído por leitores, o valor deste "mês das receitas" 
imprimiu em agosto 1917 demonstrou o conservation na ação, 
as.well.as o ingenuity das mulheres em menus redesigning para observar
racionar guidelines.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Con l'entrata degli STATI UNITI nel world.war.i, il
presidente Woodrow Wilson ha nominato il hoover del Herbert per 
dirigere la gestione recentemente creata dell'alimento degli STATI 
UNITI. Un assistente tecnico di estrazione mineraria che aveva 
organizzato con successo lo sforzo voluminoso ottenere l'alimento ai 
cittadini del Belgio dopo la spazzata dell'esercito tedesco attraverso
quel paese in 1914, hoover ora è stato caricato del riuscire 
l'agricoltura e la conservazione domestiche per alimentare l'esercito 
degli STATI UNITI ed aiutare gli eserciti ed i civili alleati. 
"l'alimento vincerà la guerra," ha dichiarato la gestione 
dell'alimento con i relativi manifesti e sforzi ubiquisti di 
pubblicità. Piantando i giardini, osservando razionamento 
volontario, evitante spreco -- questi sforzi a conservazione 
dell'alimento tutti sono venuto essere conosciuti come "Hooverizing." 
Gli scomparti delle donne egualmente hanno preso il crusade 
domestico di conservazione. Il buon governo della casa ha 
stampato i menu, offrenti a casalinghe i sensi per la preparazione dei
pasti saporiti che hanno risposto agli standard di conservazione. 
Contribuito dai lettori, il valore di questo "mese delle 
ricette" ha stampato in agosto 1917 ha dimostrato la conservazione 
nell'azione, così come ingegnosità delle donne nei menu di 
riprogettazione per osservare il razionamento della guida di 
riferimento.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Με την ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ είσοδο μέσα σε τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο
Ι, ο Πρόεδρος Woodrow Wilson ανέθεσε σε Herbert Hoover 
να διευθύνει την πρόσφατα δημιουργημένη διοίκηση ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΩΝ 
τροφίμων. Ένας μηχανικός μεταλλείας που είχε οργανώσει 
επιτυχώς την ογκώδη προσπάθεια να φτάσει τα τρόφιμα στους 
πολίτες του Βελγίου μετά από το σκούπισμα του γερμανικού 
στρατού μέσω εκείνης της χώρας το 1914, Hoover χρεώθηκε 
τώρα με να κατορθώσει την εσωτερικές γεωργία και τη συντήρηση 
προκειμένου να ταϊστεί ο ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΣ στρατός και να βοηθηθούν οι
συνδεμένοι στρατοί και οι πολίτες. "Τα τρόφιμα θα κερδίσουν
τον πόλεμο," δήλωσε τη διοίκηση τροφίμων μέσω των πανταχού 
παρουσών αφισών και των προσπαθειών δημοσιότητάς του. 
Φυτεύοντας τους κήπους, παρατηρώντας την εθελοντική διανομή
με δελτίο, που αποφεύγει τα απόβλητα -- αυτές οι προσπάθειες στη 
συντήρηση τροφίμων όλες ήρθαν να μαθευτούν ως "Hooverizing." 
Τα περιοδικά των γυναικών έλαβαν επίσης τη σταυροφορία 
βασικής συντήρησης. Η καλή οικοκυρική τύπωσε τους 
καταλόγους επιλογής, που προσφέρουν τις κατευθύνσεις νοικοκυρών 
για την προετοιμασία των νόστιμων γευμάτων που ανταποκρίθηκαν στα 
πρότυπα συντήρησης. Από τους αναγνώστες, αξία αυτού του η 
"μήνα των συνταγών" που τυπώθηκαν τον τον Αύγουστο του 1917 
κατέδειξε τη συντήρηση στην ενέργεια, καθώς επίσης και την 
ευστροφία γυναικών να ξανασχεδιάσει τους καταλόγους επιλογής για 
να παρατηρήσει τις οδηγίες διανομής με δελτίο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Con la entrada de ESTADOS UNIDOS en Primera Guerra 
Mundial, presidente Woodrow Wilson designó la aspiradora de Herberto 
para dirigir la administración nuevamente creada del alimento de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS. Ahora cargaron a un ingeniero de explotación 
minera que había ordenado con éxito el esfuerzo masivo de conseguir 
el alimento a los ciudadanos de Bélgica después del barrido del 
ejército alemán a través de ese país en 1914, aspiradora con el 
manejo de agricultura y de la conservación domésticas para alimentar
al ejército de ESTADOS UNIDOS y asistir a los ejércitos y a los 
civiles aliados. el "alimento ganará la guerra," declaró la 
administración del alimento con sus carteles y esfuerzos ubicuos de 
la publicidad. Plantando jardines, observando racionar 
voluntario, evitando la basura -- estos esfuerzos en la conservación 
del alimento todos vinieron ser conocidos como "Hooverizing." 
Los compartimientos de las mujeres también tomaron la 
cruzada casera de la conservación. Las buenas operacíones 
de entretenimiento imprimieron los menús, ofreciendo a amas de casa 
las direcciones para preparar las comidas sabrosas que resolvieron 
estándares de la conservación. Contribuido por los programas 
de lectura, valor de este el "mes de recetas" imprimió en agosto 1917
demostró la conservación en la acción, así como la ingeniosidad de
las mujeres en menús de reajuste para observar racionar guías de 
consulta.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087163</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108003</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/victory-on-the-menu-recipes-and-rationing</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
