<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105768</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105768</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973943</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Peace Games: Peace Dove</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Friedensspiele: Friedenstaube</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jeux de Paix : Colombe de Paix</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogos Da Paz: Pomba Da Paz</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giochi Di Pace: Colomba Di Pace</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παιχνίδια ειρήνης: Περιστέρι ειρήνης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Juegos De la Paz: Paloma De la Paz</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Play a game and find out about a Nobel Prize awarded discovery or work! Several people and organizations have received the Nobel Peace Prize for their efforts concerning nuclear weapons disarmament. Worldwide, the white dove is a symbol for peace. Take on the mission to disarm the world of nuclear weapons! You have eight "Peace Doves" to help you, each able to disarm one of the eight countries possessing nuclear weapons.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spielen Sie ein Spiel und finden Sie über eine 
zugesprochene Entdeckung oder eine Arbeit des Nobelpreises heraus! 
Einige Leute und Organisationen haben den Nobel Friedenspreis 
für ihre Bemühungen hinsichtlich sind der Kernwaffeabrüstung 
empfangen. Weltweit ist die weiße Taube ein Symbol für 
Frieden. Nehmen Sie auf der Mission, um die Welt der Kernwaffen 
zu entwaffnen! Sie haben acht "die Friedenstauben,", zum Sie, 
jedes zu helfen, das fähig ist, eins der acht Länder zu entwaffnen, 
die Kernwaffen besitzen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jouez un jeu et découvrez au sujet d'une 
découverte ou d'un travail attribuée de prix Nobel ! Plusieurs
personnes et organismes ont reçu le prix de paix Nobel pour leurs 
efforts au sujet du désarmement d'armes nucléaires. Dans le 
monde entier, la colombe blanche est un symbole pour la paix. 
Prenez la mission pour désarmer le monde des armes nucléaires 
! Vous avez huit "des colombes de paix" pour vous aider, chacun 
capable désarmer un des huit pays possédant les armes nucléaires.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogue um jogo e encontre-o para fora sobre uma 
descoberta ou um trabalho concedido do prêmio de nobel! 
Diversos povos e organizações receberam o prêmio da paz de 
Nobel para seus esforços a respeito do disarmament das armas 
nucleares. Worldwide, a pomba branca é um símbolo para a paz. 
Faça exame na missão para desarmar o mundo de armas nucleares!
Você tem oito "as pombas da paz" para ajudar-lhe, cada um capaz
de desarmar um dos oito países que possuem armas nucleares.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gioc un gioco e scopra circa una scoperta o un 
lavoro ricevuta del premio Nobel! Parecchie gente ed 
organizzazioni hanno ricevuto il premio di pace Nobel per i loro 
sforzi riguardo al disarmo delle armi nucleari. Universalmente, 
la colomba bianca è un simbolo per pace. Intraprenda la 
missione per disarmare il mondo delle armi nucleari! Avete otto 
"colombe di pace" per aiutarle, ciascuno in grado di disarmare uno 
degli otto paesi che possiedono le armi nucleari.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παίξτε ένα παιχνίδι και ανακαλύψτε για μια 
απονεμημένη βραβείο ανακάλυψη ή μια εργασία Νόμπελ! 
Διάφοροι άνθρωποι και οργανώσεις έχουν λάβει το βραβείο 
ειρήνης Νόμπελ για τις προσπάθειές τους σχετικά με τον αφοπλισμό
πυρηνικών όπλων. Παγκοσμίως, το άσπρο περιστέρι είναι ένα
σύμβολο για την ειρήνη. Πάρτε την αποστολή για να 
αφοπλίσετε τον κόσμο των πυρηνικών όπλων! Έχετε οκτώ 
"περιστέρια ειρήνησ" για να σας βοηθήσετε, κάθε ένας ικανός να 
αφοπλίσει μιας από τις οκτώ χώρες που κατέχουν τα πυρηνικά 
όπλα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Juegue un juego y descubra sobre un 
descubrimiento o un trabajo concedido del premio Nobel! Varios 
personas y organizaciones han recibido el premio de la paz Nobel para 
sus esfuerzos referentes al desarme de las armas nucleares. Por 
todo el mundo, la paloma blanca es un símbolo para la paz. 
¡Adquiera la misión para desarmar el mundo de armas nucleares! 
Usted tiene ocho "las palomas de la paz" para ayudarle, cada uno
capaz de desarmar uno de los ocho países que poseen las armas 
nucleares.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973943</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105768</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/peace-games-peace-dove</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
