<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105394</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105394</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086711</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Our Reason for Being": A. Philip Randolph Embraces Socialism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"unser Grund für Sein": A. Umfaßt Philip 
Randolph Sozialismus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"notre raison d'être" : A. Philip 
Randolph Embrasse Le Socialisme</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"nossa razão para ser": A. Philip Randolph 
Embraces O Socialismo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"il nostro motivo per essere": A. Philip 
Randolph Abbraccia Il Socialism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ο λόγος μας για": Α. Θ*Πχηληπ Randolph 
Embraces Socialism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"nuestra razón de ser": A. Philip Randolph 
Abraza Socialismo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Socialism , although less important in the African-American community than growing concepts of racial militancy, was one of the many ideologies debated by black Americans in the 1920s. A. Philip Randolph, who in 1925 organized the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters, was perhaps the leading black proponent of socialism as the only remedy for the plight of African Americans. In this March 1919 editorial in the  Messenger , the radical newspaper that would later become the voice of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters, Randolph rejected the "leadership" of organizations such as the NAACP. Instead, he urged black and white workers to unite, form unions, and embrace socialism in order to win political gains and economic advancement.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialismus, obgleich weniger wichtig in der 
Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Gemeinschaft als wachsende Konzepte des 
rassischen Militancy, war eine der vielen Ideologien, die von den 
schwarzen Amerikanern in den zwanziger Jahren debattiert wurden. 
A. war Philip Randolph, das in 1925 die Bruderschaft von 
Schlafwagenporters organisierte, möglicherweise der führende 
schwarze Antragsteller von sozialismus als das einzige Hilfsmittel 
für die Lage der afrikanischen Amerikaner. In diesem März 1919
Leitartikel im Kurier, wies die radikale Zeitung, die später die 
Stimme der Bruderschaft von Schlafwagenporters werden würde, Randolph
die "Führung" von Organisationen wie dem NAACP zurück. 
Stattdessen drängte er schwarze und weiße Arbeiter, um zu 
vereinigen, Anschlüße zu bilden und sozialismus zu umfassen, um 
politische Gewinne und ökonomische Zuführung zu gewinnen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le socialisme, bien que moins important dans la 
communauté afro-américaine que des concepts croissants de militantisme 
racial, était l'une des nombreuses idéologies discutées par les 
Américains noirs dans les années 20. A. Philip Randolph, 
qui dans 1925 a organisé la confrérie des bagagistes de voiture de 
sommeil, était peut-être le principal partisan noir du socialisme 
comme seul remède pour la situation difficile des Américains 
africains. En cet éditorial de mars 1919 dans le messager, le 
journal radical qui deviendrait plus tard la voix de la confrérie des
bagagistes de voiture de sommeil, Randolph a rejeté la "conduite" des
organismes tels que le NAACP. Au lieu de cela, il a invité les 
ouvriers noirs et blancs à unir, à former des syndicats, et à 
embrasser le socialisme afin de gagner les gains politiques et 
l'avancement économique.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O socialismo, embora mais menos importante na 
comunidade Africano-Americana do que conceitos crescentes do militancy
racial, era um de muitos ideologies debatidos por americanos pretos 
nos 1920s. A. Philip Randolph, que em 1925 organizou o 
brotherhood de porters do carro dormindo, era talvez o proponent preto
principal do socialismo como o único remédio para o plight de 
americanos africanos. Neste editorial de março 1919 no 
mensageiro, o jornal radical que se transformaria mais tarde a voz do 
brotherhood de porters do carro dormindo, Randolph rejeitou a 
"liderança" das organizações tais como o NAACP. Instead, 
incitou trabalhadores pretos e brancos para unir-se, dar forma a 
uniões, e para embrace o socialismo a fim ganhar ganhos políticos e 
o avanço econômico.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il socialism, anche se meno importante nella 
Comunità Africano-Americana che i concetti crescenti di militanza 
razziale, era una delle molte ideologie dibattute dagli Americani neri
negli anni 20. A. Philip Randolph, che in 1925 ha organizzato la
fratellanza dei portatori dell'automobile di sonno, era forse il 
fautore nero principale del socialism come l'unico rimedio alla 
situazione difficile degli Americani africani. In questo 
editoriale di marzo 1919 nel messaggero, il giornale radicale che più
successivamente si transformerebbe in nella voce della fratellanza dei
portatori dell'automobile di sonno, Randolph ha rifiutato "la 
direzione" delle organizzazioni quale il NAACP. Invece, ha 
invitato operai neri e bianchi per unire, formare i sindacati e per 
abbracciare il socialism per vincere i guadagni politici e 
l'avanzamento economico.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο σοσιαλισμός, αν και λιγότερο σημαντικός στην 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανική κοινότητα από τις αυξανόμενες έννοιες 
της φυλετικής μαχητικότητας, ήταν μια από τις πολλές ιδεολογίες 
που συζητήθηκαν από μαύρους Αμερικανούς στη δεκαετία του '20. 
Α. Ο Philip Randolph, που το 1925 οργάνωσε την 
αδελφοσύνη των αχθοφόρων αυτοκινήτων ύπνου, ήταν ίσως ο 
οδηγώντας μαύρος υπερασπιστής του σοσιαλισμού ως μόνη θεραπεία 
για τη δύσκολη θέση αφρικανικών Αμερικανών. Σε αυτό το 
κύριο άρθρο Μαρτίου 1919 στον αγγελιοφόρο, η ριζική εφημερίδα
που θα γινόταν αργότερα η φωνή της αδελφοσύνης των αχθοφόρων 
αυτοκινήτων ύπνου, Randolph απέρριψε τη "ηγεσία" των 
οργανώσεων όπως το NAACP. Αντ' αυτού, ώθησε τους μαύρους
και λευκούς εργαζομένους για να ενώσει, να συγκροτήσει τις 
συνδικαλιστικές οργανώσεις, και να αγκαλιάσει το σοσιαλισμό 
προκειμένου να κερδηθούν τα πολιτικά κέρδη και η οικονομική 
πρόοδος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El socialismo, aunque menos es importante en la 
comunidad Africano-Americana que conceptos cada vez mayor de la 
militancia racial, era una de las muchas ideologías discutidas por 
los americanos negros en los años 20. A. Philip Randolph, que 
en 1925 ordenó a fraternidad de los porteros del coche durmiente, era
quizás el autor negro principal del socialismo como el único remedio
para el apuro de americanos africanos. En este editorial de 
marcha 1919 en el mensajero, el periódico radical que se convirtió 
en más adelante la voz de la fraternidad de los porteros del coche 
durmiente, Randolph rechazó la "dirección" de organizaciones tales 
como el NAACP. En lugar, él impulsó los trabajadores negros y 
blancos para unir, para formar uniones, y para abrazar socialismo para
ganar aumentos políticos y el adelanto económico.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086711</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105394</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/our-reason-for-being-a-philip-randolph-embraces-socialism</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
