<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103070</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103070</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086801</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Saturday Night on the Range: Rural Life in World War I Era Montana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Samstag Nacht auf der Strecke: 
Landwirtschaftliche Lebensdauer in der Weltkrieg-Ära Montana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Samedi nuit sur l'intervalle : La vie rurale
dans l'ère Montana de Première Guerre Mondiale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Noite de sábado na escala: Vida rural na 
era Montana do world.war.i</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Notte di sabato sulla gamma: Vita rurale 
nell'era Montana di world.war.i</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σάββατο νύχτα στη σειρά: Αγροτική ζωή στον 
παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι εποχή Μοντάνα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Noche de sábado en el rango: Vida rural en 
la era Montana de la Primera Guerra Mundial</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">We often like to imagine rural life in the past as timeless, "traditional," and in some way simpler and more authentic. Yet, rural life in the years around World War I, while sometimes recalled as simpler, could often seem very much like life anywhere else. In this interview, conducted by Laurie Mercier in 1982 for the Montana Historical Society, Tom Staff remembers how Montana farmers took other jobs to supplement their incomes. Here he described how the road crew he worked on left camp for dances in town--events which, well after midnight, might turn a little ugly.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wir mögen häufig uns landwirtschaftliche 
Lebensdauer in der Vergangenheit vorstellen, wie zeitlos, 
"traditionell," und auf gewisse Weise einfacher und authentischer. 
Jedoch könnte landwirtschaftliche Lebensdauer in den Jahren um 
den Ersten Weltkrieg, während sie manchmal wieder aufgerufen wird, 
wie einfacher, wie das Leben häufig sehr viel irgendwoanders 
scheinen. In diesem Interview geleitet mit Laurie Mercier 1982 
für die Montana historische Gesellschaft, erinnert sich Tom Personal,
an wie Montana Landwirte andere Jobs nahmen, ihre Einkommen zu 
ergänzen. Hier beschrieb er, wie die Straße Mannschaft er auf 
linkem Lager für Tänze in der Stadt -- Fälle arbeitete, die, gut 
nach Mitternacht, wenig häßlich drehen konnten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Nous aimons souvent imaginer la vie rurale dans le
passé comme intemporel, "traditionnel," et d'une manière quelconque
plus simple et plus authentique. Cependant, la vie rurale en 
années autour de la Première Guerre Mondiale, tandis que parfois 
rappelée comme plus simple, a pu souvent sembler infiniment comme la 
vie n'importe où ailleurs. Dans cette entrevue, conduite par 
Laurie Mercier en 1982 pour la société historique du Montana, le 
personnel de Tom se rappelle comment les fermiers du Montana 
ont pris d'autres travaux de compléter leurs revenus. Le voici 
qui a décrit comment la route le servent d'équipier a travaillé au camp
gauche pour des danses en ville -- les événements qui, bien après 
minuit, pourraient tourner laid.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nós gostamos frequentemente de imaginar a vida 
rural no passado como timeless, "tradicional," e em alguma maneira 
mais simples e mais authentic. Ainda, a vida rural nos anos em 
torno do world.war.i, quando recordada às vezes como mais simples, 
podia frequentemente parecer muito bem como a vida seja là onde for. 
Nesta entrevista, conduzida por Laurie Mercier em 1982 para a 
sociedade histórica de Montana, a equipe de funcionários de Tom 
recorda como os fazendeiros de Montana fizeram exame de outros 
trabalhos suplementar suas rendas. Aqui descreveu como o grupo 
da estrada ele trabalhou no acampamento esquerdo para danças na 
cidade -- os eventos que, bem após a meia-noite, puderam girar um 
pouco feio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gradiamo spesso immaginare la vita rurale nel 
passato come timeless, "tradizionale," ed in qualche modo più 
semplice e più autentico. Tuttavia, la vita rurale durante gli 
anni intorno al world.war.i, mentre a volte ricordata come più 
semplice, ha potuto sembrare spesso molto come vita in qualsiasi altro
luogo. In questa intervista, condotta da Laurie Mercier in 1982 
per la società storica del Montana, il personale di Tom si ricorda di
come i coltivatori del Montana hanno preso altri lavori completare i 
loro redditi. Qui ha descritto come la squadra della strada lui 
ha lavorato all'accampamento di sinistra per i balli in città -- 
eventi che, bene dopo la mezzanotte, potrebbero girare un piccolo 
ugly.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιθυμούμε συχνά να φανταστούμε την αγροτική ζωή στο 
παρελθόν όπως άχρονο, "παραδοσιακό," και με κάποιο τρόπο 
απλούστερος και αυθεντικότερος. Ακόμα, αγροτική ζωή στα 
έτη γύρω από τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι, ενώ μερικές φορές 
θυμησμένος όπως απλούστερος, μπόρεσε συχνά να φανεί παρόμοια με
τη ζωή οπουδήποτε αλλού. Σε αυτήν την συνέντευξη, που 
πραγματοποιείται από Laurie Mercier το 1982 για την 
ιστορική κοινωνία της Μοντάνα, ο Tom Staff θυμάται πώς οι 
αγρότες της Μοντάνα ανάλαβαν άλλες δουλειές για να συμπληρώσουν 
τα εισοδήματά τους. Εδώ περιέγραψε πώς το οδικό πλήρωμα 
που εργάστηκε στο αριστερό στρατόπεδο για τους χορούς στην πόλη 
-- γεγονότα που, καλά μετά από τα μεσάνυχτα, να γίνουν λίγο 
άσχημα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Tenemos gusto a menudo de imaginar vida rural en 
el pasado como intemporal, "tradicional," y de una cierta manera más 
simple y más auténtica. Todavía, la vida rural en los años 
alrededor de la Primera Guerra Mundial, mientras que estaba recordada 
a veces como más simple, podía parecerse a menudo mucho como vida en
cualquier otro lugar. En esta entrevista, conducida por Laurie 
Mercier en 1982 para la sociedad histórica de Montana, el personal de
Tom recuerda cómo los granjeros de Montana tomaron otros trabajos de 
suplir sus rentas. Aquí él describió cómo el equipo del 
camino él trabajó en el campo izquierdo para las danzas en ciudad --
los acontecimientos que, bien después de medianoche, pudieron dar 
vuelta a un poco feo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086801</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103070</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/saturday-night-on-the-range-rural-life-in-world-war-i-era-montana</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
