<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107862</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107862</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201745</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Forces in 1 Dimension</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kräfte in 1 Maß</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Forces dans 1 dimension</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Forças em 1 dimensão</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Forze in 1 dimensione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δυνάμεις σε 1 διάσταση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fuerzas en 1 dimensión</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Explore the forces at work when you try to push a filing cabinet. Create an applied force and see the resulting friction force and total force acting on the cabinet. Charts show the forces, position, velocity, and acceleration vs. time. View a Free Body Diagram of all the forces (including gravitational and normal forces).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <language>es</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erforschen Sie die Kräfte an der Arbeit, wenn Sie
versuchen, einen Aktenschrank zu drücken. Erstellen Sie eine 
angewandte Kraft und sehen Sie die resultierende Friktion Kraft und 
Gesamtkraft, die auf dem Schrank fungieren. Diagramme zeigen die
Kräfte, die Position, die Geschwindigkeit und die Beschleunigung 
gegen Zeit. Sehen Sie ein freies Körper-Diagramm aller Kräfte 
an (einschließlich Gravitations- und normale Kräfte).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Explorez les forces au travail quand vous essayez 
de pousser un meuble d'archivage. Créez une force appliquée et
voyez la force résultante de frottement et la force totale agissant 
sur le module. Les diagrammes montrent les forces, la position, 
la vitesse, et l'accélération contre le temps. Visualisez un 
diagramme libre de corps de toutes les forces (les forces de la 
gravité et normales y compris).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Explore as forças no trabalho quando você tenta 
empurrar um armário de arquivamento. Críe uma força aplicada 
e veja a força resultante da fricção e a força total que agem no 
armário. As cartas mostram as forças, a posição, a 
velocidade, e o acceleration contra o tempo. Veja um diagrama 
livre do corpo de todas as forças (forças gravitacionais e normais 
including).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Esplori le forze sul lavoro quando provate a 
spingere un armadietto di archivario. Crei una forza applicata e
veda la forza risultante di attrito e la forza totale che si 
comportano sull'armadietto. Le tabelle mostrano le forze, la 
posizione, la velocità e l'accelerazione contro tempo. Osservi 
uno schema libero del corpo di tutte le forze (forze gravitazionali e 
normali comprese).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ερευνήστε τις δυνάμεις στην εργασία όταν προσπαθείτε 
να ωθήσετε ένα ντουλάπι αρχειοθέτησης. Δημιουργήστε μια 
εφαρμοσμένη δύναμη και δείτε την προκύπτουσα δύναμη 
τριβής και τη συνολική δύναμη ενεργώντας στο γραφείο. Τα 
διαγράμματα εμφανίζουν τις δυνάμεις, τη θέση, την ταχύτητα, και 
ταχύτητα εναντίον του χρόνου. Εμφανίστε ένα ελεύθερο 
διάγραμμα σώματος όλων των δυνάμεων (συμπεριλαμβανομένων των 
βαρύτητας και κανονικών δυνάμεων).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Explore las fuerzas en el trabajo cuando usted 
intenta empujar una cabina de clasificación. Cree una fuerza 
aplicada y vea la fuerza de la fricción que resulta y la fuerza total
que actúan en la cabina. Las cartas muestran las fuerzas, la 
posición, la velocidad, y la aceleración contra tiempo. 
Opinión un diagrama libre del cuerpo de todas las fuerzas (las 
fuerzas gravitacionales y normales incluyendo).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201745</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107862</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/forces-in-1-dimension</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
