<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105927</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105927</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086490</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Mrs. Frederick Teaches Women How to Wash the Dishes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mrs Frederick Teaches Women How, zum der Teller zu 
waschen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mme Frederick Teaches Women How pour faire la 
vaisselle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Sra. Frederick Ensinar Mulher Como para lavar os 
pratos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sig.ra Frederick Teaches Women How per lavare i 
piatti</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κα Frederick Teaches Women How να πλυθούν τα 
πιάτα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Señora Frederick Teaches Women How para lavar los 
platos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">As the principles of scientific management came to play a more significant role in the workplace, some reformers sought to apply these principles to any aspects of daily life that might be improved by standardization and routine. Perhaps no one applied the principles of scientific management to the home with as much passion as Christine Frederick, the household editor of  Ladies Home Journal  as well as the National Secretary of the Associated Clubs of Domestic Science. In 1912, she published a four-part series in the  Ladies Home Journal  that promised less housework. Each article opened with a box recounting Frederick Taylor's principles of scientific management. "Taylorization" made it possible for (compelled, really) steelworkers to quadruple their usual output, and Frederick implied that Taylor's principles would also result in a four-fold increase in home productivity. Frederick's articles were enormously popular. Although Frederick posed as an impartial efficiency expert, she had very close ties to appliance and kitchen-equipment manufacturers and helped lend scientific legitimacy to new products. In this excerpt from the first article in this series, Frederick described how to wash dishes correctly and efficiently.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während die Grundregeln der wissenschaftlichen 
Unternehmensführung kamen, eine bedeutendere Rolle an dem 
Arbeitsplatz zu spielen, suchten einige Reformer, diese 
Grundregeln an allen möglichen Aspekten der täglichen Lebensdauer 
anzuwenden, die durch Normierung und Programm verbessert werden 
konnten. Möglicherweise wendeten niemand die Grundregeln der 
wissenschaftlichen Unternehmensführung am Haus mit so vieler Neigung 
wie Christine Frederick, der Haushalt Herausgeber des 
Dame-Hauptjournals sowie den nationalen Minister fuer den verbundenen 
Vereinen der inländischen Wissenschaft an. 1912 
veröffentlichte sie eine vierteilige Serie im Dame-Hauptjournal, das 
weniger Hausarbeit versprach. Jeder Artikel öffnete sich mit 
den Grundregeln eines Kasten nachzählenden Frederick Schneiders der 
wissenschaftlichen Unternehmensführung. "Taylorization" machte 
es möglich, damit (gezwungen, wirklich) Steelworkers ihre übliche 
Ausgabe vervierfachen, und Frederick deutete an, daß Grundregeln des 
Schneiders auch eine vierfache Zunahme der Hauptproduktivität ergeben
würden. Artikel Fredericks waren enorm populär. Obgleich
Frederick, das als unparteiischen Rationalisierungsfachleute 
aufgeworfen wurde, sie sehr nahe Gleichheit zu den Geräte- und 
Küche-Ausrüstungherstellern und geholfen wissenschaftliche, 
Legitimität zu den neuen Produkten zu verleihen hatte. In 
diesem Excerpt vom ersten Artikel in dieser Serie, beschrieb 
Frederick, wie man Teller richtig und leistungsfähig wäscht.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant que les principes de la gestion 
scientifique venaient pour jouer un rôle plus significatif dans le 
lieu de travail, quelques réformateurs ont recherché à s'appliquer 
ces principes à tous les aspects de vie quotidienne qui pourraient 
être améliorés par étalonnage et sous-programme. Peut-être 
personne ne se sont appliqués les principes de la gestion 
scientifique à la maison avec autant passion que Christine Frederick,
l'éditeur de ménage du journal à la maison de dames aussi bien que 
le secrétaire national des clubs associés de la Science domestique. 
En 1912, elle a édité une série à quatre parties dans le 
journal à la maison de dames qui a promis moins de travaux 
domestiques. Chaque article s'est ouvert avec les principes d'un
tailleur de racontage de Frederick de cadre de la gestion 
scientifique. "Taylorization" a permis pour que (compulsif, 
vraiment) les travailleurs dans l'industrie sidérurgique quadruplent 
leur sortie habituelle, et Frederick a impliqué que les principes du 
tailleur auraient également comme conséquence une augmentation de 4 
fois de la productivité à la maison. Les articles de Frederick
étaient énormément populaires. Bien que Frederick posé en 
tant qu'expert de l'efficience impartial, elle ait eu les cravates 
très étroites aux constructeurs d'appareils et de cuisine-matériel 
et aidé à prêter la légitimité scientifique à de nouveaux 
produits. Dans cet extrait du premier article de cette série, 
Frederick a décrit comment laver des plats correctement et 
efficacement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Enquanto os princípios da gerência científica 
vieram jogar um papel mais significativo no workplace, alguns 
reformers procuraram aplicar estes princípios a todos os aspectos da 
vida diária que pudessem ser melhorados pela estandardização e pela
rotina. Talvez ninguém aplicaram os princípios da gerência 
científica à HOME com tanta paixão quanto Christine Frederick, o 
editor da casa do jornal home das senhoras as.well.as a secretária 
nacional dos clubes associados da ciência doméstica. Em 1912, 
publicou uma série four-part no jornal home das senhoras que prometeu
menos housework. Cada artigo abriu com princípios de um 
alfaiate recounting de Frederick da caixa da gerência científica. 
"Taylorization" fêz possível para que (compelido, realmente) 
os steelworkers quadruple sua saída usual, e Frederick implicou que 
os princípios do alfaiate resultariam também em um aumento four-fold
na produtividade home. Os artigos de Frederick eram enormemente 
populares. Embora Frederick posed como um perito de eficiência 
imparcial, ela tivesse laços muito próximos aos fabricantes do 
dispositivo e do cozinha-equipamento e ajudado emprestar o legitimacy 
científico aos produtos novos. Neste excerpt do primeiro artigo
nesta série, Frederick descreveu como lavar corretamente e 
eficientemente pratos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Mentre i principii della gestione scientifica sono 
venuto svolgere un ruolo più significativo nel posto di lavoro, 
alcuni reformers hanno cercato di applicare questi principii a tutte 
le funzioni di vita quotidiana che potrebbero essere migliorate dalla 
normalizzazione e dalla procedura. Forse nessuno hanno applicato
i principii della gestione scientifica alla sede con tanta passione 
quanto Christine Frederick, l'editore della famiglia del giornale 
domestico delle signore così come la segretaria nazionale dei 
randelli collegati della scienza domestica. In 1912, ha 
pubblicato una serie a quattro parti nel giornale domestico delle 
signore che ha promesso meno lavori domestici. Ogni articolo si 
è aperto con i principii della casella del sarto di racconto di 
Frederick della gestione scientifica. "Taylorization" ha 
permesso affinchè (coercitivo, realmente) gli addetti alla 
lavorazione dell'acciaio quadruplichi la loro uscita usuale e 
Frederick ha implicato che i principii del sarto egualmente 
provocassero un aumento quadruplo nel rendimento domestico. Gli 
articoli del Frederick erano enormemente popolari. Anche se 
Frederick proposto come esperto di risparmio di temi imparziale, lei 
ha avuto legami molto vicini ai fornitori dell'cucina-apparecchiatura 
e degli apparecchi e contribuito a prestare la legittimità 
scientifica ai nuovi prodotti. In questo brano dal primo 
articolo in questa serie, Frederick ha descritto come lavare 
correttamente ed efficientemente i piatti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Καθώς οι αρχές της επιστημονικής διαχείρισης ήρθαν να
διαδραματίσουν έναν σημαντικότερο ρόλο στον εργασιακό χώρο, 
μερικοί μεταρρυθμιστές επιδίωξαν να εφαρμόσουν αυτές τις αρχές 
σε οποιεσδήποτε πτυχές της καθημερινής ζωής που να βελτιωθεί από
την τυποποίηση και τη ρουτίνα. Ίσως κανένας εφάρμοσε τις 
αρχές της επιστημονικής διαχείρισης στο σπίτι με τόσο πάθος όσο
την Christine Frederick, τον οικιακό επεξεργαστή του 
περιοδικού γυναικείων "Οικιαών καθώς επίσης και τον εθνικό 
γραμματέα των σχετικών λεσχών της οικιακής οικονομίας. Το 
1912, δημοσίευσε μια σειρά τέσσερις-μερών στο περιοδικό 
γυναικείων "Οικιαών που υποσχέθηκε τα λιγότερα οικιακά. 
Κάθε άρθρο άνοιξε με ένα κιβώτιο που εξιστορεί τις αρχές 
Frederick taylor της επιστημονικής διαχείρισης. 
"Taylorization" το κατέστησε πιθανό για (αναγκασμένος, 
πραγματικά) τους σιδηρουργούς να τετραπλασιάσουν τη συνηθισμένη 
έξοδό τους, και Frederick υπονόησε ότι taylor οι αρχές θα 
οδηγούσαν επίσης σε μια τετραπλή αύξηση στη βασική 
παραγωγικότητα. Τα άρθρα του Frederick ήταν πάρα πολύ 
δημοφιλή. Αν και Frederick που τέθηκε ως αμερόληπτος 
εμπειρογνώμονας αποδοτικότητας, είχε τους πολύ στενούς δεσμούς 
στους κατασκευαστές συσκευών και κουζίνα-εξοπλισμού και βοήθησε 
να δανείσει την επιστημονική νομιμότητα στα νέα προϊόντα. 
Σε αυτό το απόσπασμα από το πρώτο άρθρο σε αυτήν την 
σειρά, Frederick περιέγραψε πώς να πλύνει τα πιάτα σωστά και 
αποτελεσματικά.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mientras que los principios de la gerencia 
científica vinieron desempeñar un papel más significativo en el 
lugar de trabajo, algunos reformadores intentaron aplicar estos 
principios a cualquier aspecto de la vida de cada día que se pudiera 
mejorar por la estandardización y la rutina. Quizás nadie 
aplicaron los principios de la gerencia científica al hogar con tanta
pasión como Christine Frederick, el editor de la casa del diario 
casero de las señoras así como la secretaria nacional de los clubs 
asociados de la ciencia doméstica. En 1912, ella publicó una 
serie de cuatro partes en el diario casero de las señoras que 
prometió menos quehacer doméstico. Cada artículo se abrió 
con los principios del rectángulo que contaba de nuevo de una 
personalización de Frederick de la gerencia científica. 
"Taylorization" permitió para que (obligado, realmente) los 
trabajadores siderúrgicos cuadrupliquen su salida generalmente, y 
Frederick implicó que los principios de la personalización también 
darían lugar a un aumento cuádruple en la productividad casera. 
Los artículos de Frederick eran enormemente populares. 
Aunque Frederick presentado como experto de eficacia imparcial, 
ella tenía lazos muy cercanos a los fabricantes de la aplicación y 
del cocina-equipo y ayudado a prestar legitimidad científica a los 
productos nuevos. En este extracto del primer artículo en esta 
serie, Frederick describió cómo lavar platos correctamente y 
eficientemente.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086490</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105927</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/mrs-frederick-teaches-women-how-to-wash-the-dishes</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
