<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107526</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107526</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206660</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Origins</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ursprung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Origines</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Origens</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Origini</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Προέλευση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Orígenes</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">lets us look over the shoulders of scientists and glimpse the often-unseen moments of investigation. Take virtual field trips to eight observatories -- Arecibo, where astrobiologists search for signs of life beyond the solar system; Las Cuevas, a research station in Central America's largest remaining rainforest; and others. See interviews, photos, and broadcasts that explore the origins of matter, the universe, and life itself.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">läßt uns über den Schultern der Wissenschaftler
schauen und die häufig-often-unseen Momente der Untersuchung 
flüchtig sehen. Das virtuelle Nehmen fängt Reisen zu 
acht Sternwarten -- Arecibo auf, in denen astrobiologists nach Zeichen
des Lebens über dem Solarsystem hinaus suchen; Las Cuevas, eine
Forschungsstation in Mittelamerikas größtem restlichem rainforest; 
und andere. Sehen Sie Interviews, Fotos und Sendungen, die
die Ursprung des Stoffes, des Universums und des Lebens selbst 
erforschen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">nous laisse regarder au-dessus des épaules des 
scientifiques et apercevoir les moments souvent-invisibles de la 
recherche. Prenez les voyages de zone virtuels à huit 
observatoires -- Arecibo, où les astrobiologists recherchent des 
signes de la vie au delà du système solaire ; Las Cuevas, un 
centre de recherches dans la plus grande forêt tropicale restante de 
l'Amérique Centrale ; et d'autres. Voir des entrevues, 
des photos, et les émissions qui explorent les origines de la 
matière, de l'univers, et de la vie elle-même.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">deixa-nos olhar sobre os ombros dos cientistas e 
glimpse os momentos frequentemente-despercebidos da investigação. 
Faça exame de desengates de campo virtuais a oito obervatórios
-- Arecibo, onde os astrobiologists procuraram por sinais da vida 
além do sistema solar; Las Cuevas, uma estação de pesquisa no
mais rainforest restante o maior de América Central; e outros. 
Veja entrevistas, fotos, e transmissões que exploram as origens
da matéria, do universo, e da vida própria.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">li lascia osservare sopra le spalle degli 
scienziati e glimpse i momenti spesso-often-unseen di ricerca. _
prend virtuale campo viaggio otto osservatorio -- Arecibo, in cui 
astrobiologists cerc per segno vita oltre solare sistema; Las 
Cuevas, una stazione di ricerca in più grande più rainforest 
restante dell'America Centrale; ed altri. Veda le 
interviste, le foto e le radiodiffusioni che esplorano le origini 
della materia, dell'universo e della vita in se.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">μας αφήνει να φανούμε πέρα από τους ώμους των 
επιστημόνων και της αναλαμπής οι συχνά-απαρατήρητες στιγμές της 
έρευνας. Πάρτε τα εικονικά ταξίδια πεδίων σε οκτώ 
παρατηρητήρια -- Arecibo, όπου τα astrobiologists ψάχνουν για
τα σημάδια της ζωής πέρα από το ηλιακό σύστημα  Las 
Cuevas, ένας ερευνητικός σταθμός στη μεγαλύτερη παραμονή της 
Κεντρικής Αμερικής τροπικό δάσος  και άλλοι. 
Δείτε τις συνεντεύξεις, τις φωτογραφίες, και τις 
ραδιοφωνικές μεταδόσεις που ερευνούν την προέλευση του θέματος, 
του κόσμου, και της ζωής η ίδια.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">nos deja mirar sobre los hombros de científicos y
glimpse los momentos a menudo-no vistos de la investigación. 
Lleve los disparos al campo virtuales ocho observatorios -- 
Arecibo, en donde los astrobiologists buscan para muestras de la vida 
más allá de la Sistema Solar; Las Cuevas, un centro de 
investigación en el la ma's rainforest restante más grande de 
America Central; y otros. Vea las entrevistas, las fotos, 
y las difusiones que exploran los orígenes de la materia, del 
universo, y de la vida sí mismo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206660</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107526</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/origins</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
