<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108491</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108491</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087031</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Rating Game: Broadcasters Rely on Poll Numbers They Don't Trust</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Bewertung Spiel: Rundfunkstationen 
beruhen auf Abstimmung-Zahlen, die sie nicht vertrauen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Jeu d'Estimation : Les radiodiffuseurs se
fondent sur des nombres de balayage qu'ils ne font pas confiance</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Jogo Da Avaliação: Os radiodifusores 
confiam em números que da votação não confíam</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Gioco Di Valutazione: I distributori a 
spaglio contano sui numeri che di scrutinio non si fidano di</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το παιχνίδι εκτίμησης: Οι εκφωνητές στηρίζονται 
στους αριθμούς ψηφοφορίας που δεν εμπιστεύονται</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Juego Del Grado: Los locutores confían 
en números de la encuesta que no confían en</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">From the late 1920s, when the first rival radio broadcasting networks were formed, until the present day, as network television competes for viewers with cable and satellite fare, broadcasters and advertisers have sought ways to quantify information about their audiences. The first ratings system, devised by Archibald Crossley in 1929 for the Association of National Advertisers, relied on random telephone surveys. Interviewers asked what programs and sponsors listeners remembered from the previous day. By the late 1930s, C. E. Hooper successfully challenged this method by surveying only the shows respondents were listening to at the time of the phone interview. Hooper's method dominated until the A. C. Nielsen Company began attaching Audimeters directly to television sets. The following Collier's article from 1954 offered a critique of the four ratings methods in use at that time and discussed adverse consequences caused by the industry's reliance on ratings. This assessment by author Bill Davidson and the men in the industry whom he quoted showed signs of an assumed disparagement of ordinary American housewives, identified implicitly as the predominant audience for mass media consumption. Both the reliability of housewives as part-time interviewers and their ability as viewers to maintain accurate diaries were deemed suspect in this piece.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Von den späten zwanziger Jahren als die 
übertragenden Netze des ersten Rivaleradios, bis den anwesenden Tag 
gebildet wurden, wie Netzfernsehen für Projektoren mit Kabel- und 
Satellitfahrpreise konkurriert, haben Rundfunksprecher und die 
Inserenten Methoden gesucht, Informationen über ihre Publikum 
mengenmäßig zu bestimmen. Das erste Bewertungen System, 
geplant von Archibald Crossley 1929 für die Verbindung der nationalen
Inserenten, beruhte auf gelegentlichen Telefonübersichten. 
Interviewer fragten, welchen Programmen und die Zuhörer 
fördert, die vom Vorabend erinnert werden. Bis zum den späten 
dreißiger Jahren forderte C. E. Hooper erfolgreich diese Methode 
heraus, indem er nur die Erscheinen überblickte, die Antwortende zu 
der Zeit zum Telefoninterview hörten. Die Methode des 
Böttchers, die bis A. C. Nielsen Company beherrscht wurde, fing an, 
Audimeters direkt zu den Fernsehern anzubringen. Der folgenden 
Artikel des Colliers von 1954 bot eine Kritik der vier 
Bewertungsverfahren im Gebrauch zu dieser Zeit an und behandelte die 
nachteiligen Konsequenzen, die durch das Vertrauen der Industrie auf 
Bewertungen verursacht wurden. Diese Einschätzung durch Autor 
Rechnung Davidson und die Männer in der Industrie, die er 
veranschlug, zeigte Zeichen einer angenommenen Herabsetzung der 
gewöhnlichen amerikanischen Hausfrauen, implizit gekennzeichnet als 
die überwiegenden Publikum für Massenmediaverbrauch. wurden 
die Zuverlässigkeit der Hausfrauen als Teilzeitinterviewer und ihre 
Fähigkeit als Projektoren, genaue Tagebücher beizubehalten 
vermutlich defekt in diesem Stück gemeint.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Des années 20 en retard, quand les réseaux 
d'annonce de la première radio de rival ont été formés, jusqu'à 
aujourd'hui, comme la télévision de réseau concurrence pour des 
visualisateurs le prix de câble et de satellite, les animateurs et 
les annonceurs ont recherché des voies de mesurer des informations 
sur leurs assistances. Le premier système d'estimations, conçu
par Archibald Crossley en 1929 pour l'association des Annonceurs 
nationaux, s'est fondé sur des enquêtes aléatoires de téléphone. 
Les interviewers ont demandé quels programmes et commandite des
auditeurs retrouvés de la veille. Par les années 30 en retard,
C. E. Hooper a avec succès défié cette méthode en examinant 
seulement les expositions que les répondants écoutaient au moment de
l'entrevue de téléphone. La méthode du hooper's dominée 
jusqu'à A. C. Nielsen Company a commencé à attacher Audimeters 
directement aux téléviseurs. L'article suivant de Collier 
de 1954 a offert une critique des quatre méthodes d'estimations en 
service à ce moment-là et a discuté des conséquences défavorables
provoquées par la confiance de l'industrie dans des estimations. 
Cette évaluation par la facture Davidson d'auteur et les hommes
dans l'industrie qu'il a citée a montré des signes d'un dénigrement 
assumé des femmes au foyer américaines ordinaires, identifié 
implicitement en tant qu'assistances prédominantes pour la 
consommation de mass media. Le sérieux des femmes au foyer en 
tant qu'interviewers à temps partiel et leur capacité comme 
visualisateurs de mettre à jour les agendas précis ont été 
considérés suspecte dans ce morceau.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Dos 1920s atrasados, quando as redes transmitindo 
do primeiro rádio do rival foram dados forma, até o dia atual, como 
a televisão da rede compete para visores com o fare do cabo e do 
satélite, os radiodifusores e os publicitários procuraram maneiras 
quantify a informação sobre suas audiências. O primeiro 
sistema das avaliações, planejado por Archibald Crossley em 1929 
para a associação de publicitários nacionais, confiou em exames 
aleatórios do telefone. Os interviewers perguntaram que 
programas e patrocina os ouvintes recordados do dia precedente. 
Pelos 1930s atrasados, C. E. Hooper desafiou com sucesso este 
método examinando somente as mostras que os respondents escutavam na 
altura da entrevista do telefone. O método do hooper dominado 
até o A. C. Nielsen Companhia começou a unir Audimeters diretamente 
aos jogos de televisão. O artigo do seguinte collier de 1954 
ofereceu uma crítica dos quatro métodos de avaliações no uso nesse
tempo e discutiu as conseqüências adversas causadas pelo reliance da
indústria em avaliações. Esta avaliação pela conta Davidson
do autor e pelos homens na indústria quem citou mostrou sinais de um 
disparagement suposto de housewives americanos ordinários, 
identificado implicitamente como as audiências predominant para o 
consumo dos media maciços. a confiabilidade dos housewives 
como interviewers de meio expediente e sua abilidade como visores de 
manter diários exatos foram julgadas suspeita nesta parte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dagli anni 20 tardi, quando le reti di 
radiodiffusione della prima radio del rivale sono stati formati, fino 
ad oggi, come la televisione della rete compete per i visori al prezzo
del satellite e del cavo, i distributori a spaglio ed i advertisers 
hanno cercato i modi misurare le informazioni sui loro pubblici. 
Il primo sistema di valutazioni, inventato da Archibald Crossley
in 1929 per l'associazione dei advertisers nazionali, ha contato sulle
indagini casuali del telefono. Gli intervistatori hanno chiesto 
che programmi e patrocina gli ascoltatori ricordati di dal giorno 
precedente. Entro i 1930s tardi, C. E. Hooper ha sfidato con 
successo questo metodo esaminando soltanto le esposizioni che i 
dichiaranti stavano ascoltando ai tempi dell'intervista del telefono. 
Il metodo del hooper dominato fino al A. C. Nielsen Company ha 
cominciato a fissare Audimeters direttamente ai televisori. 
L'articolo del seguente collier da 1954 ha offerto una 
valutazione dei quattro metodi di valutazioni in uso a quel tempo ed 
ha discusso le conseguenze avverse causate dal ricorso dell'industria 
alle valutazioni. Questa valutazione dalla fattura Davidson 
dell'autore e dall'uomo nell'industria quale ha citato ha mostrato i 
segni di un disparagement presupposto delle casalinghe americane 
ordinarie, identificato implicitamente come i pubblici predominanti 
per il consumo di mass-media. Sia l'affidabilità delle 
casalinghe come intervistatori part-time che la loro capacità come 
visori di effettuare i diari esatti sono state ritenute sospetta in 
questa parte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Από την πρόσφατη δεκαετία του '20, όταν διαμορφώθηκαν
τα πρώτα αντίπαλα ραδιο δίκτυα ραδιοφωνικής αναμετάδοσης, μέχρι 
την παρούσα ημέρα, όπως η τηλεόραση δικτύων ανταγωνίζεται για 
τις εμφανίσεις με το καλώδιο και τη δορυφορική τιμή, οι εκφωνητές
και οι δηαφημιστές έχουν επιδιώξει τους τρόπους να ποσολογηθούν 
οι πληροφορίες για τα ακροατήριά τους. Το πρώτο σύστημα 
εκτιμήσεων, που επινοήθηκε από Archibald Crossley το 1929 
για την ένωση των εθνικών δηαφημιστών, στηρίχθηκε στις τυχαίες 
τηλεφωνικές έρευνες. Οι ερευνητές ρώτησαν ποια προγράμματα 
και υποστηρίζει τους ακροατές που αναφέρονται από την προηγούμενη
ημέρα. Μέχρι την πρόσφατη δεκαετία του '30, Γ. Ε. Hooper 
προκάλεσε επιτυχώς αυτήν την μέθοδο με την έρευνα μόνο των 
εναγομένων επιδείξεων άκουγε κατά την διάρκεια της τηλεφωνικής 
συνέντευξης. Η μέθοδος του Hooper εξουσίασε έως ότου το 
Α. άρχισε Γ. nielsen Company Audimeters άμεσα με τα 
τηλεοπτικά σύνολα. Το άρθρο του ακόλουθου ανθρακωρύχου από
το 1954 πρόσφερε μια κριτική των τεσσάρων μεθόδων εκτιμήσεων 
σε χρήση εκείνη την περίοδο και συζήτησε τις δυσμενείς συνέπειες
που προκλήθηκαν από την εμπιστοσύνη της βιομηχανίας στις 
εκτιμήσεις. Αυτή η αξιολόγηση από το συντάκτη Bill 
Davidson και τα άτομα στη βιομηχανία που ανέφερε τα εμφανισμένα
σημάδια υποτιθέμενο disparagement των συνηθισμένων αμερικανικών
νοικοκυρών, που προσδιορίστηκε σιωπηρά ως κυρίαρχο ακροατήριο για
την κατανάλωση μαζικής επικοινωνίας μέσων. Και η αξιοπιστία
των νοικοκυρών ως μερικής απασχόλησης ερευνητές και η δυνατότητά
τους ως εμφανίσεις να διατηρήσουν τα ακριβή ημερολόγια κρίθηκαν 
ύποπτη σε αυτό το κομμάτι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">A partir de los últimos años 20, cuando las 
redes que difundían de la primera radio del rival fueron formados, 
hasta hoy, como la televisión de la red compite para los espectadores
con precio del cable y del satélite, los locutores y los publicistas 
han buscado maneras de cuantificar la información sobre sus 
audiencias. El primer sistema de los grados, ideado por 
Archibald Crossley en 1929 para la asociación de publicistas 
nacionales, confió en encuestas sobre al azar el teléfono. Los
entrevistadores preguntaron qué programas y patrocina a módulos de 
escucha recordados a partir del día anterior. Por los últimos 
años 30, C. E. Hooper desafió con éxito este método examinando 
solamente las demostraciones que los respondedores escuchaban a la 
hora de la entrevista del teléfono. El método del hooper 
dominado hasta el A. C. Nielsen Company comenzó a asociar Audimeters 
directamente a las televisiones. El artículo del collier 
siguiente a partir del 1954 ofreció una crítica de los cuatro 
métodos de grados en uso en aquella 'epoca y discutió las 
consecuencias adversas causadas por la confianza de la industria en 
grados. Este gravamen de la cuenta Davidson del autor y de los 
hombres en la industria que él cotizó mostró muestras de un 
menosprecio asumido de amas de casa americanas ordinarias, 
identificado implícito como las audiencias predominantes para la 
consumición de los medioses de comunicación. La confiabilidad 
de amas de casa como entrevistadores por horas y su capacidad como 
espectadores de mantener los diarios exactos eran juzgadas sospechada 
en este pedazo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087031</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108491</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-rating-game-broadcasters-rely-on-poll-numbers-they-dont-trust</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
