<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106913</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106913</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201741</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Fog Chamber</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nebel-Raum</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Chambre de Brouillard</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Câmara Da Névoa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Alloggiamento Della Nebbia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αίθουσα ομίχλης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Compartimiento De la Niebla</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Fog Chamber exercise is an Exploratorium Science Snack demonstration. The activity shows students how clouds and fog are created with a very simple physical model using a 1 gallon jar, latex glove, a little water, and matches. The exercise teaches students how to make a simple cloud that in order to form requires water vapor, a cooling mechanism, and condensation nuclei. This site provides information on teaching materials, teaching notes and tips, assessment suggestions and additional references. This activity is part of the Starting Point Collection: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Nebel-Raumübung ist eine Exploratorium 
Wissenschaft Imbißdemonstration. Die Aktivität zeigt 
Kursteilnehmern, wie Wolken und Nebel mit einem sehr einfachen 
körperlichen Modell mit einem 1 Gallone Glas, Latexhandschuh, einem 
wenigen Wasser und Übereinstimmungen hergestellt werden. Die 
Übung bringt Kursteilnehmern bei, wie man eine einfache Wolke bildet,
der, um sich zu bilden Wasserdampf, eine das Abkühlen Einheit und 
Kondensationkerne benötigt. Diese Site stellt Informationen auf
Lehrmitteln, Unterricht Anmerkungen und Spitzen, Einschätzung 
Vorschläge und zusätzliche Referenzen zur Verfügung. Diese 
Aktivität ist ein Teil der Ausgangspunkt-Ansammlung: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'exercice de chambre de brouillard est une 
démonstration de casse-croûte de la Science d'Exploratorium. 
L'activité montre à des étudiants comment des nuages et le 
brouillard sont créés avec un modèle physique très simple en 
utilisant une fiole de 1 gallon, le gant de latex, une peu d'eau, et 
des allumettes. L'exercice enseigne à des étudiants comment 
faire un nuage simple qu'afin de former exige de la vapeur d'eau, d'un
mécanisme le refroidissement, et des noyaux de condensation. Ce
site fournit des informations sur le matériel didactique, les notes 
et les extrémités d'enseignement, les suggestions d'évaluation et 
les références supplémentaires. Cette activité fait partie 
de la collection de point de départ : 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O exercício da câmara da névoa é uma 
demonstração do snack da ciência de Exploratorium. A 
atividade mostra a estudantes como as nuvens e a névoa são criadas 
com um modelo físico muito simples usando um frasco de 1 galão, a 
luva do latex, pouca água, e fósforos. O exercício ensina a 
estudantes como fazer uma nuvem simples que a fim dar forma requeira o
vapor de água, um mecanismo refrigerar, e núcleos da condensação. 
Este local fornece a informação em materiais de ensino, notas 
e pontas do ensino, sugestões da avaliação e referências 
adicionais. Esta atividade é parte da coleção do ponto 
começar: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'esercitazione dell'alloggiamento della nebbia è
una dimostrazione dello spuntino di scienza di Exploratorium. 
L'attività mostra ad allievi come le nubi e la nebbia sono 
create con un modello fisico molto semplice usando un vaso da 1 
gallone, il guanto del lattice, una poca acqua e le corrispondenze. 
L'esercitazione insegna ad allievi come fare una nube semplice 
che per formare richiede il vapore acqueo, un meccanismo raffreddarsi 
ed i nuclei di condensazione. Questo luogo fornisce le 
informazioni sui materiali didattici, note e punte di insegnamento, 
suggerimenti di valutazione e riferimenti supplementari. Questa 
attività fa parte dell'accumulazione del punto di partenza: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η άσκηση αιθουσών ομίχλης είναι μια επίδειξη 
πρόχειρων φαγητών επιστήμης Exploratorium. Η 
δραστηριότητα εμφανίζει στους σπουδαστές πώς τα σύννεφα και η 
ομίχλη δημιουργούνται με ένα πολύ απλό φυσικό μοντέλο 
χρησιμοποιώντας ένα βάζο 1 γαλονιού, το γάντι λατέξ, λίγο 
ύδωρ, και τις αντιστοιχίες. Η άσκηση διδάσκει τους 
σπουδαστές πώς να κάνει ένα απλό σύννεφο που προκειμένου να 
διαμορφώσει απαιτεί τον υδρατμό, έναν δροσίζοντας μηχανισμό, και
τους πυρήνες συμπύκνωσης. Αυτή η περιοχή παρέχει τις 
πληροφορίες για τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, τις σημειώσεις και τις 
άκρες διδασκαλίας, τις προτάσεις αξιολόγησης και τις πρόσθετες 
αναφορές. Αυτή η δραστηριότητα είναι μέρος της συλλογής 
αφετηρίας: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El ejercicio del compartimiento de la niebla es 
una demostración del bocado de la ciencia de Exploratorium. La 
actividad muestra a estudiantes cómo las nubes y la niebla se crean 
con un modelo físico muy simple usando un tarro de 1 galón, el 
guante del látex, una poca agua, y emparejamientos. El 
ejercicio enseña a estudiantes cómo hacer una nube simple que para 
formar requiera el vapor de agua, un mecanismo el refrescarse, y 
núcleos de la condensación. Este sitio proporciona a la 
información en los materiales didácticos, las notas y las 
extremidades de la enseñanza, las sugerencias del gravamen y las 
referencias adicionales. Esta actividad es parte de la 
colección del punto de partida: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201741</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106913</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/fog-chamber</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
