<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107740</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107740</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087367</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"All Men Are Born Free and Equal": Massachusetts Yeomen Oppose the "Aristocratickal" Constitution, January, 1788.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"alle Männer sind" getragenes freies und gleich: 
Massachusetts Yeomen setzen der "Aristocratickal" 
Beschaffenheit, Januar, 1788 entgegen.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"tous les hommes sont libres et égaux soutenus" :
Le Massachusetts Yeomen s'opposent à la constitution 
d'"Aristocratickal", janvier, 1788.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"todos os homens são livres e iguais carregados":
Os yeomen de Massachusetts opõem o constitution de 
"Aristocratickal", janeiro, 1788.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"tutti gli uomini sono libero ed uguale 
sopportati": I yeomen del Massachusetts oppongono la 
costituzione "di Aristocratickal", gennaio, del 1788.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Όλα τα άτομα είναι γεννημένα ελεύθερα και ίσα": 
Η Μασαχουσέτη Yeomen αντιτάσσει το "Aristocratickal" 
σύνταγμα, τον Ιανουάριος, του 1788.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"todos los hombres son libres e iguales nacida": 
Los yeomen de Massachusetts oponen la constitución de 
"Aristocratickal", enero de 1788.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The constitution of the United States was composed in Philadelphia in the summer of 1787. Afterward, ratifying conventions were held in the states. In Massachusetts, site of the previous year's Shay's Rebellion against government enforcement of private debt collection, ratification did not go uncontested. Farmers from the western part of the state, such as the "yeomen" who signed this letter published in the  Massachusetts Gazette  in January, 1788, were suspicious of the power that the constitution seemed to centralize in elite hands. Rural smallholders were not the only ones who felt this way, however. Thomas Jefferson, then in Paris as the United States' minister to France, felt similarly. Massachusetts ratified the constitution on February 7, 1788.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Beschaffenheit der Vereinigten Staaten bestand in 
Philadelphia am Sommer von 1787. Danach wurden bestätigende 
Versammlungen in den Zuständen angehalten. In Massachusetts 
ging Site vom Aufstand Shays des vorhergehenden Jahres gegen Regierung
Durchführung der privaten Schuldeneintreibung, Bestätigung nicht 
uncontested. Landwirte vom westlichen Teil des Zustandes, wie 
der "Yeomen" wer diesen Brief unterzeichneten, der in der 
Massachusetts Zeitung im Januar, 1788 veröffentlicht wurde, waren von
der Energie mißtrauisch, die die Beschaffenheit schien, in den 
Auslesehänden zu zentralisieren. Landwirtschaftliche 
smallholders waren nicht die einzigen, die auf diese Weise glaubten, 
jedoch. Thomas Jefferson, dann in Paris als dem Minister der 
Vereinigten Staaten nach Frankreich, Filz ähnlich. 
Massachusetts bestätigte die Beschaffenheit an Februar 7, 1788.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La constitution des Etats-Unis s'est composée à 
Philadelphie en été de 1787. Après, des conventions de 
ratification ont été tenues dans les états. Dans le 
Massachusetts, le site de la rébellion de Shay d'année précédente 
contre l'application de gouvernement de la collection de dette 
personnelle, ratification n'est pas entré uncontested. Les 
fermiers de la partie occidentale de l'état, tel que les 
"petits propriétaires" qui ont signé cette lettre éditée dans la gazette du
Massachusetts en janvier, 1788, étaient soupçonneux de la puissance 
que la constitution a semblé centraliser dans des mains d'élite. 
Les petits exploitants ruraux n'étaient pas les seuls qui ont senti 
de cette façon, cependant. Thomas Jefferson, puis à Paris en 
tant que ministre des Etats-Unis vers la France, feutre pareillement. 
Le Massachusetts a ratifié la constitution 7 février 1788.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O constitution dos estados unidos foi composto em 
Filadélfia no verão de 1787. Mais tarde, as convenções 
ratificando foram prendidas nos estados. Em Massachusetts, o 
local da rebelião de Shay de ano precedente de encontro ao 
enforcement do governo da coleção de débito confidencial, 
ratification não foi uncontested. Os fazendeiros da parte 
ocidental do estado, tal como os "yeomen" quem assinaram esta letra 
publicada no gazette de Massachusetts em janeiro, 1788, eram 
suspicious da potência que o constitution pareceu centralizar nas 
mãos do elite. Os smallholders rurais não eram únicos que 
sentiram esta maneira, entretanto. Thomas Jefferson, então em 
Paris como o ministro dos estados unidos a France, feltro 
similarmente. Massachusetts ratificou o constitution fevereiro 
em 7, 1788.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La costituzione del unito Dichiara si è composta a
Filadelfia di estate di 1787. In seguito, le convenzioni di 
ratificazione sono state tenute in dichiara. In 
Massachusetts, il luogo della Ribellione dello Shay dell'anno 
precedente contro applicazione di governo della riscossione dei 
crediti riservata, la ratifica non è andato uncontested. I 
coltivatori dalla parte occidentale del dichiarare, quali "i yeomen" 
chi hanno firmato questa lettera pubblicata nel gazette del 
Massachusetts in gennaio, del 1788, erano sospettosi dell'potenza che 
la costituzione ha sembrato centralizzare in mani dell'elite. 
Gli smallholders rurali non erano quei unici che ritenessero 
questo modo, tuttavia. Thomas Jefferson, allora a Parigi come 
unito Dichiara similmente 'il ministro in Francia, feltro.
Massachusetts ha ratificato la costituzione il 7 febbraio 1788.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το σύνταγμα των Ηνωμένων Πολιτειών συντέθηκε στη 
Φιλαδέλφεια καλοκαίρι 1787, Κατόπιν, επικυρώνοντας οι 
συμβάσεις έγιναν στα κράτη. Στη Μασαχουσέτη, περιοχή της 
εξέγερσης Shay του προηγούμενου έτους ενάντια στην κυβερνητική
επιβολή της ιδιωτικής συλλογής χρέους, η επικύρωση δεν πήγε 
ασυναγώνιστη. Οι αγρότες από το δυτικό μέρος του κράτους, 
όπως "" ποιος υπέγραψε αυτήν την επιστολή που δημοσιεύθηκε στην 
εφημερίδα της Μασαχουσέτης τον Ιανουάριο, 1788, ήταν ύποπτοι 
της δύναμης ότι το σύνταγμα φάνηκε να συγκεντρώνει στα χέρια 
ελίτ. Οι αγροτικοί μικροκτηματίες δεν ήταν οι μόνοι που 
αισθάνθηκαν αυτόν τον τρόπο, εντούτοις. Ο Thomas 
Jefferson, έπειτα στο Παρίσι ως Ηνωμένος υπουργός στη Γαλλία, 
αισθάνθηκε ομοίως. Η Μασαχουσέτη επικύρωσε το σύνταγμα στις
7 Φεβρουαρίου, 1788.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La constitución de los Estados Unidos fue compuesta en 
Philadelphia en el verano de 1787. Luego, llevaron a cabo a las 
convenciones que ratificaban en los estados. En Massachusetts, 
el sitio de la rebelión de Shay del año anterior contra la 
aplicación del gobierno del reembolso de la deuda privada, 
ratificación no entró uncontested. Los granjeros de la parte 
occidental del estado, tal como los "yeomen" quiénes firmaron esta 
letra publicada en la gaceta de Massachusetts en enero de 1788, eran 
sospechosos de la potencia que la constitución se parecía 
centralizar en manos de la élite. Los smallholders rurales no 
eran los únicos que sentían esta manera, sin embargo. Thomas 
Jefferson, entonces en París como el ministro de los Estados Unidos a
Francia, fieltro semejantemente. Massachusetts ratificó la 
constitución 7 de febrero de 1788.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087367</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107740</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/all-men-are-born-free-and-equal-massachusetts-yeomen-oppose-the-aristocratickal-constitution-january-1788</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
