<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107003</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107003</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973925</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Trade Rule Game</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geschäftsrichtlinie Spiel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jeu Commercial de Règle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogo De comércio Da Régua</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gioco Commerciale Di Regola</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παιχνίδι εμπορικού κανόνα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Juego Comercial De la Regla</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Play a game and find out about a Nobel Prize awarded discovery or work! Bertil Ohlin, awarded the Prize in Economics in 1977, showed that countries engage in and benefit from trade if their production resources differ from each other. The Sveriges Riksbank Prize in Economic Sciences in Memory of Alfred Nobel has been awarded since 1969. Alfred Nobel, in whose memory the Economics Prize is awarded, was not only an inventor, but was also an intrepreneur who established the first international holding company in the world. Play a game and find out about a work that has been awarded the Economics Prize!</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Business</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spielen Sie ein Spiel und finden Sie über eine 
zugesprochene Entdeckung oder eine Arbeit des Nobelpreises heraus! 
Bertil Ohlin, den Preis in der Volkswirtschaft 1977 
zugesprochen, gezeigt, daß Länder sich innen engagieren und vom 
Handel profitieren, wenn ihre Produktion Betriebsmittel von einander 
sich unterscheiden. Der Sveriges Riksbank Preis in den 
Wirtschaftswissenschaften im Speicher von Alfred Nobel ist seit 1969 
zugesprochen worden. Alfred Nobel, in dessen Speicher der 
Volkswirtschaft-Preis zugesprochen wird, war nicht nur ein Erfinder, 
aber war auch ein intrepreneur, das die erste internationale anhaltene
Firma in der Welt herstellte. Spielen Sie ein Spiel und finden 
Sie über eine Arbeit heraus, die den Volkswirtschaft-Preis 
zugesprochen worden ist!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jouez un jeu et découvrez au sujet d'une 
découverte ou d'un travail attribuée de prix Nobel ! Bertil 
Ohlin, attribué le prix dans les sciences économiques en 1977, 
prouvé que les pays s'engagent dedans et tirent bénéfice du 
commerce si leurs ressources de production diffèrent de l'un l'autre.
Le prix de Sveriges Riksbank en sciences économiques dans la 
mémoire d'Alfred Nobel a été attribué depuis 1969. Alfred 
Nobel, dans lequel la mémoire le prix de sciences économiques est 
attribué, était non seulement un inventeur, mais était également 
un intrepreneur qui a établi la première compagnie tenante 
internationale dans le monde. Jouez un jeu et découvrez au 
sujet d'un travail qui a été attribué le prix de sciences 
économiques !</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogue um jogo e encontre-o para fora sobre uma 
descoberta ou um trabalho concedido do prêmio de nobel! Bertil 
Ohlin, concedido o prêmio na economia em 1977, mostrado que os 
países acoplam dentro e se beneficiam do comércio se seus recursos 
da produção diferirem de se. O prêmio de Sveriges Riksbank em
ciências econômicas na memória de Alfred Nobel foi concedido desde 
1969. Alfred Nobel, cuja na memória o prêmio da economia é 
concedido, era não somente um inventor, mas era também um 
intrepreneur que estabelecesse a primeira companhia prendendo 
internacional no mundo. Jogue um jogo e encontre-o para fora 
sobre um trabalho que seja concedido o prêmio da economia!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gioc un gioco e scopra circa una scoperta o un 
lavoro ricevuta del premio Nobel! Bertil Ohlin, ricevuto il 
premio nell'economia in 1977, indicato che i paesi si agganciano 
dentro e traggono beneficio da commercio se le loro risorse di 
produzione differiscono da da a vicenda. Il premio di Sveriges 
Riksbank nelle scienze economiche nella memoria di Alfred Nobel ha 
ricevuto dal 1969. Alfred Nobel, di cui nella memoria il premio 
di economia riceve, era non soltanto un inventore, ma era egualmente 
un intrepreneur che ha istituito la prima azienda internazionale della
tenuta nel mondo. Gioc un gioco e scopra circa un lavoro 
che ha ricevuto il premio di economia!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παίξτε ένα παιχνίδι και ανακαλύψτε για μια 
απονεμημένη βραβείο ανακάλυψη ή μια εργασία Νόμπελ! Ο 
Bertil Ohlin, απένειμε το βραβείο στα οικονομικά το 1977, 
έδειξε ότι οι χώρες συμμετέχουν και ωφελούνται από το εμπόριο 
εάν τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς παραγωγής τους διαφέρουν το ένα 
από το άλλο. Το βραβείο Sveriges Riksbank στις 
οικονομικές επιστήμες στη μνήμη του Alfred Nobel έχει 
απονεμηθεί από 1969, Alfred Nobel, στην των οποίων μνήμη 
που το βραβείο οικονομικών απονέμεται, ήταν όχι μόνο εφευρέτης,
αλλά ήταν επίσης ένα intrepreneur που είδρυσε την πρώτη 
διεθνή επιχείρηση εκμετάλλευσης στον κόσμο. Παίξτε ένα 
παιχνίδι και ανακαλύψτε για μια εργασία που έχει απονεμηθεί το 
βραβείο οικονομικών!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Juegue un juego y descubra sobre un 
descubrimiento o un trabajo concedido del premio Nobel! Bertil 
Ohlin, concedido el premio en la economía en 1977, mostrado que los 
países enganchan adentro y benefician de comercio si sus recursos de 
la producción diferencian de uno a. El premio de Sveriges 
Riksbank en ciencias económicas en la memoria de Alfred Nobel se ha 
concedido desde 1969. Alfred Nobel, en que memoria se concede el
premio de la economía, era no solamente inventor, pero era también 
un intrepreneur que estableció a primera compañía que sostenía 
internacional en el mundo. ¡Juegue un juego y descubra sobre un 
trabajo que se ha concedido el premio de la economía!</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geschäft</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Affaires</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Negócio</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Commercio</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιχείρηση</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Negocio</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973925</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107003</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/trade-rule-game</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
