<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104898</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104898</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085253</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Bracero Program</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Bracero Programm</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Programme de Bracero</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Programa De Bracero</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Programma Di Bracero</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το πρόγραμμα Bracero</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Programa De Bracero</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The government-sponsored Bracero Program was the temporary importation of workers from Mexico to aid the American agricultural economy. This was an important historical event that many Americans are unaware of today. A bracero (from brazo, the Spanish word for arm) was a Mexican worker allowed entry into the United States for a limited time, usually to work on a farm. In 1942, facing an extreme shortage of farm labor workers due to the war, Congress enacted the Emergency Labor Program. It approved the temporary immigration of thousands of Mexican workers to replace the American men who were in the armed services. During the 22 years of the Bracero Program, more than 4 million Mexican workers left their families behind and came to work in the fields of California. This migration had an enormous and lasting impact on the economy and demographics of California. The photograph "Battle for Work" shows hundreds of Mexican workers waiting at the border to be selected for the Bracero Program. The contrast between Mexico and the United States at this time is shown in the photograph of the dusty streets of Mexicali in "Street Scene of Mexicans Awaiting Legal Employment in the United States" and "View from Mexicali Toward the United States." Many Mexican workers were eager to be selected for the Bracero Program. "Battle for Work" shows hundreds of Mexican workers massed at the border, hoping to be chosen. Some of the images in this group show the arrival of the first braceros by train. Some of these photographs were taken by photographer Dorothea Lange as part of a government assignment to document this event.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das staatlich geförderte Bracero Programm war der
temporäre Import der Arbeiter von Mexiko, zum der amerikanischen 
landwirtschaftlichen Wirtschaft zu unterstützen. Dieses war ein
wichtiger historischer Fall, daß viele Amerikaner von heute 
ahnungslos sind. Ein bracero (vom brazo, vom spanischen Wort 
für Arm) war ein mexikanischer Arbeiter erlaubter Eintrag in die 
Vereinigten Staaten während einer begrenzten Zeit, auf einem 
Bauernhof normalerweise zu arbeiten. 1942 einen extremen Mangel 
an die Bauernhofarbeit Arbeiter wegen des Krieges, Kongreß 
gegenüberstellend verordnete das Dringlichkeitsarbeit Programm. 
Es genehmigte die temporäre Immigration Tausenden der 
mexikanischen Arbeiter, um die amerikanischen Männer zu ersetzen, die
in den bewaffneten Dienstleistungen waren. Während der 22 Jahre
des Bracero Programms, ließen mehr als 4 Million mexikanische 
Arbeiter ihre Familien nach und kamen, in zu arbeiten 
auffängt von Kalifornien. Diese Migration hatte eine 
enorme und dauerhafte Auswirkung auf die Wirtschaft und die 
Demographie von Kalifornien. Die Fotographie "Schlacht für 
Arbeit" zeigt Hunderte der mexikanischen Arbeiter, die am für warten 
das Bracero Programm ausgewählt zu werden Rand. Der Kontrast 
zwischen Mexiko und den Vereinigten Staaten diesmal wird gezeigt in 
der Fotographie der staubigen Straßen von Mexicali "in der Straße 
Szene des Mexikaners zugelassene Beschäftigung in den Vereinigten 
Staaten" und "Ansicht von Mexicali in Richtung zu den Vereinigten 
Staaten erwartend." Viele mexikanische Arbeiter waren eifrig, 
für das Bracero Programm ausgewählt zu werden. "Schlacht für 
Arbeit" Erscheinenhunderte der mexikanischen Arbeiter sammelte sich am
Rand an und hoffte gewählt zu werden. Einige der Bilder in 
diesem Gruppe Erscheinen die Ankunft der ersten braceros durch Serie. 
Einige dieser Fotographien wurden vom Photographen Dorothea 
Lange als Teil einer Regierung Anweisung genommen, um diesen Fall zu 
dokumentieren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le programme commandité par le gouvernement de 
Bracero était l'importation provisoire des ouvriers du Mexique pour 
faciliter l'économie agricole américaine. C'était un 
événement historique important que beaucoup d'Américains sont 
ignorants d'aujourd'hui. Un bracero (du brazo, du mot espagnol 
pour le bras) était une entrée permise par ouvrier mexicain en les 
Etats-Unis pendant un temps limité, pour travailler habituellement à
une ferme. En 1942, faisant face à un manque extrême 
d'ouvriers de travail de ferme dus à la guerre, le congrès a 
décrété le programme de travail de secours. Il a approuvé 
l'immigration provisoire des milliers d'ouvriers mexicains pour 
substituer les hommes américains qui étaient dans les forces 
armées. Pendant les 22 années du programme de Bracero, plus de
4 millions d'ouvriers mexicains ont laissé leurs familles derrière 
et sont venus pour travailler dans les domaines de la Californie. 
Ce transfert a eu un énorme et durable impact sur l'économie 
et la démographie de la Californie. La photographie "bataille 
pour le travail" montre des centaines d'ouvriers mexicains attendant 
au cadre à choisir pour le programme de Bracero. Le contraste 
entre le Mexique et les Etats-Unis à ce moment est montré dans la 
photographie des rues poussiéreuses de Mexicali dans la "scène de 
rue du Mexicain attendant l'emploi légal aux Etats-Unis" et la "vue 
de Mexicali vers les Etats-Unis." Beaucoup d'ouvriers mexicains 
étaient désireux d'être choisis pour le programme de Bracero. 
la "bataille des centaines d'expositions pour travail" 
d'ouvriers mexicains a amassé au cadre, espérant être choisi. 
Certaines des images dans cette exposition de groupe l'arrivée 
des premiers braceros par chemin de fer. Certaines de ces 
photographies ont été prises par le photographe Dorothea Lange en 
tant qu'élément d'une affectation de gouvernement pour documenter 
cet événement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O programa government-sponsored de Bracero era o 
importation provisório dos trabalhadores de México para ajudar à 
economia agricultural americana. Este era um evento histórico 
importante que muitos americanos são inconscientes de hoje. Um 
bracero (do brazo, da palavra espanhola para o braço) era trabalhador
mexicano uma entrada permitida nos estados unidos por um tempo 
limitado, geralmente ao trabalho em uma fazenda. Em 1942, 
enfrentando uma falta extrema dos trabalhadores  devido à guerra, 
congress do trabalho de fazenda decretou o programa do trabalho da 
emergência. Aprovou o immigration provisório dos milhares de 
trabalhadores mexicanos para substituir os homens americanos que 
estavam nos forças armadas. Durante os 22 anos do programa de 
Bracero, mais de 4 milhão trabalhadores mexicanos deixaram suas 
famílias atrás e vieram trabalhar nos campos de Califórnia. 
Esta migração teve um impacto enorme e durável na economia e 
no demographics de Califórnia. A fotografia "batalha para o 
trabalho" mostra centenas dos trabalhadores mexicanos que esperam na 
beira a ser selecionada para o programa de Bracero. O contraste 
entre México e os estados unidos neste tempo é mostrado na 
fotografia das ruas empoeiradas de Mexicali da "na cena rua do 
mexicano que espera o emprego legal nos estados unidos" e a "vista de 
Mexicali para os estados unidos." Muitos trabalhadores mexicanos
estavam ansiosos para ser selecionado para o programa de Bracero. 
a "batalha para centenas das mostras do trabalho" de 
trabalhadores mexicanos reuniu-se na beira, esperando ser escolhido. 
Algumas das imagens nesta mostra do grupo a chegada dos 
primeiros braceros pelo trem. Algumas destas fotografias foram 
feitas exame pelo fotógrafo Dorothea Lange como a parte de uma 
atribuição do governo para documentar este evento.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il programma government-sponsored di Bracero era 
l'importazione provvisoria degli operai dal Messico per aiutare 
l'economia agricola americana. Ciò era un evento storico 
importante che molti Americani sono ignari di oggi. Un bracero 
(dal brazo, dalla parola spagnola per il braccio) era un'entrata 
permessa operaio messicano nel unito Dichiara per un tempo 
limitato, di lavorare solitamente ad un podere. In 1942, 
affrontando una scarsità estrema degli operai di lavoro dovuto la 
guerra, congresso dell'azienda agricola ha promulgato il programma di 
Lavoro di emergenza. Ha approvato l'immigrazione 
provvisoria i migliaia degli operai messicani per sostituire gli 
uomini americani che erano nelle forze armate. Durante i 22 anni
del programma di Bracero, più di 4 milione operai messicani hanno 
lasciato le loro famiglie dietro e sono venuto funzionare nei campi 
della California. Questa espansione ha avuta un effetto enorme e
durevole sull'economia e sul demographics della California. La 
fotografia "battaglia per lavoro" mostra i centinaia degli operai 
messicani che attendono al bordo da selezionare per il programma di 
Bracero. Il contrasto fra il Messico ed uniti Dichiara 
attualmente è indicato nella fotografia delle vie polverose di 
Mexicali "nella scena della via del mexicans che attende l'occupazione
legale in unito Dichiara" e "la vista da Mexicali verso unito 
Dichiara." Molti operai messicani erano desiderosi di 
essere selezionato per il programma di Bracero. "la battaglia 
per centinaia di esposizioni del lavoro" degli operai messicani si 
è ammassata al bordo, sperante di essere scelto. Alcune delle 
immagini in questa esposizione del gruppo l'arrivo dei primi braceros 
in treno. Alcune di queste fotografie sono state prese dal 
photographer Dorothea Lange come componente di un'assegnazione di 
governo per documentare questo evento.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το χρηματοδοτούμενο από την κυβέρνηση πρόγραμμα 
Bracero ήταν η προσωρινή εισαγωγή των εργαζομένων από το 
Μεξικό για να βοηθήσει την αμερικανική γεωργική οικονομία. 
Αυτό ήταν ένα σημαντικό ιστορικό γεγονός ότι πολλοί 
Αμερικανοί είναι απληροφόρητοι σήμερα. Ένα bracero (από
το brazo, την ισπανική λέξη για το βραχίονα) ήταν μια 
μεξικάνικη εργαζόμενος είσοδος μέσα σε τις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες 
για έναν περιορισμένο χρόνο, συνήθως εργάζομαι σε ένα 
αγρόκτημα. Το 1942, αντιμετωπίζοντας μια ακραία έλλειψη 
των εργαζομένων αγροτικής εργασίας λόγω στον πόλεμο, το συνέδριο
θέσπισε το πρόγραμμα εργασίας έκτακτης ανάγκης. Ενέκρινε 
την προσωρινή μετανάστευση χιλιάδων μεξικάνικοι εργαζόμενοι για 
να αντικαταστήσει τα αμερικανικά άτομα που ήταν στις Ένοπλες 
Δυνάμεις. Κατά τη διάρκεια των 22 ετών του προγράμματος 
Bracero, περισσότεροι από 4 εκατομμύριο μεξικάνικοι 
εργαζόμενοι άφησαν τις οικογένειές τους πίσω και ήρθαν να 
εργαστούν στα πεδία Καλιφόρνιας. Αυτή η μετανάστευση 
άσκησε τεράστια και μόνιμη επίδραση στην οικονομία και το 
demographics Καλιφόρνιας. Η φωτογραφία "μάχη για την 
εργασία" εμφανίζει εκατοντάδες των μεξικάνικων εργαζομένων που 
περιμένουν στα σύνορα για να επιλεχτεί για το πρόγραμμα 
Bracero. Η αντίθεση μεταξύ του Μεξικού και των Ηνωμένων 
Πολιτειών αυτή τη στιγμή εμφανίζεται στη φωτογραφία των 
σκονισμένων οδών Mexicali στη "σκηνή οδών μεξικανών που 
αναμένουν τη νομική απασχόληση στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείεσ" και "την 
όψη από Mexicali προς τις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες." Πολλοί 
μεξικάνικοι εργαζόμενοι ήταν πρόθυμοι να επιλεχτούν για το 
πρόγραμμα Bracero. "Η μάχη για την εργασία" εμφανίζει 
εκατοντάδες των μεξικάνικων εργαζομένων που μαζεύονται στα 
σύνορα, που ελπίζουν να επιλεχτεί. Μερικές από τις εικόνες
σε αυτήν την ομάδα εμφανίζουν την άφιξη των πρώτων braceros με
το τραίνο. Μερικές από αυτές τις φωτογραφίες λήφθηκαν από
το φωτογράφο Dorothea Lange ως τμήμα μιας κυβερνητικής 
ανάθεσης για να τεκμηριώσουν αυτό το γεγονός.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El programa government-sponsored de Bracero era la
importación temporal de trabajadores de México para ayudar a la 
economía agrícola americana. Esto era un acontecimiento 
histórico importante que muchos americanos son inconscientes de hoy. 
Un bracero (de brazo, de la palabra española para el brazo) era
una entrada permitida trabajador mexicano en los Estados Unidos por un
tiempo limitado, para trabajar generalmente en una granja. En 
1942, haciendo frente a una escasez extrema de los trabajadores  
debido a la guerra, congreso del trabajo de granja decretó el 
programa del trabajo de la emergencia. Aprobó la inmigración 
temporal de millares de trabajadores mexicanos para substituir a los 
hombres americanos que estaban en las fuerzas armadas. Durante 
los 22 años del programa de Bracero, más de 4 millones de 
trabajadores mexicanos dejaron a sus familias detrás y vinieron 
trabajar en los campos de California. Esta migración tenía un 
impacto enorme y duradero en la economía y el demographics de 
California. La fotografía "batalla para el trabajo" muestra a 
centenares de trabajadores mexicanos que esperan en la frontera que se
seleccionará para el programa de Bracero. El contraste entre 
México y los Estados Unidos en este tiempo se muestra en la 
fotografía de las calles polvorientas de Mexicali en la "escena de la
calle del mexicano que aguarda el empleo legal en los Estados Unidos" 
y la "visión desde Mexicali hacia los Estados Unidos." Muchos 
trabajadores mexicanos eran impacientes ser seleccionado para el 
programa de Bracero. la "batalla para los centenares de las 
demostraciones del trabajo" de trabajadores mexicanos se formó en la 
frontera, esperando ser elegido. Algunas de las imágenes en 
esta demostración del grupo la llegada de los primeros braceros en 
tren. Algunas de estas fotografías fueron tomadas por el 
fotógrafo Dorothea Lange como parte de una asignación del gobierno 
para documentar este acontecimiento.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085253</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104898</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-bracero-program</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
