<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108709</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108709</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206089</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Searching for the Building Blocks of Matter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Suchen nach den Bausteinen des Stoffes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Recherche les modules de la matière</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Procurarando pelos blocos de edifício da 
matéria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Cercando i blocchetti di costruzione della 
materia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Έρευνα για τις δομικές μονάδες του θέματος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Buscar para los bloques de edificio de la materia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">looks at Fermilab's search for the smallest building blocks of matter. It also describes the accelerator and detectors needed for the discovery of these building blocks (quarks, leptons and bosons), spin-offs along the way, and continuing efforts to reveal the basic particles and forces of nature. Fermilab is a high-energy physics laboratory that houses the Tevatron, the world's most powerful particle accelerator.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Blicke auf Suche Fermilabs nach den kleinsten 
Bausteinen des Stoffes. Er beschreibt auch das Gaspedal und die 
Detektoren, die für die Entdeckung dieser Bausteine benötigt werden 
(quarks, Leptons und Bosons), der Spin-offs entlang der Methode und 
der fortfahrenden Bemühungen, die grundlegenden Partikel und die 
Kräfte der Natur aufzudecken. Fermilab ist ein energiereiches 
Physiklabor, das das Tevatron unterbringt, das leistungsfähigste 
Partikelgaspedal der Welt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">regards à la recherche de Fermilab des plus 
petits modules de la matière. Elle décrit également 
l'accélérateur et les détecteurs requis pour la découverte de ces 
modules (quarks, leptons et bosons), d'applications secondaires le 
long de la voie, et d'efforts continus d'indiquer les particules et 
les forces de base de la nature. Fermilab est un laboratoire de 
grande énergie de physique qui loge le Tevatron, l'accélérateur le 
plus puissant des particules du monde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">olhares na busca de Fermilab para os blocos de 
edifício os menores da matéria. Descreve também o accelerator
e os detetores necessitados para a descoberta destes blocos de 
edifício (quarks, leptons e bosons), de spin-offs ao longo da 
maneira, e de esforços continuando revelar as partículas e as 
forças básicas da natureza. Fermilab é um laboratório 
high-energy que abrigue o Tevatron, o accelerator o mais poderoso da 
física da partícula do mundo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">sguardi alla ricerca del Fermilab di più piccoli 
blocchetti di costruzione della materia. Egualmente descrive 
l'acceleratore ed i rivelatori stati necessario per la scoperta di 
questi blocchetti di costruzione (quarks, leptons e bosoni), dei 
prodotti derivati lungo il modo e degli sforzi continui rivelare le 
particelle e le forze di base della natura. Fermilab è un 
laboratorio ad alta energia che alloggia il Tevatron, l'acceleratore 
di fisica della particella più potente del mondo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει την αναζήτηση Fermilab των μικρότερων 
δομικών μονάδων του θέματος. Περιγράφει επίσης τη 
συντομογραφία και τους ανιχνευτές που απαιτούνται για την 
ανακάλυψη αυτών των δομικών μονάδων (θεωρητικά και υποατομικά 
σωματίδια, leptons και bosons), των υποπροϊόντων κατά μήκος
του τρόπου, και των συνεχιμένος προσπαθειών να αποκαλυφθούν τα 
βασικές μόρια και οι δυνάμεις της φύσης. Το Fermilab 
είναι ένα υψηλής ενέργειας εργαστήριο φυσικής που στεγάζει το 
Tevatron, η συντομογραφία παγκόσμιων ισχυρότερη μορίων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">miradas en la búsqueda de Fermilab para los 
bloques de edificio más pequeños de la materia. También 
describe el acelerador y los detectores necesitados para el 
descubrimiento de estos bloques de edificio (quarks, leptons y 
bosons), de los efectos a lo largo de la manera, y de los esfuerzos de
continuación de revelar las partículas y las fuerzas básicas de la 
naturaleza. Fermilab es un laboratorio de gran energía que 
contiene el Tevatron, el acelerador más de gran alcance de la física
de la partícula del mundo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206089</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108709</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/searching-for-the-building-blocks-of-matter</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
