<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106301</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106301</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202639</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Making a Video Critique of an Information Source</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bilden einer videokritik einer Informationsquelle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Fabrication d'une critique visuelle d'un émetteur
d'informations</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fazer uma crítica video de uma fonte de 
informação</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Facendo una video valutazione di una sorgente di 
informazioni</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παραγωγή μιας τηλεοπτικής κριτικής μιας πηγής 
πληροφοριών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fabricación de una crítica video de una fuente 
de información</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">After finishing their social issues research paper for their English class (or any other type of research paper), students will write and present orally a critique of one information source used in their research papers. Students will work in pairs to videotape each other, and they must also design appropriate backdrops for their oral presentations. Students will watch and evaluate all critiques. This interdisciplinary assignment combines information skills and language arts skills, and requires collaboration between the media specialist and the English teacher.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nach der Fertigung ihres Sozialausgaben Forschung 
Papiers für ihre englische Kategorie (oder irgendeinen anderen Typen 
Forschung Papier), schreiben Kursteilnehmer und stellen mündlich eine
Kritik von einer Informationsquelle dar, die in ihren Forschung 
Papieren verwendet wird. Kursteilnehmer arbeiten in den Paaren 
videotape, und sie müssen passende Hintergründe für ihre 
Munddarstellungen auch konzipieren. Kursteilnehmer überwachen 
und werten alle Kritiken aus. Diese interdisziplinäre Anweisung
kombiniert Informationen Fähigkeiten und Sprachenkunstfähigkeiten 
und benötigt Zusammenarbeit zwischen dem Mediafachmann und dem 
englischen Lehrer.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Après avoir terminé leur papier social de 
recherches d'issues pour leur classe anglaise (ou tout autre type de 
papier de recherches), les étudiants écriront et présenteront 
oralement une critique d'un émetteur d'informations utilisé en leur 
journal de recherches. Les étudiants travailleront dans les 
paires pour s'enregistrer en vidéo, et ils doivent également 
concevoir les contextes appropriés pour leurs présentations orales. 
Les étudiants observeront et évalueront toutes les critiques. 
Cette affectation interdisciplinaire combine des qualifications 
de l'information et des qualifications d'arts de langage, et exige la 
collaboration entre le spécialiste en medias et le professeur 
anglais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Após ter terminado seu papel de pesquisa social 
das edições para sua classe inglesa (ou algum outro tipo de papel de
pesquisa), os estudantes escreverão e apresentarão oral uma crítica
de uma fonte de informação usada em seus papéis de pesquisa. 
Os estudantes trabalharão em pares para gravar-se, e devem 
também projetar backdrops apropriados para suas apresentações 
orais. Os estudantes prestarão atenção e avaliarão a todas 
as críticas. Esta atribuição interdisciplinary combina 
habilidades da informação e habilidades das artes da língua, e 
requer a colaboração entre o specialist dos media e o professor 
inglês.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dopo la rifinitura della loro pubblicazione 
sociale delle edizioni per il loro codice categoria inglese (o 
qualunque altro tipo di pubblicazione), gli allievi scriveranno 
oralmente e presenteranno una valutazione di una sorgente di 
informazioni usata in loro pubblicazioni. Gli allievi 
lavoreranno negli accoppiamenti per registrarsi su video e devono 
anche progettare i contesti adatti per le loro presentazioni orali. 
Gli allievi guarderanno e valuteranno tutte le valutazioni. 
Questa assegnazione interdisciplinare unisce le abilità delle 
informazioni e le abilità di arti di linguaggio e richiede la 
collaborazione fra l'esperto di media e l'insegnante inglese.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μετά από να τελειώσουν την κοινωνική ερευνητική 
εργασία ζητημάτων τους για την αγγλική κλάση τους (ή οποιοδήποτε
άλλοδήποτε τύπο ερευνητικής εργασίας), οι σπουδαστές θα γράψουν
και θα παρουσιάσουν προφορικά μια κριτική μιας πηγής πληροφοριών 
που χρησιμοποιείται στις ερευνητικές εργασίες τους. Οι 
σπουδαστές θα απασχοληθούν ανά τα ζευγάρια στη μαγνητοταινία ο 
ένας στον άλλο, και πρέπει επίσης να σχεδιάσουν τα κατάλληλα 
φόντα για τις προφορικές παρουσιάσεις τους. Οι σπουδαστές θα
προσέξουν και θα αξιολογήσουν όλες τις κριτικές. Αυτή η 
διεπιστημονική ανάθεση συνδυάζει τις δεξιότητες δεξιοτήτων 
πληροφοριών και γλωσσικών τεχνών, και απαιτεί τη συνεργασία 
μεταξύ του ειδικού μέσων και του αγγλικού δασκάλου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Después de acabar su papel de investigación 
social de las ediciones para su clase inglesa (o cualquier otro tipo 
de papel de investigación), los estudiantes escribirán y 
presentarán oral una crítica de una fuente de información usada en 
sus papeles de investigación. Los estudiantes trabajarán en 
pares para grabarse, y deben también diseñar los contextos 
apropiados para sus presentaciones orales. Los estudiantes 
mirarán y evaluarán todas las críticas. Esta asignación 
interdisciplinaria combina habilidades de la información y 
habilidades de los artes del lenguaje, y requiere la colaboración 
entre el especialista de los media y el profesor inglés.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:BONNIE SNYDER
FN:BONNIE SNYDER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202639</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106301</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/making-a-video-critique-of-an-information-source</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
