<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104835</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104835</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212034</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Igneous Rocks for Undergraduate Courses</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eruptivgesteine für Nichtgraduiert-Kurse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Roches plutoniques pour des cours d'étudiant 
préparant une licence</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Rochas igneous para cursos do undergraduate</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Rocce eruttive per i corsi dello studente non 
laureato</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πύρινοι βράχος για τις προπτυχιακές σειρές μαθημάτων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Rocas ígneas para los cursos del estudiante</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site contains photographs of 22 igneous rock hand samples. Clicking on an image brings up a larger view of the sample. In addition, links to thin sections are available for some of the samples. Thin sections can be seen in both crossed polarized light and plane polarized light by moving the cursor on and off the photomicrograph. This resource is part of the Teaching Petrology collection. http://serc.carleton.edu/NAGTWorkshops/petrology03/index.html</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site enthält Fotographien von 22 
Eruptivgesteinhandproben. Das Klicken auf einem Bild holt oben 
eine größere Ansicht der Probe. Zusätzlich sind die Links, 
zum der Kapitel zu verdünnen für einige der Proben vorhanden. 
Dünne Kapitel können in gekreuztes polarisiertes Licht und in 
Fläche polarisiertes Licht gesehen werden, indem man den Cursor auf 
und weg vom Photomikrobild verschiebt. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist 
ein Teil der unterrichtenden Petrologyansammlung 
http://serc.carleton.edu/NAGTWorkshops/petrology03/index.html</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site contient des photographies de 22 
échantillons de main de roche plutonique. Cliquer sur 
une image évoque une plus grande vue de l'échantillon. En 
outre, les liens pour amincir des sections sont disponibles pour 
certains des échantillons. Des sections minces peuvent être 
vues dans la lumière polarisée croisée et la lumière polarisée 
par avion en déplaçant le curseur en marche et en arrêt le 
photomicrographe. Cette ressource fait partie de la collection 
d'enseignement 
http://serc.carleton.edu/NAGTWorkshops/petrology03/index.html de 
petrology</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local contem fotografias de 22 amostras da 
mão da rocha igneous. Estalar em uma imagem traz acima uma 
vista maior da amostra. Além, as ligações para diluir 
seções estão disponíveis para algumas das amostras. As 
seções finas podem ser vistas  na luz polarizada cruzada e na luz 
polarizada plano movendo o cursor e fora do photomicrograph. 
Este recurso é parte da coleção ensinando 
http://serc.carleton.edu/NAGTWorkshops/petrology03/index.html da 
petrologia</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo contiene lle fotografie di 22 
campioni della mano della roccia eruttiva. Scattandosi su 
un'immagine porta in su una più grande vista del campione. In 
più, i collegamenti per assottigliare le sezioni sono disponibili per
alcuni dei campioni. Le sezioni sottili possono essere viste sia
alla luce polarizzata attraversata che alla luce polarizzata aereo 
spostando il cursore in funzione e a riposo il fotomicrografo. 
Questa risorsa fa parte dell'accumulazione d'istruzione 
http://serc.carleton.edu/NAGTWorkshops/petrology03/index.html di 
petrology</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή περιέχει τις φωτογραφίες 22 
δειγμάτων χεριών πύρινου βράχου. Ο κρότος σε μια εικόνα 
φέρνει επάνω μια μεγαλύτερη όψη του δείγματος. Επιπλέον, 
οι συνδέσεις για να λεπταίνουν τα τμήματα είναι διαθέσιμες για 
μερικά από τα δείγματα. Τα λεπτά τμήματα μπορούν να 
δουν και στο διασχισμένο πολωμένο φως και στο αεροπλάνο
πόλωσαν το φως με την κίνηση του δρομέα σε και από το 
φωτομικρογράφο. Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς είναι μέρος 
της συλλογής 
http://serc.carleton.edu/NAGTWorkshops/petrology03/index.html 
πετρολογίας διδασκαλίας</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio contiene las fotografías de 22 
muestras de la mano de la roca ígnea. El hacer clic en una 
imagen trae para arriba una vista más grande de la muestra. 
Además, las conexiones para enrarecer secciones están 
disponibles para algunas de las muestras. Las secciones finas se
pueden considerar en luz polarizada cruzada y luz polarizada plano 
moviendo el cursor por intervalos la fotomicrografía. Este 
recurso es parte de la colección de enseñanza 
http://serc.carleton.edu/NAGTWorkshops/petrology03/index.html de la 
petrología</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ROBERT MARSH
FN:ROBERT MARSH
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212034</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104835</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/science-hobbist-childrens-misconceptions-about-science</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
