<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103445</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103445</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203614</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Lactic Acid Bacteria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Milchsäure-Bakterium</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bactéries d'Acide Lactique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Bactérias Do Ácido Lactic</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Batteri Dell'Acido Lattico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βακτηρίδια γαλακτικού οξέος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Bacterias Del Ácido Láctico</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This on-line exercise is focused on lactic acid bacteria, a group of related bacteria that produce lactic acid as a result of carbohydrate fermentation. It includes a protocol for the enrichment of lactic acid bacteria from enriched samples (like yogurt, sauerkraut, decaying plant matter, and tooth plaque). Three parameters are measured: growth, culture diversity, and pH. The exercise also includes instructions for the isolation of some of these bacteria by using the streak-plate method.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Onlineübung wird auf Milchsäurebakterium, 
eine Gruppe in Verbindung stehendes Bakterium gerichtet, das 
Milchsäure resultierend aus Kohlenhydratgärung produzieren. 
Sie schließt ein Protokoll für die Bereicherung des 
Milchsäurebakteriums von angereicherten Proben ein (wie Joghurt, 
Sauerkraut, verfallender Betriebsstoff und Zahnplakette). Drei 
Parameter werden gemessen: Wachstum, Kulturverschiedenartigkeit 
und pH. Die Übung schließt auch Anweisungen für die 
Lokalisierung von einigem dieses Bakteriums ein, indem sie die 
Politurscheibemethode verwendet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cet exercice en ligne est concentré sur les 
bactéries d'acide lactique, un groupe de bactéries relatives qui 
produisent l'acide lactique en raison de la fermentation d'hydrate de 
carbone. Il inclut un protocole pour l'enrichissement des 
bactéries d'acide lactique des échantillons enrichis (comme le 
yaourt, la choucroute, la matière se délabrante d'usine, et la 
plaque de dent). Trois paramètres sont mesurés : 
croissance, diversité de culture, et pH. L'exercice 
inclut également des instructions pour l'isolement de certaines de 
ces bactéries en utilisant la méthode de plaque de frottis.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este exercício em linha é focalizado nas 
bactérias do ácido lactic, um grupo das bactérias relacionadas que 
produzem o ácido lactic em conseqüência do fermentation do hidrato 
de carbono. Inclui um protocolo para o enriquecimento das 
bactérias do ácido lactic das amostras enriquecidas (como o yogurt, 
o sauerkraut, a matéria deteriorando da planta, e a chapa do dente). 
Três parâmetros são medidos: crescimento, diversidade 
da cultura, e pH. O exercício inclui também instruções para 
a isolação de algumas destas bactérias usando o método do 
streak-plate.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa esercitazione in linea è messa a fuoco sui
batteri dell'acido lattico, un gruppo dei batteri relativi che 
producono l'acido lattico come conseguenza di fermentazione del 
carboidrato. Include un protocollo per l'arricchimento dei 
batteri dell'acido lattico dai campioni arricchiti (come yogurt, i 
crauti, la materia decadente della pianta e la piastra del dente). 
Tre parametri sono misurati: sviluppo, diversità della 
coltura e pH. L'esercitazione egualmente include le istruzioni 
per l'isolamento di alcuni di questi batteri usando il metodo del 
vetrino.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η σε απευθείας σύνδεση άσκηση στρέφεται στα 
βακτηρίδια γαλακτικού οξέος, μια ομάδα σχετικών βακτηριδίων που 
παράγουν το γαλακτικό οξύ ως αποτέλεσμα της ζύμωσης 
υδατανθράκων. Περιλαμβάνει ένα πρωτόκολλο για τον 
εμπλουτισμό των βακτηριδίων γαλακτικού οξέος από τα 
εμπλουτισμένα δείγματα (όπως το γιαούρτι, sauerkraut, το θέμα 
εγκαταστάσεων αποσύνθεσης, και την πινακίδα δοντιών). Τρεις 
παράμετροι μετριούνται: αύξηση, ποικιλομορφία πολιτισμού, 
και pH. Η άσκηση περιλαμβάνει επίσης τις οδηγίες για την 
απομόνωση μερικά από αυτά τα βακτηρίδια με τη χρησιμοποίηση της 
streak-plate μεθόδου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este ejercicio en línea se centra en las 
bacterias del ácido láctico, un grupo de las bacterias relacionadas 
que producen el ácido láctico como resultado de la fermentación del
carbohidrato. Incluye un protocolo para el enriquecimiento de 
las bacterias del ácido láctico de muestras enriquecidas (como el 
yogur, el sauerkraut, la materia de la planta que se decae, y la placa
del diente). Se miden tres parámetros: crecimiento, 
diversidad de la cultura, y pH. El ejercicio también incluye 
las instrucciones para el aislamiento de algunas de estas bacterias 
usando el método del streak-plate.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:LIVING IN THE MICROBIAL WORLD WORKSHOP
FN:LIVING IN THE MICROBIAL WORLD WORKSHOP
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MARINE BIOLOGICAL LABORATORY
FN:MARINE BIOLOGICAL LABORATORY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203614</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103445</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/lactic-acid-bacteria-1</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
