<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107347</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107347</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207086</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Human Genetic Variation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschliche Genetische Variante</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Variation Génétique Humaine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Variação Genetic Humana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Variazione Genetica Umana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρώπινη γενετική παραλλαγή</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Variación Genética Humana</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">offers activities exploring how genes and the environment influence human diversity, what role DNA sequences play in genetic differences, and more. Students are invited to assume the role of employees at a pharmaceutical company developing new drugs. A game helps show the links between genetic variation, environmental factors, and disease prevention. A family's case study on genetic variation testing exemplifies difficult moral and social questions for society.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">bietet die Aktivitäten an, die erforschen, wie 
Gene und die Umgebung menschliche Verschiedenartigkeit beeinflussen, 
welche Rolle DNA Spiel in den genetischen Unterschieden sequentiell 
ordnet und mehr. Kursteilnehmer werden eingeladen, die Rolle der
Angestellter bei einer pharmazeutischen Firma anzunehmen, die neue 
Drogen entwickelt. Ein Spiel hilft Erscheinen die Links zwischen
genetischer Variante, Klimafaktoren und Krankheitverhinderung. 
Fallstudie einer Familie auf der genetischen Varianteprüfung 
illustriert schwierige moralische und Sozialfragen für Gesellschaft.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">offre des activités explorant comment les gènes 
et l'environnement influencent la diversité humaine, quelle ADN de 
rôle ordonnance le jeu dans des différences génétiques, et plus. 
Des étudiants sont invités à assumer le rôle des employés 
à une compagnie pharmaceutique développant de nouvelles drogues. 
Un jeu aide l'exposition les liens entre la variation 
génétique, les facteurs environnementaux, et l'empêchement de la 
maladie. L'étude de cas d'une famille sur le test génétique 
de variation démontre des questions morales et sociales difficiles 
pour la société.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">oferece as atividades que exploram como os genes e
o ambiente influenciam a diversidade humana, que DNA do papel arranja 
em seqüência o jogo em diferenças genetic, e mais. Os 
estudantes são convidados supor o papel dos empregados em uma 
companhia pharmaceutical que desenvolve drogas novas. Um jogo 
ajuda à mostra as ligações entre a variação genetic, fatores 
ambientais, e prevenção da doença. O estudo de exemplo de uma
família em testar genetic da variação exemplifies perguntas morais 
e sociais difíceis para a sociedade.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">offre le attività che esplorano come i geni e 
l'ambiente influenzano la diversità umana, che DNA di ruolo ordina il
gioco in serie nelle differenze genetiche e più. Gli allievi 
sono invitati ad ammettere il ruolo degli impiegati ad una ditta 
farmaceutica che sviluppa le nuove droghe. Un gioco aiuta 
l'esposizione i collegamenti fra variazione genetica, i fattori 
ambientali e la prevenzione di malattia. L'inchiesta della 
famiglia sulla prova genetica di variazione spiega le domande morali e
sociali difficili per la società.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">προσφέρει τις δραστηριότητες που εξερευνούν πώς τα 
γονίδια και το περιβάλλον επηρεάζουν την ανθρώπινη ποικιλομορφία,
ποιες ακολουθίες DNA ρόλου παίζουν στις γενετικές διαφορές, 
και περισσότεροι. Οι σπουδαστές καλούνται για να υποθέσουν 
το ρόλο των υπαλλήλων σε μια φαρμακοβιομηχανία που αναπτύσσει τα 
νέα φάρμακα. Οι οδηγίες παιχνιδιών εμφανίζουν τις 
συνδέσεις μεταξύ της γενετικής παραλλαγής, των περιβαλλοντικών 
παραγόντων, και της πρόληψης ασθενειών. Η περιπτωσιολογική 
μελέτη μιας οικογένειας για τη γενετική δοκιμή παραλλαγής εξηγεί
τις δύσκολες ηθικές και κοινωνικές ερωτήσεις για την κοινωνία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece las actividades que exploran cómo los 
genes y el ambiente influencian diversidad humana, qué DNA del papel 
ordena el juego en diferencias genéticas, y más. Se invita a 
los estudiantes que asuman el papel de empleados en una compañía 
farmacéutica que desarrolla las drogas nuevas. Un juego ayuda a
la demostración las conexiones entre la variación genética, los 
factores ambientales, y la prevención de la enfermedad. El 
estudio de caso de una familia en la prueba genética de la variación
ejemplifica las preguntas morales y sociales difíciles para la 
sociedad.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207086</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107347</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/human-genetic-variation</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
