<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105995</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105995</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206346</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Remembering Jim Crow</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erinnern An Jim Krähe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Se rappeler La Corneille de Jim</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Recordando O Corvo De Jim</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ricordarsi Del Corvo Di Jim</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανάμνηση jim Crow</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Recordar El Cuervo De Jim</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Remembering Jim Crow is a companion to a radio documentary, and examines the system that, for much of the 20th century, barred many African Americans from their rights as U.S. citizens. Read personal histories of segregation. See a sampling of Jim Crow laws. Learn how African Americans fought economic hardships imposed by Jim Crow and how they built social institutions to combat segregation.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">An Jim Krähe sich zu erinnern ist ein Begleiter 
zu einem Radiodokumentarfilm und überprüft das System, das, für 
viel des 20. Jahrhunderts, viele afrikanische Amerikaner von ihren 
Rechten als VEREINIGTE STAATEN Bürger abhielt. Lesen Sie 
persönliche Geschichten der Abtrennung. Sehen Sie ein 
Musterstück der Jim Krähegesetze. Erlernen Sie, wie 
afrikanische Amerikaner die ökonomischen Härten kämpften, die von 
Jim Crow auferlegt wurden und wie sie Sozialanstalten aufbauten, um 
Abtrennung zu bekämpfen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Se rappeler la corneille de Jim est un compagnon 
à un documentaire par radio, et examine le système qui, pour une 
grande partie du 20ème siècle, a empêché beaucoup d'Américains 
africains de leurs droites comme citoyens des ETATS-UNIS. Lisez 
les histoires personnelles de la ségrégation. Voir le 
prélèvement des lois de corneille de Jim. Apprenez comment les
Américains africains ont combattu des difficultés économiques 
imposées par Jim Crow et comment ils ont établi les institutions 
sociales pour combattre la ségrégation.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Recordar o corvo de Jim é um companheiro a um 
documentary de rádio, e examina o sistema que, para muito do 20o 
século, barrou muitos americanos africanos de suas direitas como 
cidadãos de ESTADOS UNIDOS. Leia histories pessoais do 
segregation. Veja uma amostragem de leis do corvo de Jim. 
Aprenda como os americanos africanos lutaram os hardships 
econômicos impostos por Jim Corvo e como construíram instituições 
sociais para combater o segregation.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ricordarsi del corvo di Jim è un compagno ad un 
documentary radiofonico ed esamina il sistema che, per gran parte del 
ventesimo secolo, ha escluso molti Americani africani dai loro diritti
come cittadini degli STATI UNITI. Legga i dati storici personali
della segregazione. Veda un campione delle leggi del corvo di 
Jim. Impari come gli Americani africani hanno combattuto le 
difficoltà economiche imposte da Jim Crow e come hanno sviluppato le 
istituzioni sociali per combattere la segregazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ανάμνηση jim Crow είναι σύντροφος σε ένα ραδιο
ντοκιμαντέρ, και εξετάζει το σύστημα που, για ένα μεγάλο μέρος 
του 20ού αιώνα, έφραξε πολλούς αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς από τα 
δικαιώματά τους ως ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΥΣ πολίτες. Διαβάστε τις 
προσωπικές ιστορίες του διαχωρισμού. Δείτε μια 
δειγματοληψία jim Crow των νόμων. Μάθετε πώς 
αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί πάλεψαν τις οικονομικές δυσκολίες που 
επιβλήθηκαν από jim Crow και πώς έχτισαν τα κοινωνικά 
όργανα για να καταπολεμήσουν το διαχωρισμό.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Recordar el cuervo de Jim es un compañero a un 
documentary de radio, y examina el sistema que, para mucho del 
vigésimo siglo, barró a muchos americanos africanos de las sus 
derechas como ciudadanos de ESTADOS UNIDOS. Lea las historias 
personales de la segregación. Vea un muestreo de los leyes del 
cuervo de Jim. Aprenda cómo los americanos africanos lucharon 
las dificultades económicas impuestas por Jim Crow y cómo 
construyeron a instituciones sociales para combatir la segregación.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206346</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105995</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/remembering-jim-crow</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
