<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103672</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103672</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1570826106</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">AP US History</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">AP US Geschichte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Histoire de AP USA</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">History do Ap E. U.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Storia di Ap Stati Uniti</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ιστορία AP ΗΠΑ</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Historia del Ap LOS E.E.U.U.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This course is a survey of American History from the age of exploration and discovery to the present. Emphasis is placed on critical and evaluative thinking skills, essay writing, interpretation of original documents, and historiography. This History curriculum covers all of the material outlined by the College Board as necessary to prepare you to pass the AP U.S. History exam.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser Kurs ist eine Übersicht der amerikanischen
Geschichte vom Alter der Erforschung und der Entdeckung zum Geschenk. 
Nachdruck wird auf die kritischen und abschätzenden denkenden 
Fähigkeiten, Versuchschreiben, Deutung der Originalurkunden und 
Historiographie gelegt. Dieser Geschichte Lehrplan umfaßt die 
ganze Material, das durch das Hochschulgremium wie benötigt, Sie 
vorzubereiten, die AP VEREINIGTE STAATEN Geschichte Prüfung zu 
führen umrissen wird.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce cours est une étude de l'histoire américaine 
de l'âge de l'exploration et de la découverte au présent. 
L'accent est mis sur des qualifications de pensée critiques et 
évaluatives, l'écriture d'essai, la traduction des documents 
initiaux, et l'historiographie. Ce programme d'études 
d'histoire couvre tout le matériel tracé les grandes lignes par le 
conseil d'université selon les besoins pour vous préparer passer 
l'examen d'histoire de AP ETATS-UNIS.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este curso é um exame do history americano da 
idade da exploração e da descoberta ao presente. A ênfase é 
colocada em habilidades pensando críticas e evaluativas, em escrita 
do essay, em interpretação de originais originais, e em 
historiography. Este curriculum do history cobre todo o material
esboçado pela placa de faculdade como necessário prepará-lo para 
passar o exam do history do AP ESTADOS UNIDOS.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo corso è un'indagine di storia americana 
dall'età di esplorazione e della scoperta al presente. È messo
in evidenza le abilità pensanti critiche e valutative, la scrittura 
di saggio, l'interpretazione dei documenti originali e la 
storiografia. Questo programma di studi di storia tratta tutto 
il materiale descritto dal Bordo dell'università come 
necessario prepararli per passare il exam di storia di AP STATI UNITI.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η σειρά μαθημάτων είναι μια έρευνα για την 
αμερικανική ιστορία από την ηλικία της εξερεύνησης και της 
ανακάλυψης στο παρόν. Έμφαση δίνεται στις κρίσιμες και 
αξιολογικές δεξιότητες σκέψης, το δοκίμιο γράφοντας, την 
ερμηνεία των αρχικών εγγράφων, και την ιστοριογραφία. Αυτό 
το πρόγραμμα σπουδών ιστορίας καλύπτει όλο το υλικό που 
περιγράφεται από τον πίνακα κολλεγίου για να σας προετοιμάσει 
ανάλογα με τις ανάγκες για να περάσει το διαγωνισμό ιστορίας 
AP ΗΠΑ.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este curso es una encuesta de la historia 
americana de la edad de la exploración y del descubrimiento al 
presente. El énfasis se pone en habilidades de pensamiento 
críticas y evaluativas, la escritura del ensayo, la interpretación 
de documentos originales, y la historiografía. Este plan de 
estudios de la historia cubre todo el material contorneado por la 
tarjeta de universidad como necesaria para prepararle para aprobar el 
examen de la historia del AP ESTADOS UNIDOS.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:UNKNOWN
FN:UNKNOWN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1570826106</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103672</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/ap-us-history</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
