<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105791</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105791</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202780</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Interdisciplinary Integrated Unit on DNA/Genetics Part C: Language Arts</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Interdisziplinäre integrierte Maßeinheit auf 
DNA/Genetics Teil C: Sprachenkünste</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Unité intégrée interdisciplinaire sur la partie
C de DNA/Genetics : Arts de Langage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Unidade integrada interdisciplinary na parte C de 
DNA/Genetics: Artes Da Língua</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Unità integrata interdisciplinare sulla parte C 
Di DNA/Genetics: Arti Di Linguaggio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διεπιστημονική ενσωματωμένη μονάδα στο DNA/to μέρος
γ γενετικής: Γλωσσικές τέχνες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Unidad integrada interdisciplinaria en la parte C 
de DNA/Genetics: Artes Del Lenguaje</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This lesson is part of an interdisciplinary integrated unit on DNA and genetics. The idea is that students will complete a week's worth of activities in science, math, and language arts related to this topic. This lesson is Part C: Language Arts. Students will apply information retrieval skills as they investigate controversial issues on human genetic cloning. Students then will develop a point-of-view essay stating their personal opinion on whether human cloning should or should not be allowed.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Lektion ist ein Teil einer 
interdisziplinären integrierten Maßeinheit auf DNA und Genetik. 
Die Idee ist, daß Kursteilnehmer den Wert einer Woche von 
Aktivitäten in der Wissenschaft, in Mathe und in den 
Sprachenkünsten, die auf diesem Thema in Verbindung gestanden werden 
durchführen. Diese Lektion ist Teil C: Sprachenkünste. 
Kursteilnehmer wenden Information Retrieval Fähigkeiten an, wie
sie umstrittene Ausgaben auf menschlichem genetischem Klonen 
nachforschen. Kursteilnehmer dann entwickeln einen 
Punkt-von-Ansicht Versuch, der an ihre eigene Meinung angibt, ob 
menschliches Klonen nicht gewährt werden sollte oder sollte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette leçon fait partie d'une unité intégrée 
interdisciplinaire sur l'ADN et la génétique. L'idée est que 
les étudiants termineront la valeur d'une semaine des activités en 
science, maths, et arts de langage liés à ce sujet. Cette 
leçon est la partie C : Arts de Langage. Les étudiants 
appliqueront des qualifications de recherche documentaire comme ils 
étudient les issues controversées sur le clonage génétique humain.
Les étudiants alors développeront un essai de point-de-vue 
énonçant leur avis personnel en fonction si le clonage humain 
devrait ou ne devrait pas être laissé.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta lição é parte de uma unidade integrada 
interdisciplinary no DNA e no genetics. A idéia é que os 
estudantes terminarão o valor de uma semana das atividades na 
ciência, no math, e nas artes da língua relacionadas a este tópico.
Esta lição é a parte C: Artes Da Língua. Os 
estudantes aplicarão habilidades da recuperação de informação 
como investigam edições controversas no cloning genetic humano. 
Os estudantes então desenvolverão um essay da ponto-$$$-VISTA 
que indica sua opinião pessoal sobre se o cloning humano deve ou não
deve ser reservado.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa lezione fa parte di un'unità integrata 
interdisciplinare su DNA e sulla genetica. L'idea è che gli 
allievi completeranno il valore della settimana delle attività nella 
scienza, nel per la matematica e nelle arti di linguaggio relative a 
questo soggetto. Questa lezione è parte C: Arti Di 
Linguaggio. Gli allievi applicheranno le abilità di reperimento
delle informazioni come studiano le edizioni discutibili su clonazione
genetica umana. Gli allievi allora svilupperanno un saggio di 
punto-de-vista che dichiara il loro parere personale sopra se 
la clonazione umana dovrebbe o non dovrebbe concedersi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το μάθημα είναι μέρος μιας διεπιστημονικής 
ενσωματωμένης μονάδας στο DNA και τη γενετική. Η ιδέα 
είναι ότι οι σπουδαστές θα ολοκληρώσουν την αξία μιας εβδομάδας 
των δραστηριοτήτων στην επιστήμη, math, και των γλωσσικών 
τεχνών σχετικών με αυτό το θέμα. Αυτό το μάθημα είναι 
μέρος γ: Γλωσσικές τέχνες. Οι σπουδαστές θα 
εφαρμόσουν τις δεξιότητες ανάκτησης πληροφοριών δεδομένου ότι 
ερευνούν τα αμφισβητούμενα ζητήματα σε ανθρώπινη γενετική 
κλωνοποίηση. Οι σπουδαστές έπειτα θα αναπτύξουν ένα 
δοκίμιο άποψης δηλώνοντας την προσωπική άποψή τους σχετικά με 
εάν ανθρώπινη κλωνοποίηση πρέπει ή δεν πρέπει να έχουν την 
άδεια.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta lección es parte de una unidad integrada 
interdisciplinaria en la DNA y la genética. La idea es que los 
estudiantes terminarán el valor de una semana de actividades en 
ciencia, matemáticas, y artes del lenguaje relacionados con este 
asunto. Esta lección es la parte C: Artes Del Lenguaje. 
Los estudiantes aplicarán habilidades de la recuperación de 
datos como investigan ediciones polémicas en la reproducción 
genética humana. Los estudiantes entonces desarrollarán un 
ensayo de la punta-de-vista que indica su opinión personal encendido 
si la reproducción humana debe o no debe ser permitida.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JANE LENTZ
FN:JANE LENTZ
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JIMMY WHITE
FN:JIMMY WHITE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MARLENE SMITH
FN:MARLENE SMITH
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:TORI GOLDRICK
FN:TORI GOLDRICK
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202780</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105791</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/interdisciplinary-integrated-unit-on-dna-genetics-part-c-language-arts</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
