<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104499</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104499</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974097</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Millennium Report: Briefing Papers for Students</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Jahrtausend-Report: Anweisung Papiere 
für Kursteilnehmer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'État de Millénium : Papiers de briefing 
pour des étudiants</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Relatório Do Millennium: Papéis da 
instrução para estudantes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Rapporto Di Millennio: Carte da 
istruzione per gli allievi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η έκθεση χιλιετίας: Ενημερωτικά έγγραφα για τους
σπουδαστές</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Informe Del Milenio: Papeles del informe 
para los estudiantes</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The United Nations CyberSchoolBus is proud to present, especially for students, the Briefing papers from We the Peoples: the role of the United Nations in the 21st century. Based on the Secretary-General's Millennium Report, each Briefing paper is a dossier of information about a current world issue and the UN's involvement with it. There are nineteen issues, arranged in six sections: an overview, progress that's already been made, a specific focus, the next steps to be made, student activities and resources for each issue.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Nationen CyberSchoolBus sind stolz, besonders 
für Kursteilnehmer, die Anweisung Papiere von uns darzustellen die 
Völker: die Rolle der Nationen im 21. Jahrhundert. 
Gegründet auf Millennium Report des Generalsekretärs, ist 
jedes Anweisung Papier ein Dossier der Informationen über eine 
aktuelle Weltausgabe und der Miteinbeziehung des UNs mit ihm. Es
gibt neunzehn Ausgaben, geordnet in sechs Kapiteln: ein 
Überblick, Fortschritt, der bereits gebildet wird, ein spezifischer 
Fokus, die folgenden gebildet zu werden Jobsteps, 
Kursteilnehmeraktivitäten und Betriebsmittel für jede Ausgabe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Nations Unies CyberSchoolBus est fière de 
présenter, particulièrement pour les étudiants, les papiers de 
briefing de nous les peuples : le rôle des Nations Unies au 
21ème siècle. Basé Millennium Report du sécrétaire 
général, chaque papier de briefing est un dossier d'informations sur
une question actuelle du monde et de participation de l'un avec lui. 
Il y a dix-neuf issues, disposées dans six sections : une
vue d'ensemble, progrès qui déjà est fait, un foyer spécifique, 
les prochaines étapes à faire, activités d'étudiant et ressources 
pour chaque issue.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As nações unidas CyberSchoolBus são orgulhosas 
apresentar, especial para os estudantes, os papéis da instrução dos
nós os povos: o papel das nações unidas no século XXI. 
Baseado em Millennium Relatório do secretário geral, cada 
papel da instrução é um dossier da informação sobre uma edição 
atual do mundo e da participação do UN com ele. Há dezenove 
edições, arranjadas em seis seções: uma vista geral, 
progresso que é feito já, um foco específico, as etapas seguintes a
ser feitos, atividades do estudante e recursos para cada edição.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le Nazioni Unite CyberSchoolBus sono fiere 
presentare, particolarmente per gli allievi, i documenti di istruzione
dai noi la gente: il ruolo delle Nazioni Unite nel ventunesimo 
secolo. Sulla base del Millennium Report del segretario 
generale, ogni carta da istruzione è un dossier delle informazioni su
una questione attuale del mondo e della partecipazione di NU 
con esso. Ci sono diciannove edizioni, organizzate in sei 
sezioni: una descrizione, progresso che già è fatto, un fuoco 
specifico, i punti seguenti da fare, attività dell'allievo e 
risorse per ogni edizione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα Ηνωμένα Έθνη CyberSchoolBus είναι υπερήφανα για 
να παρουσιάσουν, ειδικά για τους σπουδαστές, τα ενημερωτικά 
έγγραφα από μας οι λαοί: ο ρόλος των Ηνωμένων Εθνών στο 
21$ο αιώνα. Με βάση την έκθεση χιλιετίας του Γενικού 
Γραμματέα, κάθε ενημερωτικό έγγραφο είναι ένας φάκελος των 
πληροφοριών για ένα παρόν παγκόσμιο ζήτημα και της συμμετοχής 
των Η.Ε με το. Υπάρχουν δεκαεννέα ζητήματα, που 
τακτοποιούνται σε έξι τμήματα: μια επισκόπηση, πρόοδος που 
ήδη γίνοντας, μια συγκεκριμένη εστίαση, τα επόμενα βήματα που 
γίνονται, δραστηριότητες σπουδαστών και στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς για
κάθε ζήτημα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los Naciones Unidas CyberSchoolBus son orgullosos 
presentar, especialmente para los estudiantes, los papeles del informe
de nosotros la gente: el papel de los Naciones Unidas en el 
siglo XXI. De acuerdo con Millennium Report del secretario 
general, cada papel del informe es un expediente de la información 
sobre una edición actual del mundo y de la implicación del UN con 
él. Hay diecinueve ediciones, dispuestas en seis secciones: 
una descripción, progreso que se hace ya, un foco específico, 
los pasos de progresión siguientes que se harán, actividades del 
estudiante y recursos para cada edición.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974097</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104499</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-millennium-report-briefing-papers-for-students</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
