<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107654</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107654</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202571</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Learn New Words Using Context.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erlernen Sie Neue Wörter Mit Kontext.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Apprenez Les Nouveaux Mots En utilisant Le 
Contexte.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Aprenda Palavras Novas Usando O Contexto.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Impari Le Nuove Parole Usando Il Contesto.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μάθετε τις νέες λέξεις χρησιμοποιώντας τα 
συμφραζόμενα.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Aprenda Las Nuevas Palabras Usando Contexto.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">With guided practice students will use context clues to determine meaning of unfamiliar words in short passages. When students have completed the practice activities, they will read a newspaper or magazine article, picking out unfamiliar words and using context clues to decide what the word means. As a group activity they will share the article, the words, and their meanings with the class.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mit geführter Praxis verwenden Kursteilnehmer 
Kontextanhaltspunkte, um Bedeutung der nicht vertrauten Wörter in den
kurzen Durchgängen festzustellen. Wenn Kursteilnehmer die 
Praxisaktivitäten durchgeführt haben, lesen sie einen Zeitung oder 
Zeitschrift Artikel, wählen nicht vertraute Wörter aus und verwenden
Kontextanhaltspunkte, um zu entscheiden, was das Wort bedeutet. 
Da eine Gruppe Aktivität sie den Artikel, die Wörter und ihre 
Bedeutungen mit der Kategorie teilt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Avec la pratique guidée les étudiants emploieront des 
indices de contexte pour déterminer la signification des mots peu 
familiers dans les passages courts. Quand les étudiants ont 
terminé les activités de pratique, ils liront un article de journal 
ou de magazine, sélectionnant des mots peu familiers et employant des
indices de contexte pour décider ce que signifie le mot. Car 
une activité de groupe ils partagera l'article, les mots, et leurs 
significations avec la classe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Com prática guiada os estudantes usarão indícios do 
contexto determinar o meaning de palavras estranhas em passagens 
curtas. Quando os estudantes terminaram as atividades da 
prática, lerão um artigo do jornal ou do compartimento, escolhendo 
para fora das palavras estranhas e usando indícios do contexto 
decidir-se o que a palavra significa. Porque uma atividade do 
grupo eles compartilhará do artigo, das palavras, e de seus meanings 
com a classe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Con pratica guidata gli allievi useranno gli indizii di 
contesto per determinare il significato delle parole non pratiche nei 
passaggi corti. Quando gli allievi hanno completato le attività
di pratica, leggeranno un articolo dello scomparto o del giornale, 
selezionante le parole non pratiche ed usando gli indizii di contesto 
per decidere che cosa la parola significa. Poichè un'attività 
del gruppo ripartirà l'articolo, le parole ed i loro significati con 
il codice categoria.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Με την καθοδηγημένη πρακτική οι σπουδαστές θα 
χρησιμοποιήσουν τις ενδείξεις συμφραζόμενων για να καθορίσουν την 
έννοια των άγνωστων λέξεων στις σύντομες μεταβάσεις. Όταν 
οι σπουδαστές ολοκληρώσουν τις δραστηριότητες πρακτικής, θα 
διαβάσουν ένα άρθρο εφημερίδων ή περιοδικών, που διαλέγει τις 
άγνωστες λέξεις και που χρησιμοποιεί τις ενδείξεις συμφραζόμενων 
για να αποφασίσουν τι η λέξη σημαίνει. Σαν δραστηριότητα 
ομάδας θα μοιραστούν το άρθρο, τις λέξεις, και τις έννοιές τους 
με την κλάση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Con práctica dirigida los estudiantes utilizarán pistas 
del contexto para determinar el significado de palabras desconocedoras
en pasos cortos. Cuando los estudiantes han terminado las 
actividades de la práctica, leerán un artículo del periódico o del
compartimiento, seleccionando palabras desconocedoras y usando pistas 
del contexto para decidir lo que significa la palabra. Pues una 
actividad del grupo ellos compartirá el artículo, las palabras, y 
sus significados con la clase.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:BETTY DELUCA
FN:BETTY DELUCA
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202571</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107654</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/learn-new-words-using-context</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
