<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104748</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104748</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087478</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Charlotte Perkins Gilman's "The Socialist and the Suffragist"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Charlotte Perkins Gilmans "der Sozialist und das 
Suffragist"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le socialiste de Charlotte Perkins Gilman "et la 
Suffragette"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O socialist de Charlotte Perkins Gilman "e o 
Suffragist"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il socialista de Charlotte Perkins Gilman "ed il 
Suffragist"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σαρλόττα σοσιαλιστής Perkins Gilman "ο και 
suffragist"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El socialista de Charlotte Perkins Gilman "y el 
Suffragist"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The  Appeal to Reason , the most popular radical publication in American history, was founded in 1895 by J. A. Wayland. The socialist newspaper reached a paid circulation of more than three-quarters of a million people by 1913, and during political campaigns and crises it often sold more than four million individual copies. Wayland, the paper's publisher until his suicide in 1912, had become a socialist through reading. He built his paper on the conviction that plain talk would convert others to the socialist cause. From its Kansas headquarters, the  Appeal  published an eclectic mix of news (particularly of strikes and political campaigns), essays, poetry, fiction, humor, and cartoons. During and after World War I the paper declined in circulation, and it ceased publication in November 1922. This poem by feminist Charlotte Perkins Gilman appeared in the September 28, 1912, issue.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Anklang an Grund, die populärste radikale 
Publikation in der amerikanischen Geschichte, wurde 1895 von J 
gegründet. A. Wayland. Die sozialistische Zeitung 
erreichte eine zahlende Zirkulation von mehr als Dreiviertel von 
Million Leuten bis zum 1913, und während der politischen Kampagnen 
und der Krisen verkaufte sie häufig mehr als vier Million einzelne 
Exemplare. Wayland, der Verleger des Papiers bis seinen 
Selbstmord 1912, hatte einem Sozialisten durch Messwert gestanden. 
Er baute sein Papier auf der Überzeugung auf, daß normales 
Gespräch andere in die sozialistische Ursache umwandeln würde. 
Von seinen Kansas Hauptsitzen veröffentlichte der Anklang 
eine eklektische Mischung der Nachrichten (besonders von Schlägen und
von politischen Kampagnen), der Versuche, der Poesie, der Erfindung, 
der Stimmung und der Karikaturen. Während und nach des Ersten 
Weltkrieges sank das Papier in der Zirkulation, und es hörte 
Publikation im November 1922 auf. Dieses Gedicht durch 
feministisches Charlotte Perkins Gilman erschien im September 28, 
1912, Ausgabe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'appel à la raison, la plus populaire publication
radicale dans l'histoire américaine, a été fondé en 1895 par J. 
A. Wayland. Le journal socialiste a atteint une 
circulation payée plus de de trois quarts de million de personnes 
d'ici 1913, et pendant des campagnes et des crises politiques il a 
souvent vendu plus de quatre millions de différentes copies. 
Wayland, l'éditeur du papier jusqu'à son suicide en 1912, 
était allé bien à un socialiste par la lecture. Il a 
construit son papier sur la conviction que l'entretien ordinaire 
convertirait d'autres en cause socialiste. De ses sièges 
sociaux du Kansas, l'appel a édité un mélange éclectique des 
nouvelles (en particulier des grèves et des campagnes politiques), 
des essais, de la poésie, de la fiction, de l'humeur, et des dessins 
animés. Pendant et après la Première Guerre Mondiale le 
papier a diminué dans la circulation, et il a cessé la publication 
en novembre 1922. Cette poésie par Charlotte féministe Perkins
Gilman est parue en 28 septembre 1912, issue.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A apelação à razão, a publicação radical a 
mais popular no history americano, foi fundada em 1895 por J. A.
Wayland. O jornal socialist alcançou uma circulação paga mais
de de três quartos de povos de milhão por 1913, e durante campanhas 
e crises políticas vendeu frequentemente mais de quatro milhão 
cópias individuais. Wayland, publisher do papel até seu 
suicide em 1912, tinha assentado bem em um socialist através da 
leitura. Construiu seu papel na convicção que a conversa lisa 
converteria outra à causa socialist. De suas matrizes de 
Kansas, a apelação publicou uma mistura eclectic da notícia 
(particularmente das batidas e de campanhas políticas), dos essays, 
da poesia, do fiction, do humor, e dos cartoons. Durante e após
o world.war.i o papel declinou na circulação, e cessou a 
publicação em novembro 1922. Este poema por Charlotte 
feminista Perkins Gilman publicou-se setembro no 28, 1912, edição.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'appello a motivo, la pubblicazione radicale più 
popolare nella storia americana, è stato fondato in 1895 da J. 
A. Wayland. Il giornale socialista ha raggiunto una 
circolazione paid più di di tre quarti di di milioni di persone entro
1913 e durante le campagne e le crisi politiche ha venduto spesso più
di quattro milione diverse copie. Wayland, l'editore della carta
fino al suo suicide in 1912, aveva stato bene ad un socialista 
attraverso lettura. Ha costruito la sua carta sulla convinzione 
che il colloquio normale convertirebbe altri in causa socialista. 
Dalle relative sedi del Kansas, l'appello ha pubblicato una 
miscela eclettica delle notizie (specialmente dei colpi e delle 
campagne politiche), dei saggi, della poesia, del romanzo, dell'umore 
e dei fumetti. Durante e dopo il world.war.i la carta ha 
declinato nella circolazione ed ha cessato la pubblicazione nel mese 
di novembre del 1922. Questo poem da Charlotte femminista 
Perkins Gilman è stato publicato in 28 settembre 1912, edizione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η έκκληση στο λόγο, η δημοφιλέστερη ριζική δημοσίευση
στην αμερικανική ιστορία, ιδρύθηκε το 1895 από το j. 
Α. Wayland. Η σοσιαλιστική εφημερίδα έφθασε σε μια 
πληρωμένη κυκλοφορία περισσότερο από των τριών τετάρτων 
εκατομμύριο ανθρώπων μέχρι το 1913, και κατά τη διάρκεια των 
πολιτικών εκστρατειών και των κρίσεων πώλησε συχνά περισσότερα 
από τέσσερα εκατομμύριο μεμονωμένα αντίγραφα. Το 
Wayland, ο εκδότης του εγγράφου μέχρι την αυτοκτονία του το 
1912, είχε γίνει σοσιαλιστής μέσω της ανάγνωσης. 
Στηρίχτηκε το έγγραφό του στην πεποίθηση ότι η σαφής 
συζήτηση θα μετέτρεπε άλλους στη σοσιαλιστική αιτία. Από 
την έδρα του Κάνσας της, η έκκληση δημοσίευσε ένα εκλεκτικό 
μίγμα των ειδήσεων (ιδιαίτερα των απεργιών και των πολιτικών 
εκστρατειών), των δοκίμιων, της ποίησης, της μυθιστοριογραφίας, 
του χιούμορ, και των κινούμενων σχεδίων. Κατά τη διάρκεια 
και μετά από του παγκόσμιου πολέμου Ι το έγγραφο μειώθηκε στην 
κυκλοφορία, και έπαψε τη δημοσίευση τον Νοέμβριο του 1922. 
Αυτό το ποίημα από το φεμινιστικό Σαρλόττα Perkins 
Gilman εμφανίστηκε τις 28 Σεπτεμβρίου ..1912, ζήτημα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La súplica a la razón, la publicación radical 
más popular de la historia americana, fue fundada en 1895 por J. 
A. Wayland. El periódico socialista alcanzó una 
circulación pagada de más de tres cuartos millones de personas antes
de 1913, y durante campañas y crisis políticas vendió a menudo más
de cuatro millones de copias individuales. Wayland, el editor 
del papel hasta su suicidio en 1912, había sentido bien a un 
socialista a través de la lectura. Él construyó su documento 
sobre la convicción que la charla llana convertiría otras a la causa
socialista. De sus jefaturas de Kansas, la súplica publicó una
mezcla ecléctica de las noticias (determinado de huelgas y de 
campañas políticas), de los ensayos, de la poesía, de la ficción, 
del humor, y de historietas. Durante y después de Primera 
Guerra Mundial el papel declinó en la circulación, y cesó la 
publicación en noviembre de 1922. Este poema por Charlotte 
feminista Perkins Gilman apareció en 28 de septiembre de 1912, 
edición.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087478</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104748</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/charlotte-perkins-gilmans-the-socialist-and-the-suffragist</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
