<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105946</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105946</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087156</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Union Men Competing Against Each Other: Anne and Al Filardo Describe the Construction Industry in New York City</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Anschluß-Männer, die Gegeneinander Konkurrieren:
Anne und Al Filardo beschreiben das Baugewerbe in New York City</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Hommes des Syndicats Concurrençant Les uns contre
les autres : Anne et Al Filardo décrivent l'industrie du 
bâtiment à New York City</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Homens Da União Que Competem Uns contra os 
outros: Anne e o al Filardo descrevem a indústria de 
construção em New York City</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Uomini Del Sindacato Che Competono Faccia a 
faccia: Anne ed Al Filardo descrivono l'industria edilizia a New
York City</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ατομα ένωσης που ανταγωνίζονται το ένα ενάντια στο 
άλλο: Η Anne και το Al Filardo περιγράφουν τον κλάδο
των οικοδομικών και τεχνικών έργων στην πόλη της Νέας Υόρκης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Hombres De la Unión Que compiten Cara a cara: 
Anne y el al Filardo describen la industria de construcción en 
New York City</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">House building came to a virtual standstill during the depression and war years, a lull that gave way to a massive construction boom that reached far into the postwar period. By that time, however, the nature of the construction industry was undergoing rapid changes. The introduction of new technologies and building materials meant that buildings could be built faster and cheaper. The benefits of this rise in productivity were shared unequally by bosses and workers. While workers saw a rise in wages, many homebuilders and contractors made fortunes in the millions. Al Filardo, a carpenter who worked in the construction industry in New York, remembered that workers still faced the uncertainty of not knowing when they would find or lose work, and opposition to construction unions.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bauunternehmen kam zu einem virtuellen Stillstand 
während des Tiefstands und der Kriegsjahre, eine Ruhepause, die zu 
einer massiven Aufbauhochkonjunktur nachgab, die weit in die 
Nachkriegszeit erreichte. Bis dahin jedoch machte die Natur des 
Baugewerbes schnelle Änderungen durch. Die Einleitung der neuen
Technologien und der Baumaterialien bedeutete, daß Gebäude 
aufgebautes schnelleres und preiswerter sein konnten. Der Nutzen
dieses Anstiegs in der Produktivität wurde ungleich von den Chefs und
von den Arbeitern geteilt. Während Arbeiter einen Anstieg in 
den Löhnen sahen, bildeten viele homebuilders und Fremdfirmen 
Vermögen in den Millionen. Al Filardo, ein Tischler, die im 
Baugewerbe in New York arbeiteten, daß Arbeiter die noch Ungewißheit
des Wissens, als nicht gegenüberstellten sie Arbeit finden oder 
verlieren würden und Opposition zu den Aufbauanschlüßen daran 
erinnert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le bâtiment de Chambre est venu à un arrêt 
virtuel pendant la dépression et les années de guerre, une accalmie 
qui a mené à une perche massive de construction qui a atteint loin 
dans l'après-guerre. À ce moment-là, cependant, la nature de 
l'industrie du bâtiment subissait les changements rapides. 
L'introduction de nouvelles technologies et de matériaux de 
construction a signifié que les bâtiments pourraient être plus 
rapides et meilleur marché construits. Les avantages de cette 
élévation de la productivité ont été partagés de façon inégale
par des patrons et des ouvriers. Tandis que les ouvriers 
voyaient une élévation des salaires, beaucoup de homebuilders et 
entrepreneurs ont fait des fortunes dans les millions. Al 
Filardo, un charpentier qui ont fonctionné dans l'industrie du 
bâtiment à New York, retrouvé que les ouvriers faisaient face 
toujours à l'incertitude de ne pas savoir quand ils trouveraient ou 
détruiraient le travail, et opposition aux syndicats de construction.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O edifício de casa veio a uma paralisação 
virtual durante os anos do depression e de guerra, um lull que desse a
maneira a um crescimento maciço da construção que alcançasse 
distante no período postwar. Por esse tempo, entretanto, a 
natureza da indústria de construção submetia-se a mudanças 
rápidas. A introdução de tecnologias novas e de materiais de 
edifício significou que os edifícios poderiam ser mais rápidos e 
mais baratos construídos. Os benefícios desta ascensão na 
produtividade foram compartilhados desigual por saliências e por 
trabalhadores. Quando os trabalhadores viram uma ascensão nos 
salários, muitos homebuilders e contratantes fizeram fortunas nos 
milhões. Al Filardo, um carpinteiro que trabalharam na 
indústria de construção em New York, recordado que os trabalhadores
enfrentaram ainda a incerteza de não saber quando encontrariam ou 
perderiam o trabalho, e oposição às uniões da construção.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La costruzione della Camera è venuto ad una 
fermata virtuale durante la depressione e gli anni di guerra, un lull 
che ha condotto ad un'asta voluminosa della costruzione che ha 
raggiunto lontano nel periodo. A quel punto, tuttavia, la natura
dell'industria edilizia stava subendo i cambiamenti veloci. 
L'introduzione di nuove tecnologie e di materiali da costruzione
ha significato che le costruzioni potrebbero essere più veloce e più
poco costoso costruiti. I benefici di questo aumento nel 
rendimento sono stati ripartiti diversamente dalle sporgenze e dagli 
operai. Mentre gli operai hanno visto un aumento negli stipendi,
molti homebuilders ed appaltatori hanno fatto le fortune in milioni. 
Al Filardo, un carpentiere che hanno lavorato nell'industria 
edilizia a New York, ricordato di che gli operai ancora hanno 
affrontato l'incertezza di non sapere quando troverebbero o 
perderebbero il lavoro ed opposizione ai sindacati della costruzione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η οικοδόμηση ήρθε σε ένα εικονικό σταμάτημα κατά τη 
διάρκεια των ετών κατάθλιψης και πολέμου, μια νηνεμία που έδωσε 
τόπο σε έναν ογκώδη βραχίονα οικοδόμησης που έφθασε μακριά στη 
μεταπολεμική περίοδο. Έως τότε, εντούτοις, η φύση του 
κλάδου των οικοδομικών και τεχνικών έργων υποβαλλόταν στις 
γρήγορες αλλαγές. Η εισαγωγή των νέων οικοδομικών υλικών 
τεχνολογιών και σήμανε ότι τα κτήρια θα μπορούσαν να είναι 
χτισμένα γρηγορότερα και φτηνότερα. Τα οφέλη αυτής της 
ανόδου στην παραγωγικότητα μοιράστηκαν ανομοιόμορφα από τους 
προϊσταμένους και τους εργαζομένους. Ενώ οι εργαζόμενοι 
εβλέίδαν μια άνοδο στις αμοιβές, πολλοί homebuilders και
ανάδοχοι έκαναν τις τύχες στα εκατομμύρια. Το Al 
Filardo, ένας ξυλουργός που εργάστηκε στον κλάδο των 
οικοδομικών και τεχνικών έργων στη νέα Υόρκη, θυμήθηκε ότι οι 
εργαζόμενοι αντιμετώπισαν ακόμα την αβεβαιότητα της μη γνώσης 
όταν θα έβρισκαν ή θα έχαναν την εργασία, και την αντίθεση στις 
ενώσεις κατασκευής.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El edificio de casa vino a una parada virtual 
durante los años de la depresión y de guerra, una calma que llevó a
un auge masivo de la construcción que alcanzó lejos en la posguerra.
Para ese punto, sin embargo, la naturaleza de la industria de 
construcción experimentaba cambios rápidos. La introducción 
de nuevas tecnologías y de materiales de construcción significó que
los edificios podrían ser más rápidos y más baratos construida. 
Las ventajas de esta subida de la productividad fueron 
compartidas desigual por los jefes y los trabajadores. Mientras 
que los trabajadores vieron una subida de salarios, muchos 
homebuilders y contratistas hicieron fortunas en millones. Al 
Filardo, un carpintero que trabajaron en la industria de construcción
en Nueva York, recordado que los trabajadores todavía hicieron frente
a la incertidumbre de no saber cuándo encontrarían o perderían el 
trabajo, y oposición a las uniones de la construcción.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087156</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105946</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/union-men-competing-against-each-other-anne-and-al-filardo-describe-the-construction-industry-in-new-york-city</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
