<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104319</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104319</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212602</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Harmful Algae Page</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Schädliche Algen Seite</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Page Nocive d'Algues</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A Página Prejudicial Das Algas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Pagina Nociva Delle Alghe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η επιβλαβής σελίδα αλγών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Paginación Dañosa De las Algas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This NOAA sponsored website offers a collection of hyperlinks to red tide related articles, distribution maps, photographs, news, and meetings. Links include basic information about red tide, how red tide affects humans and ecosystems, the latest news about red tide and other harmful algal blooms (HABs), and information about red tide-based meetings and conferences.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese NOAA geförderte Web site bietet eine 
Ansammlung Hypertext-Links rote Gezeiten in Verbindung 
gestandenen Artikeln, Verteilung Karten, Fotographien, Nachrichten und
Sitzungen an. Links schließen grundlegende Informationen über 
rote Gezeiten ein, wie rote Gezeiten Menschen und 
Oekosysteme, die neuesten Nachrichten über rote Gezeiten und 
andere schädliche Algenblüte (HABs) beeinflussen, und Informationen 
über rote Gezeiten-based Sitzungen und Konferenzen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site Web commandité par NOAA offre une 
collection d'hyperliens aux articles, aux cartes de distribution, aux 
photographies, aux nouvelles, et aux réunions associés par marée 
rouge. Les liens incluent des informations de base sur la marée
rouge, comment la marée rouge affecte des humains et des 
écosystèmes, les dernières nouvelles au sujet de la marée rouge et
d'autres fleurs d'algues nocives (HABs), et des informations sur des 
réunions et des conférences marée-basées rouges.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Web site patrocinado NOAA oferece uma 
coleção dos hyperlinks maré vermelha aos artigos, aos mapas da 
distribuição, às fotografias, às notícias, e às reuniões 
relacionados. As ligações incluem a informação básica sobre
a maré vermelha, como a maré vermelha afeta seres humanos e 
ecosystems, a notícia a mais atrasada sobre a maré vermelha e outras
flores algal prejudiciais (HABs), e a informação sobre reuniões e 
conferências maré-baseadas vermelhas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Web site patrocinato NOAA offre una 
collezione di hyperlinks agli articoli, ai programmi di distribuzione,
alle fotografie, alle notizie ed alle riunioni riferiti marea rossa. 
I collegamenti includono le informazioni di base sulla marea 
rossa, come la marea rossa interessa gli esseri umani ed ecosistemi, 
le ultime notizie circa la marea rossa ed altre fioriture d'alghe 
nocive (HABs) e le informazioni sulle riunioni e sui congressi 
marea-basati rossi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το NOAA υποστήριξε τον ιστοχώρο προσφέρει μια 
συλλογή των συνδέσμων υπερ-κειμένου στα κόκκινα σχετικά με την 
παλίρροια άρθρα, τους χάρτες διανομής, τις φωτογραφίες, τις 
ειδήσεις, και στις συνεδριάσεις. Οι συνδέσεις περιλαμβάνουν 
τις βασικές πληροφορίες για την κόκκινη παλίρροια, πώς η κόκκινη
παλίρροια έχει επιπτώσεις στους ανθρώπους και τα οικοσυστήματα, 
τις πιό πρόσφατες ειδήσεις για την κόκκινη παλίρροια και άλλες 
επιβλαβείς φυκώδεις ανθίσεις (HABs), και τις πληροφορίες για 
τις κόκκινες παλίρροια-βασισμένες συνεδριάσεις και τις 
διασκέψεις.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este Web site patrocinado NOAA ofrece una 
colección de hyperlinks a los artículos, a las correspondencias de 
la distribución, a las fotografías, a las noticias, y a las 
reuniones relacionados marea roja. Las conexiones incluyen la 
información básica sobre marea roja, cómo la marea roja afecta a 
seres humanos y los ecosistemas, las noticias más últimas sobre 
marea roja y otras floraciones algal dañosas (HABs), y la 
información sobre reuniones y conferencias marea-basadas rojas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:DR. DONALD M. ANDERSON
FN:DR. DONALD M. ANDERSON
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:WOODS HOLE OCEANOGRAPHIC INSTITUTION; NATIONAL SCIENCE FOUNDATION; NATIONAL OCEANOGRAPHIC AND ATMOSPHERIC ADMINISTRATION
FN:WOODS HOLE OCEANOGRAPHIC INSTITUTION; NATIONAL SCIENCE FOUNDATION; NATIONAL OCEANOGRAPHIC AND ATMOSPHERIC ADMINISTRATION
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212602</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104319</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-harmful-algae-page</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
