<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107345</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107345</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087388</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">An Early Sociologist Surveys the Fraternal Orders</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein früher Soziologe überblickt die 
brüderlichen Ordnungen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un premier sociologue examine les commandes 
fraternelles</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um sociologist adiantado examina as ordens 
fraternal</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un sociologist in anticipo esamina gli ordini 
fraterni</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένας πρώτος κοινωνιολόγος ερευνά τις αδελφικές 
κατατάξεις</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un sociólogo temprano examina las órdenes 
fraternales</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries fraternal organizations were ubiquitous. Their structure and rituals influenced a wide range of other groups, from the Knights of Labor to the Grange, from the American Protective Association to the Ku Klux Klan. In the last two decades of the 19th century, Americans created almost 500 national beneficiary orders and thousands of local lodges. The enormous membership of fraternal organizations attracted the attention of early sociologists. In this excerpt from an article published in the March 1901 issue of the  American Journal of Sociology , B. H. Meyer surveyed "Fraternal Beneficiary Societies in the United States." Although fraternal organizations like the Masons sometimes crossed class, ethnic, and religious (but almost never racial) lines, they more often reinforced those divisions. African Americans, immigrants, and the working class thus created their own complex of social and fraternal orders.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In der späten 19. und früh waren brüderliche 
Organisationen der zwanzigsten Jahrhunderte überall vorhanden. 
Ihre Struktur und Rituale beeinflußten eine breite Strecke 
anderer Gruppen, von den Rittern der Arbeit zum Gutshof, von der 
amerikanischen schützenden Verbindung zum Ku Klux Klan. In den 
letzten zwei Dekaden des 19. Jahrhunderts, stellten Amerikaner fast 
500 nationale Begünstigtordnungen und Tausenden der lokalen Hütten 
her. Die enorme Mitgliedschaft der brüderlichen Organisationen 
erregte die Aufmerksamkeit der frühen Soziologen. In diesem
Excerpt von einem Artikel veröffentlichte in der März 1901 Ausgabe 
des amerikanischen Journals der Soziologie, B. H. Meyer überblickte 
"brüderliche Begünstigt-Gesellschaften in den Vereinigten Staaten." 
Obgleich brüderliche Organisationen wie die Maurer manchmal die
Kategorie kreuzten, ethnisch und die frommen (aber fast nie 
rassischen) Zeilen, verstärkten sie häufig jene Abteilungen. 
Afrikanische Amerikaner, Immigranten und die Funktion Kategorie 
erstellten folglich ihren eigenen Komplex der Sozial- und 
brüderlichen Ordnungen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Vers la fin du dix-neuvième et tôt les 
organismes fraternels des vingtième siècles étaient omniprésents. 
Leur structure et rituels ont influencé un éventail d'autres 
groupes, des chevaliers du travail à la grange, de l'association 
protectrice américaine au Ku Klux Klan. Dans les deux 
dernières décennies du 19ème siècle, les Américains ont créé 
presque 500 commandes de bénéficiaire et milliers nationaux de loges
locales. L'énorme adhésion des organismes fraternels a attiré
l'attention de premiers sociologues. Dans cet extrait d'un 
article a édité dans l'édition de mars 1901 du journal américain 
de la sociologie, sociétés fraternelles de bénéficiaire examinées
par Meyer de B. H. "aux Etats-Unis." Bien que les organismes 
fraternels comme les maçons n'aient parfois croisé la classe, 
ethnique, et les lignes religieuses (mais presque jamais raciales), 
ils plus souvent ont renforcé ces divisions. Les Américains 
africains, les immigrés, et la classe ouvrière ont ainsi créé leur
propre complexe des commandes sociales et fraternelles.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No décimas nonas atrasado e cedo as 
organizações fraternal dos vigésimos séculos eram ubiquitous. 
Seus estrutura e rituals influenciaram uma escala larga de 
outros grupos, dos knights do trabalho ao grange, da associação 
protetora americana ao Ku Klux Klan. Nas últimas duas décadas 
do 1ø século, os americanos criaram quase 500 ordens do 
beneficiário e milhares nacionais de alojamentos locais. A 
sociedade enorme de organizações fraternal atraiu a atenção de 
sociologists adiantados. Neste excerpt de um artigo publicou na 
introdução de março 1901 do jornal americano do sociology, 
sociedades fraternal examinadas Meyer do beneficiário de B. H. "nos 
estados unidos." Embora as organizações fraternal como os 
masons cruzassem às vezes a classe, étnica, e linhas religiosas (mas
quase nunca raciais), reforçaram mais frequentemente aquelas 
divisões. Os americanos africanos, os immigrants, e a classe de
funcionamento criaram assim seu próprio complexo de ordens sociais e 
fraternal.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Verso la fine del diciannovesime e presto le 
organizzazioni fraterne di ventesimi secoli erano ubiquiste. La 
loro struttura e rituali hanno influenzato una vasta gamma di altri 
gruppi, dai cavalieri del Lavoro al grange, dall'associazione 
protettiva americana al Ku Klux Klan. Nelle ultime due decadi 
del diciannovesimo secolo, gli Americani hanno creato quasi 500 ordini
del beneficiario e migliaia nazionali delle casette locali. 
L'insieme dei membri enorme delle organizzazioni fraterne ha 
attratto l'attenzione dei sociologists in anticipo. In questo 
brano da un articolo ha pubblicato nell'edizione di marzo 1901 del 
giornale americano della sociologia, beneficiario che fraterno 
esaminato Meyer del B. H. "le società in unito Dichiara." 
Anche se le organizzazioni fraterne come i masons a volte hanno 
attraversato il codice categoria, etnico e le righe religiose (ma 
quasi mai razziali), hanno rinforzato più spesso quelle divisioni. 
Gli Americani africani, gli immigranti ed il codice categoria di
funzionamento hanno creato così il loro proprio complesso degli 
ordini sociali e fraterni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Προς το τέλος του δέκατου έννατου και εικοστοί νωρίς 
αιώνες οι αδελφικές οργανώσεις ήταν πανταχού παρούσες. Η 
δομή και τα τελετουργικά τους επηρέασαν ένα ευρύ φάσμα άλλων 
ομάδων, από τους ιππότες της εργασίας στο Grange, από την 
αμερικανική προστατευτική ένωση στο Ku Klux Klan. 
Στις τελευταίες δύο δεκαετίες του 19$ου αιώνα, Αμερικανοί 
δημιούργησαν σχεδόν 500 εθνικές δικαιούχες κατατάξεις και 
χιλιάδες τοπικά οικήματα. Η τεράστια ιδιότητα μέλους των 
αδελφικών οργανώσεων προσέλκυσε την προσοχή των πρώτων 
κοινωνιολόγων. Σε αυτό το απόσπασμα από ένα άρθρο που 
δημοσιεύθηκε στο ζήτημα Μαρτίου 1901 του αμερικανικού 
περιοδικού της κοινωνιολογίας, Β. Χ. Meyer ερεύνησε "αδελφικές 
δικαιούχες κοινωνία στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες." Αν και οι 
αδελφικές οργανώσεις όπως τους κτίστες διέσχισαν μερικές φορές 
τις εθνικών, και θρησκευτικών (αλλά σχεδόν ποτέ φυλετικών) 
γραμμές κλάσης, ενίσχυσαν συχνότερα εκείνα τα τμήματα. 
Αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί, οι μετανάστες, και η εργατική τάξη 
δημιούργησαν έτσι το συγκρότημα κοινωνικών και αδελφικών τάξεών
τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En las último diecinueveavo y las organizaciones 
fraternales de los vigésimos siglos eran temprano ubicuas. Su 
estructura y rituales influenciaron una amplia gama de otros grupos, 
de los caballeros del trabajo al grange, de la asociación protectora 
americana al Ku Klux Klan. En las dos décadas pasadas del 
diecinueveavo siglo, los americanos crearon casi 500 pedidos del 
beneficiario y millares nacionales de casas de campo locales. La
calidad de miembro enorme de organizaciones fraternales atrajo la 
atención de sociólogos tempranos. En este extracto de un 
artículo publicó en la aplicación de marcha 1901 el diario 
americano de la sociología, sociedades fraternales examinadas Meyer 
del beneficiario de B. H. "en los Estados Unidos." Aunque las 
organizaciones fraternales como los masones cruzaron a veces la clase,
étnica, y líneas religiosas (pero casi nunca raciales), reforzaron 
más a menudo esas divisiones. Los americanos africanos, los 
inmigrantes, y la clase obrera crearon así su propio complejo de 
órdenes sociales y fraternales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087388</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107345</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/an-early-sociologist-surveys-the-fraternal-orders</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
