<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106628</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106628</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086360</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Jacob Riis Tours NewYork City's Fourth Ward</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Jacob Riis Bereist Vierten Bezirk Der NewYork 
Stadt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jacob Riis Voyage Salle de la Ville de NewYork La 
Quatrième</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jacob Riis Excursiona Divisão Da Cidade De 
NewYork A Quarta</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Jacob Riis Fa un giro Del Quartiere Di 
Quarto Della Città Di NewYork</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέταρτος θάλαμος της πόλης γύρων NewYork Riis 
Jacob</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Jacob Riis Viaja Sala De la Ciudad De NewYork La 
Cuarta</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Jacob Riis--a journalist and photographer of industrial America and himself a Danish immigrant--exposed the deplorable conditions of late nineteenth-century urban life in his widely-read book,  How the Other Half Lives , published in 1890. He also presented slide shows to reform-minded, middle-class audiences. Despite his own immigrant background, Riis' attitudes mirrored the prejudices of the dominant culture toward "foreigners," as revealed in this stereotyped description of an immigrant neighborhood on New York's Lower East Side. Riis' reports on immigrant life--and his equally famous photographs--were important documents of urban conditions in late nineteenth-century urban America. But they were equally revealing as documents that showed how outsiders often reacted in horror to the lives of "the other half."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Jacob Riis -- ein Journalist und ein Photograph 
von industriellem Amerika und von selbst ein dänischer Immigrant -- 
stellte die bedauernswerten Zustände des späten 19.-Jahrhunderts, das 
städtische Lebensdauer in seiner das Buch breit-las, wie die andere 
Hälfte lebt heraus, veröffentlicht 1890. Er stellte auch 
Diavorführungen verbessern-gekümmert, Mittelklassepublikum dar. 
Trotz seines eigenen einwandernden Hintergrundes spiegelte 
Haltung Riis' die Vorurteile der dominierenden Kultur in Richtung "zu 
den Ausländern wider,", wie in dieser stereotyped Beschreibung einer 
einwandernden Nachbarschaft auf New York Ostseite niedriger 
aufgedeckt. Berichte Riis' über einwandernde Lebensdauer -- und
seine gleichmäßig berühmte Fotographien -- waren wichtige Dokumente
der städtischen Bedingungen im späten 19.-Jahrhundert städtisches 
Amerika. Aber sie deckten gleichmäßig als Dokumente auf, die 
zeigten, wie Außenseiter reagierten häufig in der Grausigkeit zu den
Lebensdauern "der anderen Hälfte."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jacob Riis -- un journaliste et un photographe de 
l'Amérique industrielle et de lui-même un immigré danois -- a 
exposé les conditions déplorables du dix-neuvième-siècle en retard
la vie où urbaine dans le sien large-a lu le livre, comment l'autre 
moitié vit, édité en 1890. Il a également présenté des 
projections de diapositives à reformer-occupé, des assistances de 
classe moyen. En dépit de son propre fond immigré, les 
attitudes de Riis ont reflété les préjudices de la culture 
dominante vers des "Étrangers," comme indiqué dans cette description
stéréotypée d'un voisinage immigré du côté est de New York plus 
bas. Les états de Riis la vie immigrée photographies -- et ses
également célèbres -- étaient les documents importants des 
conditions urbaines en dix-neuvième-siècle en retard Amérique 
urbaine. Mais ils indiquaient également comme documents qui ont
montré comment les étrangers ont souvent réagi dans l'horreur aux 
vies "de l'autre moitié."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jacob Riis -- um journalist e um fotógrafo de 
América industrial e de ele mesmo um immigrant dinamarquês -- expôs
as condições deplorable do décimo-século onde atrasado a vida 
urbana em his largo-leu o livro, como a outra metade vive, publicado 
em 1890. Apresentou também mostras de corrediça ao 
reform-ocupado, audiências do middle-class. Apesar de seu 
próprio fundo immigrant, as atitudes de Riis' espelharam os 
preconceitos da cultura dominante para "estrangeiros," como revelado 
nesta descrição stereotyped de uma vizinhança immigrant no lado do 
leste de New York mais baixo. Os relatórios de Riis' na vida 
immigrant -- e suas fotografias ingualmente famosas -- eram originais 
importantes de condições urbanas no décimo-século atrasado 
América urbana. Mas estavam revelando ingualmente como os 
originais que mostraram como os outsiders reagiram frequentemente no 
horror às vidas "da outra metade."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Jacob Riis -- un giornalista e un photographer 
dell'America industriale e di egli stesso un immigrante danese -- ha 
esposto gli stati deplorable del diciannovesimo-secolo che tardo la 
vita urbana in sua largo-ha letto il libro, come l'altra metà vive, 
pubblicato in 1890. Egualmente ha presentato le proiezioni di 
diapositive all'riform-occupato a, pubblici della classe media. 
Malgrado la sua propria priorità bassa immigrata, gli 
atteggiamenti del Riis hanno rispecchiato i pregiudizi della coltura 
dominante verso "gli stranieri," come rivelatore in questa descrizione
stereotipata di una vicinanza immigrata dal lato orientale de New York
più basso. Le relazioni del Riis su vita immigrata -- e sue le 
fotografie ugualmente famose -- erano documenti importanti dei termini
urbani nel diciannovesimo-secolo tardo America urbana. Ma 
stavano rivelando ugualmente come documenti che hanno mostrato come 
gli stranieri hanno reagito spesso nell'orrore alle durate "dell'altra
metà."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Jacob Riis -- ένας δημοσιογράφος και ένας 
φωτογράφος της βιομηχανικής Αμερικής και ο ίδιος ένας δανικός 
μετανάστης -- εξέθεσε τους λυπηρούς όρους της πρόσφατης αστικής 
ζωής δέκατος-αιώνα στο διαβασμένο βιβλίο του, πώς οι ζωές 
άλλου μισού, που δημοσιεύθηκαν το 1890. Παρουσίασε 
επίσης τις επιδείξεις φωτογραφικών διαφανειών 
μεταρρύθμιση-απασχολημένος, ακροατήρια μεσαίων τάξεων. 
Παρά το που έχουν μεταναστεύσει υπόβαθρό του, οι 
τοποθετήσεις Riis αντανάκλασαν τις προκαταλήψεις του κυρίαρχου 
πολιτισμού προς "τους αλλοδαπούς," όπως αποκαλύπτονται σε αυτήν 
την στερεοτυπημένη περιγραφή μιας που έχουν μεταναστεύσει 
γειτονιάς από την ανατολική πλευρά της Νέας Υόρκης χαμηλότερα. 
Οι εκθέσεις των Riis σχετικά με την που έχουν 
μεταναστεύσει ζωή -- και εξίσου διάσημες φωτογραφίες του -- ήταν
σημαντικά έγγραφα των αστικών όρων στον πρόσφατο δέκατος-αιώνα 
αστική Αμερική. Αλλά ήταν εξίσου αποκαλύπτοντας ως 
έγγραφα που επέδειξαν πώς οι ξένοι αντέδρασαν συχνά στη φρίκη 
στις ζωές "του άλλου μισού."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Jacob Riis -- un periodista y un fotógrafo de 
América industrial y sí mismo un inmigrante danés -- expuso las 
condiciones deplorables del último diecinueveavo-siglo que la vida 
urbana en la suya ancho-leyo' el libro, cómo vive la otra mitad, 
publicado en 1890. Él también presentó demostraciones de 
diapositiva a reformar-importado, las audiencias de la clase media. 
A pesar de su propio fondo inmigrante, las actitudes de Riis 
reflejaron los prejudicar de la cultura dominante hacia "extranjeros,"
según lo revelado en esta descripción estereotipada de una vecindad 
inmigrante en la cara del este de Nueva York más bajo. Los 
informes de Riis sobre vida inmigrante -- y sus igualmente famosas las
fotografías -- eran documentos importantes de condiciones urbanas en 
el último diecinueveavo-siglo América urbana. Pero revelaban 
igualmente como documentos que mostraron cómo los forasteros 
reaccionaron a menudo en horror a las vidas "de la otra mitad."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086360</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106628</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/jacob-riis-tours-newyork-citys-fourth-ward</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
