<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108596</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108596</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086285</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Have a Thirst that Could Sink a Ship!": Early Vaudeville</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ich habe einen Durst, der ein Schiff sinken 
könnte!": Frühes Vaudeville</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"j'ai une soif qui pourrait descendre un bateau!" 
: Vaudeville Tôt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"eu tenho um thirst que poderia afundar um 
navio!": Vaudeville Adiantado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"ho una sete che potrebbe affondare una nave!": 
Vaudeville Iniziale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"έχω μια δίψα που θα μπορούσε να βυθίσει ένα 
σκάφος!": Πρόωρη επιθεώρηση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"tengo una sed que podría hundir una nave!": 
Vaudeville Temprano</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Immigrants and African Americans decisively shaped a multiethnic urban popular culture in the late 19th century, built in large measure on the emergence of vaudeville. Vaudeville blended slapstick comedy, blackface minstrelsy, and sentimental songs into a rich and highly popular cultural stew. Among the most successful vaudeville practitioners were two Jewish singers and comics from the mean streets of Manhattan's Lower East Side, Joe Weber and Lew Fields. Weber and Fields' routines usually featured broad stereotypes of German immigrants: Fields played "Meyer," the shrewd German slickster who wanted to "put one over" on Weber's "Mike," the dumb "Dutch" newcomer. At the peak of their popularity in 1904, Weber and Fields recorded this popular routine, "The Drinking Scene," for commercial sale. Ironically, just a few months after recording this routine, the Weber and Fields team broke up, ending nearly three decades of public performances, the longest of any team in American popular theater.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Immigranten und afrikanische Amerikaner formten 
entscheidend eine multiethnische städtische populäre Kultur im des 
späten 19. jahrhunderts Jahrhundert, in großem Umfang aufgebaut auf 
dem Hervortreten von vaudeville. Vaudeville mischte slapstick 
Komödie, blackface Minstrelsy und sentimental Liede in Rich und in 
hohem Grade populäres kulturelles Eintopfgericht. Unter 
erfolgreichstem vaudeville waren die Praktiker zwei jüdische Sänger 
und Comics von den Mittelstraßen Manhattans von niedrigerer Ostseite,
von Joe Weber und von Lew Fängt auf. Weber und 
Fängt ' Programme kennzeichnete normalerweise ausgedehnte 
Stereotypen der deutschen Immigranten auf: Fängt 
gespielten "Meyer," das raffinierte deutsche slickster auf, das 
"setzen einen Überschuß" auf Webers "Mike," der stumme 
"holländische" Neuling wünschte. An der Spitze ihrer 
Popularität 1904, Fängt Weber und speicherte dieses 
populäre Programm, "die trinkende Szene," für kommerziellen Verkauf 
auf. Ironisch gerade einige Monate, nachdem er dieses Programm 
gespeichert hat, Fängt das Weber und Team brach oben auf und
beendet fast drei Dekaden der allgemeinen Leistungen, das längste 
jedes möglichen Teams im amerikanischen populären Theater.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les immigrés et les Américains africains ont 
décisivement formé une culture populaire urbaine multi-ethnique vers
la fin du 19ème siècle, établi dans une large mesure sur 
l'apparition du vaudeville. Vaudeville a mélangé le comédie 
de slapstick, le minstrelsy de blackface, et les chansons sentimentales
dans les riches et le ragoût culturel fortement populaire. 
Parmi le vaudeville le plus réussi les praticiens étaient deux
chanteurs et bandes dessinées juifs des rues moyennes du côté est 
de Manhattan, du Joe Weber et des zones inférieurs de Lew. Les 
sous-programmes de Weber et de zones ont habituellement comporté de 
larges stéréotypes des immigrés allemands : Les zones ont 
joué "Meyer," le slickster allemand judicieux qui a voulu "a mis un 
excédent" sur Mike de Weber "," le nouveau venu "hollandais" 
sourd-muet. À la crête de leur popularité en 1904, Weber et 
zones ont enregistré ce sous-programme populaire, "la scène 
potable," en vente commerciale. Ironiquement, juste quelques 
mois après enregistrement de ce sous-programme, l'équipe de Weber et
de zones s'est cassée vers le haut, terminant presque trois 
décennies des exécutions publiques, le plus long de n'importe quelle
équipe dans le théâtre populaire américain.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os immigrants e os americanos africanos deram 
forma decisively a uma cultura popular urbana multiethnic no 1ø 
século atrasado, construído na medida grande no emergence do 
vaudeville. Vaudeville misturou o comedy do slapstick, o 
minstrelsy do blackface, e canções sentimental no rich e stew 
cultural altamente popular. Entre o vaudeville o mais bem 
sucedido os practitioners eram dois singers e comics jewish das ruas 
médias de um lado do leste de Manhattan, de um Joe Weber e de uns 
campos mais baixos de Lew. As rotinas de Weber e de campos 
caracterizaram geralmente stereotypes largos de immigrants alemães: 
Os campos jogaram "Meyer," o slickster alemão shrewd que quis 
"pôs um excesso" sobre microfone de Weber o "," o newcomer 
"holandês" dumb. No pico de sua popularidade em 1904, Weber e 
os campos gravaram esta rotina popular, "a cena bebendo," para a venda
comercial. Ironically, apenas alguns meses após ter gravado 
esta rotina, a equipe de Weber e de campos quebrou acima, terminando 
quase três décadas de desempenhos públicos, o mais longo de toda a 
equipe no teatro popular americano.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli immigranti e gli Americani africani 
decisivamente hanno modellato una coltura popolare urbana multiethnic 
verso la fine del diciannovesimo secolo, sviluppato in una larga 
misura sull'emersione di vaudeville. Vaudeville ha mescolato la 
commedia dello slapstick, il minstrelsy del blackface e le canzoni 
sentimental nell'rich e stufato culturale altamente popolare. 
Fra vaudeville più riuscito i professionisti erano due cantanti
e comics ebrei dalle vie medie del lato orientale de Manhattan, di Joe
Weber e dei campi più bassi di Lew. Le procedure dei campi e di
Weber hanno caratterizzato solitamente i vasti stereotipi degli 
immigranti tedeschi: I campi hanno giocato "Meyer," lo slickster
tedesco sagace che ha desiderato "ha messo un'eccedenza" sul microfono
del Weber "," il nuovo venuto "olandese" dumb. Al picco della 
loro popolarità in 1904, Weber ed i campi hanno registrato questa 
procedura popolare, "la scena bevente," per la vendita commerciale. 
Ironicamente, appena alcuni mesi dopo la registrazione della 
questa procedura, la squadra dei campi e di Weber si è rotta in su, 
concludendosi quasi tre decadi delle prestazioni pubbliche, il più 
lungo di tutta la squadra nel teatro popolare americano.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι μετανάστες και αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί διαμόρφωσαν 
αποφασιστικά έναν multiethnic αστικό δημοφιλή πολιτισμό προς 
το τέλος του 19$ου αιώνα, που στηρίχτηκε σε μεγάλο βαθμό στην 
εμφάνιση της επιθεώρησης. Η επιθεώρηση συνδύασε slapstick
την κωμωδία, blackface minstrelsy, και συναισθηματικά 
τραγούδια πλούσιο και ιδιαίτερα δημοφιλές πολιτιστικό stew. 
Μεταξύ της επιτυχέστερης επιθεώρησης οι επαγγελματίες ήταν 
δύο εβραϊκοί τραγουδιστές και comics από τις μέσες οδούς της
χαμηλότερων ανατολικής πλευράς του Μανχάτταν, των πεδίων Joe 
Weber και Lew. Οι ρουτίνες Weber και των πεδίων 
χαρακτήρισαν συνήθως τα ευρέα στερεότυπα των γερμανικών 
μεταναστών: Τα πεδία έπαιξαν "Meyer," το πονηρό 
γερμανικό slickster που θέλησε "έβαλε ενός πέρα από" Mike 
Weber στο "," ο άλαλος "ολλανδικόσ" νεοφερμένος. Στην 
αιχμή της δημοτικότητάς τους το 1904, Weber και τα πεδία 
κατέγραψαν αυτήν την δημοφιλή ρουτίνα, "η σκηνή κατανάλωσης," 
για την εμπορική πώληση. Ειρωνικά, ακριβώς μερικούς μήνες 
μετά από να καταγράψει αυτήν την ρουτίνα, το Weber και τα 
πεδία η ομάδα χώρισε, τελειώνοντας σχεδόν τρεις δεκαετίες 
δημόσιων αποδόσεων, ο μακρύτερος οποιασδήποτε ομάδας στο 
αμερικανικό δημοφιλές θέατρο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los inmigrantes y los americanos africanos 
decisivo formaron una cultura popular urbana multiethnic en la a fines
del siglo XIX, construida en medida grande en la aparición del 
vaudeville. Vaudeville mezcló comedia del slapstick, la trova 
del blackface, y canciones sentimental en los ricos y guisado cultural
altamente popular. Entre el vaudeville más acertado los 
médicos eran dos cantantes y tebeos judíos de las calles malas de 
una cara del este de Manhattan, de un Joe Weber y de campos más bajos
de Lew. Las rutinas de Weber y de los campos ofrecieron 
generalmente amplios estereotipos de inmigrantes alemanes: Los 
campos jugaron "Meyer," el slickster alemán astuto que deseó 
"puso un excedente" en Mike de Weber "," el recién llegado 
"holandés" mudo. En el pico de su renombre en 1904, Weber y los
campos registraron esta rutina popular, "la escena que bebía," para 
la venta comercial. Irónico, apenas algunos meses después de 
registrar esta rutina, el equipo de Weber y de los campos se rompió 
para arriba, terminando casi tres décadas de funcionamientos 
públicos, el más largo de cualquier equipo en teatro popular 
americano.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086285</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108596</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-have-a-thirst-that-could-sink-a-ship-early-vaudeville</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
