<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104828</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104828</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205638</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Religions of the World (as practiced in America)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Religionen der Welt (wie in Amerika geübt)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Religions du monde (comme pratiqué en Amérique)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Religiões do mundo (como praticado em América)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Religioni del mondo (come esercitato in in 
America)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θρησκείες του κόσμου (όπως ασκείται στην Αμερική)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Religiones del mundo (según lo practicado en 
América)</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Welcome to the NROC Religions of the World course. The study of the world's religions is a lifelong journey. This course is designed to give you structure to help you organize your thoughts and enable you to make intelligent judgments about religion. You will be introduced to each faith by leading advocates of the tradition. Religion is a basic building block for society worldwide,and this course will enable you to grow in understanding and in appreciation of the many faith communities around the world.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Willkommen zu den NROC Religionen des Weltkurses. 
Die Studie der Religionen der Welt ist eine lebenslängliche 
Reise. Dieser Kurs ist konzipiert, um Ihnen Struktur zu geben, 
um Ihnen zu helfen, Ihre Gedanken zu organisieren und Sie zu 
aktivieren, intelligente Urteile über Religion zu bilden. Sie 
werden zu jedem Glauben durch das Führen der Fürsprecher der 
Tradition eingeführt. Religion ist ein Grundbaustein für 
Gesellschaft weltweit, und dieser Kurs aktiviert Sie, im Verstehen und
in der Anerkennung der vielen Glaube Gemeinschaften um die Welt zu 
wachsen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bienvenue aux religions de NROC du cours du monde.
L'étude des religions du monde est un voyage perpétuel. 
Ce cours est conçu pour vous donner la structure pour vous 
aider à organiser vos pensées et à vous permettre de faire des 
jugements intelligents au sujet de religion. Vous serez 
présenté à chaque foi en menant des avocats de la tradition. 
La religion est un bloc fonctionnel de base pour la société 
dans le monde entier, et ce cours vous permettra de vous développer 
dans l'arrangement et dans l'appréciation des nombreuses communautés
de foi autour du monde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Boa vinda às religiões de NROC do curso do 
mundo. O estudo das religiões do mundo é uma viagem lifelong. 
Este curso é projetado dar-lhe a estrutura para ajudar-lhe 
organizar seus pensamentos e permiti-lo de fazer julgamentos 
inteligentes sobre a religião. Você será introduzido a cada 
fé conduzindo a advogados da tradição. A religião é um 
bloco de edifício básico para a sociedade worldwide, e este curso 
permiti-lo-á de crescer na compreensão e na apreciação de muitas 
comunidades da fé em torno do mundo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Benvenuto alle religioni di NROC del corso del 
mondo. Lo studio sulle religioni del mondo è un viaggio 
lifelong. Questo corso è destinato per darvi la struttura per 
aiutarli ad organizzare i vostri pensieri ed a permettervi di fare i 
giudizi intelligenti circa la religione. Sarete introdotti ad 
ogni fede conducendo i fautori della tradizione. La religione è
un blocchetto di costruzione di base per la società universalmente e 
questo corso vi permetterà di svilupparsi nel capire e 
nell'apprezzamento delle molte Comunità di fede intorno al mondo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Υποδοχή στις θρησκείες NROC της παγκόσμιας σειράς 
μαθημάτων. Η μελέτη των παγκόσμιων θρησκειών είναι ένα 
ισόβιο ταξίδι. Αυτή η σειρά μαθημάτων σχεδιάζεται για να 
σας δώσει τη δομή για να σας βοηθήσει να οργανώσετε τις σκέψεις 
σας και να επιτρέψετε σε σας για να κρίνει ευφυείς τη θρησκεία. 
Θα εισαχθείτε σε κάθε πίστη από τους κύριους συνηγόρους 
της παράδοσης. Η θρησκεία είναι μια βασική δομική μονάδα 
για την κοινωνία παγκοσμίως, και αυτή η σειρά μαθημάτων θα 
επιτρέψει σε σας για να αυξηθεί στην κατανόηση και στην εκτίμηση 
των πολλών κοινοτήτων πίστης σε όλο τον κόσμο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Recepción a las religiones de NROC del curso del 
mundo. El estudio de las religiones del mundo es un viaje de por
vida. Este curso se diseña para darle la estructura para 
ayudarle a ordenar sus pensamientos y a permitirle hacer juicios 
inteligentes sobre la religión. Conduciendo le introducirá a 
cada fe a abogados de la tradición. La religión es un bloque 
de edificio básico para la sociedad por todo el mundo, y este curso 
le permitirá crecer en entender y en el aprecio de las muchas 
comunidades de la fe alrededor del mundo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MONTEREY INSTITUTE FOR TECHNOLOGY AND EDUCATION AND CHATTANOOGA STATE TECHNICAL COMMUNITY COLLEGE
FN:MONTEREY INSTITUTE FOR TECHNOLOGY AND EDUCATION AND CHATTANOOGA STATE TECHNICAL COMMUNITY COLLEGE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205638</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104828</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/religions-of-the-world-as-practiced-in-amercia</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
