<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103050</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103050</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086409</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Letters of Thomas Newe to His Father, from South Carolina (1682).</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zeichen von Thomas Newe zu seinem Vater, von 
Südcarolina (1682).</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Lettres de Thomas Newe à son père, de Caroline 
Du sud (1682).</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Letras de Thomas Newe a seu pai, de carolina sul 
(1682).</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lettere di Thomas Newe al suo padre, da Carolina 
del Sud (1682).</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστολές του Thomas Newe στον πατέρα του, από τη
νότια Καρολίνα (1682).</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cartas de Thomas Newe a su padre, de Carolina del 
Sur (1682).</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">After the restoration of the British monarchy in 1660, a group of proprietors received a royal grant to establish the colony of South Carolina. They envisioned an agricultural economy based on mixed farming, cattle raising, and trade in deerskins with the local Indians, diverging from the Chesapeake's tobacco and slave economy to the north. The Carolina proprietors sought settlers from the Caribbean by offering inexpensive land for family farms. But conditions were harsh, work was heavy, and poor nutrition was common, as Oxford University-educated Thomas Newe made clear in this 1682 letter to his father. A small minority of wealthy colonists seized economic and political control of the colony. They concentrated in the town of Charleston, drove out the local Indians, and occupied huge tracts of land. Deviating from the society that had been planned, these planters established rice cultivation, thanks to the African slaves whose experience in West Africa formed the basis for the economy. By 1707 South Carolina had the first black majority population in North America. Thomas Newe died within a year of writing these letters, at the age of 28.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nach der Wiederherstellung der britischen Monarchie 
1660, empfing eine Gruppe Eigentümer eine königliche Bewilligung, um
die Kolonie von Südcarolina herzustellen. Sie stellten sich 
eine landwirtschaftliche Wirtschaft vor, die auf dem 
Mischbewirtschaften basierten, das Vieh, das anheben, und Handel in 
den deerskins mit den lokalen Indern und liefen von der Tabak- und 
Sklavenwirtschaft des Chesapeakes zum Norden auseinander. Die 
Carolina Eigentümer suchten Siedleren von den Karibischen Meeren, 
indem sie billiges Land für Familie Bauernhöfe anboten. Aber 
Bedingungen waren rauh, war Arbeit schwer, und schlechte Nahrung war 
geläufig, da Oxford mit Universitätsausbildung Thomas Newe seinem 
Vater klar in diesem Zeichen 1682 bildete. Eine kleine 
Minorität wohlhabende Kolonisten ergriff ökonomische und politische 
Steuerung der Kolonie. Sie konzentrierten sich in der Stadt von 
Charleston, trieben aus den lokalen Indern an und besetzten sehr 
große Landstriche. Abweichend von der Gesellschaft, die geplant
worden war, stellten diese Pflanzer Reisbearbeitung, dank die 
afrikanischen Sklaven her deren Erfahrung in Westafrika die Grundlage 
für die Wirtschaft bildete. Durch 1707 hatte Südcarolina die 
erste Schwarzmajorität Bevölkerung in Nordamerika. Thomas Newe
starb innerhalb eines Jahres des Schreibens dieser Briefe, am Alter 
von 28.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Après la restauration de la monarchie britannique en 
1660, un groupe de propriétaires a reçu une concession royale pour 
établir la colonie de la Caroline du sud. Ils ont 
envisagé une économie agricole basée sur l'affermage mélangé, des
bétail augmentant, et des échanges des peaux de daim avec les Indiens 
locaux, divergeant du tabac et de l'économie slave du 
chesapeake au nord. Les propriétaires de la Caroline ont 
recherché des colons des Caraïbes en offrant la terre peu coûteuse 
pour des fermes de famille. Mais les conditions étaient dures, 
le travail était lourd, et la nutrition faible était commune, car 
Oxford Thomas diplômé d'université Newe a fait clairement dans 
cette lettre 1682 à son père. Une petite minorité de colons 
riches a saisi la commande économique et politique de la colonie. 
Ils se sont concentrés dans la ville de Charleston, ont conduit
hors des Indiens locaux, et ont occupé les régions de la terre 
énormes. Déviant de la société qui avait été projetée, 
ces planteurs ont établi la culture de riz, grâce aux esclaves 
africains dont l'expérience Afrique occidentale a formé la base pour
l'économie. Par 1707 Sud la Caroline a eu la première 
population de majorité de noir en Amérique du nord. 
Thomas Newe est mort dans une année d'écrire ces lettres, à 
l'âge de 28.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Após a restauração do monarchy britânico em 1660, um 
grupo dos proprietors recebeu uma concessão real para estabelecer a 
colônia de carolina sul. Envisioned uma economia agricultural 
baseada em cultivar misturado, o gado que levantam, e o comércio nos 
deerskins com os indians locais, diverging da economia do tabaco e do 
escravo do chesapeake ao norte. Os proprietors de Carolina 
procuraram settlers das Caraíbas oferecendo a terra barata para 
fazendas da família. Mas as circunstâncias eram ásperas, o 
trabalho era pesado, e o nutrition deficiente era comum, porque Oxford
Thomas university-educated Newe fêz claramente nesta letra 1682 a seu
pai. Um minority pequeno de colonos ricos apreendeu o controle 
econômico e político da colônia. Concentraram na cidade de 
Charleston, dirigiram para fora dos indians locais, e ocuparam 
intervalos de terra enormes. Deviating da sociedade que tinha 
sido planeada, estes plantadores estabeleceram o cultivation do arroz,
agradecimentos aos escravos africanos cuja a experiência em África 
ocidental deu forma à base para a economia. Por 1707 carolina 
sul teve a primeira população da maioria do preto em America do 
Norte. Thomas Newe morreu dentro de um ano de escrever estas 
letras, na idade de 28.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dopo il ripristino del monarchy britannico in 1660, un 
gruppo dei proprietari ha ricevuto una concessione reale per stabilire
la colonia di Carolina del Sud. Hanno previsto un'economia 
agricola basata sull'agricoltura mixed, i bestiami che si alzano ed il
commercio dei deerskins con gli indiani locali, divergendo 
dall'economia del tabacco e dello schiavo del chesapeake al nord. 
I proprietari della Carolina hanno cercato i settlers dai 
Caraibi offrendo la terra economica per i poderi della famiglia. 
Ma le circostanze erano dure, il lavoro era gravoso e la 
povera nutrizione era comune, poichè Oxford Thomas d'istruzione 
universitaria Newe ha fatto chiaramente in questa lettera 1682 al suo 
padre. Una piccola minoranza dei colonizzatori ricchi ha 
grippato il controllo economico e politico della colonia. Si 
sono concentrati nella città di Charleston, hanno guidato verso 
l'esterno gli indiani locali ed hanno occupato i tratti di terra 
enormi. Deviando dalla società che era stata progettata, queste
piantatrici hanno stabilito la coltura del riso, grazie agli schiavi 
africani di cui l'esperienza in Africa ad ovest ha costituito la base 
per l'economia. Entro 1707 Carolina del Sud ha avuta la prima 
popolazione di maggioranza di nero in America del Nord. Thomas 
Newe è morto in un anno di scrittura delle queste lettere, all'età 
di 28.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μετά από την αποκατάσταση της βρετανικής μοναρχίας το
1660, μια ομάδα ιδιοκτητών έλαβε μια βασιλική επιχορήγηση για 
να καθιερώσει την αποικία της νότιας Καρολίνας. Πρόβλεψαν 
μια γεωργική οικονομία που έδρευσαν στη μικτή καλλιέργεια, τα 
βοοειδή αυξάνοντας, και το εμπόριο στα ελάφεια δέρματα με τους 
τοπικούς Ινδούς, που αποκλίνει από τη chesapeake οικονομία 
καπνών και σκλάβων στο Βορρά. Οι ιδιοκτήτες της Καρολίνας 
επιδίωξαν τους αποίκους από τις Καραϊβικές Θάλασσες με την 
προσφορά του ανέξοδου εδάφους για τα οικογενειακά αγροκτήματα. 
Αλλά οι όροι ήταν σκληροί, η εργασία ήταν βαριά, και η 
φτωχή διατροφή ήταν κοινή, ως Οξφόρδη ο university-educated 
Thomas Newe σαφές σε αυτήν την επιστολή 1682 στον πατέρα 
του. Μια μικρή μειονότητα των πλούσιων αποίκων πήρε τον 
οικονομικό και πολιτικό έλεγχο της αποικίας. Συγκεντρώθηκαν
στην πόλη του Τσάρλεστον, εδίωξαν τους τοπικούς Ινδούς, και 
κατέλαβαν τα τεράστια κομμάτια του εδάφους. Παρεκκλίνοντας 
από την κοινωνία που ήταν προγραμματισμένη, αυτοί οι 
καλλιεργητές καθιέρωσαν την καλλιέργεια ρυζιού, χάρι στους 
αφρικανικούς σκλάβους η των οποίων εμπειρία στη δυτική Αφρική 
αποτέλεσε τη βάση για την οικονομία. Από το νότο 1707 η 
Καρολίνα είχε τον πρώτο μαύρο πληθυσμό πλειοψηφίας στη Βόρεια 
Αμερική. Ο Thomas Newe πέθανε μέσα σε ένα έτος από 
γράψιμο αυτών των επιστολών, στην ηλικία 28.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Después de la restauración de la monarquía británica 
en 1660, un grupo de propietarios recibió una concesión real para 
establecer a la colonia de Carolina del Sur. Previeron una 
economía agrícola basada en cultivar mezclado, los ganados que 
levantaban, y comercio en deerskins con los indios locales, 
divergiendo de la economía del tabaco y del esclavo del chesapeake al
norte. Los propietarios de Carolina buscaron a colonos del 
Caribe ofreciendo la pista barata para las granjas de la familia. 
Pero las condiciones eran ásperas, el trabajo era pesado, y la 
nutrición pobre era común, pues Oxford Thomas universitario Newe 
hizo claramente en esta carta 1682 a su padre. Una minoría 
pequeña de colonos ricos agarró el control económico y político de
la colonia. Se concentraron en la ciudad de Charleston, 
condujeron fuera de los indios locales, y ocuparon zonas de la pista 
enormes. Desviándose de la sociedad que había sido planeada, 
estos plantadores establecieron la cultivación del arroz, gracias a 
los esclavos africanos que experiencia en África del oeste formó la 
base para la economía. Antes de 1707 Carolina del Sur tenía la
primera población de la mayoría del negro en Norteamérica. 
Thomas Newe murió dentro de un año de escribir estas letras, 
en la edad de 28.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086409</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103050</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/letters-of-thomas-newe-to-his-father-from-south-carolina-1682</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
