<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107683</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107683</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086265</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Human Rights are Women's Rights and Workers' Rights are Women's Rights:" May Chen on the United Nations Fourth Conference on Women</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"menschliche Rechte sind Rechte der Frauen und 
Rechte der Arbeiter sind Rechte der Frauen:" Mai Chen auf der 
Nationen vierten Konferenz auf Frauen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"les droits de l'homme sont les droits des femmes 
et les droits des ouvriers sont les droits des femmes :" Mai 
Chen sur conférence des Nations Unies la quatrième sur des femmes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"as direitas humanas são direitas das mulheres e 
as direitas dos trabalhadores são direitas das mulheres:" Maio 
Chen conferência unida das nações na quarta sobre mulheres</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"i diritti dell'uomo sono diritti delle donne ed i
diritti degli operai sono diritti delle donne:" Maggio Chen sul 
congresso di Quarto delle Nazioni Unite sulle donne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα "ανθρώπινα δικαιώματα είναι δικαιώματα των 
γυναικών και τα δικαιώματα των εργαζομένων είναι δικαιώματα των 
γυναικών:" Μάιος Chen στην τέταρτη διάσκεψη Ηνωμένων
Εθνών σχετικά με τις γυναίκες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">los "derechos humanos correcto de las mujeres y 
las derechas de los trabajadores correcto de las mujeres:" Mayo 
Chen en la cuarta conferencia de Naciones Unidas sobre mujeres</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The United Nations Fourth World Conference on Women was held in Beijing, China during September 1995. The conference, which called for gender equality, development, and peace, grew out of the international women's movement and marked the end of the official United Nations decade of Women. For women like May Chen, Vice President of the Union of Needletrades, Industrial, and Textile Employees (UNITE), the conference was an opportunity to share their activist experiences and learn about issues confronting women around the world, including political and domestic violence against women and families, economic and cultural marginalization, and unfair labor practices. Chen, a long-time activist in the Asian-American community, relished the opportunity to meet and learn from well-prepared women who insisted that women's rights _ and worker's rights _ were human rights.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Nationen vierte Weltkonferenz auf Frauen wurde
in Beijing, China während Septembers 1995 angehalten. Die 
Konferenz, die Geschlechtgleichheit, -entwicklung und -frieden 
verlangte, wuchs aus der internationalen Bewegung der Frauen heraus 
und kennzeichnete das Ende der amtlichen Nationen Dekade der Frauen. 
Für Frauen mögen Sie Mai Chen, Vizepräsident des Anschlußes 
von Needletrades, industriell, und Textilangestellte (VEREINIGEN Sie),
die Konferenz waren eine Gelegenheit, ihre Aktivist Erfahrungen zu 
teilen und über die Ausgaben zu erlernen, die Frauen um die Welt, 
einschließlich politische und inländische Gewalttätigkeit gegen 
Frauen und Familien, ökonomisches und kulturelles marginalization und
unfaire Arbeit Praxis konfrontieren. Chen, ein langfristiger 
Aktivist in der Asiatisch-Amerikanischen Gemeinschaft, relished die 
Gelegenheit, von den gut vorbereiteten Frauen zu treffen und zu 
erlernen, die beharrten, daß Rechte der Frauen _ und Rechte des 
Arbeiters _ menschliche Rechte waren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Conférence du monde des Nations Unies la 
quatrième sur des femmes a été tenue dans Pékin, Chine pendant
septembre 1995. La conférence, qui a nécessité l'égalité, 
le développement, et la paix de genre, s'est développée hors du 
mouvement des femmes internationales et a marqué la fin de la 
décennie officielle des Nations Unies des femmes. Pour des 
femmes aimez mai Chen, vice-président de l'union de Needletrades, 
industrielle, et les employés de textile (UNISSEZ), la conférence 
étaient une occasion de partager leurs expériences d'activiste et de
se renseigner sur des issues confrontant des femmes autour du monde, y
compris la violence politique et domestique contre des femmes et des 
familles, le marginalization économique et culturel, et les pratiques
déloyales de travail. Chen, un activiste à long terme dans la 
communauté Asiatique-Américaine, relished l'occasion de se réunir 
et apprendre des femmes bien préparées qui ont insisté sur le fait 
que les droits des femmes _ et les droits de l'ouvrier _ étaient des 
droits de l'homme.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Conferência unida do mundo das nações a quarta 
sobre mulheres foi prendida em Beijing, China durante setembro 1995. 
A conferência, que se chamou para a igualdade, o 
desenvolvimento, e a paz do gender, cresceu fora do movimento das 
mulheres internacionais e marcou o fim da década unida oficial das 
nações das mulheres. Para mulheres goste de maio Chen, 
vice-presidente da união de Needletrades, industrial, e os empregados
de textile (UNA), a conferência eram uma oportunidade de compartilhar
de suas experiências da activista e de aprendê-las sobre as 
edições que confrontam mulheres em torno do mundo, including a 
violência política e doméstica de encontro às mulheres e as 
famílias, o marginalization econômico e cultural, e as práticas de 
trabalho unfair. Chen, uma activista long-time na comunidade 
Asian-Americana, relished a oportunidade de encontrar-se com e 
aprender das mulheres well-prepared que insistiram que as direitas das
mulheres _ e as direitas do trabalhador _ eram direitas humanas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il congresso del mondo di Quarto delle 
Nazioni Unite sulle donne è stato tenuto in Beijing, Cina durante il 
mese di settembre del 1995. Il congresso, che ha richiesto 
uguaglianza, sviluppo e pace di genere, si è sviluppato dal movimento
delle donne internazionali ed ha contrassegnato la conclusione della 
decade ufficiale delle Nazioni Unite delle donne. Per le donne 
gradisca maggio Chen, vice presidente dell'unione di Needletrades, 
industriale e gli impiegati della tessile (UNISCA), il congresso erano
un'occasione ripartire le loro esperienze dell'attivista ed imparare
circa le edizioni che confrontano le donne intorno al mondo, compreso 
la violenza politica e domestica contro le donne e famiglie, il 
marginalization economico e culturale e le pratiche di lavoro 
ingiuste. Chen, un attivista long-time nella Comunità 
Asiatico-Americana, relished l'occasione venire a contatto di ed 
imparare dalle donne ben preparate che hanno insistito che i diritti 
delle donne _ ed i diritti dell'operaio _ erano diritti dell'uomo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η διάσκεψη τέταρτων κόσμων Ηνωμένων Εθνών σχετικά με
τις γυναίκες διοργανώθηκε στο Πεκίνο, Κίνα κατά τη διάρκεια τον 
Σεπτεμβρίου του 1995. Η διάσκεψη, που απαίτησε την 
ισότητα, την ανάπτυξη, και την ειρήνη γένους, αυξήθηκε από το 
κίνημα των διεθνών γυναικών και χαρακτήρισε το τέλος της 
επίσημης δεκαετίας Ηνωμένων Εθνών γυναικών. Για τις 
γυναίκες όπως Μάιος Chen, αντιπρόεδρος της ένωσης των 
βιομηχανικών, και υφαντικών υπαλλήλων Needletrades, (ΕΝΩΣΤΕ), η 
διάσκεψη ήταν μια ευκαιρία να μοιραστεί η εμπειρία ενεργών 
στελεχών τους και να μάθει για τα ζητήματα που αντιμετωπίζουν τις 
γυναίκες σε όλο τον κόσμο, συμπεριλαμβανομένης της πολιτικής και 
βίας στο σπίτι ενάντια στις γυναίκες και τις οικογένειες, της 
οικονομικής και πολιτιστικής περιθωριοποίησης, και των αθέμιτων 
πρακτικών εργασίας. Το Chen, ένα μακροπρόθεσμο ενεργό 
στέλεχος στην ασιατικός-αμερικανική κοινότητα, ηπόλαυσε την 
ευκαιρία να συναντηθεί και να μάθει από τις πανέτοιμες γυναίκες 
που επέμειναν ότι τα δικαιώματα των γυναικών _ και τα δικαιώματα 
του εργαζομένου _ ήταν τα ανθρώπινα δικαιώματα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La cuarta conferencia del mundo de Naciones Unidas
sobre mujeres fue llevada a cabo en Beijing, China durante septiembre 
de 1995. La conferencia, que llamó para la igualdad, el 
desarrollo, y la paz del género, creció fuera del movimiento de las 
mujeres internacionales y marcó el final de la década oficial de 
Naciones Unidas de mujeres. Para las mujeres tenga gusto de mayo
Chen, vice presidente de la unión de Needletrades, industrial, y los 
empleados del textil (UNA), la conferencia eran una oportunidad de 
compartir sus experiencias del activista y de aprender sobre las 
ediciones que enfrentaban a mujeres alrededor del mundo, incluyendo 
violencia política y doméstica contra mujeres y las familias, el 
marginalization económico y cultural, y prácticas de trabajo 
injusto. Chen, activista de largo plazo en la comunidad 
Asia'tico-Americana, relished la oportunidad de satisfacer y de 
aprender de las mujeres bien preparadas que insistieron que las 
derechas de las mujeres _ y las derechas del trabajador _ eran 
derechos humanos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086265</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107683</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/human-rights-are-womens-rights-and-workers-rights-are-womens-rights-may-chen-on-the-united-nations-fourth-conference-on-women</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
