<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106167</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106167</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974029</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Puzzling Polarizers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Verwirrenpolarisatoren</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Polariseurs Embarassants</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Polarizers Confundindo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Polarizzatori D'Imbarazzo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μπερδεύοντας πολωτές</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Polarizadores De Desconcierto</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">When we apply the scientific method to real-world problems, often we can invent applications for the effects we observe even without understanding the origins of those effects. This process is commonly used in the development of new technologies; one example is the discovery of x rays. This curriculum unit is designed to encourage this investigative process through inquiry-based learning involving exploring, observing, and then applying the information gained. Light and its interactions with matter form the main focus for this activity, because light is the chief product of the Advanced Light Source (ALS). One property of light (polarization) is highlighted as a tool for exploration. This activity can be used in lessons on the scientific method, how advances in technology occur, the properties of light, how we observe things, or other related topics.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wenn wir die wissenschaftliche Methode an den 
realistischen Problemen anwenden, häufig können wir Anwendungen für
die Effekte erfinden, die wir beobachten, sogar ohne die Ursprung 
jener Effekte zu verstehen. Dieser Prozeß wird geläufig in der
Entwicklung der neuen Technologien verwendet; ein Beispiel ist 
die Entdeckung der x Strahlen. Diese Lehrplanmaßeinheit ist 
konzipiert, um diesen Untersuchungsprozeß durch das 
Anfrage-gegründete erlernenmit einbeziehende Erforschen, das 
Beobachten, und der gewonnenen Informationen dann anwenden anzuregen. 
Licht und seine Interaktionen mit Stoff bilden den Hauptfokus 
für diese Aktivität, weil Licht das Hauptprodukt der 
hochentwickelten Lichtquelle (ALS) ist. Eine Eigenschaft Licht 
(Polarisation) wird als Hilfsmittel für Erforschung markiert. 
Diese Aktivität kann in den Lektionen auf der 
wissenschaftlichen Methode verwendet werden, wie technische 
Fortschritte auftreten, die Eigenschaften des Lichtes, wie wir Sachen 
beobachten, oder andere in Verbindung stehende Themen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Quand nous nous appliquons la méthode 
scientifique aux problèmes réels, souvent nous pouvons inventer des 
demandes d'effets que nous observons même sans arrangement les 
origines de ces effets. Ce processus est généralement utilisé
dans le développement de nouvelles technologies ; un exemple 
est la découverte des rayons de x. Cette unité de programme 
d'études est conçue pour encourager ce processus investigateur 
explorer impliquant d'étude enquête-basé, observer, et puis en 
appliquant l'information obtenue. La lumière et ses 
interactions avec la matière forment le foyer principal pour cette 
activité, parce que la lumière est le produit en chef de la source 
lumineuse avançée (ALS). Une propriété de lumière 
(polarisation) est mise en valeur comme outil pour l'exploration. 
Cette activité peut être utilisée dans les leçons sur la 
méthode scientifique, comment les avances en technologie se 
produisent, les propriétés de la lumière, comment nous observons 
des choses, ou d'autres sujets relatifs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quando nós aplicamos o método científico aos 
problemas real-world, frequentemente nós podemos inventar 
aplicações para os efeitos que nós observamos mesmo sem compreender
as origens daqueles efeitos. Este processo é usado geralmente 
no desenvolvimento de tecnologias novas; um exemplo é a 
descoberta de raios de x. Esta unidade do curriculum é 
projetada incentivar este processo investigative com explorar de 
envolvimento de aprendizagem inquérito-baseado, observar, e então 
aplicar a informação ganha. A luz e suas interações com 
matéria dão forma ao foco principal para esta atividade, porque a 
luz é o produto principal da fonte clara avançada (ALS). Uma 
propriedade da luz (polarization) é destacada como uma ferramenta 
para a exploração. Esta atividade pode ser usada nas lições 
no método científico, como os avanços na tecnologia ocorrem, as 
propriedades da luz, como nós observamos coisas, ou outros tópicos 
relacionados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Quando applichiamo il metodo scientifico ai 
problemi nell'ambiente, possiamo inventare spesso le domande di 
effetti che osserviamo anche senza capire le origini di quegli 
effetti. Questo processo è usato comunemente nello sviluppo di 
nuove tecnologie; un esempio è la scoperta dei raggi di x. 
Questa unità di programma di studi è destinata per consigliare
a questo processo investigativo through l'esplorazione di 
coinvoluzione imparante inchiesta-basata, l'osservazione ed allora 
applicando delle informazioni ottenute. La luce e le relative 
interazioni con la materia formano il fuoco principale per questa 
attività, perché la luce è il prodotto principale della fonte di 
luce avanzata (ALS). Una proprietà di luce (polarizzazione) è 
evidenziata come strumento per esplorazione. Questa attività 
può essere usata nelle lezioni sul metodo scientifico, come gli 
avanzamenti nella tecnologia accadono, le proprietà di luce, come 
osserviamo le cose, o altri soggetti relativi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Όταν εφαρμόζουμε την επιστημονική μέθοδο στα 
πραγματικά προβλήματα, συχνά μπορούμε να εφεύρουμε τις εφαρμογές
για τα αποτελέσματα που παρατηρούμε ακόμη και χωρίς κατανόηση της
προέλευσης εκείνων των αποτελεσμάτων. Αυτή η διαδικασία 
χρησιμοποιείται συνήθως στην ανάπτυξη των νέων τεχνολογιών  
ένα παράδειγμα είναι η ανακάλυψη των ακτίνων Χ. Αυτή
η μονάδα προγράμματος σπουδών σχεδιάζεται για να ενθαρρύνει 
αυτήν την εξεταστική διαδικασία μέσω της έρευνα-βασισμένης στον 
περιλαμβάνοντας εξερεύνησης εκμάθησης, παρατήρηση, και έπειτα 
"Εφαρμογή" των πληροφοριών που λαμβάνονται. Το φως και οι 
αλληλεπιδράσεις του με το θέμα διαμορφώνουν τον κεντρικό αγωγό 
στρέφονται για αυτήν την δραστηριότητα, επειδή το φως είναι το 
προϊστάμενος προϊόν της προηγμένης πηγής φωτός (νόσος του 
Alsheimer). Μια ιδιοκτησία του φωτός (πόλωση) τονίζεται 
ως εργαλείο για την εξερεύνηση. Αυτή η δραστηριότητα μπορεί
να χρησιμοποιηθεί στα μαθήματα στην επιστημονική μέθοδο, πώς οι 
πρόοδοι στην τεχνολογία εμφανίζονται, οι ιδιότητες του φωτός, 
πώς παρατηρούμε τα πράγματα, ή άλλα σχετικά θέματα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cuando aplicamos el método científico a los 
problemas del mundo real, podemos inventar a menudo las aplicaciones 
para los efectos que observamos incluso sin entender los orígenes de 
esos efectos. Este proceso se utiliza comúnmente en el 
desarrollo de nuevas tecnologías; un ejemplo es el 
descubrimiento de los rayos de x. Esta unidad del plan de 
estudios se diseña para animar este proceso investigador con explorar
de participación que aprende pregunta-basado, la observación, y 
después la aplicación de la información ganada. La luz y sus 
interacciones con la materia forman el foco principal para esta 
actividad, porque la luz es el principal producto de la fuente de luz 
avanzada (ALS). Una característica de luz (polarización) se 
destaca como herramienta para la exploración. Esta actividad se
puede utilizar en lecciones en el método científico, cómo ocurren 
los avances en tecnología, las características de la luz, cómo 
observamos cosas, u otros asuntos relacionados.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:KIRSTEN DAEHLER
FN:KIRSTEN DAEHLER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974029</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106167</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/puzzling-polarizers</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
