<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106364</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106364</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203568</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Just-in-Time Teaching (JiTT) WarmUp Activity: Geologic Dating</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gerade-in-Zeit Unterricht (JiTT) Vorwärmung 
Aktivität: Geologische Datierung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Activité De Préchauffage d'Enseignement de 
Juste-dans-Temps (JiTT) : Dater Géologique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Atividade Do WarmUp Do Ensino Do Apenas-em-Tempo 
(JiTT): Datar Geologic</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Attività Di Preriscaldamento Di Insegnamento Di 
Appena-in-Tempo (JiTT): Datare Geologico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πάνω στην ώρα δραστηριότητα WarmUp διδασκαλίας 
(JiTT): Γεωλογική χρονολόγηση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Actividad Del Calentamiento De la Enseñanza Del 
Apenas-en-Tiempo (JiTT): El Fechar Geológico</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site features Just-in-Time Teaching (JiTT) warm up questions in geologic dating. The questions examine zircon formation and relative and absolute dating. The site also includes links to more information on Just-in-Time Teaching (JiTT), and to a page devoted to assessment for information and ideas on how to evaluate student responses when using this method.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Situationsmerkmale Gerade-in-Zeit Unterricht 
(JiTT) Vorwärmung Fragen in der geologischen Datierung. Die 
Fragen überprüfen zircon Anordnung und Verwandter und absolute 
Datierung. Die Site schließt auch Links zu mehr Informationen 
über Gerade-in-Zeit Unterricht (JiTT) und zu einer Seite ein, die 
Einschätzung zu Information und Ideen gewidmet wird auf, wie man 
Kursteilnehmerantworten auswertet, wenn sie diese Methode verwendet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Questions de ce de site de dispositifs de 
Juste-dans-Temps préchauffage d'enseignement (JiTT) dans dater 
géologique. Les questions examinent la formation de zircon et 
le parent et dater absolu. Le site inclut également des liens 
à plus d'information sur l'enseignement de Juste-dans-Temps (JiTT), 
et à une page consacrée à l'évaluation pour l'information et des 
idées sur la façon dont évaluer des réponses d'étudiant en 
utilisant cette méthode.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este ensino do Apenas-em-Tempo das características
de local (JiTT) aquece acima perguntas em datar geologic. As 
perguntas examinam a formação do zircon e o parente e datar 
absoluto. O local inclui também as ligações a mais 
informação no ensino do Apenas-em-Tempo (JiTT), e a uma página 
devotada à avaliação para a informação e as idéias em como 
avaliar respostas do estudante ao usar este método.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Domande di questo di luogo delle caratteristiche di
Appena-in-Tempo preriscaldamento di insegnamento (JiTT) nel datare 
geologico. Le domande esaminano la formazione dello zircon e 
parente e datare assoluto. Il luogo egualmente include i 
collegamenti alle più informazioni su insegnamento di Appena-in-Tempo
(JiTT) e ad una pagina dedicata alla valutazione per le informazioni e
le idee su come valutare le risposte dell'allievo quando usando questo
metodo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει τις πάνω στην ώρα 
ερωτήσεις προθέρμανσης διδασκαλίας (JiTT) στη γεωλογική 
χρονολόγηση. Οι ερωτήσεις εξετάζουν zircon το σχηματισμό 
και τη σχετική και απόλυτη χρονολόγηση. Η περιοχή 
περιλαμβάνει επίσης την τις συνδέσεις με περισσότερες πληροφορίες
για την πάνω στην ώρα διδασκαλία (JiTT), και σε μια σελίδα που 
αφιερώνεται στην αξιολόγηση για τις πληροφορίες και τις ιδέες για 
το πώς να αξιολογήσει τις απαντήσεις σπουδαστών κατά 
χρησιμοποίηση αυτής της μεθόδου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Preguntas de este de sitio de las características 
del Apenas-en-Tiempo calentamiento de la enseñanza (JiTT) en fechar 
geológico. Las preguntas examinan la formación del zircon y 
pariente y el fechar absoluto. El sitio también incluye 
conexiones a más información sobre la enseñanza del 
Apenas-en-Tiempo (JiTT), y a una paginación dedicada al gravamen para
la información y las ideas en cómo evaluar respuestas del estudiante
al usar este método.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:LAURA GUERTIN
FN:LAURA GUERTIN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CATHY MANDUCA
FN:CATHY MANDUCA
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203568</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106364</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/just-in-time-teaching-jitt-warmup-activity-geologic-dating</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
