<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108585</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108585</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207056</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Veterans History Project</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Veteran-Geschichte Projekt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Projet d'Histoire de Vétérans</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Projeto Do History Dos Veterans</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Progetto Di Storia Dei Veterani</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πρόγραμμα ιστορίας παλαιμάχων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Proyecto De la Historia De los Veteranos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Veterans History Project is collecting oral histories, letters, diaries, and photos of America's war veterans and those supported them. The project includes participants in World War I, World War II, and the Korean, Vietnam, and Persian Gulf wars. Students, citizens, and organizations are invited to contribute using the Project Kit, which provides all information and forms needed to interview a veteran. Libraries, museums, and civic groups can read about model veterans projects and start a project in their community</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Veteran-Geschichte Projekt sammelt 
Mundgeschichten, Zeichen, Tagebücher, und Fotos der Kriegveterane und
-deren Amerikas unterstützten sie. Das Projekt enthält 
Teilnehmer im Ersten Weltkrieg, im Zweiten Weltkrieg und in den 
Kriegen des Koreaners, Vietnams und des persischen Golfs. 
Kursteilnehmer, Bürger und Organisationen werden eingeladen mit
dem Projekt-Installationssatz beizutragen, der alle Informationen 
liefert und erforderlich sich bildet, um einen Veteran zu interviewen.
Bibliotheken, Museen und bürgerliche Gruppen können über 
vorbildliche Veteranprojekte lesen und ein Projekt in ihrer 
Gemeinschaft beginnen</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le projet d'histoire de vétérans rassemble des 
histoires orales, lettres, agendas, et les photos des anciens 
combattants et de ceux de l'Amérique les ont supportés. Le 
projet inclut des participants dans la Première Guerre Mondiale, la 
deuxième guerre mondiale, et les guerres de Coréen, du Vietnam, et 
de golfe Persique. Des étudiants, les citoyens, et les 
organismes sont invités à contribuer en utilisant le kit de projet, 
qui fournit toutes les informations et forme nécessaire pour 
interviewer un vétéran. Les bibliothèques, les musées, et 
les groupes civiques peuvent avoir connaissance des projets modèles 
de vétérans et lancer un projet dans leur communauté</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O projeto do history dos veterans está coletando 
histories orais, letras, diários, e as fotos de veterans e daqueles 
de guerra de América suportaram-nos. O projeto inclui 
participants no world.war.i, na segunda guerra mundial, e nas guerras 
do coreano, do Vietnam, e de golfo persa. Os estudantes, os 
cidadãos, e as organizações são convidados contribuir usando o 
jogo do projeto, que fornece toda a informação e a dá forma needed 
para entrevistar um veteran. As bibliotecas, os museus, e os 
grupos civic podem ler sobre os projetos modelo dos veterans e 
começar um projeto em sua comunidade</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il progetto di storia dei veterani sta 
raccogliendo i dati storici orali, le lettere, diari e le foto dei 
veterani e di quelli di guerra dell'America li hanno sostenuti. 
Il progetto include i partecipanti nel world.war.i, nella 
seconda guerra mondiale e nelle guerre del Coreano, del Vietnam e di 
golfo persiano. Gli allievi, i cittadini e le organizzazioni 
sono invitati a contribuire usando il kit di progetto, che fornisce 
tutte le informazioni e forma necessario per intervistare un veterano.
Le librerie, i musei ed i gruppi civici possono leggere sui 
progetti di modello dei veterani e lanciare un progetto nella loro 
Comunità</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το πρόγραμμα ιστορίας παλαιμάχων συλλέγει τις 
προφορικές ιστορίες, τις επιστολές, τα ημερολόγια, και τις 
φωτογραφίες των πολεμικών παλαιμάχων της Αμερικής και εκείνοι τις
υποστήριξαν. Το πρόγραμμα περιλαμβάνει τους συμμετέχοντες 
στον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι, τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο ΙΙ, και τα 
κορεατικά, το Βιετνάμ, και τους πολέμους Περσικών Κόλπων. 
Οι σπουδαστές, οι πολίτες, και οι οργανώσεις καλούνται για 
να συμβάλουν χρησιμοποιώντας την εξάρτηση προγράμματος, η οποία 
παρέχει όλες τις πληροφορίες και τις μορφές που απαιτούνται για 
να πάρουν συνέντευξη από έναν παλαίμαχο. Οι βιβλιοθήκες, 
τα μουσεία, και οι πολιτικές ομάδες μπορούν να διαβάσουν για τα 
πρότυπα προγράμματα παλαιμάχων και να αρχίσουν ένα πρόγραμμα 
στην κοινότητά τους</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El proyecto de la historia de los veteranos está 
recogiendo las historias orales, cartas, diarios, y las fotos de los 
veteranos y de ésos de guerra de América los apoyaron. El 
proyecto incluye a participantes en Primera Guerra Mundial, la Segunda
Guerra Mundial, y las guerras del coreano, de Vietnam, y del Golfo 
persa. Se invita a los estudiantes, los ciudadanos, y las 
organizaciones que contribuyan con el kit del proyecto, que 
proporciona a toda la información y forma necesario para 
entrevistarse con a un veterano. Las bibliotecas, los museos, y 
los grupos cívicos pueden leer sobre los proyectos modelo de los 
veteranos y comenzar un proyecto en su comunidad</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207056</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108585</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/veterans-history-project</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
