<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105561</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105561</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085541</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Black Solidarity Day</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Schwarzer Solidarität-Tag</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jour Noir de Solidarité</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Dia Preto Do Solidarity</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giorno Nero Di Solidarietà</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαύρη ημέρα αλληλεγγύης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Día Negro De la Solidaridad</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Black Solidarity Day 1972. Program addresses a variety of topics via a magazine-format presentation. Host John Slade introduces the following segments: 'Performance' with rock/jazz musicians Compost, 'Community Events' with Black Solidarity Day organizers Joseph Nkunta, Marie Firman, Karim Atiba Bayete, and Arnold Scott, 'Speak Out!' with Jack E. Robinson, President of the Boston Chapter of the NAACP (who talks about the need for adequate police protection in African American neighborhoods and a responsive police force), 'man on the street' interviews, in which Slade asks people whether or not they would like an African American officer to command their neighborhood's police district, a 'Save Our Cities Expo' review with Melvin Penn (a university student who interviews organizer Reverend Dr. Virgil Wood, Area Chairman of the Southern Christian Leadership Conference), and 'African Notes,' in which the building of the Volta Dam in Ghana is discussed. Program ushers in a new format that incorporates the interviews and expertise of community members. Produced by John Slade. Directed by Russell Tillman.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Schwarzer Solidarität-Tag 1972. Programm 
adressiert eine Vielzahl von Themen über eine Zeitschrift-Format 
Darstellung. Hauptrechner John Slade stellt die folgenden 
Segmente vor: ' Leistung ' mit rock/jazz Musiker Mischung, ' 
Gemeinschaftsfälle mit schwarzen solidarität-Tagesorganisatoren 
Joseph Nkunta, Marie Firman, Karim Atiba Bayete und Arnold Scott, ' 
sprechen heraus!' mit Jack E. Robinson, Präsident des Boston 
Kapitels des NAACP (wer mit der Notwendigkeit am ausreichenden 
Polizeischutz in den afrikanischen amerikanischen Nachbarschaften und 
in einer entgegenkommenden Polizeikraft sich befaßt), ' Mann auf der 
Straße ' interviewt, in der Slade Leute fragt, ob oder nicht sie 
möchten, daß ein afrikanischer amerikanischer Offizier Polizeibezirk
ihrer Nachbarschaft befiehlt, eine ' außer unserem Städteexpo ' 
Zusammenfassung mit Melvin Penn (ein Universitätskursteilnehmer, das 
Organisator Reverend Dr. Virgil Wood, Bereich Vorsitzender der 
südlichen christlichen Führung-Konferenz interviewt) und ' 
afrikanische Anmerkungen, ' in, welchem das Gebäude der Volta 
Verdammung in Ghana behandelt wird. Programmpförtner in einem 
neuen Format, das die Interviews und die Sachkenntnis der 
Gemeinschaftsbauteile enthält. Produziert durch John Slade. 
Verwiesen durch Russell Tillman.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jour Noir 1972 De Solidarité. Le programme 
adresse une variété de sujets par l'intermédiaire d'une 
présentation de magasin-format. Le centre serveur John 
Slade présente les segments suivants : l''exécution 'avec
le compost de musiciens de rock/jazz, des 'événements de la 
Communauté avec les organisateurs noirs Joseph Nkunta de jour de 
solidarité, Marie Firman, Karim Atiba Bayete, et Arnold 
Scott, 'parlent dehors!' avec Jack E. Robinson, président 
du chapitre de Boston du NAACP (qui parle du besoin de protection 
adéquate de police dans des voisinages américains africains et une 
force sensible de police), l''homme sur la rue 'interviewe, en 
laquelle Slade demande aux gens si elles voudraient que un 
officier américain africain commande la zone de la police de leur 
voisinage, une revue 'économiser notre Expo de villes 'avec 
Melvin Penn (un étudiant d'université qui interviewe Dr. Virgil 
Wood, Président de Révérend d'organisateur de zone de la 
conférence chrétienne méridionale de conduite), et 'les notes 
africaines, 'dans ce que le bâtiment du barrage de la Volte au Ghana 
est discuté. Huissiers de programme dans un nouveau format qui 
incorpore les entrevues et l'expertise de membre de la Communauté. 
Produit par John Slade. Dirigé par Russell Tillman.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Dia Preto 1972 Do Solidarity. O programa 
dirige-se a uma variedade dos tópicos através de uma apresentação 
do compartimento-formato. O anfitrião John Slade introduz os 
seguintes segmentos: ' o desempenho ' com compost dos músicos 
de rock/jazz, ' eventos da comunidade com os organizers pretos Joseph 
Nkunta do dia do solidarity, Marie Firman, Karim Atiba Bayete, e 
Arnold Scott, ' fala para fora!' com Jack E. Robinson, 
presidente do capítulo de Boston do NAACP (quem fala sobre a 
necessidade para a proteção adequada das polícias em vizinhanças 
americanas africanas e em uma força responsiva das polícias), ' o 
homem na rua ' entrevista, em que Slade pergunta a povos se ou não 
gostaria de um oficial americano africano de comandar o distrito das 
polícias da sua vizinhança, ' excepto uma revisão da nossa expo das
cidades ' com Melvin Penn (um estudante da universidade que entrevista
o Dr. Virgil Madeira de Reverend do organizer, presidente da área da 
conferência christian do sul da liderança), e ' notas africanas, ' 
em qual o edifício da represa de Volta em Ghana é discutido. 
Ushers do programa em um formato novo que incorpore as 
entrevistas e a perícia de membros de comunidade. Produzido por
John Slade. Dirigido por Russell Tillman.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giorno Nero 1972 Di Solidarietà. Il 
programma richiama una varietà di soggetti via una presentazione di 
scomparto-formato. Il calcolatore centrale John Slade introduce 
i seguenti segmenti: 'le prestazioni 'con la composta dei 
musicisti di rock/jazz, 'eventi della Comunità con gli 
organizzatori neri Joseph Nkunta di giorno di solidarietà, Marie 
Firman, Karim Atiba Bayete ed Arnold Scott, 'parlano fuori!' con
Jack E. Robinson, presidente del capitolo de Boston del NAACP (chi 
colloqui circa l'esigenza di protezione sufficiente della polizia 
in vicinanze americane africane ed in una forza sensible a reagire 
della polizia), 'l'uomo sulla via 'intervista, in cui Slade chiede 
alla gente se o non vorrebbero un ufficiale americano africano 
comandare il distretto della polizia della loro vicinanza, 'risparmi 
una revisione del nostro expo delle città 'con Melvin Penn (un 
allievo dell'università che intervista il Dott. Virgil Wood, 
presidente di Reverend dell'organizzatore di zona del congresso 
cristiano del sud di direzione) e 'note africane, 'in quale la 
costruzione della diga del Volta nel Ghana è discussa. Uscieri 
di programma in un nuovo formato che comprende le interviste e la 
perizia dei membri di Comunità. Prodotto da John Slade. 
Diretto da Russell Tillman.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαύρη αλληλεγγύη ημέρα 1972, διευθύνσεις 
προγράμματος ποικίλα θέματα μέσω μιας παρουσίασης 
περιοδικό-μορφής. Ο ξένιος χ/υ John Slade εισάγει τα 
ακόλουθα τμήματα μνήμης: "Η απόδοση" με το λίπασμα 
μουσικών βράχου/τζαζ, "κοινοτικά γεγονότα" με τους μαύρους 
διοργανωτές Joseph Nkunta, ημέρας αλληλεγγύης firman 
Marie, τον Karim Atiba Bayete, και Arnold Scott, 
"μιλά έξω!" με το Jack E. Robinson, Πρόεδρος του 
κεφαλαίου της Βοστώνης του NAACP (που μιλά για την ανάγκη για 
την επαρκή προστασία αστυνομίας στις αφρικανικές αμερικανικές 
γειτονιές και μια απαντητική αστυνομική δύναμη), "το άτομο στην 
οδό" παίρνει συνέντευξη από, στην οποία slade ρωτά τους 
ανθρώπους εάν θα επιθυμούσαν ή όχι έναν αφρικανικό αμερικανικό
ανώτερο υπάλληλο για να διατάξουν την περιοχή αστυνομίας της 
γειτονιάς τους, μια αναθεώρηση "εκτός από του EXPO πόλεών 
μασ" με Melvin Penn (ένας πανεπιστημιακός σπουδαστής που 
παίρνει συνέντευξη από το διοργανωτή Αιδεσιμότατος ο Δρ Virgil 
Wood, περιοχή πρόεδρος της νότιας χριστιανικής διάσκεψης 
ηγεσίας), και "αφρικανικές σημειώσεις," στο οποίο η οικοδόμηση 
του φράγματος Volta στην Γκάνα συζητείται. Ταξιθέτες 
προγράμματος με μια νέα μορφή που ενσωματώνει τις συνεντεύξεις 
και την πείρα των κοινοτικών μελών. Παραχθείς από John 
Slade. Κατευθυνμένος από το Russell Tillman.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Día Negro 1972 De la Solidaridad. El 
programa trata una variedad de asuntos vía una presentación del 
compartimiento-formato. El ordenador principal Juan Slade 
introduce los segmentos siguientes: el ' funcionamiento ' con 
estiércol vegetal de los músicos de rock/jazz, los ' acontecimientos
de la comunidad con los organizadores negros José Nkunta del día de 
la solidaridad, Marie Firman, Karim Atiba Bayete, y Arnold Scott, ' 
habla hacia fuera!' con Gato E. Robinson, presidente del 
capítulo de Boston del NAACP (quién habla de la necesidad de la 
protección adecuada del policía en vecindades americanas africanas y
una fuerza responsiva del policía), el ' hombre en la calle ' se 
entrevista con, en la cual Slade pregunta a gente si o no él quisiera
que un oficial americano africano ordenara el districto del policía 
de su vecindad, ' excepto una revisión de nuestra expo de las 
ciudades ' con Melvin Penn (estudiante de la universidad que se 
entreviste con a Dr. Virgil Wood, presidente de Reverend del 
organizador del área de la conferencia cristiana meridional de la 
dirección), y las ' notas africanas, ' en cuál se discute el 
edificio de la presa de Volta en Ghana. Ujieres del programa en 
un nuevo formato que incorpora las entrevistas y la maestría de los 
miembros de la Comunidad. Producido por Juan Slade. 
Dirigido por Russell Tillman.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085541</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105561</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/black-solidarity-day</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
