<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108673</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108673</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212941</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">US National Assessment of the Potential Consequences of Climate Variability and Change</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">US nationale Einschätzung der möglichen 
Konsequenzen der Klima-Veränderlichkeit und der Änderung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Évaluation nationale des USA des conséquences 
potentielles de la variabilité et du changement de climat</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Avaliação nacional dos E. U. das conseqüências
potenciais do variability e da mudança do clima</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Valutazione nazionale degli Stati Uniti delle 
conseguenze potenziali di variabilità e del cambiamento di clima</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αμερικανική εθνική αξιολόγηση των πιθανών συνεπειών 
της μεταβλητότητας και της αλλαγής κλίματος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Gravamen nacional de los E.E.U.U. de las 
consecuencias potenciales de la variabilidad y del cambio del clima</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The United States Global Change Research Program (USGCRP) was created as a high-priority national research program to: address key uncertainties about changes in the Earth's global environmental system, both natural and human-induced; monitor, understand, and predict global change; and provide a sound scientific basis for national and international decision-making. Some of the global change issues studied include: seasonal to inter-annual climate fluctuations, climate change over decades to centuries, stratospheric ozone depletion, UV radiation, and atmospheric chemistry. Another research subject is analysis of changes in land cover and in terrestrial and marine ecosystems. In addition to background on USGCRP this site contains a library of global change research documents and a listing of current or on-going research projects. Most of these papers are posted on-line in their entirety. One unique feature of this site is "Ask Doctor Global Change" by clicking on this service the user can browse a list of frequently asked global change questions or create one of their own. The answers are provided by global systems experts working at the Global Change Research Information Office. This resource is part of the Biocomplexity collection. http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Vereinigte Staaten globale Änderung Forschung
Programm (USGCRP) wurde als prioritäres nationales Forschung Programm
erstellt: adressieren Sie Schlüsselungewißheiten über 
Änderungen in der globalen Klima- und Heizungsanlage der Masse, 
natürlich und menschlich-verursacht; überwachen Sie, verstehen
Sie und sagen Sie globale Änderung voraus; und stellen Sie eine
stichhaltige wissenschaftliche Grundlage für nationale und 
internationale Beschlußfassung zur Verfügung. Einige der 
globalen studierten Änderung Ausgaben schließen ein: saisonal 
zu den Zwischen-jährlichen Klimafluktuationen, Klimaänderung zu den 
Überdekaden zu den Jahrhunderten, zur stratospheric Ozon-Entleerung, 
zur UVSTRAHLUNG und zur atmosphärischen Chemie. Ein anderes 
Forschung Thema ist Analyse der Änderungen in der Landabdeckung und 
in den terrestrischen und Marineoekosystemen. Zusätzlich zum 
Hintergrund auf USGCRP enthält diese Site eine Bibliothek der 
globalen Änderung Forschung Dokumente und Listen der aktuellen oder 
on-going Forschung Projekte. Die meisten diesen Papieren werden 
online in ihrer Ganzheit bekanntgegeben. Ein eindeutiges Merkmal
dieser Sites ist "fragen Doktor Global Change", indem es auf diesem 
Service klickt, den der Benutzer eine Liste der häufig gestellten 
globalen Änderung Fragen durchstöbern oder eins von ihren Selbst 
erstellen kann. Die Antworten werden von den globalen Systeme 
Experten zur Verfügung gestellt, die im globalen Änderung Forschung 
Informationsbüro arbeiten. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Teil der 
Biocomplexity Ansammlung http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le programme de recherche global de changement des
Etats-Unis (USGCRP) a été créé comme programme de recherche 
national prioritaire : adressez les incertitudes principales au 
sujet des changements du système environnemental global de la terre, 
normal et humain-induit ; surveillez, comprenez, et prévoyez le
changement global ; et fournissez une base scientifique solide 
pour la prise de décision nationale et internationale. 
Certaines des issues globales de changement étudiées incluent 
: saisonnier aux fluctuations inter-annuelles de climat, aux 
décennies finies de changement de climat aux siècles, à 
l'épuisement stratosphérique de l'ozone, au rayonnement UV, et à la
chimie atmosphérique. Un autre sujet de recherches est analyse 
des changements dans la couverture de terre et des écosystèmes 
terrestres et marins. En plus du fond sur USGCRP ce site 
contient une bibliothèque des documents globaux de recherches de 
changement et une liste des projets de recherche en cours ou en cours.
La plupart de ces articles sont signalées en ligne dans leur 
intégralité. Un seul dispositif de ce site est "demandent à 
docteur Global Change" en cliquant à ce service que 
l'utilisateur peut parcourir une liste de questions globales 
fréquemment posées de changement ou créer un de leurs propres. 
Les réponses sont fournies par les experts en matière globaux 
de systèmes travaillant au bureau global de l'information de 
recherches de changement. Cette ressource fait partie de la 
collection http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/ de Biocomplexity</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O programa de pesquisa global unido da mudança 
dos estados (USGCRP) foi criado como um programa de pesquisa nacional 
high-priority: dirija-se às incertezas chaves sobre mudanças 
no sistema ambiental global da terra,  natural e humano-induzido; 
monitore, compreenda, e prediga a mudança global; e 
forneça uma base científica sadia para a tomada de decisão nacional
e internacional. Algumas das edições globais da mudança 
estudadas incluem: seasonal às flutuações inter-anuais do 
clima, às décadas excedentes da mudança do clima aos séculos, ao 
depletion stratospheric do ozônio, à radiação UV, e ao chemistry 
atmosférico. Um outro assunto da pesquisa é análise das 
mudanças na tampa de terra e em ecosystems terrestrial e marinhos. 
Além ao fundo em USGCRP este local contem uma biblioteca de 
originais globais da pesquisa da mudança e uma lista de projetos de 
pesquisa atuais ou on-going. A maioria destes papéis são 
afixados em linha em sua totalidade. Uma característica 
original deste local é "pergunta a doutor Global Mudança" estalando 
neste serviço que o usuário pode browse uma lista de perguntas 
globais freqüentemente feitas da mudança ou criar um do seus 
próprios. As respostas são fornecidas pelos peritos globais 
dos sistemas que trabalham no escritório de informação global da 
pesquisa da mudança. Este recurso é parte da coleção 
http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/ de Biocomplexity</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Unito Dichiara il programma di ricerca 
globale del cambiamento (USGCRP) è stato creato come programma di 
ricerca nazionale prioritario: richiami le incertezze chiave 
circa i cambiamenti nel sistema ambientale globale della terra, sia 
naturale che umano-indotto; controlli, capisca e predica il 
cambiamento globale; e fornisca una solida base scientifica per 
risoluzione nazionale ed internazionale. Alcune delle edizioni 
globali del cambiamento studiate includono: stagionale alle 
fluttuazioni inter-annuali di clima, alle decadi eccessive del 
cambiamento di clima ai secoli, allo svuotamento stratosferico 
dell'ozono, alla radiazione UV ed alla chimica atmosferica. Un 
altro oggetto di ricerca è analisi dei cambiamenti nei tipi di 
terreno e negli ecosistemi terrestri e marini. Oltre che 
priorità bassa su USGCRP questo luogo contiene una libreria dei 
documenti globali di ricerca del cambiamento e un elenco dei progetti 
di ricerca in corso o on-going. La maggior parte di queste carte
sono inviate in linea nella loro interezza. Una caratteristica 
unica di questo luogo è "chiede al dottore Global Change" scattandosi
su questo servizio che l'utente può passare in rassegna una lista 
delle domande globali frequentemente fatte del cambiamento o creare 
uno dei loro propri. Le risposte sono fornite dagli esperti 
globali dei sistemi che lavorano all'ufficio di informazioni globale 
di ricerca del cambiamento. Questa risorsa fa parte 
dell'accumulazione http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/ di 
Biocomplexity</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το ερευνητικό πρόγραμμα Ηνωμένης σφαιρικό αλλαγής 
(USGCRP) δημιουργώ ως εθνικό ερευνητικό πρόγραμμα 
προτεραιότητας: να εξετάσει τις βασικές αβεβαιότητες για τις
αλλαγές στο γήινο σφαιρικό περιβαλλοντικό σύστημα, και φυσικό 
και ανθρώπινος-προκληθέν  να ελέγξει, να καταλάβει, και να 
προβλέψει τη σφαιρική αλλαγή  και παρέχετε μια υγιή 
επιστημονική βάση για την εθνική και διεθνή λήψη αποφάσεων. 
Μερικά από τα παγκόσμια ζητήματα αλλαγής που μελετώνται 
περιλαμβάνουν: εποχιακές έως διαχρονικές διακυμάνσεις 
κλίματος, αλλαγή κλίματος κατά τη διάρκεια των δεκαετιών στους 
αιώνες, στρατοσφαιρική μείωση όζοντος, UV ακτινοβολία, και 
ατμοσφαιρική χημεία. Ένα άλλο υποκείμενο έρευνας είναι 
ανάλυση των αλλαγών στην κάλυψη εδάφους και στα επίγεια και 
θαλάσσια οικοσυστήματα. Εκτός από το υπόβαθρο σε USGCRP 
αυτή η περιοχή περιέχει μια βιβλιοθήκη των σφαιρικών ερευνητικών
εγγράφων αλλαγής και μια λίστα των παρόντων ή τρεχόντων 
ερευνητικών προγραμμάτων. Τα περισσότερα από αυτά τα 
έγγραφα ταχυδρομούνται on-line στην ολότητά τους. Ένα 
μοναδικό χαρακτηριστικό γνώρισμα αυτής της περιοχής είναι "ρωτά
το γιατρό τη σφαιρική αλλαγή" με τον κρότο σε αυτήν την υπηρεσία
που ο χρήστης μπορεί να περιοδεύσει έναν κατάλογο συχνά 
σφαιρικών ερωτήσεων αλλαγής ή να δημιουργήσει ένα από το τους 
δικοί. Οι απαντήσεις δίνονται από τους σφαιρικούς 
εμπειρογνώμονες συστημάτων που εργάζονται στο σφαιρικό γραφείο 
ερευνητικών πληροφοριών αλλαγής. Αυτό το στοιχείο 
συμπεριφοράς είναι μέρος της Biocomplexity συλλογής 
http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El programa de investigación global del cambio de
Estados Unidos (USGCRP) fue creado como programa de investigación 
nacional prioritario: trate las incertidumbres dominantes sobre 
cambios en el sistema ambiental global de la tierra, natural y 
humano-inducido; vigile, entienda, y prediga el cambio global; 
y proporcione a una base científica sana para la toma de 
decisión nacional e internacional. Algunas de las ediciones 
globales del cambio estudiadas incluyen: estacional a las 
fluctuaciones inter-anuales del clima, a las décadas excesivas del 
cambio del clima a los siglos, al agotamiento estratosférico del 
ozono, a la radiación UV, y a la química atmosférica. Otro 
tema de la investigación es análisis de cambios en cubierta de pista
y en ecosistemas terrestres y marinas. Además de fondo en 
USGCRP este sitio contiene una biblioteca de los documentos globales 
de la investigación del cambio y un listado de los proyectos de 
investigación actuales o en curso. La mayoría de estos papeles
se fijan en línea en su totalidad. Una característica única 
de este sitio es "pregunta a doctor Global Change" haciendo clic en 
este servicio que el utilizador puede hojear una lista de preguntas 
globales con frecuencia hechas del cambio o crear uno sus el propios. 
Las respuestas son proporcionadas por los expertos globales de 
los sistemas que trabajan en la oficina de información global de la 
investigación del cambio. Este recurso es parte de la 
colección http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/ de Biocomplexity</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212941</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108673</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/us-national-assessment-of-the-potential-consequences-of-climate-variability-and-change</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
