<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104699</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104699</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209922</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Scalene triangle </string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Scalene Dreieck</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Triangle scalene</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Triângulo scalene</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Triangolo scalene</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σκαληνό τρίγωνο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Triángulo escaleno</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate the properties of scalene triangles. The applet presents a scalene triangle where any vertex can be dragged to reshape it. As it is dragged, the length of the sides and interior angles are continuously changed. If a change is made that causes two sides to be the same length, they are highlighted and the message 'not scalene' appears. The massages and measures can be turned off for class discussions. The text on the page has links to other pages defining each angle type in depth. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die die Eigenschaften der scalene Dreiecke zeigen. Der
applet stellt ein scalene Dreieck dar, in dem jeder möglicher Gipfel 
geschleppt werden kann, um ihn umzugestalten. Während er 
geschleppt wird, werden die Länge der Seiten und die Innerewinkel 
ununterbrochen geändert. Wenn eine Änderung vorgenommen wird, 
daß Ursachen zwei Seiten, zum die gleiche Länge zu sein, sie 
markiert werden und die Meldung ' nicht scalene ' erscheint. Die
Massagen und die Masse können für Kategorie Diskussionen abgestellt 
werden. Der Text auf der Seite hat Links zu anderen Seiten, die 
jeden eingehenden Winkeltypen definieren. Applet kann zum vollen
Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert
werden. Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf 
es von jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek 
ohne den benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel 
ist ein Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven 
Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent les propriétés des triangles scalene. L'applet
présente une triangle scalene où n'importe quel sommet peut être 
traîné pour le restructurer. Pendant qu'il est traîné, la 
longueur des côtés et des angles d'intérieur sont sans interruption
changés. Si un changement est fait que des causes deux côtés 
à être la même longueur, elles sont mises en valeur et le message 
'non scalene 'apparaît. Les massages et les mesures peuvent 
être arrêtés pour des discussions de classe. Le texte à la 
page a des liens à d'autres pages définissant chaque type d'angle 
détaillé. L'applet peut être agrandi à la taille de plein 
écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de classe. Le 
après utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant peut lui 
accéder encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la maison ou 
dans la bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion exigée. 
Cette ressource est un composant du projet interactif de manuel 
de la géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem as propriedades de triângulos scalene. O applet 
apresenta um triângulo scalene onde todo o vertex possa ser arrastado
para reshape o. Enquanto é arrastado, o comprimento dos lados e
os ângulos do interior estão mudados continuamente. Se uma 
mudança for feita que as causas dois lados a estar ao mesmo 
comprimento, elas estão destacadas e a mensagem ' nao scalene ' 
aparece. Os massages e as medidas podem ser desligados para 
discussões da classe. O texto na página tem as ligações a 
outras páginas que definem cada ângulo para datilografar dentro a 
profundidade. O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de tela 
cheia para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. O depois de 
uso na sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo o 
web browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma sessão
requerido. Este recurso é um componente do projeto interativo 
do textbook da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano le proprietà dei triangoli scalene. Il applet 
presenta un triangolo scalene in cui tutto il vertice può essere 
trascinato per rimodellarlo. Mentre è trascinato, la lunghezza 
dei lati e gli angoli dell'interiore sono cambiati continuamente. 
Se un cambiamento è fatto che le cause due lati da essere la 
stessa lunghezza, sono evidenziate ed il messaggio 'non scalene 
'compare. I massaggi e le misure possono essere spenti per le 
discussioni del codice categoria. Il testo alla pagina ha 
collegamenti ad altre pagine che definiscono ogni tipo di angolo 
approfondito. Il applet può essere ingrandito al formato di 
schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore dell'aula. La 
post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può accederle ancora da tutto 
il web browser nel paese o nella libreria senza l'inizio attività 
richiesto. Questa risorsa è un componente del progetto 
interattivo del manuale della geometria di riferimento aperto di per 
la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν τις ιδιότητες των σκαληνών τριγώνων. Το 
applet παρουσιάζει ένα σκαληνό τρίγωνο όπου οποιοδήποτε 
vertex μπορεί να σέρθεί για να το αναδιαμορφώσει. 
Δεδομένου ότι σέρνεται, το μήκος των πλευρών και οι 
εσωτερικές γωνίες αλλάζουν συνεχώς. Εάν μια αλλαγή 
γίνεται ότι αιτίες δύο πλευρές για να είναι το ίδιο μήκος, 
τονίζονται και το μήνυμα "μη σκαληνό" εμφανίζεται. Τα μασάζ
και τα μέτρα μπορούν να κλειθούν για τις συζητήσεις κλάσης. 
Το κείμενο στη σελίδα έχει τις συνδέσεις με άλλες σελίδες 
καθορίζοντας κάθε τύπο γωνίας σε βάθος. Το Applet 
μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με 
έναν προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο 
σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε 
ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια 
εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς 
είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος εγχειριδίων 
γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran las características de triángulos escalenos. El 
applet presenta un triángulo escaleno donde cualquier cima se puede 
arrastrar para restructurarlo. Mientras que se arrastra, la 
longitud de las caras y los ángulos del interior se cambian 
continuamente. Si se realiza un cambio que las causas dos caras 
a ser la misma longitud, ellas están destacadas y el mensaje ' no 
escaleno ' aparece. Los masajes y las medidas se pueden dar 
vuelta apagado para las discusiones de la clase. El texto en la 
paginación tiene conexiones a otras paginaciones que definen cada 
ángulo para pulsar adentro profundidad. El applet se puede 
agrandar a la talla de la pantalla completa para el uso con un 
proyector de la sala de clase. El uso posterior en la sala de 
clase, estudiante puede tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier web 
browser en el país o en la biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. 
Este recurso es un componente del proyecto interactivo del libro
de textos de la geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas
en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209922</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104699</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/scalene-triangle</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
