<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107661</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107661</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207174</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Race and Slavery Petitions Project</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Rennen-und Sklaverei-Petitionen Projekt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Projet de pétitions de course et d'esclavage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Projeto das petições da raça e do slavery</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Progetto di petizioni di slavery e della corsa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πρόγραμμα αιτήσεων φυλών και σκλαβιάς</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Proyecto de las peticiones de la raza y de la 
esclavitud</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">presents more than two dozen legislative and county court petitions that were filed in southern states between the American Revolution and the Civil War. Tens of thousands of southerners petitioned their legislatures for redress of grievances during this time. These petitions show the complex nature of race and slavery.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt sich mehr dar, als zwei Dutzend 
gesetzgebend und Amtsgerichtpetitionen, die in den südlichen 
Zuständen zwischen der amerikanischen Umdrehung und den 
Bürgerkrieg-10 von Tausenden southerners archiviert wurden, ihre 
Gesetzgebungen für Redress von Beschwerden während dieser Zeit 
ersuchten. Diese Petitionen zeigen die komplizierte Natur des 
Rennens und der Sklaverei.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">présente plus de deux douzaines législatives et 
pétitions de cour du comté qui ont été classées dans les états 
méridionaux entre la révolution américaine et les dizaines de 
guerre civile de milliers de habitants du sud ont pétitionné leurs 
législatures pour la réparation des réclamations pendant ce temps. 
Ces pétitions montrent la nature complexe de la course et de 
l'esclavage.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">apresenta-se mais de duas dúzias legislativas e 
as petições da corte de condado que foram arquivadas em estados do 
sul entre a volta americana e os dez da guerra civil dos milhares dos 
southerners peticionaram suas legislaturas para o redress das queixas 
durante este tempo. Estas petições mostram a natureza complexa
da raça e do slavery.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">si presenta più di due dozzine legislativi e le 
petizioni della corte della contea che sono state archiviate in del 
sud dichiarano fra la rivoluzione americana ed i dieci di guerra 
civile delle migliaia dei southerners hanno fatto una petizione le 
loro legislature per riparazione delle rimostranze durante questo 
tempo. Queste petizioni mostrano la natura complessa della corsa
e dello slavery.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρουσιάζει τις περισσότερη από δύο δωδεκάδα 
νομοθετικές και αιτήσεις δικαστηρίων νομών που αρχειοθετήθηκαν 
στα νότια κράτη μεταξύ της αμερικανικής επανάστασης και του 
εμφύλιου πολέμου. Οι δεκάδες χιλιάδων νότιοι υπέβαλαν 
αίτηση στα νομοθετικά σώματά τους για την επανόρθωση των 
διαμαρτυριών κατά τη διάρκεια αυτής της περιόδου. Αυτές οι
αιτήσεις εμφανίζουν σύνθετη φύση της φυλής και της σκλαβιάς.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">presenta más de dos docenas legislativas y las 
peticiones de la corte de condado que fueron clasifiadas en estados 
meridionales entre la revolución americana y los diez de la guerra 
civil de millares de southerners solicitó a sus legislaturas para la 
compensación de agravios durante este tiempo. Estas peticiones 
muestran la naturaleza compleja de la raza y de la esclavitud.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207174</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107661</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/race-and-slavery-petitions-project</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
