<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104863</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104863</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086357</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"It's a long John": Traditional African-American Work Songs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"es ist ein langer John": Traditionelle 
Afrikanisch-Amerikanische Arbeit Liede</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"c'est long John" : Chansons Afro-américaines 
Traditionnelles de Travail</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"é um John longo": Canções 
Africano-Americanas Tradicionais Do Trabalho</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"è un John lungo": Canzoni 
Africano-Americane Tradizionali Del Lavoro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Είναι μακρύς John": Παραδοσιακά 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικά τραγούδια εργασίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"es un Juan largo": Canciones 
Africano-Americanas Tradicionales Del Trabajo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Spirituals and work songs, rooted in both the slavery era and the West African societies from which most African-American slaves were originally taken, provided cultural sustenance to African Americans in the midst of intense racial oppression. They first came to be valued by northern white audiences in the late-19th century. Later, folklorists began collecting (and eventually recording) traditional southern music. John and Alan Lomax recorded southern musicians (African-American, white, and Mexican-American) for the Library of Congress. They recorded "Long John," a work song, sung by a man identified as "Lightning" and a group of his fellow black convicts at Darrington State Prison Farm in Texas in 1934. Black prisoners working in gangs to break rocks and clear swamps relied on the repeated rhythms and chants of work songs (originating in the forced gang labor of slavery) to set the pace for their collective labor. "Long John" mixed religious and secular concerns, including the notion of successful escape from bondage, a deeply felt desire of both slaves and prisoners.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Angelegenheiten- und Arbeitsliede, verwurzelt in 
der Sklavereiära und in den afrikanischen Westgesellschaften, von 
denen die meisten Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Sklaven ursprünglich 
genommen wurden, zur Verfügung gestelltes kulturelles sustenance zu 
den afrikanischen Amerikanern in der Mitte der intensiven rassischen 
Unterdrückung. Sie kamen zuerst, von den weißen Nordpublikum 
im des späten 19. jahrhunderts Jahrhundert bewertet zu werden. 
Später fingen Folkloristen, (und schließlich zu speichern an) 
traditionelle südliche Musik zu sammeln. John und Alan Lomax 
speicherten südliche Musiker (Afrikanisch-Amerikanisch, weiß und 
Mexikanisch-Amerikanisch) für die Bibliothek des Kongresses. 
Sie speicherten "langen John," ein Arbeit Lied, gesungen von 
einem Mann, der gekennzeichnet wurde, wie "Blitz" und eine Gruppe 
seines Mitschwarzen am Darrington Zustand-Gefängnis-Bauernhof in 
Texas 1934 überführt. Die schwarzen Gefangenen, die in den 
Gruppen arbeiten, um Felsen und freie Sümpfe zu brechen, bauten auf 
die wiederholten Rhythmen und singen von den Arbeit Lieden (entstehend
in der vorverlegten Gruppearbeit der Sklaverei) um den Schritt für 
ihre Kollektivarbeit einzustellen. "langer John" mischte frommes
und weltliche Interessen, einschließlich den Begriff des 
erfolgreichen Entweichens von der Knechtschaft, glaubten tief Wunsch 
der Sklaven und der Gefangenen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Chansons de chant religieux et de travail, 
enracinées dans l'ère d'esclavage et les sociétés africaines 
occidentales desquelles la plupart des esclaves afro-américains ont été
initialement pris, sustentation culturelle fournie aux Américains 
africains au milieu de l'oppression raciale intense. Ils sont 
venus la première fois pour être évalués par les assistances 
blanches nordiques en fin du 19me siècle. Plus tard, les 
folkloristes ont commencé à rassembler (et à l'enregistrer par la 
suite) la musique méridionale traditionnelle. John et 
Alan Lomax ont enregistré les musiciens méridionaux 
(Afro-Américain, blanc, et Mexicain-Américain) pour la bibliothèque du 
congrès. Ils ont enregistré "long John," une chanson de 
travail, chantée par un homme identifié comme la "foudre" et un 
groupe de son noir de camarade condamne à la ferme de prison d'état 
de Darrington dans le Texas en 1934. Les prisonniers noirs 
travaillant dans les troupes pour casser des roches et des marais 
clairs ont compté sur les rythmes répétés et chantent des chansons
de travail (provenant du travail obligatoire de troupe de l'esclavage)
pour placer le pas pour leur travail collectif. "long John" a 
mélangé religieux et les soucis séculaires, y compris la notion de 
l'évasion réussie du servage, ont profondément senti le désir des 
esclaves et des prisonniers.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Canções do espiritual e do trabalho, enraizadas
  na era do slavery e nas sociedades africanas ocidentais de que a 
maioria de escravos Africano-Americanos foram feitos exame 
originalmente, sustenance cultural fornecido aos americanos africanos 
no meio do oppression racial intenso. Vieram primeiramente ser 
avaliados por audiências brancas do norte no século late-19th. 
Mais tarde, os folklorists começaram a coletar (e eventualmente
a a gravar) a música do sul tradicional. John e Alan Lomax 
gravaram músicos do sul (Africano-Americano, branco, e 
Mexicano-Americano) para a biblioteca do congress. Gravaram 
"John longo," uma canção do trabalho, cantada por um homem 
identificado como o "relâmpago" e um grupo de seu preto do 
companheiro convicts na fazenda da prisão do estado de Darrington em 
Texas em 1934. Os prisioneiros pretos que trabalham nos grupos 
para quebrar rochas e swamps desobstruídos confiaram nos ritmos 
repetidos e chants das canções do trabalho (que originam no trabalho
forçado do grupo do slavery) para ajustar o ritmo para seu trabalho 
coletivo. "John longo" misturou religioso e os interesses 
secular, including a noção do escape bem sucedido do bondage, 
sentiram profundamente o desejo  de escravos e de prisioneiros.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Canzoni del lavoro e dello spiritual, sradicate 
sia nell'era di slavery che nelle società africane ad ovest da cui la
maggior parte dei schiavi Africano-Americani originalmente sono stati 
presi, sustenance culturale fornito al oppression razziale in mezzo a 
intenso africano degli Americani. In primo luogo sono venuto 
essere stimati dai pubblici bianchi nordici nel fine del 19esimo 
secolo. Più successivamente, i folklorists hanno cominciato a 
raccogliere (e finalmente a registrare) la musica del sud 
tradizionale. John ed Alan Lomax hanno registrato i musicisti 
del sud (Africano-Americano, bianco e messicano-american) per la 
libreria del congresso. Hanno registrato "John lungo," una 
canzone del lavoro, cantata dall'uomo identificato come "il lampo" e 
un gruppo del suo nero del collega condanna a Darrington 
Dichiarano il podere della prigione nel Texas in 1934. I 
prigionieri neri che lavorano nei gruppi per rompere le roccie e le 
paludi libere hanno contato sui ritmi ripetuti e chants delle canzoni 
del lavoro (che provengono dal lavoro forzato del gruppo di 
slavery) per regolare il passo per il loro lavoro collettivo. 
"John lungo" ha mescolato religioso e le preoccupazioni 
secolari, compreso la nozione della fuga riuscita da bondage, 
profondamente hanno ritenuto il desiderio sia degli schiavi che dei 
prigionieri.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τραγούδια Spirituals και εργασίας, που ριζοβολούν 
και στην εποχή σκλαβιάς και στις δυτικές αφρικανικές κοινωνίες 
από τις οποίες οι περισσότεροι αφρικανικός-αμερικανικοί σκλάβοι 
λήφθηκαν αρχικά, παρεχόμενο πολιτιστικό μέσο συντήρησης σε 
αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς στη μέση της έντονης φυλετικής κατοχής.
Ήρθαν αρχικά να εκτιμηθούν από τα βόρεια άσπρα ακροατήρια
στο late-19th αιώνα. Αργότερα, folklorists άρχισαν (και
τελικά) την παραδοσιακή νότια μουσική. Θ*Ιοχν και ο Alan 
Lomax κατέγραψαν τους νότιους μουσικούς 
(αφρικανικός-Αμερικανός, λευκό, και Μεξικανοαμερικάνος) για τη 
βιβλιοθήκη του συνεδρίου. Κατέγραψαν "μακρύ John," ένα 
τραγούδι εργασίας, τραγουδημένος από ένα άτομο που 
προσδιορίζεται ως "αστραπή" και ομάδα συντροφικού Μαύρου του 
καταδικάζει στο αγρόκτημα κρατικών Darrington φυλακών στο 
Τέξας σε 1934, μαύρους φυλακισμένους που εργάζονται στις 
συμμορίες για να σπάσει τους βράχους και τα σαφή έλη στηρίχθηκαν
στους επαναλαμβανόμενους ρυθμούς και τα άσματα των τραγουδιών 
εργασίας (που δημιουργούνται στην καταναγκαστική εργασία 
συμμοριών της σκλαβιάς) για να θέσουν το ρυθμό για τη συλλογική 
εργασία τους. "Μακρύς John" ανάμιξε τις θρησκευτικές και 
κοσμικές ανησυχίες, συμπεριλαμβανομένης της έννοιας της επιτυχούς
διαφυγής από τη δουλεία, μια βαθειά αισθητή επιθυμία και των 
σκλάβων και των φυλακισμένων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Canciones del espiritual y del trabajo, arraigadas
en la era y las sociedades africanas del oeste de las cuales la 
mayoría de los esclavos Africano-Americanos fueron tomados 
originalmente, sustenance cultural proporcionado de la esclavitud a 
los americanos africanos en el medio de la opresión racial intensa. 
Primero vinieron ser valorados por las audiencias blancas 
norteñas en el siglo de fines del siglo diecinueve. Más 
adelante, los folklorists comenzaron a recoger (y eventual a 
registrarla) música meridional tradicional. Juan y Alan Lomax 
registraron a músicos meridionales (Africano-Americano, blanco, y 
Mexicano-Americano) para la biblioteca del congreso. Registraron
a "Juan largo," una canción del trabajo, cantada por un hombre 
identificado como el "relámpago" y un grupo de su negro del 
compañero condena en la granja de la prisión del estado de 
Darrington en Tejas en 1934. Los presos negros que trabajaban en
cuadrillas para romper rocas y pantanos claros confiaron en los ritmos
relanzados y cantan de las canciones del trabajo (que originan en el 
trabajo forzado de la cuadrilla de la esclavitud) para fijar el paso 
para su trabajo colectivo. "Juan largo" mezcló religioso y las 
preocupaciones seculares, incluyendo la noción del escape acertado 
del bondage, sentían profundamente deseo de esclavos y de presos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086357</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104863</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/its-a-long-john-traditional-african-american-work-songs</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
