<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/24055</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>24055</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>Navet</catalog>
    <entry>skolverket_6127</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:spindeln.iml.umu.se:skolverket_6127</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>Navet</catalog>
            <entry>skolverket_6127</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">4.370 Interrogative Design Workshop, Fall 2005 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">4.370 Fragende Design-Werkstatt, Fall 2005 
(MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">4.370 Atelier Interrogatif de Conception, 
Automne 2005 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">4.370 Oficina Interrogativa Do Projeto, 
Queda 2005 (Mit)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">4.370 Gruppo di lavoro Interrogativo Di 
Disegno, Caduta 2005 (Mit)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">4.370 Ερωτηματικό εργαστήριο σχεδίου, πτώση του 
2005 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">4.370 Taller Interrogativo Del Diseño, 
Caída 2005 (Mit)</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An online course from the MIT OpenCourseWare website (http://ocw.mit.edu) operated by Massachusetts Institute of Technology. This course material is free for anyone to use who accept the terms and conditions of use. The description of this course, published on the MIT OpenCourseWare website, is: "This course is desiged in the tightly controlled space between (national) security and (civil) liberty, student projects, guest presentations, readings and workshop discussions will attempt to develop positive answers to these questions. More specifically, the course will focus on the psychological, economical and political conditions of those who are marginalized and therefore deprived of parrhesia today: the silent victims and witnesses of any kind of social and cultural exclusions.   Description from course home page:  "Parrhesia" was an Athenian right to frank and open speaking, the right that, like the First Amendment, demands a "fearless speaker" who must challenge political powers with criticism and unsolicited advice. Can designer and artist respond today to such a democratic call and demand? Is it possible to do so despite the (increasing) restrictions imposed on our liberties today? Can the designer or public artist operate as a proactive "parrhesiatic" agent and contribute to the protection, development and dissemination of "fearless speaking" in Public Space? "</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">aesthetic analyses</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Architecture</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">art history</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">performance and video</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">visual art practice</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">three-dimensional</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">personal space</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">field trips</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">long-range artistic development</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">phenomenology</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">installations</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">time-based media</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">studio practice</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">body</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Visual and Performing Arts  General</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">critical analysis</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">two-dimensional</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">installation</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">modern art</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">visiting artist presentations</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Onlinekurs von der MIT OpenCourseWare Web 
site (http://ocw.mit.edu) funktionierte durch Massachusetts Institute 
of Technology. Dieses Kursmaterial ist frei, damit jedermann 
verwendet, wem die Bedingungen des Gebrauches annehmen. Die 
Beschreibung dieses Kurses, veröffentlicht auf der MIT OpenCourseWare
Web site, ist: "dieser Kurs ist desiged im fest gesteuerten 
Platz zwischen (Staatsangehörig) Sicherheit und (Zivil) Freiheit, 
Kursteilnehmerprojekte, Gastdarstellungen, Messwerte und 
Werkstattdiskussionen versuchen, positive Antworten zu diesen Fragen 
zu entwickeln. Spezifischer, konzentriert der Kurs auf die 
psychologischen, ökonomischen und politischen Bedingungen von denen, 
die marginalized und folglich parrhesia heute beraubt werden: 
die leisen Opfer und die Zeugen irgendeiner Art Sozial- und 
kulturelle Ausschlüsse. Beschreibung vom Kurshome Page: 
"Parrhesia" war ein Athenianrecht gegenzuzeichnen und sprechend 
öffnen, das Recht, das, wie die erste Änderung, einen "furchtlosen 
Lautsprecher" verlangt, wer politische Energien mit Kritik und 
freiwilligem Rat herausfordern muß. Können Entwerfer und 
Künstler auf solch einen demokratischen Aufruf und Nachfrage heute 
reagieren? Ist zu tun möglich, also trotz der (zunehmenden) 
Beschränkungen, die heute unseren Freiheiten auferlegt werden? 
Kann der Entwerfer- oder Öffentlichkeitskünstler als 
proaktives "parrhesiatic" Mittel funktionieren und zum Schutz, zur 
Entwicklung und zur Datenübermittlung "des furchtlosen Sprechens" im 
allgemeinen Platz beitragen? "</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un cours en ligne du site Web de MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) a fonctionné par 
massachusetts.institute.of.technology. Ce matériel de cours est
libre pour que n'importe qui utilise qui reçoivent les modalités et 
les conditions de l'utilisation. La description de ce cours, 
éditée sur le site Web de MIT OpenCourseWare, est : "ce cours 
est desiged dans l'espace étroitement commandé entre la sécurité 
(de national) et liberté (civile), projets d'étudiant, 
présentations d'invité, lectures et les discussions d'atelier 
essayeront de développer des réponses positives à ces questions. 
Plus spécifiquement, le cours se concentrera sur les conditions
psychologiques, économiques et politiques de ceux qui sont 
marginalisés et privés donc du parrhesia aujourd'hui : les 
victimes et les témoins silencieux de tout genre d'exclusions 
sociales et culturelles. Description de Home Page de cours : 
"Parrhesia" était un droit d'Athénien de contresigner et 
ouvrir parlant, la droite qui, comme le premier amendement, exige "un 
haut-parleur courageux" qui doit défier des puissances politiques 
avec la critique et le conseil non sollicité. Le créateur 
et l'artiste peuvent-ils répondre aujourd'hui à un appel et à une 
demande si démocratiques ? Est-il possible de faire ainsi en 
dépit des restrictions (croissantes) imposées à nos libertés 
aujourd'hui ? L'artiste de créateur ou de public peut-il 
opérer comme agent "parrhesiatic" proactif et contribuer à la 
protection, au développement et à la diffusion "de parler courageux"
dans l'espace public ? "</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um curso em linha do Web site do MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) operou-se por Instituto de 
Tecnología de Massachusetts. Este material do curso está livre
para que qualquer um use-se quem aceitam os termos e as condições do
uso. A descrição deste curso, publicada no Web site do MIT 
OpenCourseWare, é: "este curso é desiged no espaço firmemente
controlado entre a segurança (do nacional) e liberdade (civil), 
projetos do estudante, apresentações do convidado, leituras e as 
discussões da oficina tentarão desenvolver respostas positivas a 
estas perguntas. Mais especificamente, o curso focalizará nas 
condições psicológicas, econômicas e políticas daqueles que são 
marginalizadas e privadas conseqüentemente do parrhesia hoje: 
as vítimas e as testemunhas silenciosas de algum tipo de 
exclusões sociais e cultural. Descrição do Home Page do 
curso: "Parrhesia" era uma direita do athenian franquear e para 
abrir falando, a direita que, como a primeira emenda, exige "um 
altofalante fearless" quem deve desafiar potências políticas com 
criticism e conselho unsolicited. Podem o desenhador e o artista
responder hoje a um atendimento e a uma demanda tão democráticos? 
É possível fazer assim que apesar das limitações 
(crescentes) impostas em nossas liberdades hoje? Pode o artista 
do desenhador ou do público operar-se como um agente "parrhesiatic" 
proactive e contribuir à proteção, ao desenvolvimento e à 
disseminação "do discurso fearless" no espaço público? "</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un corso in linea dal Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) ha funzionato da Massachusetts 
Institute of Technology. Questo materiale di corso è libero 
affinchè chiunque usi chi accettano i termini e le condizioni di uso.
La descrizione di questo corso, pubblicata sul Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare, è: "questo corso è desiged nello spazio 
strettamente gestito fra sicurezza (del cittadino) e libertà 
(civile), progetti dell'allievo, presentazioni dell'ospite, letture e 
le discussioni del workshop tenteranno di sviluppare le risposte 
positive a queste domande. Più specificamente, il corso 
metterà a fuoco sui termini psicologici, economici e politici di 
coloro che è marginato oggi e quindi è privato del parrhesia: 
le vittime ed i testimoni silenziosi di qualsiasi genere di 
esclusioni sociali e culturali. Descrizione dal Home Page di 
corso: "Parrhesia" era una destra del athenian spedire ed aprire
parlando, la destra che, come la prima correzione, richiede "un 
altoparlante impavido" chi deve sfidare le potenzi politiche con la 
critica ed il consiglio unsolicited. Possono il progettista e 
l'artista rispondere oggi a così chiamata e richiesta democratiche? 
È possibile da fare in modo da malgrado le limitazioni 
(aumentanti) imposte oggi alle nostre libertà? Può l'artista 
del pubblico o del progettista funzionare come agente "parrhesiatic" 
proactive e contribuire alla protezione, allo sviluppo ed alla 
diffusione "di parlare impavido" nello spazio pubblico? "</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια σε απευθείας σύνδεση σειρά μαθημάτων από τον 
ιστοχώρο MIT OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) που 
χρησιμοποιείται από το ίδρυμα της Μασαχουσέτης τεχνολογίας. 
Αυτό το υλικό σειράς μαθημάτων είναι ελεύθερο για καθένα 
να χρησιμοποιήσει ποιοι αποδέχονται τους όρους και τους όρους 
χρησιμοποίησης. Η περιγραφή αυτής της σειράς μαθημάτων, που
δημοσιεύεται στον ιστοχώρο MIT OpenCourseWare, είναι: 
"Αυτή η σειρά μαθημάτων είναι στο στενά ελεγχόμενο 
διάστημα μεταξύ (της εθνικής) ασφάλειας και (η αστική) 
ελευθερία, τα προγράμματα σπουδαστών, οι παρουσιάσεις 
φιλοξενουμένων, οι αναγνώσεις και οι συζητήσεις εργαστηρίων θα 
προσπαθήσουν να αναπτύξουν τις θετικές απαντήσεις σε αυτές τις 
ερωτήσεις. Πιό συγκεκριμένα, η σειρά μαθημάτων θα εστιάσει
στους ψυχολογικούς, οικονομικούς και πολιτικούς όρους εκείνοι που
περιθωριοποιούνται και επομένως στερούνται από το parrhesia 
σήμερα: τα σιωπηλοί θύματα και οι μάρτυρες οποιουδήποτε 
είδους κοινωνικών και πολιτιστικών αποκλεισμών. Περιγραφή 
από την αρχική σελίδα σειράς μαθημάτων: "Parrhesia" 
ήταν ένα αθηναϊκό δικαίωμα στην ειλικρινή και ανοικτή ομιλία, 
το δικαίωμα που, όπως την πρώτη τροποποίηση, απαιτεί έναν 
"άφοβο ομιλητή" ποιος πρέπει να προκαλέσει τις πολιτικές 
δυνάμεις με την κριτική και τις εκούσιες συμβουλές. Μπορούν
ο σχεδιαστής και ο καλλιτέχνης να ανταποκριθούν σήμερα σε μια 
τέτοιες δημοκρατικές κλήση και απαίτηση; Είναι δυνατό να 
κάνει έτσι παρά τους (αυξανόμενους) περιορισμούς που 
επιβάλλονται στις ελευθερίες μας σήμερα; Μπορεί ο 
σχεδιαστής ή ο δημόσιος καλλιτέχνης να λειτουργήσει ως δυναμικό 
"parrhesiatic" πράκτορα και να συμβάλει στην προστασία, την 
ανάπτυξη και τη διάδοση της "άφοβης ομιλίασ" στο δημόσιο χώρο; 
"</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un curso en línea del Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) funcionó por Instituto de 
Tecnología de Massachusetts. Este material del curso está 
libre para que cualquier persona utilice quiénes validan los 
términos y las condiciones del uso. La descripción de este 
curso, publicada en el Web site del MIT OpenCourseWare, es: 
"este curso es desiged en el espacio firmemente controlado entre
la seguridad (del nacional) y libertad (civil), proyectos del 
estudiante, presentaciones de la huésped, lecturas y las discusiones 
del taller procurarán desarrollar respuestas positivas a estas 
preguntas. Más específicamente, el curso se centrará en las 
condiciones psicologicas, económicas y políticas de los que estén 
marginadas y por lo tanto privadas de parrhesia hoy: las 
víctimas y los testigos silenciosos de cualquier clase de exclusiones
sociales y culturales. Descripción del Home Page del curso: 
"Parrhesia" un correcto del ateniense de franquear y abrir 
hablando, la derecha que, como la primera enmienda, exige un "altavoz 
audaz" quién debe desafiar potencias políticas con crítica y 
consejo no solicitado. ¿Pueden el diseñador y el artista 
responder hoy a una llamada y a una demanda tan democráticas? 
¿Es posible hacer así que a pesar de las restricciones (de 
aumento) impuestas ante nuestras libertades hoy? ¿Puede el 
artista del diseñador o del público funcionar como agente 
"parrhesiatic" proactive y contribuir a la protección, al desarrollo 
y a la difusión del "discurso audaz" en espacio público? "</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ästhetische Analysen</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Architektur</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">kunstgeschichte</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Leistung und Bildschirm</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sichtkunstpraxis</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">dreidimensional</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">persönlicher Platz</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">fangen Sie Reisen auf</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">weitreichende künstlerische Entwicklung</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">phenomenology</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Installationen</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zeit-gegründete Media</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Studiopraxis</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Körper</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sichtlich und die künste durchführend allgemein</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">kritische Analyse</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">zweidimensional</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Installation</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">moderne kunst</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Besuchskünstlerdarstellungen</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">analyses esthétiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Architecture</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">histoire d'art</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">exécution et vidéo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">pratique en matière visuelle d'art</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">tridimensionnel</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">l'espace personnel</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">voyages de zone</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">développement artistique à longue portée</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">phénoménologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">installations</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">medias temps-basés</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">pratique en matière de studio</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">corps</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Visuel et exécutant des arts généraux</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">analyse critique</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">bidimensionnel</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">installation</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">art moderne</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">présentations visitantes d'artiste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">análises aesthetic</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Arquitetura</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">history da arte</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">desempenho e vídeo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">prática visual da arte</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">tridimensional</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">espaço pessoal</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">desengates de campo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">desenvolvimento artístico de longo alcance</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">phenomenology</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">instalações</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">media tempo-baseados</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">prática do estúdio</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">corpo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Visual e executando as artes gerais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">análise crítica</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">bidimensional</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">instalação</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">arte moderna</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">apresentações visitando do artista</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">analisi estetiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Architettura</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">storia di arte</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">prestazioni e video</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">pratica visiva di arte</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">tridimensionale</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">spazio personale</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">viaggi di campo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">sviluppo artistico a lungo raggio</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">phenomenology</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">installazioni</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">media tempo-basati</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">pratica dell'studio</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">corpo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Visivo ed effettuando le arti generali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">analisi critica</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">bidimensionale</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">installazione</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">arte moderna</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">presentazioni di visita dell'artista</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">αισθητικές αναλύσεις</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αρχιτεκτονική</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ιστορία τέχνης</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">απόδοση και βίντεο</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">οπτική πρακτική τέχνης</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">τρισδιάστατος</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">προσωπικό διάστημα</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ταξίδια πεδίων</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">μεγάλης ακτίνας καλλιτεχνική ανάπτυξη</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">φαινομενολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εγκαταστάσεις</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χρόνος-βασισμένα στο μέσα</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">πρακτική στούντιο</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">σώμα</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εικαστηκές και τέχνες εκτέλεσης γενικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">κρίσιμη ανάλυση</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">δισδιάστατος</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εγκατάσταση</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">μοντέρνα τέχνη</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρουσιάσεις καλλιτεχνών επίσκεψης</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">análisis estéticos</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Configuración</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">historia del arte</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">funcionamiento y vídeo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">práctica visual del arte</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">tridimensional</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">espacio personal</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">disparos al campo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">desarrollo artístico de largo alcance</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">phenomenology</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">instalaciones</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">media tiempo-basados</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">práctica del estudio</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">cuerpo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Visual y realizando los artes generales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">análisis crítico</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">de dos dimensiones</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">instalación</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">arte moderno</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">presentaciones del artista que visitan</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Taawo;Alma
FN:Alma Taawo
ORG:skolverket
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>course</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>higher education</value>
          </context>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">18-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>85</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">architecture</string>
                <string language="sv">arkitektur</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:spindeln.iml.umu.se:skolverket_6127-M</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>Navet</catalog>
            <entry>skolverket_6127-M</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Taawo;Alma
FN:Alma Taawo
ORG:skolverket
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2009-03-15T19:42:33.0Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
N:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
ORG:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T06:12:05.08Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>Navet</catalog>
      <entry>skolverket_6127</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://ocw.mit.edu/OcwWeb/Architecture/4-370Fall-2005/CourseHome/index.htm</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
