<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82527</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82527</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>1756</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="it">Orologio di comunicazione</string>
            <string language="en">Talking clock</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sprechentaktgeber</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Horloge parlante</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Pulso de disparo falando</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ομιλούν ρολόι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Reloj que habla</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="it">Questo è un oggetto multimediale di apprendimento in forma di gioco ideato per insegnare le espressioni di tempo. Cliccando sul tasto Play, l'allievo ascolterà una clip audio corta con una espressione di tempo. L'allievo deve selezionare l'espressione di tempo dalla clip e cliccare sulla faccia dell'orologio, prima sulla lancetta delle ore e poi su quella dei minuti. Dopo che l'allievo ha cliccato sopra i punti corretti, l'orologio indicherà le ore corrette. Al tempo stesso, il programma darà le risposte anche in forma orale. Se lo studente fa un errore, sarà incoraggiato  a provare ancora e sentirà di nuovo l'espressione di tempo. Questo oggetto di apprendimento utilizza molte espressioni di tempo (ad esempio, “un quarto dopo”, “un quarto alle”, “venti minuti dopo”) e rinforza l'uso di queste espressioni standard in modo che diventino automatiche per l'allievo.</string>
            <string language="en">This is a game-like multimedia learning object designed for learning expressions of time.
By clicking on the Play button, the learner will hear a short audio clip which includes an expression of time.  The learner must pick out the expression of time from the clip and click on the face of the clock, first on the hour hand and then on the minute hand.  After the learner has clicked on the correct spots, the clock will indicate the correct times.  At the same time, the program gives feedback in spoken form.  If the learner makes a mistake, he/she will be encouraged to try again and will hear the expression of time again.  This learning object uses many expressions of time (e.g., “quarter past”, “quarter to”, “twenty past”) and reinforces the use of these standard expressions so that they become automatic for the learner.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses ist a Spiel-wie die Multimedia, welche die 
Nachricht erlernen, die für erlernenausdrücke von time.By bestimmt 
ist, das auf der Spieltaste, der Anfänger klickt, hört einen kurzen 
Audioclip, der einen Ausdruck der Zeit einschließt. Der 
Anfänger muß den Ausdruck der Zeit vom Clip auswählen und das 
Gesicht des Taktgebers, zuerst auf der Stunde Hand und dann auf der 
minuziösen Hand an klicken. Nachdem der Anfänger an die 
korrekten Punkte geklickt hat, zeigt der Taktgeber die korrekten 
Zeiten an. Gleichzeitig gibt das Programm Feedback in 
gesprochener Form. Wenn der Anfänger einen Fehler macht, wird 
he/she angeregt, noch einmal zu versuchen und den Ausdruck der Zeit 
wieder hört. Diese erlernennachricht verwendet viele Ausdrücke
der Zeit (z.B.?quarter hinter?, ?quarter zu?, ?twenty 
Vergangenheit?) und verstärkt den Gebrauch von diesen 
Standardausdrücken, damit sie für den Anfänger automatisch werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">C'est a jeu-comme des multimédia apprenant 
l'objet conçu pour des expressions d'étude de time.By 
cliquant sur le bouton de jeu, l'étudiant entendra un clip 
sonore court qui inclut une expression de temps. L'étudiant 
doit sélectionner l'expression du temps du clip et cliquer 
sur le visage de l'horloge, d'abord sur la main d'heure et puis sur la
main minutieuse. Après que l'étudiant ait cliqué sur
les taches correctes, l'horloge indiquera les temps corrects. En
même temps, le programme donne le feedback sous la forme parlée. 
Si l'étudiant fait une erreur, he/she sera encouragé à 
essayer encore et entendra l'expression du temps encore. Cet 
objet d'étude utilise beaucoup d'expressions du temps (par exemple, 
le ?quarter après ?, ?quarter à ?, passé ?twenty ?) 
et renforce l'utilisation de ces expressions standard de sorte 
qu'elles deviennent automatiques pour l'étudiant.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este é a jogo-como os multimedia que aprendem o 
objeto projetado para expressões de aprendizagem de time.By que 
estala na tecla do jogo, o learner ouvirá um grampo audio curto que 
inclua uma expressão do tempo. O learner deve escolher para 
fora da expressão do tempo do grampo e estalar sobre a cara do pulso 
de disparo, primeiramente na mão da hora e então na mão minuciosa. 
Depois que o learner estalou sobre os pontos corretos, o pulso 
de disparo indicará os tempos corretos. Ao mesmo tempo, o 
programa dá o feedback no formulário falado. Se o learner 
fizer um erro, he/she estará incentivado tentar outra vez e ouvirá a
expressão do tempo outra vez. Este objeto de aprendizagem usa 
muitas expressões do tempo (por exemplo, o?quarter após?, 
?quarter a?, passado?twenty?) e reforça o uso 
destas expressões padrão de modo que se tornem automática para o 
learner.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό είναι game-like πολυμέσα μαθαίνοντας το 
αντικείμενο που σχεδιάζεται για την εκμάθηση των εκφράσεων του 
χρόνου Με τον κρότο στο κουμπί παιχνιδιού, ο αρχάριος θα 
ακούσει έναν κοντό ηχητικό συνδετήρα που περιλαμβάνει μια 
έκφραση του χρόνου. Ο αρχάριος πρέπει να διαλέξει την 
έκφραση του χρόνου από το συνδετήρα και να χτυπήσει στο πρόσωπο 
του ρολογιού, πρώτα σε ετοιμότητα ώρας και έπειτα σε ετοιμότητα 
μικρό. Αφότου έχει χτυπήσει ο αρχάριος επιτόπου σωστά, το
ρολόι θα δείξει τους σωστούς χρόνους. Συγχρόνως, το 
πρόγραμμα δίνει την ανατροφοδότηση με προφορική μορφή. Εάν
ο αρχάριος κάνει ένα λάθος, θα ενθαρρυνθεί για να προσπαθήσει 
πάλι και θα ακούσει την έκφραση του χρόνου πάλι. Αυτό το 
αντικείμενο εκμάθησης χρησιμοποιεί πολλές εκφράσεις του χρόνου 
(π.χ., ?quarter από μπροστά;, ?quarter;, ?twenty παρελθόν;) και ενισχύει τη χρήση αυτών των 
πρότυπων εκφράσεων έτσι ώστε γίνονται αυτόματες για τον 
αρχάριο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ésta es a juego-como el objeto que aprende de las 
multimedias diseñado para las expresiones que aprenden de time.By que
hace clic en el botón del juego, el principiante oirá un clip audio 
corto que incluya una expresión del tiempo. El principiante 
debe seleccionar la expresión del tiempo del clip y hacer clic 
encendido la cara del reloj, primero en la mano de la hora y entonces 
en la mano minuciosa. Después de que el principiante haya hecho
clic encendido los puntos correctos, el reloj indicará los tiempos 
correctos. En el mismo tiempo, el programa da feedback en forma 
hablada. Si el principiante incurre en una equivocación, se 
animará que intente otra vez y oirá a he/she la expresión del 
tiempo otra vez. Este objeto que aprende utiliza muchas 
expresiones del tiempo (e.g., el?quarter más allá de?, 
?quarter a?, pasado?twenty?) y refuerza el uso de 
estas expresiones estándares de modo que lleguen a ser automáticas 
para el principiante.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>1756</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-01-26</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-21</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-21</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">9-13</string>
            <string language="en">9-13</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="it">Ripasso di espressioni di tempo; attività di comprensione orale</string>
            <string language="en">Reviewing expressions of time; listening comprehension.</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82527</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>audio/basic</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://resources.eun.org/demoportal/clock_eng.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
