<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82873</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82873</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>1537</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="fi">Comparison in action</string>
            <string language="en">Comparison in Action</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Vergleich in der Tätigkeit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Comparaison dans l'action</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Comparação na ação</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Confronto nell'azione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σύγκριση στην ενέργεια</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Comparación en la acción</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Aihion ideana on toiminnallinen vertailumuotojen harjoittelu. Tehtävässä on myös hieman pelimäisyyttä, sillä oppilaan tulee ratkaista tehtävä vihjeiden perusteella. 

Oppilaan tehtävänä on kuunnella, kun eri henkilöt kertovat itsestään napauttamalla heidän kuviaan. Oppilaan tulee sijoittaa henkilöt asteikolle (esim. youngest-oldest) kuulemansa mukaan. Kertomukset voi kuunnella niin monta kertaa kun tarpeen. Oppilas voi tarkistaa tehtävän napauttamalla Tarkista-painiketta. Oikein asetetut henkilöt kertovat tarinansa uudelleen ja heidän nimensä ilmestyvät näkyviin.</string>
            <string language="en">The idea of this task is to use activity learning to practice the comparison of adjectives. The task is built up like a game because the student has to solve the task with the help of the given hints. By clicking the pictures the student hears different people telling about themselves. The task of the student is to place the people on a scale (for example youngest-oldest) according to what he / she hears. The stories can be listened to as many times as it is necessary. The student can check the task by clicking the Check button. The persons that have been placed correctly will tell their stories again and their names will appear on the screen.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Idee dieser Aufgabe ist, das Aktivität Lernen
zu verwenden, den Vergleich von Adjektiven zu üben. Die Aufgabe
wird wie ein Spiel aufgebaut, weil der Kursteilnehmer die Aufgabe mit 
Hilfe der gegebenen Tips lösen muß. Indem er die Abbildungen 
anklickt, hört der Kursteilnehmer unterschiedliche Leute, über 
selbst zu erklären. Die Aufgabe des Kursteilnehmers ist, die 
Leute auf eine Skala zu plazieren (zum Beispiel jung-am ältesten) 
entsprechend, was er/sie hören. Die Geschichten können zu bis 
zu Malen gehört werden, es notwendig ist. Der Kursteilnehmer 
kann die Aufgabe überprüfen, indem er die Überprüfung Taste 
anklickt. Die Personen, die richtig erklären ihre Geschichten 
wieder plaziert worden sind und ihre Namen erscheinen auf dem 
Bildschirm.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'idée de ceci chargent est d'utiliser 
l'apprentissage actif pour pratiquer la comparaison des adjectifs. 
Le charger est accumulé comme un jeu parce que l'étudiant 
doit résoudre le charger avec l'aide des conseils donnés. 
En cliquant les images l'étudiant entend les personnes
différentes dire au sujet d'elles-mêmes. Le charger de 
l'étudiant doit placer le peuple sur une échelle (par exemple 
jeune-vieille) selon ce que lui/elle entend. Les histoires 
peuvent être écoutées autant de fois car il est nécessaire. 
L'étudiant peut contrôler le charger en cliquant 
le bouton de contrôle. Les personnes qui ont été placées 
correctement diront leurs histoires encore et leurs noms apparaîtront
sur l'écran.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A idéia desta tarefa é usar a aprendizagem de 
atividade praticar a comparação dos adjetivos. A tarefa é 
construída acima como um jogo porque o estudante tem que resolver a 
tarefa com a ajuda das sugestões dadas. Estalando os retratos o
estudante ouve povos diferentes dizer sobre se. A tarefa do 
estudante é colocar os povos em uma escala (para o exemplo novo-o 
mais velho) de acordo com o que/se ouve. As histórias podem ser
escutadas tantas como vezes porque é necessário. O estudante 
pode verificar a tarefa estalando a tecla da verificação. As 
pessoas que foram colocadas corretamente dirão suas histórias outra 
vez e seus nomes aparecerão na tela.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'idea di questa operazione è usare 
l'apprendimento attivo esercitarsi nel confronto degli aggettivi. 
L'operazione è sviluppata come un gioco perché l'allievo deve 
risolvere l'operazione con l'aiuto di dati suggerimenti. 
Scattando le immagini l'allievo sente la gente differente dire a
circa se stesso. L'operazione dell'allievo è di disporre la 
gente su una scala (per esempio giovane-più vecchia) secondo che cosa
lui/lei si sente. Le storia possono essere ascoltate altretante 
volte poichè è necessario. L'allievo può controllare 
l'operazione scattando il tasto del controllo. Le persone che 
sono state disposte correttamente diranno alle loro storia ancora ed i
loro nomi compariranno sullo schermo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ιδέα αυτής της στοιχειώδους εργασίας είναι να 
χρησιμοποιηθεί η εκμάθηση δραστηριότητας να ασκείται η σύγκριση 
των επιθέτων. Η στοιχειώδης εργασία ενισχύεται όπως ένα 
παιχνίδι επειδή ο σπουδαστής πρέπει να λύσει τη στοιχειώδη 
εργασία με τη βοήθεια των δεδομένων υπαινιγμών. Με τον 
κρότο των εικόνων ο σπουδαστής ακούει τους διαφορετικούς 
ανθρώπους για τους. Η στοιχειώδης εργασία του σπουδαστή 
είναι να τοποθετήσει τους ανθρώπους σε μια κλίμακα (παραδείγματος
χάριν νέος-την παλαιότερη) σύμφωνα με αυτό που ακούει. Οι 
ιστορίες μπορούν να ακουστούν τόσους χρόνους όσοι και είναι 
απαραίτητο. Ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να ελέγξει τη στοιχειώδη 
εργασία με τον κρότο του κουμπιού ελέγχου. Τα πρόσωπα που 
έχουν τοποθετηθεί σωστά θα πουν τις ιστορίες τους πάλι και τα 
ονόματά τους θα εμφανιστούν στην οθόνη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La idea de esta tarea es utilizar el aprendizaje 
activo practicar la comparación de adjetivos. La tarea se 
acumula como un juego porque el estudiante tiene que solucionar la 
tarea con la ayuda de las indirectas dadas. Haciendo clic los 
cuadros el estudiante oye a diversa gente el hablar de sí mismos. 
La tarea del estudiante es colocar a la gente en una escala (por
ejemplo joven-ma's vieja) según lo que él/ella oye. Las 
historias se pueden escuchar tantas veces pues es necesario. El 
estudiante puede controlar la tarea haciendo clic el botón del 
cheque. Las personas que se han puesto correctamente contarán 
sus historias otra vez y sus nombres aparecerán en la pantalla.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>1537</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2003-12-29</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-12</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-12</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>fi</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">10-14</string>
            <string language="fi">10-14</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Englannin kielen vertailumuotojen toiminnallinen harjoittelu</string>
            <string language="en">Activity learning to practice the comparison of the English adjectives</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">englannin kieli</string>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">kielet</string>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>718</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">oppiminen</string>
                <string language="en">learning</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82873</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>image/bmp</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://resources.eun.org/demoportal/comparisons_fi.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
