<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82526</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82526</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>1758</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="it">Confronto in azione</string>
            <string language="en">Comparison in action</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Vergleich in der Tätigkeit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Comparaison dans l'action</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Comparação na ação</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σύγκριση στην ενέργεια</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Comparación en la acción</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="it">L'idea centrale in questo oggetto di apprendimento  è di esercitarsi attivamente nei confronti. L'esercitazione inoltre ha l'aspetto di un gioco poichè l'allievo deve completare gli esercizi sulla base delle informazioni che sente. L'allievo deve cliccare sui personaggi dello schermo mentre ascolta le informazioni fornite durante la loro presentazione. Lo studente deve quindi disporre i personaggi in scala (per esempio, il più giovane-il più vecchio) sulla base di ciò che sente. L'allievo può ascoltare le descrizioni quante volte ne ha bisogno. Può controllare se l'esercitazione è completata correttamente o no cliccando sul tasto del controllo. Le descrizioni dei personaggi  che sono nei punti di destra saranno forniti di nuovo e i loro nomi compariranno sullo schermo. Quei personaggi che sono nei punti errati si libreranno verso la parte superiore dello schermo.</string>
            <string language="en">The central idea in this learning object is to actively practice comparisons.  The exercise also has a game-like aspect to it as the learner has to complete the exercises based on the information he/she hears.

The learner has to click on the characters on the screen and listen to while they are introduced and some information is given about them.  The learner then has to place the characters on a scale (e.g., youngest-oldest) based on what he/she hears.  The learner can listen to the descriptions as many times as he/she needs to.  He/she can check whether the exercise is correctly completed or not by clicking on the Check button.  The descriptions of the characters who are in the right spots will be given again and their names will appear on the screen.  Those characters that are in the wrong spots will float back to the top of the screen.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die zentrale Idee in dieser erlernennachricht ist,
Vergleiche aktiv zu üben. Die Übung hat auch a Spiel-wie 
Aspekt zu ihr, wie der Anfänger die Übungen durchführen muß, die 
auf dem Informationen he/she hears.The Anfänger basieren, muß die 
Zeichen auf dem Bildschirm an klicken und zu hören, während sie 
eingeführt werden und etwas Informationen über sie gegeben werden. 
Der Anfänger muß die Zeichen auf eine Skala (z.B., jung-am 
ältesten) dann plazieren basiert auf, was he/she hört. Der 
Anfänger kann zu den Beschreibungen hören bis zu Male, he/she 
benötigt. He/she kann überprüfen, ob die Übung richtig 
durchgeführt ist oder, nicht indem man auf der Überprüfung Taste 
klickt. Die Beschreibungen der Zeichen, die in den rechten 
Punkten werden gegeben wieder sind und ihrer Namen erscheinen auf dem 
Bildschirm. Jene Zeichen, die in den falschen Punkten sind, 
schwimmen zurück zu der Oberseite des Bildschirms.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'idée centrale dans cet objet d'étude est de 
pratiquer activement des comparaisons. L'exercice a également a
jeu-comme l'aspect à lui comme l'étudiant doit terminer les 
exercices basés sur l'étudiant de l'information he/she hears.The 
doit cliquer sur les caractères sur l'écran et écouter 
tandis qu'ils sont présentés et de l'information est fournie au 
sujet d'eux. L'étudiant alors doit placer les caractères sur 
une échelle (par exemple, jeune-vieux) basée sur ce que he/she 
entend. L'étudiant peut écouter les descriptions autant de 
fois pendant que he/she a besoin. He/she peut vérifier si 
l'exercice est correctement terminé ou pas en cliquant sur le
bouton de contrôle. Les descriptions des caractères qui sont 
dans les taches droites seront donnés encore et de leurs noms 
apparaîtront sur l'écran. Ces caractères qui sont dans les 
taches fausses flotteront de nouveau au dessus de l'écran.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A idéia central neste objeto de aprendizagem é 
praticar ativamente comparações. O exercício tem-lhe também 
a jogo-como o aspecto como o learner tem que terminar os exercícios 
baseados no learner da informação he/she hears.The tem que estalar 
sobre os caráteres na tela e escutar quando forem introduzidos e 
alguma informação está dada sobre eles. O learner então tem 
que colocar os caráteres em uma escala (por exemplo, novo-mais velho)
baseada em o que he/she se ouve. O learner pode escutar as 
descrições tantas como vezes enquanto he/she necessita. He/she
pode verificar se o exercício esteja terminado corretamente ou não 
estalando na tecla da verificação. As descrições dos 
caráteres que estão nos pontos direitos serão dados outra vez e de 
seus nomes aparecerão na tela. Aqueles caráteres que estão 
nos pontos errados flutuarão para trás ao alto da tela.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η κεντρική ιδέα σε αυτό το αντικείμενο εκμάθησης 
είναι ενεργά στις συγκρίσεις πρακτικής. Η άσκηση έχει 
επίσης μια game-like πτυχή σε το δεδομένου ότι ο αρχάριος 
πρέπει να ολοκληρώσει τις ασκήσεις βασισμένες στις πληροφορίες 
ακούει Ο αρχάριος πρέπει να χτυπήσει στους χαρακτήρες στην 
οθόνη και να ακούσει ενώ εισάγονται και κάποιες πληροφορίες 
δίνονται για τους. Ο αρχάριος πρέπει έπειτα να τοποθετήσει 
τους χαρακτήρες σε μια κλίμακα (π.χ., νέος-την παλαιότερη) 
βασισμένη σε αυτό που ακούει. Ο αρχάριος μπορεί να ακούσει
τις περιγραφές τόσοι χρόνοι όσοι και χρειάζεται. Μπορεί να
ελέγξει εάν η άσκηση ολοκληρώνεται σωστά ή όχι με τον κρότο 
στο κουμπί ελέγχου. Οι περιγραφές των χαρακτήρων που είναι 
στα σωστά σημεία θα δοθούν πάλι και τα ονόματά τους θα 
εμφανιστούν στην οθόνη. Εκείνοι οι χαρακτήρες που είναι στα
λανθασμένα σημεία θα επιπλεύσουν πίσω στην κορυφή της οθόνης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La idea central en este objeto que aprende es 
practicar activamente comparaciones. El ejercicio también tiene
a juego-como aspecto a él como el principiante tiene que terminar los
ejercicios basados en el principiante de la información he/she 
hears.The tiene que hacer clic encendido los caracteres en la pantalla
y escuchar mientras que se introducen y una cierta información se da 
sobre ellos. El principiante entonces tiene que poner los 
caracteres en una escala (e.g., joven-el ma's viejo) basada en lo que 
oye he/she. El principiante puede escuchar las descripciones 
tantas veces mientras que he/she necesita. He/she puede 
controlar si el ejercicio es terminado correctamente o no haciendo 
clic en el botón del cheque. Las descripciones de los 
caracteres que están en los puntos derechos serán dados otra vez y 
de sus nombres aparecerán en la pantalla. Esos caracteres que 
están en los puntos incorrectos flotarán de nuevo a la tapa de la 
pantalla.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>1758</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-01-26</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-21</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-21</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">10-15</string>
            <string language="en">10-15</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="it">Pratica di confronto in inglese</string>
            <string language="en">Practicing comparisons in English</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82526</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>audio/basic</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://resources.eun.org/demoportal/comparisons_eng.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
