<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82571</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82571</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>1560</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="fi">Puhelinvastaaja</string>
            <string language="en">Answering Machine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Antwortende Maschine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Répondeur</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Máquina Respondendo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Macchina Di Risposta</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτόματος τηλεφωνητής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Contestador Automático</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Oppilaan on löydettävä kuuntelemalla ja päättelemällä sopiva ajankohta kolmen henkilön tapaamiselle. Puhelinvastaajaan on jätetty viestejä, jotka oppilas voi kuunnella napauttamalla painikkeita. Viesteissä eri ihmiset kertovat, milloin heillä on menoja ja milloin kalenterissa olisi vapaata aikaa. Kuuntelemalla tarkasti oppilaan on pääteltävä, mikä annetuista viikonpäivistä ja kellonajoista on ainoa mahdollinen tapaamisajankohta. Kuullunymmärtämisen lisäksi on siis pystyttävä soveltamaan annettuja tietoja tehtävän ratkaisemiseksi.</string>
            <string language="en">The student has to find out a suitable time for a meeting of three people by listening and by using deduction. The messages left on the answering machine can be listened to by pressing the button. During the messages the people tell when they are engaged and when they are free. By listening very carefully the student has to decide which of the given days of the week and what time is the only suitable time for the meeting. In addition to listening comprehension the student has to be able to apply the given information in order to complete the task. 

</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Kursteilnehmer muß einen passenden Zeitpunkt 
für eine Sitzung von drei Leuten herausfinden, indem er hört und 
indem er Abzug verwendet. Die Meldungen verließen auf der 
antwortenden Maschine können zu, indem sie die Taste gehört werden 
betätigten. Während der Meldungen erklären die Leute, wann 
sie engagiert werden und wann sie frei sind. Indem hören sehr 
sorgfältig der Kursteilnehmer, muß entscheiden, welches der 
gegebenen Tage der Woche und welche Zeit der einzige passende 
Zeitpunkt für die Sitzung beträgt. Zusätzlich zu hörendem 
Erfassen muß der Kursteilnehmer können, die gegebenen Informationen 
anzuwenden, um die Aufgabe durchzuführen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'étudiant doit découvrir un temps approprié 
pour une réunion de trois personnes par l'écoute et en utilisant la 
déduction. Les messages sont partis sur le répondeur peuvent 
être écoutés par appuyer sur le bouton. Pendant les messages 
le peuple dit quand ils sont engagés et quand ils sont libres. 
En écoutant très soigneusement l'étudiant doit décider 
lesquels des jours indiqués de la semaine et quand est le seul moment
approprié pour la réunion. En plus de la compréhension 
d'écoute l'étudiant doit pouvoir appliquer l'information fournie 
afin de terminer le charger.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O estudante tem que encontrar para fora uma 
estadia apropriada para uma reunião de três povos escutando e usando
a dedução. As mensagens sairam na máquina respondendo podem 
ser escutadas pressionar a tecla. Durante as mensagens os povos 
dizem quando são acoplados e quando estão livres. Escutando 
muito com cuidado o estudante tem que decidir-se qual dos dias dados 
da semana e que hora é o único momento apropriado para a reunião. 
Além à compreensão escutando o estudante tem que poder  
aplicar a informação dada a fim terminar a tarefa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'allievo deve scoprire un periodo adatto per una 
riunione di tre genti ascoltando ed usando la deduzione. I 
messaggi hanno andato sulla macchina di risposta possono essere 
ascoltati premendo il tasto. Durante i messaggi la gente dice a 
quando sono agganciate ed a quando sono libere. Ascoltando 
l'allievo deve decidere molto con attenzione quale di dati giorni 
della settimana e quando è l'unico periodo adatto per la riunione. 
Oltre che la comprensione ascoltante l'allievo deve potere 
applicare le informazioni fornite per completare l'operazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο σπουδαστής πρέπει να ανακαλύψει έναν κατάλληλο 
χρόνο για μια συνεδρίαση τριών ανθρώπων με το άκουσμα και με τη 
χρησιμοποίηση της αφαίρεσης. Τα μηνύματα που αφήνονται στον 
αυτόματο τηλεφωνητή μπορούν να ακουστούν με την πίεση του 
κουμπιού. Κατά τη διάρκεια των μηνυμάτων οι άνθρωποι λένε 
πότε είναι δεσμευμένοι και πότε είναι ελεύθεροι. Από το 
άκουσμα πολύ προσεκτικά το σπουδαστή πρέπει να αποφασίσει 
όποιων των δεδομένων ημερών της εβδομάδας και τι ώρα είναι ο 
μόνος κατάλληλος χρόνος για τη συνεδρίαση. Εκτός από την 
κατανόηση ακούσματος ο σπουδαστής πρέπει να είναι σε θέση να 
εφαρμόσει τις δεδομένες πληροφορίες προκειμένου να ολοκληρωθεί η 
υποχρέωση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El estudiante tiene que descubrir un rato 
conveniente para una reunión de tres personas escuchando y usando la 
deducción. Los mensajes se fueron en el contestador automático
pueden ser escuchados presionando el botón. Durante los 
mensajes la gente dice cuándo la contratan y cuándo ella está 
libre. Escuchando el estudiante tiene que decidir muy 
cuidadosamente cuáles de los días dados de la semana y cuándo es la
única época conveniente para la reunión. Además de 
comprensión que escucha el estudiante tiene que poder aplicar la 
información dada para terminar la tarea.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>1560</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-01-12</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-12</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-12</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>fi</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">8-U</string>
            <string language="fi">&gt; 8</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Kuullunymmärtämisen harjoittelu, ajanilmausten harjoittelu, joukossa myös tyypillisiä puhelimessa käytettyjä ilmaisuja.</string>
            <string language="en">Practicing the listening comprehension, expressing time and the use of typical phrases used in telephone conversation</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">englannin kieli</string>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">kielet</string>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>710</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">kielten opetus</string>
                <string language="en">language teaching</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82571</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/puhelinvastaaja/co1_12.exe</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
