<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82403</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82403</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>1773</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="it">Snooker Di Frase</string>
            <string language="en">Sentence Snooker</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Programmsatzsnooker</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Billard de Phrase</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Snooker Da Sentença</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σνούκερ πρότασης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Snooker De la Sentencia</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="it">Lo scopo di questo oggetto per l'apprendimento  è proporre l'insegnamento delle strutture grammaticali tradizionali sotto forma di gioco. Le frasi semplici seguono solitamente lo stesso modello diretto. Questo tipo di strutture grammaticali devono tipicamente essere imparate a memoria, in modo che il principiante possa formarle automaticamente. Di conseguenza, le attività sotto forma di gioco sono particolarmente adatte all' esercitazione delle strutture grammaticali e all'ordine delle parole. Compito del principiante  è di formare le frasi organizzando le sfere sullo schermo in modo che ogni fila delle sfere formi una frase.Cliccando su una sfera, questa cadrà nella fila sottostante, o se non contiene una parola, sparirà. L'allievo deve pensare ad una strategia di gioco per cui egli possa formare quante più frasi sia possibile. Di conseguenza, non è sempre meglio cominciare dalla fila superiore; piuttosto, dovrebbe guardare tutte e cinque le file e pensare circa cinque frasi possibili allo stesso tempo e continuare da li. Ogni frase correttamente-formata sarà letta ad alta voce subito dopo che il principiante l'abbia formulata. Quando il principiante ha formato tutte le frasi o arriva ad un "punto morto” e non è possibile formare altre frasi, l'esercitazione è completata. Le sfere allora spariranno, il programma mostrerà  tutte le frasi correttamente formate ed il principiante le sentirà lette ad alta voce ancora una volta. Successivamente, il programma mostrerà il punteggio dello studente.</string>
            <string language="en">The aim of this learning object is to bring a game-like aspect to learning traditional grammatical structures.  Simple sentences usually follow the same, straightforward pattern.  These types of grammatical structures typically have to be learned by heart so that the learner is able to form them automatically.  Therefore, game-like activities are especially suitable for practicing grammatical structures and word order.

The learner’s task is to form sentences by arranging the balls on the screen so that each row of balls forms one sentence.  By clicking on a ball, it will drop into the row below it, or if it does not contain a word, it will disappear.  The learner has to think up a game strategy whereby he/she can make as many sentences as possible.  Therefore, it is not always best to start at the top row; rather, he/she should look at all five rows and think about five possible sentences at the same time and proceed from there.

Each correctly-formed sentence will be read aloud immediately after the learner has figured it out.  When the learner has formed all the sentences or come to a “dead-end” and it is not possible to form any more sentences, the exercise is completed.  The balls will then disappear, the program will show all the correctly formed sentences and the learner will hear them read aloud once more.  After this, the program will show the learner’s score.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Ziel dieser erlernennachricht ist, a Spiel-wie 
Aspekt zum Lernen der traditionellen grammatischen Strukturen zu 
holen. Einfache Programmsätze folgen normalerweise demselben, 
direktem Muster. Diese Typen der grammatischen Strukturen 
müssen auswendig gewöhnlich erlernt werden, damit der Anfänger 
kann, sie automatisch zu bilden. Folglich Spiel-wie Aktivitäten
seien Sie für das Üben der grammatischen Strukturen besonders 
verwendbar und Wort order.The learner?s Aufgabe ist, Programmsätze zu
bilden, indem sie die Kugeln auf dem Bildschirm ordnet, damit jede 
Reihe der Kugeln einen Programmsatz bildet. Indem es auf einer 
Kugel klickt, fällt sie in die Reihe unter sie, oder, wenn es nicht 
ein Wort enthält, verschwindet sie. Der Anfänger muß herauf 
eine Spielstrategie denken, hingegen he/she bis zu Programmsätze 
möglich bilden kann. Folglich ist es nicht immer am besten, an 
der oberen Reihe zu beginnen; eher sollte he/she alle fünf 
Reihen betrachten und ungefähr fünf mögliche Programmsätze 
gleichzeitig zu denken und von there.Each korrekt-gebildetem 
Programmsatz fortzufahren wird laut gelesen, sofort nachdem der 
Anfänger ihn heraus dargestellt hat. Wann hat der Anfänger 
alle Programmsätze gebildet oder zu einem?deadende gekommen? 
und es ist nicht möglich, keine Programmsätze zu bilden, die 
Übung wird durchgeführt. Die Kugeln verschwinden dann, stellt 
das Programm dar, daß alle richtig gebildeten Programmsätze und der 
Anfänger sie hört, laut noch einmal zu lesen. Nach diesem 
zeigt das Programm die learner?s Kerbe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le but de cet objet d'étude est d'apporter a 
jeu-comme l'aspect à apprendre les structures grammaticales 
traditionnelles. Les phrases simples suivent habituellement la 
même chose, configuration franche. Ces types de structures 
grammaticales typiquement doivent être appris par coeur de sorte que 
l'étudiant puisse les former automatiquement. Par conséquent, 
jeu-comme des activités soyez particulièrement approprié à 
pratiquer les structures grammaticales et les learner?s du mot 
order.The chargent doit former des phrases en arrangeant les 
boules sur l'écran de sorte que chaque ligne des boules forme une 
phrase. En cliquant sur une boule, elle relâchera dans 
la ligne au-dessous d'elle, ou s'il ne contient pas un mot, elle 
disparaîtra. L'étudiant doit penser vers le haut d'une 
stratégie de jeu par lequel he/she puisse faire autant de phrases 
comme possibles. Par conséquent, il n'est pas toujours le 
meilleur pour commencer à la ligne supérieure ; plutôt, 
he/she devrait regarder chacune des cinq lignes et penser environ cinq
phrases possibles en même temps et procéder à partir de la phrase 
correct-formée par there.Each sera lu à haute voix juste après que 
l'étudiant l'a figurée dehors. Quand l'étudiant a-t-il formé
toutes les phrases ou est-il venu à une ?dead-fin ? et il n'est
pas possible de former plus de phrases, l'exercice est terminé. 
Les boules disparaîtront alors, le programme montrera que 
toutes les phrases correctement formées et étudiant les entendra 
lire à haute voix une fois de plus. Après ceci, le programme 
montrera les points de learner?s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O alvo deste objeto de aprendizagem é trazer a 
jogo-como o aspecto a aprender estruturas gramaticais tradicionais. 
As sentenças simples seguem geralmente o mesmo, teste padrão 
direto. Estes tipos de estruturas gramaticais tipicamente têm 
que ser aprendidos pelo coração de modo que o learner possa  lhes 
dar forma automaticamente. Conseqüentemente, jogo-como 
atividades seja especial apropriado para praticar estruturas 
gramaticais e a tarefa dos learner?s da palavra order.The é dar forma
a sentenças arranjando as esferas na tela de modo que cada fileira 
das esferas dê forma a uma sentença. Estalando em uma esfera, 
deixará cair na fileira abaixo dela, ou se não contiver uma palavra,
desaparecerá. O learner tem que pensar acima de uma estratégia
do jogo por meio de que he/she pode fazer tantas como sentenças como 
possíveis. Conseqüentemente, não é sempre o mais melhor 
começar na fileira superior; rather, he/she deve olhar todas as
cinco fileiras e para pensar ao mesmo tempo de aproximadamente cinco 
sentenças possíveis e para proseguir da sentença correto-dada forma
there.Each estará lido alto imediatamente depois que o learner a 
figurou para fora. Quando o learner deu forma a todas as 
sentenças ou veio a uma?dead-extremidade? e não é possível 
dar forma a any.more sentenças, o exercício é terminado. As 
esferas desaparecerão então, o programa mostrará que todas as 
sentenças corretamente dadas forma e o learner os ouvirá ler alto 
uma vez mais. Após esta, o programa mostrará a contagem dos 
learner?s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο στόχος αυτού του αντικειμένου εκμάθησης είναι να 
παρουσιαστεί μια game-like πτυχή στην εκμάθηση των παραδοσιακών
γραμματικών δομών. Οι απλές προτάσεις ακολουθούν συνήθως 
το ίδιο, απλό πρότυπο. Αυτοί οι τύποι γραμματικών δομών 
πρέπει χαρακτηριστικά να μαθευτούν από την καρδιά έτσι ώστε ο 
αρχάριος είναι σε θέση να τους διαμορφώσει αυτόματα. 
Επομένως, οι game-like δραστηριότητες είναι ιδιαίτερα 
κατάλληλες για τις γραμματικές δομές και την κατάταξη λέξης 
Η στοιχειώδης εργασία learner?s είναι να διαμορφωθούν οι 
προτάσεις με την τακτοποίηση των σφαιρών στην οθόνη έτσι ώστε 
κάθε σειρά των σφαιρών διαμορφώνει μια πρόταση. Με τον 
κρότο σε μια σφαίρα, θα μειωθεί στη σειρά κάτω από τον, ή εάν 
δεν περιέχει μια λέξη, θα εξαφανιστεί. Ο αρχάριος πρέπει να
σκεφτεί επάνω μια στρατηγική παιχνιδιών με το οποίο μπορεί να 
κάνει όσο το δυνατόν περισσότερες προτάσεις. Επομένως, 
είναι όχι πάντα καλύτερο να αρχίσει στην κορυφαία σειρά  
μάλλον, πρέπει να εξετάσει και στις πέντε σειρές και να 
σκεφτεί για πέντε πιθανές προτάσεις συγχρόνως και να προχωρήσει 
από εκεί Κάθε σωστά-διαμορφωμένη πρόταση θα διαβαστεί 
μεγαλοφώνως αμέσως αφότου την έχει λογαριάσει ο αρχάριος έξω. 
Πότε ο αρχάριος έχει διαμορφώσει όλες τις προτάσεις ή 
έχει έρθει σε ένα?δεαδ-τέλος; και δεν είναι δυνατό να 
διαμορφωθούν άλλες προτάσεις, η άσκηση ολοκληρώνεται. Οι 
σφαίρες θα εξαφανιστούν έπειτα, το πρόγραμμα θα εμφανίσει όλες 
σωστά διαμορφωμένες προτάσεις και ο αρχάριος θα τις ακούσει που 
διαβάζονται μεγαλοφώνως ακόμα μια φορά. Μετά από αυτό, το
πρόγραμμα θα εμφανίσει αποτέλεσμα learner?s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La puntería de este objeto que aprende es traer a
juego-como aspecto a aprender las estructuras gramaticales 
tradicionales. Las sentencias simples siguen generalmente igual,
modelo directo. Estos tipos de estructuras gramaticales tienen 
que ser aprendidos típicamente de memoria de modo que el principiante
pueda formarlas automáticamente. Por lo tanto, juego-como 
actividades sea especialmente conveniente para practicar las 
estructuras gramaticales y la tarea de los learner?s de la palabra 
order.The es formar sentencias arreglando las bolas en la pantalla de 
modo que cada fila de bolas forme una sentencia. Haciendo clic 
en una bola, caerá en la fila debajo de ella, o si no contiene una 
palabra, desaparecerá. El principiante tiene que pensar encima 
de una estrategia del juego por el que he/she pueda hacer tantas 
sentencias como sea posible. Por lo tanto, no es siempre el 
mejor comenzar en la fila superior; algo, he/she debe mirar las 
cinco filas y pensar cerca de cinco sentencias posibles en el mismo 
tiempo y proceder de sentencia correcto-formada there.Each será 
leído en voz alta inmediatamente después que el principiante la ha 
calculado hacia fuera. ¿Cuándo el principiante ha formado todas
las sentencias o ha venido a un?dead-extremo? y no es posible 
formar más sentencias, el ejercicio se termina. Las bolas 
entonces desaparecerán, el programa mostrará que todas las 
sentencias correctamente formadas y el principiante las oirá leer en 
voz alta una vez más. Después de esto, el programa mostrará 
la cuenta de los learner?s.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>1773</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-01-27</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-11-05</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-11-05</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-11-05</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-11-05</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-11-05</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-11-05</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-11-05</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-11-05</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">10-15</string>
            <string language="en">10-15</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="it">Ripasso sulle strutture delle frasi inglesi e l'ordine delle parole</string>
            <string language="en">Review of basic English sentence structures and word order</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82403</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>image/bmp</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://resources.eun.org/demoportal/sentence_snooker_eng.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
