<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82436</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82436</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>1562</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="fi">Sentence Snooker</string>
            <string language="en">	Sentence Snooker</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">	Programmsatzsnooker</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">	Billard de Phrase</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">	Snooker Da Sentença</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">	Snooker Di Frase</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">	Σνούκερ πρότασης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">	Snooker De la Sentencia</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Tämän aihion tavoitteena on tuoda perinteisiin rakenneharjoituksiin pelimäisiä piirteitä. Melko helpot lauseenrakenteet noudattavat kaikki samaa, yksinkertaista kaavaa. Tyypillistä näille rakenteille on, että oppijan tulisi yltää niissä automatisoituneisiin suorituksiin, rakenteiden tulisi painua oppilaan selkärankaan. Näin ollen pelimäiset harjoitusmuodot ovat varsin sopivia rakenteiden ja sanajärjestyksen harjoitteluun.
Oppilaan tehtävänä on muodostaa lauseita järjestämällä ruudulla näkyviä pallorivistöjä niin, että yksi lause on aina yhdellä pallorivillä. Napauttamalla palloa se putoaa alemmalle riville tai jos se ei sisällä sanaa, se häviää. Oppilaan tulee miettiä toimintastrategia, jolla hän saa koottua mahdollisimman monta lauseista. Niinpä aina ei kannatakaan aloittaa ylimmältä riviltä, vaan pitää huomioida kaikki viisi lausetta samanaikaisesti ja toimia vasta sitten. 
Oikein muodostettu lause kuuluu puhuttuna heti, kun oppilas on saanut sen koottua. Kun oppilas on saanut kaikki lauseet muodostettua tai joutunut ”umpikujaan”, hän on tilanteessa jossa millään siirroilla ei enää synny lausetta, tehtävä on tehty. Pallot katoavat, ohjelma näyttää kaikki oikein muodostetut lauseet ja oppilas kuulee ne myös puhuttuna. Tämän jälkeen ohjelma näyttää oppilaan pistemäärän.</string>
            <string language="en">The aim of the task is to use a game in learning traditional grammar. Fairly easy sentence structures are all built up by using the same simple pattern. The idea is to make the student learn these so well that they become almost automatic. This type of task is very suitable for practising structures and word order. The task of the student is to make sentences by putting the balls seen on the screen in such an order that they build a sentence per line. By clicking on the ball it falls to the next line or if it doesn’t contain a word it disappears. The student should try to collect as many sentences as possible. So maybe it is not always advisable to start in the top line but to observe all five sentences at the same time and then act on them. The student hears the correct sentences as soon as he/she has built it. The task is completed when all the sentences have been built or the student has reached a dead end in which no new sentences can be built. The balls disappear, all the correct sentences are shown and the student will hear them. Finally, the score is shown.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Ziel der Aufgabe ist, ein Spiel zu benutzen, 
wenn es traditionelle Grammatik erlernt. Ziemlich einfache 
Programmsatzstrukturen werden alle aufgebaut, indem man das gleiche 
einfache Muster verwendet. Die Idee ist, den Kursteilnehmer 
diese erlernen zu lassen, die so wohl sind, daß sie fast automatisch 
werden. Dieser Typ der Aufgabe ist für übende Strukturen und 
Wortstellung sehr verwendbar. Die Aufgabe des Kursteilnehmers 
ist, Programmsätze zu bilden, indem sie die Kugeln setzt, die auf den
Bildschirm in solch eine Ordnung gesehen werden, daß sie einen 
Programmsatz pro Zeile aufbauen. Indem das Klicken auf der 
Kugel, die sie zur folgenden Zeile oder fällt, wenn sie doesn?t ein 
Wort enthält es, verschwindet. Der Kursteilnehmer sollte 
versuchen, bis zu Programmsätze möglich zu sammeln. So 
möglicherweise dann zu fungieren ist nicht immer ratsam, in der 
oberen Zeile zu beginnen aber alle fünf Programmsätze gleichzeitig 
zu beobachten und auf ihnen. Der Kursteilnehmer hört die 
korrekten Programmsätze, sobald he/she es aufgebaut hat. Die 
Aufgabe wird durchgeführt, wenn alle Programmsätze aufgebaut worden 
sind, oder der Kursteilnehmer eine Sackgasse erreicht hat, in der 
keine neuen Programmsätze aufgebaut werden können. Die Kugeln 
verschwinden, werden alle korrekten Programmsätze gezeigt und der 
Kursteilnehmer hört sie. Schließlich wird die Kerbe gezeigt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le but du charger est d'utiliser un jeu en 
apprenant la grammaire traditionnelle. Des structures de la 
phrase assez faciles toutes sont accumulées en utilisant la même 
configuration simple. L'idée est d'inciter l'étudiant à 
apprendre ces derniers si bons qu'elles deviennent presque 
automatiques. Ce type de chargent est très approprié 
aux structures et à l'ordre des mots de pratique. Le charger
de l'étudiant doit faire des phrases en mettant les boules vues sur 
l'écran dans une telle commande qu'elles établissent une phrase par 
la ligne. En cliquant sur la boule qu'elle tombe à la 
prochaine ligne ou si elle doesn?t contiennent un mot il disparaît. 
L'étudiant devrait essayer de rassembler autant de phrases 
comme possibles. Tellement peut-être il n'est pas toujours 
recommandé de commencer dans la ligne supérieure mais d'observer 
chacune des cinq phrases en même temps et d'agir alors sur elles. 
L'étudiant entend les phrases correctes dès que he/she le 
construira. Le charger est terminé quand toutes les phrases 
ont été établies ou l'étudiant a atteint une extrémité morte 
dans laquelle aucune nouvelle phrase ne peut être établie. Les
boules disparaissent, toutes les phrases correctes sont montrées et 
l'étudiant les entendra. En conclusion, les points sont 
montrés.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O alvo da tarefa é usar um jogo em aprender a 
gramática tradicional. As estruturas de sentença razoavelmente
fáceis todas são construídas acima usando o mesmo teste padrão 
simples. A idéia é fazer o estudante aprender estes assim bons
que se tornam quase automáticos. Este tipo de tarefa é muito 
apropriado para estruturas e a ordem de palavra praticando. A 
tarefa do estudante é fazer sentenças pondo as esferas vistas sobre 
a tela em tal ordem que constroem uma sentença por a linha. 
Estalando na esfera que cai à linha seguinte ou se doesn?t 
contiver uma palavra ele desaparece. O estudante deve tentar 
coletar tantas como sentenças como possíveis. Assim talvez 
não é sempre aconselhável começar na linha superior mas observar 
ao mesmo tempo todas as cinco sentenças e agir então nelas. O 
estudante ouve as sentenças corretas assim que he/she o construir. 
A tarefa está terminada quando todas as sentenças foram 
construídas ou o estudante alcançou uma extremidade inoperante em 
que nenhuma sentença nova pode ser construída. As esferas 
desaparecem, todas as sentenças corretas são mostradas e o estudante
ouvi-las-á. Finalmente, a contagem é mostrada.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lo scopo dell'operazione è usare un gioco 
nell'imparare la grammatica tradizionale. Le strutture di frase 
ragionevolmente facili tutte sono sviluppate usando lo stesso modello 
semplice. L'idea è incitare l'allievo ad imparare questi così 
buoni che diventano quasi automatiche. Questo tipo di operazione
è molto adatto a strutture e ad ordine delle parole esercitantesi. 
L'operazione dell'allievo è di fare le frasi mettendo le sfere 
viste sullo schermo in un tal ordine che sviluppano una frase per la 
riga. Scattandosi sulla sfera che cade alla riga seguente o se 
doesn?t contiene una parola esso sparisce. L'allievo dovrebbe 
provare a raccogliere altretante frasi come possibili. Così 
forse non è sempre consigliabile cominciare nella riga superiore ma 
osservare tutte e cinque le frasi allo stesso tempo ed allora 
comportarsi su loro. L'allievo sente le frasi corrette non 
appena he/she lo ha costruito. L'operazione è completata quando
tutte le frasi sono state sviluppate o l'allievo ha raggiunto 
un'estremità guasto in cui nessuna nuova frase può essere 
sviluppata. Le sfere spariscono, tutte le frasi corrette sono 
indicate e l'allievo le sentirà. Per concludere, il segno è 
indicato.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο στόχος της στοιχειώδους εργασίας είναι να 
χρησιμοποιηθεί ένα παιχνίδι στην εκμάθηση της παραδοσιακής 
γραμματικής. Οι αρκετά εύκολες δομές πρότασης όλες 
ενισχύονται με τη χρησιμοποίηση του ίδιου απλού προτύπου. Η
ιδέα είναι να γίνει ο σπουδαστής να μάθει αυτούς τόσο καλά 
ότι γίνονται σχεδόν αυτόματοι. Αυτός ο τύπος στοιχειώδους
εργασίας είναι πολύ κατάλληλος για τις δομές και τη σειρά των 
λέξεων. Η στοιχειώδης εργασία του σπουδαστή είναι να κάνει
τις προτάσεις με την τοποθέτηση των σφαιρών που βλέπουνε 
στην οθόνη σε μια τέτοια κατάταξη ότι χτίζουν μια πρόταση ανά 
γραμμή. Με τον κρότο στη σφαίρα πέφτει στην επόμενη γραμμή
ή εάν doesn?t περιέχει μια λέξη αυτό εξαφανίζεται. Ο 
σπουδαστής πρέπει να προσπαθήσει να συλλέξει όσο το δυνατόν 
περισσότερες προτάσεις. Έτσι ίσως είναι όχι πάντα 
ενδεδειγμένο να αρχίσει στην κορυφαία γραμμή αλλά να 
παρατηρηθούν και οι πέντε προτάσεις συγχρόνως και να ενεργήσει 
έπειτα σε τις. Ο σπουδαστής ακούει τις σωστές προτάσεις 
μόλις το χτίσει. Η υποχρέωση ολοκληρώνεται όταν χτιστούν 
όλες οι προτάσεις ή ο σπουδαστής έχει φθάσει σε ένα αδιέξοδο 
στο οποίο καμία νέα πρόταση δεν μπορεί να χτιστεί. Οι 
σφαίρες εξαφανίζονται, όλες οι σωστές προτάσεις εμφανίζονται και
ο σπουδαστής θα τις ακούσει. Τέλος, το αποτέλεσμα 
εμφανίζεται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La puntería de la tarea es utilizar un juego en 
aprender la gramática tradicional. Las estructuras de sentencia
bastante fáciles todas son acumuladas usando el mismo modelo simple. 
La idea es hacer que el estudiante aprende éstos tan bien que 
llegan a ser casi automáticos. Este tipo de tarea es muy 
conveniente para las estructuras y el orden de las palabras 
practicantes. La tarea del estudiante es hacer sentencias 
poniendo las bolas consideradas en la pantalla en tal orden que 
construyen una sentencia por línea. Haciendo clic en la bola 
que baja a la línea siguiente o si doesn?t contiene una palabra él 
desaparece. El estudiante debe intentar recoger tantas 
sentencias como sea posible. No es tan quizá siempre 
recomendable comenzar en la línea superior pero observar las cinco 
sentencias en el mismo tiempo y después actuar en ellas. El 
estudiante oye las sentencias correctas tan pronto como he/she lo haya
construido. Se termina la tarea cuando se han construido todas 
las sentencias o el estudiante ha alcanzado un callejón sin salida en
el cual ningunas nuevas sentencias pueden ser construidas. Las 
bolas desaparecen, se muestran todas las sentencias correctas y el 
estudiante las oirá. Finalmente, se muestra la cuenta.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>1562</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-01-12</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-15</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-15</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>fi</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">10-15</string>
            <string language="fi">10-15</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Englannin kielen peruslauserakenteiden ja sanajärjestyksen harjoittelu</string>
            <string language="en">Practicing the basic sentence structure and word order of English</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">englannin kieli</string>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">kielet</string>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>710</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">kielten opetus</string>
                <string language="en">language teaching</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82436</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/sentence_snooker/co1_14.exe</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
