<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82399</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82399</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>1753</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="it">Macchina Di Risposta</string>
            <string language="en">Answering Machine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Antwortende Maschine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Répondeur</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Máquina Respondendo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτόματος τηλεφωνητής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Contestador Automático</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="it">L'allievo deve ascoltare e scegliere un momento adatto per un incontro di tre persone. Tre messaggi sono stati lasciati sulla macchina di risposta che l'allievo può ascoltare cliccando sui tasti (1) (2) e (3). Nei messaggi, diverse persone dicono quando sono disponibili per un incontro e gli orari che non sono adatti a loro. Lo studente deve ascoltare con attenzione e decidere quale dei giorni suggeriti della settimana e quali orari sono l'unico momento possibile di incontro per tutti. Oltre all'attività di comprensione orale, lo studente deve applicare le informazioni fornite per completare l'esercitazione.</string>
            <string language="en">The learner has to listen and choose a suitable time for a meeting for three persons.  Three messages have been left on the answering machine which the learner can listen to by clicking on the buttons (1) (2) and (3).  In the messages, different people tell when they are available for a meeting and what times do not suit them.  The learner must listen carefully and decide which of the suggested days of the week and times is the only possible meeting time for all of them.  In addition to listening comprehension practice, the learner needs to apply the information given in order to complete the exercise.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Anfänger muß und einen passenden Zeitpunkt 
für eine Sitzung für drei Personen wählen hören. Drei 
Meldungen sind auf der antwortenden Maschine gelassen worden, die der 
Anfänger zu, indem er auf den Tasten hören kann (1) (2) und (3) 
klickt. In den Meldungen erklären unterschiedliche Leute, wann 
sie für eine Sitzung vorhanden sind und welche Zeiten ihnen nicht 
entsprechen. Der Anfänger muß sorgfältig hören und 
entscheiden, welches der vorgeschlagenen Tage der Woche und der Zeiten
die einzige mögliche Sitzung Zeit für alle ist. Zusätzlich zu
hörender Erfassenpraxis muß der Anfänger die Informationen 
anwenden, die gegeben werden, um die Übung durchzuführen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'étudiant doit écouter et choisir un temps 
approprié pour une réunion pour trois personnes. Trois 
messages ont été laissés sur le répondeur que l'étudiant peut 
écouter par cliquer sur les boutons (1) (2) et (3). 
Dans les messages, les personnes différentes disent quand elles
sont disponibles pour une réunion et quels temps ne leur conviennent 
pas. L'étudiant doit écouter soigneusement et décider 
lesquels des jours suggérés de la semaine et des temps sont le seul 
moment possible de réunion pour tous. En plus de la pratique en
matière d'écoute de compréhension, l'étudiant doit appliquer 
l'information fournie afin de terminer l'exercice.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O learner tem que escutar e escolher uma estadia 
apropriada para uma reunião para três pessoas. Três mensagens
foram deixadas na máquina respondendo que o learner pode escutar 
estalar nas teclas (1) (2) e (3). Nas mensagens, os povos 
diferentes dizem quando estão disponíveis para uma reunião e que 
tempos não as servem. O learner deve escutar com cuidado e 
decidir-se qual dos dias sugeridos da semana e dos tempos é o único 
momento possível da reunião para todo. Além à prática 
escutando da compreensão, o learner necessita aplicar a informação 
dada a fim terminar o exercício.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο αρχάριος πρέπει να ακούσει και να επιλέξει έναν 
κατάλληλο χρόνο για μια συνεδρίαση για τρία άτομα. Τρία 
μηνύματα έχουν αφεθεί στον αυτόματο τηλεφωνητή τον οποίο ο 
αρχάριος μπορεί να ακούσει με τον κρότο στα κουμπιά (1) (2) και 
(3). Στα μηνύματα, οι διαφορετικοί άνθρωποι λένε πότε 
είναι διαθέσιμοι για μια συνεδρίαση και ποιοι χρόνοι δεν τους 
ταιριάζουν. Ο αρχάριος πρέπει να ακούσει προσεκτικά και να 
αποφασίσει όποιος των προτεινόμενων ημερών της εβδομάδας και των 
χρόνων είναι ο μόνος πιθανός χρόνος συνεδρίασης για όλους τους.
Εκτός από την πρακτική κατανόησης ακούσματος, ο αρχάριος 
πρέπει να εφαρμόσει τις πληροφορίες που δίνονται προκειμένου να 
ολοκληρωθεί η άσκηση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El principiante tiene que escuchar y elegir un 
rato conveniente para una reunión para tres personas. Tres 
mensajes se han dejado en el contestador automático que el 
principiante puede escuchar haciendo clic en los botones (1) (2) y 
(3). En los mensajes, diversa gente dice cuándo ella está 
disponible para una reunión y qué tiempos no los satisfacen. 
El principiante debe escuchar cuidadosamente y decidir cuáles 
de los días sugeridos de la semana y de los tiempos son la única 
época posible de la reunión para todos. Además de práctica 
de la comprensión que escucha, el principiante necesita aplicar la 
información dada para terminar el ejercicio.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>1753</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-01-26</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-21</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-21</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">12-U</string>
            <string language="en">&gt; 12</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="it">Attività di comprensione orale; revisione di espressioni di tempo; incluso varie espressioni tipiche di conversazione telefonica.</string>
            <string language="en">Listening comprehension practice; reviewing expressions of time; includes various typical expressions used on the phone.</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82399</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/eng/english/answering_machine/co1_12.exe</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
