<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82624</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82624</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>4334</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="it">Passatempi</string>
            <string language="en">Hobbies</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Liebhabereien</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Passe-temps</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Passatempos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Χόμπι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Manías</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="it">Lo scopo di questo oggetto di apprendimento è di ripassare il lessico in un ambiente multimediale usando il linguaggio quotidiano. Il compito del discente è di riconoscere il vocabolario chiave che descrive le varie attività del tempo libero e collegarlo alle immagini che raffigurano queste attività. All'inizio dell'esercizio, l'alunno può vedere una serie di immagini sullo schermo che raffigurano le diverse attività del tempo libero svolte da giovani finlandesi ed anche varie nuvolette. L'alunno cliccando sulla nuvola ascolta la descrizione di un'attività ma il nome dell'attività non è menzionato. Il compit dell'alunno è di trascinare la nuvola sulla figura che descrive. Se l'alunno trova la figura corretta, la nuvola sparisce e l'alunno ascolta una dichiarazione affermativa. Inoltre, dopo ogni collegamento corretto, un box di riempimento apparirà sul monitor e conterrà una dichiarazione affermativa. L'alunno deve inserire la parola mancante. Questo obbliga il discente ad ascoltare attentamente il commento ricevuto ed a rinforzare il proprio vocabolario. Se una nuvoletta è trascinata nella figura sbagliata, tornerà indietro, in fondo allo schermo, dopo aver ricevuto un commento.</string>
            <string language="en">The aim of this learning object is to review vocabulary in a context-rich multimedia environment using everyday, authentic-sounding language.  The learner’s task is to recognize key vocabulary describing various leisure-time activities and connect them to the pictures that depict these activities.

At the beginning of the exercise, the learner can see a series of pictures on the screen, which depict various leisure-time activities done by Finnish young people as well as several speech bubbles.  When the learner clicks on the speech bubble, he/she will hear a description of an activity but the actual name of the activity is not mentioned.  The learner’s task is to drag the speech bubble onto the picture it is describing.  If the learner finds the right picture, the speech bubble disappears and the learner hears an affirming statement.  In addition, after each successful match, a gapfill box will appear on the screen containing the affirming statement.  The learner must type in the missing word(s).  This forces the learner to listen carefully to the feedback he/she receives and also reinforces the target vocabulary.  If a speech bubble is dragged to a wrong picture, it will float back to the bottom of the screen after a comment is given.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Ziel dieser erlernennachricht ist, Wortschatz 
in einem Kontext-reichen Multimediaumgebung Verwenden zu wiederholen 
täglich und authentisch-klingt Sprache. Die learner?s Aufgabe 
ist, den Schlüsselwortschatz zu erkennen, der verschiedene 
Freizeit-Zeit Aktivitäten beschreibt und sie an die Abbildungen 
anzuschließen, die diese activities.At der Anfang der Übung bildlich
darstellen, kann der Anfänger eine Reihe Abbildungen auf dem 
Bildschirm sehen, die die verschiedenen Freizeit-Zeit Aktivitäten 
bildlich darstellen, die Finnish von den jungen Leuten sowie einige 
Redeluftblasen erfolgt sind. Wenn der Anfänger an die 
Redeluftblase klickt, hört he/she eine Beschreibung einer Aktivität,
aber der tatsächliche Name der Aktivität wird nicht erwähnt. 
Die learner?s Aufgabe ist, die Redeluftblase auf die Abbildung 
zu schleppen, die sie beschreibt. Wenn der Anfänger die rechte 
Abbildung findet, verschwindet die Redeluftblase und der Anfänger 
hört eine bestätigende Anweisung. Zusätzlich nach jeder 
erfolgreichen Übereinstimmung, erscheint ein gapfill Kasten auf dem 
Bildschirm, der die bestätigende Anweisung enthält. Der 
Anfänger muß die fehlenden Wörter eintippen. Dieses erzwingt 
den Anfänger, zum Feedback he/she sorgfältig zu hören empfängt und
verstärkt auch den Zielwortschatz. Wenn eine Redeluftblase zu 
einer falschen Abbildung geschleppt wird, schwimmt sie zurück zu dem 
unteren Bildschirmrand, nachdem ein Kommentar gegeben ist.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le but de cet objet d'étude est de passer en 
revue le vocabulaire dans une utilisation contexte-riche 
d'environnement de multimédia journalière, authentique-retentissant 
le langage. Les learner?s chargent doit identifier le 
vocabulaire principal décrivant de diverses activités de 
loisir-temps et les relier aux images qui dépeignent ces 
activities.At le début de l'exercice, l'étudiant peut voir une 
série d'images sur l'écran, qui dépeignent de diverses activités 
de loisir-temps faites par les jeunes de Finnish aussi bien que 
plusieurs bulles de la parole. Quand l'étudiant 
clique sur la bulle de la parole, he/she entendra une 
description d'une activité mais le nom réel de l'activité n'est pas
mentionné. Les learner?s chargent doit traîner la 
bulle de la parole sur l'image qu'elle décrit. Si l'étudiant 
trouve la bonne image, la bulle de la parole disparaît et l'étudiant
entend un rapport d'affirmation. En outre, après chaque 
allumette réussie, un cadre de gapfill apparaîtra sur l'écran 
contenant le rapport d'affirmation. L'étudiant doit saisir les 
mots manquants. Ceci force l'étudiant à écouter soigneusement
le feedback he/she reçoit et renforce également le vocabulaire de 
cible. Si une bulle de la parole est traînée à une image 
fausse, elle flottera de nouveau au bas de l'écran après qu'un 
commentaire soit donné.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O alvo deste objeto de aprendizagem é rever o 
vocabulário em usar-se contexto-rico do ambiente dos multimedia 
diário, authentic-soando a língua. A tarefa dos learner?s é 
reconhecer o vocabulário chave que descreve várias atividades do 
lazer-tempo e para conectá-las aos retratos que descrevem estes 
activities.At o começo do exercício, o learner pode ver uma série 
dos retratos na tela, que descrevem as várias atividades do 
lazer-tempo feitas por povos novos de Finnish as.well.as diversas 
bolhas do discurso. Quando o learner estala sobre a bolha do 
discurso, he/she ouvirá uma descrição de uma atividade mas o nome 
real da atividade não é mencionado. A tarefa dos learner?s é 
arrastar a bolha do discurso no retrato que está descrevendo. 
Se o learner encontrar o retrato direito, a bolha do discurso 
desaparece e o learner ouve uma indicação de afirmação. 
Além, após cada fósforo bem sucedido, uma caixa do gapfill 
aparecerá na tela que contem a indicação de afirmação. O 
learner deve datilografar dentro as palavras faltantes. Isto 
força o learner a escutar com cuidado o feedback he/she recebe e 
reforça também o vocabulário do alvo. Se uma bolha do 
discurso for arrastada a um retrato errado, flutuará para trás ao 
fundo da tela depois que um comentário é dado.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο στόχος αυτού του αντικειμένου εκμάθησης είναι να 
αναθεωρηθεί το λεξιλόγιο σε ένα πλαίσιο-πλούσιο περιβάλλον 
πολυμέσων που χρησιμοποιεί καθημερινά, αυθεντικός-που ηχεί τη 
γλώσσα. Η στοιχειώδης εργασία learner?s είναι να 
αναγνωριστεί το βασικό λεξιλόγιο περιγράφοντας τις διάφορες 
δραστηριότητες ελεύθερου χρόνου και να συνδεθούν με τις εικόνες 
που απεικονίζουν αυτές τις δραστηριότητες Στην αρχή της 
άσκησης, ο αρχάριος μπορεί να δει μια σειρά εικόνων 
στην οθόνη, οι οποίες απεικονίζουν τις διάφορες δραστηριότητες 
ελεύθερου χρόνου που γίνονται από τους φινλανδικούς νέους καθώς
επίσης και διάφορες λεκτικές φυσαλίδες. Όταν ο αρχάριος 
χτυπά στη λεκτική φυσαλίδα, θα ακούσει μια περιγραφή μιας 
δραστηριότητας αλλά το πραγματικό όνομα της δραστηριότητας δεν 
αναφέρεται. Η στοιχειώδης εργασία learner?s είναι να 
σέρθεί η λεκτική φυσαλίδα επάνω στην εικόνα που περιγράφει. 
Εάν ο αρχάριος βρίσκει τη σωστή εικόνα, η λεκτική 
φυσαλίδα εξαφανίζεται και ο αρχάριος ακούει μια δήλωση 
επιβεβαίωσης. Επιπλέον, μετά από κάθε επιτυχή 
αντιστοιχία, ένα κιβώτιο gapfill θα εμφανιστεί στην οθόνη που 
περιέχει τη δήλωση επιβεβαίωσης. Ο αρχάριος πρέπει να 
δακτυλογραφήσει την ελλείπουσα λέξη (σ). Αυτό αναγκάζει τον
αρχάριο για να ακούσει προσεκτικά την ανατροφοδότηση που λαμβάνει
και ενισχύει επίσης το λεξιλόγιο στόχων. Εάν μια λεκτική 
φυσαλίδα σέρνεται σε μια λανθασμένη εικόνα, θα επιπλεύσει πίσω 
στο κατώτατο σημείο της οθόνης αφότου δίνεται ένα σχόλιο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La puntería de este objeto que aprende es repasar 
vocabulario al usar contexto-rico del ambiente de las multimedias 
diario, aute'ntico-sonando lenguaje. La tarea de los learner?s 
es reconocer el vocabulario dominante que describe varias actividades 
del ocio-tiempo y conectarlas con los cuadros que representan estos 
activities.At el principio del ejercicio, el principiante puede ver 
una serie de cuadros en la pantalla, que representan las varias 
actividades del ocio-tiempo hechas por la gente joven Finnish así 
como varias burbujas del discurso. Cuando el principiante hace 
clic encendido la burbuja del discurso, he/she oirá una descripción 
de una actividad pero el nombre real de la actividad no se menciona. 
La tarea de los learner?s es arrastrar la burbuja del discurso 
sobre el cuadro que está describiendo. Si el principiante 
encuentra el cuadro derecho, la burbuja del discurso desaparece y el 
principiante oye una declaración de afirmación. Además, 
después de cada emparejamiento acertado, un rectángulo del gapfill 
aparecerá en la pantalla que contiene la declaración de afirmación.
El principiante debe pulsar adentro las palabras que falta. 
Esto fuerza a principiante escuchar cuidadosamente el feedback 
he/she recibe y también refuerza el vocabulario de la blanco. 
Si una burbuja del discurso se arrastra a un cuadro incorrecto, 
flotará de nuevo al fondo de la pantalla después de que se dé un 
comentario.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>4334</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-02-27</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Congedo;Fiorenza;;;
FN:Fiorenza Congedo
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-28</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Congedo;Fiorenza;;;
FN:Fiorenza Congedo
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-28</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Congedo;Fiorenza;;;
FN:Fiorenza Congedo
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-28</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Congedo;Fiorenza;;;
FN:Fiorenza Congedo
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-28</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>other</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">12-U</string>
            <string language="en">&gt; 12</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>712</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">Latin</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82624</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>audio/basic</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://resources.eun.org/demoportal/hobbies_eng.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
