<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82385</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82385</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>4506</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="it">Numeri - il gioco dei numeri</string>
            <string language="en">Numbers - the game on numbers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zahlen - das Spiel auf Zahlen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Nombres - le jeu sur des nombres</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Números - o jogo em números</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αριθμοί - το παιχνίδι στους αριθμούς</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Números - el juego en números</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="it">
Questo oggetto di apprendimento permette il ripasso dei numeri in un modo nuovo, simile al gioco. L’esercizio consiste di cinque fasi: il computer sceglie cinque numeri a caso da ripassare. Questo esercizio è utile per insegnare all’alunno a fare un collegamento tra la forma scritta dei numeri e come sono pronunciati. Il compito dell’alunno è  di ascoltare e riconoscere i numeri. Ci sono cinque barre sul fondo dello schermo; quando l’alunno cliccherà sulla barra sentirà un numero. L’alunno deve trascinare, in ordine consecutivo, i due numeri che seguono il numero già sullo schermo. Lo scopo è di formare una continuità di tre numeri. Il programma riconosce automaticamente un numero corretto e lo inserisce in uno spazio. Se l’alunno commette un errore, il programma va alla fase successiva.</string>
            <string language="en">The learning object reviews numbers in a new, game-like way.  There are five steps in the exercises; the computer chooses different numbers at random to be practiced.  This exercise helps to teach the learner to make a connection between the written form of the number and how it is pronounced.  

The learner’s task is to listen to numbers and recognize them.  There are five bars at the bottom of the screen; when the learner clicks on a bar, he/she will hear a number.  The learner has to drag the two numbers that follow the one already on the screen into consecutive order.  The aim is to form a three-number continuum.  The program atuomatically recognizes a correct number and locks it into place.  If the learner makes a mistake, the program goes on to the next step.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die erlernennachricht wiederholt Zahlen in einem 
neuem, Spiel-wie Methode. Es gibt fünf Jobsteps in den 
Übungen; der Computer wählt die unterschiedlichen geübt zu 
werden Zahlen, zufällig. Diese Übung hilft, den Anfänger zu 
unterrichten, eine Beziehung zwischen dem schriftlichen Formular der 
Zahl herzustellen und wie sie ausgeprägt ist. Die learner?s 
Aufgabe ist, zu den Zahlen zu hören und sie zu erkennen. Es 
gibt fünf Stäbe am unteren Bildschirmrand; wenn der Anfänger 
an einen Stab klickt, hört he/she eine Zahl. Der Anfänger muß
die zwei Zahlen schleppen, die dem bereits auf dem Bildschirm in 
nachfolgende Ordnung folgen. Das Ziel ist, ein Dreizahl 
Kontinuum zu bilden. Das Programm erkennt atuomatically eine 
korrekte Zahl und Verriegelungen es in Platz. Wenn der Anfänger
einen Fehler macht, geht das Programm zum folgenden Jobstep weiter.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'objet d'étude passe en revue des nombres dans 
un nouveau, jeu-comme la voie. Il y a cinq étapes dans les 
exercices ; l'ordinateur choisit différents nombres au hasard 
à pratiquer. Cet exercice aide à enseigner l'étudiant à 
établir un rapport entre la forme écrite du nombre et comment il est
prononcé. Les learner?s chargent doit écouter des 
nombres et les identifier. Il y a cinq barres au bas de l'écran
; quand l'étudiant clique sur une barre, he/she 
entendra un nombre. L'étudiant doit traîner les deux nombres 
qui suivent celui déjà sur l'écran dans la commande consécutive. 
Le but est de former un continuum de trois-nombre. Le 
programme identifie atuomatically un nombre correct et des serrures il
dans l'endroit. Si l'étudiant fait une erreur, le programme 
passe en fonction à la prochaine étape.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O objeto de aprendizagem revê números em um 
novo, jogo-como a maneira. Há cinco etapas nos exercícios; 
o computador escolhe números diferentes em aleatório a ser 
praticado. Este exercício ajuda ensinar o learner fazer uma 
conexão entre o formulário escrito do número e como é pronunciado.
A tarefa dos learner?s é escutar números e reconhecê-los. 
Há cinco barras no fundo da tela; quando o learner estala
sobre uma barra, he/she ouvirá um número. O learner tem que 
arrastar os dois números que seguem esse já na tela na ordem 
consecutiva. O alvo é dar forma a um continuum do 
três-número. O programa reconhece atuomatically um número 
correto e fechamentos ele no lugar. Se o learner fizer um erro, 
o programa passa sobre à etapa seguinte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το αντικείμενο εκμάθησης αναθεωρεί τους αριθμούς με 
έναν νέο, game-like τρόπο. Υπάρχουν πέντε βήματα στις 
ασκήσεις  ο υπολογιστής επιλέγει τους διαφορετικούς 
αριθμούς τυχαία που ασκούνται. Αυτή η άσκηση βοηθά να 
διδάξει τον αρχάριο για να κάνει μια σύνδεση μεταξύ της γραπτής 
μορφής του αριθμού και πώς προφέρεται. Η στοιχειώδης 
εργασία learner?s είναι να ακούσει τους αριθμούς και να 
αναγνωριστούν. Υπάρχουν πέντε ράβδοι στο κατώτατο σημείο 
της οθόνης  όταν ο αρχάριος χτυπά σε μια ράβδο, θα ακούσει
έναν αριθμό. Ο αρχάριος πρέπει να σέρει τους δύο αριθμούς
που ακολουθούν αυτού ήδη στην οθόνη στη διαδοχική κατάταξη. 
Ο στόχος είναι να διαμορφωθεί μια συνέχεια τρεις-αριθμού. 
Το πρόγραμμα αναγνωρίζει atuomatically έναν σωστό αριθμό
και τον κλειδώνει στη θέση. Εάν ο αρχάριος κάνει ένα 
λάθος, το πρόγραμμα πηγαίνει προς το επόμενο βήμα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El objeto que aprende repasa números en un nuevo,
juego-como manera. Hay cinco pasos de progresión en los 
ejercicios; el ordenador elige diversos números al azar que se 
practicarán. Este ejercicio ayuda a enseñar al principiante a 
hacer una conexión entre la forma escrita del número y cómo es 
pronunciado. La tarea de los learner?s es escuchar los números 
y reconocerlos. Hay cinco barras en el fondo de la pantalla; 
cuando el principiante hace clic encendido una barra, he/she 
oirá un número. El principiante tiene que arrastrar los dos 
números que siguen el ya en la pantalla en orden consecutiva. 
La puntería es formar una serie continua del tres-nu'mero. 
El programa atuomatically reconoce un número correcto y los 
bloqueos él en lugar. Si el principiante incurre en una 
equivocación, el programa continúa al paso de progresión siguiente.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>4506</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-03-09</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Congedo;Fiorenza;;;
FN:Fiorenza Congedo
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-14</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Congedo;Fiorenza;;;
FN:Fiorenza Congedo
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-14</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">9-13</string>
            <string language="en">9-13</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="it">Esercitarsi coi numeri in inglese; fare un collegamento tra le forme scritte e orali</string>
            <string language="en">Practicing numbers in English; making a connection between written and spoken forms</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>712</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">Latin</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82385</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>audio/basic</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://resources.eun.org/demoportal/numbers_eng.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
