<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/210728398</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>210728398</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>4335</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="it">Passeggiata virtuale a Londra</string>
            <string language="en">Virtual walk in London</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Virtueller Weg in London</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Promenade virtuelle à Londres</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Caminhada virtual em Londres</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εικονικός περίπατος στο Λονδίνο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Caminata virtual en Londres</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="it">Questo oggetto di apprendimento dimostra come un ambiente dinamico puo' essere creato utilizzando immagini digitali al fine di imparare come chiedere e fornire indicazioni. All'inizio dell'esercizio, l'alunno si trova al cancello del British Museum; da lì, dovrebbe essere in grado di raggiungere il 
mercato di Covent Garden, seguendo le incazioni che gli vengono fornite. Per tutto il tempo, l'alunno vedrà sullo schermo la stessa veduta che vedrebbe qualcuno che camminasse realmente lungo la 
strada. L'alunno deve andare nella direzione  che gli viene detta ad ogni incrocio che raggiunge. Ci sono frecce che indicano diverse direzioni sullo schermo e, clicando su di esse, l'alunno puo' dirigersi verso 
la direzione finale. Allo stesso tempo, la guida turistica offre informazioni culturali riguardanti diversi posti, palazzi, ecc, lungo la strada. All'alunno viene anche chiesto di cliccare su alcuni posti lungo il 
cammino (es. segnali, palazzi) che lo costringono a notare i dintorni. Il programma commenterà ogni cambiamento di direzione sbagliato e se l'alunno si perderà lo rimanderà all'inizio.</string>
            <string language="en">This learning object demonstrates how a dynamic environment can be created using digital pictures in order to learn how to ask for and give directions.
At the beginning of the exercise, the learner is standing at the gate of the British Museum; from here, he/she should be able to get to the Covent Garden Market by following the directions that he/she is given.  The entire time, the learner will see the same view on the screen that someone really walking along the route would see.  The learner has to go in the direction he/she is told to at each crossroads that he/she comes to.  There are arrows pointing in different directions on the screen and, by clicking on them, the learner can direct him/herself toward the final destination.  At the same time, the tour guide gives British cultural information about various places, buildings, etc. along the way.  The learner is also asked to click on some sites along the way (e.g., signs, buildings) which forces him/her to notice the surroundings.  The program will comment on any possible wrong turns and, if the learner gets lost, it will send him/her back to the beginning.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zeigt diese erlernennachricht, wie eine dynamische 
Umgebung mit digitalen Abbildungen erstellt werden kann, um zu 
erlernen, wie man bittet um und directions.At den Anfang der Übung zu
geben, der Anfänger am Gatter des britischen Museums steht; von
hier sollte he/she können, an den Covent Garten-Markt zu gelangen, 
indem es den Richtungen folgt, daß he/she gegeben wird. Die 
gesamte Zeit, sieht der Anfänger die gleiche Ansicht über den 
Bildschirm, den jemand, der wirklich entlang den Weg geht, sehen 
würde. Der Anfänger muß in die Richtung he/she gehen wird 
erklärt zu an jeder Querstraße, der he/she zu kommt. Es gibt 
die Pfeile, die in unterschiedliche Richtungen auf den Bildschirm 
zeigen und, indem er auf ihnen klickt, kann der Anfänger him/herself 
in Richtung zur abschließenden Zieleinheit verweisen. 
Gleichzeitig gibt die Touranleitung britische kulturelle 
Informationen über verschiedene Plätze, Gebäude, etc. entlang der 
Methode. Der Anfänger wird auch gebeten, einige Sites entlang 
der Methode (z.B., Zeichen, Gebäude) an zu klicken welche Kräfte 
him/her, die Umlagerungen zu beachten. Das Programm kommentiert 
alle möglichen falschen Umdrehungen und, wenn der Anfänger verloren 
erhält, sendet es him/her zurück zu dem Anfang.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cet objet d'étude démontre comment un 
environnement dynamique peut être créé en utilisant les images 
digitales afin d'apprendre comment demander et donner à directions.At
le début de l'exercice, l'étudiant se tient à la porte du musée 
britannique ; d'ici, he/she devrait pouvoir obtenir au marché 
de jardin de Covent en suivant les directions que he/she est donné. 
Le temps entier, l'étudiant verra la même vue sur l'écran que
quelqu'un marchant vraiment le long de l'itinéraire verrait. On
dit l'étudiant doit aller dans la direction he/she à à chaque 
carrefour au lequel he/she vient. Il y a des flèches se 
dirigeant dans différentes directions sur l'écran et, en 
cliquant sur elles, l'étudiant peut diriger him/herself vers 
la destination finale. En même temps, le guide d'excursion 
fournit des informations culturelles britanniques sur de divers 
endroits, bâtiments, etc. le long de la voie. L'étudiant est 
également invité à cliquer sur quelques sites le long de 
la voie (par exemple, signes, bâtiments) quelles forces him/her de 
noter les environnements. Le programme présentera ses 
observations sur tous les tours faux possibles et, si l'étudiant se 
perd, il enverra him/her de nouveau au début.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este objeto de aprendizagem demonstra como um 
ambiente dinâmico pode ser criado usando retratos digitais a fim 
aprender como pedir e para dar a directions.At o começo do 
exercício, o learner está estando na porta do museu britânico; 
de aqui, he/she deve poder  começar ao mercado do jardim de 
Covent seguindo os sentidos que he/she está dado. O tempo 
inteiro, o learner verá a mesma vista na tela que alguém que anda 
realmente ao longo da rota veria. O learner tem que ir no 
sentido he/she é dito em cada crossroads a que he/she vem. Há 
setas que apontam em sentidos diferentes na tela e, estalando neles, o
learner pode dirigir him/herself para o destino final. Ao mesmo 
tempo, a guia de excursão dá a informação cultural britânica 
sobre vários lugares, edifícios, etc. ao longo da maneira. O 
learner é pedido também para estalar sobre alguns locais ao longo da
maneira (por exemplo, sinais, edifícios) que forças him/her observar
os arredors. O programa comentará em todas as voltas erradas 
possíveis e, se o learner começar perdido, emitirá him/her para 
trás ao começo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το αντικείμενο εκμάθησης καταδεικνύει πώς ένα 
δυναμικό περιβάλλον μπορεί να δημιουργηθεί χρησιμοποιώντας τις 
ψηφιακές εικόνες προκειμένου να μαθευτεί πώς να ρωτήσει για και 
να δώσει τις κατευθύνσεις Στην αρχή της άσκησης, ο αρχάριος
στέκεται στην πύλη του βρετανικού μουσείου  από εδώ, 
πρέπει να είναι σε θέση να φτάσει στην αγορά κήπων Covent με 
την ακολουθία των κατευθύνσεων που δίνεται. Ο ολόκληρος 
χρόνος, ο αρχάριος θα δει την ίδια όψη σχετικά με την
οθόνη που κάποιος που περπατά πραγματικά κατά μήκος της 
διαδρομής θα έβλεπε. Ο αρχάριος πρέπει να 
ακολουθήσει την κατεύθυνση αυτός/αυτή έχει την υποχρέωση σε 
κάθε σταυροδρόμια ότι/αυτή έρχεται. Υπάρχουν βέλη 
δείχνοντας στις διαφορετικές κατευθύνσεις στην οθόνη και, με τον 
κρότο σε τις, ο αρχάριος μπορεί να κατευθύνει εαυτό του/της προς 
τον τελικό προορισμό. Συγχρόνως, ο οδηγός γύρου δίνει τις 
βρετανικές πολιτιστικές πληροφορίες για τις διάφορα θέσεις, τα 
κτήρια, κ.λπ. κατά μήκος του τρόπου. Ο αρχάριος καλείται 
επίσης να χτυπήσει σε μερικές περιοχές κατά μήκος του τρόπου 
(π.χ., σημάδια, κτήρια) που την αναγκάζει τον/για να παρατηρήσει 
τα περίχωρα. Το πρόγραμμα θα σχολιάσει οποιεσδήποτε πιθανές
λανθασμένες στροφές και, εάν ο αρχάριος χαθεί, θα την στείλει 
τον/πίσω στην αρχή.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este objeto que aprende demuestra cómo un 
ambiente dinámico se puede crear usando cuadros digitales para 
aprender cómo pedir y dar a directions.At el principio del ejercicio,
el principiante está estando parado en la puerta del museo 
británico; de aquí, he/she debe poder conseguir al mercado del
jardín de Covent siguiendo las direcciones que he/she está dado. 
El tiempo entero, el principiante verá la misma opinión sobre 
la pantalla que alguien realmente que recorre a lo largo de la ruta 
vería. El principiante tiene que entrar en la dirección he/she
se dice en a cada encrucijada a la cual he/she venga. Hay 
flechas que señalan en diversas direcciones en la pantalla y, 
haciendo clic en ellas, el principiante puede dirigir him/herself 
hacia la destinación final. En el mismo tiempo, el guía 
turístico da la información cultural británica sobre varios 
lugares, edificios, etc. a lo largo de la manera. Piden el 
principiante también hacer clic encendido algunos sitios a lo largo 
de la manera (e.g., muestras, edificios) qué fuerzas him/her de notar
los alrededores. El programa comentará respecto a cualquier 
vuelta incorrecta posible y, si el principiante consigue perdido, 
enviará him/her de nuevo al principio.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>4335</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-02-27</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Congedo;Fiorenza;;;
FN:Fiorenza Congedo
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-20</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Congedo;Fiorenza;;;
FN:Fiorenza Congedo
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-20</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>guide</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>continuing education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">10-15</string>
            <string language="en">10-15</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>712</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">Latin</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>210728398</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>audio/basic</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://resources.eun.org/demoportal/virtual_walk_london_eng.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
