<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82605</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82605</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>4010</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Word stress</string>
            <string language="sv">Word stress</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wortdruck</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Effort de mot</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Stress da palavra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sforzo di parola</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πίεση λέξης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Tensión de la palabra</string>
          </title>
          <language>sv</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The learning object teaches the students to pay attention to then main stress of words. On the screen, there are six words lined up vertically. Next to each word there is a Play-button and clicking on that gives the spoken pronunciation of the word. The student's task is to move a section under each accented syllable. To make the exercise not to seem impossible to solve, there is also a button labeled "Solve the exercise" you can click. On this way, the exercise can first be used to learn and then to test your knowledge. In the learning phase, the student first clicks the "Solve the exercise" button and then listens through all the alternatives. In order to make sure the test part is based on authentic listening, it is worth while doing something else between the learning phase and the test phase.


</string>
            <string language="sv">Lärobjektet lär eleverna att fästa uppmärksamhet vid ordens huvudbetoning. 
I rutan finns sex ord under varandra. Bredvid varje ord finns en Play-knapp och klickar man på den hör man ordet uttalas. Elevens uppgift är att flytta en balk under varje betonad stavelse. För att uppgiften inte ska kännas oöverkomlig finns också en knapp som heter ’Lös uppgiften’, som man kan klicka på. På detta sätt kan uppgiften först användas för att lära sig och sedan för att testa sina kunskaper.

I inlärningsmomentet klickar man först på ’Lös uppgiften’ och sedan lyssnar man igenom alla alternativ. För att testmomentet ska basera sig på autentiskt lyssnande lönar det sig att göra något annat mellan inlärnings- och testmomentet.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die erlernennachricht unterrichtet die 
Kursteilnehmer, dann Hauptdruck von Wörtern zu beachten. Auf 
dem Bildschirm gibt es sechs Wörter, die vertikal ausgerichtet 
werden. Nahe bei jedem Wort gibt es eine Spiel-Taste und das 
Klicken auf dem gibt das gesprochene Aussprache des Wortes. Die 
Aufgabe des Kursteilnehmers ist, ein Kapitel unter jede betonte Silbe 
zu verschieben. Um die Übung unmöglich nicht scheinen zu 
lassen zu lösen, gibt es auch eine beschriftete Taste "lösen die 
Übung", das Sie anklicken können. Auf auf diese Weise kann die
Übung zuerst verwendet werden, um Ihr Wissen zu erlernen und dann zu 
prüfen. In der erlernenphase klickt der Kursteilnehmer erster 
die "lösen die Übung" Taste und hören dann durch alle Alternativen.
Zwecks sicherzustellen das Testteil basiert auf dem 
authentischen Hören,IST es beim Tun von von noch etwas zwischen der 
erlernenphase und der Testphase wert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'objet d'étude enseigne les étudiants à 
prêter l'attention à l'effort puis principal des mots. Sur 
l'écran, il y a six mots alignés verticalement. À côté de 
chaque mot il y a un Jeu-bouton et cliquer sur celui donne la
prononciation parlée du mot. L'étudiant chargent doit 
déplacer une section sous chaque syllabe accentuée. Pour faire
l'exercice pour ne pas sembler pour résoudre, il y a également un 
bouton étiqueté "résolvent l'exercice" que vous pouvez 
cliquer. Sur ce chemin, l'exercice peut d'abord être 
employé pour apprendre et puis pour tester votre connaissance. 
Dans la phase d'étude, l'étudiant clique d'abord le 
bouton "résolvent exercice" et puis écoutent par toutes les 
solutions de rechange. Afin de s'assurer la pièce d'essai est 
basé sur l'écoute authentique, il vaut la peine tout en faisant 
autre chose entre la phase d'étude et la phase d'essai.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O objeto de aprendizagem ensina os estudantes 
pagar a atenção ao stress então principal das palavras. Na 
tela, há seis palavras alinhadas acima de verticalmente. Ao 
lado de cada palavra há uma Jogo-tecla e estalar naquele dá a 
pronunciação falada da palavra. A tarefa do estudante é mover
uma seção sob cada sílaba acentuada. Para fazer o exercício 
para não parecer impossível de resolver, há também uma tecla 
etiquetada "resolve o exercício" que você pode estalar. Nesta 
maneira, o exercício pode primeiramente ser usado aprender e testar 
então seu conhecimento. Na fase de aprendizagem, o estudante 
primeiro estala "resolve a tecla do exercício" e escuta então com 
todas as alternativas. A fim certificar-se a peça do teste é 
baseado em escutar authentic, vale a pena ao fazer algo mais entre a 
fase de aprendizagem e a fase de teste.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'oggetto imparante insegna gli allievi prestare 
l'attenzione allo sforzo allora principale delle parole. Sullo 
schermo, ci sono sei parole allineate verticalmente. Vicino ad 
ogni parola ci è un Gioco-tasto e scattarsi su quello dà la 
pronuncia parlata della parola. L'operazione dell'allievo è di 
spostare una sezione sotto ogni sillaba accentata. Fare 
l'esercitazione per non sembrare impossible da risolvere, ci è 
egualmente un tasto identificato "risolve l'esercitazione" che potete 
scattarsi. Su questo modo, l'esercitazione può in primo luogo 
essere usata per imparare ed allora per verificare la vostra 
conoscenza. Nella fase imparante, l'allievo primo scatta 
"risolve il tasto di esercitazione" ed allora ascolta con tutte le 
alternative. Per assicurarsi la parte della prova è basato sul 
ascoltare autentico, vale mentre fa il qualcos'altro fra la fase 
imparante e la fase di prova.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το αντικείμενο εκμάθησης διδάσκει τους σπουδαστές για 
να δώσει προσοχή στην έπειτα βασική πίεση των λέξεων. Στην
οθόνη, υπάρχουν έξι λέξεις που παρατάσσονται κάθετα. 
Δίπλα σε κάθε λέξη υπάρχει ένα παιχνίδι-κουμπί και ο 
κρότος σε αυτό δίνει την προφορική προφορά της λέξης. Η 
στοιχειώδης εργασία του σπουδαστή είναι να κινήσει ένα τμήμα 
κάτω από κάθε τονισμένη συλλαβή. Για να κάνει την άσκηση 
για να μην φανεί αδύνατη να λύσει, υπάρχει επίσης ένα κουμπί 
επονομαζόμενο "λύνει την άσκηση" που μπορείτε να χτυπήσετε. 
Σε αυτόν τον τρόπο, η άσκηση μπορεί πρώτα να 
χρησιμοποιηθεί για να μάθει και έπειτα για να εξετάσει τη γνώση 
σας. Στη φάση εκμάθησης, ο σπουδαστής χτυπά αρχικά το 
κουμπί "λύνει της άσκησησ" και ακούει έπειτα μέσω όλων των 
εναλλακτικών λύσεων. Προκειμένου να σιγουρευτεί η δοκιμή το
μέρος είναι βασισμένο στο αυθεντικό άκουσμα, αξίζει κάνοντας το
κάτι άλλο μεταξύ της φάσης εκμάθησης και της φάσης δοκιμής.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El objeto que aprende enseña a estudiantes a 
prestar la atención a la tensión entonces principal de palabras. 
En la pantalla, hay seis palabras alineadas verticalmente. 
Al lado de cada palabra hay un Juego-boto'n y el hacer clic en 
ése da la pronunciación hablada de la palabra. La tarea del 
estudiante es mover una sección bajo cada sílaba acentuada. 
Hacer el ejercicio para no parecerse imposible de solucionar, 
hay también un botón etiquetado "soluciona el ejercicio" que usted 
puede hacer clic. En esta manera, el ejercicio se puede primero 
utilizar para aprender y después para probar su conocimiento. 
En la fase que aprende, el estudiante primer hace clic 
"soluciona el botón del ejercicio" y después escucha con todos los 
alternativas. Para cerciorarse de la pieza de la prueba se basa 
en escuchar auténtico, vale mientras que hace algo más entre la fase
que aprende y la fase de prueba.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>4010</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-02-16</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-30</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-30</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>sv</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>continuing education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">10-16</string>
            <string language="sv">10-16</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Exercise in discerning the word stress</string>
            <string language="sv">Övning i att urskilja betoningen i ord</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
                <string language="sv">språkområden</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
                <string language="sv">engelska språket</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82605</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>audio/basic</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://resources.eun.org/demoportal/word_stress_sve.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
