<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82696</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82696</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>1561</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="fi">Word stress</string>
            <string language="en">Word stress</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wortdruck</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Effort de mot</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Stress da palavra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sforzo di parola</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πίεση λέξης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Tensión de la palabra</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Aihio ohjaa oppilasta kiinnittämään huomiota siihen, missä kohtaa sanassa on pääpaino. Sanapainolla on englannissa aivan erilainen merkitys kuin esimerkiksi suomessa, jossa pääpaino osuu aina ensimmäiselle tavulle. Siksi natiivinkaltaiseen prosodiaan pääseminen onkin monille hankalaa. 
Ruudulla näkyy kuusi sanaa kirjoitettuna allekkain sekä näiden vieressä olevat kuuntelupainikkeet. Jokaisesta Play-nappulasta kuuluu sana äännettynä. Oppilaan tehtävä on siirtää merkki sanan pääpainon kohdalle. Jottei tehtävä tuntuisi ylitsepääsemättömältä, oikea ratkaisu on myös tarjolla Ratkaise-painiketta napauttamalla. Näin tehtävää voi käyttää ensin opetteluun ja sitten taitojen testaamiseen. 
Opetteluvaiheessa aloitetaan napauttamalla Ratkaise-painiketta ja sen jälkeen käydään läpi kaikki vaihtoehdot kuuntelemalla ne. Jotta testausvaihe perustuisi aitoon kuunteluun kannattaa opettelu- ja testausvaiheen välillä tehdä jotakin muuta.</string>
            <string language="en">The task makes the student pay attention to the main stress of the words. The word stress has a different meaning in the English language than it has in Finnish where the main stress in on the first syllable. Because of this it is quite hard for many students to reach the level of the native speakers when it comes to prosodic features of the language. Six words are seen on the screen and next to them the Play buttons for listening to the words. The task is to put a mark on the main stress of the word. If the task is too demanding the right answer can be found by clicking the Solve button. This way the task can be used both for learning and for testing the skills. When the task is used for learning the student first clicks on the Solve button and goes through all the alternatives by listening to them. In order to make the most out of the two phases of the leaning process it is advisable to do something else between them.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Aufgabe läßt den Kursteilnehmer den 
Hauptdruck der Wörter beachten. Der Wortdruck hat eine andere 
Bedeutung in der englischen Sprache, als er in finnischem wo der 
Hauptdruck innen auf der ersten Silbe hat. Wegen dieses ist es 
ziemlich hart für viele Kursteilnehmer, die Stufe der Muttersprachler
zu erreichen, wenn er zu den prosodischen Merkmalen der Sprache kommt.
Sechs Wörter werden auf den Bildschirm und nahe bei ihnen die 
Spieltasten für das Hören zu den Wörtern gesehen. Die Aufgabe
ist, eine Markierung auf den Hauptdruck des Wortes zu setzen. 
Wenn die Aufgabe auch verlangt, kann die rechte Antwort gefunden
werden, indem man die lösentaste anklickt. Auf diese Weise die 
Aufgabe kann für das Lernen und für die Prüfung der Fähigkeiten 
verwendet werden. Wenn die Aufgabe für das Lernen verwendet 
wird, klickt der Kursteilnehmer zuerst an die lösentaste und läuft 
alle Alternativen durch, indem er zu ihnen hört. Zwecks die die
meisten aus den zwei Phasen des lehnenden Prozesses heraus ihn zu 
bilden ist ratsam noch etwas zwischen ihnen zu tun.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le charger incite l'étudiant à prêter 
l'attention à l'effort principal des mots. L'effort de mot a 
une signification différente dans l'anglais qu'il a dans finlandais 
où l'effort principal dedans sur la première syllabe. Pour 
cette raison il est tout à fait difficile que beaucoup d'étudiants 
atteignent le niveau des naturels quand il vient aux dispositifs 
prosodiques du langage. Six mots sont vus sur l'écran et à 
côté d'eux les boutons de jeu pour écouter les mots. Le 
charger doit mettre une marque sur l'effort principal du mot. 
Si le charger exige trop la bonne réponse peut être 
trouvée en cliquant le bouton de solution. De cette 
façon le charger peut être utilisée pour apprendre et pour 
tester les qualifications. Quand le charger est utilisé 
pour apprendre l'étudiant d'abord clique sur le bouton de 
solution et passe par toutes les solutions de rechange en écoutant 
elles. Il est recommandé de le faire aux la plupart hors des 
deux phases du processus de penchement pour faire autre chose entre 
elles.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A tarefa faz o estudante pagar a atenção ao 
stress principal das palavras. O stress da palavra tem um 
meaning diferente na língua inglesa do que tem em finnish onde o 
stress principal dentro na primeira sílaba. Por causa deste é 
completamente duro para muitos estudantes alcançar o nível dos 
altofalantes nativos quando vem às características prosodic da 
língua. Seis palavras são vistas na tela e ao lado delas as 
teclas do jogo escutando as palavras. A tarefa é pôr uma marca
sobre o stress principal da palavra. Se a tarefa estiver 
exijindo demasiado a resposta direita pode ser encontrada estalando a 
tecla resolver. Esta maneira a tarefa pode ser usada  aprendendo
e testando as habilidades. Quando a tarefa é usada aprendendo o
estudante estala primeiramente sobre a tecla resolver e atravessa 
todas as alternativas escutando elas. A fim fazê-lo ao a 
maioria fora das duas fases do processo inclinando-se é aconselhável
fazer mais algo entre elas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'operazione incita l'allievo a prestare 
l'attenzione allo sforzo principale delle parole. Lo sforzo di 
parola ha un significato differente nella lingua inglese che ha in 
finlandese dove lo sforzo principale dentro sulla prima sillaba. 
A causa di questo per molti allievi è abbastanza duro 
raggiungere il livello degli indigeni quando viene alle 
caratteristiche prosodiche del linguaggio. Sei parole sono viste
sullo schermo e vicino loro i tasti del gioco per ascoltare le parole.
L'operazione è di mettere un contrassegno sullo sforzo 
principale della parola. Se l'operazione ugualmente sta 
richiedendo la giusta risposta può essere trovata scattando il tasto 
di risolv. Questo modo l'operazione può essere usato sia per 
imparare che per verificare le abilità. Quando l'operazione è 
usata per imparare l'allievo in primo luogo scatta sopra il tasto di 
risolv e passa con tutte le alternative ascoltando loro. Per 
renderlo il la maggior parte dalle due fasi del processo pendente è 
consigliabile da fare loro il qualcos'altro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η στοιχειώδης εργασία κάνει το σπουδαστή να δώσει 
προσοχή στη βασική πίεση των λέξεων. Η πίεση λέξης έχει 
μια διαφορετική έννοια στην αγγλική γλώσσα από έχει στα 
φιλανδικά όπου η βασική πίεση μέσα στην πρώτη συλλαβή. 
Λόγω αυτού είναι αρκετά δύσκολο για πολλούς σπουδαστές να
φθαθούν στο επίπεδο των φυσικών ομιλητών όταν τα προσωδικά 
χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα της γλώσσας. Έξι λέξεις 
βλέπουνε στην οθόνη και δίπλα σε τους τα κουμπιά παιχνιδιού
για το άκουσμα τις λέξεις. Η στοιχειώδης εργασία είναι να 
τεθεί ένα σημάδι στη βασική πίεση της λέξης. Εάν η 
στοιχειώδης εργασία είναι επίσης να απαιτήσει τη σωστή απάντηση
μπορεί να βρεθεί με τον κρότο του Solve κουμπιού. Αυτός 
ο τρόπος η στοιχειώδης εργασία μπορεί να χρησιμοποιηθεί και για 
την εκμάθηση και για τη δοκιμή των δεξιοτήτων. Όταν η 
στοιχειώδης εργασία χρησιμοποιείται για η εκμάθηση του σπουδαστή 
χτυπά αρχικά στο Solve κουμπί και περνά από όλες τις 
εναλλακτικές λύσεις με το άκουσμα σε τους. Προκειμένου να 
γίνουν οι περισσότερες από τις δύο φάσεις της διαδικασίας 
κλίσης είναι ενδεδειγμένο να γίνει το κάτι άλλο μεταξύ τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La tarea hace que el estudiante presta la 
atención a la tensión principal de las palabras. La tensión 
de la palabra tiene un diverso significado en el lenguaje inglés que 
tiene en finlandés donde la tensión principal adentro en la primera 
sílaba. Debido a esto es absolutamente duro que muchos 
estudiantes alcancen el nivel de los nativos cuando viene a las 
características prosódicas del lenguaje. Seis palabras se 
consideran en la pantalla y al lado de ellas los botones del juego 
para escuchar las palabras. La tarea es poner una marca en la 
tensión principal de la palabra. Si la tarea está exigiendo 
también la respuesta derecha puede ser encontrada haciendo clic el 
botón del solucionar. Esta manera la tarea se puede utilizar 
para aprender y para probar las habilidades. Cuando la tarea se 
utiliza para aprender el estudiante primero hace clic encendido el 
botón del solucionar y pasa con todos los alternativas escuchando 
ellos. Para hacerlo el la mayoría fuera de las dos fases del 
proceso que se inclina es recomendable hacer algo más entre ellas.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>1561</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-01-12</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-13</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-13</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>fi</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">8-U</string>
            <string language="fi">&gt; 8</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Sanapainon erottamisen harjoittelu</string>
            <string language="en">Practising the word stress</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">englannin kieli</string>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>710</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">kielten opetus</string>
                <string language="en">language teaching</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">kielet</string>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82696</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/sanapaino/co1_13.exe</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
