<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82587</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82587</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>4000</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Virtual walk in London</string>
            <string language="sv">Virtual walk in London</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Virtueller Weg in London</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Promenade virtuelle à Londres</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Caminhada virtual em Londres</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Camminata virtuale a Londra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εικονικός περίπατος στο Λονδίνο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Caminata virtual en Londres</string>
          </title>
          <language>sv</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The learning object shows a way to use digital images when creating a challenging learning environment for giving and receiving instructions on finding your way around in London. The student stands at the gates to the British Museum; from here the student will find his way, using the instructions given to him, to the Covent Garden Market. The student sees in front of him the same things that anyone, located in London, would see in the real world. At the street crossings the student is asked to go in a certain direction. On the screen there are arrows pointing in different directions and by clicking them the student gets where he or she wants to. At the same time, the student gets information about the British culture, through the places, buildings and other things the student meets on his way. The student is also asked to click on objects in his environment (for example transportation, signs, buildings). This way, the student will inevitably pay attention to what he or she sees. The program gives spoken comments on possible errors and guides the one gone astray back to the original point of departure.

</string>
            <string language="sv">Lärobjektet visar hur man med hjälp av digitalbilder kan skapa en utmanande miljö när man undervisar i att ge och få väganvisningar.
Eleven står vid portarna till British Museum; härfrån ska eleven med hjälp av de instruktioner han eller hon får ta sig till Covent Garden Market. Eleven ser framför sig samma sak som en som i verkligheten befinner sig i London. Vid korsningarna ombeds eleven gå i en viss riktning. I rutan finns pilar i olika riktningar och genom att klicka på dem kommer eleven dit han eller hon vill. På samma gång får eleven information om den brittiska kulturen, genom de platser, byggnader och annat som eleven möter på vägen. Eleven ombeds också klicka på föremål i sin omgivning (t.ex. fortskaffningsmedel, skyltar, byggnader). På detta sätt fäster eleven oundvikligen uppmärksamhet vid vad han eller hon ser. Programmet kommenterar muntligt möjliga fel och ledsagar den som gått vilse tillbaka till utgångsrutan.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die erlernennachricht zeigt eine Methode, 
digitalisierte Bilder zu verwenden, wenn sie eine schwierige 
erlernenumgebung für das Erteilen und das Empfangen von von 
Anweisungen in Ihre Methode herum finden in London erstellt. Der
Kursteilnehmer steht an den Gattern zum britischen Museum; hier 
vom Kursteilnehmer findet seine Methode mit den Anweisungen, die ihm, 
zum Covent Garten-Markt erteilt werden. Der Kursteilnehmer sieht
vor ihm die gleichen Sachen, die jedermann, gefunden in London, in die
reale Welt sehen würde. An den Straße Überfahrten wird der 
Kursteilnehmer gebeten, in eine bestimmte Richtung zu gehen. Zu 
auf dem Bildschirm gibt es die Pfeile, die in unterschiedliche zeigen 
Richtungen und indem er anklickt sie, erhält der Kursteilnehmer, wo 
er oder sie wünschen. Gleichzeitig erhält der Kursteilnehmer 
Informationen über die britische Kultur, durch die Plätze, die 
Gebäude und andere Sachen, die der Kursteilnehmer auf seiner Methode 
trifft. Der Kursteilnehmer wird auch gebeten, Nachrichten in 
seiner Umgebung (zum Beispiel Transport, Zeichen, Gebäude) an zu 
klicken. Auf diese Weise, der Kursteilnehmer beachtet 
unvermeidlich, was er oder sie sehen. Das Programm gibt 
gesprochenen Kommentar zu den möglichen Fehlern und führt das, das 
zurück zu dem ursprünglichen Ausgangspunkt verloren gegangen wird.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'objet d'étude montre une voie d'utiliser des 
images digitales en créant un environnement d'étude provocant pour 
donner et recevoir des instructions sur trouver votre chemin autour à
Londres. L'étudiant se tient aux portes au musée britannique ;
d'ici l'étudiant trouvera son chemin, en utilisant les 
instructions données à lui, au marché de jardin de Covent. 
L'étudiant voit devant lui les mêmes choses que n'importe qui,
situé à Londres, verrait dans le vrai monde. Aux croisements 
de rue l'étudiant est invité à aller dans une certaine direction. 
Sur l'écran il y a des flèches se dirigeant dans différentes 
directions et en les cliquant l'étudiant obtient à où lui 
ou elle veut. En même temps, l'étudiant obtient des 
informations sur la culture britannique, par les endroits, des 
bâtiments et d'autres choses que l'étudiant rencontre sur son 
chemin. L'étudiant est également invité à cliquer 
sur des objets dans son environnement (par exemple transport, signes, 
bâtiments). De cette façon, l'étudiant prêtera 
inévitablement l'attention à ce que lui ou elle voit. Le 
programme donne des commentaires parlés sur des erreurs possibles et 
guide celui égaré de nouveau au point de départ initial.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O objeto de aprendizagem mostra uma maneira usar 
imagens digitais ao criar um ambiente de aprendizagem challenging para
dar e receber instruções em encontrar sua maneira ao redor em 
Londres. O estudante está nas portas ao museu britânico; 
aqui do estudante encontrará sua maneira, usando as 
instruções dadas a ele, ao mercado do jardim de Covent. O 
estudante vê na frente dele as mesmas coisas que qualquer um, 
localizado em Londres, veria no mundo real. Nos cruzamentos da 
rua o estudante é pedido para ir em um determinado sentido. Na 
tela há setas que apontam em sentidos diferentes e estalando os o 
estudante começa a onde ou querem. Ao mesmo tempo, o estudante 
começa a informação sobre a cultura britânica, através dos 
lugares, edifícios e outras coisas que o estudante se encontra com em
sua maneira. O estudante é pedido também para estalar sobre 
objetos em seu ambiente (para o transporte do exemplo, os sinais, os 
edifícios). Esta maneira, o estudante pagará inevitàvel a 
atenção a o que ou vêem. O programa dá comentários falados 
em erros possíveis e guia a uma parte traseira astray ida ao ponto de
partida original.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'oggetto imparante mostra un modo usare le 
immagini digitali quando crea un ambiente imparante challenging per 
dare e la ricezione delle istruzioni sull'individuazione del vostro 
modo intorno a Londra. L'allievo si leva in piedi ai cancelli al
museo britannico; di qui l'allievo troverà il suo modo, usando 
le istruzioni date lui, al mercato del giardino di Covent. 
L'allievo vede davanti lui le stesse cose che chiunque, situato 
a Londra, vedrebbe nel mondo reale. Agli incroci della via 
l'allievo è chiesto di andare in un determinato senso. Sullo 
schermo ci sono frecce che indicano nei sensi differenti e scattandoli
l'allievo ottiene a dove lui o lei desidera. Allo stesso tempo, 
l'allievo ottiene le informazioni sulla coltura britannica, attraverso
i posti, sulle costruzioni ed altre cose che l'allievo viene a 
contatto di sul suo modo. L'allievo egualmente è chiesto di 
scattare sopra gli oggetti nel suo ambiente (per esempio trasporto, 
segni, costruzioni). Questo modo, l'allievo presterà 
inevitabilmente l'attenzione a che cosa lui o lei vede. Il 
programma dà le osservazioni parlate sugli errori possibili e guida 
quello andato smarrito di nuovo al punto di partenza originale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το την αντικείμενο εκμάθησης εμφανίζει έναν τρόπο να 
χρησιμοποιηθούν οι ψηφιακές εικόνες κατά δημιουργία ενός 
προκλητικού μαθησιακού περιβάλλοντος για το δόσιμο και τη λήψη 
των οδηγιών για να βρεί τον τρόπο σας γύρω στο Λονδίνο. Ο 
σπουδαστής στέκεται στις πύλες στο βρετανικό μουσείο  από 
εδώ το σπουδαστή θα βρεί τον τρόπο του, χρησιμοποιώντας τις 
οδηγίες που δίνονται σε του, στην αγορά κήπων Covent. Ο 
σπουδαστής βλέπει μπροστά από τον τα ίδια πράγματα που 
καθένας, που βρίσκεται στο Λονδίνο, θα έβλεπε στον 
πραγματικό κόσμο. Στις διασταυρώσεις οδών ο σπουδαστής 
καλείται να ακολουθήσει μια ορισμένη κατεύθυνση. Στην οθόνη
υπάρχουν βέλη δείχνοντας στις διαφορετικές κατευθύνσεις και με 
τον κρότο τους ο σπουδαστής παίρνει όπου θέλει. Συγχρόνως,
ο σπουδαστής παίρνει τις πληροφορίες για το βρετανικό πολιτισμό, 
μέσω των θέσεων, των κτηρίων και άλλων πραγμάτων που ο 
σπουδαστής συναντιέται στο δρόμο του. Ο σπουδαστής καλείται
επίσης να χτυπήσει στα αντικείμενα στο περιβάλλον του 
(παραδείγματος χάριν μεταφορά, σημάδια, κτήρια). Αυτός ο 
τρόπος, ο σπουδαστής θα δώσει αναπόφευκτα προσοχή σε αυτό που 
βλέπει. Το πρόγραμμα δίνει τα προφορικά σχόλια στα 
πιθανά σφάλματα και καθοδηγεί αυτό που πηγαίνουν παραστρατημένο 
πίσω στο αρχικό σημείο της αναχώρησης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El objeto que aprende muestra una manera de 
utilizar imágenes digitales al crear un ambiente que aprende 
desafiador para dar y recibir instrucciones en encontrar su manera 
alrededor en Londres. El estudiante está parado en las puertas 
al museo británico; aquí del estudiante encontrará su manera,
usando las instrucciones dadas a él, al mercado del jardín de 
Covent. El estudiante ve delante de él las mismas cosas que 
cualquier persona, localizado en Londres, vería en el mundo 
verdadero. En las travesías de la calle piden el estudiante 
entrar en cierta dirección. En la pantalla hay flechas que 
señalan en diversas direcciones y haciéndolas clic el estudiante 
consigue a donde él o ella desea. En el mismo tiempo, el 
estudiante consigue la información sobre la cultura británica, a 
través de los lugares, los edificios y otras cosas que el estudiante 
satisface en su manera. Piden el estudiante también hacer clic 
encendido objetos en su ambiente (por ejemplo transporte, muestras, 
edificios). Esta manera, el estudiante prestará inevitable la 
atención a lo que él o ella ve. El programa da comentarios 
hablados sobre errores posibles y dirige el que esta' perdido de nuevo
a la punta de la salida original.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>4000</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-02-16</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-30</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-30</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-30</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-30</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>sv</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>guide</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>continuing education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">10-15</string>
            <string language="sv">10-15</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="en">English listening comprehension and expressions related to finding your way in urban surroundings</string>
            <string language="sv">Engelsk hörförståelse samt uttryck relaterade till väganvisningar</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
                <string language="sv">språkområden</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
                <string language="sv">engelska språket</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82587</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>audio/basic</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://resources.eun.org/demoportal/virtual_walk_sve.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
