<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82680</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82680</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>3999</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The cook's day</string>
            <string language="sv">Kockens dag</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Tag des Kochs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le jour du cuisinier</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O dia do cozinheiro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il giorno del cuoco</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ημέρα του μάγειρα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El día del cocinero</string>
          </title>
          <language>sv</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The learning object illustrates the advantages of using a video clip as study material instead of a text. In this learning object the student watches a video interview and makes a day schedule in the cook's calendar, based on the video. The schedule for the day contains completed time expressions and is divided to a morning shift and an evening shift. In the sections on the screen there are nine different activities (for example ”Arrive at work”,” Start lunch service”) which the cook tells about. The student's task is to place the sections in the correct fields in the day schedule. The student can choose between working with the exercise while the video is playing or first watch the complete video. It is easy to watch and to listen to the video any number of times desired. When the student clicks on 'Check' the programme controls the answers. The correct answers change colour and lock themselves on their places and the sections that are placed wrong slide back to the starting position. The exercise goes on until all sections are on their correct places.


</string>
            <string language="sv">Lärobjektet belyser fördelarna med att använda ett videoklipp som läromaterial i stället för en text. 
I detta lärobjekt följer eleven med en videointervju och gör på basis av den ett dagsschema  i kockens kalender. Dagsschemat innehåller färdiga klockslag och är indelat i ett morgon- och kvällsskift. I de balkar som finns i rutan finns nio olika aktiviteter (t.ex. ”Arrive at work”, ”Start lunch service”) som kocken berättar om. Elevens uppgift är att placera balkarna i de rätta fälten i dagsschemat. Eleven kan välja mellan att göra uppgiften medan videon spelar eller att först lyssna på videon i sin helhet. Det är lätt att se och lyssna på videon så många gånger man vill.
När eleven klickar på ’Kontrollera’ kontrollerar programmet svaren. De korrekta svaren ändrar färg och låser sig på sina platser och de balkar som placerats fel glider tillbaka till utgångsläget. Uppgiften görs tills alla balkar är på sina rätta platser.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die erlernennachricht veranschaulicht die Vorteile 
des Verwendens eines videoclips als Studie Material anstelle von einem
Text. In dieser erlernennachricht die Kursteilnehmeruhren ein 
videointerview und Marken ein Tageszeitplan im Kalender des Kochs, 
basiert auf dem Bildschirm. Der Zeitplan für den Tag enthält 
abgeschlossene Zeitausdrücke und wird zu einer Morgenschicht und zu 
einer Abendschicht geteilt. In den Kapiteln auf dem Bildschirm 
gibt es neun unterschiedliche Aktivitäten (zum Beispiel?Arrive an der
Arbeit?? Beginnen Sie Mittagessenservice?) welches der 
Koch ungefähr erklärt. Die Aufgabe des Kursteilnehmers ist, 
die Kapitel in das korrekte zu legen auffängt im 
Tageszeitplan. Der Kursteilnehmer kann zwischen dem Arbeiten mit
der Übung wählen, während der Bildschirm spielt oder den kompletten
Bildschirm zuerst überwachen. Zu überwachen ist einfach und 
zum Bildschirm hören, den jede mögliche Zahl von Zeiten wünschte. 
Wenn der Kursteilnehmer an ' Überprüfung ' die 
Programmkontrollen die Antworten klickt. Die korrekten Antworten
ändern Farbe und sperren sich auf ihren Plätzen und die Kapitel, die
falsch plaziert werden, schieben zurück zu der Ausgangsposition. 
Die Übung geht weiter, bis alle Kapitel auf ihren korrekten 
Plätzen sind.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'objet d'étude illustre les avantages d'utiliser 
un clip visuel comme matériel d'étude au lieu d'un texte. Dans
cet objet d'étude les montres d'étudiant une entrevue visuelle et 
marques un programme de jour dans le calendrier du cuisinier, basé 
sur le vidéo. Le programme pour le jour contient des 
expressions réalisées de temps et est divisé à un décalage de 
matin et à un décalage de soirée. Dans les sections sur 
l'écran il y a neuf activités différentes (par exemple ?Arrive au 
travail ? ? Commencez le service de déjeuner ?) ce que le
cuisinier dit environ. L'étudiant chargent doit placer 
les sections dans les domaines corrects dans le programme de jour. 
L'étudiant peut choisir entre travailler avec l'exercice tandis
que le vidéo joue ou d'abord observer le vidéo complet. Il est
facile d'observer et pour écouter le vidéo que tout nombre de fois a
désiré. Quand les clics d'étudiant sur le 'contrôle 
'les commandes de programme les réponses. Les réponses 
correctes changent la couleur et se verrouillent sur leurs endroits et
les sections qui sont placées mal glissent de nouveau à la position 
de départ. L'exercice continue jusqu'à ce que toutes les 
sections soient sur leurs endroits corrects.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O objeto de aprendizagem ilustra as vantagens de 
usar um grampo video como o material do estudo em vez de um texto. 
Neste objeto de aprendizagem os relógios do estudante uma 
entrevista video e makes uma programação do dia no calendário do 
cozinheiro, baseado no vídeo. A programação para o dia contem
expressões terminadas do tempo e é dividida a uma SHIFT da manhã e 
a uma SHIFT da noite. Nas seções na tela há nove atividades 
diferentes (para o exemplo?Arrive no trabalho?? Comece o 
serviço do lunch?) qual o cozinheiro diz aproximadamente. 
A tarefa do estudante é colocar as seções nos campos corretos
na programação do dia. O estudante pode escolher entre 
trabalhar com o exercício quando o vídeo jogar ou primeiramente 
prestar atenção ao vídeo completo. É fácil prestar 
atenção e para escutar o vídeo que todo o número das épocas 
desejou. Quando o estudante estalar sobre ' a verificação ' os
controles de programa as respostas. As respostas corretas mudam 
a cor e travam-se em seus lugares e as seções que são colocadas 
erradamente deslizam para trás à posição começar. O 
exercício vai sobre até que todas as seções estejam em seus 
lugares corretos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'oggetto imparante illustra i vantaggi di per 
mezzo di video clip come materiale di studio anziché un testo. 
In questo oggetto imparante le vigilanze dell'allievo una video 
intervista e marche un programma di giorno nel calendario del cuoco, 
basato sul video. Il programma per il giorno contiene le 
espressioni completate di tempo ed è diviso ad uno spostamento di 
mattina e ad uno spostamento di sera. Nelle sezioni sullo 
schermo ci sono nove attività differenti (per esempio?Arrive sul 
lavoro?? Inizi il servizio del pranzo?) a quale il cuoco 
dice circa. L'operazione dell'allievo è di disporre le sezioni 
nei campi corretti nel programma di giorno. L'allievo può 
scegliere fra il funzionamento con l'esercitazione mentre il video sta
giocando o in primo luogo guardare il video completo. È facile 
da guardare ed ascoltare il video che tutto il numero di volte ha 
voluto. Quando l'allievo scatta sopra 'il controllo 'i comandi 
di programma le risposte. Le risposte corrette cambiano il 
colore e si bloccano sui loro posti e le sezioni che sono disposte 
male fanno scorrere di nuovo alla posizione cominciare. 
L'esercitazione accende fino a che tutte le sezioni non siano 
sui loro posti corretti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το αντικείμενο εκμάθησης επεξηγεί τα πλεονεκτήματα 
έναν τηλεοπτικό συνδετήρα ως υλικό μελέτης αντί ενός κειμένου.
Σε αυτό το αντικείμενο εκμάθησης ο σπουδαστής προσέχει μια 
τηλεοπτική συνέντευξη και κάνει ένα πρόγραμμα ημέρας στο 
ημερολόγιο του μάγειρα, βασισμένο στο βίντεο. Το πρόγραμμα 
για την ημέρα περιέχει τις ολοκληρωμένες χρονικές εκφράσεις και 
διαιρείται σε μια μετατόπιση πρωινού και μια μετατόπιση βραδιού. 
Στα τμήματα οθόνης υπάρχουν εννέα διαφορετικές 
δραστηριότητες (παραδείγματος χάριν ?Arrive στην εργασία;,; 
Υπηρεσία μεσημεριανού γεύματος έναρξης;) όποιους ο 
μάγειρας λέει για. Η στοιχειώδης εργασία του σπουδαστή 
είναι να τοποθετήσει τα τμήματα στα σωστά πεδία στο πρόγραμμα 
ημέρας. Ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να επιλέξει μεταξύ της 
εργασίας με την άσκηση ενώ το βίντεο παίζει ή προσέχει αρχικά 
το πλήρες βίντεο. Είναι εύκολο να προσέξει και να ακούσει 
το βίντεο οποιοσδήποτε αριθμός χρόνων επιθυμητών. Όταν ο 
σπουδαστής χτυπά "στον έλεγχο" τους ελέγχους προγράμματος οι 
απαντήσεις. Οι σωστές απαντήσεις αλλάζουν το χρώμα και 
κλειδώνονται στις θέσεις τους και τα τμήματα που είναι 
τοποθετημένη λανθασμένη φωτογραφική διαφάνεια πίσω στην αρχική 
θέση. Η άσκηση συνεχίζεται έως ότου είναι όλα τα τμήματα
στις σωστές θέσεις τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El objeto que aprende ilustra las ventajas de usar
un clip video como material del estudio en vez de un texto. En 
este objeto que aprende los relojes del estudiante una entrevista 
video y marcas un horario del día en el calendario del cocinero, 
basado en el vídeo. El horario para el día contiene 
expresiones terminadas del tiempo y se divide a una rotación de la 
mañana y a una rotación de la tarde. ¿En las secciones en la 
pantalla hay nueve diversas actividades (por ejemplo?Arrive en el 
trabajo?? Comience el servicio del almuerzo?) cuál el 
cocinero dice alrededor. La tarea del estudiante es poner las 
secciones en los campos correctos en el horario del día. El 
estudiante puede elegir entre el trabajo con el ejercicio mientras que
el vídeo está jugando o primero mirar el vídeo completo. Es 
fácil mirar y escuchar el vídeo que cualquier número de épocas 
deseó. Cuando el estudiante hace clic encendido el ' cheque ' 
los controles de programa las respuestas. Las respuestas 
correctas cambian color y se bloquean en sus lugares y las secciones 
que se ponen mal resbalan de nuevo a la posición de salida. El 
ejercicio continúa hasta que todas las secciones están en sus 
lugares correctos.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>3999</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-02-16</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-30</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-30</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-30</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-30</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>sv</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>vocational education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">15-U</string>
            <string language="sv">&gt; 15</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Language tuition within the hotel and restaurant sector, English listening comprehension</string>
            <string language="sv">Språkundervisning inom hotell- och restaurangbranschen, engelska hörförståelse</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
                <string language="sv">språkområden</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
                <string language="sv">engelska språket</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82680</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>audio/basic</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://resources.eun.org/demoportal/kockens_dag_sve.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
