<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82766</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82766</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>1563</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="fi">Puhelinfraasit</string>
            <string language="en">Phrases on the  Telephone </string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Phrasen am Telefon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Expressions au téléphone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Frases no telefone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Frasi sul telefono</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Φράσεις στο τηλέφωνο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Frases en el teléfono</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Oppilaan on poimittava kuulemiensa puhelinfraasien joukosta rakenteita, jotka tulisi oppia ns. automatisoituneina lauseina. Aihiossa esiintyy lukuisia käyttökelpoisia fraaseja käytettäväksi esimerkiksi työelämässä. Samalla oppilas oppii poimimaan sanontoja puheesta.
Oppilaan tehtävänä on täyttää rakennekaaviot kuulemansa perusteella. Napauttamalla kolmea puhelimen kuvaa oppilas kuulee puhelimessa yleisesti esiintyviä repliikkejä, joita käytetään, kun pahoitellaan sitä, että tavoiteltu henkilö ei ole tavoitettavissa (esim. ”I’m afraid she’s out of town all week. She’ll be back on Monday.”, “I’m sorry, he is on the other line.  Would you like to hold?”). Puhelimien alla olevassa rakennekaaviossa on valmiina joitakin sanoja ja oppilaan tulee täydentää kukin rivi poimimalla repliikkien joukosta kokonaisia fraaseja kuulon perusteella. Rakennekaavion solut reagoivat jokaiseen napautukseen vaihtamalla tekstiään ja oppilas rakentaa rivit vastaamaan kuulemiaan fraaseja. Tarkista-painiketta painamalla ohjelma tarkistaa tehtävän, oikein rakennetut fraasit lukkiutuvat paikoilleen ja kokonaiset repliikit kuuluvat puhuttuna oikein menneiden fraasien kohdalla</string>
            <string language="en">The student has to pick up phrases from telephone conversations that have to be learned so that they can be used automatically. The task contains many useful phrases that can be used for example in working life. At the same time the student learns to pick up phrases from speech. The student fills in the structure on the basis of what he/she hears. By clicking on three telephones the student hears phrases that are frequently used on the phone when a person can not be reached (“I’m afraid she’s out of town all week. She’ll be back on Monday.”, “I’m sorry, he is on the other line. Would you like to hold?”). There are already some words ready in the structures under the phones and the task is to fill in the missing parts. The parts of the structure react on every click by changing the text and the student builds the lines so that they correspond to the sentences heard. By clicking on the Check button the task is checked, the correctly constructed sentences freeze and the correct lines will be heard.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Kursteilnehmer muß Phrasen von den 
Telefongesprächen aufheben, die erlernt werden müssen, damit sie 
automatisch verwendet werden können. Die Aufgabe enthält viele
nützliche Phrasen, die zum Beispiel im Berufsleben verwendet werden 
können. Gleichzeitig erlernt der Kursteilnehmer, Phrasen von 
der Rede aufzuheben. Der Kursteilnehmer füllt die Struktur auf 
der Grundlage von aus, was he/she hört. Indem er an drei 
Telefonen klickt, hört der Kursteilnehmer Phrasen, die häufig am 
Telefon verwendet werden, wenn eine Person nicht erreicht werden kann 
(?I?m ängstlichshe?s aus Stadt heraus alle Woche. She?ll ist 
zurück am Montag?, das traurige?I?m, ist er auf der anderen 
Zeile. Wurden Sie mögen anhalten??). Es gibt bereits 
einige Wörter, die in den Strukturen unter den Telefonen 
betriebsbereit sind und die Aufgabe ist, die fehlenden Teile 
auszufüllen. Die Teile der Struktur reagieren auf jedem 
Klicken, indem sie den Text ändern und der Kursteilnehmer baut die 
Zeilen auf, damit sie den gehörten Programmsätzen entsprechen. 
Indem man auf der Überprüfung Taste klickt, wird die Aufgabe 
überprüft, frieren die richtig konstruierten Programmsätze ein und 
die korrekten Zeilen werden gehört.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'étudiant doit prendre des expressions des 
conversations téléphoniques qui doivent être apprises de sorte 
qu'elles puissent être utilisées automatiquement. Le 
charger contient beaucoup d'expressions utiles qui peuvent être 
utilisées par exemple dans la vie active. En même temps 
l'étudiant apprend à prendre des expressions de la parole. 
L'étudiant complète la structure sur la base de ce que he/she 
entend. En cliquant à trois téléphones l'étudiant 
entend les expressions qui sont fréquemment utilisées au téléphone
quand une personne ne peut pas être atteinte (les she?s effrayés de 
?I?m hors de la ville toute la semaine. She?ll soit de retour 
lundi ?, ?I?m désolé, il est sur l'autre ligne. vous 
aimez se tenir ? ?). Il y a déjà quelques mots prêts dans les
structures sous les téléphones et le charger doit compléter les 
pièces manquantes. Les parties de la structure réagissent sur 
chaque clic en changeant le texte et l'étudiant établit les 
lignes de sorte qu'elles correspondent aux phrases entendues. En
cliquant sur le bouton de contrôle le charger est 
contrôlé, les phrases correctement construites gèlent et les lignes
correctes seront entendues.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O estudante tem que escolher acima frases das 
conversações de telefone que têm que ser aprendidas de modo que 
possam ser usadas automaticamente. A tarefa contem muitas frases
úteis que podem ser usadas para o exemplo na vida de funcionamento. 
Ao mesmo tempo o estudante aprende escolher acima frases do 
discurso. O estudante preenche a estrutura na base de o que 
he/she se ouve. Estalando em três telefones o estudante ouve as
frases que estão usadas freqüentemente no telefone quando uma pessoa
não pode ser alcançada (she?s receosos do?I?m fora da cidade toda a 
semana. She?ll esteja para trás em segunda-feira?, ?I?m 
pesaroso, está na outra linha. você gosta de prender??). 
Há já algumas palavras prontas nas estruturas sob os telefones
e a tarefa é preencher as peças faltantes. As partes da 
estrutura reagem em cada clique mudando o texto e o estudante 
constrói as linhas de modo que correspondam às sentenças ouvidas. 
Estalando na tecla da verificação a tarefa é verificada, as 
sentenças corretamente construídas congelam-se e as linhas corretas 
serão ouvidas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'allievo deve prendere le frasi dalle 
conversazioni telefoniche che devono essere imparate in moda da 
poterle usare automaticamente. L'operazione contiene molte frasi
utili che possono essere usate per esempio nella vita attiva. 
Allo stesso tempo l'allievo impara prendere le frasi da 
discorso. L'allievo riempe la struttura in base a che cosa 
he/she si sente. Scattandosi su tre telefoni l'allievo sente le 
frasi che sono usate frequentemente sul telefono quando una persona 
non può essere raggiunta (she?s impauriti del?I?m dalla città tutta 
la settimana. She?ll è indietro su lunedì?, ?I?m 
spiacente, è sull'altra riga. gradite tenere??). Ci sono
già alcune parole aspettano nelle strutture sotto i telefoni e 
l'operazione è di riempire le parti mancanti. Le parti della 
struttura reagiscono su ogni scatto cambiando il testo e l'allievo 
sviluppa le righe in modo che corrispondano alle frasi sentite. 
Scattandosi sul tasto del controllo l'operazione è controllata,
le frasi correttamente costruite congelano e le righe corrette saranno
sentite.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο σπουδαστής πρέπει να πάρει τις φράσεις από τις 
τηλεφωνικές συνομιλίες που πρέπει να μαθευτούν έτσι ώστε 
μπορούν να χρησιμοποιηθούν αυτόματα. Η στοιχειώδης εργασία 
περιέχει πολλές χρήσιμες φράσεις που μπορούν να χρησιμοποιηθούν 
παραδείγματος χάριν στην οικονομικά ενεργή ζωή. Συγχρόνως 
ο σπουδαστής μαθαίνει να παίρνει τις φράσεις από την ομιλία. 
Ο σπουδαστής συμπληρώνει τη δομή βάσει αυτό που ακούει. 
Με τον κρότο σε τρία τηλέφωνα ο σπουδαστής ακούει τις 
φράσεις που χρησιμοποιούνται συχνά στο τηλέφωνο όταν δεν μπορεί 
να επιτευχθεί ένα πρόσωπο (?I?m φοβισμένο she?s από την 
πόλη όλη η εβδομάδα. Το She?ll είναι πίσω τη Δευτέρα;, 
?I?m θλιβερός, είναι στην άλλη γραμμή. Θα 
επιθυμούσατε να κρατήσετε το ??). Υπάρχουν ήδη μερικές 
λέξεις αναμένουνε στις δομές κάτω από τα τηλέφωνα και η 
στοιχειώδης εργασία είναι να συμπληρωθούν τα ελλείποντα μέρη. 
Τα μέρη της δομής αντιδρούν σε κάθε στιγμιαίο πάτημα με 
την αλλαγή του κειμένου και ο σπουδαστής χτίζει τις γραμμές έτσι
ότι αντιστοιχούν στις προτάσεις που ακούονται. Με τον κρότο
στο κουμπί ελέγχου η στοιχειώδης εργασία ελέγχεται, το σωστά 
κατασκευασμένο πάγωμα προτάσεων και οι σωστές γραμμές θα 
ακουστούν.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El estudiante tiene que tomar frases de las 
conversaciones de teléfono que tienen que ser aprendidas para 
poderlas utilizar automáticamente. La tarea contiene muchas 
frases útiles que se puedan utilizar por ejemplo en vida laboral. 
En el mismo tiempo el estudiante aprende tomar frases del 
discurso. El estudiante completa la estructura en base de lo que
oye he/she. Haciendo clic en tres teléfonos el estudiante oye 
las frases que se utilizan con frecuencia en el teléfono cuando una 
persona no puede ser alcanzada (los she?s asustados del?I?m fuera de 
la ciudad toda la semana. She?ll esté detrás el lunes?, 
?I?m apesadumbrado, él está en la otra línea. usted 
tiene gusto de sostener??). Hay ya algunas palabras listas en 
las estructuras bajo los teléfonos y la tarea es completar las piezas
que falta. Las partes de la estructura reaccionan en cada tecleo
cambiando el texto y el estudiante construye las líneas de modo que 
correspondan a las sentencias oídas. Haciendo clic en el botón
del cheque la tarea es controlada, las sentencias correctamente 
construidas congelan y las líneas correctas serán oídas.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>1563</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-01-12</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-15</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-15</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-15</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-15</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>fi</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">10-U</string>
            <string language="fi">&gt; 10</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Työelämän englannin alkeiden harjoittelu: miten kerrotaan, että joku on kokouksessa, lomalla jne.</string>
            <string language="en">Practicing the basic English in the world of work. How to tell that someone is at a meeting, on holiday etc.</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">englannin kieli</string>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>710</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">kielten opetus</string>
                <string language="en">language teaching</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">kielet</string>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82766</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/telephone_phrases/co1_19.exe</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
