<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/997010381</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>997010381</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>4314</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="it">Volare con le preposizioni</string>
            <string language="en">Flying with prepositions</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Fliegen mit Präpositionen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Voler avec des prépositions</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Voar com preposições</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πέταγμα με τις προθέσεις</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El volar con preposiciones</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="it">Questo oggetto di apprendimento dimostra come le preposizioni possono essere apprese usando animazioni ed effetti visivi. Lo scopo è di creare un'attività in cui il discente esercita una connessione visiva e auditiva tra le preposizioni e il loro significato. Questo oggetto di apprendimento è l'animazione di un aereo che vola in un cielo nuvoloso. Il discente deve scegliere le frasi preposizionali che collegano il percorso del volo dell'aereo cliccando sulla barra della parola. Il percorso di volo dell'aereo nell'animazione cambia illustrando il significato della preposizione, "attraverso la nuvola", "intorno alla nuvola", etc. Se il discente sceglie la frase preposizionale corretta, il programma gli offre un riscontro nella forma parlata in cui è menzionata la frase preposizionale. Se il discente sceglie la frase preposizionale sbagliata, l'aereo si abbatte.</string>
            <string language="en">This learning object demonstrates how prepositions can be learned using animation and visual effects.  Its goal is to create an activity where the learner makes a visual and aural connection between prepositions and their meaning.

This learning object is an animation of a plane flying in the sky where there are some clouds.  The learner has to choose the prepositional phrase that matches the plane’s flight path by clicking on the word bar.  The flight path of the plane in the animation changes illustrating the meaning of the preposition, e.g., “through the cloud”, “under the cloud”, “around the cloud”, etc. 

If the learner chooses the correct prepositional phrase, the program gives feedback in spoken form where the prepositional phrase is mentioned.  If the learner chooses the wrong prepositional phrase, the plane will crash.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>collection</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese erlernennachricht zeigt, wie Präpositionen 
mit Animation und Sichteffekten erlernt werden können. Sein 
Ziel ist, eine Aktivität zu erstellen, in der der Anfänger ein Sicht
bildet und Ohrenanschluß zwischen Präpositionen und ihrer 
meaning.This erlernennachricht eine Animation eines flachen Fliegens 
im Himmel ist, in dem es einige Wolken gibt. Der Anfänger muß 
den Präpositionalsatz wählen, der den plane?s Flugweg 
zusammenbringt, indem es auf dem Wortstab klickt. Der Flugweg 
der Fläche in der Animation ändert die Veranschaulichung der 
Bedeutung der Präposition z.B.?through die Wolke?, ?under die 
Wolke?, ?around die Wolke?, usw.. Wenn der Anfänger
den korrekten Präpositionalsatz wählt, gibt das Programm Feedback in
gesprochener Form, in der der Präpositionalsatz erwähnt wird. 
Wenn der Anfänger den falschen Präpositionalsatz wählt, 
bricht die Fläche ab.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cet objet d'étude démontre comment des 
prépositions peuvent être apprises en utilisant l'animation et les 
effets visuels. Son but est de créer une activité où 
l'étudiant fait un visuel et la connexion auditive entre les 
prépositions et leur objet d'étude de meaning.This est une animation
d'un vol plat dans le ciel où il y a quelques nuages. 
L'étudiant doit choisir la locution prépositive qui apparie la
voie d'accès de vol de plane?s en cliquant sur la barre de 
mot. La voie d'accès de vol de l'avion dans l'animation change 
illustrer la signification de la préposition, par exemple ?through le
nuage ?, ?under le nuage ?, ?around le nuage ?, 
etc... Si l'étudiant choisit la locution prépositive 
correcte, le programme donne le feedback sous la forme parlée où la 
locution prépositive est mentionnée. Si l'étudiant choisit la
locution prépositive fausse, l'avion s'écrasera.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este objeto de aprendizagem demonstra como as 
preposições podem ser aprendidas usando o animation e efeitos 
visuais. Seu objetivo é criar uma atividade onde o learner 
faça um visual e a conexão aural entre preposições e seu objeto de
aprendizagem de meaning.This seja um animation de um vôo plano no 
céu onde há algumas nuvens. O learner tem que escolher a frase
preposicional que combina o trajeto de vôo dos plane?s estalando na 
barra da palavra. O trajeto de vôo do plano no animation muda 
ilustrar o meaning da preposição, por exemplo?through a nuvem?, 
?under a nuvem?, ?around a nuvem?, etc.. Se o 
learner escolher a frase preposicional correta, o programa dá o 
feedback no formulário falado onde a frase preposicional é 
mencionada. Se o learner escolher a frase preposicional errada, 
o plano deixará de funcionar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το αντικείμενο εκμάθησης καταδεικνύει πώς οι 
προθέσεις μπορούν να μαθευτούν χρησιμοποιώντας τη ζωτικότητα και 
τα οπτικά αποτελέσματα. Ο στόχος του είναι να δημιουργήσει 
μια δραστηριότητα όπου ο αρχάριος κάνει μια οπτική και ακουστική
σύνδεση μεταξύ των προθέσεων και της έννοιάς τους Αυτό το 
αντικείμενο εκμάθησης είναι μια ζωτικότητα ενός αεροπλάνου που 
πετά στον ουρανό όπου υπάρχουν μερικά σύννεφα. Ο αρχάριος
πρέπει να επιλέξει την εμπρόθετη φράση που ταιριάζει με το 
μονοπάτι πτήσης plane?s με τον κρότο στη ράβδο λέξης. Το
μονοπάτι πτήσης του αεροπλάνου στις αλλαγές ζωτικότητας που 
επεξηγούν την έννοια της πρόθεσης, π.χ., ?through το σύννεφο;, 
?under το σύννεφο;, ?around το σύννεφο;, 
κ.λπ.... Εάν ο αρχάριος επιλέγει τη σωστή εμπρόθετη 
φράση, το πρόγραμμα δίνει την ανατροφοδότηση με προφορική μορφή 
όπου η εμπρόθετη φράση αναφέρεται. Εάν ο αρχάριος 
επιλέξει τη λανθασμένη εμπρόθετη φράση, το αεροπλάνο θα 
συντρίψει.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este objeto que aprende demuestra cómo las 
preposiciones se pueden aprender usando la animación y efectos 
visuales. Su meta es crear una actividad donde el principiante 
hace un visual y la conexión aural entre las preposiciones y su 
objeto que aprende de meaning.This es una animación de un vuelo plano
en el cielo donde hay algunas nubes. El principiante tiene que 
elegir la locución prepositiva que corresponde con el camino de vuelo
de los plane?s haciendo clic en la barra de la palabra. El 
camino de vuelo del plano en la animación cambia ilustrar el 
significado de la preposición, e.g.?through la nube?, ?under la
nube?, ?around la nube?, etc. Si el principiante 
elige la locución prepositiva correcta, el programa da feedback en la
forma hablada donde se menciona la locución prepositiva. Si el 
principiante elige la locución prepositiva incorrecta, el plano se 
estrellará.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>4314</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-02-26</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Congedo;Fiorenza;;;
FN:Fiorenza Congedo
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-28</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Congedo;Fiorenza;;;
FN:Fiorenza Congedo
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-28</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>web page</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">9-15</string>
            <string language="en">9-15</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="it">Ripasso delle frasi preposizionali in inglese</string>
            <string language="en">Review of prepositional phrases in English</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>712</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">Latin</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>997010381</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>audio/basic</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://resources.eun.org/demoportal/preposition_plane_eng.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
