<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82649</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82649</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>4012</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Sentence Snooker</string>
            <string language="sv">Sentence Snooker</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Programmsatzsnooker</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Billard de Phrase</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Snooker Da Sentença</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sentenzi Lo Snooker</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σνούκερ πρότασης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Snooker De la Sentencia</string>
          </title>
          <language>sv</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The goal of the learning object is to bring out game-like features in traditional structure exercises. The quite simple clause structures all  follow the same pattern. Typical of these patterns is that the student should achieve automatic accomplishments in them. That is the very reason why game-like exercise forms are very appropriate as to exercising structures and word order. 
The student's task is to build sentences by arranging the rows of balls so that one sentence is on one row of balls. Clicking a ball makes it fall down to the row underneath. If the ball does not contain any word it disappears. The student must figure out a strategy of action that enables him or her to put together as many sentences as possible. With other words, it does not always pay off to begin from the topmost row but the student must take all five sentences into consideration simultaneously and only take action after that. A sentence that has been formed correctly is heard spoken immediately after being put together. The exercise is completed when the student has got all the sentences together or when he or she has ended up in dead end and can not in any way put together new sentences. The balls disappear, the program shows the correctly formed sentences and they are also heard spoken. Then, the student's points are shown.


</string>
            <string language="sv">Målet med lärobjektet är att få fram spelliknande drag i traditionella strukturövningar. De ganska enkla satsstrukturerna följer alla samma mönster. Typiskt för dessa strukturer är att eleven borde uppnå automatiska prestationer i dem. Just därför är spelliknande övningsformer mycket lämpliga när det gäller att öva strukturer och ordföljd.
 
Elevens uppgift är att bilda meningar genom att arrangera raderna med bollar så att en mening är på en bollrad. Genom att klicka på en boll faller den ner till raden under. Om bollen inte innehåller något ord försvinner den. Eleven måste tänka ut en handlingsstrategi som gör att han eller hon kan sätta ihop så många meningar som möjligt. Det lönar sig alltså inte alltid att börja från översta raden utan man måste ta alla fem meningar i beaktande samtidigt och agera först sedan.

En mening som bildats korrekt hörs talad genast när den är ihopsatt. Uppgiften är färdigt utförd när eleven har fått ihop alla meningar eller när han eller hon hamnat i en återvändsgränd och inte på något sätt får ihop nya meningar. Bollarna försvinner, programmet visar de korrektbildade meningarna och de hörs också talade. Därefter visas elevens poäng.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Ziel der erlernennachricht ist herausbringen 
Spiel-wie Merkmale in den traditionellen Strukturübungen. Alle 
ziemlich einfache Klausel strukturiert folgen dem gleichen Muster. 
Typisch von diesen Mustern ist, daß der Kursteilnehmer 
automatische Vollendungen in ihnen erzielen sollte. Der ist der 
Grund, warum Spiel-wie Übung Formulare hinsichtlich der Ausübung der
Strukturen und der Wortstellung sehr angebracht sind. Die 
Aufgabe des Kursteilnehmers ist, Programmsätze aufzubauen, indem sie 
die Reihen der Kugeln ordnet, damit ein Programmsatz auf einer Reihe 
der Kugeln ist. Das Anklicken einer Kugel bildet, welches sie, 
werfen Fall zur Reihe darunterliegend nieder. Wenn die Kugel 
kein Wort enthält, verschwindet sie. Der Kursteilnehmer muß 
aus einer Strategie der Tätigkeit darstellen, die ihn oder sie 
aktiviert, bis zu Programmsätze möglich zusammenzufügen. Mit 
anderen Wörtern zahlt sie nicht immer aus, von der obersten Reihe 
anzufangen, aber der Kursteilnehmer muß alle fünf Programmsätze in 
Erwägung gleichzeitig ziehen und Tätigkeit das nur nachher nehmen. 
Einem Programmsatz, der richtig gebildet worden ist, wird 
gesprochen gehört, sofort nachdem zusammenfügend. Die Übung 
wird durchgeführt, wenn der Kursteilnehmer alle zusammen 
Programmsätze hat, oder wenn er oder sie oben in der Sackgasse 
fertiggeworden sind und nicht in keinen Weise gesetzten neuen zusammen
Programmsätzen können. Die Kugeln verschwinden, die 
Programmerscheinen die richtig gebildeten Programmsätze und ihnen 
werden auch gesprochen gehört. Dann werden die Punkte des 
Kursteilnehmers gezeigt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le but de l'objet d'étude est mettent en 
évidence jeu-comme des dispositifs dans des exercices traditionnels 
de structure. Toute la clause tout à fait simple structure 
suivent la même configuration. Typique de ces configurations 
est que l'étudiant devrait réaliser des accomplissements 
automatiques dans eux. C'est la raison même pour laquelle 
jeu-comme l'exercice les formes sont très appropriées quant à 
exercer des structures et l'ordre des mots. L'étudiant 
chargent doit établir des phrases en arrangeant les lignes des
boules de sorte qu'une phrase soit sur une ligne des boules. 
Cliquer une boule la fait que la chute avalent à la 
ligne dessous. Si la boule ne contient aucun mot elle 
disparaît. L'étudiant doit figurer hors d'une stratégie de 
l'action qui lui permet de remonter autant de phrases comme possibles.
Par d'autres mots, elle ne paye pas toujours hors fonction pour 
commencer de la ligne le plus élevé mais l'étudiant doit prendre en
compte chacune des cinq phrases simultanément et seulement prendre à
action ensuite cela. Une phrase qui a été formée correctement
est entendue parlée juste après qu'étant remonté. L'exercice
est terminé quand l'étudiant a toutes les phrases ensemble ou quand 
lui ou elle a terminé vers le haut dans l'extrémité morte et ne 
peut pas de quelque façon nouvelles phrases ensemble mises. Les
boules disparaissent, les expositions de programme les phrases 
correctement formées et elles sont également entendues parlées. 
Puis, les points de l'étudiant sont montrés.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O objetivo do objeto de aprendizagem é trazer 
para fora jogo-como características em exercícios tradicionais da 
estrutura. Toda a cláusula completamente simples estrutura 
segue o mesmo teste padrão. Típico destes testes padrões é 
que o estudante deve conseguir realizações automáticas nelas. 
Aquela é a razão very porque jogo-como o exercício os 
formulários são muito apropriados a respeito de exercitar estruturas
e ordem de palavra. A tarefa do estudante é construir 
sentenças arranjando as fileiras das esferas de modo que uma 
sentença esteja em uma fileira das esferas. Estalar uma esfera 
fá-la que a queda traga à fileira embaixo. Se a esfera não 
contiver nenhuma palavra desaparece. O estudante deve figurar 
para fora de uma estratégia da ação que a permite o ou de unir 
tantas como sentenças como possíveis. Com outras palavras, 
não paga sempre fora para começar da fileira topmost mas o estudante
deve fazer exame de todas as cinco sentenças na consideração 
simultaneamente e somente fazer exame ação em seguida disso. 
Uma sentença que seja dada forma corretamente é ouvida falada 
imediatamente depois que sendo unido. O exercício está 
terminado quando o estudante tem todas as sentenças junto ou quando 
ou terminaram acima na extremidade inoperante e não podem em nenhumas
sentenças novas junto postas maneira. As esferas desaparecem, 
as mostras do programa as sentenças corretamente dadas forma e são 
ouvidas também faladas. Então, os pontos do estudante são 
mostrados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'obiettivo dell'oggetto imparante è mette in 
evidenza gioco-come le caratteristiche nelle esercitazioni 
tradizionali della struttura. La clausola abbastanza semplice 
struttura tutta segue lo stesso modello. Tipico di questi 
modelli è che l'allievo dovrebbe realizzare loro le realizzazioni 
automatiche. Quella è la ragione per la quale stessa gioco-come
l'esercitazione le forme sono molto adatte quanto ad esercitare le 
strutture e l'ordine delle parole. L'operazione dell'allievo è 
di sviluppare le frasi organizzando le file delle sfere in modo che 
una frase sia su una fila delle sfere. Scattare una sfera la fa 
che la caduta si scola alla fila sotto. Se la sfera non contiene
alcuna parola sparisce. L'allievo deve calcolare verso l'esterno
una strategia di azione che gli permette di unire altretante frasi 
come possibili. Con altre parole, non paga sempre fuori 
cominciare dalla fila superiore ma l'allievo deve prendere 
simultaneamente tutte e cinque le frasi in considerazione e soltanto 
agire dopo quello. Una frase che è stata formata correttamente 
è sentita parlata subito dopo che essendo unendo. 
L'esercitazione è completata quando l'allievo ha insieme tutte 
le frasi o quando lui o lei si è conclusa in su in estremità guasto 
e non può in alcune nuove frasi insieme messe modo. Le sfere 
spariscono, le esposizioni di programma le frasi correttamente formate
ed egualmente sono sentite parlate. Allora, i punti dell'allievo
sono indicati.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο στόχος του αντικειμένου εκμάθησης είναι να 
παρουσιαστούν έξω τα game-like χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα στις 
παραδοσιακές ασκήσεις δομών. Η αρκετά απλή πρόταση κτίζει
όλων ακολουθεί το ίδιο πρότυπο. Χαρακτηριστικό αυτών των 
προτύπων είναι ότι ο σπουδαστής πρέπει να επιτύχει τις 
αυτόματες ολοκληρώσεις σε τα. Αυτός είναι ο ίδιος ο λόγος 
για τον οποίο οι game-like μορφές άσκησης είναι πολύ 
κατάλληλες ως προς την άσκηση των δομών και της σειράς των 
λέξεων. Η στοιχειώδης εργασία του σπουδαστή είναι να 
χτίσει τις προτάσεις με την τακτοποίηση των σειρών των σφαιρών 
έτσι ώστε μια πρόταση είναι σε μια σειρά των σφαιρών. Ο 
κρότος μιας σφαίρας το κάνει την πτώση κάτω στη σειρά κάτω 
από. Εάν η σφαίρα δεν περιέχει οποιαδήποτε λέξη 
εξαφανίζεται. Ο σπουδαστής πρέπει να υπολογίσει μια 
στρατηγική της ενέργειας που επιτρέπει σε σε για να βάλει μαζί 
όσο το δυνατόν περισσότερες προτάσεις. Με άλλες λέξεις, 
όχι πάντα πληρώνει μακριά για να αρχίσει από την κορυφαία 
σειρά αλλά ο σπουδαστής πρέπει να λάβει υπόψη και τις πέντε 
προτάσεις ταυτόχρονα και μόνο να λάβει μέτρα μετά από αυτό. 
Μια πρόταση που έχει διαμορφωθεί σωστά ακούγεται 
προφορικός αμέσως μετά από να τεθεί από κοινού. Η άσκηση
ολοκληρώνεται όταν έχει ο σπουδαστής όλες τις προτάσεις μαζί ή
όταν καταλήξει στο αδιέξοδο και δεν μπορεί να βάλει από καμιά 
άποψη μαζί τις νέες προτάσεις. Οι σφαίρες εξαφανίζονται, 
το πρόγραμμα εμφανίζει σωστά διαμορφωμένες προτάσεις και 
ακούγονται επίσης προφορικός. Κατόπιν, τα σημεία του 
σπουδαστή εμφανίζονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La meta del objeto que aprende es pone en 
evidencia juego-como características en ejercicios tradicionales de 
la estructura. La cláusula absolutamente simple estructura toda
sigue el mismo modelo. Típico de estos modelos es que el 
estudiante debe alcanzar realizaciones automáticas en ellas. 
Ésa es la misma razón por la que juego-como ejercicio las 
formas son muy apropiadas en cuanto a ejercitar las estructuras y 
orden de las palabras. La tarea del estudiante es construir 
sentencias arreglando las filas de bolas de modo que una sentencia 
esté en una fila de bolas. Hacer clic una bola la hace que la 
caída traga a la fila debajo. Si la bola no contiene ninguna 
palabra desaparece. El estudiante debe calcular fuera de una 
estrategia de la acción que permite le o le poner juntas tantas 
sentencias como sea posible. Con otras palabras, no paga siempre
apagado comenzar de la fila topmost pero el estudiante debe tomar las 
cinco sentencias en la consideración simultáneamente y solamente 
tomar a acción después eso. Una sentencia que se ha formado 
correctamente se oye hablada inmediatamente después que siendo 
juntado. Se termina el ejercicio cuando el estudiante tiene 
todas las sentencias juntas o cuando él o ella ha terminado para 
arriba en callejón sin salida y no puede en ningunas juntas nuevas 
sentencias puestas manera. Las bolas desaparecen, las 
demostraciones del programa las sentencias correctamente formadas y 
también se oyen habladas. Entonces, se muestran las puntas del 
estudiante.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>4012</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-02-16</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-30</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-30</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-30</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-30</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-30</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-30</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>sv</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>continuing education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">10-15</string>
            <string language="sv">10-15</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Exercise of elementary clause structures in English and of the word order.</string>
            <string language="sv">Övning av elementära satsstrukturer i engelska samt av ordföljden.</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
                <string language="sv">språkområden</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
                <string language="sv">engelska språket</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82649</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>audio/basic</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://resources.eun.org/demoportal/sentence_snooker_sve.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
