<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82770</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82770</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>1536</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="fi">Harrastukset</string>
            <string language="en">Hobbies</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Liebhabereien</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Passe-temps</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Passatempos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Hobby</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Χόμπι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Manías</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Tämän aihion tavoitteena on sanaston harjoittaminen kontekstirikkaassa multimediaympäristössä ja aidonoloisen puheen lomassa. Oppilaan tehtävänä on tunnistaa harrastuksen kuvauksen ydinkohdat ja liittää ne harrastustilannetta esittävään kuvaan.

Harjoittelutilanteen alkaessa oppilaan edessä on kuvaruudulla joukko kuvia, jotka esittävät erilaisia suomalaisten nuorten harrastuksia, sekä joukko puhekuplia. Kun puhekuplaa napauttaa kerran, siitä kuuluu harrastuksen esittely, mutta ei varsinaista nimeä. Oppilaan tehtävänä on siirtää puhekupla aina sen harrastuksen päälle, josta kuplassa on puhe. Jos siirto on oikea, kupla häviää ja oppilas saa vahvistavan kommentin. Lisäksi oikean vastauksen jälkeen ruudulle ilmestyy ns. gapfill-ruutu, jossa juuri kuultu lause on kirjoitettuna. Oppilaan tulee täyttää lauseesta puuttuva(t) sana(t) kirjoittamalla ne aukkoon. Tämä pakottaa oppilaan kuuntelemaan saamaansa palautetta tarkemmin ja vahvistaa myös harrastuksiin liittyvien sanojen oppimista. Väärin asetetut kuplat valuvat takaisin alkuasemiinsa pysähdyttyään ensin paikoilleen puhutun kommentin ajaksi. 

Toisessa vaiheessa harjoitellaan tehtävän edellisessä vaiheessa tutuiksi tulleita sanoja. Tällöin kuplien tilalla on puhuvat palkit, joita napauttamalla oppilas kuulee harrastusten nimiä. Hänen tulee siirtää palkit yläpuolella oleviin vastaaviin kuviin. Kun oppilas on mielestään valmis, hän saa palautetta suorituksestaan napauttamalla Tarkista-painiketta. Oikein menneet palkit katoavat ja oppilas kuulee ja näkee sanan kirjoitettuna. Väärässä kuvassa olleet palkit palautuvat ruudun alalaitaan ja oppilas saa kehoituksen yrittää uudelleen.
Sanan visualisointi auttaa oppilasta sen muistamisessa ja tekee sanaston opiskelusta mielekkäämpää. Äänen kuuleminen tuo myöskin lisäarvoa tehtävään: oppilas kokee sanan usealla aistilla ja siten aihio tukee monenlaisia oppijoita.</string>
            <string language="en">This is an exercise on vocabulary in a multimedia environment. The task is to identify the essential points of the description of a hobby and fit them with the picture of it. Starting the task the student has a set of pictures on hobbies of Finnish children on the screen and a set of balloons. When the balloon is clicked once the presentation of the hobby is heard but not what the hobby is. The task is to fit the right balloon with the right hobby. If the student’s choice is correct the balloon disappears and the student gets a reinforcing comment and a gap-fill pane will appear on the screen with the sentence in writing. The student has to fill in the missing word(s). This makes the student listen more carefully to the given feedback and in this way he / she will learn the vocabulary on the hobbies better. The balloons that have been placed incorrectly slide back to their original places after they have first stopped during the spoken comment. In the second face of the task the already familiar words are practised. In this task there are bars instead of balloons and the student hears names of hobbies by clicking them. The bars have to be fitted to the pictures above. When the student has finished the task feedback is given by clicking the Check button. The correct bars will disappear and the student will hear and see the correct word.  The bars which have been on the wrong picture will slide down on the bottom of the page and the student is asked to try again. The visualisation of the word makes it easier for the student to remember the word and makes learning vocabulary more meaningful. Hearing the voice is also an added value as the student can use many senses and in this way the task helps different kinds of learners.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses ist eine Übung auf Wortschatz in einer 
Multimediaumgebung. Die Aufgabe ist, die wesentlichen Punkte der
Beschreibung einer Liebhaberei zu kennzeichnen und sie mit der 
Abbildung von ihr zu passen. Die Aufgabe beginnend, hat der 
Kursteilnehmer ein Set Abbildungen auf Liebhabereien der finnischen 
Kinder auf dem Bildschirm und ein Set Ballone. Wenn der Ballon 
einmal geklickt wird, wird die Darstellung der Liebhaberei gehört, 
aber nicht, was die Liebhaberei ist. Die Aufgabe ist, den 
rechten Ballon mit der rechten Liebhaberei zu passen. Wenn die 
student?s Wahl der Ballon verschwindet korrekt ist und der 
Kursteilnehmer erhält einen verstärkenkommentar und Abstand-füllen 
Sie Scheibe erscheint auf dem Bildschirm mit dem Programmsatz im 
Schreiben. Der Kursteilnehmer muß die fehlenden Wörter 
ausfüllen. Dieses läßt den Kursteilnehmer zum gegebenen 
Feedback sorgfältig hören und auf diese Art erlernen er/sie den 
Wortschatz auf den Liebhabereien besser. Die Ballone, die falsch
plaziert worden sind, schieben zurück zu ihren ursprünglichen 
Plätzen, nachdem sie zuerst während des gesprochenen Kommentars 
gestoppt haben. Im zweiten Gesicht der Aufgabe werden die 
bereits vertrauten Wörter geübt. In dieser Aufgabe gibt es 
Stäbe anstelle von den Ballonen und der Kursteilnehmer hört Namen 
von Liebhabereien, indem er sie anklickt. Die Stäbe müssen zu 
den Abbildungen oben gepaßt werden. Wenn der Kursteilnehmer 
beendet hat, wird das Aufgabefeedback gegeben, indem man die 
Überprüfung Taste anklickt. Die korrekten Stäbe verschwinden 
und der Kursteilnehmer hört und sieht das korrekte Wort. Die 
Stäbe, die auf der falschen Abbildung gewesen sind, schieben unten 
auf die Unterseite der Seite und des Kursteilnehmers wird gebeten, 
noch einmal zu versuchen. Die Sichtbarmachung des Wortes bildet 
es einfacher, damit der Kursteilnehmer an das Wort sich erinnert und 
bildet erlernenwortschatz aussagefähiger. Die Stimme zu hören 
ist auch ein hinzugefügter Wert, wie der Kursteilnehmer viele 
Richtungen verwenden kann und auf diese Art die Aufgabe 
unterschiedlichen Arten der Anfänger hilft.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">C'est un exercice sur le vocabulaire dans un 
environnement de multimédia. Le charger doit identifier les
points essentiels de la description d'un passe-temps et les équiper 
de l'image de lui. Commençant le charger l'étudiant a un 
ensemble d'images sur des passe-temps des enfants finlandais sur 
l'écran et un ensemble de ballons. Quand le ballon est 
cliqué une fois la présentation du passe-temps est 
entendue mais pas ce qui est le passe-temps. Le charger doit
équiper le ballon droit du bon passe-temps. Si le choix de 
student?s est correct le ballon disparaît et l'étudiant obtient un 
commentaire de renforcement et intervalle-remplissez carreau 
apparaîtra sur l'écran avec la phrase dans l'écriture. 
L'étudiant doit compléter les mots manquants. Ceci 
incite l'étudiant à écouter plus soigneusement le feedback donné 
et de cette façon lui/elle apprendra le vocabulaire sur les 
passe-temps mieux. Les ballons qui ont été placés 
inexactement glissent de nouveau à leurs endroits initiaux après 
qu'ils se soient d'abord arrêtés pendant le commentaire parlé. 
Dans le deuxième visage du charger les mots déjà 
familiers sont pratiqués. En cela chargez là sont des
barres au lieu des ballons et l'étudiant entend des noms des 
passe-temps en les cliquant. Les barres doivent être 
adaptées aux images ci-dessus. Quand l'étudiant a terminé le 
feedback de charger est donné en cliquant le bouton de 
contrôle. Les barres correctes disparaîtront et l'étudiant 
entendra et verra le mot correct. Les barres qui ont été sur 
l'image fausse glisseront vers le bas sur le bas de la page et de 
l'étudiant est invitées à essayer encore. La visualisation du
mot le facilite pour que l'étudiant se rappelle le mot et rend le 
vocabulaire d'étude plus signicatif. Entendre la voix est 
également une valeur ajoutée comme l'étudiant peut utiliser 
beaucoup de sens et de cette façon le charger aide différents 
genres d'étudiants.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este é um exercício no vocabulário em um 
ambiente dos multimedia. A tarefa é identificar os pontos 
essenciais da descrição de um passatempo e cabê-los com o retrato 
dela. Começando a tarefa o estudante tem um jogo dos retratos 
em passatempos das crianças finnish na tela e um jogo dos balões. 
Quando o balão é estalado uma vez a apresentação do 
passatempo está ouvida mas não o que o passatempo é. A tarefa
é caber o balão direito com o passatempo direito. Se a escolha
dos student?s estiver correta o balão desaparecer e o estudante 
começa um comentário reforçando e abertura-encha a placa aparecerá
na tela com a sentença na escrita. O estudante tem que 
preencher as palavras faltantes. Isto faz o estudante escutar 
mais com cuidado o feedback dado e nesta maneira/aprenderá o 
vocabulário nos passatempos mais melhor. Os balões que foram 
colocados incorretamente deslizam para trás a seus lugares originais 
depois que pararam primeiramente durante o comentário falado. 
Na segunda cara da tarefa as palavras já familiares são 
praticadas. Nesta tarefa há barras em vez dos balões e o 
estudante ouve nomes dos passatempos estalando os. As barras 
têm que ser cabidas aos retratos acima. Quando o estudante 
terminou o feedback da tarefa está dado estalando a tecla da 
verificação. As barras corretas desaparecerão e o estudante 
ouvirá e verá a palavra correta. As barras que estiveram no 
retrato errado deslizarão para baixo no fundo da página e do 
estudante são pedidas para tentar outra vez. O visualisation da
palavra faz mais fácil para que o estudante recorde a palavra e faz o
vocabulário de aprendizagem mais significativo. Ouvir a voz é 
também um valor adicionado como o estudante pode usar muitos sentidos
e nesta maneira a tarefa ajuda a tipos diferentes dos learners.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ciò è un'esercitazione su vocabolario in un 
ambiente di multimedia. L'operazione è di identificare i punti 
essenziali della descrizione di un hobby e di misura con l'immagine di
esso. Iniziando l'operazione l'allievo ha un insieme delle 
immagini sugli hobby dei bambini finlandesi sullo schermo e un insieme
degli aerostati. Quando l'aerostato è scattato una volta la 
presentazione dell'hobby è sentita ma non che cosa l'hobby è. 
L'operazione è di misura l'aerostato di destra con il giusto 
hobby. Se la scelta degli student?s è corretta l'aerostato 
sparisce e l'allievo ottiene un commento rinforzante e spacco-riempia 
la lastra di vetro comparirà sullo schermo con la frase nella 
scrittura. L'allievo deve riempire le parole mancanti. 
Ciò incita l'allievo a ascoltare più con attenzione le date 
risposte ed in questo modo lui/lei imparerà più meglio il 
vocabolario sugli hobby. Gli aerostati che sono stati disposti 
in modo errato fanno scorrere di nuovo ai loro posti originali dopo 
che in primo luogo si siano arrestati durante il commento parlato. 
Nella seconda faccia dell'operazione le parole già esperte si 
esercitano in. In questa operazione ci sono barre anziché gli 
aerostati e l'allievo sente i nomi degli hobby scattandoli. Le 
barre devono misura alle immagini qui sopra. Quando l'allievo ha
rifinito le risposte di operazione sono date scattando il tasto del 
controllo. Le barre corrette spariranno e l'allievo sentirà e 
vedrà la parola corretta. Le barre che sono state sull'immagine
errata faranno scorrere giù sulla parte inferiore della pagina e 
dell'allievo è chiesta di provare ancora. La visualizzazione 
della parola lo rende più facile affinchè l'allievo si ricordi della
parola e rende il vocabolario imparante più espressivo. Sentire
la voce è egualmente un valore aggiunto come l'allievo può usare 
molti sensi ed in questo modo l'operazione aiuta i generi differenti 
di principianti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό είναι μια άσκηση στο λεξιλόγιο σε ένα 
περιβάλλον πολυμέσων. Η στοιχειώδης εργασία είναι να 
προσδιοριστούν τα ουσιαστικά σημεία της περιγραφής ενός χόμπι 
και να εγκατασταθούν με την εικόνα από το. Αρχικός τη 
στοιχειώδη εργασία ο σπουδαστής έχει ένα σύνολο εικόνων στα 
χόμπι των φινλανδικών παιδιών στην οθόνη και ένα σύνολο 
μπαλονιών. Όταν το μπαλόνι χτυπιέται μόλις ακουγστεί η 
παρουσίαση του χόμπι αλλά όχι τι το χόμπι είναι. Η 
στοιχειώδης εργασία είναι να εγκατασταθεί το σωστό μπαλόνι με το
σωστό χόμπι. Εάν η επιλογή student?s είναι σωστή το 
μπαλόνι εξαφανίζεται και ο σπουδαστής παίρνει ένα ενισχύοντας 
σχόλιο και ένα πλακάκι χάσμα-αφθονίας θα εμφανιστεί στην οθόνη 
με την πρόταση γράφοντας εγγράφως. Ο σπουδαστής πρέπει να 
συμπληρώσει την ελλείπουσα λέξη (σ). Αυτό κάνει το 
σπουδαστή να ακούσει προσεκτικότερα τη δεδομένη ανατροφοδότηση 
και κατ' αυτό τον τρόπο θα μάθει το λεξιλόγιο στα χόμπι 
καλύτερα. Τα μπαλόνια που είναι τοποθετημένη ανακριβώς 
φωτογραφική διαφάνεια πίσω στις αρχικές θέσεις τους αφότου 
έχουν σταματήσει αρχικά κατά τη διάρκεια του προφορικού 
σχολίου. Στο δεύτερο πρόσωπο της στοιχειώδους εργασίας οι 
ήδη γνωστές λέξεις ασκούνται. Σε αυτήν την στοιχειώδη 
εργασία υπάρχουν ράβδοι αντί των μπαλονιών και ο σπουδαστής 
ακούει τα ονόματα των χόμπι με τον κρότο τους. Οι ράβδοι 
πρέπει να εγκατασταθούν στις εικόνες ανωτέρω. Όταν ο 
σπουδαστής τελειώσει η στοιχειώδης ανατροφοδότηση δίνεται με τον 
κρότο του κουμπιού ελέγχου. Οι σωστές ράβδοι θα 
εξαφανιστούν και ο σπουδαστής θα ακούσει και θα δει τη 
σωστή λέξη. Οι ράβδοι που ήταν στη λανθασμένη εικόνα θα 
γλιστρήσουν κάτω στο κατώτατο σημείο της σελίδας και ο 
σπουδαστής καλείται να προσπαθήσει πάλι. Η απεικόνιση της 
λέξης διευκολύνει το σπουδαστή να θυμηθεί τη λέξη και καθιστά το
λεξιλόγιο εκμάθησης σημαντικότερο. Η ακοή της φωνής είναι 
επίσης μια προστιθέμενη αξία δεδομένου ότι ο σπουδαστής μπορεί 
να χρησιμοποιήσει πολλές αισθήσεις και κατ' αυτό τον τρόπο η 
στοιχειώδης εργασία βοηθά τα διαφορετικά είδη αρχαρίων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esto es un ejercicio en vocabulario en un ambiente
de las multimedias. La tarea es identificar las puntas 
esenciales de la descripción de una manía y caberlas con el cuadro 
de ella. Comenzando la tarea el estudiante tiene un conjunto de 
cuadros en manías de los niños finlandeses en la pantalla y un 
conjunto de globos. Cuando el globo se hace clic una vez la 
presentación de la manía se oye pero no cuáles la manía es. 
La tarea es caber el globo derecho con la manía derecha. 
Si desaparece la opción de los student?s está correcta el 
globo y el estudiante consigue un comentario que refuerza y 
boquete-llene el cristal aparecerá en la pantalla con la sentencia en
la escritura. El estudiante tiene que completar las palabras que
falta. Esto hace que el estudiante escucha más cuidadosamente 
el feedback dado y de esta manera él/ella aprenderá el vocabulario 
en las manías mejor. Los globos que se han colocado 
incorrectamente resbalan de nuevo a sus lugares originales después de
que primero hayan parado durante el comentario hablado. En la 
segunda cara de la tarea se practican las palabras ya familiares. 
En esta tarea hay barras en vez de los globos y el estudiante 
oye nombres de manías haciéndolas clic. Las barras tienen que 
ser cabidas a los cuadros arriba. Cuando el estudiante ha 
acabado el feedback de la tarea es dado haciendo clic el botón del 
cheque. Las barras correctas desaparecerán y el estudiante 
oirá y verá la palabra correcta. Las barras que han estado en 
el cuadro incorrecto resbalarán abajo en el fondo de la paginación y
del estudiante se piden intentar otra vez. La visualización de 
la palabra hace más fácil para que el estudiante recuerde la palabra
y hace vocabulario que aprende más significativo. Oír la voz 
es también un valor agregado como el estudiante puede utilizar muchos
sentidos y de esta manera la tarea ayuda a diversas clases de 
principiantes.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>1536</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2003-12-29</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-11</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-11</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-11</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-11</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>fi</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">10-14</string>
            <string language="fi">10-14</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Suomen kielen kuullunymmärtämisen ja sanaston harjoittelu</string>
            <string language="en">Practicing the listening comprehension and the vocabulary of Finnish</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">englannin kieli</string>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>718</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">oppiminen</string>
                <string language="en">learning</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">kielet</string>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82770</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://resources.eun.org/demoportal/hobbies_fi.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
