<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82520</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82520</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>1534</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="fi">Word stress and meaning</string>
            <string language="en">Word Stress and Meaning</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wort-Druck und Bedeutung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Effort et signification de mot</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Stress e meaning da palavra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sforzo e significato di parola</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πίεση και σημασία λέξης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Tensión y significado de la palabra</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Aihio tarjoaa harjoitteen kielen osa-alueesta, joka on ymmärtämisen kannalta tärkeä, mutta jota on hyvin vaikea harjoitella perinteisin menetelmin. Tarkoituksena on opettaa oppilasta tarkkailemaan lauseen prosodiikkaa. Sillä, miten lauseen sanoo, on joskus suurikin vaikutus sen merkitykseen.
Oppilas näkee tehtävän aikana kahdessa sarakkeessa neljä tai viisi puhekuplaa/palkkia kummassakin. Palkeista kuuluu lause, kun oppilas napauttaa niitä. Vasemmanpuoleiset lauseet ovat sanasisällöltään samoja, mutta lausepaino vaihtelee. Oppilaan tehtävä on siirtää palkit vierekkäin siten, että vasemmanpuoleinen lause saa vierelleen merkitykseltään sopivan reaktion. Oikeat lauseet tulevat näkyviin Tarkista-painikkeen napautuksella ja oppilas kuulee lauseparin puhuttuna. Pistelaskuri näyttää oppilaan tuloksen.</string>
            <string language="en">This exercise gives the student the opportunity to practise the field of language which is important for understanding but which is difficult to practise by using traditional methods. The intention here is to teach the student to pay attention to the prosodic features of the sentence. How a sentence is said has sometimes a huge effect on its meaning. In the task the student sees 4-5 balloons/bars in two columns. When clicking on the bar a sentence will be heard. The sentences on the left are the same but their intonation differs. The task is to match the bars so that the sentence on the left gets next to it a reaction that fits. The correct sentence can be seen by pressing the Check button. The student will hear the sentences and see the score.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Übung gibt dem Kursteilnehmer die 
Gelegenheit, auffangene der Sprache zu üben, die für das 
Verstehen wichtig ist, aber die schwierig, indem das Verwenden der 
traditionellen Methoden zu üben ist. Die Absicht hier ist, den 
Kursteilnehmer zu unterrichten, die prosodischen Merkmale des 
Programmsatzes zu beachten. Wie ein Programmsatz besagt ist, 
läßt manchmal ein sehr großes auf seiner Bedeutung bewirken. 
In der Aufgabe sieht der Kursteilnehmer 4-5 balloons/bars in 
zwei Spalten. Beim Klicken auf dem Stab wird ein Programmsatz 
gehört. Die Programmsätze auf dem links sind dieselben, aber 
ihre Intonation unterscheidet sich. Die Aufgabe ist, die Stäbe 
zusammenzubringen, damit der Programmsatz auf dem links nahe bei ihm 
eine Reaktion erhält, die paßt. Der korrekte Programmsatz kann
gesehen werden, indem man die Überprüfung Taste betätigt. Der
Kursteilnehmer hört die Programmsätze und sieht die Kerbe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cet exercice donne à l'étudiant l'occasion de 
pratiquer la zone du langage qui est important pour l'arrangement mais
qui il est difficile pratiquer en utilisant des méthodes 
traditionnelles. L'intention ici est d'enseigner l'étudiant à 
prêter l'attention aux dispositifs prosodiques de la phrase. 
Comment une phrase est dite fait effet parfois un énorme sur sa
signification. Dans le charger l'étudiant voit 4-5 
balloons/bars dans deux colonnes. Quand cliquant sur la 
barre une phrase sera entendue. Les phrases du côté gauche 
sont identiques mais leur intonation diffère. Le charger 
doit apparier les barres de sorte que la phrase du côté gauche 
obtienne à côté d'elle une réaction qui s'adapte. La phrase 
correcte peut être vue en appuyant sur le bouton de contrôle. 
L'étudiant entendra les phrases et verra les points.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este exercício dá ao estudante a oportunidade de
praticar o campo da língua que são importante para compreender mas 
que é difícil de praticar usando métodos tradicionais. A 
intenção aqui é ensinar o estudante pagar a atenção às 
características prosodic da sentença. Como uma sentença é 
dita manda às vezes um enorme efetuar em seu meaning. Na tarefa
o estudante vê 4-5 balloons/bars em duas colunas. Ao estalar na
barra uma sentença será ouvida. As sentenças na esquerda são
as mesmas mas seu intonation difere. A tarefa é combinar as 
barras de modo que a sentença na esquerda comece ao lado dela uma 
reação que caiba. A sentença correta pode ser vista 
pressionando a tecla da verificação. O estudante ouvirá as 
sentenças e verá a contagem.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa esercitazione dà all'allievo l'occasione 
esercitarsi nel campo del linguaggio che è importante per capire ma 
che è difficile da esercitarsi in usando i metodi tradizionali. 
L'intenzione qui è insegnare l'allievo prestare l'attenzione 
alle caratteristiche prosodiche della frase. Come una frase è 
detta fa a volte effetto un enorme sul relativo significato. 
Nell'operazione l'allievo vede 4-5 balloons/bars in due colonne.
Nel scattarsi sulla barra una frase sarà sentita. Le 
frasi a sinistra sono le stesse ma il loro intonation differisce da. 
L'operazione è di abbinare le barre in modo che la frase a 
sinistra ottenga vicino esso una reazione che misura. La frase 
corretta può essere vista premendo il tasto del controllo. 
L'allievo sentirà le frasi e vedrà il segno.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η άσκηση δίνει στο σπουδαστή την ευκαιρία να 
ασκήσει το πεδίο της γλώσσας που είναι σημαντικό για την 
κατανόηση αλλά που είναι δύσκολο στην πρακτική με τη 
χρησιμοποίηση των παραδοσιακών μεθόδων. Η πρόθεση είναι 
εδώ να διδαχθεί ο σπουδαστής για να δώσει προσοχή στα προσωδικά 
χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα της πρότασης. Πώς μια πρόταση 
λέγεται ότι έχει μερικές φορές μια τεράστια επίδραση στην 
έννοιά του. Στη στοιχειώδη εργασία ο σπουδαστής 
βλέπει 4-5 μπαλόνια/ράβδους σε δύο στήλες. Κατά
κρότο στη ράβδο την πρόταση θα ακουστεί. Οι προτάσεις στο 
αριστερό είναι οι ίδιες αλλά ο προσωδία τους διαφέρει. Η 
στοιχειώδης εργασία είναι να ταιριαχτούν με οι ράβδοι έτσι ώστε
η πρόταση στο αριστερό παίρνει δίπλα σε το μια αντίδραση που 
εγκαθιστά. Η σωστή πρόταση μπορεί να δει με την 
πίεση του κουμπιού ελέγχου. Ο σπουδαστής θα ακούσει τις 
προτάσεις και θα δει το αποτέλεσμα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este ejercicio da a estudiante la oportunidad de 
practicar el campo del lenguaje que es importante para entender pero 
que es difícil de practicar usando métodos tradicionales. La 
intención aquí es enseñar al estudiante a prestar la atención a 
las características prosódicas de la sentencia. Cómo una 
sentencia es dicha hace que a veces un enorme efectúe en su 
significado. En la tarea el estudiante ve 4-5 balloons/bars en 
dos columnas. Al hacer clic en la barra una sentencia será 
oída. Las sentencias a la izquierda son iguales pero su 
entonación diferencia. La tarea es corresponder con las barras 
de modo que la sentencia a la izquierda consiga al lado de ella una 
reacción que quepa. La sentencia correcta puede ser considerada
presionando el botón del cheque. El estudiante oirá las 
sentencias y verá la cuenta.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>1534</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2003-12-29</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-11</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-11</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>fi</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">10-15</string>
            <string language="fi">10-15</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Englannin kielen ääntämistavan ja merkityksen vuorovaikutuksen ymmärtäminen</string>
            <string language="en">Understanding the interaction of the English pronunciation and meaning</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>710</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">kielten opetus</string>
                <string language="en">language teaching</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">kielet</string>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">englannin kieli</string>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82520</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>audio/basic</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/word_stress_and_meaning/CO1_2.exe</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
