<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82821</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82821</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>3979</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">BurgerWriter</string>
            <string language="sv">BurgerWriter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">BurgerWriter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">BurgerWriter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">BurgerWriter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">BurgerWriter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">BurgerWriter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">BurgerWriter</string>
          </title>
          <language>sv</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The objective of this learning resource is to develop features similar to games in the grammar exercises. Teaching the basics in a language contains plenty of simple structures. Typical of these structures is that the student should learn to produce them automatically. Therefore, the exercises similar to games fit in here. The student's task is to design grammatically correct expressions by, in correct order, choosing a phrase or a word from the different layers of the hamburger. Further, the sentences are to link to the small picture to the left. If the structure is correct the student will hear it spoken and get a hamburger as a reward. Based on the number of hamburgers you can see the number of points for every student.</string>
            <string language="sv">Målet med detta lärobjekt är att ta fram spelliknande drag i grammatikövningarna. Undervisning i grunderna i ett språk innehåller gott om enkla strukturer. Typiska för dessa strukturer är att eleven borde lära sig prestera dem automatiskt. Därför passar just spelliknande övningar här. 
Elevens uppgift är att konstruera grammatiskt korrekta uttryck genom att i rätt ordning välja en fras eller ett ord från hamburgarens olika lager. Dessutom ska meningarna anknyta till den lilla bild som finns till vänster. Om strukturen är korrekt hör eleven den läsas upp och eleven får en hamburgare som belöning. Utifrån antalet hamburgare kan man se var och ens poäng.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Lernziel dieses erlernenhilfsmittels ist, die 
Merkmale zu entwickeln, die Spielen in den Grammatikübungen ähnlich 
sind. Das Unterrichten der Grundlagen in einer Sprache enthält 
viel der einfachen Strukturen. Typisch von diesen Strukturen 
ist, daß der Kursteilnehmer erlernen sollte, sie automatisch zu 
produzieren. Folglich die Übungen ähnlich den Spielen innen 
hier gepaßt. Die Aufgabe des Kursteilnehmers ist, grammatisch 
korrekte Ausdrücke durch zu konzipieren, in der korrekten Ordnung und
wählt eine Phrase oder ein Wort von den unterschiedlichen Schichten 
des Hamburgers. Weiter sollen die Programmsätze mit der kleinen
Abbildung nach links binden. Wenn die Struktur korrekt ist, 
hört der Kursteilnehmer sie gesprochen und erhält einen Hamburger 
als Belohnung. Gegründet auf der Zahl Hamburgern können Sie 
die Zahl Punkten für jeden Kursteilnehmer sehen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'objectif de cette ressource d'étude est de 
développer des dispositifs semblables aux jeux dans les exercices de 
grammaire. L'enseignement des fondations dans un langage 
contient l'abondance des structures simples. Typique de ces 
structures est que l'étudiant devrait apprendre à les produire 
automatiquement. Par conséquent, les exercices semblables aux 
jeux adaptés dedans ici. L'étudiant chargent doit 
concevoir des expressions grammaticalement correctes par, dans la 
commande correcte, choisissant une expression ou un mot des 
différentes couches de l'hamburger. De plus, les phrases 
doivent joindre à la petite image vers la gauche. Si la 
structure est correcte l'étudiant l'entendra parlée et obtiendra un 
hamburger comme récompense. Basé sur le nombre d'hamburgers 
vous pouvez voir le nombre de points pour chaque étudiant.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O objetivo deste recurso de aprendizagem é 
desenvolver as características similares aos jogos nos exercícios da
gramática. Ensinar os princípios em uma língua contem a 
abundância de estruturas simples. Típico destas estruturas é 
que o estudante deve aprender as produzir automaticamente. 
Conseqüentemente, os exercícios similares aos jogos cabidos 
dentro aqui. A tarefa do estudante é projetar expressões 
gramaticalmente corretas por, na ordem correta, escolhendo uma frase 
ou uma palavra das camadas diferentes do hamburger. Mais mais, 
as sentenças devem ligar ao retrato pequeno à esquerda. Se a 
estrutura estiver correta o estudante ouvi-la-á falada e 
começá-lo-á um hamburger como uma recompensa. Baseado no 
número dos hamburgers você pode ver o número dos pontos para cada 
estudante.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'obiettivo di questa risorsa imparante è 
sviluppare le caratteristiche simili ai giochi nelle esercitazioni di 
grammatica. L'istruzione dei principi fondamentali in un 
linguaggio contiene l'abbondanza delle strutture semplici. 
Tipico di queste strutture è che l'allievo dovrebbe imparare 
produrle automaticamente. Di conseguenza, le esercitazioni 
simili ai giochi misura dentro qui. L'operazione dell'allievo è
di progettare le espressioni grammaticale corrette da, nell'ordine 
corretto, scegliendo una frase o una parola dagli strati differenti 
dell'hamburger. Ulteriormente, le frasi devono collegarsi alla 
piccola immagine il a sinistra. Se la struttura è corretta 
l'allievo la sentirà parlata ed otterrà un hamburger come 
ricompensa. Sulla base del numero di hamburger potete vedere il 
numero di punti per ogni allievo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο στόχος αυτού του στοιχείου συμπεριφοράς εκμάθησης 
είναι να αναπτυχθούν τα χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα παρόμοια με τα 
παιχνίδια στις ασκήσεις γραμματικής. Η διδασκαλία των 
βασικών σε μια γλώσσα περιέχει την αφθονία των απλών δομών. 
Χαρακτηριστικό αυτών των δομών είναι ότι ο σπουδαστής 
πρέπει να μάθει να τις παράγει αυτόματα. Επομένως, οι 
ασκήσεις παρόμοιες με τα παιχνίδια ταιριάζουν εδώ. Η 
στοιχειώδης εργασία του σπουδαστή είναι να σχεδιάσει γραμματικά 
τις σωστές εκφράσεις με, στη σωστή κατάταξη, την επιλογή μιας 
φράσης ή μιας λέξης από τα διαφορετικά στρώματα του 
χάμπουργκερ. Περαιτέρω, οι προτάσεις είναι να συνδέσουν με 
τη μικρή εικόνα στο αριστερό. Εάν η δομή είναι σωστή ο 
σπουδαστής θα την ακούσει προφορική και θα πάρει ένα χάμπουργκερ
ως ανταμοιβή. Με βάση τον αριθμό χάμπουργκερ μπορείτε να 
δείτε τον αριθμό σημείων για κάθε σπουδαστή.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El objetivo de este recurso que aprende es 
desarrollar las características similares a los juegos en los 
ejercicios de la gramática. La enseñanza de los fundamentos en
un lenguaje contiene el un montón de estructuras simples. 
Típico de estas estructuras es que el estudiante debe aprender 
producirlas automáticamente. Por lo tanto, los ejercicios 
similares a los juegos cabidos adentro aquí. La tarea del 
estudiante es diseñar expresiones gramatical correctas por, en orden 
correcta, eligiendo una frase o una palabra de las diversas capas de 
la hamburguesa. Además, las sentencias son conectar al cuadro 
pequeño a la izquierda. Si la estructura está correcta el 
estudiante la oirá hablada y conseguirá una hamburguesa como 
recompensa. De acuerdo con el número de hamburguesas usted 
puede ver el número de las puntas para cada estudiante.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>3979</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-02-16</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-17</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-17</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>sv</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>continuing education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">9-13</string>
            <string language="sv">9-13</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An exercise of the basic structures in English</string>
            <string language="sv">Övning av basstrukturer i engelskan</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
                <string language="sv">språkområden</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
                <string language="sv">engelska språket</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82821</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>audio/basic</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://resources.eun.org/demoportal/burger_writer_sve.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
