<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82762</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82762</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>1759</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="it">Trovare la strada ad Helsinki</string>
            <string language="en">Finding your way around Helsinki</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Finden Ihrer Methode um Helsinki</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Trouver votre chemin autour de Helsinki</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Encontrando sua maneira em torno de Helsínquia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εύρεση του τρόπου σας γύρω από το Ελσίνκι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Encontrar su manera alrededor de Helsinki</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="it">L'allievo si muove da un posto all'altro ad Helsinki con l'aiuto di una "cartina comunicativa"  che dà istruzioni orali. La cartina comunicativa dà un riscontro ogni volta che l'allievo fa un errore.L'oggetto di apprendimento  dimostra come un semplice microcosmo può facilitare l'apprendimento di una lingua straniera. Compito dell'allievo è di diventare un turista e seguire una cartina vera usando le istruzioni che sente. (per esempio, “clicca sopra la piazza del mercato –  non è lontano dal porto.”, “clicca sopra il museo in modo da poter vedere  la tua destinazione.”). Le istruzioni sono una parte naturale della narrazione. L'allievo indicherà i luoghi cliccandoli sulla cartina; se trova il luogo giusto, una linea punteggiata apparirà sullo schermo per mostrare in quale direzione lui o lei sta camminando. Di tanto in tanto, lo studente si ferma ad ammirare i luoghi: cliccando su questi, vedrà un'immagine di alcuni siti. l'allievo sentirà un commento ogni volta clicca sul punto sbagliato. L'allievo sarà quindi esposto all'inglese parlato anche se clicca a caso su qualunque punto della cartina. Ogni volta che l'allievo clicca su un luogo, gli verrà fornita la corretta posiziione; rendendo in tal modo le istruzioni veritiere. Se lui lascia la stazione ferroviaria e si incammina nella direzione sbagliata, riceverà un riscontro dal programma, che lo incoraggerà a prendere nota di alcuni dettagli sulla cartina. Alla fine l'allievo vedrà una immagine della destinazione finale.</string>
            <string language="en">The learner moves from place to place in Helsinki with the help of a “talking map” which gives oral instructions.  The talking map gives feedback each time the learner makes a mistake.  The learning object demonstrates how a simple microcosm can facilitate learning a foreign language.
The learner’s task is to become a tourist and follow an authentic map using the instructions he/she hears.  (For example, “Click on the market square – it’s not far from the harbour.”, “Click on the museum so that you can see your destination.”).  The instructions are a natural part of the narration.  The learner will point out sites by clicking on them on the map; if he/she finds the right site, a dotted line will appear on the screen to show which way he/she is walking.  From time to time, the learner stops to admire the sites:  by clicking on them, he/she will see a picture of some of the sites.  The learner will hear a comment each time he/she clicks on the wrong spot.  The learner will thus be subjected to spoken English even if he/she just click randomly on any spot on the map.  Each time the learner clicks on a place, he/she will be told the current location; therefore, the instructions seem sensible.  If he/she leaves the railway station and heads off in the wrong direction, he/she will receive feedback from the program, which encourages him/her to notice some detail on the map.  At the end, the learner will see a picture of the final destination.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Anfänger zieht von Platz zu Platz in Helsinki
mit Hilfe einer?talking Karte um? welches Mundanweisungen 
erteilt. Die sprechenkarte gibt Feedback jede Zeit die 
Anfängermarken ein Fehler. Die erlernennachricht zeigt, wie ein
einfacher Mikrokosmos zu erlernen erleichtern kann, daß eine fremde 
language.The learner?s Aufgabe, einem Touristen zu stehen ist und 
einer authentischen Karte zu folgen, welche die Anweisungen he/she 
verwendet, hört. (zum Beispiel?Click auf dem Marktquadrat? 
it?s nicht weit von den Hafen?, ?Click auf dem Museum, 
damit Sie Ihre Zieleinheit sehen können?). Die Anweisungen sind
ein natürliches Teil der Erzählung. Der Anfänger 
unterstreicht Sites, indem er auf ihnen auf der Karte klickt; 
wenn he/she die rechte Site findet, scheint eine punktierte 
Zeile auf dem Bildschirm, zu zeigen, welche Methode he/she geht. 
Von Zeit zu Zeit, stoppt der Anfänger, um die Sites zu 
bewundern: indem es auf ihnen klickt, sieht he/she eine 
Abbildung von einigen der Sites. Der Anfänger hört, daß ein 
Kommentar jede Zeit he/she an den falschen Punkt klickt. Der 
Anfänger wird folglich gesprochenem Englisch selbst wenn he/she 
gerechtes Klicken nach dem zufall auf jedem möglichem Punkt auf der 
Karte unterworfen. Jede Zeit, die der Anfänger an einen Platz, 
he/she klickt, wird den aktuellen Standort erklärt; folglich 
scheinen die Anweisungen vernünftig. Wenn he/she den Bahnhof 
und die Köpfe weg in der falschen Richtung läßt, empfängt he/she 
Feedback vom Programm, das him/her anregt, irgendein Detail über die 
Karte zu beachten. Am Ende sieht der Anfänger eine Abbildung 
der abschließenden Zieleinheit.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'étudiant se déplace d'un endroit à l'autre 
à Helsinki avec l'aide d'une carte ?talking ? ce qui donne des 
instructions orales. La carte parlante donne le feedback chaque 
fois que l'étudiant fait une erreur. L'objet d'étude démontre
comment un microcosme simple peut faciliter apprendre que les 
learner?s étrangers d'un language.The chargent doit aller 
bien à un touriste et suivre une carte authentique utilisant les 
instructions he/she entend. (par exemple ?clic sur la place
du marché ? it?s pas loin du port ?, ?clic sur le 
musée de sorte que vous puissiez voir votre destination ?). Les
instructions sont une partie normale du récit. L'étudiant 
précisera des sites en cliquant sur eux sur la carte ; 
si he/she trouve le site droit, une ligne pointillée semblera 
sur l'écran montrer quelle voie he/she marche. De temps en 
temps, l'étudiant cesse d'admirer les sites : en 
cliquant sur eux, he/she verra une image de certains des 
sites. L'étudiant entendra un commentaire chaque fois que 
he/she clique sur la tache fausse. L'étudiant sera 
ainsi soumis à l'anglais parlé même si clic juste de he/she 
aléatoirement sur n'importe quelle tache sur la carte. Chaque 
fois que l'étudiant clique sur un endroit, on dira he/she 
l'emplacement actuel ; donc, les instructions semblent 
sensibles. Si he/she laisse la gare et les têtes hors fonction 
dans la direction fausse, he/she recevra le feedback du programme, qui
encourage him/her à noter un certain détail sur la carte. À 
l'extrémité, l'étudiant verra une image de la destination finale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O learner move-se do lugar para o lugar em 
Helsínquia com a ajuda de um mapa?talking? qual dá 
instruções orais. O mapa falando dá o feedback cada vez que o
learner faz um erro. O objeto de aprendizagem demonstra como um 
microcosm simples pode facilitar aprender que uma tarefa extrangeira 
dos learner?s de language.The é assentar bem em um turista e para 
seguir um mapa authentic que usa as instruções he/she se ouve. 
(para o exemplo?Click no quadrado do mercado? it?s não 
longe do porto?, ?Click no museu de modo que você possa ver seu
destino?). As instruções são uma parte natural do narration. 
O learner indicará locais estalando neles no mapa; se 
he/she encontrar o local direito, uma linha pontilhada parecerá na 
tela mostrar que maneira he/she está andando. Do tempo ao 
tempo, o learner para para admirar os locais: estalando neles, 
he/she verá um retrato de alguns dos locais. O learner ouvirá 
um comentário cada vez que he/she estala sobre o ponto errado. 
O learner será sujeitado assim a inglês falado mesmo se clique
justo de he/she aleatòria em todo o ponto no mapa. Cada vez que
o learner estala sobre um lugar, he/she estará dito a posição 
atual; conseqüentemente, as instruções parecem sensible. 
Se he/she deixar a estação railway e as cabeças fora no 
sentido errado, he/she receberá o feedback do programa, que incentiva
him/her observar algum detalhe no mapa. Na extremidade, o 
learner verá um retrato do destino final.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι κινήσεις αρχαρίων από μέρος σε μέρος στο Ελσίνκι 
με τη βοήθεια ενός ?talking χάρτη; όποιος δίνει τις 
προφορικές οδηγίες. Ο ομιλών χάρτης δίνει την 
ανατροφοδότηση κάθε φορά που κάνει ο αρχάριος ένα λάθος. 
Το αντικείμενο εκμάθησης καταδεικνύει πώς ένας απλός 
μικρόκοσμος μπορεί να διευκολύνει την εκμάθηση μιας ξένης 
γλώσσας Η στοιχειώδης εργασία learner?s είναι να γίνει 
τουρίστας και να ακολουθηθεί ένας αυθεντικός χάρτης που 
χρησιμοποιεί τις οδηγίες που ακούει. (Παραδείγματος χάριν, 
?Click στο τετράγωνο αγοράς; it?s όχι μακριά από το 
λιμάνι;, ?Click στο μουσείο έτσι ώστε μπορείτε να 
δείτε τον προορισμό σας;). Οι οδηγίες είναι ένα 
φυσικό μέρος της αφήγησης. Ο αρχάριος θα επισημάνει τις 
περιοχές με τον κρότο σε τους στο χάρτη  εάν βρεί τη σωστή
περιοχή, μια διαστιγμένη γραμμή θα εμφανιστεί στην οθόνη να 
εμφανίζει ποιο τρόπο περπατά. Κατά διαστήματα, ο αρχάριος 
σταματά για να θαυμάζει τις περιοχές: με τον κρότο σε τους, 
θα δει μια εικόνα μερικές από τις περιοχές. Ο 
αρχάριος θα ακούσει ένα σχόλιο κάθε χρόνος αυτός/αυτή χτυπά 
επιτόπου λανθασμένο. Ο αρχάριος θα υποβληθεί έτσι στα 
προφορικά αγγλικά ακόμα κι αν χτυπά ακριβώς τυχαία επιτόπου 
οποιοδήποτε στο χάρτη. Κάθε φορά που χτυπά ο αρχάριος σε 
μια θέση, έχει την υποχρέωση για την παρούσα θέση  
επομένως, οι οδηγίες φαίνονται λογικές. Εάν 
σταματήσει το σιδηροδρομικό σταθμό και τα κεφάλια στη λανθασμένη 
κατεύθυνση, θα λάβει την ανατροφοδότηση από το πρόγραμμα, το 
οποίο την ενθαρρύνει τον/για να παρατηρήσει κάποια λεπτομέρεια 
στο χάρτη. Στο τέλος, ο αρχάριος θα δει μια 
εικόνα του τελικού προορισμού.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿El principiante se mueve desde lugar al lugar en 
Helsinki con la ayuda de una correspondencia?talking? cuál da 
instrucciones orales. La correspondencia que habla da feedback 
cada vez que el principiante incurre en una equivocación. El 
objeto que aprende demuestra cómo un microcosm simple puede facilitar
el aprender que una tarea no nativa de los learner?s de language.The 
es sentir bien a un turista y seguir una correspondencia auténtica 
que usa las instrucciones he/she oye. ¿(por ejemplo?Click en el 
cuadrado del mercado? it?s no lejos del puerto?, ?Click en
el museo de modo que usted pueda ver su destinación?). Las 
instrucciones son una parte natural de la narración. El 
principiante precisará sitios haciendo clic en ellos en la 
correspondencia; si he/she encuentra el sitio derecho, una 
línea punteada aparecerá en la pantalla mostrar qué manera he/she 
está recorriendo. A partir de tiempo al tiempo, el principiante
para para admirar los sitios: haciendo clic en ellos, he/she 
verá un cuadro de algunos de los sitios. El principiante oirá 
un comentario cada vez que he/she hace clic encendido el punto 
incorrecto. Sujetarán al principiante así a inglés hablada 
incluso si tecleo justo de he/she aleatoriamente en cualquier punto en
la correspondencia. Cada vez que el principiante hace clic 
encendido un lugar, he/she será dicho la localización actual; 
por lo tanto, las instrucciones se parecen sensibles. Si 
he/she deja el ferrocarril y las pistas apagado en la dirección 
incorrecta, he/she recibirá feedback del programa, que anima a 
him/her que note un cierto detalle en la correspondencia. En el 
extremo, el principiante verá un cuadro de la destinación final.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>1759</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-01-26</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-21</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-21</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-21</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-21</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-21</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-21</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>guide</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">10-15</string>
            <string language="en">10-15</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="it">Attività di comprensione orale in inglese e espressioni per dare indicazioni</string>
            <string language="en">Listening comprehension in English and expressions for giving directions</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82762</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>image/bmp</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://resources.eun.org/demoportal/helsinki_map_eng.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
