<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82685</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82685</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>1556</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="fi">Kitchen computer - uutistenlukija</string>
            <string language="en">Kitchen computer-news announcer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Küche Computer-Nachrichten Ansager</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Annonceur d'ordinateur-nouvelles de cuisine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Anunciador da computador-notícia da cozinha</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Presentatore di calcolatore-notizie della cucina</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αναγγέλλων υπολογιστής-ειδήσεων κουζινών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Anunciador de las ordenador-noticias de la cocina</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Esimerkki uutismateriaalin kielellisestä työstämisestä pysyvää arvoa omaavan uutisen (tässä tapauksessa keittiötietokoneen keksiminen) avulla. Materiaaliin liittyy 4 erilaista harjoitusta..
Aluksi oppilas kuuntelee uutisen keittiötietokoneen keksimisestä ja syistä, miksi tämä 1960-luvulla mullistavana pidetty idea ei koskaan päätynyt suurien keksintöjen joukkoon. Tämän jälkeen oppilas siirtyä videon pohjalta laadittuihin harjoituksiin.
-	Ns. True or False –tehtävä on kuullunymmärrystehtävä, jossa on valittava, mitkä esitetyistä väitteistä pitävät uutisen paikkaansa. Oppilas valitsee joko ”True” tai ”False” ja voi tarkistaa vastauksensa ”Check”-painikkeesta. 
-Lexitaire-tehtävässä harjoitellaan uutisessa esiintyneitä keskeisiä sanoja ns. sanastopasianssin (lexitaire) muodossa. Vasemmalla on englanninkielisiä sanoja, jotka oppilaan tulee siirtää oikealla puolella olevien suomenkielisten vastineiden päälle. Oikein yhdistetyt sanat häviävät ja väärän sanan päälle viety englanninkielinen sana palaa takaisin lähtöpaikkaansa. 
-Synonym sweeper –tehtävässä harjoitellaan sekä sanastoa että tekstin ymmärtämistä. Oppilas näkee uutisen tekstinä. Ruudun alalaidassa on sanoja, jotka oppilaan pitää raahata tekstiin niiden synonyymien päälle. Oikean synonyymin päälle viety sana katoaa ja pisteet lisääntyvät pistelaskurissa. 
-Begin&amp;amp;end –tehtävässä harjoitellaan lauserakenteita. Ruudulla on viisi lausetta, joiden alku- ja loppuosat on sekoitettu. Oppilaan tehtävänä on muodostaa kokonaisia lauseita järjestämällä lauseet niin, että vasemmalla oleva alkuosa ja oikealla oleva loppuosa sopivat toisiinsa. Vastaukset tarkistetaan Check-painikkeesta ja ruudulle ilmestyy sen hetkinen pistemäärä.
Nämä monipuoliset tehtävät havainnollistavat, miten uutista voidaan luontevasti käyttää hyödyksi kielen eri osa-alueita harjoiteltaessa.</string>
            <string language="en">An example of using news material for language teaching purposes (in this case the invention of a kitchen computer). There are four different exercises in this material. First the student listens to the news on the invention of the kitchen computer and why this in the 1960’s epoch making idea never became one of the great inventions. After this the student will continue to the video based exercises. In the so called True or False listening comprehension the student has to decide if the given statements are true when listening to the news. The answers can be checked by clicking on the Check button. The lexitaire exercise practises the key words. The English words on the left have to be dragged matched with the Finnish ones on the right. The correct words disappear and the ones that are incorrect go back. The Synonym sweeper practises both vocabulary and reading comprehension. The student sees the news as a written text. There are words at the bottom of the screen that have to be dragged on the synonyms in the text. If the word is put on the correct synonym it disappears and the score gets higher.  With a Begin&amp;amp;end exercise the sentence structure can be practised. There are five sentences on the screen and their beginnings and ends have been mixed. The task is to match the two parts into each other so that they make an understandable sentence. The answers are checked by clicking the Check button and after that a score is given. These versatile exercises visualize a piece of news can be naturally used when practising the different fields of a language.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Beispiel des Verwendens des Nachrichten 
Materials für Sprachunterrichtzwecke (in diesem Fall die Erfindung 
von einem Küchecomputer). Es gibt vier unterschiedliche 
Übungen in diesem Material. Zuerst hört der Kursteilnehmer zu 
den Nachrichten auf der Erfindung des Küchecomputers und warum dieses
in der Epoche 1960?s, die Idee bildet nie, eine der großen 
Erfindungen wurde. Nachdem dieses, das der Kursteilnehmer zu den
video gegründeten Übungen fortsetzt. Im sogenannten 
zutreffenden oder falschen hörenden Erfassen muß der Kursteilnehmer 
entscheiden, wenn die gegebenen Anweisungen beim Hören zu den 
Nachrichten zutreffend sind. Die Antworten können überprüft 
werden, indem man auf der Überprüfung Taste klickt. Die 
lexitaire Übung übt die Schlüsselwörter. Die englischen 
Wörter auf dem links müssen geschleppt werden zusammenpaßten mit 
den finnischen auf dem Recht. Die korrekten Wörter verschwinden
und die, die falsch sind, gehen zurück. Die 
SynonymKehrmaschine übt Wortschatz und Leseerfassen. Der 
Kursteilnehmer sieht die Nachrichten als schriftlicher Text. Es 
gibt Wörter am unteren Bildschirmrand, die auf den Synonymen im Text 
geschleppt werden müssen. Wenn das Wort auf das korrekte 
Synonym gesetzt wird, das es verschwindet und die Kerbe erhält stark.
Mit einer Begin&amp;end Übung kann die Programmsatzstruktur 
geübt werden. Es gibt fünf Programmsätze auf dem Bildschirm 
und ihre Anfänge und Enden sind gemischt worden. Die Aufgabe 
ist, die zwei Teile in einander zusammenzubringen, damit sie einen 
verständlichen Programmsatz bilden. Die Antworten werden 
überprüft, indem man die Überprüfung Taste und nachher anklickt, 
daß eine Kerbe gegeben wird. Diese vielseitigen begabt Übungen
machen ein Stück Nachrichten können wenn das Üben sichtbar das 
unterschiedliche natürlich verwendet werden, von einer Sprache 
auffängt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un exemple d'utiliser le matériel de nouvelles 
pour l'enseignement des langues (dans ce cas-ci l'invention d'un 
ordinateur de cuisine). Il y a quatre exercices différents en 
ce matériel. D'abord l'étudiant écoute les nouvelles sur 
l'invention de l'ordinateur de cuisine et pourquoi ceci dans l'époque
1960?s faisant l'idée n'est jamais devenue l'une des grandes 
inventions. Après que ceci que l'étudiant continuera aux 
exercices basés visuels. Dans la prétendue compréhension 
d'écoute vraie ou fausse l'étudiant doit décider si les rapports 
donnés sont vrais en écoutant les nouvelles. Les réponses 
peuvent être contrôlées en cliquant sur le bouton de 
contrôle. L'exercice de lexitaire pratique les mots clés. 
Les mots anglais du côté gauche doivent être traînés ont 
apparié avec le finlandais du côté droit. Les mots corrects 
disparaissent et ceux qui sont incorrects retournent. La 
balayeuse de synonyme pratique le vocabulaire et la compréhension de 
lecture. L'étudiant voit les nouvelles comme texte écrit. 
Il y a des mots au bas de l'écran qui doivent être traînés 
sur les synonymes dans le texte. Si le mot est mis sur le 
synonyme correct qu'il disparaît et les points obtiennent plus haut. 
Avec un exercice de Begin&amp;end la structure de la phrase peut
être pratiquée. Il y a cinq phrases sur l'écran et leurs 
débuts et fins ont été mélangés. Le charger doit 
apparier les deux pièces dans l'un l'autre de sorte qu'elles fassent 
une phrase compréhensible. Les réponses sont contrôlées en 
cliquant le bouton de contrôle et ensuite que des points 
sont donnés. Ces exercices souples visualisent nouvelle peuvent
être naturellement utilisés en pratiquant les différentes zones 
d'un langage.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um exemplo de usar o material da notícia para 
finalidades da instrução de línguas (neste caso a invenção de um 
computador da cozinha). Há quatro exercícios diferentes neste 
material. Primeiramente o estudante escuta a notícia na 
invenção do computador da cozinha e porque esta no epoch 1960?s que 
faz a idéia nunca se transformou uma das invenções grandes. 
Depois que isto que o estudante continuará aos exercícios 
baseados video. Na Verdadeiro assim chamada ou na compreensão 
escutando falsa o estudante tem que decidir-se se as indicações 
dadas forem verdadeiras ao escutar a notícia. As respostas 
podem ser verificadas estalando na tecla da verificação. O 
exercício do lexitaire pratica as palavras chaves. As palavras 
inglesas na esquerda têm que ser arrastadas combinaram com finnish na
direita. As palavras corretas desaparecem e essas que estão 
incorretas vão para trás. O sweeper do synonym pratica  o 
vocabulário e a compreensão da leitura. O estudante vê a 
notícia como um texto escrito. Há as palavras no fundo da tela
que têm que ser arrastadas nos synonyms no texto. Se a palavra 
for posta sobre o synonym que correto desaparece e a contagem começa 
mais altamente. Com um exercício de Begin&amp;end a estrutura 
de sentença pode ser praticada. Há cinco sentenças na tela e 
seus começos e extremidades foram misturados. A tarefa é 
combinar as duas peças em se de modo que façam uma sentença 
compreensível. As respostas são verificadas estalando a tecla 
da verificação e em seguida que uma contagem está dada. Estes
exercícios versáteis visualizam uma parte de notícia podem 
naturalmente ser usados ao praticar os campos diferentes de uma 
língua.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un esempio di usando il materiale di notizie per 
gli scopi di insegnamento delle lingue (in questo caso l'invenzione di
un calcolatore della cucina). Ci sono quattro esercitazioni 
differenti in questo materiale. In primo luogo l'allievo ascolta
le notizie sull'invenzione del calcolatore della cucina e perchè 
questa nell'epoca 1960?s che fa l'idea non si è transformata in mai 
in una delle invenzioni grandi. Dopo che questo che l'allievo 
continuerà alle video esercitazioni basate. Nella cosiddetta 
comprensione ascoltante allineare o falsa l'allievo deve decidere se 
le date istruzione sono allineare quando ascolta le notizie. Le 
risposte possono essere controllate scattandosi sul tasto del 
controllo. L'esercitazione del lexitaire si esercita nelle 
parole chiave. Le parole inglesi a sinistra devono essere 
trascinate hanno abbinato con quei finlandesi a destra. Le 
parole corrette spariscono e quelle che siano errate vanno indietro. 
La spazzatrice di sinonimo si esercita sia nel vocabolario che 
nella comprensione della lettura. L'allievo vede le notizie come
testo scritto. Ci sono parole alla parte inferiore dello schermo
che devono essere trascinate sui sinonimi nel testo. Se la 
parola è messa sul sinonimo che corretto sparisce ed il segno ottiene
su. Con un'esercitazione di Begin&amp;end la struttura di frase 
può esercitarsi in. Ci sono cinque frasi sullo schermo ed i 
loro inizii ed estremità sono stati mescolati. L'operazione è 
di abbinare le due parti in a vicenda in modo che facciano una frase 
comprensibile. Le risposte sono controllate scattando il tasto 
del controllo e dopo che un segno sia dato. Queste esercitazioni
versatili prevedono una parte delle notizie possono essere usate 
naturalmente quando si esercita nei campi differenti di un linguaggio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα παράδειγμα το υλικό ειδήσεων για λόγους 
διδασκαλίας γλωσσών (σε αυτήν την περίπτωση η εφεύρεση ενός 
υπολογιστή κουζινών). Υπάρχουν τέσσερις διαφορετικές 
ασκήσεις σε αυτό το υλικό. Πρώτα ο σπουδαστής ακούει τις 
ειδήσεις στην εφεύρεση του υπολογιστή κουζινών και γιατί αυτό 
στην εποχή 1960?s που κάνει την ιδέα δεν έγινε ποτέ μια από 
τις μεγάλες εφευρέσεις. Μετά από αυτό ο σπουδαστής θα 
συνεχιστεί στις τηλεοπτικές βασισμένες ασκήσεις. Στην 
αποκαλούμενη αληθινή ή ψεύτικη κατανόηση ακούσματος ο 
σπουδαστής πρέπει να αποφασίσει εάν οι δεδομένες δηλώσεις είναι
αληθινές κατά την άκουσμα τις ειδήσεις. Οι απαντήσεις 
μπορούν να ελεγχθούν με τον κρότο στο κουμπί ελέγχου. Οι 
πρακτικές άσκησης lexitaire οι βασικές λέξεις. Οι 
αγγλικές λέξεις στο αριστερό πρέπει να σέρθούν ταιριαγμένος με 
τα φινλανδικά στο δικαίωμα. Οι σωστές λέξεις εξαφανίζονται 
και αυτές που είναι ανακριβείς επιστρέφουν. Η κατανόηση 
λεξιλογίου και ανάγνωσης πρακτικών οχημάτων αποκομιδής 
απορριμμάτων συνωνύμου και. Ο σπουδαστής βλέπει τις 
ειδήσεις ως γραπτό κείμενο. Υπάρχουν λέξεις στο κατώτατο 
σημείο της οθόνης που πρέπει να σέρθούν στα συνώνυμα στο 
κείμενο. Εάν η λέξη τίθεται στο σωστό συνώνυμο 
εξαφανίζεται και το αποτέλεσμα παίρνει υψηλότερο. Με μια 
άσκηση Begin&amp;end η δομή πρότασης μπορεί να ασκηθεί. 
Υπάρχουν πέντε προτάσεις στην οθόνη και οι αρχές και οι 
άκρες τους έχουν αναμιχθεί. Η στοιχειώδης εργασία είναι να
ταιριαχτούν με τα δύο μέρη το ένα στο άλλο έτσι ώστε κάνουν 
μια κατανοητή πρόταση. Οι απαντήσεις ελέγχονται με τον 
κρότο του κουμπιού ελέγχου και μετά από αυτό ένα αποτέλεσμα 
δίνεται. Αυτές οι ευπροσάρμοστες ασκήσεις απεικονίζουν ένα
κομμάτι των ειδήσεων μπορούν να χρησιμοποιηθούν φυσικά κατά την 
άσκηση των διαφορετικών πεδίων μιας γλώσσας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un ejemplo de usar el material de las noticias 
para los propósitos de la instrucción de lenguas (en este caso la 
invención de un ordenador de la cocina). Hay cuatro diversos 
ejercicios en este material. Primero el estudiante escucha las 
noticias en la invención del ordenador de la cocina y porqué éste 
en la época 1960?s que hacía idea nunca se convirtió en una de las 
grandes invenciones. Después de que esto que el estudiante 
continuará a los ejercicios basados video. En la comprensión 
que escucha verdadera o falsa supuesta el estudiante tiene que decidir
si las declaraciones dadas son verdades al escuchar las noticias. 
Las respuestas pueden ser controladas haciendo clic en el botón
del cheque. El ejercicio del lexitaire practica las palabras 
claves. Las palabras inglesas a la izquierda tienen que ser 
arrastradas correspondieron con con los finlandeses a la derecha. 
Las palabras correctas desaparecen y las que son incorrectos van
detrás. El barrendero del sinónimo practica vocabulario y la 
comprensión de la lectura. El estudiante ve las noticias como 
texto escrito. Hay las palabras en el fondo de la pantalla que 
tienen que ser arrastradas en los sinónimos en el texto. Si la 
palabra se pone en el sinónimo correcto que desaparece y la cuenta 
consigue más arriba. Con un ejercicio de Begin&amp;end la 
estructura de sentencia puede ser practicada. Hay cinco 
sentencias en la pantalla y se han mezclado sus principios y extremos.
La tarea es corresponder con las dos piezas en uno a de modo que
hagan una sentencia comprensible. Las respuestas son controladas
haciendo clic el botón del cheque y después que una cuenta está 
dada. Estos ejercicios versátiles visualizan un pedazo de 
noticias pueden ser utilizados naturalmente al practicar los diversos 
campos de un lenguaje.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>1556</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-01-12</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-15</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-15</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-15</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-15</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>fi</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">8-U</string>
            <string language="fi">&gt; 8</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Monipuolinen kokonaisuus englannin kuullunymmärtämisen ja sanaston opiskeluun.</string>
            <string language="en">A versatile set of exercises for studying listening comprehension and the vocabulary of English</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">englannin kieli</string>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">kielet</string>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>710</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">kielten opetus</string>
                <string language="en">language teaching</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>652</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">tieto- ja viestintäteknologia</string>
                <string language="en">information and communications technology</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82685</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/kitchen_computer/co1_16.exe</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
