<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82540</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82540</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>4315</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="it">Sondaggio in strada</string>
            <string language="en">Street Survey</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Straße Übersicht</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Enquête de Rue</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Exame Da Rua</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Έρευνα οδών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Encuesta sobre La Calle</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="it">Questo oggetto didattico usa una serie di clip audio in cui  passanti parlano del loro utilizzo di Internet. L’alunno è esposto al linguaggio autentico e deve ascoltare attentamente e collegare le domande giuste alle risposte che l’intervistato fornisce nel clip audio.  In fondo allo schermo l’alunno può vedere i profili degli intervistatori che contengono cinque domande diverse. L’alunno deve cliccare su una domanda alla volta e ascoltare attentamente le risposte che gli vengono date. Dopo aver ascoltato la domanda, l’alunno clicca sulle facce e ascolta le risposte date. L’alunno trascina ogni domanda nell’ombra dell’intervistatore accanto alla domanda giusta. Quando l’esercizio è completo, l’alunno clicca sul tasto di verifica. I profili che si trovano nei posti giusti diventeranno verdi e sia le domande che le risposte verranno lette nuovamente ad alta voce. I profili che si troveranno nei posti sbagliati verranno rimandati indietro e l’alunno dovrà riprovare.</string>
            <string language="en">This learning object uses a series of audio clips where passers-by on the street tell about their Internet use. The learner is exposed to authentic language and has to listen carefully and match the right questions to the answers the interviewees give in the audio clips. At the bottom of the screen, the learner can see the profiles of five interviewers, which contain five different questions.  The learner has to click on one at a time and listen carefully to the question being asked.  After listening to the question, the learner clicks on the faces and listens to the answers given.  He/she then drags each question onto the shadow of the interviewer beside the right question.  When the exercise is complete, the learner clicks on the Check button.  The profiles that are in the correct spots will lock into place and turn green and the questions and answers will be read aloud again.  The profiles that are in the wrong spots will float back down to the bottom of the screen and the learner has to try again.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese erlernennachricht benutzt eine Reihe 
Audioclips, in denen Passanten auf der Straße über ihren 
Internet-Gebrauch erklären. Der Anfänger wird authentischer 
Sprache ausgesetzt und muß sorgfältig hören und die rechten Fragen 
zu den Antworten zusammenbringen, welche die Interviewten in den 
Audioclips geben. Am unteren Bildschirmrand, kann der Anfänger 
die Profile von fünf Interviewern sehen, die fünf unterschiedliche 
Fragen enthalten. Der Anfänger muß einzeln an klicken und zur 
Frage sorgfältig hören, die gebeten wird. Nachdem er zur Frage
gehört hat, klickt der Anfänger an die Gesichter und hört zu den 
gegebenen Antworten. He/she schleppt dann jede Frage auf den 
Schatten des Interviewers neben der rechten Frage. Wenn die 
Übung komplett ist, klickt der Anfänger an die Überprüfung Taste. 
Die Profile, die in den korrekten Punkten sind, sperren in Platz
und drehen Grün und die Fragen und die Antworten werden gelesen laut 
wieder. Die Profile, die in den falschen Punkten sind, 
schwimmen, zurück zur Unterseite des Bildschirms und des Anfängers 
niederzuwerfen muß noch einmal versuchen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cet objet d'étude utilise une série de clips 
sonores où les passants sur la rue disent au sujet de leur 
utilisation d'Internet. L'étudiant est exposé au langage 
authentique et doit écouter soigneusement et apparier les bonnes 
questions aux réponses que les interviewés donnent dans les clips 
sonores. Au bas de l'écran, l'étudiant peut voir les profils 
de cinq interviewers, qui contiennent cinq questions différentes. 
L'étudiant doit cliquer sur un par un et écouter 
soigneusement la question étant demandée. Après avoir 
écouté la question, l'étudiant clique sur les visages et 
écoute les réponses données. He/she traîne alors chaque 
question sur l'ombre de l'interviewer près de la bonne question. 
Quand l'exercice est complet, l'étudiant clique sur 
le bouton de contrôle. Les profils qui sont dans les taches 
correctes verrouilleront sur l'endroit et tourneront le vert et les 
questions et les réponses seront lus à haute voix encore. Les 
profils qui sont dans les taches fausses flotteront en arrière pour 
avaler au bas de l'écran et de l'étudiant doit essayer encore.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este objeto de aprendizagem usa uma série dos 
grampos audio onde os transeuntes na rua dizem sobre seu uso do 
Internet. O learner é exposto à língua authentic e tem que 
escutar com cuidado e para combinar as perguntas direitas às 
respostas que os interviewees dão nos grampos audio. No fundo 
da tela, o learner pode ver os perfis de cinco interviewers, que 
contêm cinco perguntas diferentes. O learner tem que estalar 
sobre um de cada vez e escutar com cuidado a pergunta que está sendo 
pedida. Após escutar a pergunta, o learner estala sobre as 
caras e escuta as respostas dadas. He/she arrasta então cada 
pergunta na sombra do interviewer ao lado da pergunta direita. 
Quando o exercício está completo, o learner estala sobre a 
tecla da verificação. Os perfis que estão nos pontos corretos
travarão no lugar e girarão o verde e as perguntas e as respostas 
serão lidos alto outra vez. Os perfis que estão nos pontos 
errados flutuarão para trás para tragar ao fundo da tela e do 
learner têm que tentar outra vez.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το αντικείμενο εκμάθησης χρησιμοποιεί μια σειρά 
ηχητικών συνδετήρων όπου οι περαστικοί στην οδό λένε για τη 
χρήση Διαδικτύου τους. Ο αρχάριος εκτίθεται στην αυθεντική 
γλώσσα και πρέπει να ακούσει προσεκτικά και να ταιριάξει με τις 
σωστές ερωτήσεις τις απαντήσεις που οι δίδοντες συνέντευξη 
δίνουν στους ηχητικούς συνδετήρες. Στο κατώτατο σημείο της 
οθόνης, ο αρχάριος μπορεί να δει τα σχεδιαγράμματα 
πέντε ερευνητών, τα οποία περιέχουν πέντε διαφορετικές 
ερωτήσεις. Ο αρχάριος πρέπει να χτυπήσει σε ένας σε έναν 
χρόνο και να ακούσει προσεκτικά την ερώτηση που υποβάλλεται. 
Μετά από να ακούσει την ερώτηση, ο αρχάριος χτυπά στα 
πρόσωπα και ακούει τις απαντήσεις που δίνονται. Σέρνει 
έπειτα κάθε ερώτηση επάνω στη σκιά του ερευνητή εκτός από τη 
σωστή ερώτηση. Όταν η άσκηση είναι πλήρης, ο αρχάριος 
χτυπά στο κουμπί ελέγχου. Τα σχεδιαγράμματα που είναι στα 
σωστά σημεία θα κλειδώσουν στη θέση και θα γίνουν πράσινα και οι
ερωταποκρίσεις θα διαβαστούν μεγαλοφώνως πάλι. Τα 
σχεδιαγράμματα που είναι στα λανθασμένα σημεία θα επιπλεύσουν 
πίσω κάτω στο κατώτατο σημείο της οθόνης και ο αρχάριος πρέπει 
να προσπαθήσει πάλι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este objeto que aprende utiliza una serie de clips
audio donde los traseúntes en la calle hablan de su uso del Internet.
Exponen al lenguaje auténtico y tiene que escuchar al 
principiante cuidadosamente y corresponder con las preguntas derechas 
a las respuestas que los entrevistados dan en los clips audio. 
En el fondo de la pantalla, el principiante puede ver los 
perfiles de cinco entrevistadores, que contienen cinco diversas 
preguntas. El principiante tiene que hacer clic encendido uno a 
la vez y escuchar cuidadosamente la pregunta que es pedida. 
Después de escuchar la pregunta, el principiante hace clic 
encendido las caras y escucha las respuestas dadas. He/she 
entonces arrastra cada pregunta sobre la sombra del entrevistador al 
lado de la pregunta derecha. Cuando el ejercicio es completo, el
principiante hace clic encendido el botón del cheque. Los 
perfiles que están en los puntos correctos bloquearán en lugar y 
darán vuelta a verde y las preguntas y las respuestas serán leídos 
en voz alta otra vez. Los perfiles que están en los puntos 
incorrectos flotarán detrás para tragar al fondo de la pantalla y 
del principiante tienen que intentar otra vez.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>4315</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-02-26</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Congedo;Fiorenza;;;
FN:Fiorenza Congedo
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-14</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Congedo;Fiorenza;;;
FN:Fiorenza Congedo
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-14</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>continuing education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">13-15</string>
            <string language="en">13-15</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="it">Comprensione orale</string>
            <string language="en">Listening comprehension</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>712</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">Latin</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82540</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>audio/basic</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://resources.eun.org/demoportal/street_survey_eng.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
