<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82687</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82687</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>1553</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="fi">Common Background</string>
            <string language="en">Common Background</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geläufiger Hintergrund</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Fond Commun</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fundo Comum</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Priorità bassa Comune</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινό υπόβαθρο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fondo Común</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Oppilas kuulee kahdeksan henkilön esittelyt, joissa esiintyy runsaasti henkilötietosanastoa (mm. ikä, kansallisuus, asuinpaikka, harrastukset). Kuunneltuaan esittelyt, oppilaan on ryhmiteltävät henkilöt yhteisten ominaisuuksien mukaan. Useammilla henkilöillä voi olla jotain yhteistä, mutta tarkoituksena on löytää sellaiset yhdistävät tekijät, joiden perusteella henkilöt voidaan jakaa nimenomaan neljään kahden hengen ryhmään. Sanastoharjoittelun ja kuullunymmärtämisen lisäksi oppilaan on pystyttävä tekemään päätelmiä ja soveltamaan tietoa tehtävän ratkaisemiseksi. Tehtävä on haastava ja siksi ohjeessa kehotetaankin tekemään muistiinpanoja kuuntelun aikana, jotta ratkaiseminen helpottuisi.</string>
            <string language="en">The student hears the introductions of eight people. These introductions contain a lot of personal information (for example age, nationality, place of residence, hobbies etc.). After hearing the introductions the student has to group the people according to the common characteristics. Most people may have something in common but the idea is to find out the features according to which the people can divided into four pairs. In addition to practicing the vocabulary and the listening comprehension the student has to be able to draw conclusions and to use the given information to solve the task. Because the task is challenging the student is advised to make notes during the listening in order to solve the task more easily.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Kursteilnehmer hört die Einleitungen von 
acht Leuten. Diese Einleitungen enthalten eine Menge 
persönliche Informationen (zum Beispiel Alter, Nationalität, 
Wohnsitz, Liebhabereien etc.). Nachdem er die Einleitungen 
gehört hat, muß der Kursteilnehmer die Leute entsprechend den 
geläufigen Eigenschaften gruppieren. Die meisten Leute können 
etwas im Common haben, aber die Idee ist, die Merkmale herauszufinden,
entsprechend denen die Leutedose in vier Paare sich teilte. 
Zusätzlich zum Üben des Wortschatzes und des hörenden 
Erfassens muß der Kursteilnehmer können, Zusammenfassungen zu 
zeichnen und die gegebenen Informationen zu verwenden, um die Aufgabe 
zu lösen. Weil die Aufgabe schwierig ist, wird der 
Kursteilnehmer geraten, Anmerkungen während des Hörens zu bilden, 
zum der Aufgabe leicht zu lösen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'étudiant entend les introductions de huit 
personnes. Ces introductions contiennent beaucoup d'information 
personnelle (par exemple âge, nationalité, domicile, passe-temps 
etc.). Après avoir entendu les introductions l'étudiant doit 
grouper le peuple selon les caractéristiques communes. La 
plupart des personnes peuvent avoir quelque chose en commun mais 
l'idée est de découvrir les dispositifs selon lesquels le bidon de 
personnes s'est divisé en quatre paires. En plus de pratiquer 
le vocabulaire et la compréhension d'écoute l'étudiant doit pouvoir
tirer des conclusions et employer l'information fournie pour résoudre
le charger. Puisque le charger est provocant l'étudiant 
est informé faire des notes pendant l'écoute afin de résoudre le 
charger plus facilement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O estudante ouve as introduções de oito povos. 
Estas introduções contêm muitos da informação pessoal (para
a idade do exemplo, a nacionalidade, o lugar de residência, os 
passatempos etc.). Após ter ouvido as introduções o estudante
tem que agrupar os povos de acordo com as características comuns. 
A maioria de povos podem ter algo na terra comum mas a idéia é
encontrar para fora as características de acordo com que a lata dos 
povos se dividiu em quatro pares. Além a praticar o 
vocabulário e a compreensão escutando o estudante tem que poder  
desenhar conclusões e usar a informação dada resolver a tarefa. 
Porque a tarefa é challenging o estudante é recomendado fazer 
anotações durante escutar a fim resolver mais fàcilmente a tarefa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'allievo sente le introduzioni di otto genti. 
Queste introduzioni contengono le informazioni personali 
molto (per esempio età, nazionalità, luogo di residenza, hobby
ecc.). Dopo avere sentito le introduzioni l'allievo deve 
raggruppare la gente secondo le caratteristiche comuni. La 
maggior parte della gente può avere qualcosa il in comune ma l'idea 
è scoprire le caratteristiche secondo cui la latta della gente si è 
divisa in quattro accoppiamenti. Oltre che esercitarsi nel 
vocabolario e nella comprensione ascoltante l'allievo deve potere 
dissipare le conclusioni ed usare le informazioni fornite per 
risolvere l'operazione. Poiché l'operazione è challenging 
l'allievo si raccomanda di fare le note durante ascoltare per per 
risolvere più facilmente l'operazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο σπουδαστής ακούει τις εισαγωγές οκτώ ανθρώπων. 
Αυτές οι εισαγωγές περιέχουν πολλές προσωπικές πληροφορίες
(παραδείγματος χάριν ηλικία, υπηκοότητα, κατοικία, χόμπι κ.λπ.).
Μετά από να ακούσει τις εισαγωγές ο σπουδαστής πρέπει να 
ομαδοποιήσει τους ανθρώπους σύμφωνα με τα κοινά χαρακτηριστικά. 
Οι περισσότεροι άνθρωποι μπορούν να έχουν κάτι από κοινού
αλλά την ιδέα πρόκειται να ανακαλύψουν τα χαρακτηριστικά 
γνωρίσματα σύμφωνα με τα οποία οι άνθρωποι μπορούν διαιρεσμένος 
σε τέσσερα ζευγάρια. Εκτός από την άσκηση του λεξιλογίου 
και της κατανόησης ακούσματος ο σπουδαστής πρέπει να είναι σε 
θέση να συναγάγει τα συμπεράσματα και να χρησιμοποιήσει τις 
δεδομένες πληροφορίες για να λύσει τη στοιχειώδη εργασία. 
Επειδή η στοιχειώδης εργασία είναι η πρόκληση του 
σπουδαστή ενθαρρύνεται για να κάνει τις σημειώσεις κατά τη 
διάρκεια του ακούσματος προκειμένου να λυθεί η στοιχειώδης 
εργασία ευκολότερα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El estudiante oye las introducciones de ocho 
personas. Estas introducciones contienen muchos de información 
personal (por ejemplo edad, nacionalidad, domicilio, manías etc.). 
Después de oír las introducciones el estudiante tiene que 
agrupar a la gente según las características comunes. La 
mayoría de la gente puede tener algo en campo común pero la idea es 
descubrir las características según las cuales la lata de la gente 
se dividió en cuatro pares. Además de practicar el vocabulario
y la comprensión que escucha el estudiante tiene que poder trazar 
conclusiones y utilizar la información dada para solucionar la tarea.
Porque la tarea es desafiadora aconsejan el estudiante hacer 
notas durante escuchar para solucionar la tarea más fácilmente.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>1553</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-01-12</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-12</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-12</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>fi</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">8-14</string>
            <string language="fi">8-14</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Kuullunymmärtämisen harjoittelu, henkilötieto(biodata)sanaston harjoittelu; harjoittaa samalla päättelykykyä.</string>
            <string language="en">Practicing listening comprehension, bio data vocabulary and deduction</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>710</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">kielten opetus</string>
                <string language="en">language teaching</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">kielet</string>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">englannin kieli</string>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82687</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>image/bmp</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://resources.eun.org/demoportal/common_background_fi.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
