<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82868</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82868</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>4339</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A wholesome meal </string>
            <string language="sv">En hälsosam måltid</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine gesunde Mahlzeit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un repas sain</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uma refeição wholesome</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un pasto sano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα θρεπτικό γεύμα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una comida sana</string>
          </title>
          <language>sv</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">To compose a wholesome meal is an interactive program that makes it possible to compose a lunch for different example persons according to given nutrition recommendations. The program is based on a Finnish nutrition model called the dish model. The model can be applied to different individual needs. Using the program, it the easy to illustrate how the choice of dish and the portion size impacts the total energy amount of the meal. Moreover, the program aims at serving as a guideline to permanent weight control and all-round and wholesome diet. The program can, for example, be used in diet education and on lectures in home economics within compulsory education.
</string>
            <string language="sv">Komponera en hälsosam måltid är ett interaktivt program, med vilket man för olika exempelpersoner kan komponera en lunch enligt givna näringsrekommendationer. Programmet baserar sig på en finländsk näringsmodell som kallas tallriksmodellen. Modellen kan tillämpas till olika individuella behov. Med programmet är det lätt att åskådliggöra hur valet av maträtt och portionens storlek inverkar på måltidens totala energimängd. Dessutom syftar programmet till att vägleda till bestående viktkontroll samt mångsidig och hälsosam kost. Programmet kan bl.a. användas i närvårdarutbildningen samt på lektionerna i hushållslära i grundskolan.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>collection</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine gesunde Mahlzeit zu bestehen ist ein 
Dialogprogramm das Marken es möglich ein Mittagessen für 
unterschiedliche Beispielpersonen entsprechend gegebenen 
Nahrungempfehlungen zu bestehen. Das Programm basiert auf einem 
finnischen Nahrungmodell, das das Tellermodell genannt wird. Das
Modell kann an den unterschiedlichen einzelnen Notwendigkeiten 
angewendet werden. Das Programm verwenden, es das einfache, zu 
veranschaulichen, wie die Wahl des Tellers und der Teil Auswirkungen 
die Gesamtenergiemenge der Mahlzeit sortieren. Außerdem strebt 
das Programm an, als Korrekturlinie zur permanenten Gewichtsteuerung 
und zur vielseitigen und gesunden Diät zu dienen. Das Programm 
kann in der Diätausbildung und auf Vorträgen in der Hauswirtschaft 
innerhalb der Schulpflicht z.B. verwendet werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Composer un repas sain est un programme 
interactif qui des marques il possible de composer un déjeuner pour 
différentes personnes d'exemple conformément aux recommandations 
données de nutrition. Le programme est basé sur un modèle 
finlandais de nutrition appelé le modèle de plat. Le modèle 
peut être appliqué aux différents différents besoins. En 
utilisant le programme, il le facile d'illustrer comment le choix du 
plat et la partie classent des impacts toute la quantité d'énergie 
du repas. D'ailleurs, le programme vise à servir de directive 
à la commande permanente de poids et au régime total et sain. 
Le programme peut, par exemple, être utilisé dans l'éducation
de régime et sur des conférences dans l'économie ménagère dans 
l'éducation forcée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Compôr uma refeição wholesome é um programa 
interativo que makes ele possível compôr um lunch para pessoas 
diferentes do exemplo de acordo com recomendações dadas do 
nutrition. O programa é baseado em um modelo finnish do 
nutrition chamado o modelo do prato. O modelo pode ser aplicado 
às necessidades individuais diferentes. Usando o programa, ele 
o fácil de ilustrar como a escolha do prato e a parcela fazem sob 
medida impactos a quantidade total da energia da refeição. 
Além disso, o programa visa servir como um guideline ao 
controle permanente do peso e à dieta versátil e wholesome. O 
programa pode, para o exemplo, ser usado na instrução da dieta e em 
lectures na economia home dentro da instrução compulsória.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Comporre un pasto sano è un programma interattivo
che marche esso possibile comporre un pranzo per le persone differenti
di esempio conformemente alle date raccomandazioni di nutrizione. 
Il programma è basato su un modello finlandese di nutrizione 
chiamato il modello del piatto. Il modello può essere applicato
ai diversi bisogni differenti. Usando il programma, esso il 
facile illustrare come la scelta del piatto e la parte graduano gli 
effetti secondo la misura la quantità totale di energia del pasto. 
Inoltre, il programma punta su servire da guida di riferimento 
al controllo permanente del peso ed alla dieta completa e sana. 
Il programma può, per esempio, essere usato nella formazione di
dieta e sulle conferenze nell'economia domestica all'interno di 
obbligo scolastico.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Να συνθέσει ένα θρεπτικό γεύμα είναι ένα διαλογικό 
πρόγραμμα που το καθιστά πιθανό να συνθέσει ένα μεσημεριανό 
γεύμα για τα διαφορετικά πρόσωπα παραδείγματος σύμφωνα με τις 
δεδομένες συστάσεις διατροφής. Το πρόγραμμα είναι 
βασισμένο σε ένα φινλανδικό μοντέλο διατροφής αποκαλούμενο 
μοντέλο πιάτων. Το μοντέλο μπορεί να εφαρμοστεί στις 
διαφορετικές ιδιαίτερες ανάγκες. Χρησιμοποιώντας το 
πρόγραμμα, αυτό ο εύκολος να επεξηγήσει πώς η επιλογή του 
πιάτου και του μεγέθους μερίδας επηρεάζει το συνολικό ενεργειακό
ποσό του γεύματος. Επιπλέον, το πρόγραμμα στοχεύει να 
χρησιμεύσει ως μια οδηγία στο μόνιμο έλεγχο βάρους και την ολική
και θρεπτική διατροφή. Το πρόγραμμα μπορεί, παραδείγματος 
χάριν, να χρησιμοποιηθεί στην εκπαίδευση διατροφής και στις 
διαλέξεις στα βασικά οικονομικά μέσα στην υποχρεωτική 
εκπαίδευση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Componer una comida sana es un programa interactivo
que los permitir  componer un almuerzo para diversas personas del 
ejemplo según recomendaciones dadas de la nutrición. El 
programa se basa en un modelo finlandés de la nutrición llamado el 
modelo del plato. El modelo se puede aplicar a diversas 
necesidades individuales. Usando el programa, él el fácil 
ilustrar cómo la opción del plato y la porción clasifican impactos 
la cantidad total de la energía de la comida. Por otra parte, 
el programa tiene como objetivo el servir como guía de consulta al 
control permanente del peso y a la dieta versátil y sana. El 
programa se puede, por ejemplo, utilizar en la educación de la dieta 
y en conferencias en la economía doméstica dentro de la educación 
obligatoria.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>4339</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-02-27</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-30</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-30</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>sv</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>exploration</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>vocational education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>continuing education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">12-18</string>
            <string language="sv">12-18</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>911</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">nutrition education</string>
                <string language="sv">näringslära</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82868</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>application/x-shockwave-flash</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/sve/maltid/</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
