<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82664</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82664</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>1557</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="fi">Kokin päivä</string>
            <string language="en">The Chef's Day</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Tag Des Chefs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Jour du Chef</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Dia Do Chef</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Giorno Del Chef</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ημέρα του αρχιμάγειρα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Día Del Cocinero</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Aihio havainnollistaa etuja, jotka saavutetaan ottamalla oppimateriaalissa primääriseksi kielen esitysmuodoksi videoleike tekstikappaleen sijasta. Kun aihio toteutetaan kevyellä videotekniikalla, se soveltuu esimerkiksi tavaksi taltioida mm. työohjeita, tehtävien toimeksiantoja tai vastaavia siten, että niitä voidaan omaksua omaan tahtiin.
Tässä aihiossa oppilas seuraa autenttista videohaastattelua, jonka perusteella hän tekee kokin päivästä päiväjärjestyksen kalenteriin. Päiväjärjestyksessä on valmiina kellonajat ja se on jaettu aamu- ja iltavuoroon. Ruudulla näkyvissä palkeissa on yhdeksän eri toimintoa (esim. ”Arrive at work”, ”Start lunch service”), jotka esiintyvät kokin kertomuksessa. Oppilaan tehtävänä on siirtää palkit oikeisiin kenttiin päiväjärjestyksessä. Oppilas voi tehdä tehtävää videon pyöriessä tai kuunnella sen ensin kokonaisuudessaan. Videoa on helppo katsoa ja kuunnella niin monta kertaa kuin haluaa.
Kone tarkistaa vastaukset, kun oppilas napauttaa Tarkista-painiketta. Oikeat vastaukset muuttavat väriä ja jähmettyvät paikoilleen ja väärin menneet palkit palaavat takaisin alkuasemiinsa. Tehtävää tehdään niin kauan, että kaikki palkit ovat oikeissa paikoissa.</string>
            <string language="en">The task in question is a good example of using a video clip as the main learning material instead of a traditional book. When it is created by using light video technique it can be used for example for filing working instructions, assignments etc. so that they can be adapted individually. The student watches an authentic video interview and makes an agenda for the chef. The times of the day are ready on the agenda and it is divided into morning and evening shift. On the bars seen on the screen there are 9 different activities (for example”Arrive at work”,”Start lunch service”) that are also to be found in the chef’s story. The task of the student is to move the bars into their right places on the agenda. This can be done while the video is running or by listening to it completely before starting. The video can be rerun as many times as needed. The programme checks the answers when the student clicks on the Check button. The correct answers will change colour and freeze but the incorrect ones return to their original places. The task is repeated until all the bars are in the correct places. </string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Aufgabe in der Frage ist ein gutes Beispiel 
des Verwendens eines videoclips als das Haupterlernenmaterial anstelle
von einem traditionellen Buch. Wenn sie erstellt wird, indem man
helle videotechnik verwendet, die sie zum Beispiel für Archivierung 
Arbeitsanweisungen verwendet werden kann, Anweisungen etc., damit sie 
einzeln angepaßt werden können. Der Kursteilnehmer überwacht 
ein authentisches videointerview und bildet eine Tagesordnung für den
Chef. Die Tageszeiten sind auf der Tagesordnung betriebsbereit 
und sie wird in Morgen- und Abendschicht geteilt. Auf den 
Stäben, die auf den Bildschirm gibt es gesehen werden, 9 
unterschiedliche Aktivitäten (für example?Arrive am work?, am?Start 
Mittagessenservice?) das sind auch, in der chef?s Geschichte 
gefunden zu werden. Die Aufgabe des Kursteilnehmers ist, die 
Stäbe in ihre rechten Plätze auf der Tagesordnung zu verschieben. 
Dieses kann getan werden, während der Bildschirm läuft oder, 
indem er vollständig zu ihm hört, bevor er beginnt. Der 
Bildschirm kann wieder laufen gelassen werden bis zu erforderliche 
Mal. Das Programm überprüft die Antworten, wenn der 
Kursteilnehmer an die Überprüfung Taste klickt. Die korrekten 
Antworten ändern Farbe und frieren ein, aber die falschen gehen zu 
ihren ursprünglichen Plätzen zurück. Die Aufgabe wird 
wiederholt, bis alle Stäbe in den korrekten Plätzen sind.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le charger en question est un bon exemple 
d'utiliser un clip visuel comme matériel d'étude principal au lieu 
d'un livre traditionnel. Quand il est créé en utilisant la 
technique visuelle légère qu'il peut être utilisé par exemple pour
des instructions de fonctionnement de classement, les affectations 
etc. de sorte qu'ils puissent être adaptés individuellement. 
L'étudiant observe une entrevue visuelle authentique et fait un
ordre du jour pour le chef. Les temps du jour sont prêts à 
l'ordre du jour et il est divisé en décalage de matin et de soirée.
Sur les barres vues sur l'écran il y a 9 activités 
différentes (pour example?Arrive au work?, au service de déjeuner de
?Start ?) ce doivent également être trouvés dans l'histoire 
de chef?s. Le charger de l'étudiant doit entrer les barres 
dans leurs bons endroits à l'ordre du jour. Ceci peut être 
fait tandis que le vidéo fonctionne ou en écoutant lui complètement
avant de démarrer. Le vidéo peut être réexécuté autant de 
fois aussi nécessaires. Le programme contrôle les réponses 
quand l'étudiant clique sur le bouton de contrôle. 
Les réponses correctes changeront la couleur et gèleront mais 
l'incorrecte revient à leurs endroits initiaux. Le charger 
est répété jusqu'à ce que toutes les barres soient dans les 
endroits corrects.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A tarefa na pergunta é um exemplo bom de usar um
grampo video como o material de aprendizagem principal em vez de um 
livro tradicional. Quando for criada usando a técnica que video
clara pode ser usada para o exemplo para arquivar instruções de 
funcionamento, as atribuições etc. de modo que possam ser adaptadas 
individualmente. O estudante presta atenção a uma entrevista 
video authentic e faz uma agenda para o chef. Os tempos do dia 
estão prontos na agenda e é dividida na SHIFT da manhã e da noite. 
Nas barras vistas na tela há 9 atividades diferentes (para 
example?Arrive no work?, no serviço do lunch do?Start?) aquele 
é também ser encontrado na história dos chef?s. A tarefa do 
estudante é mover as barras em seus lugares direitos na agenda. 
Isto pode ser feito quando o vídeo funcionar ou escutando ele 
completamente antes de começar. O vídeo pode ser tornado a 
colocar em funcionamento tantas como vezes tão needed. O 
programa verifica as respostas quando o estudante estala sobre a tecla
da verificação. As respostas corretas mudarão a cor e 
congelar-se-ão mas incorretas retornam a seus lugares originais. 
A tarefa é repetida até que todas as barras estejam nos 
lugares corretos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'operazione in questione è un buon esempio di 
per mezzo di video clip come il materiale imparante principale 
anziché un libro tradizionale. Quando è creata usando la video
tecnica che chiara può essere usata per esempio per le istruzioni di 
funzionamento dell'archivario, assegnazioni ecc. in moda da poterli 
adattarsi individualmente. L'allievo guarda una video intervista
autentica e fa un ordine del giorno per il chef. I tempi del 
giorno sono aspettano all'ordine del giorno ed è diviso nello 
spostamento di sera e di mattina. Sulle barre viste sullo 
schermo ci sono 9 attività differenti (per example?Arrive a work?, a 
servizio del pranzo del?Start?) quella è egualmente di essere 
trovata nella storia dei chef?s. L'operazione dell'allievo è di
entrare le barre nei loro giusti posti all'ordine del giorno. 
Ciò può essere fatta mentre il video sta funzionando o 
ascoltando esso completamente prima dell'avviarsi. Il video può
essere ripetuto altretante volte necessarie. Il programma 
controlla le risposte quando l'allievo scatta sopra il tasto del 
controllo. Le risposte corrette cambieranno il colore e 
congeleranno ma quei errati ritornano ai loro posti originali. 
L'operazione è ripetuta fino a che tutte le barre non siano nei
posti corretti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η στοιχειώδης εργασία εν λόγω είναι ένα καλό 
παράδειγμα έναν τηλεοπτικό συνδετήρα ως βασικό υλικό εκμάθησης 
αντί ενός παραδοσιακού βιβλίου. Όταν δημιουργείται με τη 
χρησιμοποίηση της ελαφριάς τηλεοπτικής τεχνικής μπορεί να 
χρησιμοποιηθεί παραδείγματος χάριν για την αρχειοθέτηση των 
οδηγιών εργασίας, των αναθέσεων κ.λπ. έτσι ώστε μπορούν να 
προσαρμοστούν χωριστά. Ο σπουδαστής προσέχει μια αυθεντική 
τηλεοπτική συνέντευξη και κάνει μια ημερήσια διάταξη για τον 
αρχιμάγειρα. Οι χρόνοι της ημέρας είναι αναμένουνε στην
ημερήσια διάταξη και διαιρείται σε μετατόπιση πρωινού και 
βραδιού. Στις ράβδους που βλέπουνε στην οθόνη 
υπάρχουν 9 διαφορετικές δραστηριότητες (για example?Arrive στην 
υπηρεσία μεσημεριανού γεύματος work?, ?Start;) που 
πρόκειται επίσης να βρεθεί στην ιστορία chef?s. Η 
στοιχειώδης εργασία του σπουδαστή είναι να κινήσει τις ράβδους 
στις σωστές θέσεις τους στην ημερήσια διάταξη. Αυτό μπορεί
να γίνει ενώ το βίντεο τρέχει ή με να ακούσει σε το εντελώς 
πρίν αρχίζει. Το βίντεο μπορεί να είναι επανάληψη τόσο 
πολλοί χρόνοι όπως απαιτείται. Το πρόγραμμα ελέγχει τις 
απαντήσεις όταν χτυπά ο σπουδαστής στο κουμπί ελέγχου. Οι 
σωστές απαντήσεις θα αλλάξουν το χρώμα και θα παγώσουν αλλά οι 
ανακριβείς επιστρέφουν στις αρχικές θέσεις τους. Η 
στοιχειώδης εργασία επαναλαμβάνεται έως ότου είναι όλες οι 
ράβδοι στις σωστές θέσεις.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La tarea en la pregunta es un buen ejemplo de 
usar un clip video como el material que aprende principal en vez de un
libro tradicional. Cuando es creada usando técnica video ligera
que puede ser utilizada por ejemplo para las instrucciones de 
funcionamiento de la clasificación, las asignaciones etc. para 
poderlos adaptarse individualmente. El estudiante mira una 
entrevista video auténtica y hace una agenda para el cocinero. 
Los tiempos del día son listos en la agenda y se divide en la 
rotación de la mañana y de la tarde. En las barras vistas en 
la pantalla hay 9 diversas actividades (para example?Arrive en el 
work?, el servicio del almuerzo del?Start?) ése debe también 
ser encontrado en la historia del cocinero. La tarea del 
estudiante es mover las barras en sus lugares derechos en la agenda. 
Esto puede ser hecha mientras que el vídeo se está ejecutando 
o escuchando él totalmente antes de comenzar. El vídeo se 
puede volver a efectuar tantas veces tan necesarias. El programa
controla las respuestas cuando el estudiante hace clic encendido el 
botón del cheque. Las respuestas correctas cambiarán color y 
congelarán pero los incorrectos vuelven a sus lugares originales. 
Se relanza la tarea hasta que todas las barras están en los 
lugares correctos.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>1557</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-01-12</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-15</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-15</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>fi</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">10-U</string>
            <string language="fi">&gt; 10</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">englannin kieli</string>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">kielet</string>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>710</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">kielten opetus</string>
                <string language="en">language teaching</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>700</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">työ</string>
                <string language="en">labour</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82664</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/kokki/co3.exe</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
