<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82439</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82439</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>3984</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Common background</string>
            <string language="sv">Common background</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geläufiger Hintergrund</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Fond commun</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fundo comum</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Priorità bassa comune</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινό υπόβαθρο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fondo común</string>
          </title>
          <language>sv</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The student listens to presentations of eight persons. In the presentations an extensive vocabulary is used, vocabulary that relates to records of the individuals (among others age, nationality, home location, hobbies). Then the student is to place the individuals in groups, based on their common properties. Several of the persons can have something in common but the point is that the student should find the unifying factors that make it possible to divide the persons in four groups of two persons. Apart from listening comprehension and vocabulary knowledge, the student must be able to draw conclusions and apply the information in order to solve the exercise. This exercise is challenging and therefore the instructions urge the student to take notes during the task.
</string>
            <string language="sv">Eleven hör presentationer av åtta personer. I presentationerna finns rikligt med vokabulär som anknyter till personuppgifter (bl.a. ålder, nationalitet, boningsort, hobbyer). Sedan ska eleven gruppera personerna på basis av deras gemensamma egenskaper. Flera av personerna kan ha någonting gemensamt men meningen är att eleven ska hitta de förenande faktorerna som gör att man kan dela in personerna just i fyra grupper på två personer. Förutom hörförståelse och kunskap om ordförråd måste eleven för att lösa uppgiften kunna dra slutsatser och tillämpa informationen. Denna uppgift är utmanande och i instruktionerna uppmanas eleven därför att föra anteckningar under uppgiften.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Kursteilnehmer hört zu den Darstellungen von 
acht Personen. In den Darstellungen wird ein umfangreicher 
Wortschatz, Wortschatz verwendet, der auf Sätzen der Einzelpersonen 
in Verbindung steht (unter anderen altern Sie, Nationalität, 
Hauptstandort, Liebhabereien). Dann soll der Kursteilnehmer die 
Einzelpersonen in die Gruppen legen, basiert auf ihrem 
gemeinschaftlichen Allgemeingut. Mehrere der Personen können 
etwas im Common haben, aber der Punkt ist, daß der Kursteilnehmer die
Vereinheitlichenfaktoren finden sollte, die es möglich, die Personen 
in vier Gruppen von zwei Personen zu teilen machen. Abgesehen 
von hörendem Erfassen- und Wortschatzwissen muß der Kursteilnehmer 
können, Zusammenfassungen zu zeichnen und die Informationen 
anzuwenden, um die Übung zu lösen. Diese Übung ist schwierig 
und folglich drängen die Anweisungen den Kursteilnehmer, Anmerkungen 
während der Aufgabe zu nehmen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'étudiant écoute des présentations de huit 
personnes. Dans les présentations un vocabulaire étendu est 
utilisé, le vocabulaire qui associe aux enregistrements des individus
(entre d'autres vieillissez, nationalité, emplacement à la maison, 
passe-temps). Alors l'étudiant doit placer les individus dans 
les groupes, basés sur leurs propriétés communes. Plusieurs 
des personnes peuvent avoir quelque chose en commun mais le point est 
que l'étudiant devrait trouver les facteurs d'unification qui 
permettent pour diviser les personnes dans quatre groupes de deux 
personnes. Indépendamment de la connaissance d'écoute de 
compréhension et de vocabulaire, l'étudiant doit pouvoir tirer des 
conclusions et appliquer l'information afin de résoudre l'exercice. 
Cet exercice est provocant et donc les instructions invitent 
l'étudiant à prendre des notes pendant le charger.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O estudante escuta apresentações de oito 
pessoas. Nas apresentações um vocabulário extensivo é usado,
o vocabulário que se relaciona aos registros dos indivíduos (entre 
outros envelheça, nacionalidade, posição home, passatempos). 
Então o estudante deve colocar os indivíduos nos grupos, 
baseados em suas propriedades comuns. Diversas das pessoas podem
ter algo na terra comum mas o ponto é que o estudante deve encontrar 
os fatores unifying que fazem possível dividir as pessoas em quatro 
grupos de duas pessoas. Aparte do conhecimento escutando da 
compreensão e do vocabulário, o estudante deve poder  desenhar 
conclusões e aplicar a informação a fim resolver o exercício. 
Este exercício é challenging e conseqüentemente as 
instruções incitam o estudante fazer exame de notas durante a 
tarefa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'allievo ascolta lle presentazioni di otto 
persone. Nelle presentazioni un vasto vocabolario è usato, 
vocabolario che si riferisce ai record degli individui (tra altri 
invecchi, nazionalità, posizione domestica, hobby). Allora 
l'allievo deve disporre gli individui nei gruppi, basati sulle loro 
proprietà comuni. Varie delle persone possono avere qualcosa il
in comune ma il punto è che l'allievo dovrebbe trovare i fattori di 
unificazione che permettono di dividere le persone in quattro gruppi 
di due persone. Oltre a conoscenza ascoltante di vocabolario e 
di comprensione, l'allievo deve potere dissipare le conclusioni ed 
applicare le informazioni per risolvere l'esercitazione. Questa 
esercitazione è challenging e quindi le istruzioni invitano l'allievo
a prendere le note durante l'operazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο σπουδαστής ακούει τις παρουσιάσεις οκτώ ατόμων. 
Στις παρουσιάσεις ένα εκτενές λεξιλόγιο χρησιμοποιείται, 
λεξιλόγιο που αφορά τα αρχεία των ατόμων (μεταξύ των άλλων 
ηλικία, υπηκοότητα, βασική θέση, χόμπι). Κατόπιν ο 
σπουδαστής πρόκειται να τοποθετήσει τα άτομα κατά ομάδες, που 
εδρεύουν στις κοινές ιδιότητές τους. Αρκετά από τα 
πρόσωπα μπορούν να έχουν κάτι από κοινού αλλά το σημείο είναι
ότι ο σπουδαστής πρέπει να βρεί τους ενοποιώντας παράγοντες που 
το καθιστούν πιθανό να διαιρέσουν τα πρόσωπα σε τέσσερις ομάδες 
δύο ατόμων. Εκτός από την κατανόηση ακούσματος και τη 
γνώση λεξιλογίου, ο σπουδαστής πρέπει να είναι σε θέση να 
συναγάγει τα συμπεράσματα και να εφαρμόσει τις πληροφορίες 
προκειμένου να λυθεί η άσκηση. Αυτή η άσκηση είναι 
προκλητική και επομένως οι οδηγίες ωθούν το σπουδαστή για να 
πάρουν τις σημειώσεις κατά τη διάρκεια της στοιχειώδους 
εργασίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El estudiante escucha las presentaciones de ocho 
personas. En las presentaciones se utiliza un vocabulario 
extenso, el vocabulario que se relaciona con los expedientes de los 
individuos (entre otros envejezca, nacionalidad, localización casera,
manías). Entonces el estudiante debe colocar a los individuos 
en los grupos, basados en sus características comunes. Varias 
de las personas pueden tener algo en campo común pero la punta es que
el estudiante debe encontrar los factores de la unificación que 
permiten dividir a las personas en cuatro grupos de dos personas. 
Aparte de conocimiento de la comprensión que escucha y del 
vocabulario, el estudiante debe poder trazar conclusiones y aplicar la
información para solucionar el ejercicio. Este ejercicio es 
desafiador y por lo tanto las instrucciones impulsan a estudiante 
tomar notas durante la tarea.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>3984</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-02-16</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-17</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-17</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>sv</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">8-15</string>
            <string language="sv">8-15</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Listening comprehension exercise, exercise of vocabulary related to individual information; simultaneously trains the powers of deduction.
</string>
            <string language="sv">Hörförståelseövning, övning av  ordförrådet relaterat till personuppgifter; övar samtidigt slutledningsförmågan</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
                <string language="sv">språkområden</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
                <string language="sv">engelska språket</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82439</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>audio/basic</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://resources.eun.org/demoportal/common_background_sve.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
