<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82761</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82761</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>1532</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="fi">AudioGrammar</string>
            <string language="en">AudioGrammar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">AudioGrammar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">AudioGrammar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">AudioGrammar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">AudioGrammar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">AudioGrammar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">AudioGrammar</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Aihio esittelee laajakäyttöisen tavan opettaa oppilasta poimimaan rakenteellista informaatiota puheesta. Siinä korostetaan uuden tekniikan vaikutusta perinteiseen kieliopin kaavio-opetukseen.

Oppilaan tehtävänä on rakentaa rakennekaaviot kuulemansa perusteella. Harjoituksen materiaalina ovat kysymyslauseet, joilla tiedustellaan ihmisten preferenssejä. Oppilas näkee eri lausetyyppien kohdalla vaillinaisesti täytetyn rakennekaavion ja 6-8 henkilön kuvaa. Napauttamalla kuvaa oppilas kuulee kysymyksen, joka sopii ainoastaan yhdelle rakennekaavion riville. Rakennekaavion solut reagoivat jokaiseen napautukseen vaihtamalla tekstiään ja oppilas rakentaa rivit vastaamaan kuulemiaan kysymyksiä. Tarkista-painiketta painamalla ohjelma tarkistaa tehtävän, oikein rakennetut lauseet kuuluvat puhuttuna ja näkyvät ruudulla.</string>
            <string language="en">This exercise teaches the student to pick structural information from the speech. It emphasises the use of modern technologies when teaching grammar. The student’s task is to build a structural diagram on the basis of what he/ she has heard. The material consists of questions on peoples’ preferences. The student sees an incomplete structural diagram next to a sentence and pictures of 6-8 people. By clicking the picture the pupil hears a question which only fits one line of the structural diagram. The cells of the diagram react to every click by changing the text and the pupil completes the lines so that they correspond to the sentences heard. By pressing the check button the programme checks the task. The sentences that are completed correctly can be heard and they are also shown on the screen.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Übung unterrichtet den Kursteilnehmer, 
strukturelle Informationen von der Rede auszuwählen. Sie hebt 
den Gebrauch von modernen Technologien hervor, wenn sie Grammatik 
unterrichten. Die student?s Aufgabe ist, aufzubauen ein 
strukturelles Diagramm auf der Grundlage von, was er sie gehört hat. 
Das Material besteht aus Fragen über Völker? 
Präferenzen. Der Kursteilnehmer sieht ein 
unvollständiges strukturelles Diagramm nahe bei einem Programmsatz 
und Abbildungen von 6-8 Leuten. Indem er die Abbildung anklickt,
hört die Schüler eine Frage, die nur eine Zeile des strukturellen 
Diagramms paßt. Die Zellen des Diagramms reagieren zu jedem 
Klicken, indem sie den Text ändern und die Pupille führt die Zeilen 
durch, damit sie den gehörten Programmsätzen entsprechen. 
Indem Sie die Überprüfung betätigen, knöpfen Sie die 
Programmüberprüfungen die Aufgabe. Die Programmsätze, die 
richtig können gehört werden durchgeführt werden und sie werden 
auch auf dem Bildschirm gezeigt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cet exercice enseigne l'étudiant à 
sélectionner l'information structurale du discours. Il souligne
l'utilisation des technologies modernes en enseignant la grammaire. 
Les student?s chargent doit établir un diagramme 
structural sur la base de ce qu'il elle a entendu. Le matériel 
se compose des questions sur des peuples ? préférences. 
L'étudiant voit un diagramme structural inachevé à côté 
d'une phrase et des images de 6-8 personnes. En cliquant
l'image l'élève entend une question qui adapte seulement une ligne 
du diagramme structural. Les cellules du diagramme réagissent 
à chaque clic en changeant le texte et la pupille termine les 
lignes de sorte qu'elles correspondent aux phrases entendues. En
appuyant le contrôle boutonnez les contrôles de programme le 
charger. Les phrases qui sont terminées correctement peuvent
être entendues et elles sont également montrées sur l'écran.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este exercício ensina o estudante escolher a 
informação estrutural do discurso. Emfatiza o uso de 
tecnologias modernas ao ensinar a gramática. A tarefa dos 
student?s é construir um diagrama estrutural na base de o que ela se 
ouviu. O material consiste em perguntas em povos? 
preferências. O estudante vê um diagrama estrutural 
incompleto ao lado de uma sentença e dos retratos de 6-8 povos. 
Estalando o retrato o aluno ouve uma pergunta que caiba somente 
uma linha do diagrama estrutural. As pilhas do diagrama reagem a
cada clique mudando o texto e a pupila termina as linhas de modo que 
correspondam às sentenças ouvidas. Pressionando a 
verificação abotoe as verificações do programa a tarefa. As 
sentenças que são terminadas corretamente podem ser ouvidas e são 
mostradas também na tela.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa esercitazione insegna l'allievo 
selezionare le informazioni strutturali dal discorso. Dà 
risalto all'uso delle tecnologie moderne quando insegna la grammatica.
L'operazione degli student?s è di sviluppare uno schema 
strutturale in base a che cosa lei si è sentito. Il materiale 
consiste delle domande sulla gente? preferenze. L'allievo 
vede uno schema strutturale incompleto vicino ad una frase ed alle 
immagini di 6-8 genti. Scattando l'immagine l'allievo sente una 
domanda che misura soltanto una riga dello schema strutturale. 
Le cellule dello schema reagiscono ad ogni scatto cambiando il 
testo e la pupilla completa le righe in modo che corrispondano alle 
frasi sentite. Premendo il controllo abbottoni i controlli di 
programma l'operazione. Le frasi che sono completate 
correttamente possono essere sentite e egualmente sono indicate sullo 
schermo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η άσκηση διδάσκει το σπουδαστή για να επιλέξει 
τις δομικές πληροφορίες από την ομιλία. Υπογραμμίζει τη 
χρήση των σύγχρονων τεχνολογιών κατά το διδασκαλία της 
γραμματικής. Η στοιχειώδης εργασία student?s είναι να 
χτιστεί ένα δομικό διάγραμμα βάσει αυτό που έχει ακούσει. 
Το υλικό αποτελείται από τις ερωτήσεις στους λαούς; 
προτιμήσεις. Ο σπουδαστής βλέπει ένα ελλιπές 
δομικό διάγραμμα δίπλα σε μια πρόταση και τις εικόνες 6-8 
ανθρώπων. Με τον κρότο της εικόνας ο μαθητής ακούει μια 
ερώτηση που εγκαθιστά μόνο μια γραμμή του δομικού διαγράμματος. 
Τα κύτταρα του διαγράμματος αντιδρούν σε κάθε στιγμιαίο 
πάτημα με την αλλαγή του κειμένου και ο μαθητής ολοκληρώνει τις 
γραμμές έτσι ώστε αντιστοιχούν στις προτάσεις που ακούονται. 
Με την πίεση του κουμπιού ελέγχου το πρόγραμμα ελέγχει τη 
στοιχειώδη εργασία. Οι προτάσεις που ολοκληρώνονται σωστά 
μπορούν να ακουστούν και εμφανίζονται επίσης στην οθόνη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este ejercicio enseña a estudiante a escoger la 
información estructural del discurso. Acentúa el uso de 
tecnologías modernas al enseñar la gramática. La tarea de los
student?s es construir un diagrama estructural en base de lo que él 
ella ha oído. ¿El material consiste en preguntas sobre la 
gente? preferencias. El estudiante ve un diagrama 
estructural incompleto al lado de una sentencia y de los cuadros de 
6-8 personas. Haciendo clic el cuadro la pupila oye una pregunta
que quepa solamente una línea del diagrama estructural. Las 
células del diagrama reaccionan a cada tecleo cambiando el texto y la
pupila termina las líneas de modo que correspondan a las sentencias 
oídas. Presionando el cheque abotone los cheques del programa 
la tarea. Las sentencias que se terminan correctamente pueden 
ser oídas y ellas también se muestran en la pantalla.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>1532</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2003-12-23</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-10</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-10</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>fi</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">9-13</string>
            <string language="fi">9-13</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Englannin kielen peruslauserakenteiden ja sanajärjestyksen harjoittelu</string>
            <string language="en">Practicing the basic sentence structure and word order of English.</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">kielet</string>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>710</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">kielten opetus</string>
                <string language="en">language teaching</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">englannin kieli</string>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1277</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">opetus</string>
                <string language="en">teaching</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1281</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">opetusmateriaalit</string>
                <string language="en">teaching materials</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82761</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>image/bmp</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://resources.eun.org/demoportal/audio_grammar_fi1.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
