<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82759</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82759</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>4002</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Numbers - a game about digits</string>
            <string language="sv">Numbers - sifferspelet</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zahlen - ein Spiel über Digits</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Nombres - un jeu au sujet des chiffres</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Números - um jogo sobre dígitos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Numeri - un gioco circa le cifre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αριθμοί - ένα παιχνίδι για τα ψηφία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Números - un juego sobre dígitos</string>
          </title>
          <language>sv</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The learning object practices numbers in a new and game-like way. The exercise consists of five parts and the machine randomly outputs different numbers to practise on. The exercise especially develops the ability to connect a number in writing and the corresponding pronunciation. In the lower edge of the screen there are five speech bubbles, from which different numbers are heard. The student will place the correct figures in the sections after the figure that already is in the square. The idea is to form an entity with three subsequent numbers. The program recognizes automatically the correct number and locks it on its place. When encountering a wrong placement, the program continues to the next part.



</string>
            <string language="sv">Lärobjektet övar siffrorna på ett nytt och spelliknande sätt. Uppgiften består av fem moment och maskinen lottar alltid ut olika stora siffror att öva. Uppgiften utvecklar särskilt förmågan att kunna koppla ihop en siffra i skrift och siffrans uttal.

I nedre kanten av rutan finns fem pratbubblor. Från dem hörs olika siffror. Eleven ska placera de rätta siffrorna i balkarna efter den siffra som finns färdigt i rutan. Meningen är att bilda en helhet med tre efterföljande siffror. Programmet känner automatiskt igen den korrekta siffran och låser den på sin plats. Vid felplaceringar fortsätter programmet till följande moment.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die erlernennachricht übt Zahlen in einem neuem 
und Spiel-wie Methode. Die Übung besteht aus fünf Teilen und 
die Maschine gibt nach dem zufall unterschiedliche Zahlen aus, um an 
zu üben. Die Übung entwickelt besonders die Fähigkeit, eine 
Zahl im Schreiben und im entsprechenden Aussprache anzuschließen. 
Im untereren Rand des Bildschirms gibt es fünf Redeluftblasen, 
von denen unterschiedliche Zahlen gehört werden. Der 
Kursteilnehmer legt die korrekten Abbildungen in die Kapitel nach der 
Abbildung, die bereits im Quadrat ist. Die Idee ist, eine 
Instanz mit drei folgenden Zahlen zu bilden. Das Programm 
erkennt automatisch die korrekte Zahl und die Verriegelungen es auf 
seinem Platz. Wenn es eine falsche Plazierung antrifft, fährt 
das Programm zum folgenden Teil fort.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'objet d'étude pratique des nombres dans un 
nouveau et jeu-comme la voie. L'exercice se compose de cinq 
parts et la machine sort aléatoirement différents nombres pour 
pratiquer en fonction. L'exercice développe particulièrement 
la capacité de relier un nombre dans l'écriture et la prononciation 
correspondante. Dans le bord inférieur de l'écran il y a cinq 
bulles de la parole, dont différents nombres sont entendus. 
L'étudiant placera les figures correctes dans les sections 
après la figure qui est déjà dans la place. L'idée est de 
former une entité avec trois nombres ultérieurs. Le programme 
identifie automatiquement le nombre et les serrures corrects il sur 
son endroit. En rencontrant un placement faux, le programme 
continue à la prochaine partie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O objeto de aprendizagem pratica números em um 
novo e jogo-como a maneira. O exercício consiste em cinco 
porções e a máquina outputs aleatòria números diferentes para 
praticar sobre. O exercício desenvolve especial a abilidade de 
conectar um número na escrita e na pronunciação correspondente. 
Na borda mais baixa da tela há cinco bolhas do discurso, de que
os números diferentes são ouvidos. O estudante colocará as 
figuras corretas nas seções após a figura que está já no 
quadrado. A idéia é dar forma a uma entidade com três 
números subseqüentes. O programa reconhece automaticamente o 
número e os fechamentos corretos ele em seu lugar. Ao encontrar
uma colocação errada, o programa continua à parte seguinte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'oggetto imparante si esercita nei numeri in un 
nuovo e gioco-come il modo. L'esercitazione consiste di cinque 
parti e la macchina produce a caso i numeri differenti per esercitarsi
in sopra. L'esercitazione sviluppa particolarmente la capacità 
di collegare un numero nella scrittura e nella pronuncia 
corrispondente. Nel bordo più basso dello schermo ci sono 
cinque bolle di discorso, da cui i numeri differenti sono sentiti. 
L'allievo disporrà le figure corrette nelle sezioni dopo la 
figura che già è nel quadrato. L'idea è formare un'entità 
con tre numeri successivi. Il programma riconosce 
automaticamente il numero e le serrature corretti esso sul relativo 
posto. Nell'incontrare una disposizione errata, il programma 
continua alla parte seguente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι αριθμοί πρακτικών αντικειμένου εκμάθησης με έναν 
νέο και game-like τρόπο. Η άσκηση αποτελείται από πέντε
μέρη και τους διαφορετικούς αριθμούς αποτελεσμάτων μηχανών 
τυχαία στην πρακτική επάνω. Η άσκηση αναπτύσσει ειδικά τη 
δυνατότητα να συνδεθεί ένας αριθμός εγγράφως να γράψει και η 
αντίστοιχη προφορά. Στη χαμηλότερη άκρη της οθόνης 
υπάρχουν πέντε λεκτικές φυσαλίδες, από τις οποίες οι 
διαφορετικοί αριθμοί λαμβάνονται νέα. Ο σπουδαστής θα 
τοποθετήσει τους σωστούς αριθμούς στα τμήματα μετά από τον 
αριθμό που είναι ήδη στο τετράγωνο. Η ιδέα είναι να 
διαμορφωθεί μια οντότητα με τρεις επόμενους αριθμούς. Το 
πρόγραμμα αναγνωρίζει αυτόματα το σωστό αριθμό και τον κλειδώνει
στη θέση του. Κατά αντιμετώπιση μιας λανθασμένης 
τοποθέτησης, την πρόγραμμα συνεχίζεται στο επόμενο μέρος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El objeto que aprende practica números en un 
nuevo y juego-como manera. El ejercicio consiste en cinco 
porciones y la máquina hace salir aleatoriamente diversos números 
para practicar encendido. El ejercicio desarrolla especialmente 
la capacidad de conectar un número en la escritura y la 
pronunciación correspondiente. En el borde más bajo de la 
pantalla hay cinco burbujas del discurso, de las cuales se oyen 
diversos números. El estudiante pondrá las figuras correctas 
en las secciones después de la figura que está ya en el cuadrado. 
La idea es formar una entidad con tres números subsecuentes. 
El programa reconoce automáticamente el número y los bloqueos 
correctos él en su lugar. Al encontrar una colocación 
incorrecta, el programa continúa a la parte siguiente.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>4002</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-02-16</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-30</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-30</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>sv</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">9-13</string>
            <string language="sv">9-13</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Exercise of numbers in English; to connect pronunciation and spelling</string>
            <string language="sv">Övning av siffror på engelska; att koppla ihop uttal och stavning</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
                <string language="sv">språkområden</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
                <string language="sv">engelska språket</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82759</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>audio/basic</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://resources.eun.org/demoportal/numbers_sve.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
