<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82552</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82552</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>1539</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="fi">Finding your way aroung Helsinki</string>
            <string language="en">Finding your way around Helsinki</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Finden Ihrer Methode um Helsinki</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Trouver votre chemin autour de Helsinki</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Encontrando sua maneira em torno de Helsínquia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Individuazione del vostro modo intorno ad 
Helsinki</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εύρεση του τρόπου σας γύρω από το Ελσίνκι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Encontrar su manera alrededor de Helsinki</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Oppilas etenee suullisten ohjeiden mukaisesti paikasta toiseen Helsingin keskustan ”puhuvalla kartalla”. Ruudulla näkyvä kartta kommentoi jatkuvasti virheellistä työskentelyä. Aihio havainnollistaa yksinkertaisen mikromaailman hyödyntämistä vieraan kielen opiskelussa.
Oppilaan tehtävänä on eläytyä turistin rooliin ja kulkea saamiensa ohjeiden mukaan aidolla kartalla. (Esimerkiksi ”Kulje satamasta Kauppatorille ostamaan jäätelöä.”, ”Näytä missä on nykytaiteen museo Kiasma”.) Ohjeet sisältyvät todentuntuiseen kertomukseen. Oppilas osoittaa kohteita napauttamalla niitä kartalla ja mikäli kohde on paikannettu oikein, kartalle ilmestyy etenemistä osoittava kävelyreitti. Välillä pysähdytään myös ihailemaan nähtävyyksiä: joitakin kohteita napauttamalla oppilas näkee ruudulla valokuvan kohteesta. Kaikkia vääriä napautuksia seuraa puhuttu kommentti.  Näin oppilas altistuu puhutulle kielelle myös yrittäessään umpimähkäisesti napauttaa karttaa sieltä täältä.  Koska oppilaan napautuksesta välittyy aina paikkatieto, ohjeet tuntuvat oppilaasta järkeviltä. Jos hän esimerkiksi lähtee rautatieasemalta väärään suuntaan, hän saa siitä ohjelmalta oikeaan palautteen, joka kehottaa kiinnittämään huomiota johonkin tiettyyn yksityiskohtaan kartalla. Lopuksi oppilas näkee kuvan kohteesta, johon hän on päätynyt.</string>
            <string language="en">The student moves from one place to another on “a speaking map” of Helsinki according to the given oral instructions. The map on the screen makes remarks if the student doesn’t work correctly. The task is using a simple micro world in language teaching. The student is supposed to become a tourist and move on the map according to the given instructions. (For example “Walk from the harbour to the Market square to buy some ice cream.”, “Show me where the Museum of Contemporary Art Kiasma is”.) The instructions are built upon an apparently truthful story. The student indicates places by clicking on them on the map and if the place is located correctly the route will appear on the map. Now and then sights are also admired because by clicking on certain sights a photo of the place is shown on the screen. Every wrong click will be followed by a spoken comment. This way by random clicking the map the student is also predisposed to the spoken language. Because the student always gets information on the place after the clicking, the directions seem sensible. For example, if he /she leaves the railway station and walks in the wrong direction instant feedback is given and he / she is asked to pay attention to a certain detail on the map. Finally the student sees a picture of the place that he / she has ended up in.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Kursteilnehmer zieht von einem Platz auf 
andere auf?a sprechender Karte um? von Helsinki entsprechend den
erteilten Mundanweisungen. Die Karte auf den Bildschirmmarken 
erwähnt, wenn das Kursteilnehmer doesn?t richtig arbeiten. Die 
Aufgabe benutzt eine einfache Mikrowelt im Sprachunterricht. Der
Kursteilnehmer soll ein Tourist werden und auf die Karte entsprechend 
den erteilten Anweisungen umziehen. (zum Beispiel?Walk vom Hafen
zum Marktquadrat, zum von von etwas Eiscreme zu kaufen?, ?Show 
ich, wo das Museum der zeitgenössischen kunst Kiasma?. ist) Die
Anweisungen werden nach einer anscheinend truthful Geschichte 
aufgebaut. Der Kursteilnehmer zeigt an, daß Plätze, indem sie 
auf ihnen auf der Karte und wenn der Platz richtig lokalisiert wird, 
der Weg klicken, auf der Karte erscheinen. Jetzt und dann wird 
Anblick auch bewundert, weil, indem man auf bestimmtem Anblick klickt,
ein Foto des Platzes auf dem Bildschirm gezeigt wird. Jedes 
falsche Klicken wird von einem gesprochenen Kommentar gefolgt. 
Diese Methode durch gelegentliches, die Karte anklickend der 
Kursteilnehmer, ist auch für die gesprochene Sprache veranlagt. 
Weil der Kursteilnehmer immer Informationen über den Platz nach
dem Klicken erhält, scheinen die Richtungen vernünftig. Z.B. 
wenn er /she verläßt, wird der Bahnhof und die Wege im falsche 
Richtung sofortigen Feedback gegeben und er/sie werden gebeten, ein 
bestimmtes Detail über die Karte zu beachten. Schließlich 
sieht der Kursteilnehmer eine Abbildung des Platzes, den er/sie oben 
innen beendet haben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'étudiant se déplace d'un endroit à l'autre 
sur la carte parlante de ?a ? de Helsinki selon les instructions
orales données. La carte sur les marques d'écran remarque si 
le doesn?t d'étudiant fonctionnent correctement. Le charger
utilise un monde micro simple dans l'enseignement des langues. 
L'étudiant est censé devenir un touriste et se déplacer sur 
la carte selon les instructions données. (par exemple ?Walk du 
port à la place du marché pour acheter de la crême glacée ?, 
?Show j'où le musée de l'art contemporain Kiasma est ?.) 
Les instructions sont établies sur une histoire apparent 
véridique. L'étudiant indique que les endroits en 
cliquant sur elles sur la carte et si l'endroit est localisé
correctement l'itinéraire apparaîtront sur la carte. Des vues 
également maintenant et puis sont admirées parce qu'en 
cliquant sur certaines vues une photo de l'endroit est 
montrée sur l'écran. Chaque clic faux sera suivi d'un 
commentaire parlé. Cette voie par aléatoire cliquant 
la carte l'étudiant est également prédisposée au langage parlé. 
Puisque l'étudiant obtient toujours l'information sur l'endroit
après cliquer, les directions semblent sensibles. Par
exemple, s'il /she part la gare et les promenades dans le feedback 
instantané de direction fausse est donnée et lui/elle est invité à
prêter l'attention à un certain détail sur la carte. Enfin 
l'étudiant voit une image de l'endroit que lui/elle a terminé vers 
le haut dedans.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O estudante move-se de um lugar para outro no mapa 
falador do?a? de Helsínquia de acordo com as instruções orais
dadas. O mapa nos makes da tela observa se o doesn?t do 
estudante trabalhar corretamente. A tarefa está usando um micro
mundo simples na instrução de línguas. O estudante é suposto
transformar-se um turista e mover-se no mapa de acordo com as 
instruções dadas. (para o?Walk do exemplo do porto ao quadrado
do mercado para comprar algum creme de gelo?, ?Show mim onde o 
museu da arte contemporary Kiasma está?.) As instruções são 
construídas em cima de uma história aparentemente truthful. O 
estudante indica que os lugares estalando nelas no mapa e se o lugar 
for encontrado corretamente a rota aparecerão no mapa. As 
vistas são admiradas agora e então também porque estalando em 
determinadas vistas uma foto do lugar é mostrada na tela. Cada 
clique errado será seguido por um comentário falado. Esta 
maneira por aleatório estalando o mapa o estudante é também 
predisposed à língua falada. Porque o estudante começa sempre
a informação no lugar após estalar, os sentidos parecem sensible. 
Para o exemplo, se /she sairem a estação railway e as 
caminhadas no feedback imediato do sentido errado é dada e/é pedido 
para pagar a atenção a um determinado detalhe no mapa. 
Finalmente o estudante vê um retrato do lugar que/terminou 
acima dentro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'allievo si muove da un posto verso un altro sul 
programma parlante di?a? di Helsinki secondo le date istruzioni 
orali. Il programma sulle marche dello schermo rileva se il 
doesn?t dell'allievo funziona correttamente. L'operazione sta 
usando un micro mondo semplice nell'insegnamento delle lingue. 
L'allievo è supposto di diventare un turista e di muoversi sul 
programma secondo le date istruzioni. (per esempio?Walk dal 
porto al quadrato del mercato per comprare un certo gelato?, 
?Show me dove il museo dell'arte contemporanea Kiasma è?.) 
Le istruzioni sono sviluppate su una storia apparentemente 
sincera. L'allievo indica che i posti scattandosi su loro sul 
programma e se il posto è individuato correttamente l'itinerario 
compariranno sul programma. Ora ed allora le viste egualmente 
sono ammirate perché scattandosi su determinate viste una foto del 
posto è indicata sullo schermo. Ogni scatto errato sarà 
seguito da un commento parlato. Questo modo da casuale scattando
il programma l'allievo è egualmente predisposed al linguaggio 
parlato. Poiché l'allievo ottiene sempre le informazioni sul 
posto dopo scattarsi, i sensi sembrano ragionevoli. Per esempio,
se /she va la stazione ferroviaria e le camminate nelle risposte 
istanti di senso errato è data e lui/lei è chiesta di prestare 
l'attenzione ad un determinato particolare sul programma. Infine
l'allievo vede un'immagine del posto che lui/lei ha concluso in su 
dentro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο σπουδαστής κινείται από μια θέση προς άλλη στο 
χάρτη ομιλίας ?a; από το Ελσίνκι σύμφωνα με τις 
δεδομένες προφορικές οδηγίες. Ο χάρτης στην οθόνη κάνει 
τις παρατηρήσεις εάν ο σπουδαστής doesn?t εργάζεται σωστά. 
Η στοιχειώδης εργασία χρησιμοποιεί έναν απλό κόσμο 
μικροϋπολογιστών στη διδασκαλία γλωσσών. Ο σπουδαστής 
είναι υποτιθέμενος για να γίνει τουρίστας και να κινηθεί στο 
χάρτη σύμφωνα με τις δεδομένες οδηγίες. (Παραδείγματος 
χάριν ?Walk από το λιμάνι στο τετράγωνο αγοράς για να 
αγοράσει κάποιο παγωτό;, ?Show εγώ όπου το μουσείο της
σύγχρονης τέχνης Kiasma είναι;.) Οι οδηγίες χτίζονται 
επάνω σε μια προφανώς ειλικρινή ιστορία. Ο σπουδαστής 
δείχνει τις θέσεις με τον κρότο σε τους στο χάρτη και εάν η θέση
βρίσκεται σωστά η διαδρομή θα εμφανιστεί στο χάρτη. Τώρα 
και έπειτα οι θέες θαυμάζονται επίσης επειδή με τον κρότο σε 
ορισμένες θέες μια φωτογραφία της θέσης εμφανίζεται στην οθόνη. 
Κάθε λανθασμένο στιγμιαίο πάτημα θα ακολουθηθεί από ένα 
προφορικό σχόλιο. Αυτός ο τρόπος από τυχαίο χτυπώντας το 
χάρτη ο σπουδαστής είναι επίσης προδιαθεμένος στην προφορική 
γλώσσα. Επειδή ο σπουδαστής παίρνει πάντα τις πληροφορίες 
για τη θέση μετά από τον κρότο, οι κατευθύνσεις φαίνονται 
λογικές. Παραδείγματος χάριν, εάν αφήνει το σιδηροδρομικό 
σταθμό και περπατά στη λανθασμένη κατεύθυνση που η στιγμιαία 
ανατροφοδότηση δίνεται και καλείται να δώσει προσοχή σε μια 
ορισμένη λεπτομέρεια στο χάρτη. Τελικά ο σπουδαστής 
βλέπει μια εικόνα της θέσης στην οποία έχει καταλήξει.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿El estudiante se mueve a partir de un lugar a 
otro en correspondencia de discurso del?a? de Helsinki según 
las instrucciones orales dadas. La correspondencia en las marcas
de la pantalla comenta si el doesn?t del estudiante trabaja 
correctamente. La tarea está utilizando un mundo micro simple 
en la instrucción de lenguas. Suponen al estudiante hacer un 
turista y moverse en la correspondencia según las instrucciones 
dadas. (por ejemplo?Walk del puerto al cuadrado del mercado para
comprar un poco de helado?, ?Show yo donde está el museo del 
arte contemporáneo Kiasma?.) Las instrucciones se construyen 
sobre una historia al parecer veraz. El estudiante indica que 
los lugares haciendo clic en ellas en la correspondencia y si el lugar
se localiza correctamente la ruta aparecerán en la correspondencia. 
Ahora y después las vistas también se admiran porque haciendo 
clic en ciertas vistas una foto del lugar es mostrada en la pantalla. 
Cada tecleo incorrecto será seguido por un comentario hablado. 
Esta manera por al azar haciendo clic la correspondencia el 
estudiante está también predispuesta al lenguaje hablado. 
Porque el estudiante consigue siempre la información sobre el 
lugar después de hacer clic, las direcciones se parecen sensibles. 
Por ejemplo, si él /she se va el ferrocarril y las caminatas en
el feedback inmediato de la dirección incorrecta se da y le/le piden 
prestar la atención a cierto detalle en la correspondencia. 
Finalmente el estudiante ve un cuadro del lugar que él/ella ha 
terminado para arriba adentro.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>1539</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2003-12-29</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-12</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-12</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>fi</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>guide</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">10-15</string>
            <string language="fi">10-15</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Englannin kielen kuullunymmärtäminen ja tien neuvomiseen liittyvät ilmaisut</string>
            <string language="en">Listening comprehension and phrases connected with giving directions in English</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">englannin kieli</string>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>710</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">kielten opetus</string>
                <string language="en">language teaching</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">kielet</string>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>718</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">oppiminen</string>
                <string language="en">learning</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82552</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://db3.oph.fi/celebrate/ln/helsinki/CO1_9.exe</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
