<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82407</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82407</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>3813</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="fi">Silittämisen salat</string>
            <string language="en">The Secrets of Ironing</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Geheimnisse des Bügelns</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les secrets de repasser</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os segredos de ironing</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I segreti di rivestire di ferro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα μυστικά του σιδερώματος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los secretos de planchar</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Opiskelijat erilaisissa ammatillisissa oppilaitoksissa tarvitsevat silittämisen taitoa esim. huolehtiessaan asiakkaiden vaatteista, valmistaessaan vaatteita jne. Myös ravitsemusalan yrityksissä tarvitaan silitettyjä tekstiilejä.

Silittämisen taito ja merkitys on siis tärkeä opettaa jokaiselle opiskelijalle, koska silitetty tekstiili on miellyttävä käyttää ja näyttää huolitellulta. 
Silittämisen verkkomoduuli on tarkoitettu ensisijaisesti toisen asteen ammatillisille opiskelijoille, mutta sitä voidaan käyttää myös muissa oppilaitoksissa, esimerkiksi peruskouluissa tekstiilityön ja kotitalouden opiskelussa. Moduuli soveltuu myös oppisopimusopiskelijoiden oppimateriaaliksi ja opitun kertaamiseen. Opiskelijoiden ikärakenne eri kursseilla voi olla suuri, 15 vuodesta ylöspäin.</string>
            <string language="en">The students in different vocational schools need to know how to iron when taking care of the clients’ clothes or when manufacturing them etc. Ironed clothes are also needed in the catering trade. It is important to learn every student ironing and its meaning because a garment that has been ironed is comfortable to wear and looks neat. The net module on ironing is primarily intended for upper-secondary level vocational students but it can also be used in other teaching establishment, for example, in textile handicrafts and home economics in upper secondary schools. The module can also be used in apprenticeship training and as revision material. The module is intended for students of the age 15-&gt;.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="fi">house keeping</string>
            <string language="en">house keeping</string>
          </keyword>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>collection</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Kursteilnehmer in den unterschiedlichen 
beruflichen Schulen müssen können bügeln, wenn sie um den Klienten 
kümmern? Kleidung oder wenn hergestellt werden, sie usw.. 
Gebügelte Kleidung wird auch im Hotel- und Gaststättengewerbe 
benötigt. Es ist wichtig, jedes Kursteilnehmerbügeln und seine
Bedeutung zu erlernen, weil ein Kleid, das gebügelt worden ist, 
bequem ist zu tragen und schaut ordentlich. Das Nettomodul auf 
dem Bügeln ist hauptsächlich für waagerecht ausgerichtete 
berufliche obersekundarkursteilnehmer bestimmt, aber es kann in 
anderer unterrichtender Einrichtung z.B. in den Textilhandwerken und 
in der Hauswirtschaft in den obersekundarschulen auch benutzt werden. 
Das Modul kann im Lehretraining und als Änderungmaterial auch 
benutzt werden. Das Modul ist für Kursteilnehmer des Alters 15 
- &gt;. bestimmt</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les étudiants dans différentes écoles 
professionnelles doivent savoir repasser en prenant soin des clients ?
vêtements ou en fabriquant eux etc... Des vêtements 
repassés sont nécessaires également dans le commerce de 
restauration. Il est important d'apprendre chaque repasser 
d'étudiant et sa signification parce qu'un vêtement qui a été 
repassé est confortable pour porter et semble ordonné. Le 
module net sur repasser est principalement destiné pour les 
étudiants professionnels de niveau secondaires deuxième cycle mais 
il peut également être utilisé dans l'autre établissement 
d'enseignement, par exemple, dans des travaux manuels de textile et 
l'économie ménagère dans les écoles secondaires deuxième cycle. 
Le module peut également être utilisé dans la formation 
d'apprentissage et comme matériel de révision. Le module est 
destiné pour des étudiants de l'âge 15 - &gt;.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os estudantes em escolas vocacionais diferentes 
necessitam saber iron ao tomar cuidado dos clientes? roupa ou ao
manufaturá-los etc.. A roupa ironed é necessitada também no 
comércio de catering. É importante aprender cada ironing do 
estudante e seu meaning porque um garment que ironed é confortável 
desgastar e olha puro. O módulo líquido em ironing é 
pretendido primeiramente para estudantes vocacionais nivelados 
upper-secondary mas pode também ser usado no outro estabelecimento 
ensinando, para o exemplo, em handicrafts de textile e na economia 
home em escolas secundárias superiores. O módulo pode também 
ser usado no treinamento do apprenticeship e como o material da 
revisão. O módulo é pretendido para estudantes da idade 15 - 
&gt;.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli allievi in scuole professionali differenti 
devono sapere rivestire di ferro quando prende la cura dei clienti? 
vestiti o quando lo producono ecc. I vestiti rivestiti di 
ferro egualmente sono necessari nel commercio di approvvigionamento. 
È importante imparare ogni rivestire di ferro dell'allievo ed 
il relativo significato perché un indumento che è stato rivestito di
ferro sta bene portare e sembra accurato. Il modulo netto sul 
rivestire di ferro soprattutto è inteso per gli allievi professionali
livellati superiori-secondarii ma può anche essere usato nell'altra 
istituzione d'istruzione, per esempio, negli artigianato della tessile
e nell'economia domestica in scuole superiori-secondarie. Il 
modulo può anche essere utilizzato nell'addestramento di 
apprendistato e come materiale di revisione. Il modulo è inteso
per gli allievi dell'età 15 - &gt;.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι τη σπουδαστές στις διαφορετικές επαγγελματικές 
σχολές πρέπει να ξέρουν πώς να σιδερώσουν κατά φροντίδα των 
χρηστών; τα ενδύματα ή κατά την κατασκευή τους σιδερωμένα 
κ.λπ. ενδύματα απαιτούνται επίσης στο εμπόριο τομέα εστιάσεως. 
Είναι σημαντικό να μαθευτεί κάθε σιδέρωμα σπουδαστών και η
έννοιά του επειδή ένα ένδυμα που έχει σιδερωθεί είναι άνετο 
για να φορέσει και φαίνεται τακτοποιημένο. Η καθαρή ενότητα
στο σιδέρωμα προορίζεται πρώτιστα για τους upper-secondary 
επαγγελματικούς σπουδαστές επιπέδων αλλά μπορεί επίσης να 
χρησιμοποιηθεί σε άλλη καθιέρωση διδασκαλίας, παραδείγματος 
χάριν, στις υφαντικά βιοτεχνίες και τα βασικά οικονομικά στην 
ανώτερη δευτεροβάθμια εκπαίδευση. Η ενότητα μπορεί επίσης 
να χρησιμοποιηθεί στην κατάρτιση μαθητείας και ως υλικό 
αναθεώρησης. Η ενότητα προορίζεται για τους σπουδαστές της 
ηλικίας 15 - &gt;.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿Los estudiantes en diversas escuelas 
vocacionales necesitan saber planchar al tomar el cuidado de los 
clientes? ropas o al fabricar los etc. Las ropas 
planchadas también se necesitan en el comercio de abastecimiento. 
Es importante aprender cada planchar del estudiante y su 
significado porque una ropa se ha planchado que es cómoda desgastar y
parece aseado. El módulo neto en planchar se piensa sobre todo 
para los estudiantes vocacionales llanos superiores-secundarios pero 
puede también ser utilizado en el otro establecimiento de enseñanza,
por ejemplo, en artesanías del textil y la economía doméstica en 
escuelas superiores-secundarias. El módulo se puede también 
utilizar en el entrenamiento del aprendizaje y como material de la 
revisión. El módulo se piensa para los estudiantes de la edad 
15 - &gt;.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Haushalten</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">garder de maison</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">manter-se da casa</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">mantenere della casa</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">κράτηση σπιτιών</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">el guardar de la casa</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>3813</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-02-12</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-11</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-11</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>fi</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>vocational education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">9-15</string>
            <string language="fi">9-15</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>225</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">vaatetus</string>
                <string language="en">clothing</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82407</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>audio/wav</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/silitys/</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
