<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82942</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82942</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>4313</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Word stress and meaning</string>
            <string language="sv"> Word stress and meaning</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wortdruck und -bedeutung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Effort et signification de mot</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Stress e meaning da palavra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sforzo e significato di parola</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πίεση και σημασία λέξης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Tensión y significado de la palabra</string>
          </title>
          <language>sv</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This learning object makes it possible to practise a part of the language that is important for the understanding, but that is difficult to work on with traditional methods. The idea of the exercise is to teach the student to take notice of the prosody of a sentence. The way a sentence is said has, of course, sometimes a big impact on its meaning. During the exercise, the student sees four or five sections/speech bubbles in two columns. By clicking the sections the student hears a sentence. The sentences in the left column all contain the same words but the accentuation varies. The student's task is to move the sections beside each other so that the section in left column gets a logical reaction in the section to the right. When the student clicks the button 'Control', the correct sentences are shown and the student hears them spoken. The point counter shows the student's results.


</string>
            <string language="sv">Detta lärobjekt gör det möjligt att öva ett delområde i språket som är viktigt för förståelsen, men som är svårt att öva med traditionella metoder. Meningen är att lära eleven lägga märke till satsens prosodi. Sättet på vilket en mening sägs har ju ibland en stor skillnad för betydelsen. 

Under uppgiften ser eleven fyra eller fem balkar/pratbubblor i två spalter. Genom att klicka på balkarna hör eleven en replik. Replikerna i den vänstra spalten innehåller alla samma ord men betoningen varierar. Elevens uppgift är att flytta balkarna bredvid varandra så att balken i vänster spalt får en logisk reaktion i balken till höger. När man klickar på knappen ’Kontrollera’ syns de rätta meningarna och eleven hör dem läsas upp. Poängräknaren visar elevens resultat.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese erlernennachricht macht es möglich, ein 
Teil der Sprache zu üben, die für das Verständnis wichtig ist, aber
die schwierig, mit traditionellen Methoden an zu arbeiten ist. 
Die Idee der Übung ist, den Kursteilnehmer zu unterrichten, 
Begriff vom prosody eines Programmsatzes zu nehmen. Die Methode,
die ein Programmsatz besagt ist, hat selbstverständlich manchmal eine
grosse Auswirkung auf seine Bedeutung. Während der Übung sieht
der Kursteilnehmer vier oder fünf sections/speech Luftblasen in zwei 
Spalten. Indem er die Kapitel anklickt, hört der Kursteilnehmer
einen Programmsatz. Alle Programmsätze in der linken Spalte 
enthalten die gleichen Wörter, aber die Betonung verändert sich. 
Die Aufgabe des Kursteilnehmers ist, die Kapitel neben einander 
zu verschieben, damit das Kapitel in der linken Spalte eine logische 
Reaktion im Kapitel an das Recht gelangt. Wenn der 
Kursteilnehmer die Taste ' Steuerung ' anklickt, werden die korrekten 
Programmsätze gezeigt und der Kursteilnehmer hört sie gesprochen. 
Der Punktkostenzähler zeigt die Resultate des Kursteilnehmers.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cet objet d'étude permet pour pratiquer une 
partie du langage qui est important pour l'arrangement, mais qui il 
est difficile travailler en fonction avec des méthodes 
traditionnelles. L'idée de l'exercice est d'enseigner 
l'étudiant à prendre la notification de la prosodie d'une phrase.
La voie que une phrase est dite a, naturellement, parfois un 
grand impact sur sa signification. Pendant l'exercice, 
l'étudiant voit quatre ou cinq bulles de sections/speech dans deux 
colonnes. En cliquant les sections l'étudiant entend 
une phrase. Toutes les phrases dans la colonne gauche 
contiennent les mêmes mots mais l'accentuation change. 
L'étudiant chargent doit déplacer les sections près 
de l'un l'autre de sorte que la section dans la colonne gauche 
obtienne une réaction logique dans la section vers la droite. 
Quand l'étudiant clique le bouton 'commande ', les 
phrases correctes sont montrées et l'étudiant les entend parlées. 
Le compteur de point montre les résultats de l'étudiant.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este objeto de aprendizagem faz possível 
praticar uma parte da língua que são importante para a compreensão,
mas que é difícil de trabalhar sobre com métodos tradicionais. 
A idéia do exercício é ensinar o estudante fazer exame da 
observação do prosody de uma sentença. A maneira que uma 
sentença é dita tem, naturalmente, às vezes um impacto grande em 
seu meaning. Durante o exercício, o estudante vê quatro ou 
cinco bolhas de sections/speech em duas colunas. Estalando as 
seções o estudante ouve uma sentença. Todas as sentenças na 
coluna esquerda contêm as mesmas palavras mas o accentuation varia. 
A tarefa do estudante é mover as seções ao lado de se de modo
que a seção na coluna esquerda comece uma reação lógica na 
seção à direita. Quando o estudante estala a tecla ' controle
', as sentenças corretas estão mostradas e o estudante ouve-as 
faladas. O contador do ponto mostra os resultados do estudante.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo oggetto imparante permette di esercitarsi 
in una parte del linguaggio che è importante per la comprensione, ma 
che è difficile da funzionare sopra con i metodi tradizionali. 
L'idea dell'esercitazione è insegnare l'allievo prendere 
l'avviso del prosody di una frase. Il modo che una frase è 
detta ha, naturalmente, a volte un effetto grande sul relativo 
significato. Durante l'esercitazione, l'allievo vede quattro o 
cinque bolle di sections/speech in due colonne. Scattando le 
sezioni l'allievo sente una frase. Le frasi nella colonna di 
sinistra tutte contengono le stesse parole ma l'accentuazione varia. 
L'operazione dell'allievo è di spostargli le sezioni in modo 
che la sezione in colonna di sinistra ottenga una reazione logica 
nella sezione alla destra. Quando l'allievo scatta il tasto 
'controllo ', le frasi corrette sono indicate e l'allievo le sente 
parlate. Il contatore del punto mostra i risultati dell'allievo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το αντικείμενο εκμάθησης το καθιστά πιθανό να 
ασκήσει ένα μέρος της γλώσσας που είναι σημαντική για την 
κατανόηση, αλλά που είναι δύσκολο να εργαστεί με τις 
παραδοσιακές μεθόδους. Η ιδέα της άσκησης είναι να 
διδαχθεί ο σπουδαστής για να πάρει την ειδοποίηση της προσωδίας 
μιας πρότασης. Ο τρόπος μια πρόταση λέγεται ότι ασκεί, 
φυσικά, μερικές φορές μεγάλη επίδραση στην έννοιά του. 
Κατά τη διάρκεια της άσκησης, ο σπουδαστής βλέπει 
τις φυσαλίδες τεσσάρων ή πέντε τμημάτων/ομιλία σε δύο στήλες. 
Με τον κρότο των τμημάτων ο σπουδαστής ακούει μια πρόταση. 
Οι προτάσεις στην αριστερή στήλη όλες περιέχουν τις ίδιες 
λέξεις αλλά ο τονισμός ποικίλλει. Η στοιχειώδης εργασία 
του σπουδαστή είναι να κινήσει τα τμήματα ο ένας εκτός από τον 
άλλον έτσι ώστε το τμήμα στην αριστερή στήλη παίρνει μια 
λογική αντίδραση στο τμήμα στο δικαίωμα. Όταν ο σπουδαστής
χτυπά το κουμπί "έλεγχοσ", οι σωστές προτάσεις εμφανίζονται και 
ο σπουδαστής τους ακούει προφορικούς. Ο μετρητής σημείου 
εμφανίζει αποτελέσματα του σπουδαστή.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este objeto que aprende permite practicar una parte
del lenguaje que es importante para la comprensión, pero que es 
difícil de trabajar encendido con métodos tradicionales. La 
idea del ejercicio es enseñar al estudiante a tomar el aviso del 
prosody de una sentencia. La manera que una sentencia es dicha 
tiene, por supuesto, a veces un impacto grande en su significado. 
Durante el ejercicio, el estudiante ve cuatro o cinco burbujas 
de sections/speech en dos columnas. Haciendo clic las secciones 
el estudiante oye una sentencia. Las sentencias en la columna 
izquierda todas contienen las mismas palabras pero la acentuación 
varía. La tarea del estudiante es mover las secciones al lado 
de uno a de modo que la sección en columna izquierda consiga una 
reacción lógica en la sección a la derecha. Cuando el 
estudiante hace clic el botón ' control ', se muestran las sentencias
correctas y el estudiante las oye habladas. El contador de la 
punta muestra los resultados del estudiante.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>4313</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-02-26</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-30</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-30</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>sv</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>continuing education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">10-15</string>
            <string language="sv">10-15</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="en">To understand the interaction between accentuation and meaning in English.</string>
            <string language="sv">Att förstå samspelet mellan betoning och betydelse i engelskan.</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>712</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">Latin</string>
                <string language="sv">latin</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
                <string language="sv">engelska språket</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82942</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>audio/basic</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/sve/engelska/word_stress_and_meaning/co1_2.exe</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
