<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82432</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82432</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>1701</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="it">Grammatica Audio</string>
            <string language="en">AudioGrammar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">AudioGrammar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">AudioGrammar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">AudioGrammar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">AudioGrammar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">AudioGrammar</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="it">L'oggetto di apprendimento dimostra come gli allievi possono imparare a scegliere le strutture grammaticali ascoltando la lingua oggetto di studio. Inoltre mostra come la nuova tecnologia può aumentare l'istruzione della grammatica tradizionale. Il compito dell'allievo è di costruire la tabella della struttura grammaticale basata su ciò che sente. Il materiale utilizzato è una serie di domande riguardanti ciò che la gente gradisce. Invece di vedere le frasi complete, il discente può vedere una tabella incompleta e 6-8 teste comunicanti. Cliccando su una testa, l'allievo sente una domanda che si inserisce soltanto in una linea nella tabella. Il testo nei campi della tabella cambia quando i campi sono cliccati. Il discente deve costruire le frasi che ha sentito. Cliccando sul tasto di controllo, il programma verificherà che l'esercitazione è stata svolta correttamente. Le frasi corrette saranno lette ad alta voce e compariranno sullo schermo.</string>
            <string language="en">The learning object demonstrates how students can learn to pick up grammatical structures by listening to the target language.  It also shows how new technology can enhance traditional grammar instruction.
The learner’s task is to build the grammar structure table based on what he/she hears.  The material used is a series of questions asking what people like.  Instead of seeing the completed sentences, the learner can see an incomplete table and 6-8 talking heads.  By clicking on a head, the student hears a question which only fits into one line in the table.  The text in the fields of the table changes when the fields are clicked on.  The learner has to construct the sentences he/she has heard.  By clicking on the Check button, the program will verify that the exercise is done correctly.  The correct sentences will be read aloud and will appear on the screen.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die erlernennachricht zeigt, wie Kursteilnehmer 
erlernen können, grammatische Strukturen aufzuheben, indem sie zur 
Zielsprache hören. Sie zeigt auch, wie neue Technologie 
traditionelle Grammatik instruction.The learner?s erhöhen kann, die 
Aufgabe, die Grammatikstrukturtabelle aufzubauen ist, die basiert auf,
was he/she hört. Das benutzte Material ist eine Reihe Fragen 
des Bittens, welche Leute mögen. Anstatt, die abgeschlossenen 
Programmsätze zu sehen, kann der Anfänger eine unvollständige 
Tabelle und 6-8 sprechenköpfe sehen. Indem er auf einem Kopf 
klickt, hört der Kursteilnehmer eine Frage, die nur in eine Zeile in 
der Tabelle paßt. Der Text in fängt von den Tabelle 
Änderungen auf, wenn werden geklickt an auffängt. Der
Anfänger muß die Programmsätze konstruieren, die he/she gehört 
hat. Indem es auf der Überprüfung Taste klickt, überprüft 
das Programm, daß die Übung richtig erfolgt ist. Die korrekten
Programmsätze werden laut gelesen und erscheinen auf dem Bildschirm.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'objet d'étude démontre comment les étudiants 
peuvent apprendre à prendre les structures grammaticales en écoutant
la langue cible. Il montre également comment la nouvelle 
technologie peut mettre en valeur les learner?s traditionnels de la 
grammaire instruction.The chargent doit construire la table de 
structure de grammaire basée sur ce que he/she entend. La 
matière employée est une série de demander de questions quelles 
personnes aiment. Au lieu de voir les phrases réalisées, 
l'étudiant peut voir une table inachevée et 6-8 chefs parlants. 
En cliquant sur une tête, l'étudiant entend une 
question qui s'adapte seulement dans une ligne dans la table. Le
texte dans les domaines de la table change quand les zones sont 
cliquées en fonction. L'étudiant doit construire les 
phrases que he/she a entendues. En cliquant sur le 
bouton de contrôle, le programme vérifiera que l'exercice est fait 
correctement. Les phrases correctes seront lues à haute voix et
apparaîtront sur l'écran.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O objeto de aprendizagem demonstra como os 
estudantes podem aprender escolher acima estruturas gramaticais 
escutando a língua de alvo. Mostra também como a tecnologia 
nova pode realçar learner?s que tradicionais da gramática 
instruction.The a tarefa é construir a tabela da estrutura da 
gramática baseada em o que he/she se ouve. O material usado é 
uma série de pedir das perguntas que povos gostam. Em vez de 
ver as sentenças terminadas, o learner pode ver uma tabela incompleta
e 6-8 cabeças falando. Estalando em uma cabeça, o estudante 
ouve uma pergunta que caiba somente em uma linha na tabela. O 
texto nos campos da tabela muda quando os campos são estalados sobre.
O learner tem que construir as sentenças que he/she se ouviu. 
Estalando na tecla da verificação, o programa verificará que 
o exercício está feito corretamente. As sentenças corretas 
serão lidas alto e aparecidas na tela.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το αντικείμενο εκμάθησης καταδεικνύει πώς οι 
σπουδαστές μπορούν να μάθουν να παίρνουν τις γραμματικές δομές 
με το άκουσμα στη γλώσσα στόχο. Επιδεικνύει επίσης πώς η 
νέα τεχνολογία μπορεί να ενισχύσει την παραδοσιακή οδηγία 
γραμματικής Η στοιχειώδης εργασία learner?s είναι να 
χτιστεί ο πίνακας δομών γραμματικής βασισμένος σε αυτό που 
ακούει. Το υλικό χρησιμοποιούμενο είναι μια σειρά 
ερωτήσεων ρωτώντας ποιοι άνθρωποι συμπαθούν. Αντί να 
δει τις ολοκληρωμένες προτάσεις, ο αρχάριος μπορεί να 
δει ελλιπή πίνακα και 6-8 ομιλούντα κεφάλια. 
Με τον κρότο σε ένα κεφάλι, ο σπουδαστής ακούει μια 
ερώτηση που αρμόζει μόνο σε μια γραμμή στον πίνακα. Το 
κείμενο στα πεδία του πίνακα αλλάζει όταν χτυπιούνται επάνω τα 
πεδία. Ο αρχάριος πρέπει να κατασκευάσει τις προτάσεις που 
έχει ακούσει. Με τον κρότο στο κουμπί ελέγχου, το 
πρόγραμμα θα ελέγξει ότι η άσκηση γίνεται σωστά. Οι 
σωστές προτάσεις θα διαβαστούν μεγαλοφώνως και θα εμφανιστούν 
στην οθόνη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El objeto que aprende demuestra cómo los 
estudiantes pueden aprender tomar las estructuras gramaticales 
escuchando la lengua objetivo. También muestra cómo la nueva 
tecnología puede realzar learner?s tradicionales de la gramática 
instruction.The que la tarea es construir el vector de la estructura 
de la gramática basado en lo que oye he/she. El material usado 
es una serie de pedir de las preguntas qué gente tiene gusto. 
En vez de ver las sentencias terminadas, el principiante puede 
ver a un vector incompleto y a 6-8 pistas que hablan. Haciendo 
clic en una pista, el estudiante oye una pregunta que quepa solamente 
en una línea en el vector. El texto en los campos del vector 
cambia cuando los campos se hacen clic encendido. El 
principiante tiene que construir las sentencias que he/she ha oído. 
Haciendo clic en el botón del cheque, el programa verificará 
que el ejercicio está hecho correctamente. Las sentencias 
correctas serán leídas en voz alta y aparecerán en la pantalla.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>1701</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-01-21</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-19</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-19</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-19</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-19</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-19</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-19</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-19</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-19</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">9-13</string>
            <string language="en">9-13</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="it">Strutture grammaticali di base e esercitazione in inglese pratica dell' ordine delle parole</string>
            <string language="en">Basic grammatical structures and word order practice in English</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>710</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">language teaching</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82432</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>audio/basic</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://resources.eun.org/demoportal/audio_grammar_eng.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
