<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103830</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103830</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087115</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Throwing His Hat in the Ring: Henry George Runs for Mayor</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Werfen seines Hutes im Ring: Henry George 
Durchläufe für Bürgermeister</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Lancement de son chapeau dans la boucle : 
Passages de George d'Henry pour le maire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogando seu chapéu no anel: Funcionamentos
de George do Henry para o mayor</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gettare il suo cappello nell'anello: 
Funzionamenti di George di henry per il sindaco</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ρίψη του καπέλου του στο δαχτυλίδι: Θ*Χενρυ 
George Runs για το δήμαρχο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Lanzar su sombrero en el anillo: 
Funcionamientos de George del Henrio para el alcalde</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Henry George's 1886 mayoral campaign generated tremendous enthusiasm among New York City's working people, particularly trade union members. George, author of the 1879 book  Progress and Poverty , considered private land ownership to be the cause of inequality and advocated a "single tax" to remedy it. Although George campaigned for less than a month, he spoke more than one hundred times, sometimes addressing five or more labor unions and church groups in a single evening. His acceptance speech for the nomination of the United Labor Party, delivered at Cooper Union on October 5, 1886, conveyed George's identification with organized labor and his desire to channel the ground swell of working-class activism of the mid-1880s toward electoral politics. Some sense of George's rapport with his working-class supporters can be glimpsed in the audience reactions of "laughter" and "vociferous cheers" that a reporter for the New York  World  recorded in this account of George's acceptance speech.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Henry Georges 1886 bürgermeisterliche Kampagne 
festgelegte enorme Begeisterung unter Leuten Funktion der New York 
Stadt, besonders Gewerkschaftbauteile. George, Autor des der 
1879 Buch Fortschritts und Armut, betrachtete privaten Landbesitz, die
Ursache der Verschiedenheit zu sein und befürwortete eine "einzelne 
Steuer", um sie zu beheben. Obgleich George für kleiner als ein
Monat warb, sprach er mehr als hundertmal und manchmal adressierte 
fünf oder mehr Arbeiterverbände und Kirchegruppen in einem einzelnen
Abend. Seine Abnahmerede für die Nennung der vereinigten 
ArbeitsPartei, geliefert am Faßbinder-Anschluß an Oktober 5,
1886, Kennzeichen übermittelten Georges mit organisierter Arbeit und 
sein Wunsch, das Grundschwellen von Arbeiterklasseaktivismus des 
mid-1880s in Richtung zu den Wahlpolitiken zu lenken. Etwas 
Richtung von Bericht Georges mit seinen 
Arbeiterklasseverfechtern kann in den Publikum Reaktionen "des 
Gelächters" und "des vociferous Beifalls" flüchtig gesehen werden, 
die ein Reporter für die New York Welt in diesem Konto der 
Abnahmerede Georges speicherte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'enthousiasme énorme produit par campagne du 
maire de George 1886 d'Henry parmi des personnes du fonctionnement
de la ville de New York, en particulier membres de syndicat. 
George, auteur du progrès et de la pauvreté de 1879 
livres, a considéré comme étant la propriété terrienne privée la
cause de l'inégalité et a préconisé "un taxe unique" pour 
remédier à de lui. Bien que George ait fait campagne pour
moins qu'un mois, il a parlé plus de cent fois, parfois adressant 
cinq syndicats ou plus et groupes d'église en seule soirée. 
Son discours d'acceptation pour la nomination du parti 
travailliste uni, fournie à l'union de tonnelier 5 octobre 1886, à 
l'identification de George transporté avec le travail organisé 
et à son désir de creuser des rigoles la bosse moulue de l'activisme
de classe ouvrière du mid-1880s vers la politique électorale. 
Un certain sens du rapport de George avec ses 
défenseurs de classe ouvrière peut être aperçu dans les réactions
d'assistances du "rire" et "des acclamations bruyantes" qu'un 
journaliste pour le monde de New York a enregistrées dans ce compte 
de la parole de l'acceptation de George.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Entusiasmo tremendo gerado de George 1886 do 
Henry campanha mayoral entre povos do funcionamento da cidade de New 
York, particularmente membros de união de comércio. George, 
autor do progresso e de uma pobreza de 1879 livros, considerou a posse
de terra confidencial ser a causa do desigualdade e advogou um "único
imposto" para remediá-lo. Embora George fizesse campanha para 
menos do que um mês, falou mais de cem vezes, às vezes dirigindo-se 
a cinco ou mais uniões labor e grupos da igreja em uma única noite. 
Seu discurso da aceitação para o nomination do partido labor 
unido, entregado na união do cooper em outubro 5, 1886, 
identificação de George feito saber com trabalho organizado e seu 
desejo canalizar o inchamento à terra do activism do working-class do
mid-1880s para a política electoral. Algum sentido do rapport 
de George com seus supporters do working-class pode glimpsed nas 
reações das audiências do "laughter" e "dos cheers vociferous" que 
um repórter para o mundo de New York gravou neste cliente do discurso
da aceitação de George.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Entusiasmo tremendo generato campagna mayoral del
George 1886 di henry fra la gente di funzionamento della città de New
York, specialmente membri del sindacato. George, autore del 
progresso e di una povertà dei 1879 libri, ha considerare la 
proprietà terriera riservata come la causa di diseguaglianza ed ha 
sostenuto "una singola tassa" per rimediarlo. Anche se George ha
fatto una campagna per di meno che un mese, ha parlato più di cento 
volte, a volte parlando a cinque o più sindacati di lavoro e gruppi 
della chiesa in una singola sera. Il suo discorso di 
accettazione per la nomina del partito Di lavoro unito, trasportata 
all'unione del cooper ottobre 5, 1886, identificazione del George 
trasportato con il lavoro organizzato ed il suo su desiderio 
scavare canali lo swell a terra di activism della classe operaia del 
mid-1880s verso le politiche elettorali. Un certo senso di 
rapport del George con i suoi sostenitori della classe operaia può 
glimpsed nelle reazioni dei pubblici "del laughter" e "delle 
acclamazioni vociferous" che un reporter per il mondo de New York 
ha registrato in questo cliente di discorso di accettazione del 
George.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Mayoral παραγμένος εκστρατεία τεράστιος 
ενθουσιασμός 1886 Henry George's μεταξύ των εργαζόμενων 
ανθρώπων της πόλης της Νέας Υόρκης, ιδιαίτερα μέλη συνδικάτων. 
Θ*Γεοργε, συντάκτης της προόδου και της ένδειας 1879 
βιβλίων, θεώρησε την ιδιωτική ιδιοκτησία εδάφους η αιτία της 
ανισότητας και υποστήριξε έναν "ενιαίο φόρο" για να την 
θεραπεύσει. Αν και George έκανε εκστρατεία για έναν 
λιγότερο από μήνα, μίλησε περισσότερους του ενός εκατό φορές, 
απευθυμένος μερικές φορές στα πέντε ή περισσότερες εργατικά 
συνδικάτα και ομάδες εκκλησιών ένα ενιαίο βράδυ. Η ομιλία
αποδοχής του για το διορισμό του ενωμένου εργατικού κόμματος, που
παραδόθηκε στην ένωση βαρελοποιών στις 5 Οκτωβρίου ..1886, 
μεταβίβασε τον προσδιορισμό George με την οργανωμένη εργασία 
και η επιθυμία του να διοχετεύσει το έδαφος πρήζεται του 
ακτιβισμού εργατικών τάξεων τα μέσα της 1880s προς την 
εκλογική πολιτική. Κάποια αίσθηση της έκθεσης George με 
τους υποστηρικτές εργατικών τάξεών του μπορεί να είναι στις 
αντιδράσεις ακροατηρίων "του γέλιου" και των "θορυβωδών ευθυμιών"
που ένας δημοσιογράφος για τον κόσμο της Νέας Υόρκης κατέγραψε 
σε αυτόν τον απολογισμό της ομιλίας αποδοχής George.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Entusiasmo generado campaña mayoral de George 
1886 del Henrio enorme entre la gente del funcionamiento de la ciudad 
de Nueva York, determinado miembros del sindicato. George, autor
del progreso y de la pobreza de 1879 libros, consideraba propiedad de 
terreno privada ser la causa de la desigualdad y abogó un "solo 
impuesto" para remediarlo. Aunque George hizo campaña para 
menos que un mes, él habló más de cientos veces, a veces 
dirigiéndose a cinco o más sindicatos y grupos de la iglesia por una
sola tarde. Su discurso de la aceptación para el nombramiento 
del partido laborista unido, entregado en la unión del fabricante de 
vinos de octubre el 5, 1886, identificación de George transportado 
con el trabajo ordenado y su deseo de acanalar la inflamación de 
tierra del activismo de la clase obrera del mid-1880s hacia políticas
electorales. Un cierto sentido de la simpatía de George con sus
partidarios de la clase obrera se puede glimpsed en las reacciones de 
las audiencias de la "risa" y de las "aclamaciones vociferantes" que 
un reportero para el mundo de Nueva York registró en esta cuenta del 
discurso de la aceptación de George.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087115</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103830</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/throwing-his-hat-in-the-ring-henry-george-runs-for-mayor</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
