<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107770</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107770</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206475</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Dinosaurs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dinosauriere</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dinosaurs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Dinosaurs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dinosaurs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δεινόσαυροι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Dinosaurios</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">helps students answer questions about dinosaurs: What makes a dinosaur a dinosaur? Where did they live? What caused their mass extinction? Students can participate in a virtual dinosaur discovery, follow milestones in dinosaur evolution, and see behind-the-scenes slideshows of the lab environment where vertebrate specimens are prepared for exhibits and research.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hilfen Kursteilnehmer-Antwortfragen über 
Dinosauriere: Was bildet einen Dinosaurier einen Dinosaurier? 
Wo lebten sie? Was verursachte ihre Massenlöschung? 
Kursteilnehmer können an einer virtuellen Dinosaurierentdeckung
teilnehmen, Meilensteinen in der Dinosauriergeschichte folgen, und 
Hinter-dszenen Slideshows der Laborumgebung sehen, in der vertebrate 
Probenmaterialien für Ausstellungen und Forschung vorbereitet werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">questions de réponse d'étudiants d'aides au 
sujet des dinosaurs : Que fait à un dinosaur un dinosaur ? 
Où ont-ils habité ? Qu'a causé leur extinction de masse
? Les étudiants peuvent participer à une découverte virtuelle
de dinosaur, suivre des étapes importantes dans l'évolution de 
dinosaur, et voir des présentations de derrière-le-scènes de 
l'environnement de laboratoire où des spécimens vertébrés sont 
disposés pour des objets exposés et la recherche.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">perguntas da resposta dos estudantes das ajudas 
sobre dinosaurs: Que faz a um dinosaur um dinosaur? Onde 
viveram? Que causou sua extinção maciça? Os estudantes 
podem participar em uma descoberta virtual do dinosaur, seguir marcos 
miliários na evolução do dinosaur, e ver slideshows das 
atrás-$$$-CENAS do ambiente do laboratório onde os espécimes 
vertebrate são preparados para exibições e pesquisa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">domande di risposta degli allievi di aiuti circa i
dinosaurs: Che cosa rende ad un dinosaur un dinosaur? Dove
hanno vissuto? Che cosa ha causato la loro estinzione totale? 
Gli allievi possono partecipare ad una scoperta virtuale del 
dinosaur, seguire le pietre nello sviluppo del dinosaur e vedere gli 
slideshows di dietro-$$$-SCENE dell'ambiente del laboratorio in cui 
gli esemplari vertebrati sono preparati per le esposizioni e la 
ricerca.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">βοηθά τις ερωτήσεις απάντησης σπουδαστών για τους 
δεινοσαύρους: Αυτό που κάνει έναν δεινόσαυρο έναν 
δεινόσαυρο; Πού έζησαν; Αυτό που προκάλεσε τη μαζική
εξάλειψή τους; Οι σπουδαστές μπορούν να συμμετέχουν σε μια 
εικονική ανακάλυψη δεινοσαύρων, να ακολουθήσουν τα κύρια σημεία 
στην εξέλιξη δεινοσαύρων, και να δουν τις πίσω 
από-ο-σκηνές slideshows του περιβάλλοντος εργαστηρίων όπου τα 
σπονδυλωτά δείγματα προετοιμάζονται για τα εκθέματα και την 
έρευνα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">preguntas de la respuesta de los estudiantes de 
las ayudas sobre dinosaurios: ¿Qué hace un dinosaurio un 
dinosaurio? ¿Dónde vivieron? ¿Qué causó su extinción 
total? Los estudiantes pueden participar en un descubrimiento 
virtual del dinosaurio, seguir jalones en la evolución del 
dinosaurio, y ver los slideshows de las detra's-$$$-ESCENAS del 
ambiente del laboratorio donde los especímenes vertebrados están 
preparados para los objetos expuestos y la investigación.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206475</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107770</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/dinosaurs</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
