<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105552</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105552</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206137</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Rockets: Educators Guide</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Raketen: Erzieher-Anleitung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Fusées : Guide D'Éducateurs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Foguetes: Guia Dos Educadores</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Razzi: Guida Degli Educatori</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πύραυλοι: Οι εκπαιδευτικοί καθοδηγούν</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cohetes: Guía De los Educadores</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">provides lessons, activities, and information on basic rocket science and rocket history. Lessons include making and flying paper rockets, investigating ways to increase the power of rocket fuels, estimating the altitude a rocket achieves during flight, and demonstrating how rocket liftoff is an application of Newton's Laws of Motion. Emphasis is on hands-on science, prediction, data collection and interpretation, teamwork, and problem solving.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt Lektionen, Aktivitäten und Informationen 
auf grundlegender Rakete Wissenschaft und Rakete Geschichte zur 
Verfügung. Lektionen schließen das Bilden ein und das Fliegen 
Papierder raketen, Methoden nachforschend, die Energie der Rakete 
Kraftstoffe zu erhöhen, die Höhe schätzend eine Rakete erzielt 
während des Fluges und des Demonstrierens, wie Rakete liftoff eine 
Anwendung der Gesetze des Newtons der Bewegung ist. Hauptgewicht
ist auf Blindeinschub Wissenschaft, Vorhersage, Datenerfassung und 
Deutung, Teamwork und Lösen von Problemen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fournit des leçons, des activités, et des 
informations sur la science de fusée et l'histoire de base de fusée.
Les leçons incluent la fabrication et voler des fusées de 
papier, étudiant des voies d'augmenter la puissance des carburants de
fusée, estimant l'altitude une fusée réalise pendant le vol, et 
démontrer comment le liftoff de fusée est une application des lois 
de newton du mouvement. L'emphase est sur la science, 
prévision, collecte et traduction de données, travail d'équipe, et 
résolution des problèmes à commande manuelle.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fornece lições, atividades, e informação na 
ciência do foguete e no history básicos do foguete. As 
lições incluem fazer e voar foguetes de papel, investigando maneiras
aumentar a potência de combustíveis do foguete, estimando a altura 
um foguete consegue durante o vôo, e demonstrar como o liftoff do 
foguete é uma aplicação de leis do newton do movimento. A 
ênfase está na ciência, predição, levantamento de dados e 
interpretação de, teamwork, e resolver de problema hands-on.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fornisce le lezioni, le attività e le 
informazioni sulla scienza del razzo e sulla storia di base del razzo.
Le lezioni includono fare e volare i razzi di carta, studiando i
modi aumentare l'potenza dei combustibili del razzo, valutante 
l'altezza un razzo realizza durante il volo e la dimostrazione come il
liftoff del razzo è un'applicazione delle leggi del Newton di 
movimento. L'enfasi è sulla scienza, previsione, raccolta di 
dati e l'interpretazione, lavoro di squadra e la soluzione dei 
problemi hands-on.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρέχει τα μαθήματα, τις δραστηριότητες, και τις 
πληροφορίες για τη βασικές επιστήμη πυραύλων και την ιστορία 
πυραύλων. Τα μαθήματα περιλαμβάνουν τους κάνοντας και 
πετώντας πυραύλους εγγράφου, ερευνώντας τους τρόπους να αυξηθεί 
η δύναμη των καυσίμων πυραύλων, υπολογίζοντας το ύψος που ένας 
πύραυλος επιτυγχάνει κατά τη διάρκεια της πτήσης, και επίδειξη 
πώς η εκτόξευση πυραύλων είναι μια εφαρμογή των νόμων Newton 
της κίνησης. Η έμφαση είναι στην εμπράγματη επιστήμη, την 
πρόβλεψη, τη συλλογή δεδομένων και την ερμηνεία, την ομαδική 
εργασία, και την επίλυση προβλήματος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">proporciona a lecciones, a actividades, y a la 
información en ciencia del cohete e historia básicas del cohete. 
Las lecciones incluyen la fabricación y volar los cohetes de 
papel, investigando maneras de aumentar la potencia de los 
combustibles del cohete, estimando la altitud un cohete alcanza 
durante vuelo, y demostrar cómo el liftoff del cohete es una 
aplicación de los leyes del neutonio del movimiento. El 
énfasis está en ciencia, predicción, colección e interpretación 
de datos, trabajo en equipo, y el solucionar de problema con manos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206137</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105552</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/rockets-educators-guide</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
