<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103132</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103132</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211647</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Presenting the Geologic Timescale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Darstellen der geologischen 
Synchronisierzeitmarke</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Présentation du calendrier géologique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Apresentando o timescale geologic</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Presentare la scala cronologica geologica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παρουσίαση του γεωλογικού χρονοδιαγράμματος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Presentación del calendario geológico</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This project has students model the geologic timescale using distance as a metaphor for time. Each student writes a summary of a major event or fossil organism. The students then station themselves and their summaries along a path within a gymnasium. Each student's position along the path determines how long ago their organism lived or the event occurred, so students can appreciate the scale of geologic time. On this Starting Point page, users can access information about the exercise's learning goals, context for use, teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment ideas, references and topics covered.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Projekt läßt Kursteilnehmer die 
geologische Synchronisierzeitmarke mit Abstand als Metapher für Zeit 
formen. Jeder Kursteilnehmer schreibt eine Zusammenfassung eines
Hauptfalls oder des Fossilorganismus. Die Kursteilnehmer 
stationieren dann sich und ihre Zusammenfassungen entlang einem Pfad 
innerhalb eines Gymnasiums. Position jedes Kursteilnehmers 
entlang dem Pfad stellt fest, wie vor langer Zeit ihr Organismus 
lebte, oder der Fall auftrat, also können Kursteilnehmer die Skala 
der geologischen Zeit schätzen. Auf dieser Ausgangspunktseite 
können Benutzer auf Informationen über die erlernenziele der Übung,
Kontext für Gebrauch-, die Unterrichtenumfaßten anmerkungen und 
Spitzen, Lehrmittel, Einschätzung Ideen, Referenzen und Themen 
zugreifen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce projet fait modeler à des étudiants le 
calendrier géologique en utilisant la distance comme métaphore pour 
le temps. Chaque étudiant écrit un sommaire d'un événement 
ou d'une organization important de fossile. Les étudiants se 
postent alors et leurs sommaires le long d'une voie d'accès dans un 
gymnase. La position de chaque étudiant le long de la voie 
d'accès détermine combien de temps il y a leur organization a vécu 
ou l'événement s'est produit, ainsi les étudiants peuvent 
apprécier l'échelle du temps géologique. À cette page de 
point de départ, les utilisateurs peuvent accéder aux informations 
sur les buts d'étude de l'exercice, contexte pour les extrémités 
d'utilisation, d'enseignement les notes et, le matériel didactique, 
les idées d'évaluation, les références et les sujets couverts.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este projeto manda estudantes modelar o timescale 
geologic usando a distância como um metaphor por o tempo. Cada 
estudante escreve um sumário de um evento ou de um organismo 
principal do fossil. Os estudantes postam-se então e seus 
sumários ao longo de um trajeto dentro de um gymnasium. A 
posição de cada estudante ao longo do trajeto determina quanto tempo
há seu organismo viveu ou o evento ocorreu, assim que os estudantes 
podem apreciar a escala do tempo geologic. Nesta página do 
ponto começar, os usuários podem alcançar a informação sobre os 
objetivos de aprendizagem do exercício, contexto para as pontas do 
uso, ensinar as notas e, os materiais de ensino, as idéias da 
avaliação, as referências e os tópicos cobertos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo progetto fa modellare agli allievi la scala
cronologica geologica usando la distanza come metafora per il tempo. 
Ogni allievo scrive un sommario di un evento o di un organismo 
importante del fossile. Gli allievi allora si dispongono ed i 
loro sommari lungo un percorso all'interno di una palestra. 
Posizione di ogni allievo lungo il percorso determina quanto 
tempo fa il loro organismo ha vissuto o l'evento ha accaduto, in modo 
da gli allievi possono apprezzare la scala di tempo geologico. A
questa pagina del punto di partenza, gli utenti possono accedere alle 
informazioni sugli obiettivi imparanti dell'esercitazione, contesto 
per le punte di istruzione, di uso note e, i materiali didattici, le 
idee di valutazione, i riferimenti ed i soggetti coperti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το πρόγραμμα έχει τους σπουδαστές να 
διαμορφώσουν το γεωλογικό χρονοδιάγραμμα που χρησιμοποιεί την 
απόσταση ως μεταφορά για το χρόνο. Κάθε σπουδαστής γράφει 
μια περίληψη ενός σημαντικού γεγονότος ή ενός απολιθωμένου 
οργανισμού. Οι σπουδαστές έπειτα σταθμός οι ίδιοι και οι 
περιλήψεις τους κατά μήκος ενός μονοπατιού μέσα σε ένα 
γυμνάσιο. Η θέση κάθε σπουδαστή κατά μήκος του μονοπατιού
καθορίζει πόσο πολύ καιρό πριν ο οργανισμός τους έζησε ή το 
γεγονός εμφανίστηκε, έτσι οι σπουδαστές μπορούν να εκτιμήσουν 
την κλίμακα του γεωλογικού χρόνου. Σε αυτήν την σελίδα 
αφετηρίας, οι χρήστες μπορούν να έχουν πρόσβαση στις πληροφορίες
για τους στόχους εκμάθησης της άσκησης, πλαίσιο για τη χρήση, τις
σημειώσεις και τις άκρες διδασκαλίας, τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, τις 
ιδέες αξιολόγησης, τις αναφορές και τα θέματα που καλύπτονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este proyecto hace que los estudiantes modelen el 
calendario geológico usando distancia como metáfora por tiempo. 
Cada estudiante escribe un resumen de un acontecimiento o de un 
organismo importante del fósil. Los estudiantes entonces se 
colocan y sus resúmenes a lo largo de un camino dentro de un 
gimnasio. La posición de cada estudiante a lo largo del camino 
se determina cuánto tiempo hace su organismo vivió u ocurrió el 
acontecimiento, así que los estudiantes pueden apreciar la escala del
tiempo geológico. En esta paginación del punto de partida, los
utilizadores pueden tener acceso a la información sobre las metas que
aprenden del ejercicio, contexto para las extremidades del uso, de la 
enseñanza las notas y, los materiales didácticos, las ideas del 
gravamen, las referencias y los asuntos cubiertos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:LAURA GUERTIN
FN:LAURA GUERTIN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CATHERINE NGUYEN
FN:CATHERINE NGUYEN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211647</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103132</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/presenting-the-geologic-timescale</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
