<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104269</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104269</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086269</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Am Entitled to Counsel of My Choice": Radical Attorney Robert Treuhaft Challenges HUAC and "McCarthyism"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ich werde zu den Ratschlägen meiner Wahl" 
erlaubt: Radikaler Rechtsanwalt Robert Treuhaft fordert HUAC und
"McCarthyism" heraus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"j'ai droit aux avocats-conseils de mon choix" : 
Le mandataire radical Robert Treuhaft défie HUAC et 
"McCarthyism"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"eu sou intitulado aos conselhos de minha 
escolha": O advogado radical Robert Treuhaft desafia HUAC e 
"McCarthyism"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"sono autorizzato ai consulenti legali della mia 
scelta": L'avvocato radicale Robert Treuhaft sfida HUAC e 
"McCarthyism"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"έχω δικαίωμα για να συμβουλεύσω της επιλογής μου": 
Ριζικός πληρεξούσιος Robert Treuhaft Challenges 
HUAC και "McCarthyism"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"me dan derecho a los consejos de mi opción": 
El abogado radical Roberto Treuhaft desafía HUAC y 
"McCarthyism"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1940, Congress passed the Smith Act making it illegal to support the overthrow of state or national governments. In 1949, 11 Communist Party leaders were convicted under this Act. The attorneys for the accused were themselves convicted of contempt of court and half served prison terms. Subsequently, most lawyers refused to represent suspected Communists unless they themselves were members of the Communist Party. In the following testimony before a House Committee on Un-American Activities (HUAC) hearing investigating Communist activities in the San Francisco area, radical attorney Robert E. Treuhaft (1912-2001) described his unsuccessful attempts to hire respected lawyers--who privately disapproved of HUAC--to represent him. Treuhaft, an Oakland-based lawyer who had represented labor unions and African-Americans deprived of civil rights, had joined the Communist Party in the 1940s. Subsequently, he became the unpaid counsel for the Civil Rights Congress (CRC), a trust fund that supplied bail money for Communists arrested under the Smith Act. The Justice Department included the CRC on their official list of subversive organizations, and following his appearance before HUAC, the Committee listed Treuhaft among the 39 most dangerous subversive lawyers in their pamphlet, "Communist Legal Subversives: The Role of the Communist Lawyer." Jessica Mitford, Treihaft_s wife, wrote in her memoir,  A Fine Old Conflict , that the San Francisco HUAC hearing targeted did serious damage "in destroying livelihoods and muzzling political dissent at the grass-roots level."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1940 führte Kongreß die Smith Tat, die es 
ungültig, den Overthrow des Zustandes oder der Nationalregierungen zu
unterstützen bildet. 1949 wurden 11 kommunistische 
Parteiführer unter dieser Tat überführt. Die 
Rechtsanwälte für beschuldigt wurden selbst der Missachtung des 
Gerichts überführt und Hälfte diente Gefängnisbezeichnungen. 
Nachher lehnten die meisten Rechtsanwälte ab, vermutete 
Kommunisten darzustellen, es sei denn sie selbst Bauteile der 
kommunistischen Partei waren. Im folgenden Zeugnis vor 
einem Haus-Ausschuß für nachforschende kommunistische Aktivitäten 
Un-Amerikanischen Aktivitäten (HUAC) Hörens im San Francisco 
Bereich, beschrieb radikaler Rechtsanwalt Robert E. Treuhaft 
(1912-2001) seine erfolglosen Versuche, respektierte Rechtsanwälte 
anzustellen -- wem privat HUAC mißbilligten -- um ihn darzustellen. 
Treuhaft, ein Oakland-gegründeter Rechtsanwalt, der 
Arbeiterverbände dargestellt hatte und Afrikanisch-Amerikaner 
Zivilrechte beraubten, hatte die kommunistische Partei in den 
vierziger Jahren nachher, er wurde der unbezahlte Ratschlag für den 
Zivilrecht-Kongreß (zyklische Blockprüfung), eine Vertrauen Kapital 
verbunden, die Kaution Geld für die Kommunisten angab, die unter der 
Smith Tat festgehalten wurden. Die Gerechtigkeit-Abteilung 
schloß die zyklische Blockprüfung auf ihrer amtlichen 
Börsennotierung der subversiveen Organisationen und nach seinem 
Aussehen vor HUAC, das Ausschuß ausgedruckte Treuhaft unter den 39 
gefährlichsten subversiveen Rechtsanwälten in ihrer Flugschrift, 
"kommunistisches zugelassenes Subversives ein: Die Rolle des 
kommunistischen Rechtsanwalts." Jessica Mitford, Treihaft_s 
Frau, schrieb in ihre Abhandlung, eine feine alte $überschneidung, 
daß die gezielte San Francisco HUAC Hörfähigkeit tat ernste 
Beschädigung "in zerstörenden Lebensunterhalt und in muzzling 
politischer Meinungsverschiedenheit an den Grass-roots gleich."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1940, le congrès a passé la Loi de Smith le 
rendant illégal pour supporter le renversement de l'état ou des 
gouvernements nationaux. En 1949, 11 amorces de parti communiste
ont été condamnées sous cette Loi. Les mandataires pour 
accusé eux-mêmes ont été condamnés du mépris de la cour et la 
moitié a servi des limites de prison. Ultérieurement, la 
plupart des avocats ont refusé de représenter les communistes 
suspectés à moins qu'ils eux-mêmes aient été des membres du parti
communiste. Dans le témoignage suivant devant un comité de 
Chambre des activités communistes d'investigation d'entendre 
Un-Américain des activités (HUAC) dans la région de San 
Francisco, le mandataire radical Robert E. Treuhaft (1912-2001) a 
décrit ses tentatives non réussies de louer les avocats respectés 
-- qui ont en privé désapprové HUAC -- pour le représenter. 
Treuhaft, un avocat Oakland-basé qui avait représenté les 
syndicats et les Afro-Américains ont privés des droits civiques, avait 
joint le parti communiste dans les années 40 ultérieurement, il est 
devenu l'avocat-conseil impayé pour le congrès de droits civiques 
(CRC), un fonds en fidéicommis qui a fourni l'argent de presseur pour
des communistes arrêtés sous l'acte de Smith. Le service de 
justice a inclus le CRC sur leur liste officielle d'organismes 
subversifs, et après son aspect avant HUAC, le Treuhaft énuméré 
par Comité parmi les 39 avocats subversifs les plus dangereux en leur
brochure, "Subversives légal communiste : Le rôle de l'avocat 
communiste." Jessica Mitford, épouse de Treihaft_s, a écrit 
dans son mémoire, un vieux conflit fin, que l'audition de San 
Francisco HUAC visée a fait des dommages sérieux "dans des vies 
détruisantes et la dissidence politique muselante aux bases de 
niveau."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1940, o congress passou o ato de Smith que faz 
o ilegal para suportar o overthrow do estado ou de governos nacionais.
Em 1949, 11 líderes do partido comunista convicted sob este 
ato. Os advogados para acusado eles mesmos convicted do contempt
de corte e a metade serviu a termos da prisão. 
Subseqüentemente, a maioria de advogados recusaram representar 
comunistas suspeitados a menos que eles mesmos fossem membros do 
partido comunista. No seguinte testimony antes de um comitê da 
casa em atividades comunistas investigando da audição Un-Americana 
das atividades (HUAC) na área do San Francisco, o advogado radical 
Robert E. Treuhaft (1912-2001) descreveu suas tentativas mal sucedidas
de empregar os advogados respeitados -- quem disapproved 
confidencialmente de HUAC -- para representá-lo. Treuhaft, um 
advogado Oakland-baseado que representasse uniões labor e os 
Africano-Americanos privassem de direitas civis, tinha juntado o 
partido comunista nos 1940s. subseqüentemente, ele transformou-se o 
conselho por pagar para o congress das direitas civis (CRC), um fundo 
de confiança que fornecesse o dinheiro do prendedor para os 
comunistas prendidos sob o ato de Smith. O departamento da 
justiça incluiu o CRC em sua lista oficial de organizações 
subversivas, e depois de sua aparência antes de HUAC, o Treuhaft 
alistado comitê entre os 39 advogados subversivos os mais perigosos 
em seu panfleto, "Subversives legal comunista: O papel do 
advogado comunista." Jessica Mitford, esposa de Treihaft_s, 
escreveu em seu memoir, um conflito velho fino, que o hearing do San 
Francisco HUAC alvejado fêz os danos sérios "em meios de 
subsistência destruindo e no dissent político açaimando nos 
grass-roots ao nível."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1940, il congresso ha passato la Legge dello 
Smith che lo rende illegale per sostenere il overthrow di 
dichiara o governi nazionali. In 1949, 11 capo 
del partito comunista è stato condannato a norma di questa legge. 
Gli avvocati per accusato essi stessi sono stati condannati di 
contempt della corte e la metà ha servito i termini della prigione. 
Successivamente, la maggior parte dei avvocati hanno rifiutato 
di rappresentare i comunisti ritenuti sospetto a meno che essi stessi 
fossero membri del partito comunista. Nella seguente 
testimonianza prima di un comitato della Camera delle attività 
comuniste di studio sentirsi ONU-Americano di attività (HUAC) nella 
zona de San Francisco, l'avvocato radicale Robert E. Treuhaft 
(1912-2001) ha descritto i suoi tentativi infruttuosi di assumere gli 
avvocati rispettati -- chi hanno disapprovato privatamente HUAC -- per
rappresentarlo. Treuhaft, un avvocato Oakland-basato che aveva 
rappresentato i sindacati di lavoro e gli Africano-Americani hanno 
privato dei diritti civili, aveva unito il partito comunista nei 
1940s. successivamente, lui si è transformato in nel consulente 
legale non pagato per il congresso di diritti civili (CRC), un fondo 
fiduciario che ha fornito i soldi della barra per i comunisti 
arrestati a norma della legge dello Smith. Il reparto della 
giustizia ha incluso il CRC sulla loro lista ufficiale delle 
organizzazioni sovversive e dopo la sua apparenza prima di HUAC, il 
Treuhaft elencato comitato fra i 39 avvocati sovversivi più 
pericolosi in loro opuscolo, "Subversives legale comunista: Il 
ruolo dell'avvocato comunista." Jessica Mitford, moglie di 
Treihaft_s, ha scritto nella sua memoria, un vecchio conflitto fine, 
che l'udienza de San Francisco HUAC designata ha fatto danni serii 
"nel distruggere le vite e nel mettere la museruola al dissenso 
politico ai grass-roots a livello."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1940, το συνέδριο πέρασε το νόμο Smith που 
καθιστά το παράνομο να υποστηρίξει τη συντριβή του κράτους ή των
εθνικών κυβερνήσεων. Το 1949 ..11 κομμουνιστικοί 
αρχηγοί κόμματος καταδικάστηκαν στο πλαίσιο αυτού του νόμου. 
_ ο πληρεξούσιος για ο κατηγορώ είμαι ο καταδικάζω 
περιφρόνηση δικαστήριο και κατά το ήμισυ εξυπηρετώ φυλακή όρος.
Στη συνέχεια, οι περισσότεροι δικηγόροι αρνήθηκαν να 
αντιπροσωπεύσουν τους πιθανούς κομμουνιστές εκτός αν οι ίδιοι 
ήταν μέλη του Κομμουνιστικού Κόμματος. Στην ακόλουθη 
κατάθεση ενώπιον μιας Επιτροπής σπιτιών των αντιαμερικανικών 
κομμουνιστικών δραστηριοτήτων έρευνας ακοής δραστηριοτήτων 
(HUAC) στην περιοχή του Σαν Φρανσίσκο, ο ριζικός πληρεξούσιος 
Robert E. Treuhaft (1912-2001) περιέγραψε τις 
ανεπιτυχείς προσπάθειές του να μισθώσει τους σεβαστούς 
δικηγόρους -- ποιοι αποδοκίμασαν ιδιαιτέρως HUAC -- για να τον 
αντιπροσωπεύσει. Το Treuhaft, ένας Όουκλαντ-βασισμένος 
στο δικηγόρος που είχε αντιπροσωπεύσει τα εργατικά συνδικάτα και 
αφρικανικός-Αμερικανοί στέρησαν από τα αστικά δικαιώματα, είχε 
προσχωρήσει στο Κομμουνιστικό Κόμμα στη δεκαετία του '40 Στη
συνέχεια, έγινε η απλήρωτη συμβουλή για το συνέδριο αστικών 
δικαιωμάτων (κέντρο ανίχνευσης και ελέγχου), ένα κεφάλαιο 
εμπιστοσύνης που παρείχε τα χρήματα εγγυήσεων για τους 
κομμουνιστές που συλλήφθηκαν στο πλαίσιο του νόμου Smith. 
Το Υπουργείο Δικαιοσύνης περιέλαβε το κέντρο ανίχνευσης και
ελέγχου στον επίσημο κατάλογό τους ανατρεπτικών οργανώσεων, και 
μετά από την εμφάνισή του πριν από HUAC, το εμφανισμένο 
λίστα Επιτροπή Treuhaft μεταξύ των 39 πιό επικίνδυνων 
ανατρεπτικών δικηγόρων στο τεύχος τους, "κομμουνιστικό νομικό 
Subversives: Ο ρόλος του κομμουνιστικού δικηγόρου." 
Το Jessica Mitford, σύζυγος Treihaft_s, έγραψε στα 
απομνημονεύματά της, μια λεπτή παλαιά σύγκρουση, ότι η ακρόαση 
του Σαν Φρανσίσκο HUAC στοχοθετημένη έκανε τη σοβαρή ζημία 
"στην καταστροφή livelihoods και την muzzling πολιτική 
διαφωνία στο επίπεδο σε επίπεδο βάσης."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1940, el congreso pasó el acto de Smith que lo
hacía ilegal utilizar el derrocamiento del estado o de gobiernos 
nacionales. En 1949, condenaron a 11 arranques de cinta del 
partido comunista bajo este acto. Condenaron a los abogados para
acusado ellos mismos por el desprecio de la corte y la mitad sirvió 
términos de la prisión. Posteriormente, la mayoría de los 
abogados rechazaron representar a comunistas sospechados a menos que 
ellos mismos fueran miembros del partido comunista. En el 
testimonio siguiente ante un comité de la casa sobre actividades 
comunistas que investigaban el oír Un-Americano de las actividades 
(HUAC) en el área de San Francisco, el abogado radical Roberto E. 
Treuhaft (1912-2001) describió sus tentativas fracasadas de emplear a
los abogados respetados -- quiénes desaprobaron privado HUAC -- para 
representarlo. Treuhaft, abogado Oakland-basado que había 
representado sindicatos y los Africano-Americanos privaron de las 
derechas civiles, había ensamblado el partido comunista en los años 
40 posteriormente, él se convirtió en el consejo sin pagar para el 
congreso de las derechas civiles (CRC), una fondo fiduciaria que 
proveió el dinero de la fianza para los comunistas arrestados bajo 
acto de Smith. El departamento de la justicia incluyó el CRC en
su lista oficial de organizaciones subversivas, y después de su 
aspecto antes de HUAC, el Treuhaft enumerado comité entre los 39 
abogados subversivos más peligrosos de su folleto, "Subversives legal
comunista: El papel del abogado comunista." Jessica 
Mitford, esposa de Treihaft_s, escribió en su memoria, un viejo 
conflicto fino, que la audiencia de San Francisco HUAC apuntada hizo 
daño serio "en sustentos que destruían y la disensión política que
abozalaba en los pueblos llano."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086269</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104269</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-am-entitled-to-counsel-of-my-choice-radical-attorney-robert-treuhaft-challenges-huac-and-mccarthyism</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
