<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103777</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103777</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203557</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Junk in Space</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Trödel im Platz</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ordure dans l'espace</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Sucata no espaço</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Roba di rifiuto nello spazio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παλιοπράγματα στο διάστημα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Chatarra en espacio</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">There are currently millions of man-made orbital ruins that make up "space junk". Space junk can be anything from hatches blown off space modules, paint fragments from the space shuttle, or satellites that no longer work. On this website you will help to capture junk that's floating out there in space. Each time you capture junk, you also find a short description of the junk, how it arrived in space and links to additional information. This is an activity that takes less than 5 minutes and is a fun way to learn about man-made orbital ruins.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Es gibt aktuell Millionen der synthetischen 
Augenhöhlenruinen, die "Platztrödel" bilden. Platztrödel kann
aller von Luken weggeblasenen Platzmodulen, Farbe Fragmente vom 
Platzdoppelventilkegel oder Satelliten sein, die nicht mehr arbeiten. 
Auf dieser Web site helfen Sie, Trödel zu erfassen, der heraus 
dort in Platz schwimmt. Jede Zeit erfassen Sie Trödel, finden 
Sie auch eine kurze Beschreibung des Trödels, wie er im Platz und in 
den Links zu den zusätzlichen Informationen ankam. Dieses ist 
eine Aktivität, die weniger als nimmt, 5 Minuten und ist eine 
Spaßmethode, über synthetische Augenhöhlenruinen zu erlernen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Il y a actuel des millions de ruines orbitales 
synthétiques qui composent l'"ordure de l'espace". L'ordure de 
l'espace peut être quelque chose des modules de l'espace enlevés à 
l'air comprimé par trappes, des fragments de peinture de la navette 
spatiale, ou des satellites qui ne fonctionnent plus. Sur ce 
site Web vous aiderez à capturer l'ordure qui éloigne du rivage là 
dans l'espace. Chaque fois que vous capturez l'ordure, vous 
trouvez également une description courte de l'ordure, comment elle 
est arrivée dans l'espace et des liens à l'information 
supplémentaire. C'est une activité qui prend moins de 5 
minutes et est une voie d'amusement de se renseigner sur des ruines 
orbitales synthétiques.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Há atualmente uns milhões das ruínas orbitais 
sintéticas que fazem acima do "a sucata espaço". A sucata do 
espaço pode ser qualquer coisa dos portais fundidos fora dos módulos
do espaço, dos fragmentos da pintura do shuttle de espaço, ou dos 
satélites que nenhum trabalho mais longo. Neste Web site você 
ajudará capturar a sucata que está flutuando para fora lá no 
espaço. Cada vez que você captura a sucata, você encontra 
também uma descrição curta da sucata, como chegou no espaço e nas 
ligações à informação adicional. Esta é uma atividade que 
faça exame menos de 5 minutos e é uma maneira do divertimento 
aprender sobre ruínas orbitais sintéticas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ci sono attualmente milioni di rovine orbitali 
artificiali che compongono "la roba di rifiuto dello spazio". La
roba di rifiuto dello spazio può essere qualche cosa dai moduli dello
spazio scaricati portelli, frammenti della vernice dalla spola di 
spazio, o satelliti che più non funzionano. Su questo Web site 
contribuirete a bloccare la roba di rifiuto che sta galleggiando fuori
là nello spazio. Ogni volta bloccate la roba di rifiuto, 
egualmente trovate una descrizione corta della roba di rifiuto, come 
è arrivato nello spazio e nei collegamenti alle informazioni 
supplementari. Ciò è un'attività che prende più meno di 5 
minuti ed è un modo di divertimento imparare circa le rovine orbitali
artificiali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Υπάρχουν αυτήν την περίοδο εκατομμύρια των 
προκαλούμενων από τον άνθρωπο τροχιακών καταστροφών που 
αποτελούν τα "διαστημικά παλιοπράγματα". Τα διαστημικά 
παλιοπράγματα μπορούν να είναι τίποτα από βγοντες από τη θέση 
που ήταν τις πόρτες διαστημικές ενότητες, τεμάχια χρωμάτων από 
τη διαστημική σαϊ'τα, ή δορυφόροι που δεν λειτουργούν πλέον. 
Σε αυτόν τον ιστοχώρο θα βοηθήσετε να συλλάβετε τα 
παλιοπράγματα που επιπλέοντας έξω εκεί στο διάστημα. Κάθε 
φορά που συλλαμβάνετε τα παλιοπράγματα, βρίσκετε επίσης μια 
σύντομη περιγραφή των παλιοπραγμάτων, πώς έφθασε στο διάστημα 
και τις συνδέσεις με τις πρόσθετες πληροφορίες. Αυτό είναι 
μια δραστηριότητα που διαρκεί λιγότερο από 5 λεπτά και είναι 
ένας τρόπος διασκέδασης να μάθει για τις προκαλούμενες από τον 
άνθρωπο τροχιακές καταστροφές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Hay actualmente millones de ruinas orbitales 
artificiales que hagan para arriba la "chatarra del espacio". La
chatarra del espacio puede ser cualquier cosa de los módulos 
descargados las portillas del espacio, de los fragmentos de la pintura
de la lanzadera de espacio, o de los satélites que ningún trabajo 
más largo. En este Web site usted ayudará a capturar la 
chatarra que está flotando hacia fuera allí en espacio. Cada 
vez que usted captura la chatarra, usted también encuentra una 
descripción corta de la chatarra, cómo llegó en espacio y 
conexiones a la información adicional. Ésta es una actividad 
que toma menos de 5 minutos y es una manera de la diversión de 
aprender sobre ruinas orbitales artificiales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203557</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103777</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/junk-in-space</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
