<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107873</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107873</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973985</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">U.N. Convention on the Rights of the Child Lesson Modules</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">U.N. Versammlung über die Rechte der 
Kind-Lektion-Module</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">U.N. Convention sur les droits de l'enfance 
les modules de leçon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">U.N. Convenção nas direitas dos módulos 
da lição da criança</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">U.N. Convenzione sui diritti dei moduli di 
lezione del bambino</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Συνθήκη των Η.Ε σχετικά με τα δικαιώματα των ενοτήτων 
μαθήματος παιδιών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">U.N. Convención sobre las derechas de los 
módulos de la lección del niño</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In recognition of the historic 18th Birthday of the U.N. Convention on the Rights of the Child (CRC), we have assembled a human rights education media environment to help introduce the CRC to learners. Our intended audience is young adults, middle school through early college. The components include an interactive workshop on the CRC which can be easily facilitated in a single class period, background information on the Convention, the text of the CRC including a shortened child-friendly version, an essay by the creator of the workshop on how it was designed and an actual application of the activities with students, a multi-media visual essay using the photographic archives of Magnum Photos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In der Anerkennung des historischen 18. 
Geburtstages U.N. Convention auf den Rechten des Kindes (zyklische 
Blockprüfung), haben wir Media eine der menschlichen Rechte 
Ausbildung zusammengebaut, die Umgebung zur Hilfe die zyklische 
Blockprüfung zu den Anfängern vorstellen. Unser beabsichtigtes
Publikum ist junge Erwachsene, mittlere Schule durch frühe 
Hochschule. Die Bestandteile enthalten ein interaktives Seminar 
über die zyklische Blockprüfung, die in einer einzelnen Kategorie 
Periode, Hintergrundinformationen leicht erleichtert werden kann über
die Vereinbarung, der Text der zyklischen Blockprüfung 
einschließlich eine verkürzte Kind-freundliche Version, ein Versuch 
durch den Schöpfer des Seminars über, wie es und eine tatsächliche 
Anwendung der Aktivitäten mit Kursteilnehmern konzipiert war, ein 
multi-media Sichtversuch mit den fotographischen Archiven der 
Magnum-Fotos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans l'identification du 18ème anniversaire 
historique d'U.N. Convention sur les droits de l'enfance (CRC), nous 
avons assemblé des medias d'une éducation de droits de l'homme que 
l'environnement à l'aide présentent le CRC aux étudiants. 
Notre assistance destinée est les jeunes adultes, collège par 
l'université tôt. Les composants incluent un atelier 
interactif sur le CRC qui peut être facilement facilité dans une 
seule période de classe, information de fond sur la convention, le 
texte du CRC comprenant une version enfant-amicale raccourcie, un 
essai par le créateur de l'atelier sur la façon dont il a été 
conçu et une application réelle des activités avec des étudiants, 
un essai visuel multimédia en utilisant les archives photographiques 
des photos de magnum.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No recognition do 18o aniversário historic do 
U.N. Convenção nas direitas da criança (CRC), nós montamos media 
que de uma instrução das direitas humanas o ambiente à ajuda 
introduz o CRC aos learners. Nossa audiência pretendida é os 
adultos novos, escola média através da faculdade adiantada. Os
componentes incluem uma oficina interativa no CRC que pode fàcilmente
ser facilitado em um único período da classe, informação de fundo 
na convenção, o texto do CRC including uma versão 
criança-amigável encurtada, um essay pelo criador da oficina em como
foi projetada e uma aplicação real das atividades com estudantes, um
essay visual multi-media usando os arquivos fotográficos de fotos do 
magnum.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nel riconoscimento del diciottesimo compleanno 
storico del U.N. Convention sui diritti del bambino (CRC), abbiamo 
montato i media che di formazione di diritti dell'uomo l'ambiente ad 
aiuto introduce il CRC ai principianti. Il nostro pubblico 
progettato è adulti giovani, scuola centrale attraverso l'università
in anticipo. I componenti includono un workshop interattivo sul 
CRC che può essere facilitato facilmente in un singolo periodo del 
codice categoria, informazioni di base sulla convenzione, il testo del
CRC compreso una versione bambino-amichevole ridotta, un saggio dal 
creatore del workshop su come è stato progettato e un'applicazione 
reale delle attività con gli allievi, un saggio visivo multimedio 
usando gli archivi fotografici delle foto del magnum.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αναγνώριση των ιστορικών 18$ων γενεθλίων της 
περιβάλλον μέσων εκπαίδευσης Συνθήκης των Η.Ε σχετικά με τα 
δικαιώματα του παιδιού (κέντρο ανίχνευσης και ελέγχου), έχουμε 
συγκεντρώσει ένα των ανθρώπινων δικαιωμάτων για να βοηθήσουμε να 
εισαγάγουμε το κέντρο ανίχνευσης και ελέγχου στους αρχαρίους. 
Το προοριζόμενο ακροατήριό μας είναι νέοι ενήλικοι, 
δευτεροβάθμια εκπαίδευση μέσω του πρώτου κολλεγίου. Τα 
συστατικά περιλαμβάνουν ένα διαλογικό εργαστήριο στο κέντρο 
ανίχνευσης και ελέγχου που μπορεί να διευκολυνθεί εύκολα σε μια 
ενιαία περίοδο κλάσης, βασικές πληροφορίες για τη Συνθήκη, το 
κείμενο του κέντρου ανίχνευσης και ελέγχου συμπεριλαμβανομένης 
μιας μικρότερης παιδί-φιλικής έκδοσης, ένα δοκίμιο από το 
δημιουργό του εργαστηρίου στον τρόπο με τον οποίο σχεδιάστηκε και
μια πραγματική εφαρμογή των δραστηριοτήτων με τους σπουδαστές, 
ένα οπτικό δοκίμιο πολυμέσων χρησιμοποιώντας τα φωτογραφικά 
αρχεία των φωτογραφιών φιαλών δύο λίτρων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En el reconocimiento del décimo octavo 
cumpleaños histórico del U.N. Convention en las derechas del niño 
(CRC), hemos ensamblado media de una educación de los derechos 
humanos que el ambiente a la ayuda introduce el CRC a los 
principiantes. Nuestra audiencia prevista es los adultos 
jóvenes, escuela media a través de la universidad temprana. 
Los componentes incluyen un taller interactivo sobre el CRC que 
se puede facilitar fácilmente en un solo período de la clase, 
información de fondo sobre la convención, el texto del CRC 
incluyendo una versión niño-co'moda acortada, un ensayo del creador 
del taller sobre cómo fue diseñado y una aplicación real de las 
actividades con los estudiantes, un ensayo visual multi-media usando 
los archivos fotográficos de las fotos de la botella doble.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973985</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107873</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/u-n-convention-on-the-rights-of-the-child-lesson-modules</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
