<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106309</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106309</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212606</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The High Plains: Land of Extremes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Hohen Ebenen: Land von Übermaßen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Hautes Plaines : Terre des extrémités</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As Planícies Elevadas: Terra dos extremos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le Alte Pianure: Terra degli estremi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι υψηλές πεδιάδες: Έδαφος των άκρων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los Llanos Altos: Pista de extremos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This website is dedicated to the High Plains: Land of Extremes Exercise. This exercise covers the physical features of the High Plains (or Great Plains), the grasses and plants of the area, prairie dog ecosystems, riparian areas, mining, management, water resources, and fire cycles. Student activities are based on the study of groundwater movement, energy resources, wind energy, and riparian areas. A debate allows students to understand the viewpoints of different interest groups in considering whether the black-footed ferret should be reintroduced onto public lands. On this Starting Point page, teachers can find learning goals, teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment hints and references and resources dealing with this exercise. It also describes the context in which the exercise is best used.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Web site wird den hohen Ebenen eingesetzt: 
Land der Übermaß-Übung. Diese Übung umfaßt die 
körperlichen Merkmale der hohen Ebenen (oder der Prairien), der 
Gräser und der Betriebe des Bereiches, der 
Graslandhundeoekosysteme, der riparian Bereiche, des Bergbaus, des 
Managements, der Wasserbetriebsmittel und der Feuerschleifen. 
Kursteilnehmeraktivitäten basieren auf der Studie der 
Grundwasserbewegung, der Energiebetriebsmittel, der Windenergie und 
der riparian Bereiche. Eine Debatte erlaubt Kursteilnehmern, die
Veranschaulichungen der unterschiedlichen Interesse Gruppen zu 
verstehen, wenn sie betrachtet, ob das schwarz-füßige Frettchen auf 
allgemeine Länder wieder eingeführt werden sollte. Auf dieser 
Ausgangspunktseite können Lehrer die erlernenziele, unterrichtende 
Anmerkungen und Spitzen, Lehrmittel, Einschätzung Tips und Referenzen
und Betriebsmittel beschäftigend diese Übung finden. Sie 
beschreibt auch den Kontext, in dem die Übung gut verwendet wird.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site Web est consacré aux hautes plaines : 
Terre d'exercice d'extrémités. Cet exercice couvre les 
dispositifs physiques des hautes plaines (ou de grandes plaines), les 
herbes et les usines de la zone, les écosystèmes de chien de 
prairie, les zones ripicoles, l'exploitation, la gestion, les 
ressources d'eau, et les cycles du feu. Des activités 
d'étudiant sont basées sur l'étude du mouvement d'eaux 
souterraines, des ressources énergétiques, de l'énergie éolienne, 
et des zones ripicoles. Une discussion permet à des 
étudiants de comprendre les points de vue de différents groupes 
d'intérêt en considérant si le furet noir-aux pieds devrait être 
réintroduit sur les terres publiques. À cette page de point de
départ, les professeurs peuvent trouver des buts d'étude, des notes 
et des extrémités d'enseignement, matériel didactique, des conseils
d'évaluation et des références et des ressources traitant cet 
exercice. Il décrit également le contexte dans lequel 
l'exercice mieux est utilisé.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Web site é dedicado às planícies elevadas:
Terra do exercício dos extremos. Este exercício cobre as
características físicas das planícies elevadas (ou planícies 
grandes), as gramas e as plantas da área, os ecosystems do cão da 
pradaria, as áreas riparian, a mineração, a gerência, os recursos 
de água, e os ciclos do fogo. As atividades do estudante são 
baseadas no estudo do movimento do groundwater, dos recursos de 
energia, da energia do vento, e de áreas riparian. Um debate 
permite que os estudantes compreendam os viewpoints de grupos de 
interesse diferentes em considerar se a doninha preto-black-footed 
deve reintroduced em terras públicas. Nesta página do ponto 
começar, os professores podem encontrar os objetivos de aprendizagem,
as notas e as pontas ensinando, os materiais de ensino, as sugestões 
da avaliação e as referências e os recursos tratando deste 
exercício. Descreve também o contexto em que o exercício é 
usado melhor.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Web site è dedicato alle alte pianure: 
Terra dell'esercitazione di estremi. Questa esercitazione 
riguarda le caratteristiche fisiche di alte pianure (o pianure 
grandi), le erbe e le piante della zona, gli ecosistemi del cane dal 
prairie, le zone riparian, l'estrazione mineraria, la gestione, le 
risorse idriche ed i cicli del fuoco. Le attività dell'allievo 
sono basate sullo studio sul movimento dell'acqua freatica, sulle 
risorse energetiche, sull'energia del vento e sulle zone riparian. 
Un dibattito permette che gli allievi capiscano i punti di vista
dei gruppi di interesse comune differenti nel considerare se il 
furetto nero-black-footed dovrebbe essere rintrodotto sulle terre 
pubbliche. A questa pagina del punto di partenza, gli insegnanti
possono trovare gli obiettivi imparanti, note e punte d'istruzione, 
materiali didattici, suggerimenti di valutazione e riferimenti e 
risorse occupantesi di questa esercitazione. Egualmente descrive
il contesto in cui l'esercitazione è usata il più bene.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος αφιερώνεται στις υψηλές πεδιάδες: 
Έδαφος της άσκησης άκρων. Αυτή η άσκηση καλύπτει τα 
φυσικά χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα των υψηλών πεδιάδων (ή των 
μεγάλων πεδιάδων), των χλοών και των εγκαταστάσεων της περιοχής, 
των οικοσυστημάτων σκυλιών λιβαδιών, των παρόχθιων περιοχών, της 
μεταλλείας, της διαχείρισης, των υδάτινων πόρων, και των κύκλων 
πυρκαγιάς. Οι δραστηριότητες σπουδαστών είναι βασισμένες 
στη μελέτη της μετακίνησης υπόγειων νερών, των ενεργειακών 
στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς, της ενέργειας αέρα, και των παρόχθιων 
περιοχών. Μια συζήτηση επιτρέπει στους σπουδαστές για να 
καταλάβει τις απόψεις των διαφορετικών ομάδων ενδιαφέροντος στην 
εξέταση εάν το μαύρος-πληρωμένο κουνάβι πρέπει να επανεισαχθεί 
επάνω στα δημόσια εδάφη. Σε αυτήν την σελίδα αφετηρίας, οι
δάσκαλοι μπορούν να βρούν τους στόχους εκμάθησης, τις σημειώσεις
και τις άκρες διδασκαλίας, τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, τους 
υπαινιγμούς αξιολόγησης και τις αναφορές και τα στοιχεία 
συμπεριφοράς εξετάζοντας αυτήν την άσκηση. Περιγράφει 
επίσης το πλαίσιο στο οποίο η άσκηση χρησιμοποιείται καλύτερα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este Web site se dedica a los llanos altos: 
Pista del ejercicio de los extremos. Este ejercicio cubre 
las características físicas de los llanos altos (o los grandes 
llanos), las hierbas y las plantas del área, los ecosistemas del 
perro de la pradera, las áreas riparian, la explotación minera, la 
gerencia, los recursos de agua, y los ciclos del fuego. Las 
actividades del estudiante se basan en el estudio del movimiento de la
agua subterránea, de los recursos energéticos, de la energía del 
viento, y de las áreas riparian. Un discusión permite que los 
estudiantes entiendan los puntos de vista de diversos grupos de 
interés en la consideración de si el hurón negro-black-footed sea 
reintroducido sobre pistas públicas. En esta paginación del 
punto de partida, los profesores pueden encontrar las metas que 
aprenden, las notas y las extremidades de enseñanza, los materiales 
didácticos, las indirectas del gravamen y las referencias y los 
recursos ocupándose de este ejercicio. También describe el 
contexto en el cual el ejercicio se utiliza lo más mejor posible.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:RANEL CAPRON
FN:RANEL CAPRON
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:RICHARD BROOK
FN:RICHARD BROOK
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ELIZABETH RIEBEN
FN:ELIZABETH RIEBEN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212606</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106309</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-high-plains-land-of-extremes</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
