<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107033</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107033</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201828</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">What is a Profile? </string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Was ist ein Profil?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Quel est un profil ?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Que é um perfil?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Che cosa è un profilo?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τι είναι ένα σχεδιάγραμμα;</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿Cuál es un perfil?</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Using TIG profiles as an entry point, this activity explores a broader theme of "profiling" to enable students to examine how they present themselves, as well as cultural perceptions and biases within themselves, their peers, and their community. Students will read TIG profiles and Member Stories, with the objective of better understanding others' perspectives to critically reflect and write about their own identity. </string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mit TIG Profilen als Einsprungadresse, erforscht diese 
Aktivität ein ausgedehnteres Thema "des Ein Profil erstellens,", zum 
der Kursteilnehmer, zu überprüfen, wie sie, sowie kulturelle 
Vorstellungen und Vorspannungen innerhalb selbst, ihre Gleichen sich 
darstellen, und ihrer Gemeinschaft zu aktivieren. Kursteilnehmer
lesen TIG Profile und Bauteil-Geschichten, mit dem Lernziel des 
besseren Verständnisses anderer Perspektiven, um über ihre eigene 
Identität kritisch sich zu reflektieren und zu schreiben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En utilisant des profils de TIG comme point d'entrée, 
cette activité explore un plus grand thème du "profilage" pour 
permettre aux étudiants d'examiner comment ils se présentent, aussi 
bien que des perceptions et des polarisations culturelles dans 
eux-mêmes, leurs pairs, et à leur communauté. Les étudiants 
liront des profils de TIG et des histoires de membre, avec l'objectif 
d'un meilleur arrangement d'autres des perspectives en critique pour 
se refléter et écrire au sujet de leur propre identité.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Usando perfis do TIG como um ponto de entrada, esta 
atividade explora um tema mais largo de "perfilar" para permitir 
estudantes de examinar como se apresentam, as.well.as percepções e 
polarizações cultural dentro dse, seus pares, e sua comunidade. 
Os estudantes lerão perfis do TIG e histórias do membro, com o
objetivo da compreensão melhor outros perspectives para refletir e 
escrever crìticamente sobre sua própria identidade.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Usando i profili di TIG come punto di entrata, questa 
attività esplora un più grande tema "di delineamento" per permettere
agli allievi di esaminare come si presentano, così come le percezioni
e le polarizzazioni culturali all'interno di se stesso, i loro pari ed
alla loro Comunità. Gli allievi leggeranno i profili di TIG e 
le storia del membro, con l'obiettivo di comprensione migliore altri 
prospettive per riflettere e scrivere criticamente circa la loro 
propria identità.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Χρησιμοποιώντας tig τα σχεδιαγράμματα ως σημείο 
εισόδων, αυτή η δραστηριότητα ερευνά ένα ευρύτερο θέμα "της 
σκιαγράφησησ" για να επιτρέψει στους σπουδαστές για να εξετάσει 
πώς παρουσιάζονται, καθώς επίσης και τις πολιτιστικές αντιλήψεις
και τις πολώσεις εντός τους, των συνομήληκών τους, και της 
κοινότητάς τους. Οι σπουδαστές θα διαβάσουν tig τα 
σχεδιαγράμματα και τις ιστορίες μελών, με στόχο καλύτερα να 
καταλάβουν άλλες τις προοπτικές για να απεικονίσουν αυστηρά και 
να γράψουν για την ταυτότητά τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Usando perfiles del TIG como punto de entrada, esta 
actividad explora un tema más amplio de "perfilar" para permitir a 
estudiantes examinar cómo se presentan, así como opiniones y 
diagonales culturales dentro de sí mismos, sus pares, y a su 
comunidad. Los estudiantes leerán perfiles del TIG e historias 
del miembro, con el objetivo de una comprensión mejor otros las 
perspectivas para reflejar y para escribir críticamente sobre su 
propia identidad.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201828</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107033</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/what-is-a-profile</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
