<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103377</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103377</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212910</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Underneath the Mountains</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Unter die Berge</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sous les montagnes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Debaixo das montanhas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sotto le montagne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κάτω από τα βουνά</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Por debajo de las montañas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">These lecture notes discuss the role of buoyancy, flexure, and erosion in the earth's topography and the lifetime of mountain ranges. It recalls Pascal's law that pressure of a material overlying a fluid is equal everywhere at a given depth and Archimedes' principle that a body in a fluid is buoyed up with a force equal to the weight (mass x volume) of the displaced fluid. Continents are buoyant crust floating on denser mantle, so a 4 km high mountain range must have a 20 km deep root. According to Archimedes' principle, when mountain ranges erode, pressure is released from the surface and the mountain root is bouyed up to equalize the pressure. Continental crust is about 40 km thick, so it is strong enough to support smaller topographic loads, like small volcanoes, without the aid of a buoyant root.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Vortraganmerkungen behandeln die Rolle des 
Tragvermögens, der Biegung und der Abnutzung in der Topographie der 
Masse und der Lebenszeit der Gebirgsstrecken. Er erinnert an 
Gesetz des Pascal, daß Druck von einem materiellem, eine Flüssigkeit
überlagernd, überall an einer gegebenen Tiefe und an der Grundregel 
Archimedes gleich ist, daß ein Körper in einer Flüssigkeit oben mit
einer Kraft Auftrieb gegeben wird, die dem Gewicht gleich ist (Massenx
Datenträger) der verlegten Flüssigkeit. Kontinente sind die 
schwimmende Kruste, die auf dichteren Umhang schwimmt, also muß eine 
4 Kilometer hohe Gebirgsstrecke eine 20 Kilometer tiefe Wurzel haben. 
Entsprechend Grundregel Archimedes wenn Gebirgsstrecken 
abfressen, wird Druck von der Oberfläche freigegeben und die 
Gebirgswurzel ist- bouyed ausgleichen bis den Druck. 
Kontinentale Kruste ist ungefähr 40 Kilometer stark, also ist 
sie genug stark, kleinere topographische Eingaben, wie kleine Vulkane,
ohne das Hilfsmittel einer schwimmenden Wurzel zu unterstützen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ces notes de conférence discutent le rôle de la 
flottabilité, de la flexure, et de l'érosion en topographie de la 
terre et de la vie des intervalles de montagne. Elle rappelle la
loi du Pascal que la pression d'un matériel recouvrant un fluide est 
égale partout à une profondeur donnée et au principe d'Archimède 
qu'un corps dans un fluide est maintenu à flot vers le haut avec une 
force égale au poids (volume de masse de x) du fluide déplacé. 
Les continents sont croûte flottable flottant sur un manteau 
plus dense, ainsi un intervalle de haut de montagne de 4 kilomètres 
doit avoir une racine profonde de 20 kilomètres. Selon le 
principe d'Archimède, quand les intervalles de montagne érodent, de 
la pression est libérée de la surface et la racine de montagne est 
bouyed égalisent jusqu'à la pression. La croûte continentale 
est d'environ 40 kilomètres d'épaisseur, ainsi elle est assez forte 
pour supporter de plus petits chargements topographiques, comme de 
petits volcans, sans aide d'une racine flottable.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Estas notas do lecture discutem o papel do 
buoyancy, do flexure, e da erosão no topography da terra e da vida de
escalas da montanha. Recorda a lei do Pascal que a pressão de 
um material overlying um líquido é igual em toda parte em uma 
profundidade dada e no princípio de Archimedes' que um corpo em um 
líquido buoyed acima com uma força igual ao peso (volume maciço de 
x) do líquido deslocado. Os continentes são crosta flutuante 
que flutua em um mantle mais denso, assim que uma escala elevada da 
montanha de 4 quilômetros deve ter uma raiz profunda de 20 
quilômetros. De acordo com o princípio de Archimedes', quando 
as escalas da montanha se corroem, a pressão é liberada da 
superfície e a raiz da montanha é bouyed iguala até a pressão. 
A crosta continental tem aproximadamente 40 quilômetros grossa,
assim que é forte bastante suportar cargas topographic menores, como 
vulcões pequenos, sem o dae (dispositivo automático de entrada) de 
uma raiz flutuante.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Queste note di conferenza discutono il ruolo di 
galleggiabilità, di flessione e di erosione in topografia della terra
e del corso della vita delle gamme della montagna. Ricorda la 
legge del Pascal che la pressione di un materiale ricoprendo un 
liquido è uguale dappertutto ad una data profondità ed al principio 
del Archimedes che un corpo in un liquido buoyed in su con una forza 
uguale al peso (volume totale di x) del liquido spostato. I 
continenti sono crosta capace di galleggiare che galleggia sul manto 
più denso, in modo da una gamma d'altezza della montagna da 4 
chilometri deve avere una radice profonda da 20 chilometri. 
Secondo il principio del Archimedes, quando le gamme della 
montagna corrodono, la pressione è liberata dalla superficie e la 
radice della montagna è bouyed fino a livella la pressione. La 
crosta continentale è spessa circa 40 chilometri, in modo da è 
abbastanza forte sostenere i più piccoli carichi topografici, come i 
piccoli vulcani, senza il sussidio di una radice capace di 
galleggiare.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτές οι σημειώσεις διάλεξης συζητούν το ρόλο της 
πλευστότητας, της κάμψης, και της διάβρωσης στη γήινη τοπογραφία 
και της διάρκειας ζωής των σειρών βουνών. Υπενθυμίζει το 
νόμο PASCAL ότι η πίεση ενός υλικού που επικαλύπτει ένα 
ρευστό είναι ίση παντού σε ένα δεδομένο βάθος και αρχή του 
Αρχιμήδη ότι ένα σώμα σε ένα ρευστό είναι επάνω με μια δύναμη
ίση με το βάρος (μάζα Χ ένταση του ήχου) του μετατοπισμένου 
ρευστού. Οι ήπειροι είναι επιπλέουσα κρούστα που επιπλέει 
στον πυκνότερο μανδύα, έτσι μια 4 χλμ υψηλή σειρά βουνών πρέπει
να έχει μια βαθιά ρίζα 20 χλμ. Σύμφωνα με την αρχή του 
Αρχιμήδη, όταν διαβρώνουν οι σειρές βουνών, η πίεση εκδίδεται 
από την επιφάνεια και η ρίζα βουνών είναι μέχρι εξισώνει την 
πίεση. Η ηπειρωτική κρούστα είναι περίπου 40 χλμ παχιά,
έτσι είναι αρκετά ισχυρή να υποστηρίξει τα μικρότερα 
τοπογραφικά φορτία, όπως τα μικρά ηφαίστεια, χωρίς την ενίσχυση
μιας επιπλέουσας ρίζας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Estas notas de la conferencia discuten el papel de
la flotabilidad, de la flexión, y de la erosión en la topografía de
la tierra y del curso de la vida de los rangos de la montaña. 
Recuerda la ley del PASCAL que la presión de un material 
cubriendo un líquido es igual por todas partes en una profundidad 
dada y el principio de Archimedes que un cuerpo en un líquido buoyed 
para arriba con una fuerza igual al peso (volumen total de x) del 
líquido desplazado. Los continentes son corteza boyante que 
flota en una capa más densa, así que un alto rango de la montaña de
4 kilómetros debe tener una raíz profunda de 20 kilómetros. 
Según el principio de Archimedes, cuando los rangos de la 
montaña erosionan, la presión release/versión de la superficie y la
raíz de la montaña es bouyed hasta iguala la presión. La 
corteza continental es cerca de 40 kilómetros de grueso, así que es 
bastante fuerte utilizar cargas topográficas más pequeñas, como los
volcanes pequeños, sin la ayuda de una raíz boyante.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212910</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103377</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/underneath-the-mountains</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
