<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105588</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105588</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209613</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Climate Change Emission Calculator Kit (Climate CHECK)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Klima-Änderung Emission-Rechner-Installationssatz
(Klima ÜBERPRÜFUNG)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Kit de Calculatrice D'Émission de Changement de 
Climat (CONTRÔLE de Climat)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogo Da Calculadora Da Emissão Da Mudança Do 
Clima (VERIFICAÇÃO Do Clima)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Kit Del Calcolatore Dell'Emissione Del Cambiamento
Di Clima (CONTROLLO Di Clima)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εξάρτηση υπολογιστών εκπομπής αλλαγής κλίματος 
(ΕΛΕΓΧΟΣ κλίματος)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Kit De la Calculadora De la Emisión Del Cambio 
Del Clima (CHEQUE Del Clima)</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">High school students can investigate the link between everyday actions at their high school, greenhouse gas emissions and climate change. Using this site, students can learn about climate change, estimate their school's greenhouse gas emissions and conceptualize ways to mitigate their school's climate impact. Students gain detailed understandings of climate-change drivers, impacts, and science; produce an emission inventory and action plan; and can even submit the results of their emission inventory to their school district.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">High School Kursteilnehmer können das Link 
zwischen täglichen Tätigkeiten an ihrer High School, 
Gewächshausgasemissionen und Klimaänderung nachforschen. Mit 
dieser Site können Kursteilnehmer über Klimaänderung erlernen, 
Gewächshaus-Gasemissionen ihrer Schule schätzen und Methoden 
auffassen, Klimaauswirkung ihrer Schule abzuschwächen. 
Kursteilnehmer gewinnen ausführliche Bedingung von 
Klima-ändern Treiber, Auswirkungen und Wissenschaft; 
produzieren Sie einen Emissioninhalt und einen Aktionsplan; 
und kann die Resultate ihres Emissioninhalts bei ihrem 
Schulebezirk sogar eingeben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les étudiants de lycée peuvent étudier le lien 
entre les actions journalières à leur lycée, les émissions de gaz 
de serre chaude et le changement de climat. En utilisant ce 
site, les étudiants peuvent se renseigner sur le changement de 
climat, estimer les émissions de gaz de la serre chaude de leur 
école et conceptualiser des voies d'atténuer l'impact du climat de 
leur école. Les étudiants gagnent des vues 
détaillées de climat-changent des gestionnaires, des impacts, et la 
science ; produisez un inventaire d'émission et un plan 
d'action ; et peut même soumettre les résultats de leur 
inventaire d'émission à leur zone d'école.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os estudantes da High School podem investigar a 
ligação entre ações diárias em sua High School, emissões de gás
da estufa e mudança do clima. Usando este local, os estudantes 
podem aprender sobre a mudança do clima, estimar emissões de gás da
estufa da sua escola e conceptualize maneiras mitigate o impacto do 
clima da sua escola. Os estudantes ganham understandings 
detalhados de clima-mudam excitadores, impactos, e ciência; 
produza uma planta do inventário e de ação da emissão; 
e pode mesmo submeter os resultados de seu inventário da 
emissão a seu distrito da escola.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli allievi della High School possono studiare il 
collegamento fra le azioni giornalieri alla loro High School, le 
emissioni di gas della serra ed il cambiamento di clima. Usando 
questo luogo, gli allievi possono imparare circa il cambiamento di 
clima, valutare le emissioni di gas della serra della loro scuola e 
concettualizzare i modi attenuare l'effetto di clima della loro 
scuola. Gli allievi guadagnano i understandings dettagliati di 
clima-cambiano i driver, gli effetti e la scienza; produca un 
inventario dell'emissione e un piano d'azione; e può persino 
presentare i risultati del loro inventario dell'emissione al loro 
distretto della scuola.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι σπουδαστές γυμνασίου μπορούν να ερευνήσουν τη 
σύνδεση μεταξύ των καθημερινών ενεργειών στο γυμνάσιό τους, των 
εκπομπών θερμοκηπίων αέριο και της αλλαγής κλίματος. 
Χρησιμοποιώντας αυτήν την περιοχή, οι σπουδαστές μπορούν να
μάθουν για την αλλαγή κλίματος, να υπολογίσουν τις εκπομπές 
θερμοκηπίων του σχολείου τους αέριο και να αντιληφθούν τους 
τρόπους να μετριάσουν τον αντίκτυπο κλίματος του σχολείου τους. 
Οι σπουδαστές κερδίζουν τους λεπτομερείς όρους των οδηγών, 
των επιδράσεων, και της επιστήμης κλίμα-αλλαγής  παράγετε 
ένα πρόγραμμα καταλόγων και δράσης εκπομπής  και μπορεί 
ακόμη και να υποβάλει τα αποτελέσματα του καταλόγου εκπομπής τους
στη σχολική περιοχή τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los estudiantes de la High School secundaria 
pueden investigar la conexión entre las acciones diarias en su High 
School secundaria, las emisiones de gas del invernadero y el cambio 
del clima. Usando este sitio, los estudiantes pueden aprender 
sobre cambio del clima, estimar las emisiones de gas del invernadero 
de su escuela y conceptuar maneras de atenuar el impacto del clima de 
su escuela. Los estudiantes ganan entendimiento detallado de 
clima-cambian programas pilotos, impactos, y ciencia; produzca 
un plan del inventario y de acción de la emisión; y puede 
incluso someter los resultados de su inventario de la emisión a su 
districto de la escuela.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:US ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION AGENCY
FN:US ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION AGENCY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209613</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Public Domain</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105588</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/climate-change-emission-calculator-kit</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
