<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/170411807</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>170411807</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209958</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Online Science-athon: How Tall Am I?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Onlinewissenschaft-athon: Bin Ich Wie Hoch?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science-athon En ligne : Combien Est-ce 
que Grand Je Suis ?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência-athon Em linha: Como Alto Sou Eu?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza-athon In linea: Quanto Alto Sono?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε απευθείας σύνδεση επιστήμη -επιστήμη-ατχον: 
Πόσο ψηλό είναι το ι;</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia-athon En línea: ¿Cómo Alto Soy?</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Online Science-athon offers elementary and middle-grade students opportunities to discover the science in their daily lives. Presented as challenges, the Science-athon asks students to investigate their world in ways that are engaging and fun, easy for teachers to incorporate into their teaching, and instructive. Students participating in How Tall Am I? create a way to measure their height as accurately as possible. On Measuring Day students collect and record data and share it with other students doing the challenge. Display and analysis of the data in the challenge database allow them to see if the larger data set supports their conjectures and predictions.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Onlinewissenschaft-athon bietet die grundlegende und 
Mittlergrad Kursteilnehmer Gelegenheiten, die Wissenschaft in ihren 
täglichen Lebensdauern zu entdecken an. Dargestellt als 
Herausforderungen, bittet die Wissenschaft-athon Kursteilnehmer, ihre 
Welt in den Methoden, die und sich engagieren, im Spaß 
nachzuforschen, einfach, damit Lehrer in ihren Unterricht verbinden, 
und lehrreich. Kursteilnehmer, die an wie hohes morgens I 
teilnehmen? erstellen Sie eine Methode, ihre Höhe so genau zu 
messen, wie möglich. An messendem Tag sammeln Kursteilnehmer 
und speichern Daten und teilen es mit anderen Kursteilnehmern, welche 
die Herausforderung tun. Bildschirmanzeige und Analyse der Daten
in der Herausforderung Datenbank lassen sie sehen, wenn die größere 
Datei ihre Vermutungen und Vorhersagen unterstützt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science-athon en ligne offre les étudiants 
élémentaires et de moyen-catégorie des occasions de découvrir la 
science dans leurs vies quotidiennes. Présenté en tant que 
défis, la Science-athon demande à des étudiants d'étudier leur 
monde des voies qui s'engagent et de l'amusement, facile pour des 
professeurs d'incorporer à leur enseignement, et instructif. 
Étudiants participant à la façon dont AM grand I ? 
créez une voie de mesurer leur taille aussi exactement comme 
possible. Le jour de mesure les étudiants rassemblent et 
enregistrent des données et les partagent avec d'autres étudiants 
faisant le défi. L'affichage et l'analyse des données dans la 
base de données de défi leur permettent de voir si le Modem plus 
grand supporte leurs conjectures et prévisions.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A Ciência-athon em linha oferece estudantes elementares e
da médio-classe oportunidades de descobrir a ciência em suas vidas 
diárias. Apresentado como desafios, a Ciência-athon pede que 
os estudantes investiguem seu mundo nas maneiras que estão acoplando 
e no divertimento, fácil para que os professores incorporem em seu 
ensino, e instructive. Estudantes que participam em como Am alto
I? críe uma maneira medir tão exatamente sua altura como 
possível. No dia de medição os estudantes coletam e gravam 
dados e compartilham d com outros estudantes que fazem o desafio. 
O indicador e a análise dos dados na base de dados do desafio 
permitem que v se a série de dados de maior suportar seus conjectures
e predições.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Scienza-athon in linea offre gli allievi del 
centrale-grado ed elementari occasioni scoprire la scienza nelle loro 
vite quotidiane. Presentato come sfide, la Scienza-athon chiede 
agli allievi di studiare il loro mondo nei modi che stanno 
agganciandosi e nel divertimento, facile affinchè gli insegnanti 
incorpori nel loro insegnamento ed istruttivo. Allievi che 
partecipano a come alto I? crei un modo misurare esattamente la 
loro altezza come possibile. Il giorno di misurazione gli 
allievi raccolgono e registrano i dati e li ripartiscono con altri 
allievi che fanno la sfida. La visualizzazione e l'analisi dei 
dati nella base di dati di sfida li permettono di vedere se il più 
grande insieme di dati sostiene le loro congetture e previsioni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η σε απευθείας σύνδεση επιστήμη -επιστήμη-ατχον 
προσφέρει τις στοιχειώδεις και μέσες ευκαιρίες σπουδαστών να 
ανακαλύψουν την επιστήμη στις καθημερινές ζωές τους. 
Παρουσιασμένη ως προκλήσεις, η επιστήμη -επιστήμη-ατχον 
ζητά από τους σπουδαστές για να ερευνήσει τον κόσμο τους στους 
τρόπους που δεσμεύουν και διασκέδαση, εύκολη για τους δασκάλους 
να ενσωματώσουν στη διδασκαλία τους, και διδακτική. 
Σπουδαστές που συμμετέχουν στο πώς ψηλός είναι ι; 
δημιουργήστε έναν τρόπο να μετρηθεί το ύψος τους όσο το 
δυνατόν ακριβέστερα. Στη μέτρηση της ημέρας οι σπουδαστές 
συλλέγουν και στοιχεία αρχείων και τον μοιράζονται με άλλους 
σπουδαστές που κάνουν την πρόκληση. Η παρουσίαση και η 
ανάλυση των στοιχείων στη βάση δεδομένων πρόκλησης επιτρέπουν σε
τους για να δουν εάν το μεγαλύτερο σύνολο στοιχείων 
υποστηρίζει τις υποθέσεις και τις προβλέψεις τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Ciencia-athon en línea ofrece a estudiantes 
elementales y del medio-grado las oportunidades de descubrir la 
ciencia en sus vidas diarias. Presentado como desafíos, la 
Ciencia-athon pide que los estudiantes investiguen su mundo de las 
maneras que están enganchando y de la diversión, fácil para que los
profesores incorporen en su enseñanza, e instructivo. 
¿Estudiantes que participan en cómo alta I? cree una 
manera de medir su altura tan exactamente como sea posible. En 
día que mide los estudiantes recogen y registran datos y los 
comparten con otros estudiantes que hacen el desafío. La 
visualización y el análisis de los datos en la base de datos del 
desafío permiten que consideren si el modem más grande utiliza sus 
conjeturas y predicciones.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209958</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>170411807</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/how-tall</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
