<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107609</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107609</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086062</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Debs Attacks "the Monstrous System" of Capitalism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Debs nimmt "das ungeheuere System" von 
Kapitalismus in Angriff</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Debs attaque "le système monstrueux" du 
capitalisme</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Debs ataca "o sistema monstrous" do capitalismo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Debs attaca "il sistema enorme" del capitalismo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Debs επιτίθεται "στο τερατώδες σύστημα" της 
κεφαλαιοκρατίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Debs ataca "el sistema monstruoso" del 
capitalismo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1912, four candidates battled to become President of the United States. Republican incumbent William Howard Taft and Democrat Woodrow Wilson, a moderate governor, represented the two major parties. Former President Theodore Roosevelt, angered over what he felt was a betrayal of his policies by Taft, his hand-picked successor, abandoned the Republican party and founded the Progressive or "Bull Moose" Party. While all four candidates appealed directly to working-class voters, whose votes would prove decisive, by far the most radical platform in the campaign was that of the Socialist Party nominee, Eugene V. Debs. Running for the fourth time, Debs called for the abolition of capitalism rather than for its reform. In this speech accepting the party's nomination he proclaimed the Socialist Party "the party of progress, the party of the future." Debs finished last in the contest, receiving 900,000 votes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1912 kämpften vier Anwärter, um Präsident der 
Vereinigten Staaten zu werden. Republikanischer Amtsinhaber 
William Howard Taft und Demokrat Woodrow Wilson, ein gemäßigter 
Regler, vertrat die zwei HauptParteien. Ehemaliger 
Präsident Theodore Roosevelt, verärgert über was er war ein Verrat 
seiner politischen Richtlinien durch Taft, sein handverlesener 
Nachfolger, verließ die republikanische Partei glaubte und 
gegründet dem Progressisten oder "die Bull Elch-" Partei. 
Während alle vier Anwärter direkt Arbeiterklassewählern 
gefielen, deren Stimmen entscheidendes prüfen würden, bei weitem war
die radikalste Plattform in der Kampagne die des sozialistischen 
Parteikandidaten, Eugene V. Debs. Laufend für das vierte 
mal, verlangte Debs für die Aufhebung von Kapitalismus anstatt seine 
Verbesserung. In dieser Rede, welche die Parteinennung 
proklamierte er annimmt, die sozialistische Partei "die 
Partei des Fortschritts, die Partei der Zukunft." 
Debs beendete zuletzt im Wettbewerb und empfing 900.000 Stimmen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1912, quatre candidats ont lutté pour devenir 
président des Etats-Unis. Le candidat sortant républicain 
William Howard Taft et démocrate Woodrow Wilson, un gouverneur 
modéré, a représenté les deux parties principales. L'ancien 
Président Theodore Roosevelt, irrité au-dessus de ce que s'est senti
il était une trahison de ses politiques par Taft, son successeur 
trié à la main, a abandonné la partie républicaine et fondé la 
partie d'orignaux de progressif ou "de Bull". Tandis que chacun 
des quatre candidats faisait directement appel aux électeurs de 
classe ouvrier, dont les voix prouveraient décisif, de loin la 
plateforme la plus radicale dans la campagne était celle du dénommé
de parti socialiste, Eugene V. Debs. Exécutant pour la 
quatrième fois, Debs a nécessité pour l'abolition du capitalisme 
plutôt que sa réforme. Dans ce discours recevant la nomination
de la partie il a proclamé le parti socialiste "la partie du 
progrès, la partie du futur." Debs a terminé pour la dernière
fois dans le concours, recevant 900.000 voix.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1912, quatro candidatos battled para 
transformar-se presidente dos estados unidos. O encarregado 
republicano William Howard Taft e democrata Woodrow Wilson, um 
regulador moderado, representou os dois partidos principais. 
Presidente anterior Theodore Roosevelt, irritado sobre o que 
sentiu era um betrayal de suas políticas por Taft, seu sucessor 
hand-picked, abandonou o partido republicano e fundado o partido dos 
alces do progressista ou da "Bull". Quando todos os quatro 
candidatos apelaram diretamente aos eleitores do working-class, cujos 
os votos provariam decisive, distante pela plataforma a mais radical 
na campanha estava aquele do nominee do partido socialist, Eugene V. 
Debs. Funcionando para a quarta vez, Debs chamou-se para o 
abolition do capitalismo melhor que para sua reforma. Neste 
discurso que aceita o nomination do partido proclamou o partido 
socialist "o partido do progresso, o partido do futuro." Debs 
terminou por último na competição, recebendo 900.000 votos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1912, quattro candidati combattuti per 
diventare presidente del unito Dichiara. Il incumbent 
repubblicano William Howard Taft e la carbossimetilazione Woodrow 
Wilson, un regolatore moderato, ha rappresentato i due partiti 
principali. Ex presidente Theodore Roosevelt, fatto arrabbiare 
sopra che cosa ha ritenuto era un betrayal delle sue politiche da 
Taft, il suo successore raccolto a mano, ha abbandonato il partito 
Repubblicano e fondato il partito delle alci del Bull "o del 
progressive". Mentre tutti e quattro i candidati hanno fatto 
appello direttamente agli elettori della classe operaia, di cui i voti
dimostrerebbero decisivo, di gran lunga la piattaforma più radicale 
nella campagna era quella del nominee del partito socialista, Eugene 
V. Debs. Funzionando per il tempo di quarto, Debs ha 
richiesto per l'abolizione del capitalismo piuttosto che la relativa 
riforma. In questo discorso che accetta la nomina del partito ha
affermato il partito socialista "il partito di progresso, il partito 
del futuro." Debs ha rifinito l'ultima volta nel concorso, 
ricevente 900.000 voti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1912, τέσσερις υποψήφιοι μάχονταν για να γίνουν 
Πρόεδρος των Ηνωμένων Πολιτειών. Δημοκρατικός επιβεβλημένος
William Howard Taft και δημοκράτης Woodrow Wilson, 
ένας μέτριος κυβερνήτης, αντιπροσώπευσε τα δύο σημαντικά 
συμβαλλόμενα μέρη. Ο προηγούμενος Πρόεδρος Theodore 
Roosevelt, που θυμώθηκε πέρα από αυτό που αισθάνθηκε ήταν μια
προδοσία των πολιτικών του από Taft, ο μαζεμμένος με το χέρι 
διάδοχός του, εγκατέλειψε το δημοκρατικό κόμμα και ίδρυσε το 
προοδευτικό ή συμβαλλόμενο μέρος "αλκών του Bull". Ενώ 
και οι τέσσερις υποψήφιοι απευθύνθηκαν άμεσα στους ψηφοφόρους 
εργατικών τάξεων, οι των οποίων ψηφοφορίες θα αποδεικνύονταν 
αποφασιστικές, κατά πολύ η ριζικότερη πλατφόρμα στην εκστρατεία 
ήταν αυτή του σοσιαλιστικού υποψηφίου συμβαλλόμενου μέρους, 
Eugene Θ*Β. Debs. Τρέχοντας για την τέταρτη φορά, 
Debs απαίτησε για την κατάργηση της κεφαλαιοκρατίας παρά τη 
μεταρρύθμισή του. Σε αυτήν την ομιλία που αποδέχεται το 
διορισμό του συμβαλλόμενου μέρους πιστοποίησε το Σοσιαλιστικό 
Κόμμα "το συμβαλλόμενο μέρος της προόδου, το συμβαλλόμενο μέρος 
του μέλλοντος." Το Debs τελείωσε στο τέλος στο 
διαγωνισμό, που λαμβάνει 900.000 ψήφους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1912, cuatro candidatos lucharon para hacer 
presidente de los Estados Unidos. El titular republicano 
Guillermo Howard Taft y demócrata Woodrow Wilson, un gobernador 
moderado, representó los dos partidos principales. Presidente 
anterior Theodore Roosevelt, encolerizado sobre lo que él se sentía 
era una traición de sus políticas de Taft, su sucesor recogido a 
mano, abandonó el partido republicano y fundado el partido de los 
alces del progresista o "de Bull". Mientras que los cuatro 
candidatos abrogaron directamente a los votantes de la clase obrera, 
que votos probarían decisivo, en gran medida la plataforma más 
radical de la campaña era la del candidato del partido socialista, 
Eugene V. Debs. Ejecutándose para la cuarta vez, Debs llamó 
para la abolición del capitalismo más bien que para su reforma. 
En este discurso que validaba el nombramiento del partido él 
proclamó el partido socialista "el partido del progreso, el partido 
del futuro." Debs acabó por último en la competencia, 
recibiendo 900.000 votos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086062</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107609</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/debs-attacks-the-monstrous-system-of-capitalism</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
