<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105833</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105833</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206529</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Old Courthouse in St. Louis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Altes Gericht in St. Louis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Vieux tribunal à St Louis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Tribunal velho em St. Louis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Vecchio courthouse a St. Louis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παλαιό δικαστήριο στο ST Louis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Viejo palacio de justicia en St. Louis</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is exhibit about a place which, throughout the 19th century, served not only as a house of justice, but also as a public gathering place for pioneers planning their westward trek across the plains. Its iron-framed dome was the forerunner of many similar domes erected on government buildings throughout the country. The site contains maps, readings, photos, drawings, as well as a guide for doing a student project.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist Ausstellung über einen Platz, der, während 
des 19. Jahrhunderts, nicht nur als Haus von Gerechtigkeit diente, 
aber auch als allgemeiner erfassenplatz für die Pioniere, die ihren 
nach Westen gerichteten Trek über den Ebenen planen. Seine 
Eisen-gestaltete Haube war der Vorläufer vieler ähnlicher Hauben, 
die auf Regierung Gebäuden in dem Land aufgerichtet wurden. Die
Site enthält Karten, Messwerte, Fotos, Zeichnungen, sowie eine 
Anleitung für das Tun eines Kursteilnehmerprojektes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est l'objet exposé au sujet d'un endroit qui, tout
au long du 19ème siècle, a servi non seulement de maison de justice,
mais également comme endroit sourcilleux public pour des pionniers 
projetant leur voyage à l'ouest à travers les plaines. Son 
dôme fer-encadré était le précurseur de beaucoup de dômes 
semblables érigés sur des bâtiments de gouvernement dans tout le 
pays. Le site contient des cartes, lectures, photos, schémas, 
comme un guide pour faire un projet d'étudiant.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é a exibição sobre um lugar que, durante todo o 
1ø século, sirva não somente como uma casa da justiça, mas também
como um lugar de recolhimento público para os pioneiros que planeiam 
seu trek na direcção ocidental através das planícies. Sua 
abóbada ferro-moldada era o precursor de muitas abóbadas similares 
erigidas em edifícios do governo durante todo o país. O local 
contem mapas, leituras, fotos, desenhos, assim como uma guia para 
fazer um projeto do estudante.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è l'esposizione circa un posto che, durante il 
diciannovesimo secolo, ha servito non soltanto da casa di giustizia, 
ma anche come posto riuniscente pubblico per i pionieri che 
progettano il loro viaggio westward attraverso le pianure. La 
relativa cupola ferro-incorniciata era il precursore di molte cupole 
simili erette sulle costruzioni di governo durante il paese. Il 
luogo contiene i programmi, le letture, le foto, illustrazioni, come 
pure una guida per fare un progetto dell'allievo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι έκθεμα για μια θέση που, καθ' όλη τη διάρκεια 
του 19$ου αιώνα, εχρησίμευσε όχι μόνο ως σπίτι της δικαιοσύνης, 
αλλά και ως μια δημόσια θέση συλλογής για τους πρωτοπόρους που 
προγραμματίζουν το δυτικό ταξίδι τους στις πεδιάδες. Ο 
σίδηρος-πλαισιωμένος θόλος του ήταν ο πρόδρομος πολλών 
παρόμοιων θόλων που δημιουργήθηκαν στα κυβερνητικά κτήρια σε όλη
τη χώρα. Η περιοχή περιέχει τους χάρτες, τις αναγνώσεις, 
τις φωτογραφίες, τα σχέδια, καθώς επίσης και έναν οδηγό για να 
κάνει ένα πρόγραμμα σπουδαστών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es el objeto expuesto sobre un lugar que, a través
del diecinueveavo siglo, sirvió no solamente como casa de la 
justicia, pero también como lugar de acopio público para los 
pioneros que planean sus que va hacia el oeste emigran a 
través de los llanos. Su bóveda hierro-enmarcada era el 
precursor de muchas bóvedas similares erigidas en edificios del 
gobierno a través del país. El sitio contiene las 
correspondencias, lecturas, fotos, gráficos, tan bien como una guía 
para hacer un proyecto del estudiante.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206529</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105833</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/old-courthouse-in-st-louis</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
