<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/244418547</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>244418547</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206204</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Exploring the Nanoworld Teaching Modules</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erforschen der Nanoworld unterrichtenden Module</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Explorer les modules d'enseignement de Nanoworld</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Explorando os módulos ensinando de Nanoworld</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Esplorazione dei moduli d'istruzione di Nanoworld</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Να ερευνήσει τις ενότητες διδασκαλίας Nanoworld</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Explorar los módulos de enseñanza de Nanoworld</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Helps teachers incorporate nanotechnology into high school chemistry and middle school technology classes. High school modules explore x-ray diffraction and scanning probe microscopy, shape-memory alloys, light emitting diodes, and ferrofluid. Middle school modules examine magnetism, memory metals, and How we can 'see' what we cannot see. Modules include overviews, curriculum suggestions, lesson plans, guided notes, experiments, and assessments.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hilfen Lehrer enthalten nanotechnology in High 
School Chemie und in Technologiekategorien der mittleren Schule. 
High School Module erforschen Röntgenstrahlbeugung- und 
-abtastungprüfspitze Mikroskopie, Form-Speicher Legierungen, 
lichtemittierende Dioden und ferrofluid. Module der mittleren 
Schule überprüfen Magnetismus, Speichermetalle und wie wir Dose ' 
sehen ', was wir nicht sehen können. Module schließen 
Überblicke, Lehrplanvorschläge, Lektionpläne, geführte 
Anmerkungen, Experimente und Einschätzungen ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les professeurs d'aides incorporent le 
nanotechnology à la chimie de lycée et aux classes de technologie de
collège. Les modules de lycée explorent la microscopie de 
sonde de diffraction et de lecture de rayon X, les alliages de 
forme-mémoire, les diodes luminescentes, et le ferrofluid. Les 
modules de collège examinent le magnétisme, des métaux de mémoire,
et comment nous bidon 'voyons 'ce que nous ne pouvons pas voir. 
Les modules incluent des vues d'ensemble, des suggestions de 
programme d'études, des plans de leçon, des notes guidées, des 
expériences, et des évaluations.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os professores das ajudas incorporam o 
nanotechnology no chemistry da High School e nas classes da tecnologia
da escola média. Os módulos da High School exploram o 
microscopy da ponta de prova do diffraction e da exploração de raio 
X, as ligas da forma-memória, a luz que emitem-se diodos, e o 
ferrofluid. Os módulos da escola média examinam o magnetismo, 
metais da memória, e como nós lata ' vemos ' o que nós não podemos
ver. Os módulos incluem vistas gerais, sugestões do 
curriculum, plantas da lição, notas guiadas, experiências, e 
avaliações.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli insegnanti di aiuti incorporano il 
nanotechnology in chimica della High School e nei codici categoria di 
tecnologia della scuola centrale. I moduli della High School 
esplorano la microscopia della sonda di diffrazione e di esame di 
raggi X, le leghe di figura-memoria, i diodi luminescenti ed il 
ferrofluid. I moduli della scuola centrale esaminano il 
magnetismo, metalli di memoria e come latta 'vediamo 'che cosa non 
possiamo vedere. I moduli includono le descrizioni, i 
suggerimenti di programma di studi, i programmi di lezione, le note 
guidate, gli esperimenti e le valutazioni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βοηθά τους δασκάλους να ενσωματώσουν τη νανοτεχνολογία
στη χημεία γυμνασίου και τις μέσες κλάσεις σχολικής τεχνολογίας.
Οι ενότητες γυμνασίου ερευνούν την των ακτίνων X 
διάθλαση και τη μικροσκόπηση ελέγχων ανίχνευσης, κράματα 
μορφή-μνήμης, φως που εκπέμπει τις διόδους, και ferrofluid. 
Οι μέσες σχολικές ενότητες εξετάζουν το μαγνητισμό, 
μέταλλα μνήμης, και πώς μπορούμε "να δούμε" τι δεν 
μπορούμε να δούμε. Οι ενότητες περιλαμβάνουν τις 
επισκοπήσεις, προτάσεις προγράμματος σπουδών, σχέδια μαθήματος, 
καθοδηγημένες σημειώσεις, πειραματίζονται, και αξιολογήσεις.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los profesores de las ayudas incorporan 
nanotechnology en química de la High School secundaria y clases de la
tecnología de la escuela media. Los módulos de la High School 
secundaria exploran microscopia de la punta de prueba de la 
difracción y de la exploración de radiografía, las aleaciones de la
dimensio'n de una variable-memoria, los diodos electroluminosos, y el 
ferrofluid. Los módulos de la escuela media examinan 
magnetismo, los metales de la memoria, y cómo lata ' vemos ' qué no 
podemos ver. Los módulos incluyen descripciones, sugerencias 
del plan de estudios, planes de la lección, notas dirigidas, 
experimentos, y gravámenes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206204</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>244418547</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/exploring-the-nanoworld-teaching-modules</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
