<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107760</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107760</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206596</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Paterson, New Jersey: America's Silk City</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Paterson, Neu-Jersey: Amerikas Silk Stadt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Paterson, New Jersey : La Ville En soie de 
l'Amérique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Paterson, Novo-Jersey: Cidade De seda De 
América</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Paterson, Nuovo-Jersey: Città Di seta 
Dell'America</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Paterson, Νιου Τζέρσεϋ: Πόλη μεταξιού της 
Αμερικής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Paterson, Nuevo-Jersey: Ciudad De seda De 
América</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">examines conditions that led to the famous 1913 strike in a city that produced nearly half the U.S.'s manufactured silk. Conflicts between labor and management increased in the U.S. during the early 20th century. In Paterson, on January 27, 1913, when Henry Doherty tried to extend a new four-loom system throughout his plant, 800 silk weavers walked out. More than 20,000 Paterson silk workers took part in the strike, which lasted over five months.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">überprüft Bedingungen, die das zu den berühmten
Schlag 1913 in einer Stadt führte, die fast Hälfte der hergestellte 
Seide US produzierte. Cuberschneidungen zwischen Arbeits- und 
Management erhöhten sich der VEREINIGTEN STAATEN während des frühen
20. Jahrhunderts. In Paterson an Januar 27, 1913, als Henry 
Doherty versuchte, ein neues Vierwebstuhl System in seinem Betrieb 
auszudehnen, gingen 800 silk Weber heraus. Mehr als 20.000 
Paterson silk Arbeiter nahmen am Schlag teil, der über fünf Monaten 
dauerte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">examine des conditions que cela a menées à la 
grève 1913 célèbre dans une ville qui a produit presque la moitié 
de la soie construite des États-Unis. Les conflits entre 
partenaires sociaux ont augmenté aux ETATS-UNIS pendant le début du 
20ème siècle. Dans Paterson, 27 janvier 1913, quand Henry 
Doherty a essayé d'étendre un nouveau système de quatre-manche dans
toute son usine, 800 tisserands en soie ont marché dehors. Plus
de 20.000 ouvriers en soie de Paterson ont participé à la grève, 
qui a duré plus de cinq mois.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">examina circunstâncias que isso conduziu à 
batida 1913 famosa em uma cidade que produzisse quase a metade da seda
manufaturada dos E. U.. Os conflitos entre labor e a gerência 
aumentaram nos ESTADOS UNIDOS durante o 20o século adiantado. 
Em Paterson, janeiro em 27, 1913, quando o Henry Doherty tentou 
estender um sistema novo do quatro-tear durante todo sua planta, 800 
weavers de seda andaram para fora. Mais de 20.000 trabalhadores 
de seda de Paterson fizeram exame da parte na batida, que durou sobre 
cinco meses.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esamina le circostanze che quello ha condotto al 
colpo famoso 1913 in una città che ha prodotto quasi la metà della 
seta prodotta degli Stati Uniti. I conflitti fra il lavoro
e la gestione sono aumentato in STATI UNITI durante l'inizio del 
20esimo secolo. In Paterson, il 27 gennaio 1913, quando il henry
Doherty ha provato ad estendere un nuovo sistema del quattro-telaio 
durante la sua pianta, 800 tessitori di seta hanno camminato fuori. 
Più di 20.000 operai di seta di Paterson hanno partecipato al 
colpo, che ha durato oltre cinque mesi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει τους όρους ότι οδηγημένος στη διάσημη 
απεργία του 1913 σε μια πόλη που παρήγαγε το σχεδόν μισό 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ κατασκευασμένο μετάξι. Οι συγκρούσεις μεταξύ της
εργασίας και της διαχείρισης αυξήθηκαν στις ΗΠΑ κατά τη διάρκεια 
του πρόωρου 20ού αιώνα. Σε Paterson, στις 27 
Ιανουαρίου ..1913, όταν προσπάθησε να επεκτείνει Henry 
Doherty ένα νέο σύστημα τέσσερις-αργαλειών σε όλες τις 
εγκαταστάσεις του, 800 υφαντές μεταξιού περπάτησαν έξω. 
Περισσότεροι από 20.000 εργαζόμενοι μεταξιού Paterson 
συμμετείχαν στην απεργία, η οποία διάρκεσε πάνω από πέντε 
μήνες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">examina condiciones que eso condujo a la huelga 
famosa 1913 en una ciudad que produjo casi la mitad de la seda 
fabricada de los E.E.U.U.. Los conflictos entre de trabajo y la 
gerencia aumentaron de los ESTADOS UNIDOS durante el vigésimo siglo 
temprano. En Paterson, 27 de enero de 1913, cuando el Henrio 
Doherty intentó extender un nuevo sistema del cuatro-telar a través 
de su planta, 800 tejedores de seda recorrieron hacia fuera. 
Más de 20.000 trabajadores de seda de Paterson participaron en 
la huelga, que duró sobre cinco meses.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206596</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107760</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/paterson-new-jersey-americas-silk-city</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
