<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106756</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106756</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206580</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">History &amp; Culture</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geschichte U. Kultur</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Histoire et Culture</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">History &amp; Cultura</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Storia &amp; Coltura</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ιστορία &amp; πολιτισμός</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Historia Y Cultura</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">offers educators Park Service resources that help teach about our nation's cultural heritage, and which look at how the NPS is protecting and preserving them. Subjects include archaeology, historic buildings and structures, mapping, military history, and national historic landmarks. The resources may be in the form of learning programs, case studies, lesson plans, teachers' handbooks, and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">bietet Erziehern Park-Service-Betriebsmittel an, 
die helfen, über kulturelles Erbe unserer Nation zu unterrichten, und
welche Blick auf, wie das NPS ist, konservierend schützend und sie. 
Themen schließen Archäologie, historische Gebäude und 
Strukturen, Diagramm, militärische Geschichte und nationale 
historische Grenzsteine ein. Die Betriebsmittel können in Form 
von Lernprogrammen, Fallstudien, Lektionplänen, Handbüchern der 
Lehrer und mehr sein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">offre à des éducateurs les ressources de service
de parc qui aident à enseigner au sujet du acquis culturel de notre 
nation, et quel regard à la façon dont le NPS est les protégeant et
préservant. Les sujets incluent l'archéologie, les bâtiments 
et les structures historiques, tracer, l'histoire militaire, et les 
bornes limites historiques nationales. Les ressources peuvent 
être sous forme de programmes d'étude, d'études de cas, de plans de
leçon, de manuels des professeurs, et de plus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">oferece a educadores os recursos do serviço do 
parque que ajudam ensinar sobre o heritage cultural da nossa nação, 
e quais olhar em como o NPS é protegendo e preservando os. Os 
assuntos incluem o archaeology, edifícios e estruturas historic, 
traçar, history militar, e marcos historic nacionais. Os 
recursos podem estar no formulário de programas de aprendizagem, de 
estudos de caso, de plantas da lição, de manuais dos professores, e 
de mais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">offre ad educatori le risorse di servizio del 
parco che contribuiscono ad insegnare circa l'eredità culturale della
nostra nazione e quale sguardo a come il NPS è proteggente lei e 
conservante. Gli oggetti includono il archaeology, costruzioni e
strutture storiche, tracciare, storia militare e limiti storici 
nazionali. Le risorse possono essere sotto forma d'i programmi 
imparanti, le inchieste, i programmi di lezione, i manuali degli 
insegnanti e più.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">προσφέρει τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς υπηρεσιών πάρκων 
εκπαιδευτικών που βοηθούν να διδάξουν για την πολιτιστική 
κληρονομιά του έθνους μας, και που εξετάζουν το πώς το NPS τα 
προστατεύει και συντηρεί. Τα θέματα περιλαμβάνουν την 
αρχαιολογία, τα ιστορικές κτήρια και τις δομές, τη χαρτογράφηση, 
τη στρατιωτική ιστορία, και τα εθνικά ιστορικά ορόσημα. Τα 
στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς μπορούν να είναι υπό μορφή εκμάθησης των 
προγραμμάτων, των περιπτωσιολογικών μελετών, των σχεδίων 
μαθήματος, των εγχειριδίων των δασκάλων, και περισσότερων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece a educadores los recursos del servicio del 
parque que ayudan a enseñar sobre el patrimonio cultural de nuestra 
nación, y cuáles mirada en cómo el NPS es de protección y que 
ellos preserva de. Los temas incluyen archaeology, los edificios
y las estructuras históricas, el asociar, historia militar, y las 
señales históricas nacionales. Los recursos pueden estar en la
forma de programas que aprenden, de estudios de caso, de planes de la 
lección, de los manuales de los profesores, y más.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206580</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106756</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/history-culture</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
