<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108361</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108361</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205328</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">You Decide: Should physician-assisted suicide be legal in the United States?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sie Entscheiden: Sollte Arzt-unterstützter 
Selbstmord in den Vereinigten Staaten zugelassen sein?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Vous Décidez : Le suicide médecin-aidé 
devrait-il être légal aux Etats-Unis ?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Você Decide-se: Deve o suicide 
médico-ajudado ser legal nos estados unidos?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Decidete: Dovrebbe il suicide medico-aiutato
essere legale in unito Dichiara?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αποφασίζετε: Θα έπρεπε η παθολόγος-βοηθημένη 
αυτοκτονία να είναι νομικός στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες;</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Usted Decide: ¿Debe el suicidio 
me'dico-asistido ser legal en los Estados Unidos?</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This educational guide focuses on euthanasia and related issues such as physician-assisted suicide (PAS) and mercy killing. Students are invited to examine the arguments on both sides of the debate, develop, critical thinking skills as they work through the activities, and learn how to support their arguments with evidence and reason. It is expected that at the end of this guide students will determine where they stand on this controversial issue.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese pädagogische Anleitung konzentriert auf Euthanasie 
und in Verbindung stehende Ausgaben wie Arzt-unterstützte Tötung des
Selbstmords (PAS) und der Gnade. Kursteilnehmer werden 
eingeladen, die Argumente auf beiden Seiten der Debatte, sich zu 
entwickeln, der kritischen denkenden Fähigkeiten zu überprüfen, 
während sie durch die Aktivitäten arbeiten, und erlernen, wie man 
ihre Argumente mit Beweis und Grund unterstützt. Es wird 
erwartet, daß am Ende dieser Anleitung Kursteilnehmer feststellen, wo
sie zu diesem umstrittenen Punkt stehen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce guide éducatif se concentre sur l'euthanasie et les 
questions relatives telles que le massacre médecin-aidé du suicide 
(PAS) et de la pitié. Des étudiants sont invités à examiner 
les arguments des deux côtés de la discussion, se développer, des 
qualifications de pensée critiques pendant qu'ils travaillent par les
activités, et apprennent comment supporter leurs arguments avec 
l'évidence et la raison. On s'attend à ce qu'à l'extrémité 
de ce guide les étudiants déterminent où ils se tiennent sur cette 
question controversée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta guia educacional focaliza no euthanasia e em 
edições relacionadas tais como a matança médico-ajudada do suicide
(PAS) e da mercê. Os estudantes são convidados examinar os 
argumentos em ambos os lados do debate, para tornar-se, de habilidades
pensando críticas enquanto trabalham com as atividades, e aprendem 
como suportar seus argumentos com evidência e razão. Espera-se
que na extremidade desta guia os estudantes determinarão onde estão 
nesta edição controversa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa guida educativa mette a fuoco su euthanasia e sulle
edizioni relative quale l'uccisione medico-aiutata di suicide (PAS) e 
di misericordia. Gli allievi sono invitati ad esaminare gli 
argomenti da entrambi i lati del dibattito, svilupparsi, delle 
abilità pensanti critiche mentre lavorano con le attività ed 
imparano come sostenere i loro argomenti con prova e motivo. È 
previsto che all'estremità di questa guida allievi determinino dove 
si levano in piedi su questa edizione discutibile.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο εκπαιδευτικός οδηγός εστιάζει στην ευθανασία 
και τα σχετικά ζητήματα όπως η παθολόγος-βοηθημένη δολοφονία 
αυτοκτονίας (pas) και ελέους. Οι σπουδαστές καλούνται για
να εξετάσουν τα ορίσματα και στις δύο πλευρές της συζήτησης, να 
αναπτυχθούν, κρίσιμες δεξιότητες σκέψης όπως λειτουργούν μέσω 
των δραστηριοτήτων, και μαθαίνουν πώς να υποστηρίξουν τα 
ορίσματά τους με τα στοιχεία και το λόγο. Αναμένεται ότι 
στο τέλος αυτού του οδηγού οι σπουδαστές θα καθορίσουν όπου 
στέκονται σε αυτό το αμφισβητούμενο ζήτημα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta guía educativa se centra en euthanasia y ediciones 
relacionadas tales como matanza me'dico-asistida del suicidio (PAS) y 
de la misericordia. Se invita que examinen los argumentos en 
ambas caras del discusión, convertirse, de habilidades de pensamiento
críticas como trabajan con las actividades, y aprenden a los 
estudiantes cómo utilizar sus argumentos con evidencia y razón. 
Se espera que en el extremo de esta guía los estudiantes se 
determinen dónde están parados en esta edición polémica.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205328</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108361</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/you-decide-should-physician-assisted-suicide-be-legal-in-the-united-states</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
