<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107927</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107927</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086835</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Slumming Among the Unemployed: William Wycoff Studies Joblessness in the 1890s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Slumming unter den Arbeitslosen: William 
Wycoff studiert Joblessness im 1890s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Slumming parmi les chômeurs : William 
Wycoff étudie le chômage dans le 1890s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Slumming entre os desempregados: William 
Wycoff estuda o joblessness no 1890s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Slumming fra i disoccupati: William Wycoff 
studia il joblessness nel 1890s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Slumming μεταξύ των ανέργων: Θ*Ωηλληαμ 
Wycoff Studies Joblessness στο 1890s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Slumming entre los parados: Guillermo Wycoff
estudia desempleo en el 1890s</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Even before the 1890s depression struck with devastating force in 1893, large numbers of jobless men and women competed in tight labor markets and faced homelessness. One of the best first-hand descriptions of "what it is to look for work and fail to find it" comes from political economist Walter Wycoff's two-volume study of  The Workers: An Experiment in Reality , first published in 1899. Wycoff had abandoned his studies at Princeton to seek a more concrete appreciation of social problems. His record of his two years spent as a common laborer became an early classic of sociological writing.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sogar bevor der Tiefstand 1890s mit verheerender 
Kraft 1893 anschlug, konkurrierten viele arbeitslose Männer und 
Frauen in den festen Arbeitsmarkt und stellten Heimatlosigkeit 
gegenüber. Eine der besten aus erster Hand bezogenen 
Beschreibungen von ", was sie ist, nach Arbeit zu suchen und 
Ausfallen, zum sie zu finden" politischen von der 
Wirtschaftswissenschaftler Walter Wycoffs Zweidatenträger Studie der 
Arbeiter kommt: Ein Experiment in der Wirklichkeit, zuerst 
veröffentlicht 1899. Wycoff hatte seine Studien bei Princeton 
verlassen, um eine konkretere Anerkennung von Sozialproblemen zu 
suchen. Sein Satz seiner zwei Jahre, die als gemeiner 
Hilfsarbeiter verbracht wurden, wurde ein früher Klassiker des 
soziologischen Schreibens.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Même avant que la dépression 1890s a frappé 
avec la force dévastatrice en 1893, un grand nombre d'hommes et de 
femmes sans emploi ont concurrencé sur les marchés du travail 
serrés et ont fait face au phénomène des sans-abri. Une des meilleures 
descriptions de première main de "ce qui est elle pour rechercher le 
travail et l'échouer pour le trouver" vient de l'étude de 
deux-volume de Walter Wycoff politique d'économiste des ouvriers : 
Une expérience en réalité, d'abord édité en 1899. 
Wycoff avait abandonné ses études chez Princeton pour 
rechercher une appréciation plus concrète des problèmes sociaux. 
Son enregistrement de ses deux années passées en tant que 
travailleur commun est devenu un classique tôt de l'écriture 
sociologique.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Mesmo antes que o depression 1890s golpeou com 
força devastating em 1893, um grande número homens e mulheres 
jobless competiram em mercados labor apertados e enfrentaram o 
homelessness. Uma das mais melhores descrições first-hand de 
"o que é procurar o trabalho e a falha para o encontrar" vem do 
estudo do dois-volume de Walter Wycoff político do economista dos 
trabalhadores: Uma experiência na realidade, publicada 
primeiramente em 1899. Wycoff tinha abandonado seus estudos em 
Princeton para procurar uma apreciação mais concreta de problemas 
sociais. Seu registro de seus dois anos gastados como um laborer
comum transformou-se um clássico adiantado da escrita sociological.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Anche prima che la depressione 1890s colpisca con 
forza devastating in 1893, tantissimi uomini e donne senza lavoro 
hanno competuto nei mercati di lavoro stretti ed hanno affrontato il 
homelessness. Una delle descrizioni di prima mano migliori di 
"che cosa è cercare il lavoro ed il venire a mancare per trovarlo" 
viene dallo studio del due-volume di Walter Wycoff politico 
dell'economista degli operai: Un esperimento in realtà, in 
primo luogo pubblicato in 1899. Wycoff aveva abbandonato i suoi 
studi a Princeton per cercare un apprezzamento più concreto dei 
problemi sociali. Il suo record dei suoi due anni 
spesi come laborer comune si è transformato in in un 
classico in anticipo di scrittura sociologica.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ακόμη και πριν από την κατάθλιψη 1890s που 
χτυπήθηκε με την καταστρεπτική δύναμη το 1893, οι μεγάλοι 
αριθμοί άνεργων ανδρών και γυναικών ανταγωνίστηκαν στις σφιχτές 
αγορές εργασίας και αντιμετώπισαν την έλλειψη στέγης. Μια 
από τις καλύτερες από πρώτο χέρι περιγραφές "τι πρόκειται να 
ψάξει την εργασία και να αποτύχει να το βρεί" προέρχεται από την
πολιτική walter Wycoff's οικονομολόγων μελέτη δύο-έντασης 
του ήχου των εργαζομένων: Ένα πείραμα στην πραγματικότητα, 
που δημοσιεύθηκε πρώτα σε 1899, Wycoff είχε εγκαταλείψει τις
μελέτες του σε Princeton για να επιδιώξει μια πιό συγκεκριμένη 
εκτίμηση των κοινωνικών προβλημάτων. Το αρχείο δύο ετών 
του του που ξοδεύτηκαν ως κοινό laborer έγινε ένας πρόωρος 
κλασικός του κοινωνιολογικού γραψίματος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Incluso antes de que la depresión 1890s pulso con
la fuerza devastadora en 1893, una gran cantidad de hombres y de 
mujeres desempleados compitieron en mercados de trabajo apretados e 
hicieron frente a falta de vivienda. Una de las mejores descripciones 
de primera mano de "cuáles es buscar el trabajo y el fall para 
encontrarlo" viene del estudio del dos-volumen de Walter Wycoff 
político del economista de los trabajadores: Un experimento en 
la realidad, primero publicada en 1899. Wycoff había abandonado
sus estudios en Princeton para buscar un aprecio más concreto de 
problemas sociales. Su expediente de sus dos años pasados como 
laborer común se convirtió en una obra clásica temprana de la 
escritura sociológica.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086835</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107927</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/slumming-among-the-unemployed-william-wycoff-studies-joblessness-in-the-1890s</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
