<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107005</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107005</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086713</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Outside Looking In: Byington on Homestead's Women</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Außenseite, die In Schaut: Byington auf 
Frauen des Gehöfts</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Extérieur Regardant Dans : Byington sur les
femmes de la ferme</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Parte externa Que Olha Em: Byington em 
mulheres do homestead</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Parte esterna Che Osserva In: Byington sulle
donne della fattoria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εξωτερικό που κοιτάζει σε: Byington στις 
γυναίκες του αγροτικού σπιτιού</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Exterior Que mira En: Byington en las 
mujeres de la granja</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1892, Homestead, Pennsylvania, was the site of one of the most dramatic strikes in U.S. history. The Carnegie Steel Company's ultimate victory resulted in the destruction of a once-powerful union of skilled iron and steel workers. By 1907, almost 7,000 workers toiled at the Homestead plant for the U.S. Steel Corporation. In 1907-1908, the Russell Sage Foundation undertook an intensive study that attempted to understand the dramatic changes that had reshaped Homestead and other industrial communities. The resulting six-volume report, written by progressive social reformers, included Margaret Byington's  Homestead: The Households of a Mill Town , first published in 1910. This excerpt from Byington's study depicted work and home life for the immigrant women of Homestead. Byington's account, while sympathetic to the immigrants who comprised the bulk of the steel town's labor force, was written from the perspective of an outsider. She emphasized women's limited participation in the paid labor force in steel mill towns like Homestead, yet she provided repeated testimony regarding the multiple economic and social roles of women in Homestead as managers of family finances and family relationships.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1892 war Gehöft, Pennsylvania, die Site von einem
der drastischsten Schläge in der VEREINIGTE STAATEN Geschichte. 
Der Carnegie entscheidende Sieg des Stahlwerkes ergab die 
Zerstörung eines sobald-leistungsfähigen Anschlußes der erfahrenen 
Eisen- und Stahlarbeiter. Bis zum 1907 plagten fast 
7.000 Arbeiter am Gehöftbetrieb für die VEREINIGTEN STAATEN Steel 
Corporation ab. 1907-1908 nahm sich die Russell Sage Grundlage 
eine intensive Studie auf, die versuchte, die drastischen Änderungen 
zu verstehen, die Gehöft und andere industrielle Gemeinschaften 
umgestaltet hatten. Der resultierende Sechsdatenträger Report, 
geschrieben von den progressiven SozialReformern, enthielt 
Margaret Byingtons Gehöft: Die Haushalte einer 
Tausendstel-Stadt, zuerst veröffentlicht 1910. Dieses Excerpt 
von Byingtons Studie bildlich dargestellter Arbeit und 
Hauptlebensdauer für die einwandernden Frauen des Gehöfts. 
Konto Byingtons, wenn sympatisch zu den Immigranten, die den 
Hauptteil von den StahlArbeitskräften der stadt enthielten, wurde von
der Perspektive eines Außenseiters geschrieben. Sie hob 
begrenzte Teilnahme der Frauen an den zahlenden Arbeitskräften in den
Stahltausendstelstädten wie Gehöft hervor, dennoch stellte sie 
wiederholte das Zeugnis betreffend ist die mehrfachen ökonomischen 
und Sozialrollen der Frauen im Gehöft während Manager der Familie 
Finanzen und der Familie Verhältnisse zur Verfügung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1892, la ferme, Pennsylvanie, était le site 
d'une des grèves les plus excessives dans l'histoire des ETATS-UNIS. 
La victoire finale de l'aciérie de Carnegie a eu comme 
conséquence la destruction d'une union une fois-puissante de fer 
habile et des ouvriers en acier. D'ici 1907, presque 7.000 
ouvriers travaillent fort à l'usine de ferme pour les ETATS-UNIS 
Steel Corporation. En 1907-1908, la base sage de Russell a 
entrepris une étude intensive qui a essayé de comprendre les 
changements excessifs qui avaient restructuré la ferme et d'autres 
communautés industrielles. L'état résultant de six-volume, 
écrit par les réformateurs sociaux progressifs, a inclus la ferme de 
Margaret Byington : Les ménages d'une ville de moulin, 
d'abord édités en 1910. Cet extrait du travail représenté 
par étude de Byington et vie à la maison pour les femmes immigrées 
de la ferme. Le compte de Byington, tandis que sympathique aux 
immigrés qui ont comporté le volume de la main-d'oeuvre de la ville 
en acier, a été écrit de la perspective d'un étranger. Elle 
a souligné la participation limitée des femmes à la main-d'oeuvre 
payée dans des villes d'aciérie comme la ferme, pourtant elle a 
fourni a répété le témoignage concernant les rôles économiques 
et sociaux multiples des femmes dans la ferme pendant que des 
gestionnaires des finances de famille et des rapports de famille.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1892, o homestead, Pensilvânia, era o local de
uma das batidas as mais dramáticas no history de ESTADOS UNIDOS. 
A vitória final de companhia de aço de Carnegie resultou na 
destruição de uma união uma vez que-poderosa de ferro hábil e dos 
trabalhadores de aço. Por 1907, quase 7.000 trabalhadores 
labutam na planta do homestead para os ESTADOS UNIDOS Aço 
Corporation. Em 1907-1908, a fundação prudente de Russell 
empreendeu um estudo intensive que tentasse compreender as mudanças 
dramáticas que reshaped o homestead e outras comunidades industriais.
O relatório resultante do seis-volume, escrito por reformers 
sociais progressivos, incluiu o homestead de Margaret Byington: 
As casas de uma cidade do moinho, publicadas primeiramente em 
1910. Este excerpt do trabalho descrito estudo de Byington e 
vida home para as mulheres immigrant do homestead. O cliente de 
Byington, quando sympathetic aos immigrants que compreenderam o volume
da força labor da cidade de aço, foi escrito do perspective de um 
outsider. Emfatizou a participação limitada das mulheres na 
força labor paga em cidades do moinho de aço como o homestead, 
contudo forneceu repetiu o testimony a respeito dos papéis 
econômicos e sociais múltiplos das mulheres no homestead enquanto 
gerentes de finanças da família e de relacionamentos da família.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1892, la fattoria, Pensilvania, era il luogo di
uno dei colpi più drammatici nella storia degli STATI UNITI. 
Vittoria dell'acciaieria di Carnegie l'ultima ha provocato la 
distruzione di un'unione una volta che-potente nei dei lavoratori 
dell'industria siderurgica esperti e del ferro. Entro 1907, 
quasi 7.000 operai lavorano duramente nella pianta della fattoria per 
gli STATI UNITI Steel Corporation. In 1907-1908, il fondamento 
prudente di Russell ha intrapreso uno studio intenso che ha tentato di
capire i cambiamenti drammatici che avevano rimodellato la fattoria ed
altre Comunità industriali. Il rapporto risultante del 
sei-volume, scritto dai reformers sociali progressivi, ha incluso la 
fattoria di Margaret Byington: Le famiglie di una città del 
laminatoio, in primo luogo pubblicate in 1910. Questo brano dal 
lavoro rappresentato studio del Byington e vita domestica per le donne
immigrate della fattoria. Il cliente del Byington, mentre 
simpatico agli immigranti che hanno contenuto la massa la forza 
di lavoro della città d'acciaio, è stato scritto dalla prospettiva 
di uno straniero. Ha dato risalto alla partecipazione limitata 
delle donne alla forza di lavoro paid nelle città dell'acciaieria 
come la fattoria, tuttavia ha fornito ha ripetuto la testimonianza per
quanto riguarda i ruoli economici e sociali multipli delle donne in 
fattoria mentre gestori delle finanze della famiglia e dei rapporti 
della famiglia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1892, το αγροτικό σπίτι, Πενσυλβανία, ήταν η 
περιοχή μια από τις πιό δραματικές απεργίες στην ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ 
ιστορία. Η τελευταία νίκη της επιχείρησης χάλυβα 
Carnegie οδήγησε στην καταστροφή μιας μόλις-ισχυρής ένωσης των
ειδικευμένων εργαζομένων σιδήρου και χάλυβα. Μέχρι το 
1907, σχεδόν 7.000 εργαζόμενοι κοπίασαν στις εγκαταστάσεις 
αγροτικών σπιτιών για την εταιρία ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΥ χάλυβα. Το 
1907-1908, ο Russell Sage Foundation ανέλαβε μια 
εντατική μελέτη που προσπάθησε να καταλάβει τις δραματικές 
αλλαγές που είχαν αναδιαμορφώσει το αγροτικό σπίτι και άλλες 
βιομηχανικές κοινότητες. Η προκύπτουσα έκθεση έξι-έντασης 
του ήχου, που γράφτηκε από τους προοδευτικούς κοινωνικούς 
μεταρρυθμιστές, περιέλαβε το αγροτικό σπίτι της Margaret 
Byington: Οι οικογένειες μιας πόλης μύλων, δημοσίευσαν 
αρχικά το 1910. Αυτό το απόσπασμα από τη μελέτη 
Byington απεικόνισε τη ζωή εργασίας και σπιτιών για τις που 
έχουν μεταναστεύσει γυναίκες του αγροτικού σπιτιού. Ο 
απολογισμός του Byington, ενώ συμπονετικός στους μετανάστες που
περιέλαβαν τον όγκο του πόλης εργατικού δυναμικού χάλυβα, 
γράφτηκε από την προοπτική ενός ξένου. Υπογράμμισε την 
περιορισμένη συμμετοχή των γυναικών στο πληρωμένο εργατικό 
δυναμικό στις πόλεις μύλων χάλυβα όπως το αγροτικό σπίτι, όμως
παρείχε την επαναλαμβανόμενη κατάθεση σχετικά με τους 
πολλαπλάσιους οικονομικούς και κοινωνικούς ρόλους των γυναικών 
στο αγροτικό σπίτι καθώς οι διευθυντές της οικογένειας 
χρηματοδοτούν και οικογενειών σχέσεις.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1892, la granja, Pennsylvania, era el sitio de 
una de las huelgas más dramáticas de la historia de ESTADOS UNIDOS. 
Victoria de la empresa siderúrgica de Carnegie la última dio 
lugar a la destrucción de una unión una vez que-de gran alcance del 
hierro experto y de los trabajadores de acero. Antes de 1907, 
casi 7.000 trabajadores trabajan en la planta de la granja para los 
ESTADOS UNIDOS Steel Corporation. En 1907-1908, la fundación 
sabia de Russell emprendió un estudio intensivo que procuró entender
los cambios dramáticos que habían restructurado a la granja y a 
otras comunidades industriales. El informe del seis-volumen que 
resultaba, escrito por los reformadores sociales progresivos, incluyó 
la granja de Margaret Byington: Las casas de una ciudad del 
molino, primero publicadas en 1910. Este extracto del trabajo 
representado estudio de Byington y vida casera para las mujeres 
inmigrantes de la granja. La cuenta de Byington, mientras que es
comprensiva a los inmigrantes que abarcaron el bulto de la mano de 
obra de la ciudad de acero, fue escrita de la perspectiva de un 
forastero. Ella acentuó la participación limitada de las 
mujeres en la mano de obra pagada en ciudades del molino de acero como
granja, con todo ella proporcionó relanzó el testimonio con respecto
al papeles económica y social múltiple de mujeres en granja mientras
que los encargados de las finanzas de la familia y de los lazos de la 
familia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086713</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107005</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/outside-looking-in-byington-on-homesteads-women</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
