<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104796</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104796</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207146</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The American Jury: Bulwark of Democracy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Amerikanische Jury: Bollwerk der 
Demokratie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Jury Américain : Rempart de démocratie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Júri Americano: Bulwark da democracia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Giuria Americana: Bulwark della 
democrazia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η αμερικανική κριτική επιτροπή: Πρόχωμα της 
δημοκρατίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Jurado Americano: Baluarte de la 
democracia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is designed to help students, teachers, and citizens understand the American jury system and its role in American legal, social, and political life. It features lessons, information, and resources developed by the Constitutional Rights Foundation Chicago with high school teachers and in cooperation with national experts and scholars on the jury system.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist konzipiert, Kursteilnehmern, Lehrern zu 
helfen, und Bürger verstehen das amerikanische jury System und seine 
Rolle in der amerikanischen zugelassenen, Sozial- und politischen 
Lebensdauer. Sie kennzeichnet Lektionen, Informationen und die 
Betriebsmittel, die durch die konstitutionelle Recht-Grundlage Chicago
mit High School Lehrern und in Zusammenarbeit mit nationalen Experten 
und Gelehrten auf dem jury System entwickelt werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est conçu pour aider des étudiants, professeurs,
et les citoyens comprennent le système de fortune américain et son 
rôle dans la vie légale, sociale, et politique américaine. 
Elle comporte des leçons, l'information, et des ressources 
développées par la base constitutionnelle Chicago de droites avec 
des professeurs de lycée et en coopération avec les experts et les 
disciples nationaux sur le système de fortune.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é projetado ajudar a estudantes, professores, e 
os cidadãos compreendem o sistema jury americano e seu papel na vida 
legal, social, e política americana. Caracteriza lições, 
informação, e recursos desenvolvidos pela fundação constitutional 
Chicago das direitas com os professores da High School e na 
cooperação com os peritos e os scholars nacionais no sistema jury.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è destinato a aiutare gli allievi, insegnanti ed 
i cittadini capiscono il sistema jury americano ed il relativo ruolo 
nella vita legale, sociale e politica americana. Caratterizza le
lezioni, le informazioni e le risorse sviluppate dal fondamento 
costituzionale Chicago di diritti con gli insegnanti della High School
ed in collaborazione con gli esperti e gli eruditi nazionali sul 
sistema jury.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">σχεδιάζεται για να βοηθήσει τους σπουδαστές, δάσκαλοι,
και οι πολίτες καταλαβαίνουν το αμερικανικό σύστημα κριτικών 
επιτροπών και το ρόλο του στην αμερικανική νομική, κοινωνική, και
πολιτική ζωή. Χαρακτηρίζει τα μαθήματα, τις πληροφορίες, 
και τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς που αναπτύσσονται από το 
συνταγματικό ίδρυμα Σικάγο δικαιωμάτων με τους δασκάλους 
γυμνασίου και σε συνεργασία με τους εθνικούς εμπειρογνώμονες και 
τους μελετητές στο σύστημα κριτικών επιτροπών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">se diseña ayudar a los estudiantes, profesores, y
los ciudadanos entienden el sistema del jurado americano y su papel en
vida legal, social, y política americana. Ofrece lecciones, la 
información, y los recursos desarrollados por la fundación 
constitucional Chicago de las derechas con los profesores de la High 
School secundaria y en la cooperación con los expertos y los eruditos
nacionales en el sistema del jurado.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207146</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104796</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-american-jury-bulwark-of-democracy</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
