<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107758</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107758</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087371</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"All the Colored Women Like This Work": Black Workers During World War I</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"alle farbigen Frauen so Arbeit": Schwarze 
Arbeiter Während Des Ersten Weltkrieges</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"toutes les femmes colorées comme ceci travail" :
Ouvriers Noirs Pendant La Première Guerre Mondiale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"todas as mulheres coloridas como isto trabalho": 
Trabalhadores Pretos Durante O World.war.i</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"tutte le donne colorate come questo lavoro": 
Operai Neri Durante Il World.war.i</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Όλες οι έγχρωμες γυναίκες συμπαθούν αυτήν την 
εργασία": Μαύροι εργαζόμενοι κατά τη διάρκεια του 
παγκόσμιου πολέμου Ι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"todas las mujeres coloreadas como esto trabajo": 
Trabajadores Negros Durante Primera Guerra Mundial</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Wartime production demanded the mobilization of thousands of workers to make steel and rubber, to work in petrochemical industries, and to build ships. As a result, African Americans made striking gains in employment even while also facing continuing discrimination. Black women, for example, got jobs working on the railroads for the first time during the world war. Black women found jobs as laborers, cleaning cars, wiping engines, tending railroad beds. Helen Ross was one of them, working for the Santa Fe Railroad. In an interview with the Women's Service Section of U.S. Railroad Administration, Ross described the advantages of her railroad job. Nevertheless, the same agency later declared such work too heavy for women.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kriegproduktion verlangte die Mobilisierung von 
Tausenden Arbeitern, um Stahl und Gummi zu bilden, in den 
petrochemischen Industrien zu arbeiten, und Schiffe aufzubauen. 
Infolgedessen bildeten afrikanische Amerikaner schlagende 
Gewinne in der Beschäftigung, sogar beim fortfahrende Unterscheidung 
auch gegenüberstellen. Schwarze Frauen z.B. erhielten die Jobs,
die zum ersten Mal auf den Eisenbahnen während des Weltkrieges 
arbeiten. Schwarze Frauen fanden Jobs als Arbeiter, 
Reinigungsautos und wischten die Maschinen ab und neigten 
Eisenbahnbetten. Helen Ross war eine von ihnen und arbeitete 
für die Santa Fe Eisenbahn. In einem Interview mit dem 
Service-Kapitel der Frauen der VEREINIGTE STAATEN Eisenbahn-Leitung, 
beschrieb Ross die Vorteile ihres Eisenbahnjobs. Dennoch 
erklärte die gleiche Agentur später solche Arbeit, die für Frauen 
zu schwer ist.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La production de temps de guerre a exigé la 
mobilisation des milliers d'ouvriers pour faire l'acier et le 
caoutchouc, pour travailler dans des industries pétrochimiques, et 
pour construire des bateaux. En conséquence, les Américains 
africains ont fait des gains de frappement dans l'emploi même tout en
également faisant face à la discrimination continue. Les 
femmes noires, par exemple, ont obtenu les travaux travaillant aux 
chemins de fer pour la première fois pendant la guerre mondiale. 
Les femmes noires ont trouvé les travaux comme travailleurs, 
voitures de nettoyage, essuyant des moteurs, tendant des lits de 
chemin de fer. Helen Ross était l'une d'entre elles, 
travaillant pour le chemin de fer de technicien de Santa. Dans 
une entrevue avec la section du service des femmes de la gestion de 
chemin de fer des ETATS-UNIS, Ross a décrit les avantages de son 
travail de chemin de fer. Néanmoins, la même agence plus tard 
a déclaré un tel travail trop lourd pour des femmes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A produção do wartime exijiu o mobilization dos 
milhares dos trabalhadores fazer o aço e a borracha, trabalhar em 
indústrias petrochemical, e construir navios. Em 
conseqüência, os americanos africanos fizeram ganhos golpeando no 
emprego mesmo ao também enfrentar a discriminação continuando. 
As mulheres pretas, para o exemplo, começaram os trabalhos que 
trabalham nas estradas de ferro para a primeira vez durante a guerra 
de mundo. As mulheres pretas encontraram trabalhos como 
laborers, carros de limpeza, limpando os motores, tendendo camas da 
estrada de ferro. Helen Ross era um delas, trabalhando para a 
estrada de ferro do Fe de Santa. Em uma entrevista com a seção
do serviço das mulheres da administração da estrada de ferro de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS, Ross descreveu as vantagens de seu trabalho da estrada
de ferro. Não obstante, a mesma agência declarou mais tarde 
tal trabalho demasiado pesado para mulheres.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La produzione di wartime ha richiesto la 
mobilizzazione dei migliaia degli operai per fare l'acciaio e la 
gomma, per funzionare nelle industrie petrochimiche e per costruire le
navi. Di conseguenza, gli Americani africani hanno fatto gli 
aumenti di colpenti l'occupazione persino mentre però affrontando la 
distinzione continua. Le donne nere, per esempio, hanno ottenuto
i lavori che lavorano per la prima volta alle ferrovie durante la 
guerra mondiale. Le donne nere hanno trovato i lavori come 
lavoratori, automobili di pulitura, pulendo i motori, tendenti le basi
della ferrovia. Helen Ross era un di loro, funzionando per la 
ferrovia del tecnico di assistenza di Santa. In un'intervista 
con la sezione di servizio delle donne della gestione della ferrovia 
degli STATI UNITI, Ross ha descritto i vantaggi del suo lavoro della 
ferrovia. Tuttavia, la stessa agenzia più successivamente ha 
dichiarato tale lavoro troppo gravoso per le donne.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η εν καιρώ πολέμου παραγωγή απαίτησε την κινητοποίηση
χιλιάδων εργαζόμενοι για να κάνει το χάλυβα και το λάστιχο, για 
να εργαστεί στις πετροχημικές βιομηχανίες, και για να ναυπηγήσει 
τα σκάφη. Κατά συνέπεια, αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί έκαναν τα 
εντυπωσιακά κέρδη στην απασχόληση ακόμη και επίσης 
αντιμετωπίζοντας τη συνεχιμένος διάκριση. Οι μαύρες 
γυναίκες, παραδείγματος χάριν, πήραν τις εργασίες εργαζόμενες 
στους σιδηροδρόμους για πρώτη φορά κατά τη διάρκεια του 
παγκόσμιου πολέμου. Οι μαύρες γυναίκες βρήκαν τις εργασίες
ως laborers, καθαρίζοντας αυτοκίνητα, σκουπίζοντας μηχανές, που
τείνουν τα κρεβάτια σιδηροδρόμου. Η Helen Ross ήταν 
ένας από τους, που λειτουργούν για το σιδηρόδρομο Φε Santa. 
Σε μια συνέντευξη με το τμήμα υπηρεσιών των γυναικών της 
διοίκησης ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΥ σιδηροδρόμου, ο Ross περιέγραψε τα 
πλεονεκτήματα της εργασίας σιδηροδρόμου της. Εντούτοις, η 
ίδια αντιπροσωπεία κήρυξε αργότερα τέτοια εργασία πάρα πολύ 
βαριά για τις γυναίκες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La producción del tiempo de guerra exigió la 
movilización de millares de trabajadores para hacer el acero y el 
caucho, para trabajar en industrias petroquímicas, y para construir 
las naves. Consecuentemente, los americanos africanos hicieron 
aumentos de pulso en el empleo incluso mientras que también hacían 
frente a la discriminación de continuación. Las mujeres 
negras, por ejemplo, consiguieron los trabajos que trabajaban en los 
ferrocarriles para la primera vez durante la guerra mundial. Las
mujeres negras encontraron trabajos como trabajadores, coches de 
limpieza, limpiando los motores, tendiendo a camas del ferrocarril. 
Helen Ross era una de ellas, trabajando para el ferrocarril del 
FE de santa. En una entrevista con la sección del servicio de 
las mujeres de la administración del ferrocarril de ESTADOS UNIDOS, 
Ross describió las ventajas de su trabajo del ferrocarril. Sin 
embargo, la misma agencia declaró más adelante tal trabajo demasiado
pesado para las mujeres.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087371</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107758</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/all-the-colored-women-like-this-work-black-workers-during-world-war-i</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
