<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108131</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108131</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206127</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">More Than Skin Deep, A Teacher's Guide to Caves</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mehr als enthäuten tief, die Anleitung eines 
Lehrers zu den Höhlen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Plus que pèlent profondément, le guide d'un 
professeur des cavernes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Mais do que descascam profundamente, guia de um 
professor às cavernas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Più di pelano in profondità, guida 
dell'insegnante alle caverne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Περισσότερο απ' ό,τι ξεφλουδίστε βαθιά, ο οδηγός 
ενός δασκάλου στις σπηλιές</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Más que pelan profundamente, la guía de un 
profesor a las cuevas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">provides information and activities about the biology of caves, how caves and stalactites form, how bats and birds differ, and more. The site is designed for students planning to visit Round Spring Caverns, one of more than 300 caves identified in the Ozark National Scenic River ways of southeast Missouri.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt Informationen und Aktivitäten über die 
Biologie der Höhlen zur Verfügung, wie Höhlen und stalactites sich 
bilden, wie Hiebe und Vögel sich unterscheiden und mehr. Die 
Site ist für die Kursteilnehmer konzipiert, die planen, ringsum 
Frühling Höhlen, eine zu besuchen von mehr als 300 Höhlen, die in 
den Ozark nationalen szenischen Flußmethoden von Südostmissouri 
gekennzeichnet werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fournit des informations et des activités au 
sujet de la biologie des cavernes, comment les cavernes et des 
stalactites forment, comment les battes et des oiseaux diffèrent, et
plus. Le site est conçu pour des étudiants projetant visiter 
autour des cavernes de ressort, une de plus de 300 cavernes 
identifiées des voies scéniques nationales de fleuve d'Ozark du 
Missouri du sud-est.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fornece a informação e atividades sobre a 
biologia das cavernas, como as cavernas e stalactites dão forma, como
os bastões e pássaros diferem, e mais. O local é projetado 
para os estudantes que planeiam visitar em volta das cavernas da mola,
uma de mais de 300 cavernas identificadas nas maneiras scenic 
nacionais do rio de Ozark de Missouri do sudeste.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fornisce le informazioni ed attività circa la 
biologia delle caverne, come le caverne e stalactites formano, come i 
blocchi ed uccelli differiscono da e più. Il luogo è 
progettato per gli allievi che progettano visitare intorno alle 
spelonche della molla, una di più di 300 caverne identificate nei 
modi scenici nazionali del fiume di Ozark del Missouri sudorientale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρέχει τις πληροφορίες και τις δραστηριότητες για τη 
βιολογία των σπηλιών, πώς οι σπηλιές και οι σταλακτίτες 
διαμορφώνουν, πώς τα ρόπαλα και τα πουλιά διαφέρουν, και 
περισσότερο. Η περιοχή σχεδιάζεται για τους σπουδαστές που 
προγραμματίζουν να επισκεφτεί γύρω από τα σπήλαια ανοίξεων, μια 
από περισσότερες από 300 σπηλιές που προσδιορίζονται με 
εθνικοί φυσικοί τρόπος ποταμών Ozark του νοτιοανατολικού 
Μισσούρι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">proporciona a la información y las actividades 
sobre la biología de cuevas, cómo las cuevas y los stalactites 
forman, cómo diferencian los palos y los pájaros, y más. El 
sitio se diseña para los estudiantes que planean visitar alrededor de
las cavernas del resorte, una de más de 300 cuevas identificadas de 
las maneras escénicas nacionales del río de Ozark de Missouri 
suroriental.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206127</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108131</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/more-than-skin-deep-a-teachers-guide-to-caves</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
