<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103043</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103043</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209942</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Triangle centroid </string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dreieckschwerpunkt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Centre de surface de triangle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Centróide do triângulo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Centro di massa del triangolo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Centroid τριγώνων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Centro de figura del triángulo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A web page and interactive applet demonstrating the concept of the centroid of a triangle. The applet shows a triangle where the user can drag the vertices around. The centroid and the median lines that generate it are continuously moved as the user drags the vertices. By experimentation the user can observe that the centroid always remains inside the triangle. The page text explains the definition of the centroid and how to find it. It also shows that the centroid is the center of gravity of the triangle. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Webseite und ein interaktiver applet, die das
Konzept des Schwerpunkts eines Dreiecks zeigen. Der applet zeigt
einem Dreieck, wo der Benutzer die Gipfel herum schleppen kann. 
Der Schwerpunkt und die mittleren Zeilen, die ihn festlegen, 
werden ununterbrochen verschoben, während der Benutzer die Gipfel 
schleppt. Durch Experimentieren kann der Benutzer beobachten, 
daß der Schwerpunkt immer innerhalb des Dreiecks bleibt. Der 
Seite Text beschreibt die Definition des Schwerpunkts und wie man ihn 
findet. Er zeigt auch, daß der Schwerpunkt der Schwerpunkt des 
Dreiecks ist. Applet kann zum vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch 
mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. 
Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von 
jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den 
benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein 
Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven 
Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une page Web et un applet interactif démontrant
le concept du centre de surface d'une triangle. L'applet montre 
à une triangle où l'utilisateur peut traîner les sommets autour. 
Le centre de surface et les lignes médianes qui produisent de 
lui sont sans interruption déplacés pendant que l'utilisateur 
traîne les sommets. Par expérimentation l'utilisateur peut 
observer que le centre de surface reste toujours à l'intérieur de la
triangle. Le texte de page explique la définition du centre de 
surface et comment le trouver. Il prouve également que le 
centre de surface est le centre de la gravité de la triangle. 
L'applet peut être agrandi à la taille de plein écran pour 
l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de classe. Le après 
utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant peut lui accéder 
encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la maison ou dans la 
bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion exigée. Cette 
ressource est un composant du projet interactif de manuel de la 
géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um Web page e um applet interativo que demonstram 
o conceito do centróide de um triângulo. O applet mostra a um 
triângulo onde o usuário pode arrastar os vertices ao redor. O
centróide e as linhas medianas que o geram são movidos continuamente
enquanto o usuário arrasta os vertices. Pela experimentação o
usuário pode observar que o centróide remanesce sempre dentro do 
triângulo. O texto da página explica a definição do 
centróide e como encontrá-lo. Mostra também que o centróide 
é o centro de gravidade do triângulo. O applet pode ser 
ampliado ao tamanho de tela cheia para o uso com um projetor da sala 
de aula. O depois de uso na sala de aula, estudante pode 
alcançá-la outra vez de todo o web browser na HOME ou na biblioteca 
com nenhum início de uma sessão requerido. Este recurso é um 
componente do projeto interativo do textbook da geometria da 
referência aberta do math em http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un Web page e un applet interattivo che dimostrano
il concetto del centro di massa di un triangolo. Il applet 
mostra ad un triangolo dove l'utente può trascinare i vertici 
intorno. Il centro di massa e le righe mediane che lo generano 
sono spostati continuamente mentre l'utente trascina i vertici. 
Da esperimento l'utente può osservare che il centro di massa 
rimane sempre all'interno del triangolo. Il testo della pagina 
spiega la definizione del centro di massa e come trovarlo. 
Egualmente indica che il centro di massa è il centro di 
gravità del triangolo. Il applet può essere ingrandito al 
formato di schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore dell'aula. La
post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può accederle ancora da tutto 
il web browser nel paese o nella libreria senza l'inizio attività 
richiesto. Questa risorsa è un componente del progetto 
interattivo del manuale della geometria di riferimento aperto di per 
la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ιστοσελίδας και διαλογικό ένα applet που 
καταδεικνύουν την έννοια centroid ενός τριγώνου. Το 
applet εμφανίζει ένα τρίγωνο όπου ο χρήστης μπορεί να σέρει 
vertices γύρω. Centroid και οι μεσαίες γραμμές που 
παράγουν αυτό κινούνται συνεχώς δεδομένου ότι ο χρήστης σέρνει
vertices. Από τον πειραματισμό ο χρήστης μπορεί να 
παρατηρήσει ότι centroid παραμένει πάντα μέσα στο τρίγωνο. 
Το κείμενο σελίδων εξηγεί τον καθορισμό centroid και πώς
να τον βρεί. Επίσης δείχνει ότι centroid είναι το 
κέντρο βάρους του τριγώνου. Το Applet μπορεί να 
διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με έναν 
προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο 
σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε 
ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια 
εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς 
είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος εγχειριδίων 
γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un Web page y un applet interactivo que demuestran
el concepto del centro de figura de un triángulo. El applet 
muestra a triángulo donde el utilizador puede arrastrar las cimas 
alrededor. El centro de figura y las líneas medianas que lo 
generan se mueven continuamente mientras que el utilizador arrastra 
las cimas. Por la experimentación el utilizador puede observar 
que el centro de figura permanece siempre dentro del triángulo. 
El texto de la paginación explica la definición del centro de 
figura y cómo encontrarlo. También muestra que el centro de 
figura es el centro de gravedad del triángulo. El applet se 
puede agrandar a la talla de la pantalla completa para el uso con un 
proyector de la sala de clase. El uso posterior en la sala de 
clase, estudiante puede tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier web 
browser en el país o en la biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. 
Este recurso es un componente del proyecto interactivo del libro
de textos de la geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas
en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209942</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103043</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/triangle-centroid</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
