<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102884</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102884</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087570</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Commonwealth of Learning Publications</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Commonwealth der erlernenpublikationen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Commonwealth des publications d'étude</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Comunidade de publicações de aprendizagem</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Commonwealth delle pubblicazioni imparanti</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινοπολιτεία της εκμάθησης των δημοσιεύσεων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Commonwealth de publicaciones que aprenden</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A wide range of studies, reports and research documents have been published by the Commonwealth of Learning. Materials include monographs, curriculum and course development, training toolkits, directories, videos, and more. Most are available for download, free-of-charge, on this web site. Government agencies and institutions in developing Commonwealth countries may receive copies at no charge. Nominal charges apply to orders from developed, newly developed and non-Commonwealth countries.</string>
          </description>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine breite Strecke der Studien, Reports und 
Forschung Dokumente sind durch den Commonwealth des Lernens 
veröffentlicht worden. Materialien enthalten Monographien, 
Lehrplan- und Kursentwicklung, ausbildentoolkits, Verzeichnisse, 
videos und mehr. Die meisten sind für Download, 
frei-von-aufladen, auf dieser Web site vorhanden. 
Regierungsagenturen und Anstalten in sich entwickelnden 
Commonwealthländern können Exemplare an keiner Ladung empfangen. 
Schutzgebühren treffen auf Ordnungen von entwickelten, eben 
entwickelten und NichtCommonwealth Ländern zu.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un éventail d'études, des états et les 
documents de recherches ont été édités par le Commonwealth de 
l'étude. Les matériaux incluent des monographies, 
développement de programme d'études et de cours, des trousses à outils 
s'exerçantes, des répertoires, des videos, et plus. Les la 
plupart sont disponibles pour le téléchargement, libre-de-chargent, 
sur ce site Web. Les organismes gouvernementaux et les 
établissements dans les pays se développants de Commonwealth peuvent
recevoir des copies à aucune charge. Les sommes nominales 
s'appliquent aux commandes à partir des pays développé, 
nouvellement développé et de non-Commonwealth.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uma escala larga dos estudos, os relatórios e os 
originais da pesquisa foram publicados pela comunidade da 
aprendizagem. Os materiais incluem monografias, desenvolvimento 
do curriculum e do curso, toolkits treinando, diretórios, videos, e 
mais. A maioria estão disponíveis para o download, 
livre-$$$-CARREGAM, neste Web site. As agências e as 
instituições de governo em países tornando-se da comunidade podem 
receber cópias em nenhuma carga. As cargas nominais aplicam-se 
às ordens dos países desenvolvido, recentemente desenvolvido e da 
non-Comunidade.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Una vasta gamma degli studi, i rapporti ed i 
documenti di ricerca sono stati pubblicati dal commonwealth di 
imparare. I materiali includono le monografie, sviluppo di corso
e di programma di studi, toolkits d'addestramento, indici, videos e 
più. La maggior parte sono disponibili per il trasferimento dal
sistema centrale verso i satelliti, libero-de-si caricano, su questo 
Web site. Gli enti governativi e le istituzioni nei paesi di 
sviluppo del commonwealth possono ricevere le copie a nessuna carica. 
Le spese nominali si applicano agli ordini dai paesi sviluppato,
recentemente sviluppato e del non-Commonwealth.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα ευρύ φάσμα των μελετών, οι εκθέσεις και τα 
ερευνητικά έγγραφα έχουν δημοσιευθεί από την Κοινοπολιτεία της 
εκμάθησης. Τα υλικά περιλαμβάνουν τις μονογραφίες, την 
ανάπτυξη προγράμματος σπουδών και σειράς μαθημάτων, τα κουτιά 
εργαλείων κατάρτισης, τους καταλόγους αρχείων, τα βίντεο, και 
περισσότεροι. Οι περισσότεροι είναι διαθέσιμοι για 
μεταφορτώνουν, δωρεάν, σε αυτόν τον ιστοχώρο. Οι 
κυβερνητικά αντιπροσωπείες και τα όργανα στην ανάπτυξη των
χωρών Κοινοπολιτείας μπορούν να λάβουν τα αντίγραφα σε καμία 
δαπάνη. Οι ονομαστικές δαπάνες ισχύουν για τις κατατάξεις 
από αναπτυγμένος, πρόσφατα αναπτυγμένος και χώρες 
μη-Κοινοπολιτειών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una amplia gama de estudios, los informes y los 
documentos de la investigación han sido publicados por la 
Commonwealth de aprender. Los materiales incluyen las 
monografías, desarrollo del plan de estudios y del curso, las cajas 
de herramientas de entrenamiento, los directorios, los videos, y más.
La mayoría están disponibles para la transferencia directa, 
libre-de-cargan, en este Web site. Las agencias y las 
instituciones de estatal en países de la Commonwealth que se 
convierten pueden recibir copias en ninguna carga. Las cargas 
nominales se aplican a las órdenes de países desarrollado, 
nuevamente desarrollado y de la no-Commonwealth.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087570</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102884</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/matters/col-publications</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
