<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103227</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103227</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203752</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Major Environmental Laws</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hauptklimagesetze</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Lois Environnementales Principales</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Leis Ambientais Principais</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Leggi Ambientali Importanti</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σημαντικοί περιβαλλοντικοί νόμοι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Leyes Ambientales Importantes</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site provides a listing of major environmental laws and regulations which may be viewed in full text or as summary versions. Laws include the National Environmental Policy Act, the Clean Air Act, the Clean Water Act, the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act (Superfund), the Endangered Species Act, the Freedom of Information Act, the Occupational Safety and Health Act, the Resource Conservation and Recovery Act, the Safe Drinking Water Act and others.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site liefert Listen der Hauptklimagesetze und
der Regelungen, die in Ganztext- oder als zusammenfassende Versionen 
angesehen werden können. Gesetze schließen die nationale 
Klimapolitik-Tat, die saubere Luft-Tat, die saubere Wasser-Tat, die 
komplette Klimaantwort, Ausgleich ein, und Verbindlichkeit Tat 
(Superfund), die gefährdete Sorte fungieren, die Freiheit der 
Informationen Tat, der beruflichen Sicherheit und Gesundheit Tat, der 
Hilfsmittel-Erhaltung und Wiederanlauf-Tat, der sicheren der 
Trinkwassertat und -anderer.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site fournit une liste des lois et des 
règlements environnementaux principaux qui peuvent être visualisés 
dans versions à texte intégral ou en tant que récapitulatives. 
Les lois incluent l'acte environnemental national de politique, 
la Loi propre d'air, l'acte propre de l'eau, la réponse 
environnementale complète, compensation, et la Loi de responsabilité
(Superfund), les Espèces mises en danger agissent, la liberté 
de Loi de l'information, de l'acte professionnel de sûreté et de 
santé, de la Loi d'économie de ressource et de reprise, de la Loi 
sûre et de d'autres d'eau potable.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local fornece uma lista das leis e dos 
regulamentos ambientais principais que podem ser vistos no texto cheio
ou como versões sumárias. As leis incluem o ato ambiental 
nacional da política, o ato limpo do ar, o ato limpo da água, a 
resposta ambiental detalhada, compensação, e o ato da 
responsabilidade (Superfund), a espécie posta em perigo age, a 
liberdade do ato da informação, do ato ocupacional de segurança e 
de saúde, do ato do conservation do recurso e da recuperação, do 
ato seguro e de outro da água bebendo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo fornisce un elenco delle leggi e 
delle regolazioni ambientali importanti che possono essere osservate 
in versioni a testo integrale o come sommarie. Le leggi 
includono la Legge ambientale nazionale di politica, la Legge pulita 
dell'aria, la Legge pulita dell'acqua, la risposta ambientale 
completa, compensazione e la Legge di responsabilità (Superfund), la 
specie in pericolo si comporta, la libertà della Legge delle 
informazioni, della Legge professionale di sicurezza e salubrità, 
della Legge di conservazione delle risorse e di recupero, della Legge 
sicuro e di altre dell'acqua potabile.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή παρέχει μια λίστα σημαντικών 
περιβαλλοντικών νόμων και κανονισμών που μπορούν να εμφανιστούν 
στο πλήρες κείμενο ή ως συνοπτικές εκδόσεις. Οι νόμοι 
περιλαμβάνουν τον εθνικό νόμο πολιτικής για το περιβάλλον, τον 
καθαρό νόμο αέρα, τον καθαρό νόμο ύδατος, την περιεκτική 
περιβαλλοντική απάντηση, την αποζημίωση, και το νόμο ευθύνης 
(Superfund), το διακυβευμένο νόμο ειδών, το νόμο ελευθερίας 
των πληροφοριών, το νόμο επαγγελματικής ασφάλειας και υγείας, το 
νόμο συντήρησης των στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς και αποκατάστασης, τον
ασφαλή νόμο πόσιμου νερού και άλλοι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio proporciona a un listado de los leyes y
de las regulaciones ambientales importantes que se pueden ver en texto
completo o como versiones sumarias. Los leyes incluyen el acto 
ambiental nacional de la política, el acto limpio del aire, el acto 
limpio del agua, la respuesta ambiental comprensiva, remuneración, y 
el acto del defecto (Superfund), la especie puesta en peligro actúa, 
la libertad del acto de la información, del acto ocupacional de 
seguridad y de la salud, del acto de la conservación del recurso y de
la recuperación, del acto seguro y de otros del agua potable.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203752</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103227</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/major-environmental-laws</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
