<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105992</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105992</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973937</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Medicine Games: Malaria - Parasite</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Medizin-Spiele: Malaria - Parasit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jeux de Médecine : Malaria - Parasite</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogos Da Medicina: Malária - Parasite</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giochi Della Medicina: Malaria - Parassita</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παιχνίδια ιατρικής: Ελονοσία - παράσιτο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Juegos De la Medicina: Malaria - Parásito</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Play a game and find out about a Nobel Prize awarded discovery or work! Malaria is one of the world's most common diseases, caused by a parasite that is transmitted to humans by a female mosquito's bite. The discovery of this parasite in mosquitoes earned the British scientist Ronald Ross the Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine in 1902. In 1907, Alphonse Laveran received the prize for his findings that the parasite was present in human blood. Prize awarded discovery or work! Take control of a parasite, try to find your way inside a human being, and multiply as fast as possible.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spielen Sie ein Spiel und finden Sie über eine 
zugesprochene Entdeckung oder eine Arbeit des Nobelpreises heraus! 
Malaria ist eine der geläufigsten Krankheiten der Welt, 
verursacht durch einen Parasiten, der Menschen durch den Bissen eines 
weiblichen Moskitos übermittelt wird. Die Entdeckung dieses 
Parasiten in den Moskitos erwarb dem britischen Wissenschaftler Ronald
Ross den Nobelpreis in der Physiologie oder Medizin 1902. 1907 
empfing Alphonse Laveran den Preis für seine Entdeckungen, daß der 
Parasit im menschlichen Blut anwesend war. Prize zugesprochene 
Entdeckung oder Arbeit! Nehmen Sie Steuerung eines Parasiten, 
versuchen Sie, Ihre Methode innerhalb eines menschlichen Wesens zu 
finden, und multiplizieren Sie so schnell wie möglich.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jouez un jeu et découvrez au sujet d'une 
découverte ou d'un travail attribuée de prix Nobel ! La 
malaria est l'une des maladies les plus communes du monde, causé par 
un parasite qui est communiqué à des humains par la morsure d'un 
moustique femelle. La découverte de ce parasite dans les 
moustiques a gagné au scientifique britannique Ronald Ross le 
prix Nobel en physiologie ou la médecine en 1902. En 1907, 
Alphonse Laveran a reçu le prix pour ses résultats que le parasite 
était présent dans le sang humain. Découverte ou travail 
attribuée professionnelle ! Prenez la commande d'un parasite, 
essayez de trouver votre chemin à l'intérieur d'un être humain, et 
multipliez-vous aussi rapidement que possible.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogue um jogo e encontre-o para fora sobre uma 
descoberta ou um trabalho concedido do prêmio de nobel! A 
malária é uma das doenças as mais comuns do mundo, causado por um 
parasite que seja transmitido aos seres humanos pela mordida de um 
mosquito fêmea. A descoberta deste parasite nos mosquitos 
ganhou ao cientista britânico Ronald Ross o prêmio de nobel no 
physiology ou a medicina em 1902. Em 1907, Alphonse Laveran 
recebeu o prêmio para seus findings que o parasite estava atual no 
sangue humano. Descoberta ou trabalho concedido premiado! 
Faça exame do controle de um parasite, tente-o encontrar sua 
maneira dentro ser humano, e multiplique-o tão rapidamente quanto 
possível.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gioc un gioco e scopra circa una scoperta o un 
lavoro ricevuta del premio Nobel! La malaria è una delle 
malattie più comuni del mondo, causato da un parassita che è 
trasmesso agli esseri umani dal morso della zanzara femminile. 
La scoperta di questo parassita in zanzare ha guadagnato allo 
scienziato britannico Ronald Ross il premio Nobel in fisiologia o la 
medicina in 1902. In 1907, Alphonse Laveran ha ricevuto il 
premio per i suoi risultati che il parassita era presente nell'anima 
umana. Scoperta o lavoro ricevuta premiata! Prenda il 
controllo di un parassita, provi a trovare il vostro modo all'interno 
di un umano e moltiplichisi velocemente quanto possibile.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παίξτε ένα παιχνίδι και ανακαλύψτε για μια 
απονεμημένη βραβείο ανακάλυψη ή μια εργασία Νόμπελ! Η 
ελονοσία είναι μια από τις παγκόσμιες πιό κοινές ασθένειες, που
προκαλείται από ένα παράσιτο που διαβιβάζεται στους ανθρώπους 
από το δάγκωμα ενός θηλυκού κουνουπιού. Η ανακάλυψη αυτού
του παρασίτου στα κουνούπια κέρδισε το βρετανικό επιστήμονα 
Ronald Ross το βραβείο Νόμπελ στη φυσιολογία ή την ιατρική 
το 1902. Το 1907, ο Alphonse Laveran έλαβε το 
βραβείο για τα συμπεράσματά του ότι το παράσιτο ήταν παρόν στο 
ανθρώπινο αίμα. Απονεμημένη βραβείο ανακάλυψη ή εργασία! 
Πάρτε τον έλεγχο ενός παρασίτου, προσπαθήστε να βρείτε τον
τρόπο σας μέσα σε έναν άνθρωπο, και πολλαπλασιάστε όσο το 
δυνατόν γρηγορότερα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Juegue un juego y descubra sobre un 
descubrimiento o un trabajo concedido del premio Nobel! La 
malaria es una de las enfermedades más comunes del mundo, causado por
un parásito que sea transmitido a los seres humanos por la mordedura 
de un mosquito femenino. El descubrimiento de este parásito en 
mosquitos ganó a científico británico Ronald Ross el premio Nobel 
en fisiología o la medicina en 1902. En 1907, Alphonse Laveran 
recibió el premio para sus resultados que el parásito estaba 
presente en sangre humana. ¡Descubrimiento o trabajo concedido 
premiado! Tome el control de un parásito, intente encontrar su 
manera dentro de un humano, y multipliqúese tan rápidamente como sea
posible.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973937</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105992</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/medicine-games-malaria-parasite</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
