<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103802</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103802</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087177</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"We Are Not Entirely Out of Civilization": A Homesteader Writes Home in 1873</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"wir sind nicht völlig aus Zivilisation heraus": 
Ein Homesteader schreibt nach Hause 1873</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"nous ne sommes pas entièrement hors de 
civilisation" : Un Propriétaire écrit à la maison en 1873</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"nós não somos inteiramente fora da 
civilização": Um Homesteader escreve para casa em 1873</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"non siamo interamente da civilizzazione": 
Un Homesteader scrive a casa in 1873</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Δεν είμαστε εξ ολοκλήρου από τον πολιτισμό": Homesteader γράφει τη "Οικία" το 1873</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"no estamos enteramente fuera de civilización": 
Un Homesteader escribe a casa en 1873</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Moving to the Great Plains meant building a home on broad, flat, and treeless prairies. Borrowing from the Plains Indians and earlier pioneers in Kansas, Mattie Oblinger and other homesteaders built sod houses. They cut the prairie sod deep and wide, laid it up like giant bricks, and fit the bricks together snugly without mortar. Mattie and her husband Uriah obtained their land through the Homestead Act of 1862, claiming and improving their 160 acres over five years. Other lands for farmers became available from the vast acreages of public land given to the railroad companies as subsidies. The Oblingers and other settlers formed communities of young families with a rough social equality and common concerns about crops, religion, and social isolation. They faced a series of hardships on the land in the 1870s: blizzards, droughts, and grasshoppers, as well as low crop prices. Mattie died in childbirth at the age of thirty-six.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Bewegen auf die Prairien bedeutete das 
Aufbauen eines Hauses auf ausgedehntem, Ebene und treeless 
Grasland. Borgen von den Ebenen Indern und von den 
früheren Pionieren in Kansas, in Mattie Oblinger und in anderen 
homesteaders baute Grasschollehäuser auf. Sie schnitten die 
Graslandgrasscholle tief und weit, legten sie oben wie riesige 
Ziegelsteine und paßten die Ziegelsteine zusammen sind gemütlich 
ohne Mörtel. Mattie und ihr Ehemann Uriah erreichten ihr Land 
durch die Gehöft-Tat von 1862 und behaupteten und verbessern ihre 160
Morgen über fünf Jahren. Andere Länder für Landwirte wurden 
von den beträchtlichen Flächeninhalt des allgemeinen Landes gegeben 
den Eisenbahnfirmen als Beihilfe vorhanden. Das Oblingers und 
andere Siedleren bildeten Gemeinschaften der jungen Familien mit einer
rauhen Sozialgleichheit und Common-Interessen über Getreide, Religion
und Soziallokalisierung. Sie stellten eine Reihe Härten auf dem
Land im 1870s gegenüber: Blizzarde, Dürren und Heuschrecken, 
sowie niedrige Getreidepreise. Mattie starb in der Geburt am 
Alter von thirty-six.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Se déplacer aux grandes plaines a signifié 
établir une maison sur large, l'appartement, et les prairies 
déboisées. L'emprunt des Indiens de plaines et des pionniers 
plus tôt au Kansas, à Mattie Oblinger et à d'autres propriétaires a 
construit des maisons de gazon. Elles ont coupé le gazon de 
prairie profondément et au loin, l'ont étendu vers le haut comme les
briques géantes, et ont adapté les briques ensemble confortablement 
sans mortier. Mattie et son mari Uriah ont obtenu leur terre par
la Loi de ferme de 1862, réclamant et améliorant leurs 160 acres sur
cinq ans. D'autres terres pour des fermiers sont devenues 
fournies par les vastes surfaces cultivées de terre publique données
aux compagnies de chemin de fer comme subventions. l'Oblingers 
et d'autres colons ont formé les communautés de jeunes familles avec
une égalité sociale approximative et des soucis de terrain communal 
concernant des collectes, la religion, et l'isolement social. 
Ils ont fait face à une série de difficultés sur la terre 
dans le 1870s : tempêtes de neige, sécheresses, et 
sauterelles, aussi bien que de bas prix de collecte. Mattie est 
mort dans l'accouchement à l'âge de trente-six.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Mover-se para as planícies grandes significou 
construir uma HOME em largo, no plano, e em pradarias treeless. 
O empréstimo dos indians de planícies e dos pioneiros mais 
adiantados em Kansas, em Mattie Oblinger e em outros homesteaders 
construiu casas do sod. Cortaram o sod da pradaria profundamente
e largamente, colocaram-no acima como tijolos gigantes, e couberam-nos
os tijolos junto confortavelmente sem o almofariz. Mattie e seu 
marido Uriah obtiveram sua terra com o ato do homestead de 1862, 
reivindicando e melhorando seus 160 acres sobre cinco anos. 
Outras terras para fazendeiros tornaram-se disponíveis dos 
acreages vastos da terra pública dados às companhias da estrada de 
ferro como subsídios. O Oblingers e outros settlers deram forma
a comunidades de famílias novas com uma igualdade social áspera e 
interesses da terra comum sobre colheitas, religião, e a isolação 
social. Enfrentaram uma série dos hardships na terra no 1870s: 
blizzards, secas, e gafanhotos, as.well.as preços baixos da 
colheita. Mattie morreu no parto na idade de trinta e seis.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Muovendosi verso le pianure grandi ha significato 
lo sviluppo della sede su vasto, sul piano e sui prairies treeless. 
Il borrowing dagli indiani di pianure e dai pionieri più in 
anticipo in Kansas, in Mattie Oblinger ed in altri homesteaders ha 
costruito le case della piota. Hanno tagliato la piota del 
prairie in profondità e largamente, la hanno posta in su come i 
mattoni giganti e misura i mattoni insieme comodamente senza mortaio. 
Mattie ed il suo marito Uriah hanno ottenuto la loro terra con 
la Legge della fattoria di 1862, esigente e migliorante i loro 160 
acri in cinque anni. Altre terre per i coltivatori sono 
diventato disponibili dalle superfici in acri ampie di terra pubblica 
date alle aziende della ferrovia come sovvenzioni. Il Oblingers 
ed altri settlers hanno formato le Comunità delle famiglie giovani 
con un'uguaglianza sociale approssimativa e lle preoccupazioni del 
terreno comunale circa i raccolti, la religione e l'isolamento 
sociale. Hanno affrontato una serie di difficoltà sulla terra 
nel 1870s: blizzards, siccità e grasshoppers, così come i 
prezzi bassi del raccolto. Mattie è morto nel parto all'età di
trentasei.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η κίνηση προς τις μεγάλες πεδιάδες σήμανε ένα σπίτι 
σε ευρύ, το επίπεδο, και τα treeless λιβάδια. Δανειμένος 
από τις πεδιάδες Ινδοί και τους πιό πρώτους πρωτοπόρους στο 
Κάνσας, Mattie Oblinger και άλλοι homesteaders έχτισαν τα 
σπίτια γρασιδιών. Έκοψαν το γρασίδι λιβαδιών βαθιά και 
ευρέως, το έβαλαν επάνω όπως τα γιγαντιαία τούβλα, και 
εγκατέστησαν τα τούβλα μαζί βολικά χωρίς κονίαμα. Το 
Mattie και ο σύζυγός της Uriah έλαβαν το έδαφός τους μέσω 
του νόμου αγροτικών σπιτιών 1862, που απαιτεί και που 
βελτιώνει 160 στρέμματά τους πάνω από πέντε έτη. Αλλα
εδάφη για τους αγρότες διατέθηκαν από τις απέραντες επιφάνειες 
του δημόσιου εδάφους που δόθηκαν στις επιχειρήσεις σιδηροδρόμου 
ως επιχορηγήσεις. Το Oblingers και άλλοι άποικοι 
διαμόρφωσαν τις κοινότητες των νέων οικογενειών με μια τραχιά 
κοινωνική ισότητα και κοινές ανησυχίες για τις συγκομιδές, τη 
θρησκεία, και την κοινωνική απομόνωση. Αντιμετώπισαν μια 
σειρά δυσκολιών στο έδαφος 1870s: χιονοθύελλες, 
ξηρασίες, και grasshoppers, καθώς επίσης και χαμηλές τιμές 
συγκομιδών. Το Mattie πέθανε στον τοκετό στην ηλικία 
τριάντα έξι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La mudanza a los grandes llanos significó la 
construcción de un hogar en amplio, plano, y praderas sin árboles. 
El préstamo de los indios de llanos y de los pioneros 
anteriores en Kansas, Mattie Oblinger y otros homesteaders construyó 
casas del césped. Cortaron el césped de la pradera 
profundamente y de par en par, lo pusieron para arriba como ladrillos 
gigantes, y cupieron los ladrillos juntos ajustado sin el mortero. 
Mattie y su marido Uriah obtuvieron su pista con el acto de la 
granja de 1862, demandando y mejorando sus 160 acres sobre cinco 
años. Otras pistas para los granjeros llegaron a estar 
disponibles de las áreas cultivadas extensas de pista pública dadas 
a las compañías del ferrocarril como subsidios. El Oblingers y
otros colonos formaron a comunidades de familias jóvenes con una 
igualdad social áspera y preocupaciones del campo común por 
cosechas, la religión, y el aislamiento social. Hicieron frente
a una serie de dificultades en la pista en el 1870s: ventiscas, 
sequías, y saltamontes, así como precios bajos de la cosecha. 
Mattie murió en parto en la edad de treinta y seis.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087177</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103802</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/we-are-not-entirely-out-of-civilization-a-homesteader-writes-home-in-1873</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
