<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104416</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104416</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202585</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Lawrence Kohlberg's Six Stages of Moral Reasoning</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lawrence Kohlbergs sechs Stadien moralische 
Argumentation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Six étapes de Laurent Kohlberg de raisonnement 
moral</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Seis estágios de Lawrence Kohlberg do raciocínio
moral</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sei fasi del Lawrence Kohlberg di ragionamento 
morale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Έξι στάδια Lawrence Kohlberg του ηθικού 
συλλογισμού</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Seis etapas de Lorenzo Kohlberg de razonamiento 
moral</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">There are many aspects to the understanding of human behavior. The study of psychology would be incomplete without a detailed analysis of Lawrence Kohlberg's Six Stages of Moral Reasoning. It is a vital part of the different stages in the life cycle. This lesson plan will help students understand and become more aware of their own human behavior as it relates to the concept of moral reasoning.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Es gibt viele Aspekte zum Verständnis des 
menschlichen Verhaltens. Die Studie der Psychologie würde ohne 
eine ausführliche Analyse von Lawrence Kohlbergs sechs Stadien 
moralischer Argumentation unvollständig sein. Es ist ein 
lebenswichtiges Teil der unterschiedlichen Stadien im Lebenszyklus. 
Dieser Lektionplanwille helfen Kursteilnehmern ihrem eigenen 
menschlichen Verhalten zu verstehen und bewußter zu werden, während 
er auf dem Konzept der moralischen Argumentation in Verbindung steht.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Il y a beaucoup d'aspects à l'arrangement du 
comportement humain. L'étude de la psychologie serait 
inachevée sans analyse détaillée de six étapes de Laurent Kohlberg
de raisonnement moral. C'est une partie essentielle des 
différentes étapes dans le cycle de vie. Cette volonté de 
plan de leçon aident des étudiants à comprendre et se rendre compte
de leur propre comportement humain pendant qu'elle associe au concept 
du raisonnement moral.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Há muitos aspectos à compreensão do 
comportamento humano. O estudo do psychology estaria incompleto 
sem uma análise detalhada de seis estágios de Lawrence Kohlberg do 
raciocínio moral. É uma parte vital dos estágios diferentes 
no ciclo de vida. Esta vontade da planta da lição ajuda a 
estudantes compreender e tornar-se mais cientes de seu próprio 
comportamento humano enquanto se relaciona ao conceito do raciocínio 
moral.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ci sono molte funzioni alla comprensione del 
comportamento umano. Lo studio sulla psicologia sarebbe 
incompleto senza un'analisi dettagliata di sei fasi del Lawrence 
Kohlberg di ragionamento morale. È una parte vitale delle fasi 
differenti nel ciclo di vita. Questa volontà di programma di 
lezione aiuta gli allievi a capire e diventare più coscienti del loro
proprio comportamento umano mentre si riferisce al concetto di 
ragionamento morale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Υπάρχουν πολλές πτυχές στην κατανόηση της ανθρώπινης 
συμπεριφοράς. Η μελέτη της ψυχολογίας θα ήταν ελλιπής 
χωρίς μια λεπτομερή ανάλυση έξι σταδίων Lawrence Kohlberg 
του ηθικού συλλογισμού. Είναι ένα ζωτικής σημασίας μέρος 
των διαφορετικών σταδίων στον κύκλο ζωής. Αυτό το σχέδιο 
μαθήματος θα βοηθήσει τους σπουδαστές να καταλάβουν και να γίνουν
πιό ενήμερους για την ανθρώπινη συμπεριφορά τους όπως αφορά την 
έννοια του ηθικού συλλογισμού.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Hay muchos aspectos a la comprensión del 
comportamiento humano. El estudio de la psicología sería 
incompleto sin un análisis detallado de seis etapas de Lorenzo 
Kohlberg de razonamiento moral. Es una parte vital de las 
diversas etapas en el ciclo vital. Esta voluntad del plan de la 
lección ayuda a estudiantes a entender y a ser más enterados de su 
propio comportamiento humano mientras que se relaciona con el concepto
del razonamiento moral.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JAMES MACH
FN:JAMES MACH
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202585</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104416</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/lawrence-kohlbergs-six-stages-of-moral-reasoning</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
