<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105737</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105737</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206225</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">NSF Science and Technology Center for Environmentally Responsible Solvents and Processes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">NSF Wissenschaft und Technologie-Mitte für 
umweltsmäßig verantwortliche Lösungsmittel und Prozesse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science de NSF et centre de technologie pour les
dissolvants dans l'environnement responsables et des processus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência do NSF e centro da tecnologia para 
solventes ambiental responsáveis e processos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza del NSF e centro di tecnologia per i 
solventi in condizioni ambientali responsabili ed i processi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κέντρο επιστήμης NSF και τεχνολογίας για τους 
περιβαλλοντικά αρμόδιους διαλύτες και τις διαδικασίες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia del NSF y centro de la tecnología para los
solventes ambientalmente responsables y los procesos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">provides activities for exploring carbon dioxide and polymers. Learn how much carbon dioxide is in a soda. Make carbon dioxide and observe its effects. Create silly putty and oobleck to learn about polymers. Test how much water can be absorbed by polyacrylate (the absorbent polymer in disposable diapers).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt Aktivitäten für erforschendes Kohlendioxyd
und Polymer-Plastiken zur Verfügung. Erlernen Sie, wieviel 
Kohlendioxyd in einem Soda ist. Bilden Sie Kohlendioxyd und 
beobachten Sie seine Effekte. Erstellen Sie dummen Kitt und 
oobleck, um über Polymer-Plastiken zu erlernen. Prüfen Sie, 
wieviel Wasser durch polyacrylate (das saugfähige Polymer-Plastik in 
den Wegwerfwindeln) aufgesogen werden kann.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fournit des activités pour l'anhydride carbonique 
et les polymères les explorant. Apprenez combien anhydride 
carbonique coûte dans une soude. Préparez l'anhydride 
carbonique et observez ses effets. Créez le mastic et l'oobleck
idiots pour se renseigner sur des polymères. Testez combien 
d'eau peut être absorbée par le polyacrylate (le polymère absorbant
dans des couches-culottes jetables).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fornece atividades para o dióxido e polímeros 
explorando de carbono. Aprenda quanto dióxido de carbono está 
em uma soda. Faça o dióxido de carbono e observe seus efeitos.
Críe o putty e o oobleck silly para aprender sobre polímeros. 
Teste quanto água pode ser absorvida pelo polyacrylate (o 
polímero absorvente em diapers descartáveis).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fornisce le attività per l'anidride carbonica ed i
polimeri d'esplorazione. Impari quanta anidride carbonica è in 
una soda. Prepari l'anidride carbonica ed osservi i relativi 
effetti. Crei il mastice ed il oobleck silly per imparare circa 
i polimeri. Esamini quanta acqua può essere assorbita da 
polyacrylate (il polimero assorbente in diapers a gettare).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρέχει τις δραστηριότητες για την εξερεύνηση του 
διοξειδίου του άνθρακα και των πολυμερών σωμάτων. Μάθετε 
πόσο διοξείδιο του άνθρακα είναι σε μια σόδα. Κάνετε το 
διοξείδιο του άνθρακα και παρατηρήστε τα αποτελέσματά του. 
Δημιουργήστε ανόητο putty και oobleck για να μάθετε για
τα πολυμερή σώματα. Εξετάστε πόσο ύδωρ μπορεί να 
απορροφηθεί από το polyacrylate (το απορροφητικό πολυμερές 
σώμα στις μίας χρήσης πάνες).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">proporciona a las actividades para el bióxido y 
los polímeros de carbono que exploran. Aprenda cuánto bióxido
de carbono está en una soda. Haga el bióxido de carbono y 
observe sus efectos. Cree la masilla y el oobleck tontos para 
aprender sobre los polímeros. Pruebe cuánto agua se puede 
absorber por el polyacrylate (el polímero absorbente en pañales 
disponibles).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206225</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105737</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/nsf-science-and-technology-center-for-environmentally-responsible-solvents-and-processes</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
