<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105849</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105849</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205446</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Not in Our Town Northern California: Staging a Response to Hate - Newark, CA</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nicht in unserer Stadt Nordkalifornien: 
Inszenierung eine Antwort zum Haß - Newark, Ca</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pas en notre ville la Californie nordique : 
Mettant en scène une réponse à la haine - Newark, CA</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Não em nossa cidade Califórnia do norte: 
Encenando uma resposta ao ódio - Newark, CA</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Non nella nostra città California del Nord: 
Organizzando una risposta ad avversione - Newark, CA</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Όχι στην πόλη μας βόρεια Καλιφόρνια: 
Οργανώνοντας μια απάντηση στο μίσος - Newark, ασβέστιο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">No en nuestra ciudad California norteña: 
Efectuando una respuesta al odio - Newark, CA</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">"Not In Our Town Northern California: When Hate Happens Here" looks at five communities that are dealing with hate violence. This Educator Guide addresses events that took place in Newark. Students from Memorial High School were planning a presentation of "The Laramie Project" for their fall play when they learned that one of their peers, a transgender student, had been murdered in a crime similar to the one they were exploring on stage. This Guide includes discussion ideas and activities related to hate crimes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Nicht In Unserer Stadt Nordkalifornien: 
Wenn Haß hier "Blicke bei fünf Gemeinschaften geschieht, die 
Haßgewalttätigkeit beschäftigen. Diese Erzieher-Anleitung 
adressiert Fälle, die in Newark stattfanden. Kursteilnehmer von
der Erinnerungshigh School planten eine Darstellung "des Laramie 
Projektes" für ihr Fallspiel, als sie dieser ihrer Gleichen 
erlernten, ein transgender Kursteilnehmer, waren ermordet worden in 
einem Verbrechen, das bis das ähnlich ist, das sie auf Stadium 
erforschten. Diese Anleitung schließt die Diskussion Ideen und 
Aktivitäten ein, die auf Haßverbrechen in Verbindung gestanden 
werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Pas En Notre Ville La Californie Nordique : 
Quand la haine se produit ici des "regards aux cinq communautés
qui traitent la violence de haine. Ce guide d'éducateur adresse
les événements qui ont eu lieu à Newark. Les étudiants du 
lycée commémoratif projetaient une présentation "du projet de 
Laramie" pour leur jeu de chute quand ils ont appris celui-là de 
leurs pairs, un étudiant de transgender, avaient été assassinés 
dans un crime semblable à celui qu'ils les exploraient sur l'étape. 
Ce guide inclut des idées et des activités de discussion 
liées aux crimes de haine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Não Em Nossa Cidade Califórnia Do norte: 
Quando o ódio acontecer aqui "olhares em cinco comunidades que 
estão tratando da violência do ódio. Esta guia do educador 
dirige-se aos eventos que ocorreram em Newark. Os estudantes da 
High School memorial planeavam uma apresentação "do projeto de 
Laramie" para seu jogo quando aprenderam esse de seus pares, um 
estudante da queda do transgender, tinham sido assassinados em um 
crime similar a esse que exploravam no estágio. Esta guia 
inclui as idéias e as atividades da discussão relacionadas aos 
crimes do ódio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Non Nella Nostra Città California Del Nord: 
Quando l'avversione accade qui "sguardi a cinque Comunità che 
stanno occupandosi della violenza di avversione. Questa guida 
dell'educatore richiama gli eventi che hanno avvenuto a Newark. 
Gli allievi dalla High School commemorativa stavano progettando 
una presentazione "del progetto Laramie" per il loro gioco quando 
hanno imparato quell'dei loro pari, un allievo di caduta del 
transgender, erano stati assassinati in un crimine simile a quello che
stavano esplorando sulla fase. Questa guida include le idee e le
attività di discussione relative ai crimini di avversione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Όχι στην πόλη μας βόρεια Καλιφόρνια: Όταν το 
μίσος συμβαίνει ότι εδώ "εξετάζει πέντε κοινότητες που 
εξετάζουν τη βία μίσους. Αυτός ο οδηγός εκπαιδευτικών 
εξετάζει τα γεγονότα που πραγματοποιήθηκαν στο Newark. Οι 
σπουδαστές από το αναμνηστικό γυμνάσιο προγραμμάτιζαν μια 
παρουσίαση "του προγράμματος Laramie" για το παιχνίδι πτώσης 
τους όταν έμαθαν ότι ένας από τους συνομήληκούς τους, ένας 
transgender σπουδαστής, ήταν δολοφονημένος σε ένα έγκλημα 
παρόμοιο με αυτό που εξερευνούσαν στη σκηνή. Αυτός ο 
οδηγός περιλαμβάνει τις ιδέες και τις δραστηριότητες συζήτησης 
σχετικές με τα εγκλήματα μίσους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"No En Nuestra Ciudad California Norteña: 
Cuando sucede el odio aquí las "miradas en cinco comunidades 
que se estén ocupando de violencia del odio. Esta guía del 
educador trata los acontecimientos que ocurrieron en Newark. Los
estudiantes de la High School secundaria conmemorativa planeaban una 
presentación "del proyecto de Laramie" para su juego cuando 
aprendieron a aquél de sus pares, estudiante de la caída del 
transgender, habían sido asesinados en un crimen similar a el que 
exploraban en etapa. Esta guía incluye las ideas y las 
actividades de la discusión relacionadas con los crímenes del odio.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205446</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105849</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/not-in-our-town-northern-california-staging-a-response-to-hate-newark-ca</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
