<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105036</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105036</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200490</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Aquifer Basics</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Aquifer-Grundlagen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Fondations de Couche aquifère</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Princípios Do Aquifer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Principi fondamentali Dello Strato acquifero</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βασικά υδροφόρων στρωμάτων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fundamentos Del Acuífero</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This USGS site explains what an aquifer is and defines the different types of aquifers based on six principal lithologies; sandstone, carbonate, sandstone-carbonate, igneous and metamorphic, sand and gravel, and other rock types. The site features maps and descriptions of the major aquifers in the United States as well as general information about groundwater occurrence and quality. The site also provides links to additional maps and data about specific aquifers across the nation.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese USGS Site erklärt, was ein Aquifer ist und 
definiert die unterschiedlichen Typen der Aquifers, die auf sechs 
allgemeinen Lithologien basieren; Sandstein, Karbonat, 
Sandstein-Karbonat, Eruptiv- und metamorphes, Sand und Kies und andere
Felsentypen. Die Situationsmerkmalkarten und die Beschreibungen 
der Hauptaquifers in den Vereinigten Staaten sowie allgemeine 
Informationen über Grundwasserauftreten und -qualität. Die 
Site stellt auch Links zu den zusätzlichen Karten und Daten über 
spezifische Aquifers über der Nation zur Verfügung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site d'USGS explique ce qu'est une couche 
aquifère et définit les différents types de couches aquifères 
basées sur six principales lithologies ; grès, carbonate, 
grès-carbonate, igné et métamorphique, sable et gravier, et 
d'autres types de roche. Les cartes de dispositifs de site et 
les descriptions des couches aquifères principales aux Etats-Unis 
aussi bien que des informations générales au sujet d'occurrence et 
de qualité d'eaux souterraines. Le site fournit également des 
liens aux cartes supplémentaires et des données au sujet des couches
aquifères spécifiques à travers la nation.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local de USGS explica o que um aquifer é e 
define os tipos diferentes de aquifers baseados em seis lithologies 
principais; sandstone, carbonato, sandstone-carbonato, igneous e
metamorphic, areia e cascalho, e outros tipos da rocha. Os mapas
das características de local e as descrições dos aquifers 
principais nos estados unidos as.well.as a informação geral sobre a 
ocorrência e a qualidade do groundwater. O local fornece 
também as ligações aos mapas adicionais e os dados sobre aquifers 
específicos através da nação.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo di USGS spiega che cosa uno strato 
acquifero è e definisce i tipi differenti di strati acquiferi basati 
sulle sei litologie principali; arenaria, carbonato, 
arenaria-carbonato, igneo e metamorfico, sabbia e ghiaia ed altri tipi
della roccia. I programmi delle caratteristiche di luogo e le 
descrizioni degli strati acquiferi principali in unito Dichiara
come pure generalità sulla presenza e sulla qualità dell'acqua 
freatica. Il luogo egualmente fornisce i collegamenti ai 
programmi supplementari ed i dati circa gli strati acquiferi 
specifici attraverso la nazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή USGS εξηγεί τι ένα υδροφόρο στρώμα
είναι και καθορίζει τους διαφορετικούς τύπους υδροφόρων 
στρωμάτων βασισμένων σε έξι κύριες λιθολογίες  ψαμμίτης, 
ανθρακικό άλας, ψαμμίτης-ανθρακικό άλας, πύρινος και 
μεταμορφικός, άμμος και αμμοχάλικο, και άλλοι τύποι βράχου. 
Η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει τους χάρτες και τις περιγραφές των 
σημαντικότερων υδροφόρων στρωμάτων στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες καθώς
επίσης και γενικές πληροφορία για το περιστατικό και την ποιότητα
υπόγειων νερών. Η περιοχή παρέχει επίσης τις συνδέσεις με 
τους πρόσθετους χάρτες και τα στοιχεία για τα συγκεκριμένα 
υδροφόρα στρώματα σε ολόκληρο το έθνος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio de USGS explica cuál es un acuífero y
define los diversos tipos de acuíferos basados en seis lithologies 
principales; piedra arenisca, carbonato, piedra-carbonato, 
ígneo y metamórfico, arena y grava, y otros tipos de la roca. 
Las correspondencias de las características de sitio y las 
descripciones de los acuíferos principales en los Estados Unidos así
como la información de carácter general sobre ocurrencia y calidad 
de la agua subterránea. El sitio también proporciona a 
conexiones a las correspondencias adicionales y a datos sobre los 
acuíferos específicos a través de la nación.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200490</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105036</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/aquifer-basics</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
