<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107371</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107371</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086843</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Sowing and reaping."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"säend und erntend."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"semant et récoltant."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"semeando e reaping."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"seminando e raccogliendo."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Σπορά και συγκέντρωση."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"sembrando y cosechando."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The northern  Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper  presented an unflattering portrait of southern white womanhood in a May 1863 illustration. The depiction contrasted sharply with the view promoted by plantation elites of virtuous southern white mothers and wives who obeyed and deferred to men. The panel on the left showed southern women hounding their men on to Rebellion." The panel on the right depicted them "feeling the effects of Rebellion and creating Bread Riots." The latter panel referred to the Richmond bread riot</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die aufrichtigen des Nordleslies erläuterte Zeitung 
stellte ein unflattering Portrait des südlichen weißen womanhood a 
Mai 1863 in der Abbildung dar. Die Beschreibung kontrastierte 
scharf zur Ansicht, die durch Plantageauslesen der rechtschaffenen 
südlichen weißen Mütter und der Frauen, die, gefördert wurde zu 
den Männern befolgten und aufschoben. Das Panel auf den linken 
gezeigten südlichen Frauen, die an verfolgen ihre Männer zum 
Aufstand." Das Panel auf dem Recht stellte sie "den Effekten des
Aufstands glaubend und Brot-Aufstände erstellend." bildlich dar 
Das letzte Panel sprach den Richmond Brotaufstand an</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le journal illustré du Leslie franc nordique a présenté
une verticale unflattering de condition féminine blanche méridionale dans 
l'illustration de a mai 1863. La description a différé 
brusquement de la vue favorisée par des élites de plantation des 
mères et des épouses blanches méridionales vertueuses qui ont obéi
et ont reporté aux hommes. Le panneau sur les femmes 
méridionales montrées gauches traquant leurs hommes en fonction à 
la rébellion." Le panneau du côté droit les a dépeints 
"sentant les effets de la rébellion et créant des émeutes de pain."
Le dernier panneau s'est rapporté à l'émeute de pain de 
Richmond</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O jornal ilustrado do Leslie frank do norte apresentou um 
retrato unflattering do womanhood branco do sul na ilustração de a 
maio 1863. O depiction contrastou agudamente com a vista 
promovida por elites da plantação das matrizes e das esposas brancas
do sul virtuous que obedeceram e adiaram para homens. O painel 
nas mulheres do sul mostradas esquerdas que perseguem seus homens 
sobre à rebelião." O painel na direita descreveu-os "que 
sentem os efeitos da rebelião e que críam motins do pão." O 
último painel consultou ao motim do pão de Richmond</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il giornale illustrato del Leslie franco nordico ha 
presentato un ritratto unflattering del womanhood bianco del sud 
nell'illustrazione di a maggio 1863. Il depiction ha 
contrapposto acutamente con la vista promossa dalle elite della 
piantagione delle madri e delle mogli bianche del sud virtuose che 
hanno obbedito e rinviato agli uomini. Il pannello sulle donne 
del sud indicate di sinistra che perseguitano i loro uomini sopra alla
Ribellione." Il pannello a destra lo ha descritti "che 
ritengono gli effetti della Ribellione e che creano i tumulti del 
pane." Il pannello posteriore si è riferito al tumulto del pane
de Richmond</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η βόρεια διευκρινισμένη εφημερίδα του Frank 
Leslie's παρουσίασε ένα ελάχιστα κολακευτικό πορτρέτο της 
νότιας άσπρης γυναικείας φύσης σε έναν Μάιος 1863 
απεικόνιση. Η απεικόνιση αντιπαρέβαλε αισθητά με την όψη 
που προωθήθηκε από τη φυτεία elites των ενάρετων νότιων 
λευκών μητέρων και των συζύγων που υπακουσμένος και αναβεβλημένος
στα άτομα. Η επιτροπή στις αριστερές εμφανισμένες νότιες 
γυναίκες poy οι άνδρες τους προς την εξέγερση." Η 
επιτροπή στο δικαίωμα τους απεικόνισε "που αισθάνονται τα 
αποτελέσματα της εξέγερσης και που δημιουργούν τις ταραχές 
ψωμιού." Η τελευταία επιτροπή αναφέρθηκε στην ταραχή 
ψωμιού του Ρίτσμοντ</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El periódico ilustrado del Leslie franco norteño 
presentó un retrato unflattering del womanhood blanco meridional en 
la ilustración de a mayo de 1863. La pintura puso en contraste 
sostenidamente con la visión promovida por las élites de la 
plantación de las madres y de las esposas blancas meridionales 
virtuosas que obedecieron y difirieron a los hombres. El panel 
en las mujeres meridionales mostradas izquierdas que persiguen a sus 
hombres encendido a la rebelión." El panel a la derecha los 
representó "que sentían los efectos de la rebelión y que creaban 
alborotos del pan." El último panel refirió al alboroto del 
pan de Richmond</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086843</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107371</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/sowing-and-reaping</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
