<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106475</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106475</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087463</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Camella Teoli Testifies about the 1912 Lawrence Textile Strike</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Camella Teoli bezeugt über den Lawrence 
Textilschlag 1912</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Camella Teoli témoigne au sujet de la grève 1912
de textile de Laurent</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Camella Teoli testifies sobre a batida 1912 de 
textile de Lawrence</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Camella Teoli testimonia circa il colpo 1912 della
tessile del Lawrence</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Camella Teoli πιστοποιεί για την υφαντική 
απεργία Lawrence του 1912</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Camella Teoli atestigua sobre la huelga 1912 del 
textil de Lorenzo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">When 30,000 largely immigrant workers walked out of the Lawrence, Massachusetts, textile mills in January 1912, they launched one of the epic confrontations between capital and labor. The strike began in part because of unsafe working conditions in the mills, which were described in graphic detail in the testimony that fourteen-year-old millworker Camella Teoli delivered before a U.S. Congressional hearing in March 1912. Her testimony (a portion of which was included here) about losing her hair when it got caught in a textile machine she was operating gained national headlines in 1912--in part because Helen Herron Taft, the wife of the president, was in the audience when Teoli testified. The resulting publicity helped secure a strike victory.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Als 30.000 groß einwandernde Arbeiter aus dem 
Lawrence, Massachusetts heraus gingen, Textiltausendstel im Januar 
1912, stießen sie eine der epischen Konfrontationen zwischen Kapital 
und Arbeit aus. Der Schlag fing im Teil wegen der unsicheren 
Arbeitsbedingungen in den Tausendsteln an, die ausführlich 
graphisches im Zeugnis beschrieben wurden, das vierzehn-Jahr-alter 
Fabrikarbeiter Camella Teoli vor einer VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Kongreßhörfähigkeit im März 1912 lieferte. Ihr Zeugnis 
(deren Teil hier eingeschlossen war), über das Verlieren ihres 
Haares, als er in einer Textilmaschine abgefangen erhielt, die sie 
gewonnene nationale Schlagzeilen 1912 laufen ließ -- im Teil, weil 
Helen Herron Taft, die Frau des Präsidenten, in den Publikum war, als
Teoli bezeugte. Die resultierende Werbung half sicher einem 
Schlagsieg.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Quand 30.000 ouvriers en grande partie immigrés 
ont marché hors de Laurent, le Massachusetts, des moulins de textile 
en janvier 1912, ils ont lancé une des confrontations épiques entre 
le capital et le travail. La grève a commencé en partie en 
raison des conditions de travail peu sûres dans les moulins, qui ont 
été décrits dans le détail graphique dans le témoignage que le 
quatorze-année-vieil ouvrier d'usine Camella Teoli a fourni avant une
audition congressionnelle des ETATS-UNIS en mars 1912. Son 
témoignage (dont une partie a été inclus ici) au sujet de détruire
ses cheveux quand elle s'est faite attraper dans une machine de 
textile qu'elle actionnait les titres nationaux gagnés en 1912 -- en 
partie parce que Helen Herron Taft, l'épouse du président, était 
dans les assistances quand Teoli a témoigné. La publicité 
résultante a aidé bloqué une victoire de grève.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quando 30.000 trabalhadores pela maior parte 
immigrant andaram fora do Lawrence, Massachusetts, moinhos de textile 
em janeiro 1912, lançaram um dos confrontations epic entre o capital 
e o trabalho. A batida começou na parte por causa das 
condições de funcionamento inseguras nos moinhos, que foram 
descritos no detalhe gráfico no testimony que o millworker 
quatorze-ano-velho Camella Teoli entregou antes de um hearing 
congressional de ESTADOS UNIDOS em março 1912. Seu testimony 
(uma parcela de que foi incluído aqui) sobre perder seu cabelo quando
começou travada em uma máquina que de textile operava headlines 
nacionais ganhos em 1912 -- na parte porque Helen Herron Taft, esposa 
do presidente, estava nas audiências quando Teoli testified. O 
publicity resultante ajudou seguro a uma vitória da batida.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Quando 30.000 operai in gran parte immigrati hanno
camminato dal Lawrence, Massachusetts, laminatoi della tessile nel 
mese di gennaio del 1912, hanno lanciato uno dei confronti epic fra 
capitale ed il lavoro. Il colpo ha cominciato in parte a 
causa delle condizioni di lavoro pericolose nei laminatoi, che sono 
stati descritti in dettaglio grafico nella testimonianza che il 
quattordici-anno-vecchio operaio di fabbrica Camella Teoli ha 
trasportato prima di un'udienza congressuale degli STATI UNITI nel 
mese di marzo del 1912. La sua testimonianza (una parte di cui 
è stato incluso qui) circa perdere i suoi capelli quando ha ottenuto 
interferito in una macchina che della tessile stava funzionando i 
titoli nazionali guadagnati in 1912 -- in parte perché Helen Herron 
Taft, la moglie del presidente, era nei pubblici quando Teoli ha 
testimoniato. La pubblicità risultante ha aiutato sicuro una 
vittoria di colpo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Όταν 30.000 κατά ένα μεγάλο μέρος που έχουν 
μεταναστεύσει εργαζόμενοι περπάτησαν από το Lawrence, 
Μασαχουσέτη, υφαντικοί μύλοι τον Ιανουάριο του 1912, προώθησαν
μια από τις επικές αντιπαραθέσεις μεταξύ του κεφαλαίου και της 
εργασίας. Η απεργία άρχισε εν μέρει λόγω των επισφαλών 
συνθηκών εργασίας στους μύλους, οι οποίοι περιγράφηκαν με 
γραφικές λεπτομέρειες στην κατάθεση ότι 
δεκατέσσερις-χρονών millworker Camella Teoli που 
παραδόθηκε πριν από μια ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ του Κογκρέσου ακρόαση τις 
1912, Μαρτίου την κατάθεσή της (μια μερίδα της οποίας 
συμπεριλήφθηκε εδώ) για την απώλεια της τρίχας της όταν πήρε 
πιασμένη σε μια υφαντική μηχανή ενεργοποιούσε τους κερδισμένους 
εθνικούς τίτλους το 1912 -- εν μέρει επειδή η Helen 
Herron Taft, η σύζυγος του Προέδρου, ήταν στο ακροατήριο 
όταν πιστοποίησε Teoli. Η προκύπτουσα δημοσιότητα που 
ενισχύεται να εξασφαλίσει μια νίκη απεργίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cuando 30.000 trabajadores en gran parte 
inmigrantes recorrieron del Lorenzo, Massachusetts, los molinos del 
textil en enero de 1912, lanzaron una de las confrontaciones épicas 
entre el capital y el trabajo. La huelga comenzó en parte 
debido a condiciones de trabajo inseguras en los molinos, que fueron 
descritos en detalle gráfico en el testimonio que el 
catorce-año-viejo obrero Camella Teoli entregó antes de una 
audiencia del congreso de ESTADOS UNIDOS en marcha de 1912. Su 
testimonio (una porción de el cual fue incluido aquí) sobre perder 
su pelo cuando consiguió cogida en una máquina del textil que ella 
funcionaba títulos nacionales ganados en 1912 -- en parte porque 
Helen Herron Taft, la esposa del presidente, estaba en las audiencias 
cuando Teoli atestiguó. La publicidad que resultaba ayudó 
seguro a una victoria de la huelga.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087463</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106475</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/camella-teoli-testifies-about-the-1912-lawrence-textile-strike</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
