<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106800</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106800</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087169</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Waiting for the Reduction of the Army."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">", die Verkleinerung der Armee wartend."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"attendant la réduction de l'armée."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"esperando a redução do exército."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"aspettando la riduzione dell'esercito."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Περιμένοντας τη μείωση του στρατού."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"esperando la reducción del ejército."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The massive strike of 1877 shook the very foundations of the political and economic order. Begun with a spontaneous railroad strike in West Virginia, the "Great Uprising" spread rapidly across the country, as the entire working populations of many cities went out on strike. Workers across the country along with sympathizers in their communities were galvanized by official violence, as state and federal troops fired on protesters in several cities. As this 1878 cartoon from the  New York Daily Graphic  indicated, in the aftermath of the strike Indians, trade unionists, immigrants, and tramps were increasingly grouped together in the press as symbols of disorder and opposition to the nation's progress.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der massive Schlag von 1877 rüttelte die Grundlagen der 
politischen und ökonomischen Ordnung. Angefangen mit einem 
spontanen Eisenbahnschlag in West Virginia, erlosch der "große 
Aufstieg", der schnell über dem Land, als die gesamten 
erwerbstätigen Bevölkerungen vieler Städte verbritten wurde, auf 
Schlag. Arbeiter über dem Land zusammen mit Gleichgesinnten in 
ihren Gemeinschaften wurden durch amtliche Gewalttätigkeit, als 
Zustand und Bundestruppen galvanisiert, die auf Protesters in einigen 
Städte gefeuert wurden. Als diese Karikatur 1878 von der 
angezeigten New York täglichen Graphik, in der Nachmahd der Schlag 
Inder, wurden Gewerkschaftler, Immigranten und die Tramps in 
zunehmendem Maße zusammen in der Presse als Symbole der Störung und 
der Opposition zum Fortschritt der Nation gruppiert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La grève massive de 1877 a secoué les bases mêmes de 
l'ordre politique et économique. Commencé par une grève 
spontanée de chemin de fer en Virginie Occidentale, le "grand 
soulèvement" écarté rapidement à travers le pays, comme 
populations actives entières de beaucoup de villes est sorti en 
grève. Des ouvriers à travers le pays avec des sympathisants 
dans leurs communautés ont été galvanisés par violence officielle,
comme état et troupes fédérales mis le feu sur des protestataires 
dans plusieurs villes. En tant que ce dessin animé 1878 du 
graphique quotidien de New York indiqué, dans la conséquence des 
Indiens de grève, des syndicalistes, les immigrés, et les vagabonds 
ont été de plus en plus groupés ensemble dans la presse comme 
symboles de désordre et d'opposition au progrès de la nation.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A batida maciça de 1877 agitou as fundações very da 
ordem política e econômica. Começado com uma batida 
espontânea da estrada de ferro em Virgínia ocidental, "o uprising 
grande" espalhado ràpidamente através do país, como as populações
de funcionamento inteiras de muitas cidades saiu na batida. Os 
trabalhadores através do país junto com sympathizers em suas 
comunidades galvanized pela violência oficial, como o estado e as 
tropas federais ateados fogo em protesters em diversas cidades. 
Como este cartoon 1878 do gráfico diário de New York indicado,
no aftermath dos indians da batida, os unionists de comércio, os 
immigrants, e as caminhadas foram agrupados cada vez mais junto na 
imprensa como símbolos do disorder e da oposição ao progresso da 
nação.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il colpo voluminoso di 1877 ha agitato i fondamenti stessi
dell'ordine politico ed economico. Cominciato con un colpo 
spontaneo della ferrovia nella Virginia dell'Ovest, "la Rivolta 
grande" sparsa velocemente attraverso il paese, come le intere 
popolazione attiva di molte città ha uscito sul colpo. Gli 
operai attraverso il paese con i simpatizzanti nelle loro Comunità 
sono stati galvanizzati dalla violenza ufficiale, come dichiarano
e dalle truppe federali infornate sui contestatori in parecchie città.
Come questo fumetto 1878 dal grafico quotidiano de New York 
indicato, nel guaime degli indiani di colpo, i sindacalisti, gli 
immigranti ed i vagabondi sempre più sono stati raggruppati insieme 
nella pressa come simboli di disordine e di opposizione al progresso 
della nazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ογκώδης απεργία 1877 τίναξε τα ίδια τα θεμέλια 
της πολιτικής και οικονομικής τάξης. Αρχισμένη με μια 
αυθόρμητη απεργία σιδηροδρόμου στη δυτική Βιρτζίνια, η "μεγάλη 
έγερση" διέδωσε γρήγορα σε ολόκληρη τη χώρα, όπως οι ολόκληροι 
οικονομικά ενεργοί πληθυσμοί πολλών πόλεων βγήκαν στην απεργία.
Οι εργαζόμενοι σε ολόκληρη τη χώρα μαζί με τους 
υποστηρικτές στις κοινότητές τους γαλβανίστηκαν από την επίσημη 
βία, ως κράτος και ομοσπονδιακά στρατεύματα που βάλθηκαν φωτιά 
στους διαμαρτυρομένους σε διάφορες πόλεις. Σαν αυτά τα 
κινούμενα σχέδια 1878 από γραφική δειγμένη της Νέας Υόρκης 
καθημερινά, στη συνέπεια της απεργίας Ινδοί, οι συνδικαλιστές, οι
μετανάστες, και οι αγύρτες συγκεντρώθηκαν όλο και περισσότερο 
στον Τύπο ως σύμβολα της αναταραχής και της αντίθεσης στην πρόοδο
του έθνους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La huelga masiva de 1877 quebrantó las mismas bases de la
orden política y económica. Comenzado con una huelga 
espontánea del ferrocarril en Virginia Occidental, la "gran 
sublevación" separada rápidamente a través del país, como las 
poblaciones en activo enteras de muchas ciudades salió en huelga. 
Violencia oficial galvanizaron a los trabajadores a través del 
país junto con simpatizantes en sus comunidades, como el estado y 
tropas federales encendidos en manifestantes en varias ciudades. 
Como esta historieta 1878 del gráfico diario de Nueva York 
indicado, en las consecuencias de los indios de la huelga, agruparon a
los unionistas comerciales, a los inmigrantes, y a los vagabundos cada
vez más juntos en la prensa como símbolos del desorden y de la 
oposición al progreso de la nación.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087169</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106800</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/waiting-for-the-reduction-of-the-army</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
