<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106185</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106185</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087118</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Time Did Not Reconcile Me To My Chains": Charles Ball's Journey to South Carolina, 1837</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Zeit Versöhnte Mich Nicht Zu Meinen Ketten": 
Reise der Charles Kugel nach Südcarolina, 1837</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le "Temps Ne m'a pas réconcilié À Mes Chaînes"
: Le voyage de la boule de Charles vers la Caroline du sud,
1837</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O "Tempo Não reconcile Me A Minhas Correntes": 
Viagem da esfera de Charles a carolina sul, 1837</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Il Tempo Non lo ha riconciliato Alle Mie Catene":
Viaggio della sfera del Charles a Carolina del Sud, 1837</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ο χρόνος δεν με συμφιλίωσε στις αλυσίδες μου": 
Ταξίδι Charles Ball's στη νότια Καρολίνα, 1837</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El "Tiempo No me reconcilió A Mis 
Encadenamientos": Viaje de la bola de Charles a Carolina del 
Sur, 1837</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Charles Ball was born a slave around 1785 in Calvert County, Maryland. When he was four years old, his family was broken up by the sale of his mother. As a young man he was separated from his wife and children and sold to a slave trader. The journey described here occurred after that sale. Ball carefully observed his route and later used that knowledge to escape from a South Carolina cotton plantation and return to his family in Maryland. After his escape, Ball lived as a free man in Maryland and Washington, D.C. When his wife died, he remarried, established a new family, and farmed his own property near Baltimore. This period of happiness, however, did not last. Ball and his family were captured, separated, and dragged back into slavery. Although Ball managed to escape again, his family did not. He dictated this memoir while living in Philadelphia, free, but still fearful of recapture.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Charles Kugel wurde ein Sklave um 1785 in der 
Calvert Grafschaft, Maryland getragen. Als er vier Jahre alt 
war, war seine Familie oben durch den Verkauf seiner Mutter 
unterbrochen. Wie ein junger Mann er von seiner Frau und von 
Kindern getrennt wurde und an einen Sklavenhändler verkauft. 
Die Reise beschrieb hier nachher aufgetreten diesem Verkauf. 
Kugel beobachtete sorgfältig seinen Weg und verwendete später 
daß Wissen, von einer Südcarolina Baumwolplantage zu entgehen und zu
seiner Familie in Maryland zurückzugehen. Nachdem seins 
Entweichen, Kugel lebte, wie ein freier Mann in Maryland und in 
Washington, D.C., When, das seine Frau starb, remarried er, 
hergestellt einer neuen Familie, und seiner eigenen Eigenschaft nahe 
Baltimore bewirtschaftet. Diese Periode des Glückes jedoch 
dauerte nicht. Kugel und seine Familie wurden zurück in 
Sklaverei erfaßt, getrennt und geschleppt. Obgleich Kugel 
handhatte, wieder zu entgehen, seine Familie nicht. Er schrieb 
diese Abhandlung beim Wohnen in Philadelphia vor, frei, aber noch 
ängstlich von erlangen Sie wieder.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La boule de Charles a été soutenue autour un 
1785 slave dans le comté de Calvert, le Maryland. Quand il
avait quatre ans, sa famille était cassée vers le haut par la vente 
de sa mère. Comme un jeune homme il a été séparé de son 
épouse et enfants et vendu à un commerçant slave. Le 
voyage a décrit ici produit ensuite cette vente. La boule a 
soigneusement observé son itinéraire et plus tard l'a utilisé que 
la connaissance pour s'échapper d'une plantation du sud de coton
de la Caroline et pour retourner à sa famille dans le Maryland. 
Après que sien évasion, boule ait vécu comme un homme libre 
le Maryland et à Washington, D.C. When que son épouse est mort, il 
remarried, établi une nouvelle famille, et cultivé sa propre 
propriété près de Baltimore. Cette période de bonheur, 
cependant, n'a pas duré. La boule et sa famille ont été 
capturées, séparées, et traînées de nouveau dans l'esclavage. 
Bien que la boule soit parvenue à s'échapper encore, sa 
famille pas . Il a dicté ce mémoire tout en habitant à 
Philadelphie, libre, mais encore craintif de reprenez.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A esfera de Charles foi carregada um escravo em 
torno de 1785 no condado de Calvert, Maryland. Quando tinha 
quatro anos velho, sua família era quebrada acima pela venda de sua 
matriz. Como um homem novo ele foi separado de suas esposa e 
crianças e vendido a um comerciante slave. A viagem descreveu 
ocorrido aqui em seguida essa venda. A esfera observou com 
cuidado sua rota e usou-se mais tarde que conhecimento escapar-se de 
uma plantação do algodão de carolina sul e retornar a sua família 
em Maryland. Depois que his escape, esfera viveu como um homem 
livre em Maryland e em Washington, C.C. Quando que sua esposa morreu, 
remarried, estabelecido uma família nova, e cultivado sua própria 
propriedade perto de Baltimore. Este período da felicidade, 
entretanto, não durou. A esfera e sua família foram 
capturadas, separadas, e arrastadas para trás no slavery. 
Embora a esfera controlasse se escapar outra vez, sua família 
não . Ditou este memoir ao viver em Filadélfia, livre, mas 
ainda temível de recapture.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La sfera del Charles è stata sopportata uno 
schiavo verso 1785 nella contea di Calvert, Maryland. Quando 
aveva quattro anni, la sua famiglia era rotta in su dalla vendita 
della sua madre. Come un giovane lui è stato separato dalla 
suoi moglie e bambini ed è stato venduto ad un commerciante slave. 
Il viaggio ha descritto qui accaduto dopo quella vendita. 
La sfera ha osservato con attenzione il suo itinerario e più 
successivamente ha usato che conoscenza fuoriuscire da una piantagione
del cotone della Carolina del Sud e ritornare alla sua famiglia in 
Maryland. Dopo che suo fuga, sfera viva come un uomo libero in 
Maryland ed in Washington, D.C. When che la sua moglie è morto, 
remarried, stabilito una nuova famiglia e coltivato la sua propria 
proprietà vicino a Baltimora. Questo periodo di felicità, 
tuttavia, non ha durato. La sfera e la sua famiglia sono state 
bloccate, separato state e sono trascinato state nuovamente dentro 
slavery. Anche se la sfera è riuscito a fuoriuscire ancora, la 
sua famiglia non. Ha dettato questa memoria mentre viveva a 
Filadelfia, libera, ma ancora spaventoso di riprenda.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θ*Θχαρλες Ball γεννήθηκε ένας σκλάβος περίπου 
1785 Calvert στο νομό, Μέρυλαντ. Όταν ήταν τεσσάρων 
ετών, η οικογένειά του χωρίστηκε από την πώληση της μητέρας 
του. Σαν νεαρό άνδρα χωρίστηκε από τη σύζυγο και τα παιδιά
του και πώλησε σε έναν έμπορο σκλάβων. Το ταξίδι που 
περιγράφηκε εδώ εμφανίστηκε μετά από εκείνη την πώληση. Η
σφαίρα παρατήρησε προσεκτικά τη διαδρομή του και αργότερα 
χρησιμοποίησε ότι γνώση στη διαφυγή από μια φυτεία βαμβακιού 
της νότιας Καρολίνας και επιστροφή στην οικογένειά του στη 
Μέρυλαντ. Μετά από τη διαφυγή του, η σφαίρα έζησε ως 
ελεύθερο άτομο στη Μέρυλαντ και την Ουάσιγκτον, ΣΥΝΕΧΈΣ ΡΕΎΜΑ 
Όταν η σύζυγός του πέθανε, καθιέρωσε μια νέα οικογένεια, 
και καλλιέργησε την ιδιοκτησία του κοντά στη Βαλτιμόρη. 
Αυτή η περίοδος ευτυχίας, εντούτοις, δεν διάρκεσε. Η 
σφαίρα και η οικογένειά του συλλήφθηκαν, χωρίστηκαν, και 
σέρθηκαν πίσω στη σκλαβιά. Αν και η σφαίρα κατόρθωσε να 
δραπετεύσει πάλι, η οικογένειά του όχι. Υπαγόρευσε αυτά 
τα απομνημονεύματα ζωντανός στη Φιλαδέλφεια, ελεύθερη, αλλά 
ακόμα έντρομος συλλάβετε εκ νέου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La bola de Charles fue llevada un esclavo 
alrededor de 1785 en el condado de Calvert, Maryland. Cuando él
era cuatro años de viejo, su familia estaba quebrada para arriba por 
la venta de su madre. Como separaron de su esposa y niños y 
fueron vendido a un hombre joven él a un comerciante auxiliar. 
El viaje describió aquí ocurrido después esa venta. La 
bola observó cuidadosamente su ruta y la utilizó más adelante que 
conocimiento escaparse de una plantación del algodón de Carolina del
Sur y volver a su familia en Maryland. Después de que viviera 
el suyo escape, bola como un hombre libre en Maryland y Washington, 
D.C. When que su esposa murió, él remarried, establecido una nueva 
familia, y cultivado su propia característica cerca de Baltimore. 
Este período de la felicidad, sin embargo, no duró. 
Capturaron, fueron separadas, y arrastradas la bola y a su 
familia nuevamente dentro de esclavitud. Aunque la bola manejó 
escaparse otra vez, su familia no . Él dictó esta memoria 
mientras que vivía en Philadelphia, libre, pero todavía temeroso de 
recobre.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087118</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106185</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/time-did-not-reconcile-me-to-my-chains-charles-balls-journey-to-south-carolina-1837</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
