<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108035</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108035</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087400</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"And We Shall Overcome": President Lyndon B. Johnson's Special Message to Congress</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Und Wir Überwinden": Präsident Lyndon B. 
Johnsons Sondermeldung zum Kongreß</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Et Nous Surmonterons" : Message spécial du
Président Lyndon B. Johnson au congrès</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"E Nós Superaremos": Mensagem especial do 
presidente Lyndon B. Johnson ao congress</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"E Sormonteremo": Messaggio speciale del 
presidente Lyndon B. Johnson al congresso</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Και θα υπερνικήσουμε": Special μήνυμα 
Προέδρου Lyndon B. Johnson's στο συνέδριο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Y Superaremos": Mensaje especial de 
presidente Lyndon B. Johnson al congreso</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Although the 15th Amendment, ratified in 1870, guaranteed citizens the right to vote regardless of race, by 1957 only 20 percent of eligible African Americans voted, due in part to intimidation and discriminatory state requirements such as poll taxes and literacy tests. Despite the passage of the landmark Civil Rights Act of 1964, which outlawed discrimination in employment and public accommodations based on race, religion, national origin, or sex, efforts to register African Americans as voters in the South were stymied. In 1965, following the murder of a voting rights activist by an Alabama sheriff's deputy and the subsequent attack by state troopers on a massive protest march in Selma, Alabama, President Lyndon B. Johnson pressed Congress in the following speech to pass a voting rights bill with teeth. As Majority Leader of the Senate, Johnson had helped weaken the 1957 Civil Rights Act. When he assumed the presidency following the assassination of John F. Kennedy in November 1963, however, Johnson called on Americans "to eliminate from this nation every trace of discrimination and oppression that is based upon race or color," and in the following speech adopted the "We Shall Overcome" slogan of civil rights activists. His rhetoric and subsequent efforts broke with past presidential precedents of opposition to or lukewarm support for strong civil rights legislation. Johnson signed the Voting Rights Act of 1965 into law on August 6.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Obgleich die 15. Änderung, bestätigt 1870, 
Bürgern das Recht, unabhängig davon Rennen, durch 1957 nur 20 
Prozent geeignete afrikanische Amerikaner zu wählen garantierte, die 
gewählt wurden, im Teil zur Einschüchterung und in den 
diskriminierenden Zustandanforderungen wie Gemeindeabgaben und 
Bildungsgradtests passend. Trotz des Durchganges der Grenzstein 
Zivilrecht-Tat von 1964, die Unterscheidung in der Beschäftigung 
ächtete und Öffentlichkeit Anpassungen auf Rennen, Religion, 
nationalem Ursprung oder Geschlecht gründete, stymied Bemühungen, 
afrikanische Amerikaner zu registrieren, während Wähler im Süden 
waren. 1965 dem Mord an einem Aktivisten der wählenden Rechte 
vom Abgeordneten eines Alabama Polizeichefs und am folgenden Angriff 
von den Zustand troopers folgend auf einem massiven Protestmärz in 
Selma, Alabama, betätigte Präsident Lyndon B. Johnson Kongreß in 
der folgenden Rede, einen Gesetz der wählenden Rechte mit den Zähnen
zu verabschieden. Als Majorität Führer des Senats, hatte 
Johnson geholfen, die 1957 Zivilrecht-Tat zu schwächen. Als er 
den Vorsitz annahm, welche der Ermordung von John F. Kennedy im 
November 1963, jedoch, Johnson ersuchte Amerikaner "folgt, um von 
dieser Nation jede Spur der Unterscheidung und der Unterdrückung zu 
beseitigen, die, nach Rennen oder Farbe basiert," und in der folgenden
Rede nahm "wir überwindt" Slogan der Zivilrechtaktivisten an. 
Seine Rhetorik und folgenden Bemühungen brachen mit letzten 
Präsidentenpräzedenzfällen der Opposition zu oder des lauwarmen 
Supports für starke Zivilrechtgesetzgebung. Johnson 
unterzeichnete die wählende Recht-Tat von 1965 in Gesetz an August 6.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bien que le 15ème amendement, ratifié en 1870, 
ait garanti des citoyens la droite de voter indépendamment de la 
course, par 1957 seulement 20 pour cent d'Américains africains 
éligibles votés, dus en partie de l'intimidation et des conditions 
discriminatoires d'état telles que des impôts locaux et des essais 
d'instruction. En dépit du passage de l'acte de droits civiques
de borne limite de 1964, qui a proscrit la discrimination dans 
l'emploi et logement de public a basé sur la course, la religion, 
l'origine nationale, ou le sexe, les efforts d'enregistrer les 
Américains africains pendant que les électeurs dans les Sud 
étaient stymied. En 1965, suivant le meurtre d'un activiste de 
droit de vote du député d'un shérif de l'Alabama et de l'attaque 
ultérieure des soldats de la cavalerie d'état sur une march de protestation 
massive dans Selma, Alabama, le Président Lyndon B. Johnson a 
appuyé le congrès dans le discours suivant passer une facture de 
droit de vote avec des dents. Comme amorce de majorité du 
sénat, Johnson avait aidé à affaiblir la Loi de 1957 droits 
civiques. Quand il a assumé la présidence suivant l'assassinat
de John F. Kennedy en novembre 1963, cependant, Américains 
invités par Johnson "pour éliminer de cette nation chaque trace 
de discrimination et d'oppression qui est basée lors de la course ou 
de la couleur," et dans le discours suivant a adopté "nous 
surmontera" le slogan des activistes de droits civiques. Sa 
rhétorique et efforts ultérieurs se sont cassés avec des 
précédents présidentiels passés de l'opposition à ou du soutien 
tiède de la législation forte de droits civiques. Johnson 
a signé la Loi de droit de vote de 1965 dans la loi août 6.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Embora a 1ä emenda, ratificada em 1870, 
garantisse cidadãos a direita votar não obstante a raça, por 1957 
somente 20 por cento dos americanos africanos elegíveis votados, 
devidos na parte à intimidação e em exigências discriminatory do 
estado tais como impostos de votação e testes do literacy. 
Apesar da passagem do ato das direitas civis do marco de 1964, 
que outlawed a discriminação no emprego e acomodações do público 
baseou na raça, na religião, na origem nacional, ou no sexo, os 
esforços registar americanos africanos enquanto os eleitores no sul 
eram stymied. Em 1965, seguindo o assassinato de uma activista 
das direitas votando pelo deputado de um sheriff de Alabama e do 
ataque subseqüente por troopers do estado em um março de protesto 
maciço em Selma, Alabama, o presidente Lyndon B. Johnson pressionou o
congress no seguinte discurso passar uma conta das direitas votando 
com dentes. Como o líder da maioria do senate, Johnson tinha 
ajudado enfraquecer o ato de 1957 direitas civis. Quando supos o
presidency que segue o assassination de John F. Kennedy em novembro 
1963, entretanto, em americanos convidados Johnson "para eliminar 
desta nação cada traço da discriminação e do oppression que é 
baseado na raça ou na cor," e no seguinte discurso adotou "nós 
superará" o slogan de activistas das direitas civis. Seus 
rhetoric e esforços subseqüentes quebraram com precedents 
presidenciais passados da oposição a ou da sustentação morna para 
a legislação forte das direitas civis. Johnson assinou o ato 
das direitas votando de 1965 na lei agosto em 6.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Anche se la quindicesima correzione, ratificata in
1870, ha garantito i cittadini la destra votare senza riguardo alla 
corsa, da 1957 soltanto 20 per cento degli Americani africani 
eleggibili votati, dovuto in parte all'intimidazione e discriminatorio
dichiari i requisiti quali le tasse di scrutinio e le prove 
di literacy. Malgrado il passaggio della Legge di diritti civili
del limite di 1964, che ha proscritto la distinzione nell'occupazione 
e sistemazioni del pubblico ha basato sulla razza, sulla religione, 
sull'origine nazionale, o sul sesso, gli sforzi registrare gli 
Americani africani mentre gli elettori nel sud erano stymied. In
1965, seguendo l'omicidio di un attivista di diritti di voto dal 
delegato e dall'attacco successivo dello sheriff dell'Alabama vicino 
dichiari i troopers su un procedere di protesta voluminoso in
Selma, Alabama, congresso premuto Johnson del presidente Lyndon B. nel
seguente discorso per passare una fattura di diritti di voto con i 
denti. Come Capo di maggioranza del senato, Johnson 
aveva contribuito ad indebolire la Legge di 1957 diritti civili. 
Quando ha ammesso la presidenza che segue l'assassinio di John
F. Kennedy in novembre del 1963, tuttavia, in Americani invitati 
Johnson "per eliminare da questa nazione ogni traccia di distinzione e
del oppression che è basato sulla corsa o sul colore," e nel seguente
discorso ha adottato "noi sormonterà" lo slogan degli attivisti di
diritti civili. La suoi retorica e sforzi successivi si sono 
rotti con i precedenti presidenziali passati di opposizione a o di 
sostegno tiepido legislazione forte di diritti civili. Johnson 
ha firmato la Legge di diritti di voto di 1965 in legge il 6 agosto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αν και η 15$η τροποποίηση, που επικυρώθηκε το 1870, 
εγγυήθηκε στους πολίτες το δικαίωμα να ψηφίσει ανεξάρτητα από τη
φυλή, μέχρι το 1957 μόνο 20 τοις εκατό επιλέξιμων αφρικανικών
Αμερικανών που ψηφίστηκαν, που οφείλονται εν μέρει στον εκφοβισμό
και τις μεροληπτικές κρατικές απαιτήσεις όπως οι κεφαλικοί φόροι
και οι δοκιμές βασικής εκπαίδευσης. Παρά τη μετάβαση του 
νόμου αστικών δικαιωμάτων ορόσημων του 1964, που πρόγραψε τη 
διάκριση στην απασχόληση και τις δημόσιες στεγάσεις βασισμένες 
στη φυλή, τη θρησκεία, την εθνική προέλευση, ή το φύλο, οι 
προσπάθειες να εγγραφούν αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί όπως οι 
ψηφοφόροι στο νότο ήταν. Το 1965, μετά από τη δολοφονία
ενός ενεργού στελέχους δικαιωμάτων ψήφου από τον αναπληρωτή 
ενός της Αλαμπάμα σερίφη και της επόμενης επίθεσης από τους 
κρατικούς στρατιώτες ιππικού σε μια ογκώδη διαμαρτυρία Μάρτιος 
σε Selma, Αλαμπάμα, ο Πρόεδρος Lyndon B. Johnson πάτησε
το συνέδριο στην ακόλουθη ομιλία για να ψηφίσει ένα νομοσχέδιο 
δικαιωμάτων ψήφου με τα δόντια. Σαν ηγέτη πλειοψηφίας της 
Συγκλήτου, Johnson είχε βοηθήσει να αποδυναμώσει το νόμο 
αστικών δικαιωμάτων του 1957. Όταν υπέθεσε την προεδρία 
μετά από τη δολοφονία John F. Kennedy τον Νοέμβριο του 
1963, εντούτοις, Johnson κάλεσε Αμερικανούς "για να αποβάλει
από αυτό το έθνος κάθε ίχνος διάκρισης και κατοχής που είναι 
βασισμένο στη φυλή ή το χρώμα," και στην ακόλουθη ομιλία 
υιοθέτησε "εμείς θα υπερνικήσει" το σύνθημα των ενεργών στελεχών
αστικών δικαιωμάτων. Η ρητορική και οι επόμενες 
προσπάθειές του έσπασαν με τα προεδρικά προηγούμενα παρελθόντος 
της αντίθεσης ή της χλιαρής υποστήριξης για την ισχυρή νομοθεσία
αστικών δικαιωμάτων. Το Johnson υπέγραψε το νόμο 
δικαιωμάτων ψήφου του 1965 στο νόμο σχετικά με στις 6 
Αυγούστου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Aunque la décimo quinta enmienda, ratificada en 
1870, garantizó a ciudadanos la derecha de votar sin importar la 
raza, por 1957 solamente 20 por ciento de americanos africanos 
elegibles votados, debidos en parte a la intimidación y requisitos 
discriminatorios del estado tales como impuestos de encuesta y pruebas
de la instrucción. A pesar de el paso del acto de las derechas 
civiles de la señal de 1964, que proscribió la discriminación en el
empleo y las comodidades del público basó en la raza, la religión, 
el origen nacional, o el sexo, los esfuerzos de colocar a americanos 
africanos como eran los votantes en el sur stymied. En 1965, 
siguiendo el asesinato de un activista de los derechos al voto del 
diputado de un sheriff de Alabama y del ataque subsecuente por 
troopers del estado contra una manifestación masiva en Selma, 
Alabama, presidente Lyndon B. Johnson presionó a congreso en el 
discurso siguiente aprobar una cuenta de los derechos al voto con los 
dientes. Como arranque de cinta de la mayoría del senado, 
Johnson había ayudado a debilitar el acto de las 1957 derechas 
civiles. Cuando él asumió la presidencia que seguía el 
asesinato de John F. Kennedy en noviembre de 1963, sin embargo, 
americanos invitados Johnson "para eliminar de esta nación cada 
rastro de la discriminación y de la opresión que se basa sobre la 
raza o el color," y en el discurso siguiente adoptó "nosotros 
superará" el lema de los activistas de las derechas civiles. Su
retórico y esfuerzos subsecuentes se rompieron con últimos 
precedentes presidenciales de la oposición a o de la ayuda tibia para
la legislación fuerte de las derechas civiles. Johnson firmó 
el acto de los derechos al voto de 1965 en ley de agosto el 6.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087400</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108035</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/and-we-shall-overcome-president-lyndon-b-johnsons-special-message-to-congress</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
