<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106523</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106523</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204616</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">What Do YOU See? (Post-Visit)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Was Sehen SIE? (Pfosten-Besuchen Sie)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Que Voyez-vous ? (Poteau-Visitez)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Que VOCÊ Vê? (Borne-Visite)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Che cosa Vedete? (Alberino-Visiti)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τι Βλέπετε; (Μετα-επίσκεψη)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿Qué USTED Ve? (Poste-Visite)</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this lesson, students will use observations and reflections made while visiting the Ackland Art Museum to draw conclusions about interpreting artwork (and other works/events), make quality scientific observations, and see how these concepts are related. Students will be reproducing artwork they viewed at the museum, sharing their personal interpretations of various works, and analyzing how the presentation of information (in any situation) can influence our interpretations of a work or event. This lesson is the final lesson in the series of lessons, "What Do YOU See?", which uses the Ackland Art Museum as a resource.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In dieser Lektion verwenden Kursteilnehmer die 
gebildeten Beobachtungen und Reflexionen, beim Besichtigen des Ackland
kunst-Museums, um Zusammenfassungen über deutengestaltungsarbeit (und
anderes works/events) zu zeichnen, bilden Qualität wissenschaftliche 
Beobachtungen und sehen, wie diese Konzepte in Verbindung stehend 
sind. Kursteilnehmer werden Gestaltungsarbeit, die reproduzieren
sie am Museum ansahen, ihre persönlichen Deutungen der verschiedenen 
Arbeiten teilen und analysieren, wie die Darstellung der Informationen
(in irgendeiner Situation) unsere Deutungen einer Arbeit oder des 
Falls beeinflussen kann. Diese Lektion ist die abschließende 
Lektion in der Reihe von Lektionen, ", was SIE?" sehen, welches 
das Ackland kunst-Museum als Hilfsmittel benutzt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cette leçon, les étudiants utiliseront des 
observations et des réflexions faites tout en visitant le musée 
d'art d'Ackland pour tirer des conclusions au sujet de dessin-modèle 
d'interprétation (et de tout autre works/events), font à qualité 
des observations scientifiques, et voient comment ces concepts sont 
connexes. Les étudiants reproduiront le dessin-modèle qu'ils 
ont visualisé au musée, partageront leurs traductions personnelles 
de divers travaux, et analyseront comment la présentation 
d'information (dans toute situation) peut influencer nos traductions 
d'un travail ou d'un événement. Cette leçon est la leçon 
finale de la série de leçons, "ce qui VOUS voient?", ce qui 
utilise le musée d'art d'Ackland comme ressource.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta lição, os estudantes usarão as 
observações e as reflexões feitas ao visitar o museu da arte de 
Ackland para desenhar conclusões sobre a arte -final de 
interpretação (e o outro works/events), fazem a qualidade 
observações científicas, e vêem como estes conceitos são 
relacionados. Os estudantes estarão reproduzindo a arte -final 
que viram no museu, estarão compartilhando de suas interpretações 
pessoais de vários trabalhos, e estarão analisando como a 
apresentação da informação (em alguma situação) pode influenciar
nossas interpretações de um trabalho ou de um evento. Esta 
lição é a lição final na série das lições, "o que VOCÊ 
vêem?", qual usa o museu da arte de Ackland como um recurso.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questa lezione, gli allievi useranno le 
osservazioni e le riflessioni fatte mentre visitano il museo di arte 
di Ackland per dissipare le conclusioni circa illustrazione 
d'interpretazione (e l'altro works/events), rendono a qualità le 
osservazioni scientifiche e vedono come questi concetti sono relativi.
Gli allievi riprodurranno l'illustrazione che hanno osservato al
museo, ripartiranno le loro interpretazioni personali di vari impianti
ed analizzeranno come la presentazione delle informazioni (in 
qualsiasi situazione) può influenzare le nostre interpretazioni di un
lavoro o di un evento. Questa lezione è la lezione finale in 
serie di lezioni, "che cosa VOI vedono?", quale usa il museo di 
arte di Ackland come risorsa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτό το μάθημα, οι σπουδαστές θα χρησιμοποιήσουν 
τις παρατηρήσεις και οι αντανακλάσεις έκαναν επισκεμμένος το 
μουσείο τέχνης Ackland για να συναγάγουν τα συμπεράσματα για 
την ερμηνεία του έργου τέχνης (και άλλων εργασιών/γεγονότων), 
κάνουν την ποιότητα τις επιστημονικές παρατηρήσεις, και 
βλέπουνε πώς αυτές οι έννοιες συσχετίζονται. Οι 
σπουδαστές θα αναπαράγουν το έργο τέχνης που εμφάνισαν στο 
μουσείο, μοιραμένος τις προσωπικές ερμηνείες διάφορων εργασιών 
τους, και αναλύοντας πώς η παρουσίαση των πληροφοριών (σε 
οποιαδήποτε κατάσταση) μπορεί να επηρεάσει τις ερμηνείες μας μιας
εργασίας ή ενός γεγονότος. Αυτό το μάθημα είναι το 
τελικό μάθημα στη σειρά μαθημάτων, "τι ΕΣΕΙΣ Βλέπει;", 
ποιες χρήσεις το μουσείο τέχνης Ackland ως στοιχείο 
συμπεριφοράς.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta lección, los estudiantes utilizarán las 
observaciones y las reflexiones hechas mientras que visitan el museo 
del arte de Ackland para trazar conclusiones sobre las ilustraciones 
que interpretan (y el otro works/events), hacen calidad observaciones 
científicas, y ven cómo estos conceptos son relacionados. Los 
estudiantes reproducirán las ilustraciones que vieron en el museo, 
compartirán sus interpretaciones personales de varios trabajos, y 
analizarán cómo la presentación de la información (en cualquier 
situación) puede influenciar nuestras interpretaciones de un trabajo 
o de un acontecimiento. Esta lección es la lección final en la
serie de lecciones, "qué USTED ven?", cuál utiliza el museo 
del arte de Ackland como recurso.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:REAGAN WEST
FN:REAGAN WEST
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204616</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106523</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/what-do-you-see-post-visit</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
