<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108561</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108561</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086353</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"It Was Considered Low Music": Pianist Eubie Blake on the Birth of Ragtime at the Turn of the Century</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Es Galt Als Niedrige Musik": Pianist Eubie 
Blake auf der Geburt von Ragtime an der Jahrhundertwende</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"On l'a considéré Basse Musique" : Pianiste
Eubie Blake sur la naissance de Ragtime à la fin du siècle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Considerou-se Música Baixa": Pianist Eubie 
Blake no nascimento de Ragtime na volta do século</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"È stato considerato Musica Bassa": Pianist 
Eubie Blake sulla nascita di Ragtime alla fine del secolo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Θεωρήθηκε χαμηλή μουσική": Pianist Eubie 
Blake στη γέννηση του εήδου μουσικής τζαζ στο γύρισμα του 
αιώνα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Era considerado Música Baja": Pianist Eubie
Blake en el nacimiento de Ragtime al final del siglo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Ragtime music, with its syncopated, polyrhythmic style, was born, according to cultural historian Robert Snyder, in the 1890s in the black saloons and brothels of southern and Midwestern cities like Baltimore and St. Louis. By the end of the 19th century ragtime had assumed a place at the center of American popular music and remained there until the 1920s. Ragtime meant a tinkling piano and no one played the ragtime piano any better or longer than Eubie Blake, born in Baltimore in 1887. In this selection from an interview performance conducted in 1970 for public television by musician Max Morath, Blake recalled how he began playing ragtime as a young man at the turn of the century.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ragtime Musik, mit seiner synkopierten, 
polyrhythmic Art, wurde, nach Ansicht des kulturellen Historikers 
Robert Snyder, im 1890s in den schwarzen Saloons und in den Bordellen 
der südlichen und des mittleren Westensstädte wie Baltimore und St. 
Louis getragen. Ende des 19. Jahrhunderts hatte das ragtime 
einen Platz in der Mitte der amerikanischen populären Musik 
angenommen und dort geblieben, bis die zwanziger Jahre Ragtime 
bedeutete, daß ein klingelndes Klavier und niemand das ragtime 
Klavier irgendwie besser oder länger als Eubie Blake spielten, 
getragen in Baltimore 1887. _ in dies Auswahl von ein Interview 
Leistung leiten in 1970 für allgemein Fernsehen durch Musiker maximal
Morath, Blake wieder.aufrufen wie er anfangen spielen ragtime als ein 
jung Mann an d Umdrehung von d Jahrhundert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La musique de Ragtime, avec son modèle syncopé et
polyrhythmic, a été soutenue, selon l'historien culturel Robert 
Snyder, dans le 1890s dans les salles et les bordels noirs des villes 
méridionales et du milieu du middle-ouest comme Baltimore et St 
Louis. Vers la fin du 19ème siècle le ragtime avait assumé un
endroit au centre de la musique populaire américaine et était 
demeuré là jusqu'à ce que les années 20 Ragtime ait signifié que 
un piano de tintement et personne n'ont joué le piano de ragtime  
mieux ou plus longtemps qu'eubie Blake, soutenu à Baltimore en 1887. 
_ dans ce sélection un entrevue exécution conduire dans 1970 
pour public télévision par musicien maximum Morath, Blake rappeler 
comment commencer jouer ragtime comme un jeune homme à la fin le 
siècle.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A música de Ragtime, com seu estilo syncopated, 
polyrhythmic, foi carregada, de acordo com o historian cultural Robert
Snyder, no 1890s nos saloons e nos brothels pretos de cidades do sul e
midwestern como Baltimore e St. Louis. Para o fim do 1ø século
o ragtime supos um lugar no centro da música popular americana e 
remanesceu lá até que os 1920s. Ragtime significou que um piano 
tilintando e ninguém jogaram o piano do ragtime  mais melhor ou mais 
por muito tempo do que Eubie Blake, carregado em Baltimore em 1887. 
_ este seleção um entrevista desempenho conduz 1970 para 
público televisão músico máximo Morath, Blake record como ele 
começ jog ragtime como um novo homem volta século.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La musica di Ragtime, con il relativo stile 
sincopato e polyrhythmic, è stata sopportata, secondo lo storico 
culturale Robert Snyder, nel 1890s nei saloni e nei brothels neri 
delle città del sud e midwestern come Baltimora e St. Louis. 
Per la fine del diciannovesimo secolo il ragtime aveva 
presupposto un posto al centro di musica popolare americana ed era 
rimasto là fino a che gli anni 20 Ragtime non significasse che un 
piano tinkling e nessuno giocassero affatto più meglio o più 
lungamente il piano del ragtime di Eubie Blake, sopportato a Baltimora
in 1887. _ questo selezione un intervista prestazione condur 
1970 per pubblico televisione musicista massimo Morath, Blake ricord
come lui cominci gioc ragtime come un young giovane alla fine secolo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η μουσική εήδων μουσικής τζαζ, με το συνκομμένο, 
polyrhythmic ύφος της, γεννήθηκε, σύμφωνα με τον πολιτιστικό 
ιστορικό Robert Snyder, στο 1890s στις μαύρα αίθουσες και 
τα πορνεία των νότιων και midwestern πόλεων όπως τη Βαλτιμόρη 
και το ST Louis. Μέχρι το τέλος του 19$ου αιώνα το 
εήδος μουσικής τζαζ είχε υποθέσει μια θέση στο κέντρο της 
αμερικανικής δημοφιλούς μουσικής και παραμένοντας μέχρι το εήδο 
μουσικής τζαζ της δεκαετίας του '20 σήμανε ένα tinkling πιάνο 
και κανένας έπαιξε το πιάνο εήδων μουσικής τζαζ καθόλου 
καλύτερα ή περισσότερο από Eubie Blake, γεννημένο στη 
Βαλτιμόρη το 1887. Σε αυτήν την επιλογή από μια απόδοση 
συνέντευξης που διευθύνθηκε το 1970 για τη δημόσια τηλεόραση 
από το μουσικό ανώτατο Morath, Blake υπενθύμισε πώς άρχισε
το εήδο μουσικής τζαζ ως νεαρό άνδρα στο γύρισμα του αιώνα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La música de Ragtime, con su estilo sincopado, 
polyrhythmic, fue llevada, según el historiador cultural Roberto 
Snyder, en el 1890s en los salones y los burdeles negros de 
ciudades meridionales y midwestern como Baltimore y St. Louis. 
Antes de fin de diecinueveavo siglo había seguido habiendo el 
ragtime había asumido un lugar en el centro de la música popular 
americana y allí hasta que los años 20 Ragtime significó que un 
piano que tintineaba y nadie jugaron el piano del ragtime  mejor o 
más de largo que Eubie Blake, llevado en Baltimore en 1887. _ 
en este selección uno entrevista funcionamiento conducir en 1970 para
público televisión por músico máximo Morath, Blake recordar cómo 
él comenzar jugar ragtime como uno joven hombre al final siglo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086353</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108561</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/it-was-considered-low-music-pianist-eubie-blake-on-the-birth-of-ragtime-at-the-turn-of-the-century</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
