<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105695</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105695</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086923</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Cook and the Governor: Seeing Eye-to-Eye on Unemployment</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Koch und der Gouverneur: Sehen des 
Auge-zu-Auges auf Arbeitslosigkeit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le cuisinier et le gouverneur : Voir 
l'Oeil-à-Oeil sur le chômage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O cozinheiro e o regulador: Vendo o 
Olho-à-Olho no desemprego</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il cuoco ed il regolatore: Vedere 
Occhio-$$$-Occhio su disoccupazione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο μάγειρας και ο κυβερνήτης: Να δει το
μάτι-$$$-ΜΑΤΙ στην ανεργία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El cocinero y el gobernador: Ver el 
Ojo-a-Ojo en el desempleo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The word "tramp" came into common usage in the 1870s as a disparaging description of homeless men thrown out of work by the economic depression and forced to take to the road in search of a job or food. Fears of the "tramp menace" were revived during the even more devastating depression that began in 1893. Many Americans viewed tramps with a combination of fear and disgust. In this 1893 letter to Kansas governor Lorenzo Dow Lewelling, out-of-work cook R. L. Robinson expressed dismay for the harsh treatment he and a traveling companion received while looking for work in Kewanee, Kansas. Lewelling was far more sympathetic to jobless travelers than other government officials, in part, from personal experience. He himself had wandered the roads in search of work in the 1870s depression.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Wort "Tramp" kam in geläufigen Verbrauch im 
1870s als herabsetzende Beschreibung der heimatlosen Männer, die 
heraus von der Arbeit durch die Wirtschaftskrise geworfen wurden und 
erzwungen waren, zur Straße in der Suche eines Jobs oder der Nahrung 
zu nehmen. Furcht vor der "Trampdrohung" wurde während des 
sogar verheerenderen Tiefstands wieder belebt, der 1893 anfing. 
Viele angesehene Amerikaner tramps mit einer Kombination von 
Furcht und von Ekel. In diesem Zeichen 1893 zum Kansas Regler 
Lorenzo Dow Lewelling, heraus-von-arbeiten Sie Koch R. L. Robinson 
ausgedrückten Schrecken für die rauhe Behandlung er und ein 
reisender empfangener Begleiter beim Suchen nach Arbeit in Kewanee, 
Kansas. Lewelling war zu den arbeitslosen Reisenden als andere 
Regierungsbeamte, im Teil, von der persönlichen Erfahrung weites 
sympatischeres. Er selbst wandered die Straßen auf der Suche 
nach Arbeit im Tiefstand 1870s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le mot "bruit" a hérité l'utilisation commune 
dans le 1870s comme description de dépréciation des hommes sans 
foyer jetés sans emploi par la dépression économique et forcés de 
prendre à la route à la recherche d'un travail ou d'un aliment. 
Des craintes de la "menace de bruit" ont été rétablies 
pendant la dépression bien plus dévastatrice qui a commencé en 
1893. Beaucoup d'Américains visualisés marche à pas marqués 
avec une combinaison de la crainte et du dégoût. Dans cette 
lettre 1893 au Gouverneur Lorenzo Dow Lewelling du Kansas, 
dehors-de-travaillez la consternation exprimée Robinson de R. L. de 
cuisinier pour le traitement dur lui et un compagnon de déplacement 
reçu tout en cherchant le travail dans Kewanee, le Kansas. 
Lewelling était plus sympathique bien aux voyageurs sans emploi
que d'autres fonctionnaires de gouvernement, en partie, d'une 
expérience personnelle. Il lui-même avait erré les routes à 
la recherche du travail dans la dépression 1870s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A palavra "caminhada" veio no uso comum no 1870s 
como uma descrição despreciando dos homens desabrigados jogados fora
do trabalho pelo depression econômico e forçados a fazer exame à 
estrada na busca de um trabalho ou de um alimento. Os medos da 
"da ameaça caminhada" revived durante o depression mesmo mais 
devastating que começou em 1893. Muitos americanos vistos vagam
com uma combinação do medo e da aversão. Nesta letra 1893 ao 
regulador Lorenzo Dow Lewelling de Kansas, para fora-$$$-TRABALHE o 
desânimo expressado Robinson de R. L. do cozinheiro para o tratamento
áspero ele e um companheiro viajando recebido ao procurar o trabalho 
em Kewanee, Kansas. Lewelling era mais sympathetic distante aos 
viajantes jobless do que outros oficiais de governo, na parte, da 
experiência pessoal. Ele mesmo tinha vagueado as estradas na 
busca do trabalho no depression 1870s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La parola "vagabondo" ha entrato nell'uso comune 
nel 1870s come descrizione di sottovalutazione degli uomini senza casa
gettati senza lavoro dalla depressione economica e costretti a 
prendere alla strada alla ricerca di un lavoro o di un alimento. 
I timori "della minaccia del vagabondo" sono stati fatti 
rivivere durante la depressione ancor più devastating che ha 
cominciato in 1893. Molti Americani osservati preme il piede con
una combinazione di timore e di repulsione. In questa lettera 
1893 al regolatore Lorenzo il Dow Lewelling del Kansas, 
fuori-de-funzioni la costernazione espressa Robinson del R. L. del 
cuoco per il trattamento duro lui e un compagno mobile ricevuto mentre
cercano il lavoro in Kewanee, Kansas. Lewelling era molto più 
simpatico ai viaggiatori senza lavoro che altri funzionari di governo,
in parte, da esperienza personale. Egli stesso aveva vagato le 
strade alla ricerca di lavoro nella depressione 1870s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η λέξη "αγύρτησ" ήρθε στην κοινή χρήση 1870s ως 
περιγραφή δυσφήμησης των άστεγων ατόμων που ρίχτηκε έξω της 
εργασίας από την οικονομική ύφεση και που αναγκάστηκε να πάρει 
στο δρόμο στην αναζήτηση μιας εργασίας ή τροφίμων. Οι 
φόβοι της "απειλής αγυρτών" αναβιώθηκαν κατά τη διάρκεια της 
ακόμα πιό καταστρεπτικής κατάθλιψης που άρχισε σε 1893, 
Πολλοί Αμερικανοί εμφάνισαν τους αγύρτες με έναν συνδυασμό
φόβου και αποστροφής. Σε αυτήν την επιστολή 1893 στον 
κυβερνήτη Lorenzo Dow Lewelling του Κάνσας, ο μάγειρας Ρ. 
Λ. Robinson έξω-$$$-ΕΡΓΑΣΊΑΣ εξέφρασε το φόβο για τη σκληρή 
επεξεργασία αυτός και ένας διακινούμενος σύντροφος έλαβε 
ψάχνοντας την εργασία σε Kewanee, Κάνσας. Το Lewelling 
ήταν πολύ πιό συμπονετικό στους άνεργους ταξιδιώτες από άλλους
κυβερνητικούς ανώτερους υπαλλήλους, εν μέρει, από την προσωπική 
εμπειρία. Ο ίδιος είχε περιπλανηθεί οι δρόμοι σε αναζήτηση
της εργασίας στη 1870s κατάθλιψη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La palabra "vagabundo" vino en uso común en el 
1870s como descripción que desacreditaba de los hombres sin hogar 
lanzados sin trabajo por la depresión económica y forzados llevar el
camino en búsqueda de un trabajo o de un alimento. Los miedos 
de la "amenaza del vagabundo" fueron restablecidos durante la 
depresión aún más devastadora que comenzó en 1893. Muchos 
americanos vistos andan por con una combinación del miedo y de la 
repugnancia. En esta carta 1893 al gobernador Lorenzo Dow 
Lewelling de Kansas, hacia fuera-de-trabaje la consternación 
expresada Robinson de R. L. del cocinero para el tratamiento áspero 
él y un compañero que viaja recibido mientras que busca el trabajo 
en Kewanee, Kansas. Lewelling era más comprensivo lejano a las 
hojas de ruta (traveler) desempleadas que otros oficiales del 
gobierno, en parte, de la experiencia personal. Él sí mismo 
había vagado los caminos en la búsqueda del trabajo en la depresión
1870s.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086923</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105695</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-cook-and-the-governor-seeing-eye-to-eye-on-unemployment</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
