<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103010</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103010</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213166</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Who Can Live Here? Life in Extreme Environments</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wer Kann Phasen Hier? Leben in den extremen 
Umgebungen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Qui Peut de phase Ici ? La vie dans les 
environnements extrêmes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quem Pode Vivo Aqui? Vida em ambientes 
extremos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Chi Può In tensione Qui? Vita negli 
ambienti estremi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ποιος μπορεί ζωντανός εδώ; Ζωή στα ακραία 
περιβάλλοντα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿Quién Puede Vivo Aquí? Vida en ambientes 
extremos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Astrobiology in the Classroom leads students in the exploration of the limits of life on Earth to extend their beliefs about life to include its possibility on other worlds. In this four-part activity, students first explore the environments of several mammals and birds to better understand how living things and their environments interact and depend on each other. In the second part, students match bacterial types with their more extreme environments. Students discover that an environment's temperature, salinity, pH, and sources of carbon and energy are important for what can live there. Next, students are given readings on life in extreme environments that cover the latest scientific findings in this field and are asked to answer reflective-questions. With their new understanding of the limits of life on Earth, the final part guides students in the exploration of environments on other planets and moons in our Solar System. Word is required for opening this document.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Astrobiology im Klassenzimmer führt 
Kursteilnehmer in der Erforschung der Begrenzungen auf das Leben auf 
Masse, ihren Glauben über das Leben auszudehnen, um seine 
Möglichkeit auf anderen Welten einzuschließen. In dieser 
vierteiligen Aktivität erforschen Kursteilnehmer zuerst die 
Umgebungen einiger Säugetiere und Vögel, um besser zu verstehen, wie
lebende Sachen und ihre Umgebungen von einander zusammenwirken und 
abhängen. Im zweiten Teil bringen Kursteilnehmer bakterielle 
Typen mit ihren extremeren Umgebungen zusammen. Kursteilnehmer 
entdecken, daß die Temperatur, die Salzigkeit, pH und die Quellen 
einer Umgebung des Carbons und der Energie wichtig sind für, was dort
leben kann. Zunächst werden Kursteilnehmern Messwerte auf dem 
Leben in den extremen Umgebungen gegeben, die die neuesten 
wissenschaftlichen Entdeckungen diesbezüglich auffangen und 
werden gebeten, Reflektierendfragen zu beantworten umfassen. Mit
ihrem neuen Verständnis der Begrenzungen auf das Leben auf Masse, 
führen das Endrunde Teil Kursteilnehmer in die Erforschung der 
Umgebungen auf anderen Planeten und Monden in unserem Solarsystem. 
Wort wird für das Öffnen dieses Dokumentes benoetigt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Astrobiology dans la salle de classe mène des 
étudiants dans l'exploration des limites de la vie sur terre à 
étendre leur croyance au sujet de la vie pour inclure sa possibilité
sur d'autres mondes. Dans cette activité à quatre parties, les
étudiants explorent d'abord les environnements de plusieurs 
mammifères et oiseaux pour comprendre mieux comment les choses 
vivantes et leurs environnements agissent l'un sur l'autre et 
dépendent de l'un l'autre. Dans la deuxième partie, les 
étudiants apparient les types bactériens avec leurs environnements 
plus extrêmes. Les étudiants découvrent que la température, 
la salinité, le pH, et les sources d'un environnement de carbone et 
énergie sont importants pour ce qui peut vivre là. Ensuite, 
des étudiants sont donnés des lectures la vie dans les 
environnements extrêmes qui couvrent les derniers résultats 
scientifiques dans ce domaine et sont invités à répondre à des 
r3fléchissant-questions. Avec leur nouvel arrangement des 
limites de la vie sur terre, la pièce de finale guident des 
étudiants dans l'exploration des environnements sur d'autres 
planètes et lunes dans notre système solaire. Le mot est 
exigé pour ouvrir ce document.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Astrobiology na sala de aula conduz a estudantes 
na exploração dos limites da vida na terra estender sua opinião 
sobre a vida para incluir sua possibilidade em outros mundos. 
Nesta atividade four-part, os estudantes exploram primeiramente 
os ambientes de diversos mamíferos e pássaros para compreender mais 
melhor como as coisas vivas e seus ambientes interagem e dependem de 
se. Na segunda parte, os estudantes combinam tipos bacterianos 
com seus ambientes mais extremos. Os estudantes descobrem que a 
temperatura, o salinity, o pH, e as fontes de um ambiente do carbono e
da energia são importantes para o que pode viver lá. Em 
seguida, os estudantes são dados leituras na vida nos ambientes 
extremos que cobrem os findings científicos os mais atrasados neste 
campo e pedidos para responder a reflexivo-perguntas. Com sua 
compreensão nova dos limites da vida na terra, a peça do final guia 
estudantes na exploração dos ambientes em outros planetas e luas em 
nosso sistema solar. A palavra é requerida abrindo este 
original.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Astrobiology nell'aula conduce gli allievi 
nell'esplorazione dei limiti di vita su terra estendere la loro 
credenza circa vita per includere la relativa possibilità su altri 
mondi. In questa attività a quattro parti, gli allievi in primo
luogo esplorano gli ambienti di parecchi mammiferi ed uccelli per 
capire più meglio come le cose viventi ed i loro ambienti si 
interagiscono e dipendono da a vicenda. Nella seconda parte, gli
allievi abbinano i tipi batterici con i loro ambienti più estremi. 
Gli allievi scoprono che la temperatura, la salinità, il pH e 
le sorgenti dell'ambiente di carbonio e di energia sono importanti per
che cosa può vivere là. Dopo, gli allievi sono dati le letture
su vita negli ambienti estremi che riguardano gli ultimi risultati 
scientifici in questo campo e sono chiesti di rispondere alle 
riflettente-domande. Con la loro nuova comprensione dei limiti 
di vita su terra, la parte di finale guida gli allievi 
nell'esplorazione degli ambienti su altri pianeti e lune nel nostro 
sistema solare. La parola è richiesta per l'apertura del questo
documento.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Astrobiology στην τάξη οδηγεί τους σπουδαστές 
στην εξερεύνηση των ορίων της ζωής στη γη για να επεκτείνει τις 
πεποιθήσεις τους για τη ζωή για να περιλάβει τη δυνατότητά του σε
άλλους κόσμους. Σε αυτήν την δραστηριότητα τέσσερις-μερών,
οι σπουδαστές ερευνούν αρχικά τα περιβάλλοντα διάφορων 
θηλαστικών και πουλιών για να καταλάβουν καλύτερα πώς τα 
πράγματα διαβίωσης και τα περιβάλλοντά τους αλληλεπιδρούν και 
εξαρτώνται το ένα από το άλλο. Στο δεύτερο μέρος, οι 
σπουδαστές ταιριάζουν με τους βακτηριακούς τύπους τα πιό ακραία 
περιβάλλοντά τους. Οι σπουδαστές ανακαλύπτουν ότι η 
θερμοκρασία, η αλατότητα, το pH, και οι πηγές ενός 
περιβάλλοντος άνθρακα και ενέργειας είναι σημαντικές για αυτό 
που μπορεί να ζήσει εκεί. Έπειτα, στους σπουδαστές 
δίνονται οι αναγνώσεις στη ζωή στα ακραία περιβάλλοντα που 
καλύπτουν τα πιό πρόσφατα επιστημονικά συμπεράσματα σε αυτό το 
πεδίο και καλούνται να απαντήσουν στις αντανακλαστικός-ερωτήσεις.
Με τη νέα κατανόησή τους των ορίων της ζωής στη γη, το 
τελικό μέρος καθοδηγεί τους σπουδαστές στην εξερεύνηση των 
περιβαλλόντων σε άλλους πλανήτες και τα φεγγάρια στο ηλιακό 
σύστημά μας. Η λέξη απαιτείται για το άνοιγμα του παρόντος
εγγράφου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Astrobiology en la sala de clase conduce a 
estudiantes en la exploración de los límites de la vida en la tierra
a ampliar su creencia sobre vida para incluir su posibilidad en otros 
mundos. En esta actividad de cuatro partes, los estudiantes 
primero exploran los ambientes de varios mamíferos y pájaros para 
entender mejor cómo las cosas vivas y sus ambientes obran 
recíprocamente y dependen de uno a. En la segunda parte, los 
estudiantes corresponden con tipos bacterianos con sus ambientes más 
extremos. Los estudiantes descubren que la temperatura, la 
salinidad, el pH, y las fuentes de un ambiente del carbón y de la 
energía son importantes para qué puede vivir allí. Después, 
dan lecturas el vida en los ambientes extremos que cubren los 
resultados científicos más últimos de este campo y se piden los 
estudiantes contestar a reflexivo-preguntas. Con su nueva 
comprensión de los límites de la vida en la tierra, la pieza del 
final dirige a estudiantes en la exploración de ambientes en otros 
planetas y lunas en nuestra Sistema Solar. La palabra se 
requiere para abrir este documento.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:NASA/MSU-BOZEMAN CENTER FOR EDUCATIONAL RESOURCES PROJECT
FN:NASA/MSU-BOZEMAN CENTER FOR EDUCATIONAL RESOURCES PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213166</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103010</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/who-can-live-here-life-in-extreme-environments</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
