<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104347</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104347</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206651</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Genetic Science and Technology Learning Center</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Genetische Wissenschaft und 
Technologie-erlernenmitte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Centre d'étude génétique de la Science et de 
technologie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Centro de aprendizagem genetic da ciência e da 
tecnologia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Centro imparante genetico di tecnologia e di 
scienza</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γενετικό κέντρο εκμάθησης επιστήμης και τεχνολογίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Centro que aprende genético de la ciencia y de la 
tecnología</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features animations and activities for learning about DNA, cells, and other topics in genetics and bioscience. Build a DNA molecule. Transcribe and translate a gene. See why a firefly's tail glows. Use DNA evidence to solve a mystery. Extract DNA from wheat germ and see real DNA. Find out how genetics are being used to save endangered species. Learn about stem cells, addiction, gene therapy, cloning, and genetically modified food.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Merkmale Animationen und Aktivitäten für das 
Lernen über DNA, Zellen und andere Themen in den Genetik und im 
bioscience. Bauen Sie ein DNA Molekül auf. Übertragen 
Sie und übersetzen Sie ein Gen. Sehen Sie, warum das Endstück 
eines Leuchtkäfers glüht. Verwenden Sie DNA Beweis, um ein 
Geheimnis zu lösen. Extrahieren Sie DNA von der Weizenmikrobe 
und sehen Sie reale DNA. Finden Sie heraus, wie Genetik 
verwendet werden, um gefährdete Sorte zu sichern. Erlernen Sie 
über Stammzellen, Neigung, Gentherapie, Klonen und genetisch 
geänderte Nahrung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">animations et activités de dispositifs pour se 
renseigner sur l'ADN, les cellules, et d'autres sujets en génétique 
et biosciences. Construisez une molécule d'ADN. 
Transcrivez et traduisez un gène. Voyez pourquoi la queue
d'une luciole rougeoie. Employez l'évidence d'ADN pour 
résoudre un mystère. Extrayez l'ADN à partir du germe de blé
et voyez la vraie ADN. Découvrez comment la génétique est 
employée pour sauvegarder des espèces mises en danger. 
Renseignez-vous sur des cellules de tige, le penchant, la 
thérapie de gène, le clonage, et la nourriture génétiquement 
modifiée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">animations e atividades das características para 
aprender sobre o DNA, as pilhas, e os outros tópicos nos genetics e 
no bioscience. Construa uma molécula do DNA. Transcreva e
traduza um gene. Veja porque a cauda de um firefly incandesce. 
Use a evidência do DNA resolver um mistério. Extraia o 
DNA do germe do trigo e veja o DNA real. Encontre para fora como
os genetics estão sendo usados conservar a espécie posta em perigo. 
Aprenda sobre pilhas de haste, addiction, terapia do gene, 
cloning, e o alimento genetically modificado.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">animazioni ed attività delle caratteristiche per 
imparare circa il DNA, le cellule ed altri soggetti nella genetica ed 
in bioscience. Costruisca una molecola del DNA. Trascriva 
e traduca un gene. Veda perchè la coda della lucciola emette 
luce. Usi la prova del DNA per risolvere un mistero. 
Estragga il DNA dal germe del frumento e veda il DNA reale. 
Scopra come la genetica sta usanda per salvare la specie in 
pericolo. Impari circa le cellule formative, l'aggiunta, la 
terapia del gene, la clonazione e l'alimento geneticamente modificato.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χαρακτηρίζει τις ζωτικότητες και τις δραστηριότητες για
την εκμάθηση για το DNA, τα κύτταρα, και άλλα θέματα στη 
γενετική και τις βιοεπιστήμες. Χτίστε ένα μόριο DNA. 
Μεταγράψτε και μεταφράστε ένα γονίδιο. 
Δείτε γιατί η ουρά ενός firefly καίγεται. 
Χρησιμοποιήστε τα στοιχεία DNA για να λυθεί ένα 
μυστήριο. Εξάγετε το DNA από το μικρόβιο σίτου και 
δείτε το πραγματικό DNA. Ανακαλύψτε πώς η 
γενετική χρησιμοποιείται για να σώσει τα απειλούμενα υπό 
εξαφάνιση είδη. Μάθετε για τα κύτταρα μίσχων, τον εθισμό, 
τη θεραπεία γονιδίων, κλωνοποιώντας, και τα γενετικά 
τροποποιημένα τρόφιμα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">animaciones y actividades de las características 
para aprender sobre la DNA, las células, y otros asuntos en 
genéticas y bioscience. Construya una molécula de la DNA. 
Transcriba y traduzca un gene. Vea porqué brilla 
intensamente la cola de una luciérnaga. Utilice la evidencia de
la DNA para solucionar un misterio. Extraiga la DNA del germen 
del trigo y vea la DNA verdadera. Descubra cómo las genéticas 
se están utilizando para salvar especie puesta en peligro. 
Aprenda sobre las células de vástago, el apego, la terapia del
gene, la reproducción, y el alimento genético modificado.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206651</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104347</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/genetic-science-and-technology-learning-center</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
