<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105398</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105398</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087082</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Workingman's Ten Commandments</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die 10 Gebote Des Workingmans</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Dix Commandements de l'Ouvrier</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os Dez Commandments Do Workingman</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I Dieci Ordini Del Workingman</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι δέκα εντολές του Workingman</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los Diez Mandamientos Del Workingman</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Although publicists for late nineteenth-century corporations celebrated their "efficiency" and the "science" of management, their employees did not always join the celebration. What looked like careful and disciplined management from one perspective might be viewed as petty tyranny from below. Some workers directed their anger to the very top of the corporations. An anonymous author, writing in the  Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen's Monthly Magazine  in 1878, claimed that these "ten commandments" were "written down in the Statute-Books of Railroad Officials and idle Monopolists, and Jay Gould Aristocrats."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Obgleich Publizisten für späte 19.-Jahrhundert 
Korporationen ihre "Leistungsfähigkeit" und die "Wissenschaft" des 
Managements feierten, verbanden ihre Angestellten nicht immer die 
Feier. Von unterhalb was ausgesehen wie vorsichtiges und 
diszipliniertes Management von einer Perspektive angesehen werden 
konnte als geringfügige Tyrannei. Einige Arbeiter verwiesen 
ihren Zorn auf die Oberseite der Korporationen. Ein anonymer 
Autor, schreibend in die Bruderschaft der Monatszeitschrift der sich 
fortbewegenden Feuerwehrmänner 1878, behauptete, daß diese "10 
Gebote in den Gesetz-Büchern der Eisenbahn-Beamter und der untätigen
Monopolisten notiert" wurden ", und Eichelhäher Gould Aristokraten."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bien que les publicistes pour des sociétés en 
retard de dix-neuvième-siècle aient célébré leur "efficacité" et
la "science" de la gestion, leurs employés n'ont pas toujours joint 
la célébration. De dessous ce que ressemblé à la gestion 
soigneuse et disciplinée d'une perspective pourrait être visualisé 
en tant que tyrannie petite. Quelques ouvriers ont dirigé leur 
colère vers le dessus même des sociétés. Un auteur anonyme, 
écrivant dans la confrérie du magazine mensuel des pompiers 
locomotifs en 1878, a réclamé que ces "dix commandements" "ont été
notés dans les Statut-Livres des fonctionnaires de chemin de fer et 
des monopoleurs de veille, et des aristocrates de Gould de geai."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Embora os publicists para corporation atrasados de
décimo-século comemorassem sua "eficiência" e a "ciência" da 
gerência, seus empregados não juntaram sempre o celebration. O
que olhado como a gerência cuidadosa e disciplinada de um perspective
pôde ser visto como o tyranny petty abaixo. Alguns 
trabalhadores dirigiram sua raiva ao alto very dos corporation. 
Um autor anonymous, escrevendo no brotherhood do compartimento 
mensal dos firemen locomotive em 1878, reivindicou que estes "dez 
commandments" "estiveram escritos para baixo nos Statute-Livros de 
oficiais da estrada de ferro e de monopolists inativos, e aristocrats 
de Gould do jay."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Anche se i publicists per le società ritardate di
diciannovesimo-secolo hanno celebrato il loro "risparmio di temi" e 
"la scienza" della gestione, i loro impiegati non hanno unito sempre 
la celebrazione. Che cosa assomigliato alla gestione attenta e 
disciplinata da una prospettiva potrebbe essere osservato come 
tirannia piccola da sotto. Alcuni operai hanno diretto la loro 
rabbia verso la parte superiore stessa delle società. Un autore
anonimo, scrivente nella fratellanza dello scomparto mensile dei 
vigili del fuoco locomotivi in 1878, ha sostenuto che questi "dieci 
ordini" "sono stati annotati nei Statuto-Libri dei funzionari della 
ferrovia e dei monopolisti al minimo ed aristocrats di Gould del jay."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αν και οι πολιτικοί αρθρογράφοι για τις πρόσφατες 
εταιρίες δέκατος-αιώνα γιόρτασαν "την αποδοτικότητά τουσ" και τη
"επιστήμη" της διαχείρισης, οι υπάλληλοί τους όχι πάντα ένωσαν 
τον εορτασμό. Αυτό που εμοίασε με την προσεκτική και 
πειθαρχημένη διαχείριση από μια προοπτική να εμφανιστεί ως 
ασήμαντη τυραννία από κάτω από. Μερικοί εργαζόμενοι 
κατεύθυναν το θυμό τους πολύ στον κορυφαίο των εταιριών. 
Ένας ανώνυμος συντάκτης, που γράφει στην αδελφοσύνη του 
μηνιαίου περιοδικού των κινητήριων πυροσβεστών το 1878, 
υποστήριξε ότι αυτές οι "δέκα εντολέσ" "γράφτηκαν κάτω στα 
καταστατικό-βιβλία των ανώτερων υπαλλήλων σιδηροδρόμου και των μη
απασχόλησης μονοπωλητών, και τους αριστοκράτες Jay Gould."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Aunque los publicistas para las últimas 
corporaciones del diecinueveavo-siglo celebraron su "eficacia" y la 
"ciencia" de la gerencia, sus empleados no ensamblaron siempre la 
celebración. Qué parecida la gerencia cuidadosa y disciplinada
a partir de una perspectiva pudo ser visto como tiranía pequeña 
debajo. Algunos trabajadores dirigieron su cólera a la misma 
tapa de las corporaciones. Un autor anónimo, escribiendo en la 
fraternidad del compartimiento mensual de los bomberos locomotores en 
1878, demandó que estos "diez mandamientos" "fueron anotados en los 
Estatuto-Libros de los funcionarios del ferrocarril y de los 
monopolistas ociosos, y los Aristócratas de Gould del jay."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087082</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105398</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-workingmans-ten-commandments</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
