<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104071</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104071</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086717</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Packed Densely, Like Herrings": Gottlieb Mittelberger Warns His Countryman of the Perils of Emigration, 1750</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Dicht Gepackt, Wie Heringe": Gottlieb 
Mittelberger warnt seinen Landsmann der Gefahren von Auswanderung, 
1750</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Emballé En masse, Comme des Harengs" : 
Gottlieb Mittelberger avertit son compatriote des périls de 
l'émigration, 1750</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Embalado Densa, Como Herrings": Gottlieb 
Mittelberger adverte seu compatriota dos perils do emigration, 1750</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Imballato Densamente, Come Le Aringhe": 
Gottlieb Mittelberger avverte il suo countryman dei pericoli di 
emigrazione, 1750</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Συσκευασμένος πυκνά, όπως τις ρέγγεσ": Το 
Gottlieb Mittelberger προειδοποιεί το χωρικό του των κινδύνων
για την αποδημία, 1750</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Pila de discos Denso, Como Los Arenques": 
Gottlieb Mittelberger advierte a su paisano de los peligros de 
la Emigración, 1750</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the seventeenth and early eighteenth centuries, many colonists arrived as indentured servants or bondsmen who served a term of service before receiving their freedom. This practice meant that impoverished Germans and other Europeans financed their passage across the Atlantic. Between 1749 and 1754 more than 30,000 Germans came to Pennsylvania, and by mid-century they constituted about one third of the colony's population. Gottlieb Mittelberger arrived in Philadelphia in late 1750 aboard the  Osgood , along with 500 of his fellow countrymen. With fortunes better than most, he settled as an organist and schoolmaster in New Providence, a German farming community outside Philadelphia. He found much distasteful about his new home and returned in 1754 to write an expose warning Germans about fraudulent accounts of ideal conditions in America.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In den seventeenth und früh achtzehnten 
Jahrhunderten kamen viele Kolonisten wie indentured Bedienstete oder 
Bürgen an, die eine Bezeichnung des Services dienten, bevor sie ihre 
Freiheit empfingen. Diese Praxis bedeutete, daß verarmte 
Deutsche und andere Europäer ihren Durchgang über dem Atlantik 
finanzierten. Zwischen 1749 und 1754 mehr als 30.000 Deutschen 
kam nach Pennsylvania, und bis zum Mid-century setzten sie ungefähr 
Drittel der Bevölkerung der Kolonie fest. Gottlieb Mittelberger
kam in Philadelphia spätem 1750 an Bord des Osgood, zusammen mit 500 
seiner Mitlandsmänner an. Mit Vermögenn verbessern Sie, als 
die meisten, er als Organist und Schoolmaster in der neuen Vorsehung, 
ein deutscher Bauernverband außerhalb Philadelphias vereinbarten. 
Er fand viel distasteful über sein neues Haus und kam 1754 
zurück, um einem Exposé warnende Deutsche über betrügerische 
Konten der idealen Bedingungen in Amerika zu schreiben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Aux dix-septièmes et tôt dix-huitième siècles,
beaucoup de colons sont arrivés comme indentured les domestiques ou 
les garants qui ont servi une limite de service avant de recevoir leur
liberté. Cette pratique a signifié que les Allemands appauvris
et d'autres Européens ont financé leur passage à travers l'Océan 
atlantique. Entre 1749 et 1754 plus de 30.000 Allemands est venu
en Pennsylvanie, et par la moitié du siècle ils ont constitué 
environ un tiers de la population de la colonie. Gottlieb 
Mittelberger est arrivé à Philadelphie vers la fin de 1750 à bord 
de l'Osgood, avec 500 de ses compatriotes de camarade. Avec des 
fortunes améliorez que les la plupart, il ont arrangé en tant qu'un 
organiste et maître dans la nouvelle providence, une communauté 
d'exploitation agricole allemande en dehors de Philadelphie. Il 
a trouvé beaucoup désagréable au sujet de sa nouvelle maison et est
retourné en 1754 pour écrire à une exposition les Allemands 
d'avertissement au sujet des comptes frauduleux des conditions 
idéales en Amérique.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nos décimos séptimos e cedo décimos oitavos 
séculos, muitos colonos chegaram como indentured os empregados ou os 
fiadores que serviram a um termo de serviço antes de receber sua 
liberdade. Esta prática significou que os alemães impoverished
e outros Europeus financiaram sua passagem através do Atlântico. 
Entre 1749 e 1754 mais de 30.000 alemães veio a Pensilvânia, e
pelo mid-century constituíram aproximadamente um third da população
da colônia. Gottlieb Mittelberger chegou em Filadélfia em 1750
atrasado a bordo do Osgood, junto com 500 de seus compatriotas do 
companheiro. Com fortunas melhore do que a maioria, ele se 
estabeleciram como um organist e um schoolmaster no providence novo, 
uma comunidade cultivando alemão fora de Filadélfia. Encontrou
muito distasteful sobre sua HOME nova e retornou em 1754 para escrever
a uma exposição alemães de advertência sobre clientes fraudulent 
de circunstâncias ideais em América.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nei diciassettesimi e presto diciottesimi secoli, 
molti colonizzatori sono arrivato come indentured servi o garanti che 
hanno servito un termine di servizio prima della ricezione della loro 
libertà. Questa pratica ha significato che i tedeschi 
impoveriti ed altri Europei hanno finanziato il loro passaggio 
attraverso l'Atlantico. Fra 1749 e 1754 più di 30.000 tedeschi 
è venuto in Pensilvania ed entro la metà del secolo hanno costituito
circa un terzo della popolazione della colonia. Gottlieb 
Mittelberger è arrivato a Filadelfia verso la fine del 1750 a bordo 
del Osgood, con 500 dei suoi countrymen del collega. Con le 
fortune migliori che la maggior parte, lui si sono depositati come un 
organist e schoolmaster nel nuovo providence, una comune agricola 
tedesca fuori di Filadelfia. Ha trovato molto distasteful circa 
la sua nuova sede ed ha ritornato in 1754 per scrivere ad una denunzia
i tedeschi d'avvertimento circa i clienti fraudolenti delle 
circostanze ideali in America.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στους δέκατους έβδομους και δέκατους όγδοους νωρίς 
αιώνες, πολλοί άποικοι έφθασαν όπως υπάλληλοι ή bondsmen που
εξυπηρέτησαν μια θητεία της υπηρεσίας πρίν λαμβάνουν την 
ελευθερία τους. Αυτή η πρακτική σήμανε ότι Γερμανοί και οι
άλλοι Ευρωπαίοι χρηματοδότησαν τη μετάβασή τους πέρα από τον 
Ατλαντικό. Μεταξύ 1749 και 1754 περισσότερων από 
30.000 Γερμανών ήρθε στην Πενσυλβανία, και μέχρι mid-century
που αποτέλεσαν για το ένα τρίτο του πληθυσμού της αποικίας. 
Το Gottlieb Mittelberger έφθασε στη Φιλαδέλφεια σε 
πρόσφατα 1750 στο Osgood, μαζί με 500 των συντροφικών 
χωρικών του. Με τις τύχες καλύτερες από οι περισσότερες, 
εγκατέστησε ως οργανοπαίκτης και schoolmaster στη New 
Providence, μια γερμανική καλλιεργώντας κοινότητα έξω από τη 
Φιλαδέλφεια. Βρήκε πολύ δυσάρεστος για το νέο σπίτι του 
και επέστρεψε το 1754 για να γράψει μια προειδοποίηση Γερμανοί 
έκθεσης για τους ψευδείς απολογισμούς των ιδανικών όρων στην 
Αμερική.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En los decimoséptimos y temprano décimo octavos 
siglos, muchos colonos llegaron como indentured los criados o los 
fiadores que sirvieron un término del servicio antes de recibir su 
libertad. Esta práctica significó que los alemanes 
empobrecidos y otros europeos financiaron su paso a través del 
Atlántico. Entre 1749 y 1754 más de 30.000 alemanes vino a 
Pennsylvania, y por mediados de siglo constituyeron a cerca de un 
tercio de la población de la colonia. Gottlieb Mittelberger 
llegó en Philadelphia en finales de 1750 a bordo del Osgood, junto 
con 500 de sus paisanos del compañero. Con fortunas mejore que 
la mayoría, él colocaron como un organist y profesor en nuevo 
providence, comunidad agrícola alemana fuera de Philadelphia. 
Él encontró mucho desagradable sobre su nuevo hogar y volvió 
en 1754 para escribir a una exposición alemanes amonestadores sobre 
cuentas fraudulentas de condiciones ideales en América.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086717</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104071</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/packed-densely-like-herrings-gottlieb-mittelberger-warns-his-countryman-of-the-perils-of-emigration-1750</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
