<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108422</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108422</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086038</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Began to Feel the Happiness, Liberty, of which I Knew Nothing Before": Boston King Chooses Freedom and the Loyalists during the War for Independence</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ich fing an, dem Glück, Freiheit zu glauben, von
der ich nichts vor" wußte: Boston König Chooses Freedom und 
die Loyalists während des Krieges für Unabhängigkeit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"j'ai commencé à sentir le bonheur, la liberté, 
avant dont je n'ai su rien" : Le Roi de Boston Chooses Freedom 
et les loyalistes pendant la guerre pour l'indépendance</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"eu comecei a sentir a felicidade, a liberdade, de 
que eu não soube nada antes": Rei Escolher Liberdade e 
loyalists de Boston durante a guerra para a independência</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"ho cominciato a ritenere la felicità, la 
libertà, di cui non ho conosciuto niente prima": Re Chooses 
Freedom ed i loyalists de Boston durante la guerra per indipendenza</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"άρχισα να αισθάνομαι την ευτυχία, ελευθερία, για την 
οποία δεν ήξερα τίποτα πριν από": Ο βασιλιάς της Βοστώνης 
επιλέγει την ελευθερία και το Loyalists κατά τη διάρκεια του 
πολέμου για την ανεξαρτησία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"comencé a sentir la felicidad, la libertad, antes
de la cual no sabía nada": Rey Chooses Freedom y los 
legitimistas de Boston durante la guerra para la independencia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Realizing that their best chance of emancipation lay with the British army, as many as 100,000 enslaved African Americans became Loyalists during the War for Independence. They risked possible resale by the British or capture by the Americans, and many became refugees when the British withdrew at the end of the war. Born near Charleston, South Carolina, Boston King fled his owner to join the British. He escaped captivity several times and made his way to New York, the last American port to be evacuated by the British. King was listed in the "Book of Negroes" and issued a certificate of freedom, allowing him to board one of the military transport ships bound for the free black settlements in Nova Scotia. There, King worked as a carpenter and became a Methodist minister. He moved to Sierra Leone in 1792 and published his memoirs, one of a handful of first-person accounts by African-American Loyalist refugees.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Feststellend, daß ihre beste Wahrscheinlichkeit 
der Emanzipation mit der britischen Armee legen, wurden bis zu, wie 
100.000 versklavten, afrikanische Amerikaner Loyalists während des 
Krieges für Unabhängigkeit. Sie riskierten möglichen 
Weiterverkauf durch die Briten oder Sicherung durch die Amerikaner, 
und viele wurden Flüchtlinge, als die Briten am Ende des Krieges 
zurücktraten. Geborenes nahes Charleston, Südcarolina, Boston 
König floh seinen Inhaber, um die Briten zu verbinden. Er 
entging Gefangenschaft mehrmals und bildete seine Methode nach New 
York, den letzten amerikanischen Kanal, von den Briten evakuiert zu 
werden. König wurde im "Buch der Schwarzen" ausgedruckt und 
eine Bescheinigung der Freiheit ausstellte und erlaubte ihm, eins der 
militärischen Transportschiffe zu verschalen, die für die freien 
schwarzen Regelungen in Neuschottland gesprungen wurden. Dort 
arbeitete König als Tischler und wurde ein methodistischer Minister. 
Er zog nach Sierra Leone 1792 um und veröffentlichte seine 
Abhandlungen, eine einer Handvoll Erstperson Rechnungsprüfungen durch
Afrikanisch-African-American Loyalist Flüchtlinge.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Se rendant compte que leur meilleure chance 
d'émancipation s'étendent avec l'armée britannique, autant de comme
100.000 ont asservi Américains africains sont devenus des loyalistes 
pendant la guerre pour l'indépendance. Ils ont risqué la 
revente possible par les Anglais ou la saisie par les Américains, et 
beaucoup sont devenus des réfugiés quand les Anglais se sont 
retirés à la fin de la guerre. Le roi de Charleston proche 
né, Caroline du sud, Boston s'est sauvé son propriétaire pour 
joindre les Anglais. Il a échappé à la captivité plusieurs 
fois et a fait son chemin vers New York, le dernier port américain 
d'être évacué par les Anglais. Le roi a été énuméré dans
le "livre des nègres" et a délivré un certificat de la liberté, 
lui permettant d'embarquer un des bateaux militaires de transport 
liés pour les règlements noirs libres en Nouvelle-Écosse. 
Là, le roi a travaillé en tant que charpentier et est devenu 
un ministre méthodiste. Il s'est déplacé en Sierra Leone en 
1792 et a édité ses mémoires, un d'une poignée de comptes de 
premier-personne par les réfugiés loyalistes afro-américains.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Realizando que sua mais melhor possibilidade do 
emancipation coloca com o exército britânico, tantos como como 
100.000 enslaved americanos africanos transformaram-se loyalists 
durante a guerra para a independência. Arriscaram o resale 
possível pelos Ingleses ou a captação pelos americanos, e muitos 
transformaram-se refugees quando os Ingleses se retiraram no fim da 
guerra. O rei de Charleston próximo nascido, carolina sul, 
Boston fujiu seu proprietário para juntar os Ingleses. Escapou 
do captiveiro diversas vezes e fêz sua maneira a New York, a última 
porta americana ser evacuado pelos Ingleses. O rei foi alistado 
no "livro dos negroes" e emitiu um certificado da liberdade, 
permitindo que board um dos navios militares do transporte limitados 
para os estabelecimentos pretos livres em Nova Escócia. Lá, o 
rei trabalhou como um carpinteiro e transformou-se um ministro 
methodist. Moveu-se para Sierra Leão em 1792 e publicou-se seus
memoirs, um de um punhado de clientes da primeiro-pessoa por refugees 
de Africano-Americano Loyalist.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Rendendosi conto che la loro probabilità migliore 
di emancipazione pone con l'esercito britannico, altretanti come 
100.000 hanno asservito Americani africani sono diventato loyalists 
durante la guerra per indipendenza. Hanno rischiato il resale 
possibile dai Britannici o il bloccaggio dagli Americani e molti sono 
diventato rifugiati quando i Britannici si sono ritirati alla 
conclusione della guerra. Il re de Charleston vicino nato, 
Carolina del Sud, Boston ha fuggito il suo proprietario per unire i 
Britannici. Ha fuoriuscito la prigionia parecchie volte ed ha 
fatto il suo modo a New York, l'ultima porta americana essere evacuato
dai Britannici. Il re è stato elencato "nel libro dei negroes" 
ed ha emesso un certificato della libertà, permettendolo al 
bordo uno delle navi militari di trasporto limitate per gli 
stabilimenti neri liberi in Nuova Scozia. Là, il re ha lavorato
come carpentiere ed è diventato un ministro methodist. Si è
mosso in Sierra Leone in 1792 ed ha pubblicato le sue memorie, una di 
una manciata di clienti della primo-persona dai rifugiati 
dell'Africano-African-American Loyalist.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πραγματοποιώντας ότι η καλύτερη πιθανότητα 
χειραφέτησης τους βάζει με το βρετανικό στρατό, τουλάχιστον 
100.000 υποδουλωμένοι αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί έγιναν 
Loyalists κατά τη διάρκεια του πολέμου για την ανεξαρτησία. 
Διακινδύνευσαν την πιθανή μεταπώληση από τους Βρετανούς ή 
συλλαμβάνουν από τους Αμερικανούς, και πολλοί έγιναν πρόσφυγες 
όταν απέσυραν οι Βρετανοί στο τέλος του πολέμου. Βασιλιάς 
του γεννημένου κοντινού Τσάρλεστον, νότια Καρολίνα, Βοστώνη 
τρεπόμενος σε φυγή τον ιδιοκτήτη του για να ενώσει τους 
Βρετανούς. Δραπέτευσε την αιχμαλωσία αρκετές φορές και 
έκανε τον τρόπο του στη Νέα Υόρκη, ο τελευταίος αμερικανικός 
λιμένας που εκκενώνεται από τους Βρετανούς. Ο βασιλιάς 
εμφανίστηκε λίστα στο "βιβλίο των νέγρων" και εξέδωσε ένα 
πιστοποιητικό της ελευθερίας, που επιτρέπει σε τον για να 
επιβιβαστεί σε ενός από τα στρατιωτικά σκάφη μεταφορών που 
δεσμεύθηκαν για τις ελεύθερες μαύρες τακτοποιήσεις στη Νέα 
Σκοτία. Εκεί, ο βασιλιάς εργάστηκε ως ξυλουργός και έγινε 
μεθοδιστής υπουργός. Κινήθηκε προς τη Σιέρα Λεόνε το 
1792 και δημοσίευσε τα απομνημονεύματά του, μια από μια χούφτα
των απολογισμών πρώτος-προσώπων από African-American 
Loyalist τους πρόσφυγες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Realizando que su mejor ocasión de la 
emancipación pone con el ejército británico, tantos como 100.000 
esclavizaron americanos africanos hicieron legitimistas durante la 
guerra para la independencia. Arriesgaron reventa posible de los
Británicos o captura de los americanos, y muchos hicieron refugiados 
cuando los Británicos se retiraron en el final de la guerra. El
rey de Charleston cercana nata, Carolina del Sur, Boston huyó a su 
propietario para ensamblar a los Británicos. Él escapó 
cautiverio varias veces e hizo su manera a Nueva York, el acceso 
americano pasado de ser evacuado por los Británicos. Enumeraron
en el "libro de negros" y publicó al rey un certificado de la 
libertad, permitiendo que él suba a una de las naves militares del 
transporte limitadas para los establecimientos negros libres en Nueva 
Escocia. Allí, el rey trabajó como carpintero e hizo ministro 
methodist. Él se trasladó a Sierra Leona en 1792 y publicó 
sus memorias, una de un puñado de cuentas de la primero-persona de 
los refugiados Africano-african-American Loyalist.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086038</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108422</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/boston-king</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
