<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105894</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105894</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087287</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A Craft Unionist Rewrites the Ten Commandments</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Fertigkeit-Unionist schreibt die 10 Gebote 
neu</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un syndicaliste de métier récrit les Dix 
commandements</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um unionist do ofício reescreve os dez 
commandments</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un unionista del mestiere riscrive i dieci ordini</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένας ενωτικός τεχνών ξαναγράφει τις δέκα εντολές</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un unionista del arte reescribe los diez 
mandamientos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The moral code of craft unionism was part of a larger system of late nineteenth-century working-class values that went well beyond behavior on the job. Moreover, those values drew upon other deeply held moral beliefs, particularly those growing out of religion. In "Labor's Decalogue," G. Edmonston, the first president of the United Brotherhood ofCarpenters and Joiners, offered a new twist on the biblical Ten Commandments. Edmonston's novel set of "rules" for workers found its way into a variety of labor publications, including an issue of the  Florida Labor Journal  on May 13, 1903. While this document revealed the indebtedness of craft culture to universalist religious ideas, it also reflected the exclusive nature of craft work (members of craft unions in this era were overwhelmingly white and male).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der moralische Code von Fertigkeit unionism war 
ein Teil eines Großsystems der späten 19.-Jahrhundert 
Arbeiterklassewerte, die gut über Verhalten auf dem Job hinaus 
gingen. Außerdem zeichneten jene Werte nach anderem tief 
angehaltenen moralischen Glauben, besonders die, die aus Religion 
heraus wachsen. In "Decalogue der Arbeit" boten G. Edmonston, 
der erste Präsident der vereinigten Bruderschaft ofCarpenters und die
Schreiner, eine neue Torsion auf den biblischen 10 Geboten an. 
Romanset Edmonstons "Richtlinien" für Arbeiter fand seine 
Methode in eine Vielzahl der Arbeitspublikationen, einschließlich 
eine Ausgabe des Florida Arbeitsjournals an Mai 13, 1903. 
Während dieses Dokument die Verschuldung der Fertigkeitkultur 
universalist zu den frommen Ideen aufdeckte, reflektierte es auch die 
exklusive Natur der Fertigkeitarbeit (Bauteile der 
Handwerker-Gewerkschaften in dieser Ära waren überwältigend weiß 
und männlich).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le code moral du syndicalisme de métier faisait 
partie d'un plus grand système des valeurs en retard de classe 
ouvrier de dix-neuvième-siècle qui ont bien dépassé le 
comportement sur le travail. D'ailleurs, ces valeurs ont 
utilisé autre la croyance morale profondément jugée, en particulier
ceux accroissant hors de la religion. Dans le "Décalogue du 
travail," G. Edmonston, le premier président des ofCarpenters unis de
confrérie et les menuisiers, ont offert une nouvelle torsion sur les 
Dix commandements bibliques. L'ensemble du roman d'Edmonston de 
"règles" pour des ouvriers a réussi à pénétrer son une variété 
de publications de travail, y compris une édition du journal de 
travail de la Floride 13 mai 1903. Tandis que ce document 
indiquait l'endettement de la culture de métier aux idées 
religieuses d'universaliste, il a également reflété la nature 
exclusive du travail de métier (les membres des syndicats de métier 
dans cette ère étaient primordialement blancs et mâles).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O código moral do unionism do ofício era parte 
de um sistema maior dos valores atrasados do working-class de 
décimo-século que foram bem além do comportamento no trabalho. 
Além disso, aqueles valores desenharam em cima de outra a 
opinião moral profundamente prendida, particularmente aquelas que 
crescem fora da religião. Do "em Decalogue trabalho," G. 
Edmonston, o primeiro presidente dos ofCarpenters unidos do 
brotherhood e os joiners, ofereceram uma torção nova nos dez 
commandments biblical. O jogo da novela de Edmonston de 
"réguas" para trabalhadores encontrou sua maneira em uma variedade de
publicações labor, including uma introdução do jornal labor de 
Florida maio em 13, 1903. Quando este original revelou o 
indebtedness da cultura do ofício às idéias religiosas do 
universalist, refletiu também a natureza exclusiva do trabalho do 
ofício (os membros de uniões de ofício nesta era eram 
overwhelmingly brancos e masculinos).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il codice morale del unionism del mestiere faceva 
parte di più grande sistema dei valori ritardati della classe operaia
di diciannovesimo-secolo che sono andato bene oltre comportamento sul 
lavoro. Inoltre, quei valori hanno dissipato su altra la 
credenza morale profondamente tenuta, specialmente quelle che crescono
dalla religione. "in Decalogue Di lavoro," G. Edmonston, il 
primo presidente dei ofCarpenters uniti della fratellanza ed i 
falegnami, hanno offerto una nuova torsione sui dieci ordini biblici. 
L'insieme del romanzo del Edmonston "delle regole" per gli 
operai ha riuscito a penetrare relativo una varietà di pubblicazioni 
di lavoro, compreso un'edizione del giornale Di lavoro della Florida
maggio su 13, 1903. Mentre questo documento ha rivelato il 
indebitamento della coltura del mestiere alle idee religiose di 
universalist, egualmente ha riflesso la natura esclusiva del lavoro 
del mestiere (membri dei sindacati di mestiere in questa era erano in 
modo schiacciante bianchi e maschii).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο ηθικός κώδικας του συνδικαλισμού τεχνών ήταν μέρος
ενός μεγαλύτερου συστήματος των πρόσφατων αξιών εργατικών 
τάξεων δέκατος-αιώνα που εξεπέρασαν τη συμπεριφορά στην εργασία.
Επιπλέον, εκείνες οι τιμές βασίστηκαν σε άλλες βαθειά 
κρατημένες ηθικές πεποιθήσεις, ιδιαίτερα εκείνοι που αυξάνονται 
από τη θρησκεία. Στο "δεκάλογο της εργασίας," Γ. 
Edmonston, ο πρώτος Πρόεδρος της ενωμένης αδελφοσύνης 
ofCarpenters και των ξυλουργών, πρόσφερε μια νέα συστροφή στις 
βιβλικές δέκα εντολές. Το νέο σύνολο του Edmonston 
"κανόνων" για τους εργαζομένους βρήκε τον τρόπο του σε ποικίλες 
δημοσιεύσεις εργασίας, συμπεριλαμβανομένου ενός ζητήματος του 
περιοδικού εργασίας της Φλώριδας σε Μάιος 13, το 1903. 
Ενώ το παρόν έγγραφο αποκάλυψε την υποχρέωση του 
πολιτισμού τεχνών στις παγκόσμιες θρησκευτικές ιδέες, απεικόνισε
επίσης την αποκλειστική φύση της εργασίας τεχνών (τα μέλη των 
ενώσεων τεχνών σε αυτήν την εποχή ήταν συντριπτικά λευκά και 
αρσενικά).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El código moral del unionism del arte era parte 
de un sistema más grande de los últimos valores de la clase obrera 
del diecinueveavo-siglo que fueron bien más allá de comportamiento 
en el trabajo. Por otra parte, esos valores trazaron sobre otra 
la creencia moral profundamente llevada a cabo, determinado ésas que 
crecían fuera de la religión. En "Decalogue del trabajo," G. 
Edmonston, el primer presidente de los ofCarpenters unidos de la 
fraternidad y los carpinteros, ofrecieron una nueva torcedura en los 
diez mandamientos bíblicos. El conjunto de la novela de 
Edmonston de "reglas" para los trabajadores encontró su manera en una
variedad de publicaciones de trabajo, incluyendo una aplicación el 
diario de trabajo de la Florida 13 de mayo de 1903. Mientras 
que este documento reveló el endeudamiento de la cultura del arte a 
las ideas religiosas del universalist, también reflejó la naturaleza
exclusiva del trabajo del arte (los miembros de las uniones de arte en
esta era eran de forma aplastante blancos y masculinos).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087287</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105894</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-craft-unionist-rewrites-the-ten-commandments</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
