<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103585</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103585</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086484</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"More Work for Mother"?: Scientific Management At Home</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"mehr Arbeit für Mutter"?: 
Wissenschaftliche Unternehmensführung Zu Hause</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"plus travail pour la mère" ? : Gestion 
Scientifique À la maison</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"mais trabalho para a matriz"?: Gerência 
Científica Na HOME</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"più lavoro per la madre"?: Gestione 
Scientifica Nel paese</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Περισσότερη εργασία για τη μητέρα";: 
Επιστημονική διαχείριση στο σπίτι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"más trabajo para la madre"?: Gerencia 
Científica En el país</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the early 20th century, new household technology was both accomplished and inspired by the tremendous increase in American industrial production. As in industry, mechanization and scientific management were part of a larger reorganization of work. And as in industry, efficient housekeeping was partially a response to labor unrest--both the "servant problem" and the growing disquiet of middle-class wives. A major proponent of the new housekeeping, Christine Frederick was consulting household editor for  Ladies Home Journal  from 1912 to 1919 and the author of numerous books and pamphlets on scientific management in the home. First published in 1913, Frederick's  The New Housekeeping  opened with her conversion to the "efficiency gospel" under the tutelage of her husband and a male efficiency expert. In chapter 12, Frederick exhorted middle-class women to escape the drudgery of housework by shedding their bad attitudes--and as she enumerated those, she revealed some of the pervasive discontents of women in the home.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im frühen 20. Jahrhundert wurde neue Haushalt 
Technologie durch die enorme Zunahme der amerikanischen industriellen 
Industrieproduktion vollendet und angespornt. Wie in der 
Industrie, waren Mechanisierung und wissenschaftliche 
Unternehmensführung ein Teil einer größeren Reorganisierung der 
Arbeit. Und wie in der Industrie, war leistungsfähige 
Haushaltung teilweise eine Antwort zur Arbeitsruhelosigkeit -- das 
"Bedienstetproblem" und die wachsende Besorgnis der 
Mittelklassefrauen. Ein Hauptantragsteller der neuen 
Haushaltung, Christine Frederick beriet Haushalt Herausgeber für 
Dame-Hauptjournal von 1912 bis 1919 und den Autor der zahlreichen 
Bücher und der Flugschriften auf wissenschaftlicher 
Unternehmensführung im Haus. Zuerst veröffentlicht 1913, 
Fredericks öffnete sich die neue Haushaltung mit ihrer Konvertierung 
zum "Leistungsfähigkeit Evangelium" unter dem tutelage ihres Ehemanns
und der männlichen Rationalisierungsfachleute. In Kapitel 12, 
Frederick exhorted Mittelklassefrauen, zum der Schufterei der 
Hausarbeit durch Shedding zu entgehen ihre falsche Haltung -- und da 
sie die aufzählte, deckte sie einige der durchdringenden discontents 
der Frauen im Haus auf.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En début du 20ème siècle, la nouvelle 
technologie de ménage a été accomplie et inspirée par 
l'augmentation énorme de la production industrielle américaine. 
Comme dans l'industrie, la mécanisation et la gestion 
scientifique faisaient partie d'une plus grande réorganisation de 
travail. Et comme dans l'industrie, le ménage efficace était 
partiellement une réponse au malaise ouvrier -- le "problème 
d'domestique" et l'inquiétude croissante des épouses de classe 
moyenne. Un partisan important du nouveau ménage, Christine 
Frederick consultait l'éditeur de ménage pour le journal à la 
maison de dames de 1912 à 1919 et l'auteur de nombreux livres et 
brochures sur la gestion scientifique dans la maison. D'abord 
édité en 1913, ménage de Frederick le nouveau s'est ouvert avec sa 
conversion en "evangile d'efficacité" sous la tutelle de son mari
et d'un expert de l'efficience mâle. En chapitre 12, Frederick 
recommandé instamment femmes de classe moyen pour échapper à la 
servitude des travaux domestiques par la perte leurs mauvaises 
attitudes -- et car elle a énuméré ceux, elle a indiqué certains 
des discontents dominants des femmes dans la maison.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No 20o século adiantado, a tecnologia nova da 
casa  foi realizada e inspirada pelo aumento tremendo na produção 
industrial americana. Como na indústria, o mechanization e a 
gerência científica eram parte de um reorganization maior do 
trabalho. E como na indústria, as tarefas domésticas 
eficientes eram parcialmente uma resposta ao unrest labor --  do "o 
problema empregado" e o disquiet crescente de esposas do middle-class.
Um proponent principal das tarefas domésticas novas, Christine 
Frederick consultava o editor da casa para o jornal home das senhoras 
de 1912 a 1919 e o autor de livros e de panfletos numerosos na 
gerência científica na HOME. Publicado primeiramente em 1913, 
as tarefas domésticas novas de Frederick abriram com sua conversão 
da "ao gospel eficiência" sob o tutelage de seu marido e de um perito
de eficiência masculino. No capítulo 12, Frederick exhorted 
mulheres do middle-class para escapar do drudgery do housework pelo 
derramamento suas atitudes más -- e porque enumerated aquelas, 
revelou alguns dos discontents pervasive das mulheres na HOME.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nell'inizio del 20esimo secolo, la nuova 
tecnologia della famiglia sia è stata compiuta che ispirato stata 
tramite l'incremento tremendo della produzione industriale americana. 
Come nell'industria, la meccanizzazione e la gestione 
scientifica facevano parte di più grande riorganizzazione di lavoro. 
E come nell'industria, il governo della casa efficiente era 
parzialmente una risposta ad agitazione di lavoro -- sia "il problema
del servo" che l'inquietudine crescente delle mogli della classe 
media. Un fautore importante di nuovo governo della casa, 
Christine Frederick stava consultando l'editore della famiglia per il 
giornale domestico delle signore da 1912 a 1919 e l'autore dei libri e
degli opuscoli numerosi sulla gestione scientifica nella sede. 
In primo luogo pubblicato in 1913, governo della casa del 
Frederick il nuovo si è aperto con la sua conversione "al gospel di 
risparmio di temi" sotto il tutelage del suo marito e di un esperto di
risparmio di temi maschio. Nel capitolo 12, Frederick exhorted 
le donne della classe media fuoriuscire il drudgery di lavori 
domestici dallo spargimento i loro atteggiamenti difettosi -- e mentre
ha enumerato quelle, ha rivelato alcuni dei discontents dominanti 
delle donne nella sede.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στις αρχές του 20ού αιώνα, η νέα οικιακή τεχνολογία 
και ολοκληρώθηκε και εμπνεύστηκε από την τεράστια αύξηση στην 
αμερικανική βιομηχανική παραγωγή. Όπως στη βιομηχανία, η 
μηχανοποίηση και η επιστημονική διαχείριση ήταν μέρος μιας 
μεγαλύτερης αναδιοργάνωσης της εργασίας. Και όπως στη 
βιομηχανία, η αποδοτική οικοκυρική ήταν μερικώς μια απάντηση 
στην ανησυχία εργασίας -- και το "πρόβλημα υπαλλήλων" και η 
αυξανόμενη ανησυχία των συζύγων μεσαίων τάξεων. Ένας 
σημαντικός υπερασπιστής της νέας οικοκυρικής, Christine 
Frederick συμβουλευόταν τον οικιακό επεξεργαστή για το 
περιοδικό γυναικείων "Οικιαών από το 1912 ως το 1919 και το 
συντάκτη των πολυάριθμων βιβλίων και των τευχών για την 
επιστημονική διαχείριση στο σπίτι. Πρώτα δημοσιευμένη το 
1913, οικοκυρική Frederick η νέα άνοιξε με τη μετατροπή της 
στο "Ευαγγέλιο αποδοτικότητασ" κάτω από την κηδεμονία του 
συζύγου της και ενός αρσενικού εμπειρογνώμονα αποδοτικότητας. 
Στο κεφάλαιο 12, Frederick προέτρεψε τις γυναίκες 
μεσαίων τάξεων για να δραπετεύσει το μόχθο των οικιακών με το 
σκόρπισμα των κακών τοποθετήσεών τους -- και δεδομένου ότι 
απαρίθμησε εκείνους, αποκάλυψε μερικά από τα κυρίαρχα 
discontents των γυναικών στο σπίτι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En el vigésimo siglo temprano, la nueva 
tecnología de la casa fue lograda e inspirada por el enorme aumento 
en la producción industrial americana. Como en industria, la 
mecanización y la gerencia científica eran parte de una 
reorganización más grande del trabajo. Y como en industria, 
las operacíones de entretenimiento eficientes eran parcialmente una 
respuesta al malestar de trabajo -- el "problema del criado" y la 
inquietud cada vez mayor de las esposas de la clase media. Un 
autor importante de las nuevas operacíones de entretenimiento, 
Christine Frederick consultaba el editor de la casa para el diario 
casero de las señoras a partir de 1912 a 1919 y el autor de libros y 
de folletos numerosos en la gerencia científica en el hogar. 
Primero publicado en 1913, las nuevas operacíones de 
entretenimiento de Frederick se abrieron con su conversión al 
"evangelio de la eficacia" bajo el tutelage de su marido y de un 
experto de eficacia masculino. En el capítulo 12, Frederick 
suplicó a mujeres de la clase media que escaparan la servidumbre del 
quehacer doméstico por el vertimiento sus malas actitudes -- y como 
ella enumeró ésos, ella reveló algunos de los discontents 
penetrantes de mujeres en el hogar.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086484</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103585</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/more-work-for-mother-scientific-management-at-home</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
