<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108332</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108332</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085262</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Japanese American Relocation Digital Archives</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Japanische Amerikanische Verschiebung Digital 
Archive</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Archives Américaines Japonaises de Digital de 
Réadressage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Arquivos Americanos Japoneses De Digital Do 
Relocation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Archivi Americani Giapponesi Di Digital Di 
Rilocazione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ιαπωνικά αμερικανικά ψηφιακά αρχεία επαναμετάθεσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Archivos Americanos Japoneses De Digital De la 
Realocación</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">On December 7, 1941, Japan bombed Pearl Harbor. The next day, the United States and Britain declared war on Japan. Two months later, on February 19, 1942, the lives of thousands of Japanese Americans were dramatically changed when President Franklin D. Roosevelt signed Executive Order 9066. This order led to the assembly and evacuation and relocation of nearly 122,000 men, women, and children of Japanese ancestry on the west coast of the United States.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">An Dezember 7, 1941, Japan bombardierte Pearl 
Harbor. Am nächsten Tag, erklärten die Vereinigten Staaten und
das Großbritannien Krieg auf Japan. Zwei Monate später, an 
Februar 19, 1942, wurden die Leben von Tausenden der japanischen 
Amerikaner drastisch geändert, als Präsident Franklin D. Roosevelt 
Ausführungsverordnung 9066 unterzeichnete. Diese Ordnung 
führte zu den Zusammenbau und die Evakuierung und die Verschiebung 
von fast 122.000 Männern, von Frauen und von Kindern japanischem 
Geschlecht auf der Westküste der Vereinigten Staaten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">7 décembre 1941, Japon a bombardé le port de 
perle. Le jour suivant, les Etats-Unis et la Grande-Bretagne ont
déclaré la guerre sur le Japon. Deux mois plus tard, février 
19, 1942, les vies des milliers d'Américains japonais ont été 
excessivement changées quand le Président Franklin D. Roosevelt a 
signé la commande exécutive 9066. Cette commande a mené à 
l'assemblage et l'évacuation et le réadressage de presque 122.000 
hommes, femmes, et enfants d'ascendance japonaise sur la côte 
occidentale des Etats-Unis.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Dezembro em 7, 1941, Japão bombardeou o porto de 
pérola. No dia seguinte, os estados e o Grâ Bretanha unidos 
declararam a guerra em Japão. Dois meses mais tarde, fevereiro 
em 19, 1942, as vidas dos milhares de americanos japoneses foram 
mudadas dramàtica quando o presidente Franklin D. Roosevelt assinou a
ordem executiva 9066. Esta ordem conduziu ao conjunto e a 
evacuação e o relocation de quase 122.000 homens, mulheres, e 
crianças do ancestry japonês na costa ocidental dos estados unidos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il 7 dicembre 1941, Giappone ha bombardato il 
porto di perla. Il giorno seguente, unito Dichiara e 
guerra dichiarata la Gran-Bretagna con Giappone. Due mesi più 
successivamente, il 19 febbraio 1942, le vite dei migliaia degli 
Americani giapponesi sono state cambiate drammaticamente quando il 
presidente Franklin D. Roosevelt ha firmato l'ordine esecutivo 9066. 
Questo ordine ha condotto al complessivo e l'evacuamento e la 
rilocazione di quasi 122.000 uomini, donne e bambini dell'ascendenza 
giapponese sul litorale ad ovest del unito Dichiara.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στις 7 Δεκεμβρίου ..1941, βομβαρδισμένο η Ιαπωνία 
λιμάνι μαργαριταριών. Η επόμενη ημέρα, οι Ηνωμένες 
Πολιτείες και η Μεγάλη Βρετανία κήρυξαν πόλεμος στην Ιαπωνία. 
Δύο μήνες αργότερα, στις 19 Φεβρουαρίου ..1942, τις 
ζωές χιλιάδων ιαπωνικοί Αμερικανοί άλλαξαν εντυπωσιακά όταν 
υπέγραψε ο Πρόεδρος Franklin D. Roosevelt την εκτελεστική 
κατάταξη 9066. Αυτή η κατάταξη οδήγησε στη συμβολική 
γλώσσα και την εκκένωση και την επαναμετάθεση των σχεδόν 
122.000 ανδρών, γυναικών, και παιδιών της ιαπωνικής καταγωγής 
δυτική ακτή των Ηνωμένων Πολιτειών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">7 de diciembre de 1941, Japón bombardeó el 
puerto de perla. El día siguiente, los Estados Unidos y la Gran
Bretaña declararon guerra en Japón. Dos meses más adelante, 
19 de febrero de 1942, las vidas de millares de americanos 
japoneses fueron cambiadas dramáticamente cuando presidente Franklin 
D. Roosevelt firmó la orden ejecutiva 9066. Esta orden condujo 
al ensamblaje y la evacuación y la realocación de casi 122.000 
hombres, mujeres, y niños de ascendencia japonesa en la costa del 
oeste de los Estados Unidos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085262</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108332</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/japanese-american-relocation-digital-archives</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
