<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103401</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103401</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206562</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Samuel F. B. Morse Papers at the Library of Congress, 1793-1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Samuel F. B. Morse Papers an der Bibliothek von 
Kongreß, 1793-1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Samuel F. B. Morse Papers à la bibliothèque du 
congrès, 1793-1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Samuel F. B. Morse Papel na biblioteca do 
congress, 1793-1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Samuel F. B. Morse Papers alla libreria del 
congresso, 1793-1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Έγγραφα του Samuel F. Β. Μορς στη βιβλιοθήκη του 
συνεδρίου, 1793-1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Samuel F. B. Morse Papers en la biblioteca del 
congreso, 1793-1919</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">presents 6,500 items that document Morse's invention of the electromagnetic telegraph, his participation in the development of telegraph systems in the U.S. and abroad, his career as a painter, his family life, his travels, and more. Included in this collection are correspondence, letterbooks, diaries, scrapbooks, printed matter, maps, and drawings.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt 6.500 Einzelteile, die Erfindung Morse des 
elektromagnetischen Fernschreibers, seine Teilnahme an der Entwicklung
der Fernschreibersysteme in den VEREINIGTEN STAATEN und auswärts 
dokumentieren, seine Karriere als Maler, sein Familienleben dar, reist
seins und mehr. In dieser Ansammlung geschlossen Korrespondenz, 
letterbooks, Tagebücher, Scrapbooks, Drucksache, Karten und 
Zeichnungen ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">présente 6.500 éléments qui documentent 
l'invention de Morse du télégraphe électromagnétique, sa 
participation au développement des systèmes de télégraphe aux 
ETATS-UNIS et à l'étranger, sa carrière en tant que peintre, sa vie
de famille, sien voyage, et plus. Inclus dans cette collection 
sont la correspondance, les letterbooks, les agendas, les albums, la 
matière imprimée, les cartes, et les schémas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">apresenta 6.500 artigos que documentam a 
invenção do telégrafo eletromagnético, sua participação de Morse
no desenvolvimento de sistemas do telégrafo nos ESTADOS UNIDOS e no 
exterior, sua carreira como um pintor, sua vida de família, his 
viaja, e mais. São incluídos nesta coleção a 
correspondência, os letterbooks, os diários, os scrapbooks, a 
matéria impressa, os mapas, e os desenhos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">presenta 6.500 articoli che documentano 
l'invenzione del telegrafo elettromagnetico, la sua partecipazione del
Morse allo sviluppo dei sistemi del telegrafo negli STATI UNITI ed 
all'estero, la sua carriera come pittore, la sua vita di famiglia, suo
viaggia e più. Sono inclusi in questa accumulazione la 
corrispondenza, i letterbooks, i diari, gli album, la materia 
stampata, i programmi e le illustrazioni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρουσιάζει 6.500 αντικείμενα που τεκμηριώνουν την 
εφεύρεση Μορς του ηλεκτρομαγνητικού τηλέγραφου, τη συμμετοχή του 
στην ανάπτυξη των συστημάτων τηλέγραφων στις ΗΠΑ και στο 
εξωτερικό, τη σταδιοδρομία του ως ζωγράφο, την οικογενειακή ζωή 
του, τα ταξίδια του, και περισσότερων. Περιλαμβάνονται σε 
αυτήν την συλλογή η αλληλογραφία, letterbooks, τα ημερολόγια, 
τα λευκώματα αποκομμάτων, το τυπωμένο θέμα, οι χάρτες, και τα 
σχέδια.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">presenta 6.500 items que documenten la invención 
del telégrafo electromágnetico, su participación de Morse en el 
desarrollo de los sistemas del telégrafo en los ESTADOS UNIDOS y al 
exterior, su carrera como pintor, su vida de familia, el suyo viaja, y
más. Se incluyen en esta colección la correspondencia, los 
letterbooks, los diarios, los libros de recuerdos, la materia impresa,
las correspondencias, y los gráficos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206562</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103401</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/samuel-f-b-morse-papers-at-the-library-of-congress-1793-1919</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
