<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105904</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105904</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212553</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Derivatives and Extrema</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ableitungen und Extrema</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dérivés et extrema</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Derivatives e extrema</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Derivati ed estremi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παράγωγα και extrema</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Derivados y extrema</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The particular ability of the internet to demonstrate concepts interactively in a visually arresting fashion is fully realized in this attractive and easily navigated site. An interactive screen allows the user to select a function and examine the visual representation of its derivative through magnification of the resulting graph. The site provides a wonderful opportunity to see and understand the sometimes elusive concept of derivation. This resource is part of the Teaching Quantitative Skills in the Geosciences collection. http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die bestimmte Fähigkeit des Internets, Konzepte 
interaktiv auf eine sichtlich festhaltene Art und Weise zu 
demonstrieren wird völlig in dieser attraktiven und leicht 
gesteuerten Site verwirklicht. Ein interaktiver Bildschirm 
erlaubt dem Benutzer, eine Funktion auszuwählen und die 
Sichtdarstellung seiner Ableitung durch Vergrößerung des 
resultierenden Diagramms zu überprüfen. Die Site liefert eine 
wundervolle Gelegenheit, das manchmal schwer bestimmbare Konzept der 
Ableitung zu sehen und zu verstehen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein 
Teil der Unterricht quantitativen Fähigkeiten in der Geosciences 
Ansammlung http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La capacité particulière de l'Internet de 
démontrer des concepts en mode interactif d'une mode visuellement 
frappante est entièrement réalisée dans ce site attrayant et 
facilement dirigé. Un écran interactif permet à l'utilisateur
de choisir une fonction et d'examiner la représentation visuelle de 
son dérivé par le rapport optique du graphique résultant. Le 
site fournit une occasion merveilleuse de voir et comprendre le 
concept parfois évasif de la dérivation. Cette ressource fait 
partie des qualifications quantitatives d'enseignement dans la 
collection http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/ de Geosciences</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A abilidade particular do Internet de demonstrar 
conceitos em uma forma visualmente prendendo é realizada 
interativamente inteiramente neste local atrativo e fàcilmente 
navigated. Uma tela interativa permite que o usuário selecione 
uma função e examine a respresentação visual de seu derivative com
a ampliação do gráfico resultante. O local fornece uma 
oportunidade maravilhosa de ver e compreender o conceito às vezes 
elusive da derivação. Este recurso é parte das habilidades 
quantitative do ensino na coleção 
http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/ de Geosciences</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La capacità particolare del Internet di 
dimostrare i concetti ad un modo visivamente arrestante completamente 
è realizzata con interazione in questo luogo attraente e facilmente 
traversato. Uno schermo interattivo permette che l'utente 
selezioni una funzione ed esamini la rappresentazione visiva del 
relativo derivato con ingrandimento del grafico risultante. Il 
luogo fornisce un'occasione meravigliosa vedere e capire il concetto a
volte evasivo della derivazione. Questa risorsa fa parte delle 
abilità quantitative di insegnamento nell'accumulazione 
http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/ di Geosciences</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ιδιαίτερη δυνατότητα του Διαδικτύου να καταδείξει 
τις έννοιες αμφίδρομα σε μια μόδα οπτικά σύλληψης 
πραγματοποιείται πλήρως σε αυτήν την ελκυστική και εύκολα 
πλοηγημένη περιοχή. Μια διαλογική οθόνη επιτρέπει στο 
χρήστη για να επιλέξει μια λειτουργία και να εξετάσει την οπτική 
αντιπροσώπευση του παραγώγου της μέσω της ενίσχυσης της 
προκύπτουσας γραφικής παράστασης. Η περιοχή παρέχει μια 
θαυμάσια ευκαιρία να δει και να γίνει κατανοητή η 
μερικές φορές αόριστη έννοια της παραγωγής. Αυτό το 
στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς είναι μέρος των ποσοτικών δεξιοτήτων 
διδασκαλίας στη Geosciences συλλογή 
http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La capacidad determinada del Internet de demostrar
conceptos en una manera visualmente de arresto se observa 
recíprocamente completamente en este sitio atractivo y fácilmente 
navegado. Una pantalla interactiva permite que el utilizador 
seleccione una función y examine la representación visual de su 
derivado con la ampliación del gráfico que resulta. El sitio 
proporciona a una oportunidad maravillosa de ver y de entender el 
concepto a veces evasivo de la derivación. Este recurso es 
parte de las habilidades cuantitativas de la enseñanza en la 
colección http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/ de Geosciences</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:GEOFFREY DIXON
FN:GEOFFREY DIXON
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212553</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105904</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-evolution-evidence-page</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
