<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106082</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106082</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201365</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Earth Exploration Toolbook Chapter: Investigating Earthquakes: GIS Mapping and Analysis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Masse Erforschung Toolbook Kapitel: 
Nachforschende Erdbeben: GIS Diagramm und Analyse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Chapitre de Toolbook d'Exploration de la Terre : 
Tremblements de terre d'Investigation : Tracer et analyse 
de GIs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Capítulo De Toolbook Da Exploração Da Terra: 
Terremotos Investigando: Traçar e análise dos SOLDADOS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Capitolo Di Toolbook Di Esplorazione Della Terra: 
Terremoti Di Studio: Tracciato ed analisi di GIS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κεφάλαιο Toolbook γήινης εξερεύνησης: Σεισμοί
έρευνας: Χαρτογράφηση και ανάλυση GIS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Capítulo De Toolbook De la Exploración De la 
Tierra: Terremotos Que investigan: El asociar y análisis 
de los SOLDADOS ENROLADOS EN EL EJÉRCITO</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This activity describes the technique of preparing latitude-longitude based data so it can be imported into a geographic information system (GIS). The chapter describes the steps to create a map to display data and guides users through some basic geographic analyses. The focus of the chapter's case study is earthquake prediction. Users download and format near real-time and historical earthquake data from the USGS. They import the data into ArcVoyager Special Edition GIS software, and analyze patterns by querying records and overlaying datasets. Users examine earthquake distributions, monitor current earthquake activity, and try to predict where the next big earthquake will occur. Any data set that specifies latitude and longitude coordinates can be prepared for importing into a GIS with the techniques described in this chapter. Examples of data sets that can be investigated include stream flow conditions, global land and sea surface temperatures, and data gathered with a GPS.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Aktivität beschreibt die Technik des 
Vorbereitens der Breite-Länge gegründeten Daten, also kann sie in 
ein geographisches Informationssystem (GIS) importiert werden. 
Das Kapitel beschreibt die Jobsteps, um eine Karte herzustellen,
um Daten anzuzeigen und führt Benutzer durch etwas grundlegende 
geographische Analysen. Der Fokus der Fallstudie des Kapitels 
ist Erdbebenvorhersage. Benutzer downloaden und formatieren nahe
den Echtzeit- und historischen Erdbebendaten vom USGS. Sie 
importieren die Daten in ArcVoyager Sonderausgabe GIS-Software und 
analysieren Muster, indem sie Sätze abfragen und Datensätze 
bedecken. Benutzer überprüfen Erdbebenverteilungen, 
überwachen aktuelle Erdbebenaktivität und versuchen, vorauszusagen, 
wo das folgende grosse Erdbeben auftritt. Irgendeine Datei, die 
Breite- und Längekoordinaten spezifiziert, kann für das Importieren 
in vorbereitet werden von von GIS mit den Techniken, die in diesem 
Kapitel beschrieben werden. Beispiele der Dateien, die 
nachgeforscht werden können, schließen Stromflußzustände, globale 
Land- und Seoberflächentemperaturen und die Daten, die mit einem GPS 
erfaßt werden ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette activité décrit la technique de préparer 
des données basées parlongitude ainsi elle peut être importée dans
un système d'information géographique (GIs). Le 
chapitre décrit les étapes pour créer une carte pour afficher des 
données et guide des utilisateurs par quelques analyses 
géographiques de base. Le centre de l'étude de cas du chapitre
est prévision de tremblement de terre. Les utilisateurs 
téléchargent et formatent près des données en temps réel et 
historiques de tremblement de terre de l'USGS. Ils importent les
données dans le logiciel de GIs d'édition spéciale 
d'ArcVoyager, et analysent des configurations en questionnant des 
enregistrements et en recouvrant des ensembles de données. Les 
utilisateurs examinent des distributions de tremblement de terre, 
surveillent l'activité actuelle de tremblement de terre, et essayent 
de prévoir où le prochain grand tremblement de terre se produira. 
N'importe quel Modem qui indique des coordonnées de latitude et
de longitude peut être préparé pour importer dans des GIs 
avec les techniques décrites en ce chapitre. Les exemples des 
Modem qui peuvent être étudiés incluent des états d'écoulement de
jet, des températures de surface globales de terre et de mer, et des 
données recueillies avec un GPS.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta atividade descreve a técnica de preparar 
dados baseados latitude-longitude assim que pode ser importada em um 
sistema de informação geográfico (SOLDADOS). O capítulo 
descreve as etapas para criar um mapa para indicar dados e guia 
usuários com algumas análises geográficas básicas. O foco do
estudo de caso do capítulo é predição do terremoto. Os 
usuários download e formatam perto dos dados real-time e históricos 
do terremoto do USGS. Importam os dados no software dos SOLDADOS
da edição especial de ArcVoyager, e analisam testes padrões 
perguntando registros e cobrindo séries de dados. Os usuários 
examinam distribuições do terremoto, monitoram a atividade atual do 
terremoto, e tentam-na predizer onde o terremoto grande seguinte 
ocorrerá. Qualquer série de dados de que especificar 
coordenadas da latitude e da longitude pode ser preparada importando 
no SOLDADOS com as técnicas descritas neste capítulo. Os 
exemplos das séries de dados de que podem ser investigadas incluem 
condições do fluxo do córrego, temperaturas de superfície globais 
da terra e do mar, e dados recolhidos com um GPS.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa attività descrive la tecnica di redazione 
dei dati basati latitudine-longitudine in modo da può essere 
importata in un sistema d'informazione geografico (GIS). Il 
capitolo descrive i punti per creare un programma per visualizzare i 
dati e guida gli utenti con alcune analisi geografiche di base. 
Il fuoco dell'inchiesta del capitolo è previsione di terremoto.
Gli utenti trasferiscono e formattano vicino ai dati in tempo 
reale e storici di terremoto dal USGS. Importano i dati nel 
software di GIS dell'edizione speciale di ArcVoyager ed analizzano i 
modelli interrogando i record e ricoprendo i gruppi di dati. Gli
utenti esaminano le distribuzioni di terremoto, controllano 
l'attività corrente di terremoto e provano a predire dove il 
terremoto grande seguente accadrà. Qualunque insieme di dati 
che specifica le coordinate di longitudine e di latitudine può essere
preparato per l'importazione nell'dei GIS con le tecniche descritte in
questo capitolo. Gli esempi degli insiemi di dati che possono 
essere studiati includono gli stati di flusso del flusso, le 
temperature in superficie globali del mare e della terra ed i dati 
riuniti con un GPS.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η δραστηριότητα περιγράφει την τεχνική βασισμένα
τα στο πλάτος-γεωγραφικό μήκος στοιχεία έτσι μπορεί να εισαχθεί
σε ένα γεωγραφικό σύστημα πληροφοριών (GIS). Το κεφάλαιο
περιγράφει τα βήματα για να δημιουργήσει έναν χάρτη στα στοιχεία
παρουσίασης και καθοδηγεί τους χρήστες μέσω μερικών βασικών 
γεωγραφικών αναλύσεων. Η εστίαση της περιπτωσιολογικής 
μελέτης του κεφαλαίου είναι πρόβλεψη σεισμού. Οι χρήστες 
μεταφορτώνουν και σχηματοποιούν κοντά στα σε πραγματικό χρόνο και
ιστορικά στοιχεία σεισμού από το USGS. Εισάγουν τα 
στοιχεία ArcVoyager στο λογισμικό ειδικών εκδόσεων GIS, και 
αναλύουν τα πρότυπα με τη συζήτηση των αρχείων και την επίστρωση 
των συνόλων δεδομένων. Οι χρήστες εξετάζουν τις διανομές 
σεισμού, ελέγχουν την παρούσα δραστηριότητα σεισμού, και 
προσπαθούν να προβλέψουν όπου ο επόμενος μεγάλος σεισμός θα 
εμφανιστεί. Οποιοδήποτε σύνολο στοιχείων που προσδιορίζει 
τις συντεταγμένες γεωγραφικού πλάτους και γεωγραφικού μήκους 
μπορεί να προετοιμαστεί για την εισαγωγή σε ένα GIS με τις 
τεχνικές που περιγράφονται σε αυτό το κεφάλαιο. Τα 
παραδείγματα των συνόλων στοιχείων που μπορούν να ερευνηθούν 
περιλαμβάνουν τους όρους ροής ρευμάτων, τις σφαιρικές 
θερμοκρασίες επιφάνειας εδάφους και θάλασσας, και τα στοιχεία που
συγκεντρώνονται με ένα ΠΣΤ.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta actividad describe la técnica de elaborar 
datos basados latitud-longitud así que puede ser importada en un 
sistema de información geográfico (SOLDADOS ENROLADOS EN EL 
EJÉRCITO). El capítulo describe los pasos de progresión para 
crear una correspondencia para visualizar datos y dirige a 
utilizadores con algunos análisis geográficos básicos. El 
foco del estudio de caso del capítulo es predicción del terremoto. 
Los utilizadores descargan y formataron cerca de datos en tiempo
real e históricos del terremoto del USGS. Importan los datos en
software de los SOLDADOS ENROLADOS EN EL EJÉRCITO de la edición 
especial de ArcVoyager, y analizan modelos preguntando expedientes y 
sobreponiendo datasets. Los utilizadores examinan distribuciones
del terremoto, vigilan actividad actual del terremoto, e intentan 
predecir donde ocurrirá el terremoto grande siguiente. 
Cualquier modem que especifique coordenadas de la latitud y de 
la longitud se puede preparar para importar en SOLDADOS ENROLADOS EN 
EL EJÉRCITO con las técnicas descritas en este capítulo. Los 
ejemplos de los modems que pueden ser investigados incluyen 
condiciones del flujo de la secuencia, temperaturas superficiales 
globales de la pista y del mar, y los datos recopilados con un GPS.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CARLA MCAULIFFE
FN:CARLA MCAULIFFE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201365</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106082</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/earth-exploration-toolbook-chapter-investigating-earthquakes-gis-mapping-and-analysis</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
