<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108335</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108335</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086680</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Not So Private Negotiations": Mexico Expropriates the Oil Companies</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Nicht So Private Vermittlungen": Mexiko 
enteignet die Öl-Firmen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Négociations Pas aussi Privées" : Le 
Mexique exproprie les compagnies pétrolières</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Negociações Não assim Confidenciais": 
México expropriates as companhias de óleo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Trattative Non così Riservate": Il Messico
expropriates le compagnie petrolifere</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Όχι τόσο ιδιωτικές διαπραγματεύσεισ": Το 
Μεξικό απαλλοτριώνει τις επιχειρήσεις πετρελαίου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Negociaciones No tan Privadas": México 
expropriates las compañías petroleras</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1933, newly elected President Franklin Roosevelt announced a "Good Neighbor Policy" that promised a more friendly and less interventionist policy toward Latin America. The policy was prompted as much by Latin American resistance to U.S. intervention as by the U.S. government's benevolence. In 1937, the policy was put to the test when Bolivia charged that Standard Oil of New Jersey had defrauded the Bolivian government; Bolivia canceled the company's oil drilling rights and confiscated its facilities. True to its new policy, the United States avoided military intervention and instead pressured Bolivia by withholding loans and technical assistance. The following year, a war of words erupted between the government of Mexico and the Standard Oil Company of New Jersey over who owned the rights to exploit a portion of Mexico's oil reserves. After U.S. oil companies refused to accept the arbitration terms of the Mexican labor board, Mexican President Lzaro Crdenas expropriated oil company properties worth an estimated half billion dollars. In  The True Facts about the Expropriation of the Oil Companies' Properties in Mexico , the Mexican government clarified its position to the American public and justified expropriation of Standard Oil's property.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1933 eben gewählt Präsidenten Franklin Roosevelt
verkündete eine "gute Nachbarpolitik", die eine freundlichere und 
weniger der Interventionisten Politik in Richtung zu lateinischem 
Amerika versprach. Der Politik wurde so viel durch 
lateinamerikanischen Widerstand zur VEREINIGTE STAATEN Intervention 
wie durch die Wohltätigkeit der VEREINIGTE STAATEN Regierung 
aufgefordert. 1937 wurde die Politik zum Test gesetzt, als 
Bolivien auflud, daß Standardöl von Neu-Jersey die bolivianische 
Regierung betrogen hatte; Bolivien beendete die 
Erdölbohrungrechte der Firma und konfiszierte seine Teildienste. 
Richten Sie zu seiner neuen Politik, die Vereinigte Staaten 
vermiedene militärische Intervention aus und drueckte anstatt 
Bolivien, indem Sie Darlehen und technische Unterstützung 
zurückhalten. Das folgende Jahr, brach ein Krieg von Wörtern 
zwischen der Regierung von Mexiko und Standard Oil Company des 
Neu-Jersey Überschusses aus, die die Rechte besaß, einen Teil 
Ölreserven Mexikos auszunutzen. Nachdem VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Ölfirmen ablehnten, die Schlichtung Bedingungen des mexikanischen 
Arbeitsbrettes zu akzeptieren, enteignete mexikanischer Präsident 
Lzaro Crdenas Ölfirmaeigenschaften wert eine geschätzte Hälfte 
Milliarde Dollar. In den zutreffenden Tatsachen über die 
Enteignung der Öl-der Gesellschaften Eigenschaften in Mexiko, 
erklärte die mexikanische Regierung seine Position zur amerikanischen
Öffentlichkeit und schloß Enteignung der Eigenschaft des 
Standardöls aus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1933, nouvellement élu le Président Franklin 
Roosevelt a annoncé une "bonne politique voisine" qui a promis moins 
de interventionnistes de politique plus amicale et vers l'Amérique 
latine. La politique a été incitée autant par résistance 
latino-américaine à l'intervention des ETATS-UNIS que par la 
bienveillance du gouvernement des ETATS-UNIS. En 1937, la 
politique a été mise à l'essai quand la Bolivie a chargé que 
l'huile standard de New Jersey avait fraudé le gouvernement bolivien
; La Bolivie a annulé les droites de forage d'huile de la 
compagnie et a confisqué ses équipements. Rectifiez à sa 
nouvelle politique, l'intervention militaire évitée par Etats-Unis 
et avez à la place pressurisé la Bolivie en retenant des prêts et 
l'assistance technique. L'année suivante, une guerre des mots a
éclaté entre le gouvernement du Mexique et Pétrolier Standard le 
Company de l'excédent de New Jersey qui a possédé les droites 
d'exploiter une partie de réserves du pétrole du Mexique. 
Après que les compagnies pétrolières des ETATS-UNIS aient 
refusé de recevoir les limites d'arbitrage du panneau de travail 
mexicain, le Président mexicain Lzaro Crdenas a exproprié des 
propriétés de compagnie pétrolière en valeur une moitié estimée 
de milliard de dollars. Dans les faits vrais sur l'expropriation
des propriétés des sociétés d'huile au Mexique, le gouvernement 
mexicain a clarifié sa position au public américain et a justifié 
l'expropriation de la propriété de l'huile standard.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1933, eleito recentemente presidente Franklin 
Roosevelt anunciou "uma política vizinha boa" que prometesse menos 
interventionist política dos mais amigável e para América latin. 
A política foi alertada tanto quanto pela resistência de Latin
Americano à intervenção de ESTADOS UNIDOS quanto pelo benevolence 
do governo de ESTADOS UNIDOS. Em 1937, a política foi posta ao 
teste quando Bolívia carregou que o óleo padrão de Novo-Jersey 
tinha defraudado o governo bolivian; Bolívia cancelou as 
direitas perfurar de óleo da companhia e confiscated suas 
facilidades. Rectifique a sua política nova, os estados unidos 
evitaram a intervenção militar e exerceram pressão sobre 
preferivelmente Bolívia retendo empréstimos e o auxílio técnico. 
O seguinte ano, uma guerra das palavras erupted entre o governo 
de México e os Padrão Óleo Companhia do excesso de Novo-Jersey que 
possuiu as direitas explorar uma parcela de reservas do óleo de 
México. Depois que as companhias de óleo de ESTADOS UNIDOS 
recusaram aceitar os termos do arbitration da placa labor mexicana, o 
presidente mexicano Lzaro Crdenas expropriated propriedades da 
companhia de óleo worth uma metade estimada de bilhão dólares. 
Nos fatos verdadeiros sobre o expropriation das propriedades 
companies' do óleo em México, o governo mexicano esclareceu sua 
posição ao público americano e justificou o expropriation da 
propriedade do óleo padrão.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1933, recentemente scelto presidente Franklin 
Roosevelt ha annunciato "una buona politica contigua" che ha promesso 
interventisti meno e più amichevole una politica verso l'america 
latina. La politica è stata richiamata tanto da resistenza 
dell'America latina ad intervento degli STATI UNITI quanto dal 
benevolence del governo degli STATI UNITI. In 1937, la politica 
è stata messa alla prova quando la Bolivia si è caricata che l'olio 
standard della Nuovo-Jersey aveva defraudato il governo boliviano; 
La Bolivia ha annullato i diritti perforare di olio dell'azienda
ed ha confiscato le relative attrezzature. Allineare alla 
relativa nuova politica, unito Dichiara l'intervento militare 
evitato e la Bolivia preferibilmente pressured ritenendo i prestiti e 
l'assistenza tecnica. Il seguente anno, una guerra delle parole 
ha scoppiato fra il governo del Messico ed i Standard Oil 
Company dell'eccedenza della Nuovo-Jersey che ha posseduto i diritti 
di sfruttare una parte delle riserve dell'olio del Messico. Dopo
che le compagnie petrolifere degli STATI UNITI rifiutino di accettare 
i termini di arbitrato del bordo di lavoro messicano, il 
presidente messicano Lzaro Crdenas expropriated le proprietà della 
compagnia petrolifera degno una metà valutata dei miliardo dollari. 
Nei fatti allineare circa l'espropriazione delle proprietà 
delle società dell'olio nel Messico, il governo messicano ha 
chiarito la relativa posizione al pubblico americano ed ha 
giustificato l'espropriazione della proprietà dell'olio standard.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1933, εξέλεξε πρόσφατα τον Πρόεδρο Franklin 
Roosevelt ανήγγειλε μια "καλή πολιτική γειτόνων" που 
υποσχέθηκε μια πολιτική πιό φιλική και λιγότερη οπαδών του 
παρεμβατισμού προς τη λατινική Αμερική. Η πολιτική 
προτράπηκε τόσο από τη λατινοαμερικανική αντίσταση στην 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ επέμβαση όσο και από την καλοκαγαθία της ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ 
κυβέρνησης. Το 1937, η πολιτική τέθηκε στη δοκιμή όταν 
χρέωσε η Βολιβία ότι το πρότυπο πετρέλαιο του Νιου Τζέρσευ! 
είχε αφαιρέσει δολίως τη βολιβιανή κυβέρνηση  Η Βολιβία 
ηκύρωσε τα δικαιώματα διάτρυσης πετρελαίου της επιχείρησης και 
δήμευσε τις εγκαταστάσεις της. Αληθινός στη νέα πολιτική 
της, οι Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες απέφυγαν τη στρατιωτική επέμβαση και 
πίεσαν αντ' αυτού τη Βολιβία με την παρακράτηση των δανείων και 
της τεχνικής βοήθειας. Το επόμενο έτος, ένας πόλεμος των 
λέξεων εξερράγη μεταξύ της κυβέρνησης του Μεξικού και της 
πρότυπης επιχείρησης πετρελαίου του Νιου Τζέρσευ! πέρα από ποιος
ήταν κύριος των δικαιωμάτων να εκμεταλλευτεί μια μερίδα των 
αποθεμάτων πετρελαίου του Μεξικού. Αφότου αρνήθηκαν να 
αποδεχθούν οι επιχειρήσεις ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΥ πετρελαίου τους όρους 
διαιτησίας της μεξικάνικης επιτροπής εργασίας, ο μεξικάνικος 
Πρόεδρος Lzaro Crdenas απαλλοτρίωσε τις ιδιότητες 
επιχείρησης πετρελαίου αξίας κατ' εκτίμηση μισών από 
δισεκατομμύριο δολάρια. Στα αληθινά γεγονότα για την 
απαλλοτρίωση των ιδιοτήτων των επιχειρήσεων πετρελαίου στο 
Μεξικό, η μεξικάνικη κυβέρνηση διευκρίνισε τη θέση της στην 
αμερικανική δημόσια και δικαιολογημένη απαλλοτρίωση της 
ιδιοκτησίας του πρότυπου πετρελαίου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1933, nuevamente elegido presidente Franklin 
Roosevelt anunció una "buena política vecina" que prometió una 
menos intervencionistas política más cómoda y hacia América 
latina. La política fue incitada tanto por la resistencia Latin
american a la intervención de ESTADOS UNIDOS como por la benevolencia
del gobierno de ESTADOS UNIDOS. En 1937, la política fue puesta
a la prueba cuando Bolivia cargó que hubiera defraudado el aceite 
estándar de Nuevo-Jersey el gobierno boliviano; Bolivia 
canceló las derechas de perforación petrolífera de la compañía y 
confiscó sus recursos. Verdad a su nueva política, la 
intervención militar evitada Estados Unidos y en lugar de otro 
ejerció presión sobre Bolivia reteniendo préstamos y asistencia 
técnica. El año siguiente, una guerra de palabras entró en 
erupción entre el gobierno de México y los Standard Oil Company del 
excedente de Nuevo-Jersey que poseyó las derechas de explotar una 
porción de las reservas del aceite de México. Después de que 
las compañías petroleras de ESTADOS UNIDOS rechazaran validar los 
términos del arbitraje de la tarjeta de trabajo mexicana, presidente 
mexicano Lzaro Crdenas expropriated características de la compañía 
petrolera digno de una mitad estimada de mil millones dólares. 
En los hechos verdaderos sobre la expropiación de las 
características de sociedades del aceite en México, el gobierno 
mexicano clarificó su posición al público americano y alineó la 
expropiación de la característica del aceite estándar.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086680</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108335</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/not-so-private-negotiations-mexico-expropriates-the-oil-companies</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
