<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105420</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105420</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213030</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Visualizations Useful for Teaching Tides</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sichtbarmachungen nützlich für das Unterrichten 
von von Gezeiten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Visualisations utiles pour enseigner des marées</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Visualizations úteis para ensinar marés</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Visualizzazioni utili per l'istruzione delle 
maree</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Απεικονίσεις χρήσιμες για τις παλίρροιες διδασκαλίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Visualizaciones útiles para enseñar mareas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site houses a collection of web-based visual resources suitable for teaching about tides. Visualizations include photos, simple animations, animated maps and field videos. Resources can be integrated into lectures, labs, classes, or other activities about tides, their distribution in space and time, their role in sedimentary processes, and their use as an energy source.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site bringt eine Ansammlung Web-gegründete 
Sichtbetriebsmittel unter, die für das Unterrichten über 
Gezeiten verwendbar sind. Sichtbarmachungen enthalten 
Fotos, einfache Animationen, lebhafte Karten und fangen 
videos auf. Betriebsmittel können in Vorträge, in Labors, in 
Kategorien oder in andere Aktivitäten über Gezeiten, in ihre 
Verteilung im Platz und in der Zeit, in ihre Rolle in den 
sedimentären Prozessen und in ihren Gebrauch als Energiequelle 
integriert werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site loge une collection de ressources 
visuelles Web-basées appropriées à l'enseignement au sujet des 
marées. Les visualisations incluent des photos, des animations 
simples, des cartes animées et des videos de zone. Des 
ressources peuvent être intégrées dans des conférences, des 
laboratoires, des classes, ou d'autres activités au sujet des 
marées, leur distribution dans l'espace et le temps, leur rôle dans 
des processus sédimentaires, et leur utilisation comme source 
d'énergie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local abriga uma coleção dos recursos 
visuais Web-baseados apropriados para ensinar sobre marés. Os 
visualizations incluem fotos, animations simples, mapas animated e 
videos do campo. Os recursos podem ser integrados em lectures, 
em laboratórios, em classes, ou em outras atividades sobre marés, em
sua distribuição no espaço e no tempo, em seu papel em processos 
sedimentary, e em seu uso como uma fonte de energia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo alloggia una collezione di risorse 
visive Web-basate adatte ad istruzione circa le maree. Le 
visualizzazioni includono le foto, le animazioni semplici, i programmi
animati ed i videos del campo. Le risorse possono essere 
integrate nelle conferenze, nei laboratori, nei codici categoria, o in
altre attività circa le maree, nella loro distribuzione dello spazio 
e del tempo, nel loro ruolo nei processi sedimentari e nel loro uso 
come sorgente di energia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή στεγάζει μια συλλογή των βασισμένων 
στο WEB οπτικών στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς κατάλληλων για για τις 
παλίρροιες. Οι απεικονίσεις περιλαμβάνουν τις φωτογραφίες, 
τις απλές ζωτικότητες, τους ζωντανεψονταυς χάρτες και τα βίντεο 
πεδίων. Τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς μπορούν να ενσωματωθούν 
στις διαλέξεις, τα εργαστήρια, τις κλάσεις, ή άλλες 
δραστηριότητες για τις παλίρροιες, τη διανομή τους στο διάστημα 
και το χρόνο, το ρόλο τους στις ιζηματώδεις διαδικασίες, και τη 
χρήση τους ως πηγή ενέργειας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio contiene una colección de recursos 
visuales Web-basados convenientes para enseñar sobre mareas. 
Las visualizaciones incluyen las fotos, las animaciones simples,
las correspondencias animadas y los videos del campo. Los 
recursos se pueden integrar en conferencias, laboratorios, clases, u 
otras actividades sobre mareas, su distribución en espacio y tiempo, 
su papel en procesos sedimentarios, y su uso como fuente de energía.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213030</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105420</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/visualizations-useful-for-teaching-tides</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
