<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107343</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107343</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087269</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">100,000,000 Guinea Pigs : The Dangers of Consumption</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">100.000.000 Guine-Schweine: Die Gefahren des 
Verbrauchs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">100.000.000 Cobayes : Les dangers de la 
consommation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">100.000.000 Porcos Do Guinea: Os perigos do 
consumo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">100.000.000 Cavie: I pericoli di consumo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">100,000,000 Ινδικά χοιρίδια: Οι κίνδυνοι της 
κατανάλωσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">100.000.000 Cerdos De Guinea: Los peligros de
la consumición</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1927, responding to the seemingly overpowering claims of advertisers and mass marketers, engineer Frederick Schlink and economist Stuart Chase published  Your Money's Worth , which argued for an "extension of the principle of buying goods according to impartial scientific tests rather than according to the fanfare and triumphs of higher salesmanship."  Your Money's Worth  became an instant best-seller, and the authors organized Consumers' Research, a testing bureau that provided information and published product tests in a new magazine,  Consumers' Research Bulletin . The 1929 stock market crash heightened suspicion of consumer capitalism, and the magazine had 42,000 subscribers by 1932. In 1933, Schlink and Arthur Kallet (executive secretary of Consumers' Research) published  100,000,000 Guinea Pigs: Dangers in Everyday Foods, Drugs, and Cosmetics . The book struck a responsive chord in depression-era America--it went through thirteen printings in its first six months and became one of the best-selling books of the decade. The book's first chapter ("The Great American Guinea Pig"), gave a flavor of their vigorous arguments.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1927 reagierend auf die scheinbar überwältigenden
Ansprüche der Inserenten und der Masse Marketingspezialisten, 
veröffentlichten Ingenieur Frederick Schlink und 
Wirtschaftswissenschaftler Stuart Verfolgung Wert Ihres Geldes, der 
argumentierte für eine "Extension der Grundregel der kaufenden Waren 
entsprechend unparteiischen wissenschaftlichen Tests anstatt 
entsprechend der Fanfare und den Triumphen des höheren salesmanship."
Ihres Geldes wert wurde ein sofortiger Bestseller, und die 
Autoren organisierten Verbraucherforschung, ein prüfenbüro, das 
Informationen lieferte und Produkttests in einer neuen Zeitschrift 
veröffentlichte, Verbraucherforschung-Nachricht. Das erhöhte 
Misstrauen 1929 der Börse Systemabsturz von 
Verbraucherkapitalismus und die Zeitschrift hatten 42.000 Teilnehmer 
bis zum 1932. 1933 veröffentlichten Schlink und Arthur Kallet 
(Geschäftsführer der Verbraucherforschung) 100.000.000 
Meerschweinchen: Gefahren in den täglichen Nahrungsmitteln, in 
den Drogen und in den Kosmetik. Das Buch schlug einen 
entgegenkommenden Akkord in der Tiefstand-Ära Amerika an -- es lief 
dreizehn printings in seinen ersten sechs Monaten durch und wurde eins
der gut-verkaufenden Bücher der Dekade. Das erste Kapitel des 
Buches ("das große amerikanische Guine-Schwein"), gab ein Aroma ihrer
kräftigen Argumente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1927, répondant aux réclamations maîtrisantes
apparemment des annonceurs et des acheteurs de la masse, 
l'ingénieur Frederick Schlink et la chasse Stuart d'économiste ont 
édité la valeur de votre argent, qui a plaidé pour une "extension 
du principe des marchandises achetantes selon les essais scientifiques
impartiaux plutôt que selon la fanfare et les triomphes d'un plus 
haut salesmanship." Votre argent en valeur est devenu un 
best-seller instantané, et les auteurs ont organisé la étude de 
marché, un bureau de test qui a fourni des informations et a édité 
des essais de produit dans un nouveau magasin, bulletin de la étude 
de marché. Le soupçon 1929 intensifié par panne totale de 
marché boursier du capitalisme du consommateur, et le magasin ont eu 42.000
abonnés d'ici 1932. En 1933, Schlink et Arthur Kallet 
(secrétaire de direction de la étude de marché) ont édité 
100.000.000 cobayes : Dangers en nourritures, drogues, et 
produits de beauté journaliers. Le livre a heurté une corde 
sensible dans la dépression-ère Amérique -- il est passé par 
treize printings en ses six premiers mois et est devenu l'un des 
livres devente de la décennie. Le premier chapitre du livre 
("le grand cobaye américain"), a donné une saveur de leurs arguments
vigoureux.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1927, respondendo às reivindicações seemingly
overpowering dos publicitários e dos comerciantes da massa, o 
coordenador Frederick Schlink e a perseguição de Stuart do 
economista publicaram o valor do seu dinheiro, que discutiu para uma 
"extensão do princípio de bens de compra de acordo com testes 
científicos imparciais melhor que de acordo com o fanfare e os 
triunfos de um salesmanship mais elevado." Seu dinheiro worth 
transformou-se um bestseller imediato, e os autores organizaram a 
pesquisa de consumidores, um departamento testando que fornecesse a 
informação e publicasse testes do produto em um compartimento novo, 
boletim da pesquisa de consumidores. A suspeita heightened do 
ruído elétrico de mercado 1929 conservado em estoque do capitalismo 
do consumidor, e o compartimento teve 42.000 subscritores por 1932. 
Em 1933, Schlink e Arthur Kallet (secretária executiva da 
pesquisa de consumidores) publicaram 100.000.000 porcos do guinea: 
Perigos em alimentos, em drogas, e em cosméticos diários. 
O livro golpeou uma corda responsiva na depression-era América 
-- atravessou treze printings em seus primeiros seis meses e 
transformou-se um dos livros melhor-vendendo da década. O 
primeiro capítulo do livro ("o porco americano grande do guinea"), 
deu um sabor de seus argumentos vigorosos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1927, rispondendo ai reclami apparentemente 
overpowering dei advertisers e dei marketers della massa, l'assistente
tecnico Frederick Schlink e l'inseguimento dello Stuart 
dell'economista hanno pubblicato il valore dei vostri soldi, che ha 
parlato a favore "di un'estensione del principio delle merci 
d'acquisto secondo le prove scientifiche imparziali piuttosto che 
secondo il fanfare ed i trionfi di più alto salesmanship." I 
vostri soldi degno si sono transformati in in un best-seller istante e
gli autori hanno organizzato la ricerca dei consumatori, un ufficio 
difficile che ha fornito le informazioni ed ha pubblicato le prove del
prodotto in un nuovo scomparto, bollettino di ricerca dei consumatori.
L'arresto di mercato azionario 1929 ha intensificato il sospetto
del capitalismo del consumatore e lo scomparto ha avuto 42.000 
abbonati entro 1932. In 1933, Schlink ed Arthur Kallet 
(segretaria esecutiva di ricerca dei consumatori) hanno pubblicato 
100.000.000 cavie: Pericoli in alimenti, droghe ed estetiche 
giornalieri. Il libro ha colpito una corda sensible a reagire 
nell'depressione-era America -- ha passato con tredici printings nei 
relativi primi sei mesi e si è transformato in in uno dei libri 
migliore-vendenti della decade. Il primo capitolo del libro ("la
cavia americana grande"), ha dato un sapore dei loro argomenti 
vigorosi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1927, η απάντηση στις φαινομενικά 
εξουδετερώνοντας αξιώσεις των δηαφημιστών και των μαζικών 
εμπόρων, του μηχανικού Frederick Schlink και stuart 
οικονομολόγων του αυλακώματος δημοσίευσε των χρημάτων σας αξίας, 
τα οποία υποστήριξαν μια "επέκταση της αρχής τα αγαθά σύμφωνα με
τις αμερόληπτες επιστημονικές δοκιμές παρά σύμφωνα με τη 
φιλαρμονική και τους θριάμβους του υψηλότερου salesmanship." 
Τα χρήματά σας αξίας έγιναν ένα στιγμιαίο 
best-$l*seller, και οι συντάκτες οργάνωσαν την καταναλωτική 
έρευνα, ένα εξεταστικό γραφείο που παρείχε τις πληροφορίες και 
δημοσίευσε τις δοκιμές προϊόντων σε ένα νέο περιοδικό, δελτίο 
καταναλωτικής έρευνας. Η συντριβή χρηματιστηρίου του 1929
ύψωσε την υποψία της καταναλωτικής κεφαλαιοκρατίας, και το 
περιοδικό είχε 42.000 συνδρομητές μέχρι το 1932. Το 
1933, Schlink και αρθούρος Kallet (εκτελεστικός γραμματέας
της καταναλωτικής έρευνας) δημοσίευσαν 100.000.000 ινδικά 
χοιρίδια: Κίνδυνοι στα καθημερινά τρόφιμα, τα φάρμακα, και 
τα καλλυντικά. Το βιβλίο χτύπησε μια απαντητική χορδή στην 
κατάθλιψη-εποχή Αμερική -- επέρασε από δέκα τρεις εκτυπώσεις σε
πρώτους έξι μήνες του και έγινε ένα από τα με εμπορική 
επιτυχία βιβλία της δεκαετίας. Το πρώτο κεφάλαιο του 
βιβλίου ("το μεγάλο αμερικανικό ινδικό χοιρίδιο"), έδωσε μια 
γεύση των σφριγηλών ορισμάτων τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1927, respondiendo a las demandas aparentemente 
que dominaban de publicistas y de vendedores de la masa, el ingeniero 
Frederick Schlink y la persecución de Estuardo del economista 
publicaron el valor de su dinero, que discutió para una "extensión 
del principio de mercancías que compraban según pruebas científicas
imparciales más bien que según la fanfarria y los triunfos de un 
salesmanship más alto." Su dinero digno de se convirtió en un 
bestseller inmediato, y los autores ordenaron la investigación de 
consumidores, una oficina de prueba que proporcionó a la información
y publicó pruebas del producto en un compartimiento nuevo, boletín 
de la investigación de consumidores. La suspicacia aumentada 
caída 1929 de la bolsa del capitalismo del consumidor, y el 
compartimiento tenían 42.000 suscriptores antes de 1932. En 
1933, Schlink y Arturo Kallet (secretaria ejecutiva de la 
investigación de consumidores) publicaron 100.000.000 cerdos de 
Guinea: Peligros en alimentos, drogas, y cosméticos diarios. 
El libro pulso un acorde responsivo en la depresio'n-era 
América -- pasó con trece printings en sus primeros seis meses y se 
convirtió en uno de los libros mejor-vendedores de la década. 
El primer capítulo del libro ("el gran cerdo americano de 
Guinea"), dio un sabor de sus argumentos vigorosos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087269</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107343</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/100-000-000-guinea-pigs-the-dangers-of-consumption</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
