<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106728</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106728</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212660</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Mysterious Life of Caves</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die geheimnisvolle Lebensdauer der Höhlen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La vie mystérieuse des cavernes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A vida misteriosa das cavernas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La durata mysterious delle caverne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η μυστήρια ζωή των σπηλιών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La vida misteriosa de cuevas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This is a companion website to a NOVA television series investigating strange life-forms found in toxic caverns. The program reviews the traditional theory of cave formation; introduces new theories of microbial sulfuric acid production; examines the role of oil-feeding microbes in dissolving limestone; presents the discovery of microbes in caves that live solely on chemical nutrients; and reviews other extreme environments. The site offers an interview with a microbiologist, an essay by a caver, a slide show of decorated caves, a teacher's guide including the classroom activity entitled "Microbial Townhouse," and interactive animation about cave formation. The video of the program may be ordered from PBS (Public Broadcasting Service), but is not necessary to complete the activites.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses ist eine Begleiterweb site zu einer 
NOVA-Fernsehenserie, welche die merkwürdigen Lebensdauer-Formulare 
nachforscht, die in den giftigen Höhlen gefunden werden. Das 
Programm wiederholt die traditionelle Theorie der Höhleanordnung; 
stellt neue Theorien der durch Mikrobenschwefelsäureproduktion 
vor; überprüft die Rolle der Öl-einziehenden Mikroben in 
auflösendem Kalkstein; stellt die Entdeckung der Mikroben in 
den Höhlen dar, die nur auf chemischen Nährstoffen leben; und 
Zusammenfassungen andere extreme Umgebungen. Die Site bietet ein
Interview mit einem Biologen, einen Versuch durch ein caver, eine 
Diavorführung der verzierten Höhlen, die Anleitung eines Lehrers 
einschließlich die Klassenzimmeraktivität an, die 
"Mikrobenstadtwohnung," erlaubt wird und interaktive Animation über 
Höhleanordnung. Der Bildschirm des Programms kann von PBS 
(allgemeiner Sendedienst) bestellt werden, aber ist nicht notwendig, 
um die activites durchzuführen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">C'est un site Web de compagnon à une série de 
télévision de NOVA étudiant les vie-formes étranges trouvées dans
les cavernes toxiques. Le programme passe en revue la théorie 
traditionnelle de formation de caverne ; présente de nouvelles 
théories de production acide sulfurique microbienne ; examine 
le rôle des microbes d'huile-alimentation en pierre à chaux de 
dissolution ; présente la découverte des microbes en cavernes 
qui vivent seulement sur les aliments chimiques ; et revues 
d'autres environnements extrêmes. Le site offre une entrevue 
avec un microbiologiste, un essai par un caver, une projection de 
diapositives des cavernes décorées, le guide d'un professeur 
comprenant l'activité de salle de classe intitulée "maison urbaine 
microbienne," et l'animation interactive au sujet de la formation de 
caverne. Le vidéo du programme peut être commandé de PBS 
(service de radiodiffusion public), mais n'est pas nécessaire pour 
terminer les activites.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este é um Web site do companheiro a uma série da
televisão do NOVA que investiga os vida-formulários estranhos 
encontrados em cavernas tóxicas. O programa revê a teoria 
tradicional da formação da caverna; introduz teorias novas da 
produção ácida sulfúrica microbial; examina o papel de 
micróbios dealimentação na pedra calcária dissolvendo-se; 
apresenta a descoberta dos micróbios nas cavernas que vivem 
unicamente em nutrientes químicos; e revisões outros ambientes
extremos. O local oferece uma entrevista com um microbiologist, 
um essay por um caver, uma mostra de corrediça de cavernas decoradas,
a guia de um professor including a atividade da sala de aula 
intitulada "townhouse microbial," e o animation interativo sobre a 
formação da caverna. O vídeo do programa pode ser requisitado
de PBS (serviço de transmissão público), mas não é necessário 
para terminar os activites.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ciò è un Web site del compagno ad una serie 
della televisione del NOVA che studia le vita-forme sconosciute 
trovate in spelonche tossiche. Il programma rivede la teoria 
tradizionale di formazione della caverna; introduce le nuove 
teorie di produzione acida solforica microbica; esamina il ruolo
dei microbi d'alimentazione in calcare di dissoluzione; presenta
la scoperta dei microbi in caverne che vivono solamente sulle sostanze
nutrienti chimiche; e rassegne altri ambienti estremi. Il 
luogo offre un'intervista con un microbiologo, un saggio da un caver, 
una proiezione di diapositive delle caverne decorate, la guida 
dell'insegnante compreso l'attività dell'aula intitolata "casa urbana
microbica," e la animazione interattiva circa formazione della 
caverna. Il video del programma può essere ordinato da PBS 
(servizio di broadcasting pubblico), ma non è necessario da 
completare i activites.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό είναι ένας ιστοχώρος συντρόφων σε μια 
τηλεοπτική σειρά NOVA ερευνώντας τις παράξενες ζωή-μορφές που
βρίσκονται στα τοξικά σπήλαια. Το πρόγραμμα αναθεωρεί την 
παραδοσιακή θεωρία του σχηματισμού σπηλιών  εισάγει τις 
νέες θεωρίες της μικροβιακής θειικής όξινης παραγωγής  
εξετάζει το ρόλο της λάδι-σίτισης των μικροβίων στη 
διάλυση του ασβεστόλιθου  παρουσιάζει την ανακάλυψη των 
μικροβίων στις σπηλιές που ζουν απλώς στις χημικές θρεπτικές 
ουσίες  και αναθεωρήσεις άλλα ακραία περιβάλλοντα. Η 
περιοχή προσφέρει μια συνέντευξη με έναν μικροβιολόγο, ένα 
δοκίμιο από ένα caver, μια επίδειξη φωτογραφικών διαφανειών 
των διακοσμημένων σπηλιών, τον οδηγό ενός δασκάλου 
συμπεριλαμβανομένης της δραστηριότητας τάξεων που τιτλοφορείται 
"μικροβιακό townhouse," και τη διαλογική ζωτικότητα για το 
σχηματισμό σπηλιών. Το βίντεο του προγράμματος μπορεί να 
διαταχτεί από PBS (δημόσια υπηρεσία ραδιοφωνικων 
αναμεταδόσεων), αλλά δεν είναι απαραίτητο για να ολοκληρώσει τα 
activites.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esto es un Web site del compañero a una serie de 
la televisión de la NOVA que investiga las vida-formas extrañas 
encontradas en cavernas tóxicas. El programa repasa la teoría 
tradicional de la formación de la cueva; introduce nuevas 
teorías de la producción de ácido sulfúrico microbiana; 
examina el papel de microbios de aceite-alimentacio'n en piedra 
caliza que disuelve; presenta el descubrimiento de microbios en 
las cuevas que viven solamente en los alimentos químicos; y 
revisiones otros ambientes extremos. El sitio ofrece una 
entrevista con un microbiólogo, un ensayo por un caver, una 
demostración de diapositiva de cuevas adornadas, la guía de un 
profesor incluyendo la actividad de la sala de clase dada derecho 
"casa urbana microbiana," y la animación interactiva sobre la 
formación de la cueva. El vídeo del programa se puede pedir de
PBS (servicio de difusión público), pero no es necesario terminar 
los activites.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:NOVA SCIENCE PROGRAMMING ON AIR AND ONLINE
FN:NOVA SCIENCE PROGRAMMING ON AIR AND ONLINE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PUBLIC BROADCASTING SERVICE (PBS) AND WGBH
FN:PUBLIC BROADCASTING SERVICE (PBS) AND WGBH
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212660</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106728</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-mysterious-life-of-caves</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
