<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108334</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108334</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1037366503</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Northwest Homesteader: A Curriculum Project for Washington Schools</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nordwesthomesteader: Ein Lehrplan-Projekt 
für Washington Schulen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Propriétaire du nord-ouest : Un projet de 
programme d'études pour des écoles de Washington</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Homesteader Noroeste: Um projeto do 
curriculum para escolas de Washington</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Homesteader Di nord-ovest: Un progetto di 
programma di studi per le scuole de Washington</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βορειοδυτικός homesteader: Ένα πρόγραμμα 
προγράμματος σπουδών για τα σχολεία της Ουάσιγκτον</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Homesteader Del noroeste: Un proyecto del 
plan de estudios para las escuelas de Washington</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This packet provides materials that relate to the history of homesteading in Washington state. In many respects homesteading was a national story, born of an era when the United States was both agrarian and expansionist. The major themes of this packet invite teachers and students to think about how regional, state, and local history fit within the broader American context.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Paket liefert Materialien, die auf der 
Geschichte von Homesteading im Staat Washington in Verbindung stehen. 
In vielerlei Hinsicht war das Homesteading eine nationale 
Geschichte, getragen von einer Ära, als die Vereinigten Staaten 
landwirtschaftlich und expansionist waren. Die Hauptthemen 
dieses Pakets laden Lehrer und Kursteilnehmer ein, zu denken an, wie 
regional, Zustand und die lokale Geschichte, die innerhalb des 
ausgedehnteren amerikanischen Kontextes gepaßt wird.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce paquet fournit les matériaux qui associent à 
l'histoire de homesteading dans l'état de Washington. À bien 
des égards homesteading était une histoire nationale, soutenue d'une
ère où les Etats-Unis étaient agraires et expansionnistes. 
Les thèmes principaux de ce paquet invitent des professeurs et 
des étudiants à penser à la façon dont régionaux, état, et 
histoire locale entrée dans le contexte américain plus large.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este pacote fornece os materiais que se relacionam 
ao history de homesteading no estado de Washington. Em muitos 
respeitos homesteading era uma história nacional, carregada de uma 
era em que os estados unidos fossem  agrarian e expansionist. Os
temas principais deste pacote convidam professores e estudantes pensar
sobre como regionais, estado, e history local cabido dentro do 
contexto americano mais largo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo pacchetto fornisce i materiali che si 
riferiscono alla storia di homesteading a Washington dichiarano. 
Per molti aspetti homesteading era una storia nazionale, 
sopportata di un'era in cui unito Dichiara era sia agrario che 
expansionist. I temi principali di questo pacchetto invitano gli
insegnanti ed allievi a pensare a quanto regionale, dichiari e
storia locale entrata nel più vasto contesto americano.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το πακέτο παρέχει τα υλικά που αφορούν την 
ιστορία στο κράτος της Ουάσιγκτον. Από πολλές απόψεις 
ήταν μια εθνική ιστορία, γεννημένος μιας εποχής όταν οι 
Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες ήταν και αγροτικές και επεκτατικές. Τα 
σημαντικότερα θέματα αυτού του πακέτου προσκαλούν τους δασκάλους
και τους σπουδαστές για να σκεφτούν για το πώς περιφερειακά, το 
κράτος, και την τοπική ιστορία κατάλληλη μέσα στο ευρύτερο 
αμερικανικό πλαίσιο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este paquete proporciona a los materiales que se 
relacionan con la historia de homesteading en el estado de Washington.
En muchos respectos el homesteading era una historia nacional, 
llevada de una era en que los Estados Unidos eran agrarios y 
expansionistas. Los temas principales de este paquete invitan a 
profesores y los estudiantes que piensen de cómo son regionales, 
estado, e historia local cabida dentro del contexto americano más 
amplio.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1037366503</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108334</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/northwest-homesteader-a-curriculum-project-for-washington-schools</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
