<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107667</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107667</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087092</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"There Is Something To Be Learned Even in a Country Store": P.T. Barnum Learns Commerce in a Connecticut Country Store</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"es gibt etwas, sogar in einem Gemischtwarenladen 
erlernt zu werden": P.T. Barnum Learns Handel in einem 
Connecticut Gemischtwarenladen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"il y a quelque chose être apprise même dans une
mémoire de pays" : Commerce de P.T. Barnum Learns dans une 
mémoire de pays du Connecticut</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"há algo ser aprendido mesmo em uma loja de 
país": Comércio de P.T. Barnum Aprendizagem em uma loja de 
país de Connecticut</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"ci è qualcosa essere imparato anche in un 
deposito di paese": Commercio del P.T. Barnum Learns in un 
deposito di paese del Connecticut</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Υπάρχει κάτι που μαθαίνεται ακόμη και σε ένα 
κατάστημα χώρασ": P.T. Barnum μαθαίνει το εμπόριο σε 
ένα κατάστημα χώρας του Κοννέκτικατ</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"hay algo ser aprendido incluso en un almacén de 
país": Comercio de P.T. Barnum Learns en un almacén de país 
de Connecticut</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The country store was an important crossroads in nineteenth-century rural communities. In the decades after the War for Independence, commercial activity increased in the hinterlands as rural residents brought their farm produce to local storekeepers to exchange for commodities (such as rum) that were not produced locally. With cash scarce, much of the trade was conducted by barter and recorded in the merchant's account books or "daybooks," and traveling peddlers extended market activity beyond the reach of village stores. It was in this commercializing environment that Phineas Taylor Barnum honed his entrepreneurial skills. Barnum, born in Bethel, Connecticut, in 1810, eventually took his skills to New York City where he achieved fame as a cultural impresario and museum owner. He wrote several autobiographies that became key documents in the substantial nineteenth-century advice literature on how to achieve fame and fortune; this excerpt is drawn from  The Life of P.T. Barnum, Written By Himself  (1855) where he described his early days in greatest detail.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Gemischtwarenladen war eine wichtige 
Querstraße 19.-Jahrhundert in den landwirtschaftlichen 
Gemeinschaften. der Dekaden nach dem Krieg für 
Unabhängigkeit, erhöhte sich kommerzielle Aktivität des 
Hinterlands, während landwirtschaftliche Bewohner den lokalen 
Storekeepers ihr Bauernhoferzeugnis zum Austausch für Gebrauchsgüter
holten (wie Rum) die nicht lokal produziert wurden. Mit dem 
knappen Bargeld, wurde viel des Handels durch Kompensationsgeschäft 
geleitet und gespeichert in in den Geschäftsbücher oder "den 
daybooks des Kaufmannes," und in reisenden Hausierern dehnte 
Marktaktivität über der Reichweite der Dorfspeicher hinaus aus. 
Es war in dieser in den Handel bringenumgebung, daß Phineas 
Schneider Barnum seine unternehmerischen Fähigkeiten abzog. 
Barnum, getragen in der Kirche, Connecticut, 1810, nahm 
schließlich seine Fähigkeiten nach New York City, in dem er Ruhm als
kultureller Impresario und Museum Inhaber erzielte. Er schrieb 
einige Autobiographien, die Schlüsseldokumente in der erheblichen 
19.-Jahrhundert Rateliteratur wurden auf, wie man Ruhm und Vermögen 
erzielt; dieses Excerpt wird vom Leben von P.T. Barnum 
gezeichnet, allein geschrieben (1855) wo er seine frühen Tage 
ausführlich größtes beschrieb.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La mémoire de pays était un carrefour important 
dans les communautés rurales de dix-neuvième-siècle. Dans les
décennies après la guerre pour l'indépendance, l'activité 
commerciale a augmenté dans les hinterlands pendant que les 
résidants ruraux apportaient leur produit de ferme aux magasiniers 
locaux à l'échange pour les produits (tels que le rhum) qui n'ont 
pas été produits localement. Avec l'argent comptant rare, une 
grande partie des échanges a été effectué par échange et 
enregistré dans les livres de comptes ou les "daybooks du 
négociant," et les marchands ambulants de déplacement a étendu 
l'activité du marché au delà de l'extension des mémoires de 
village. C'était dans cet environnement de commercialisation 
que le tailleur Barnum de Phineas a rectifié ses qualifications 
entreprenantes. Barnum, soutenu dans le lieu de prière, le 
Connecticut, en 1810, a par la suite pris ses qualifications à New 
York City où il a réalisé la renommée en tant qu'un imprésario et
propriétaire culturels de musée. Il a écrit plusieurs 
autobiographies qui sont devenues les documents principaux dans la 
littérature substantielle de conseil de dix-neuvième-siècle sur 
la façon dont réaliser la renommée et la fortune ; cet 
extrait est tiré de la vie de P.T. Barnum, écrite tout seul (1855) 
où il a décrit ses jours tôt dans le plus grand détail.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A loja de país era um crossroads importante em 
comunidades rurais de décimo-século. Nas décadas após a 
guerra para a independência, a atividade comercial aumentou nos 
hinterlands enquanto os residentes rurais trouxeram seu produto da 
fazenda aos storekeepers locais à troca para os productos (tais como 
o rum) que não foram produzidos localmente. Com o dinheiro 
escasso, muito do comércio foi conduzido pelo barter e gravado nos 
livros ou nos "daybooks de cliente do comerciante," e em peddlers 
viajando estendeu a atividade do mercado além do alcance de lojas da 
vila. Era neste ambiente commercializing que o alfaiate Barnum 
de Phineas afiou suas habilidades entrepreneurial. Barnum, 
carregado no bethel, Connecticut, dentro 1810, fêz exame 
eventualmente de suas habilidades a New York City onde conseguiu a 
fama como um impresario e um proprietário cultural do museu. 
Escreveu diversos autobiographies que se transformaram originais
chaves na literatura substancial do conselho de décimo-século em 
como conseguir a fama e a fortuna; este excerpt é desenhado da 
vida de P.T. Barnum, escrita por himself (1855) onde descreveu seus 
dias adiantados no detalhe o mais grande.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il deposito di paese era una strada trasversale 
importante nelle Comunità rurali di diciannovesimo-secolo. di 
decadi dopo la guerra per indipendenza, l'attività commerciale è 
aumentato di retroterre mentre i residenti rurali hanno portato i loro
prodotti dell'azienda agricola agli storekeepers locali allo scambio 
per i prodotti (quale rum) che non sono stati prodotti localmente. 
Con contanti limitati, gran parte di è stato eseguito dal 
baratto e registrato nei libri contabili o "nei daybooks del 
commerciante," ed in peddlers mobili ha esteso l'attività del mercato
oltre l'estensione dei depositi del villaggio. Era in questo 
ambiente di commercializzazione che il sarto Barnum di Phineas 
smerigliatrice le sue abilità imprenditoriali. Barnum, 
sopportato in bethel, Connecticut, dentro 1810, finalmente ha preso le
sue abilità a New York City in cui ha realizzato la fama come un 
impresario e proprietario culturali del museo. Ha scritto 
parecchi autobiographies che si sono transformati in in documenti 
chiave nella letteratura notevole di consiglio di 
diciannovesimo-secolo su come realizzare la fama e la fortuna; 
questo brano è dissipato dalla vita di P.T. Barnum, scritta da 
sè (1855) dove ha descritto i suoi giorni in anticipo in dettaglio 
più grande.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το κατάστημα χωρών ήταν σημαντικά σταυροδρόμια στις 
αγροτικές κοινότητες δέκατος-αιώνα. Στις δεκαετίες μετά 
από τον πόλεμο για την ανεξαρτησία, η εμπορική δραστηριότητα 
αυξήθηκε στις ενδοχώρες καθώς οι αγροτικοί κάτοικοι έφεραν τα 
αγροτικά προϊόντα τους στους τοπικούς αποθηκαρίους για να 
ανταλλάξουν για τα προϊόντα (όπως το ρούμι) που δεν παρήχθησαν 
τοπικά. Με τα μετρητά λιγοστά, ένα μεγάλο μέρος του 
εμπορίου διευθύνθηκε από την ανταλλαγή και καταγράφηκε στα 
βιβλία απολογισμού του εμπόρου ή "daybooks," και τη 
διακινούμενη εκτεταμένη γυρολόγοι δραστηριότητα αγοράς πέρα από
την προσιτότητα των του χωριού καταστημάτων. Ήταν σε αυτό 
το εμπορευματοποιώντας περιβάλλον ότι Phineas taylor 
Barnum ηκόνισε τις επιχειρηματικές δεξιότητές του. Το 
Barnum, γεννημένο σε Bethel, Κοννέκτικατ, το 1810, πήρε 
τελικά τις δεξιότητές του στην πόλη της Νέας Υόρκης όπου 
επέτυχε τη φήμη ως πολιτιστικό ιδιοκτήτη impresario και 
μουσείων. Έγραψε διάφορες αυτοβιογραφίες που έγιναν βασικά
έγγραφα στην ουσιαστική βιβλιογραφία συμβουλών δέκατος-αιώνα στο
πώς να επιτύχουν τη φήμη και την τύχη  αυτό το απόσπασμα 
προέρχεται από τη ζωή P.T. Barnum, γραπτή μόνος του 
(1855) όπου περιέγραψε των στις αρχές ημερών του με μέγιστες 
λεπτομέρειες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El almacén de país era una encrucijada 
importante en comunidades rurales del diecinueveavo-siglo. De 
las décadas después de la guerra para la independencia, la actividad
comercial aumentó de los Hinterland mientras que los residentes 
rurales trajeron su producto de la granja a los tenderos locales al 
intercambio para las materias (tales como ron) que no fueron 
producidas localmente. Con el efectivo escaso, mucho del 
comercio fue conducido por trueque y registrado en los libros de 
cuentas o los "daybooks del comerciante," y los vendedores ambulantes 
que viajaban amplió actividad del mercado más allá del alcance de 
los almacenes de la aldea. Era en este ambiente de 
comercialización que la personalización Barnum de Phineas afiló con
piedra sus habilidades emprendedoras. Barnum, llevado en el 
bethel, Connecticut, adentro 1810, llevó eventual sus habilidades New
York City en donde él alcanzó fama como un empresario y 
propietario culturales del museo. Él escribió varias 
autobiografías que se convirtieron en documentos dominantes en la 
literatura substancial del consejo del diecinueveavo-siglo en cómo 
alcanzar fama y fortuna; este extracto se traza a partir 
de la vida de P.T. Barnum, escrita por se (1855) donde él describió 
sus días tempranos en el detalle más grande.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087092</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107667</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/there-is-something-to-be-learned-even-in-a-country-store-p-t-barnum-learns-commerce-in-a-connecticut-country-store</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
