<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106201</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106201</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086657</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"National Suicide": Margaret Chase Smith and Six Republican Senators Speak Out Against Joseph McCarthy's Attack on "Individual Freedom"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Nationaler Selbstmord": Margaret Verfolgung
Smith und sechs republikanisches Angriff der Senator-Speak Out Against
Joseph McCarthys auf "einzelner Freiheit"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Suicide National" : Chasse Smith et six 
attaque des sénateurs Speak Out Against Joseph McCarthy républicains
de Margaret sur "la liberté individuelle"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Suicide Nacional": Perseguição Smith e 
seis ataque dos senators Discurso Para fora De encontro Joseph 
McCarthy republicanos de Margaret "na liberdade individual"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Suicide Nazionale": Inseguimento Smith e 
sei attacco Repubblicano dei senatori Speak Out Against Joseph McCarthy
di Margaret "a libertà individuale"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Εθνική αυτοκτονία": Θ*Μαργαρετ Chase Smith 
και έξι δημοκρατικοί γερουσιαστές μιλούν έξω ενάντια σε 
Joseph McCarthy's Attack στη "μεμονωμένη ελευθερία"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Suicidio Nacional": Persecución Smith y 
seis ataque de senadores Speak Out Against José McCarthy republicanos
de Margaret contra la "libertad individual"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The anticommunist crusader Senator Joseph McCarthy stepped into national prominence on February 9, 1950, when he mounted an attack on President Truman's foreign policy agenda. McCarthy charged that the State Department and its Secretary, Dean Acheson, harbored "traitorous" Communists. McCarthy's apocalyptic rhetoric--he portrayed the Cold War conflict as "a final, all-out battle between communistic atheism and Christianity"--made critics hesitate before challenging him. His purported lists of Communist conspirators multiplied in subsequent years to include employees in government agencies, the broadcasting and defense industries, universities, the United Nations, and the military. Most of those accused were helpless to defend their ruined reputations and faced loss of employment, damaged careers, and in many cases, broken lives. In protest, Republican Senator Margaret Chase Smith composed the following "Declaration of Conscience," condemning the atmosphere of suspicion and blaming leaders of both parties for their "lack of effective leadership." Although Smith convinced six additional Republican Senators to join her in the Declaration, the seven refused to support a Senate report prepared by Democrats that called McCarthy's charges against State Department personnel fraudulent.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der anticommunist Kreuzfahrer Senator Joseph 
McCarthy trat in nationalen Vorsprung an Februar 9, 1950, als er einen
Angriff auf Präsident Trumans Tagesordnung der fremden Politik 
einhing. McCarthy lud auf, daß die Zustand-Abteilung und seine 
Sekretärin, Dekan Acheson, "traitorous" Kommunisten beherbargen. 
McCarthys apokalyptische Rhetorik -- er schilderte die 
$überschneidung des kalten Krieges als "abschließende, all-out 
Schlacht zwischen communistic Atheismus und Christentum" -- 
gebildete Kritiker zögern vor schwierigem er. Seins behauptete 
Listen der kommunistischen Verschwörer, die in den folgenden Jahren 
multipliziert wurden, um Angestellte in den Regierungsagenturen zu 
enthalten, die Sendung und Verteidigungindustrien, Universitäten, die
Nationen und das Militär. Die meisten denen, die beschuldigt 
wurden, waren hilflos, ihre ruinierten Renommees zu verteidigen und 
stellten Verlust der Beschäftigung gegenüber, beschädigten die 
Karrieren und in vielen Fällen, gebrochen Leben. Im Protest 
bestand republikanischer Senator Margaret Chase Smith die folgende 
"Erklärung aus Gewissenhaftigkeit,", die Atmosphäre des Misstrauens 
verurteilend und Führer beider Parteien für ihren "Mangel an 
wirkungsvoller Führung tadelnd." Obgleich Smith sechs 
zusätzliche republikanische Senatoren überzeugte, sie in der 
Erklärung zu verbinden, lehnten die sieben ab, einen Senatreport zu 
unterstützen, der von Democrats vorbereitet wurde, der Ladungen 
McCarthys gegen Zustand-Abteilung Personal betrügerisch nannte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le sénateur Joseph McCarthy de croisé 
d'anticommunist a fait un pas dans la proéminence nationale février 
9, 1950, quand il a monté une attaque à l'ordre du jour de politique
étrangère du Président Truman's. McCarthy a chargé que le 
service d'état et son secrétaire, doyen Acheson, ont hébergé les 
communistes "déloyaux". La rhétorique apocalyptique de 
McCarthy -- il a dépeint le conflit de guerre froide comme "bataille 
entre l'athéisme communisant et christianisme finals et globaux" -- 
les critiques faits hésitent avant provocant il. Sien a 
prétendu des listes de conspirateurs communistes multipliés en 
années ultérieures pour inclure des employés aux organismes 
gouvernementaux, les industries de radiodiffusion et de défense, des 
universités, les Nations Unies, et les militaires. Les la 
plupart de ceux accusées étaient délaissées pour défendre leurs 
réputations ruinées et ont fait face à la perte d'emploi, ont 
endommagé des carrières, et dans beaucoup de cas, cassées les vies.
Dans la protestation, la chasse républicaine Smith de sénateur
Margaret a composé la "déclaration suivante de conscience," 
condamnant l'atmosphère du soupçon et blâmant des amorces des deux 
parties par leur "manque de conduite pertinente." Bien que Smith
ait convaincu six sénateurs républicains supplémentaires de la 
joindre dans la déclaration, les sept ont refusé de supporter un 
état de sénat préparé par Democrats qui a appelé les frais de 
McCarthy's contre le personnel de service d'état frauduleux.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O senator Joseph McCarthy do cruzado do 
anticommunist pisou no prominence nacional fevereiro em 9, 1950, 
quando montou um ataque na agenda da política extrangeira do 
presidente Truman. McCarthy carregou que o departamento do 
estado e sua secretária, decano Acheson, abrigaram comunistas 
"traitorous". O rhetoric apocalyptic de McCarthy -- portrayed o 
conflito da guerra fria como "uma batalha entre o atheism communistic 
e um christianity finais, all-out" -- críticos feitos hesitate antes 
de challenging ele. His purported listas dos conspirators 
comunistas multiplicados em anos subseqüentes para incluir empregados
em agências de governo, as indústrias da transmissão e da defesa, 
universidades, as nações unidas, e as forças armadas. A 
maioria daquelas acusadas era helpless defender suas reputações 
arruinadas e enfrentava a perda do emprego, carreiras danificadas, e 
em muitas caixas, quebradas vidas. No protesto, o senator 
republicano Margaret Perseguir Smith compôs a seguinte "declaração 
do conscience," condemning a atmosfera da suspeita e responsabilizando
líderes de ambos os partidos por sua "falta da liderança eficaz." 
Embora Smith convencesse seis senators republicanos adicionais a
juntar na declaração, os sete recusaram suportar um relatório do 
senate preparado por Democrata que chamou cargas de McCarthy de 
encontro ao pessoal do departamento do estado fraudulent.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il senatore Joseph McCarthy del crociato di 
anticommunist ha fatto un passo nella protuberanza nazionale il 9 
febbraio 1950, quando ha montato un attacco all'ordine del giorno di 
politica straniera del presidente Truman. McCarthy si è 
caricato che State Department e la relativa segretaria, il decano Acheson, 
harbored i comunisti "traitorous". La retorica apocalyptic del 
McCarthy -- ha ritratto il conflitto di guerra fredda come "una 
battaglia fra atheism communistic e christianity finali e con tutti i mezzi a disposizione"
-- critici fatti esita prima di challenging lui. Suo ha preteso 
le liste dei conspirators comunisti moltiplicati durante gli anni 
successivi per includere gli impiegati negli enti governativi, le 
industrie della difesa e di broadcasting, università, le Nazioni 
Unite ed i militari. La maggior parte di quelli accusati erano 
helpless difendere le loro reputazioni rovinate ed hanno affrontato la
perdita di occupazione, hanno danneggiato le carriere ed in molti 
casi, rotte vite. Nella protesta, il senatore Repubblicano 
Margaret Chase Smith ha composto la seguente "dichiarazione di 
coscienza," condannando l'atmosfera di sospetto ed incolpando dei 
capi di entrambi i partiti la loro "mancanza di direzione 
efficace." Anche se Smith ha convinto sei senatori Repubblicani 
supplementari unirlo nella dichiarazione, i sette hanno rifiutato di 
sostenere un rapporto del senato preparato da Democrats che ha 
chiamato le spese del McCarthy contro i personali di State Department 
fraudolente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο αντικομμουνιστής σταυροφόρος γερουσιαστής Joseph 
McCarthy περπάτησε στην εθνική προεξοχή στις 9 Φεβρουαρίου 
..1950, όταν επικόλλησε μια επίθεση στην ημερήσια διάταξη 
εξωτερικής πολιτικής Προέδρου Truman's. McCarthy 
χρέωσε ότι το υπουργείο εξωτερικών και ο γραμματέας του, Dean 
Acheson, οι "προδοτικοί" κομμουνιστές. McCarthy's η 
αποκαλυπτική ρητορική -- απεικόνισε τη σύγκρουση ψυχρού πολέμου 
ως "τελική, ενθουσιώδη μάχη μεταξύ του κομμουνιστικού αθεϊσμού 
και χριστιανισμό" -- γίνονται κριτικοί διστάζει πρίν προκαλεί 
τον. Οι ισχυρισμένοι κατάλογοι κομμουνιστικών συνωμοτών του 
πολλαπλασίασαν στα επόμενα έτη για να περιλάβουν τους υπαλλήλους 
στις κυβερνητικές αντιπροσωπείες, τις βιομηχανίες ραδιοφωνικής 
αναμετάδοσης και υπεράσπισης, τα πανεπιστήμια, τα Ηνωμένα Έθνη, 
και τους στρατιωτικούς. Οι περισσότεροι από εκείνους 
κατηγορούμενους ήταν ανίσχυροι για να υπερασπίσουν τις φήμες τους
και αντιμετώπισαν την απώλεια απασχόλησης, έβλαψαν τις 
σταδιοδρομίες, και σε πολλές περιπτώσεις, που έσπασαν ζωές. 
Στη διαμαρτυρία, ο Δημοκρατικός γερουσιαστής Margaret 
Chase Smith σύνθεσε την ακόλουθη "Διακήρυξη της συνείδησης,"
καταδικάζοντας την ατμόσφαιρα της υποψίας και κατηγορώντας τους 
ηγέτες αμφότερων των συμβαλλόμενων μερών για "την έλλειψη 
αποτελεσματικής ηγεσίας τους." Αν και Smith έπεισε έξι 
πρόσθετους δημοκρατικούς γερουσιαστές για να την ενώσει στη 
Διακήρυξη, οι επτά αρνήθηκαν να υποστηρίξουν μια έκθεση 
Συγκλήτου που προετοιμάστηκε από τους δημοκράτες που κάλεσαν τις 
δαπάνες McCarthy's ενάντια στο προσωπικό υπουργείου εξωτερικών
ψευδές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El senador José McCarthy del cruzado del 
anticommunist caminó en prominencia nacional 9 de febrero de 1950,
cuando él montó un ataque contra agenda de la política no nativa de
presidente Truman. McCarthy cargó que el departamento y su 
secretaria, decano Acheson del estado, abrigaran comunistas 
"traidores". El retórico apocalíptico de McCarthy -- él 
retrató el conflicto de la guerra fría como "una batalla entre el 
ateismo comunista y cristianismo finales, totales" -- los 
críticos hechos vacila antes de desafiador él. El suyo 
pretendió las listas de los conspirators comunistas multiplicados en 
años subsecuentes para incluir a empleados en agencias de estatal, 
las industrias de la difusión y de la defensa, las universidades, los
Naciones Unidas, y los militares. La mayoría de ésos acusados 
eran desamparados defender sus reputaciones arruinadas e hicieron 
frente a la pérdida de empleo, dañaron las carreras, y en muchos 
casos, rotas las vidas. En protesta, senador republicano 
Margaret Chase Smith compuso el "declaración siguiente de 
conciencia," condenando la atmósfera de la suspicacia y culpando a 
arranques de cinta de ambas partes por su "carencia de la dirección 
eficaz." Aunque Smith convenció a seis senadores republicanos 
adicionales que la ensamblaran en el declaración, los siete 
rechazaron utilizar un informe del senado preparado por Democrats que 
llamó las cargas de McCarthy contra personal del departamento del 
estado fraudulentas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086657</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106201</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/national-suicide-margaret-chase-smith-and-six-republican-senators-speak-out-against-joseph-mccarthys-attack-on-individual-freedom</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
