<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105406</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105406</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1651176674</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">AP Biology</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">AP Biologie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Biologie de AP</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Biologia do Ap</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Biologia di Ap</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η βιολογία AP</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Biología del Ap</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This curriculum covers all of the material outlined by the College Board as necessary to prepare students to pass the AP Biology exam.  This course is designed to acquaint you with the general concepts of life including reproduction, balance in nature, and the nature of living things.  You will focus on three broad sections that align with the goals for the AP exam: Molecules and Cells, Heredity and Evolution, and Organisms and Populations.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser Lehrplan umfaßt die ganze Material, das 
durch das Hochschulgremium wie benötigt, Kursteilnehmer 
vorzubereiten, die AP Biologieprüfung zu führen umrissen wird. 
Dieser Kurs ist konzipiert, um Sie mit den allgemeinen 
Lebensanschauungen einschließlich Wiedergabe mitzuteilen, ausgleicht 
in der Natur und in der Natur der lebenden Sachen. Sie 
konzentrieren auf drei ausgedehnte Kapitel, die mit den Zielen für 
die AP Prüfung übereinstimmen: Moleküle und Zellen, Vererbung
und Entwicklung und organismen und Bevölkerungen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce programme d'études couvre tout le matériel 
tracé les grandes lignes par le conseil d'université selon les 
besoins pour préparer des étudiants passer l'examen de biologie de 
AP. Ce cours est conçu pour vous mettre au courant des concepts
de la vie généraux comprenant la reproduction, équilibre dans la 
nature, et la nature des choses vivantes. Vous vous concentrerez
sur trois larges sections qui alignent avec les buts pour l'examen de 
AP : Molécules et cellules, hérédité et évolution, et 
organizations et populations.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este curriculum cobre todo o material esboçado 
pela placa de faculdade como necessário preparar estudantes para 
passar o exam da biologia do AP. Este curso é projetado 
familiarizá-lo com os conceitos de vida gerais including a 
reprodução, balança na natureza, e na natureza de coisas vivas. 
Você focalizará em três seções largas que alinham com os 
objetivos para o exam do AP: Moléculas e pilhas, heredity e 
evolução, e organismos e populações.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo programma di studi tratta tutto il 
materiale descritto dal Bordo dell'università come necessario 
preparare gli allievi per passare il exam di biologia di AP. 
Questo corso è destinato per informarlo dei concetti di vita 
generali compreso la riproduzione, equilibra nella natura e nella 
natura delle cose viventi. Metterete a fuoco su tre vaste 
sezioni che si allineano con gli obiettivi per il exam di AP: 
Molecole e cellule, eredità e sviluppo ed organismi e 
popolazioni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το πρόγραμμα σπουδών καλύπτει όλο το υλικό που 
περιγράφεται από τον πίνακα κολλεγίου για να προετοιμάσει 
ανάλογα με τις ανάγκες τους σπουδαστές για να περάσει το 
διαγωνισμό της βιολογίας AP. Αυτή η σειρά μαθημάτων 
σχεδιάζεται για να σας εξοικειώσει με τις γενικές έννοιες της 
ζωής συμπεριλαμβανομένης της αναπαραγωγής, να ισορροπήσετε στη 
φύση, και τη φύση των πραγμάτων διαβίωσης. Θα εστιάσετε σε 
τρία ευρέα τμήματα που ευθυγραμμίζουν με τους στόχους για το 
διαγωνισμό AP: Μόρια και κύτταρα, κληρονομικότητα και 
εξέλιξη, και οργανισμοί και πληθυσμοί.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este plan de estudios cubre todo el material 
contorneado por la tarjeta de universidad como necesaria para preparar
a estudiantes para aprobar el examen de la biología del AP. 
Este curso se diseña para conocerle de los conceptos de la vida
generales incluyendo la reproducción, balancea en naturaleza, y la 
naturaleza de cosas vivas. Usted se centrará en tres amplias 
secciones que alineen con las metas para el examen del AP: 
Moléculas y células, herencia y evolución, y organismos y 
poblaciones.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:UNKNOWN
FN:UNKNOWN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1651176674</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105406</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/ap-biology-1</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
