<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106872</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106872</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205590</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Use of a Piece of Land Lesson Plan</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Gebrauch von einem Stück des 
Land-Lektion-Planes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'utilisation d'un morceau de plan de leçon de 
terre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O uso de uma parte de planta da lição da terra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'uso di una parte del programma di lezione della 
terra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η χρήση ενός κομματιού του σχεδίου μαθήματος εδάφους</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El uso de un pedazo del plan de la lección de la 
pista</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This activity is designed to engage students in a practical exercise in land use planning; to make the students aware of the positive and negative aspects of land use laws and local zoning ordinances through role-playing. The students represent groups interested in purchasing the same piece of land. Each group must research to devise a plan that is legal and attractive and present proposals to convince the current owners to sell the land to their group. The instructor is advised to use a real plot of land so that real land use laws can be researched.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Aktivität ist konzipiert, um sich 
Kursteilnehmer in einer praktischen Übung in der 
Flächennutzungplanung zu engagieren; die Kursteilnehmer bewußt
bilden den positiven und negativen Aspekten der Flächennutzunggesetze
und der lokalen Zoningbefehle durch das Rolle Spielen Rolle Spielen. 
Die Kursteilnehmer stellen die Gruppen dar, die an dem Kaufen 
des gleichen Stückes des Landes interessiert werden. Jede 
Gruppe muß erforschen, um einen Plan zu planen, der zugelassene und 
attraktive und anwesende Anträge ist, die aktuellen Inhaber zu 
überzeugen, das Land an ihre Gruppe zu verkaufen. Der Ausbilder
wird geraten, einen realen Plot des Landes zu benutzen, damit reale 
Flächennutzunggesetze erforscht werden können.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette activité est conçue pour engager des 
étudiants dans un exercice pratique dans la planification 
d'utilisation de la terre ; pour mettre au courant les 
étudiants des aspects positifs et négatifs des lois d'utilisation de
la terre et des ordonnances locales de zonage en jouant un rôle.
Les étudiants représentent des groupes intéressés à acheter
le même morceau de terre. Chaque groupe doit rechercher pour 
concevoir un plan qui est des propositions légales et attrayantes et 
actuelles pour convaincre les propriétaires actuels de vendre la 
terre à leur groupe. L'instructeur est informé utiliser un 
vrai traçage de terre de sorte que de vraies lois d'utilisation de la
terre puissent être recherchées.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta atividade é projetada acoplar estudantes em 
um exercício prático no planeamento do uso de terra; para 
fazer os estudantes cientes dos aspectos positivos e negativos de leis
do uso de terra e de ordinances locais do zoning com role-playing. 
Os estudantes representam os grupos interessados em comprar a 
mesma parte de terra. Cada grupo deve pesquisar para planejar 
uma planta que seja propostas legais e atrativas e atuais convencer os
proprietários atuais vender a terra a seu grupo. O instrutor é
recomendado usar um lote de terra real de modo que as leis reais do 
uso de terra possam ser pesquisadas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa attività è destinata per agganciare gli 
allievi in un'esercitazione pratica nella pianificazione di 
utilizzazione delle terre; per informare gli allievi delle 
funzioni positive e negative delle leggi di utilizzazione delle terre 
e delle ordinanze locali di zoning con atteggiarsi. Gli allievi 
rappresentano i gruppi interessati a comprare la stessa parte di 
terra. Ogni gruppo deve ricercare per inventare un programma che
è proposte legali ed attraenti ed attuali convincere i proprietari 
correnti vendere la terra al loro gruppo. L'istruttore si 
raccomanda di usare un lotto reale in moda da potere ricercare le 
leggi reali di utilizzazione delle terre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η δραστηριότητα έχει ως σκοπό να συμμετέχει τους
σπουδαστές σε μια πρακτική άσκηση στον προγραμματισμό χρήσης 
εδάφους  για να καταστήσει τους σπουδαστές ενήμερους για τις
θετικές και αρνητικές πτυχές του εδάφους να χρησιμοποιήσουν τους 
νόμους και τις τοπικές διατάξεις χωρισμού μέσω του 
ρόλος-παιχνιδιού. Οι σπουδαστές αντιπροσωπεύουν τις ομάδες 
ενδιαφερόμενες στην αγορά του ίδιου κομματιού του εδάφους. 
Κάθε ομάδα πρέπει να ερευνήσει για να επινοήσει ένα 
σχέδιο που είναι νομικές και ελκυστικές και παρούσες προτάσεις 
να πειστούν οι παρόντες ιδιοκτήτες για να πωλήσει το έδαφος στην 
ομάδα τους. Ο εκπαιδευτικός ενθαρρύνεται για να 
χρησιμοποιήσει ένα πραγματικό οικόπεδο έτσι ώστε οι πραγματικοί
νόμοι χρήσης εδάφους μπορούν να ερευνηθούν.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta actividad se diseña para contratar a 
estudiantes a un ejercicio práctico en hojas de operación (planning)
de la utilización del suelo; para hacer a los estudiantes 
enterados de los aspectos positivos y negativos de los leyes de 
utilización del suelo y de las ordenanzas locales del zoning con la 
actuación de papeles. Los estudiantes representan a grupos 
interesados en comprar el mismo pedazo de pista. Cada grupo debe
investigar para idear un plan que sea ofertas legales y atractivas y 
actuales convencer a los propietarios actuales que vendan la pista a 
su grupo. Aconsejan el instructor utilizar un diagrama de la 
pista verdadero para poder investigar leyes verdaderos de utilización
del suelo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:DUANE LEAVITT
FN:DUANE LEAVITT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205590</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106872</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-use-of-a-piece-of-land-lesson-plan</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
