<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104092</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104092</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086220</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Haymarket Martyr Louis Lingg Says Good-bye</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Haymarket Märtyrer Louis Lingg Sagt Auf 
Wiedersehen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Martyre Louis Lingg de Haymarket Dit Au revoir</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Martyr Louis Lingg De Haymarket Diz Adeus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Martyr Louis Lingg Di Haymarket Dice 
Arrivederci</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μάρτυρας Louis Lingg Says Good-bye 
Haymarket</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Martyr Louis Lingg De Haymarket Dice Adiós</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Chicago radicals convicted of the infamous May 4, 1886 Haymarket Square bombing in which one policeman was killed remained openly defiant to the end. Twenty-one-year-old German-born Carpenter Louis Lingg enthusiastically embraced the principles of anarchism and the violence he thought necessary to emancipate the working class in his final address before the court that convicted him of participating in the bombing.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Chicago Radikale, die des unbeliebten Mais 4, 
1886 Haymarket quadratische Bombardierung überführt wurden, in der 
ein Polizist beendet wurde, blieben öffentlich zum Ende defiant. 
Zwanzig-ein-Jahr-alter Deutsch-getragener Tischler Louis Lingg 
umfaßte enthusiastisch die Grundregeln der Anarchie und der 
Gewalttätigkeit, die er notwendiges dachte, die Funktion Kategorie in
seinem Schlußvortrag vor dem Gericht zu emanzipieren, das ihn des 
Teilnehmens an der Bombardierung überführte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les radicaux de Chicago condamnés mai infâme de 
4, 1886 le bombardement carré de Haymarket dans lequel un policier a 
été détruit sont restés ouvrir provoquants d'extrémité. le
Vingt-un-année-vieux charpentier Allemand-soutenu Louis Lingg a avec 
enthousiasme embrassé les principes de l'anarchisme et de la violence
qu'il a pensé nécessaire d'émanciper la classe ouvrière dans sa 
adresse finale devant la cour qui l'a condamné de participer au 
bombardement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os radicais de Chicago convicted maio infamous do 
4, 1886 o bombardeio quadrado de Haymarket em que um polícia foi 
matado remanesceram abertamente defiant à extremidade. o 
carpinteiro Alemão-carregado Vinte-um-ano-velho Louis Lingg embraced 
entusiàstica os princípios do anarchism e da violência que pensou 
de necessário emancipate a classe de funcionamento em seu endereço 
final antes da corte que convicted o de participar no bombardeio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I radicali del Chicago condannati maggio malfamato 
del 4, 1886 bombardamento quadrato di Haymarket in cui un poliziotto 
è stato ucciso sono rimasto apertamente ribelle all'estremità. 
il Venti-un-anno-vecchio carpentiere Tedesco-sopportato Louis 
Lingg ha abbracciato entusiastico i principii dell'anarchismo e della 
violenza che ha pensato necessario emancipate il codice categoria di 
funzionamento nel suo indirizzo finale davanti alla corte che lo ha 
condannato di partecipare al bombardamento.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι ριζοσπάστες του Σικάγου που καταδικάζονται του 
κακόφημου Μάιος 4 τετραγωνικός βομβαρδισμός ..1886 
Haymarket σε ποιος ένας αστυνομικός σκοτώθηκε παραμένοντας 
ανοιχτά προκλητικός στο τέλος. Ο 
είκοσι-ένας-χρονών γερμανικός-γεννημένος ξυλουργός 
Louis Lingg αγκαλίασε ενθουσιωδώς τις αρχές του αναρχισμού 
και της βίας που σκέφτηκε απαραίτητη χειραφετώ την εργατική τάξη
στην τελική διεύθυνσή του ενώπιον του δικαστηρίου που τον 
καταδίκασε της συμμετοχής στο βομβαρδισμό.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los radicales de Chicago condenados del de mayo 
infame 4 de 1886 el bombardeo cuadrado de Haymarket en el cual mataron
a un policía seguían siendo abiertamente desafiantes al extremo. 
el Veinte-uno-año-viejo carpintero Alema'n-llevado Louis Lingg 
abrazó entusiástico los principios del anarquismo y de la violencia 
que él pensó necesario para emancipate la clase obrera en su 
direccionamiento final antes de la corte que lo condenó por 
participar en el bombardeo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086220</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104092</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/haymarket-martyr-louis-lingg-says-good-bye</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
