<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105667</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105667</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209865</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Area enclosed by an ellipse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bereich umgeben durch einen Ellipse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Zone entourée par une ellipse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Área incluída por um ellipse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Zona chiusa da un ellisse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Περιοχή που εσωκλείεται από μια έλλειψη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Área incluida por una elipse</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate the area of an ellipse. The major and minor axes can be dragged and the area is continuously recalculated. The ellipse has a grid inside it so that students can estimate the area and compare the result to the calculated one. The web page has the formula for the area calculation. The web page also has links to other pages defining the various properties of an ellipse and to some ellipse constructions. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die den Bereich eines Ellipse zeigen. Die Haupt- und 
geringen Äxte können geschleppt werden und der Bereich wird 
ununterbrochen nachgerechnet. Der Ellipse hat ein Rasterfeld 
nach innen es, damit Kursteilnehmer den Bereich schätzen und das 
Resultat bis errechnete vergleichen können. Die Webseite hat 
die Formel für die Bereich Berechnung. Die Webseite hat auch 
Links zu anderen Seiten, welche die verschiedenen Eigenschaften eines 
Ellipse definieren und zu etwas Ellipseaufbauten. Applet kann 
zum vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor 
vergrößert werden. Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, 
Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause 
oder in der Bibliothek ohne den benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. 
Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes 
Bezugsinteraktiven Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent la zone d'une ellipse. Les haches principales et
mineures peuvent être traînées et la zone est sans interruption 
recalculée. L'ellipse a une grille à l'intérieur il de sorte 
que les étudiants puissent estimer la zone et comparer le résultat 
à calculé. La page Web a la formule pour le calcul de zone.
La page Web a également des liens à d'autres pages 
définissant les diverses propriétés d'une ellipse et à quelques 
constructions d'ellipse. L'applet peut être agrandi à la 
taille de plein écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de 
classe. Le après utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant
peut lui accéder encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la 
maison ou dans la bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion 
exigée. Cette ressource est un composant du projet interactif 
de manuel de la géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem a área de um ellipse. Os machados principais e 
menores podem ser arrastados e a área recalculated continuamente. 
O ellipse tem uma grade para dentro ele de modo que os 
estudantes possam estimar a área e comparar o resultado ao calculado.
O Web page tem a fórmula para o cálculo da área. O Web 
page tem também as ligações a outras páginas que definem as 
várias propriedades de um ellipse e a algumas construções do 
ellipse. O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de tela cheia 
para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. O depois de uso na 
sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo o web 
browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma sessão 
requerido. Este recurso é um componente do projeto interativo 
do textbook da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano la zona di un ellisse. Le ascie principali e 
secondarie possono essere trascinate e la zona è ricalcolata 
continuamente. L'ellisse ha una griglia all'interno esso in moda
da potere valutare la zona e confrontare gli allievi il risultato a 
quello calcolato. Il Web page ha la formula per il calcolo di 
zona. Il Web page egualmente ha collegamenti ad altre pagine che
definiscono le varie proprietà di un ellisse e ad alcune costruzioni 
di ellisse. Il applet può essere ingrandito al formato di 
schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore dell'aula. La 
post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può accederle ancora da tutto 
il web browser nel paese o nella libreria senza l'inizio attività 
richiesto. Questa risorsa è un componente del progetto 
interattivo del manuale della geometria di riferimento aperto di per 
la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν τον τομέα μιας έλλειψης. Οι σημαντικότεροι και
δευτερεύοντες άξονες μπορούν να σέρθούν και η περιοχή 
υπολογίζεται εκ νέου συνεχώς. Η έλλειψη έχει ένα πλέγμα 
μέσα αυτό έτσι ώστε οι σπουδαστές μπορούν να υπολογίσουν την 
περιοχή και να συγκρίνουν το αποτέλεσμα με υπολογισμένο. 
Ιστοσελίδας έχει τον τύπο για τον υπολογισμό περιοχής. 
Ιστοσελίδας έχει επίσης τις συνδέσεις με άλλες σελίδες 
καθορίζοντας τις διάφορες ιδιότητες μιας έλλειψης και σε μερικές 
κατασκευές έλλειψης. Το Applet μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο 
πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με έναν προβολέα τάξεων. 
Μετά από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει 
πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι
ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια εισόδου που απαιτείται. 
Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του 
ανοικτού προγράμματος εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math 
διαλογικού σε http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran el área de una elipse. Las hachas principales y de 
menor importancia pueden ser arrastradas y el área se recalcula 
continuamente. La elipse tiene una rejilla adentro él de modo 
que los estudiantes puedan estimar el área y comparar el resultado 
calculado. El Web page tiene el fórmula para el cálculo del 
área. El Web page también tiene conexiones a otras 
paginaciones que definen las varias características de una elipse y a
algunas construcciones de la elipse. El applet se puede agrandar
a la talla de la pantalla completa para el uso con un proyector de la 
sala de clase. El uso posterior en la sala de clase, estudiante 
puede tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier web browser en el país o 
en la biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. Este recurso es un 
componente del proyecto interactivo del libro de textos de la 
geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas en 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209865</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105667</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/area-enclosed-by-an-ellipse</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
