<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106981</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106981</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203571</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Just-in-Time Teaching (JiTT) WarmUp Activity: Life on the Moon and Mars</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gerade-in-Zeit Unterricht (JiTT) Vorwärmung 
Aktivität: Leben auf dem Mond und dem Mars</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Activité De Préchauffage d'Enseignement de 
Juste-dans-Temps (JiTT) : La vie sur la lune et le Mars</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Atividade Do WarmUp Do Ensino Do Apenas-em-Tempo 
(JiTT): Vida na lua e no Marte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Attività Di Preriscaldamento Di Insegnamento Di 
Appena-in-Tempo (JiTT): Vita sulla luna e sul Marte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πάνω στην ώρα δραστηριότητα WarmUp διδασκαλίας 
(JiTT): Ζωή στο φεγγάρι και τον Αρη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Actividad Del Calentamiento De la Enseñanza Del 
Apenas-en-Tiempo (JiTT): Vida en la luna y el Marte</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site from SERC presents Just-in-Time Teaching (JiTT) warm up questions about life on the Moon and Mars. The questions promote the examination of Archaea, evidence of life on Mars and protolife on the Moon, as well as what it would mean to scientists and society if life were found on Mars or the Moon.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site von SERC stellt Gerade-in-Zeit 
Unterricht (JiTT) Vorwärmung Fragen über das Leben auf dem Mond und 
dem Mars dar. Die Fragen fördern die Prüfung von Archaea, 
Beweis des Lebens auf Mars und protolife auf dem Mond, sowie, was es 
zu den Wissenschaftlern und zur Gesellschaft bedeuten würde, wenn das
Leben auf Mars oder dem Mond gefunden wurden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site de SERC présente des questions de 
préchauffage d'enseignement de Juste-dans-Temps (JiTT) au sujet de la
vie sur la lune et le Mars. Les questions favorisent l'examen 
d'Archaea, l'évidence de la vie sur Mars et le protolife sur la lune,
aussi bien que ce que signifierait il aux scientifiques et à la 
société si la vie étaient trouvées sur Mars ou la lune.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local do ensino do Apenas-em-Tempo dos 
presentes de SERC (JiTT) aquece acima perguntas sobre a vida na lua e 
no Marte. As perguntas promovem a examinação de Archaea, a 
evidência da vida em Marte e o protolife na lua, as.well.as o que 
significaria aos cientistas e à sociedade se a vida for encontrada em
Marte ou na lua.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo da SERC presenta le domande di 
preriscaldamento di insegnamento di Appena-in-Tempo (JiTT) circa vita 
sulla luna e sul Marte. Le domande promuovono l'esame di 
Archaea, la prova di vita su Marte ed il protolife sulla luna, così 
come che cosa significherebbe agli scienziati ed alla società se la 
vita fosse trovata su Marte o sulla luna.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή από SERC παρουσιάζει τις πάνω στην 
ώρα ερωτήσεις προθέρμανσης διδασκαλίας (JiTT) για τη ζωή στο 
φεγγάρι και τον Αρη. Οι ερωτήσεις προωθούν την εξέταση 
Archaea, στοιχεία της ζωής στον Αρη και protolife στο 
φεγγάρι, καθώς επίσης και τι θα σήμαινε στους επιστήμονες και την
κοινωνία εάν η ζωή βρέθηκε στον Αρη ή το φεγγάρι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio de SERC presenta preguntas del 
calentamiento de la enseñanza del Apenas-en-Tiempo (JiTT) sobre vida 
en la luna y el Marte. Las preguntas promueven la examinación 
de Archaea, la evidencia de la vida en Marte y el protolife en la 
luna, así como lo que significaría a los científicos y a la 
sociedad si la vida fue encontrada en Marte o la luna.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:LAURA GUERTIN
FN:LAURA GUERTIN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CATHY MANDUCA
FN:CATHY MANDUCA
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203571</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106981</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/just-in-time-teaching-jitt-warmup-activity-life-on-the-moon-and-mars</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
