<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107257</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107257</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202972</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Glacial Landforms Resulting from Erosion and Deposition</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Glazial- Landforms, resultierend aus Abnutzung und
Absetzung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Formes de relief glaciaires résultant de l'érosion 
et du dépôt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Landforms glacial resultando da erosão e do 
deposition</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Landforms glaciale derivando dall'erosione e dal 
deposito</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παγετώδη landforms ως αποτέλεσμα της διάβρωσης και 
της απόθεσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Landforms glacial resultando de la erosión y de 
la deposición</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site provides visual resources and supporting material about how glaciers modify the landscape. Animations and movies illustrate both depositional and erosional landforms such as moraines, outwash plains, U-shaped valleys, cirques, and hanging waterfalls. These resources may be incorporated into lectures, labs, and other activities.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site liefert Sichtbetriebsmittel und 
Hilfsmaterial über, wie Gletscher die Landschaft ändern. 
Animationen und Filme veranschaulichen die Ablagerungs- und 
erosional landforms wie moraines, outwash Ebenen, ue-förmig Senken, 
cirques und hängende Wasserfälle. Diese Betriebsmittel können
in Vorträge, in Labors und in andere Aktivitäten enthalten werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site fournit les ressources et le matériel de 
support visuels au sujet de la façon dont les glaciers modifient 
l'horizontal. Les animations et les films illustrent les 
formes de relief dépositionnelles et érosionnelles telles que des 
moraines, des plaines d'outwash, des vallées en U, des cirques, et 
des chutes d'eau s'arrêtantes. Ces ressources peuvent être 
incorporées aux conférences, aux laboratoires, et à d'autres 
activités.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local fornece recursos visuais e o material 
suportando sobre como as geleiras modificam a paisagem. Os 
animations e os filmes ilustram  landforms depositional e erosional 
tais como moraines, planícies do outwash, vales em forma de u, 
cirques, e cachoeiras de suspensão. Estes recursos podem ser 
incorporados em lectures, em laboratórios, e em outras atividades.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo fornisce le risorse ed il materiale 
visivi di sostegno circa come i ghiacciai modificano il paesaggio. 
Le animazioni ed i film illustrano sia i landforms 
depositional che erosional quali i moraines, le pianure del outwash, 
le valli a forma di U, i cirques e le cascate appendenti. Queste
risorse possono essere comprese nelle conferenze, nei laboratori ed in
altre attività.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή παρέχει τα οπτικά στοιχεία 
συμπεριφοράς και το ενισχυτικό υλικό για το πώς οι παγετώνες 
τροποποιούν το τοπίο. Οι ζωτικότητες και οι κινηματογράφοι 
επεξηγούν και depositional και erosional landforms όπως τα 
moraines, outwash πεδιάδες, σε σχήμα υ κοιλάδες, cirques, 
και κρεμώντας καταρράκτες. Αυτά τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς 
μπορούν να ενσωματωθούν στις διαλέξεις, τα εργαστήρια, και άλλες 
δραστηριότητες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio proporciona a recursos visuales y al 
material que utiliza sobre cómo los glaciares modifican el paisaje. 
Las animaciones y las películas ilustran landforms 
deposicionales y erosional tales como moraines, llanos del outwash, 
valles en forma de "U", cirques, y cascadas que cuelgan. Estos 
recursos se pueden incorporar en conferencias, laboratorios, y otras 
actividades.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202972</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107257</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/glacial-landforms-resulting-from-erosion-and-deposition</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
