<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103764</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103764</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087027</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Process of Coming Back into the World": An American Indian Movement (A.I.M.) Activist Advocates Cultural and Political Unification</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"der Prozeß des Zurückkommens in die Welt": 
Eine Indianische Bewegung (A.I.M.) Aktivist befürwortet 
kulturelle und politische Vereinheitlichung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"le processus de revenir au monde" : Un 
Mouvement Indien (A.I.M.) L'activiste préconise l'unification 
culturelle et politique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"o processo de voltar no mundo": Um Movimento
Indian Americano (A.I.M.) A activista advoga o unification 
cultural e político</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"il processo di ritorno nel mondo": Un 
Movimento Indiano Americano (A.I.M.) L'attivista sostiene 
l'unificazione culturale e politica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η διαδικασία στον κόσμο": Μια αμερικανική 
ινδική πολιτιστική και πολιτική ενοποίηση συνηγόρων ενεργών 
στελεχών μετακίνησης (A.I.M.)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"el proceso de volverse en el mundo": Un 
Movimiento Indio Americano (A.I.M.) El activista aboga la 
unificación cultural y política</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1968, young urban-based American Indians in Minnesota formed the American Indian Movement (AIM) to fight mistreatment by police and to improve prospects for jobs, education, and housing. In 1972, AIM initiated "The Trail of Broken Treaties," and a subsequent march to Washington to present the Nixon administration with a 20-point sovereignty proposal. From its beginning, AIM suffered from disagreement between "traditionals" holding reservation-oriented agendas and urban-based "progressives". By the end of the 1970s, plagued by repression and internal disputes, AIM declined as a leading militant organization. In the following document written in 1974, Jimmie Durham of AIM's American Indian Support Committee, critically addressed attitudes of white progressives that had caused friction within the group. The paper, which Durham, a Cherokee Indian, has acknowledged was influenced by Marxist writers, was subsequently doctored by the FBI and submitted to Tribal Councils and the Senate Subcommittee on Internal Security to discredit him. (The version appearing below is excerpted from Durham's published original and reprinted with his permission.) In 1974, Durham founded the International Indian Treaty Council to lobby the United Nations towards decolonization of indigenous peoples worldwide. The Treaty Council helped create the 1977 UN conference on indigenous affairs, attended by representatives of 98 indigenous peoples. Durham subsequently resigned from the Treaty Council and he has become an acclaimed artist and poet, writing on cultural and political subjects.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1968 bildeten junge städtisch-gegründete Indianer
in Minnesota die indianische Bewegung (ZIEL) zur Kampfmißhandlung 
durch Polizei und Aussichten für Jobs, Ausbildung und Gehäuse zu 
verbessern. 1972 initialisiert ZIEL "die Spur der unterbrochenen
Verträge," und des folgenden Märzes nach Washington, um die Nixon 
Leitung mit einem Antrag der Hoheit darzustellen 20-point. Von 
seinem Anfang litt ZIEL unter Widerspruch zwischen "traditionals" 
Holding Reservierung-orientierten Tagesordnungen und 
städtisch-gründete "Progressisten". Ende der siebziger Jahre 
gequält durch Unterdrückung und interne Debatten, ZIELEN Sie 
gesunken als führende militante Organisation. Im folgenden 
Dokument, das 1974 geschrieben wurde, adressierte Jimmie Durham des 
indianischen Ausschusses Unterstützung des Zieles, kritisch Haltung 
der weißen Progressisten, die Friktion innerhalb der Gruppe 
verursacht hatten. Das Papier, das Durham, ein Cherokee Inder, 
bestätigt hat, wurde von den Marxist Verfassern beeinflußt, wurde 
nachher durch das FBI behandelt und eingegeben bei den Stammes- Räten
und bei der Senat-Unterausschuß auf interner Sicherheit, um ihn zu 
diskreditieren. (die Version, die unten erscheint, wird von 
Durhams erschienenem ursprünglichem excerptiert und neugedruckt mit 
seiner Erlaubnis.) 1974 gründete Durham den internationalen 
indischen Vertrag-Rat, um die Nationen in Richtung zum Decolonization 
der eingeborenen Völker weltweit zu beeinflussen. Der 
Vertrag-Rat geholfen, die 1977 UNO Konferenz auf den eingeborenen 
Angelegenheiten zu erstellen, bedient durch Repräsentanten von 98 
eingeborenen Völkern. Durham fand nachher vom Vertrag-Rat ab 
und er ist ein mit Beifall begrüßter Künstler und ein Dichter 
geworden und geschrieben auf die kulturellen und politischen Themen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1968, les jeunes Indiens d'Amerique 
urbain-basés au Minnesota ont formé le mouvement indien (BUT) au 
mauvais traitement de combat par la police et pour améliorer des 
perspectives pour les travaux, l'éducation, et le logement. En 
1972, le BUT lance "la traînée des Traités cassés," et d'une 
marche ultérieure à Washington pour présenter la gestion de Nixon 
avec une proposition de la souveraineté 20-point. De son 
début, le BUT a souffert du désaccord entre les ordres du jour 
réservation-orientés par possession de "traditionals" et urbain-a 
basé des "progressifs". Vers la fin des années 70, infestées 
par répression et conflits internes, VISEZ diminué comme principale 
organisation militante. Dans le document suivant écrit en 
1974, Jimmie Durham du Comité indien du support du but, a en critique
adressé des attitudes des progressifs blancs qui avaient causé le 
frottement chez le groupe. Le papier, que Durham, un Indien 
cherokee, a reconnu a été influencé par des auteurs de Marxist, a 
été ultérieurement soigné par le FBI et soumis aux Conseils
tribals et au sous-comité de sénat sur la sécurité interne pour le
critiquer. (la version apparaissant ci-dessous est extraite 
d'initial édité de Durham et réimprimée avec sa permission.) 
En 1974, Durham a fondé le Conseil indien international de 
Traité pour inciter les Nations Unies vers la décolonisation du 
peuple autochtone dans le monde entier. Le Conseil de Traité 
aidé à créer la conférence des 1977 ONU sur des affaires 
indigènes, occupées par des représentants de 98 peuples 
autochtones. Durham a ultérieurement démissionné du Conseil 
de Traité et il est devenu un artiste et un poèt acclamés, 
écrivant sur les sujets culturels et politiques.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1968, os indians americanos urbano-baseados 
novos em Minnesota deram forma ao movimento indian americano (ALVO) ao
mau trato da luta por polícias e para melhorar prospetos para 
trabalhos, instrução, e carcaça. Em 1972, o ALVO inicía "a 
fuga de tratados quebrados," e de um março subseqüente a Washington 
para apresentar a administração de Nixon com uma proposta do 
sovereignty 20-point. De seu começo, o ALVO sofreu do 
disagreement entre agendas reservation-orientadas terra arrendada dos 
"traditionals" e urbano-baseou "progressistas". Para o fim dos 
1970s, flagelados pelo repression e por disputas internas, APONTE 
declinado como uma organização militant principal. No seguinte
original escrito em 1974, Jimmie Durham do comitê indian americano da
sustentação do alvo, dirigiu-se crìticamente a atitudes dos 
progressistas brancos que tinham causado a fricção dentro do grupo. 
O papel, que Durham, um indian cherokee, reconheceu foi 
influenciado por escritores de Marxist, subseqüentemente medicado 
pelo FBI e submetido aos conselhos tribais e à subcomissão do senate
na segurança interna para desacreditá-lo. (a versão que 
aparece abaixo excerpted de original publicado de Durham e reprinted 
com sua permissão.) Em 1974, Durham fundou o conselho indian 
internacional do tratado para lobby worldwide as nações unidas para 
o decolonization de povos indígenos. O conselho do tratado 
ajudado criar a conferência de 1977 UN sobre os casos indígenos, 
atendidos por representantes de 98 povos indígenos. Durham 
renunciou subseqüentemente do conselho do tratado e transformou-se um
artista e um poeta aclamados, escrevendo em assuntos cultural e 
políticos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1968, gli indiani americani urbano-basati 
giovani nel Minnesota hanno formato il movimento indiano americano 
(SCOPO) a maltrattamento di lotta dalla polizia e migliorare i 
prospetti per i lavori, la formazione e l'alloggiamento. In 
1972, lo SCOPO inizia "la traccia dei Trattati rotti," e di un 
procedere successivo a Washington per presentare la gestione di Nixon 
con una proposta della sovranità 20-point. Dal relativo inizio,
lo SCOPO ha sofferto da disaccordo fra gli ordini del giorno 
prenotazione-orientati tenuta "di traditionals" ed urbano-ha 
basato "i progressives". Per la fine degli anni 70, contagiati 
da repressione e da dispute interne, MIRI ribassante come 
organizzazione principale del militante. Nel seguente 
documento redatto in 1974, Jimmie Durham del comitato indiano 
americano di sostegno dello scopo, ha richiamato criticamente gli 
atteggiamenti dei progressives bianchi che avevano causato l'attrito 
presso il gruppo. La carta, che Durham, un indiano cherokee, ha 
riconosciuto è stata influenzata dai produttori del Marxist, 
successivamente è stata aggiustata dal FBI ed è stata presentata ai 
Consigli tribali ed al sottocomitato del senato su sicurezza interna 
per screditarla. (la versione che compare sotto è stralciata da
originale pubblicato del Durham ed è ristampata con il suo permesso.)
In 1974, Durham ha fondato il Consiglio indiano internazionale 
di Trattato per incitare le Nazioni Unite verso decolonization della 
gente indigena universalmente. Consiglio di Trattato contribuito
a creare il congresso 1977 di NU sugli affari indigeni, 
assistiti a dai rappresentanti di 98 genti indigene. Durham 
successivamente si è dimesso dal Consiglio di Trattato ed è 
diventato un artista e un poet applauditi, scrivendo sugli oggetti 
culturali e politici.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1968, νέοι αστικός-βασισμένοι αμερικανικοί 
Ινδοί σε Μινεσότα διαμόρφωσαν το αμερικανικό ινδικό Κίνημα 
(AIM) για να παλεψουν την κακή μεταχείριση από την αστυνομία 
και για να βελτιώσουν τις προοπτικές για τις εργασίες, την 
εκπαίδευση, και την κατοικία. Το 1972, το AIM άρχισε 
"το ίχνος των σπασμένων Συνθηκών," και ενός επόμενου του Μαρτίου
στην Ουάσιγκτον για να υποβάλει στην κυβέρνηση Nixon με μια 
πρόταση κυριαρχίας 20-σημείου. Από την αρχή του, το AIM 
έπασχε από τη διαφωνία μεταξύ των επιφύλαξη-προσανατολισμένων 
στον την εκμετάλλευση ημερήσιων διατάξεων "traditionals" και των
αστικός-βασισμένων "progressives". Μέχρι το τέλος της 
δεκαετίας του '70, που μολύνθηκε από την καταστολή και τις 
εσωτερικές διαφωνίες, το AIM μειώθηκε ως κορυφαία στρατευμένη 
οργάνωση. Στο ακόλουθο έγγραφο που γράφτηκε το 1974, 
Jimmie Durham της αμερικανικής ινδικής Επιτροπής υποστήριξης
του AIM, εξέτασε αυστηρά τις τοποθετήσεις των άσπρων 
progressives που είχαν προκαλέσει την τριβή μέσα στην ομάδα. 
Το έγγραφο, που Durham, ένας τσερόκι Ινδός, έχει 
αναγνωρίσει επηρεάστηκε από τους μαρξιστικούς συγγραφείς, ήταν 
στη συνέχεια από τη FBI και υπέβαλε στα φυλετικά Συμβούλια και
την υποεπιτροπή Συγκλήτου στην εσωτερική ασφάλεια για να τον 
δυσφημήσει. (Η έκδοση που εμφανίζεται κατωτέρω είναι από 
δημοσιευμένο αρχικό Durham και ανατυπωμένος με τη δικαιοδοσία 
του.) Το 1974, Durham ίδρυσε το διεθνές ινδικό 
Συμβούλιο Συνθήκης για να πιέσει τα Ηνωμένα Έθνη προς το 
decolonization των γηγενών λαών παγκοσμίως. Το Συμβούλιο 
Συνθήκης που ενισχύεται να δημιουργήσει τη διάσκεψη των Η.Ε του 
1977 σχετικά με τις γηγενείς υποθέσεις, που παρακολουθούνται 
από τους αντιπροσώπους 98 γηγενών λαών. Θ*Δuρχαμ που 
παραιτείται στη συνέχεια από το Συμβούλιο Συνθήκης και έχει 
γίνει επευφημημένοι καλλιτέχνης και ένας ποιητής, που γράφει στα
πολιτιστικά και πολιτικά θέματα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1968, los indios americanos urbano-basados 
jóvenes en Minnesota formaron el movimiento indio americano 
(PUNTERÍA) al maltratamiento de la lucha del policía y mejorar las 
perspectivas de trabajos, de la educación, y de la cubierta. En
1972, la PUNTERÍA inició "el rastro de tratados quebrados," y de un 
marzo subsecuente a Washington para presentar la administración de 
Nixon con una oferta de la soberanía 20-point. De su principio,
la PUNTERÍA sufrió del desacuerdo entre las agendas 
reservacio'n-orientadas tenencia de los "traditionals" y urbano-baso' 
a "progresistas". Para el final de los años 70, plagados por la
represión y conflictos internos, APUNTE declinado como organización 
militante principal. En el documento siguiente escrito en 
1974, Jimmie Durham del comité indio americano de la ayuda de la 
puntería, trató críticamente actitudes de los progresistas blancos 
que habían causado la fricción dentro del grupo. El papel, que
Durham, indio cherokee, ha reconocido fue influenciado por los 
programas de escritura de Marxist, posteriormente cuidado por el FBI y
sometido a los consejos tribales y al subcomité del senado en 
seguridad interna para desacreditarlo. (la versión que aparece 
abajo se extracta de original publicada de Durham y se reimprime con 
su permiso.) En 1974, Durham fundó a consejo indio 
internacional del tratado para cabildear los Naciones Unidas hacia la 
descolonización de la gente indígena por todo el mundo. El 
consejo del tratado ayudado a crear la conferencia de la 1977 O.N.U 
sobre los asuntos indígenas, atendidos por los representantes de 98 
personas indígenas. Durham dimitió posteriormente del consejo 
del tratado y él ha hecho artista y poeta aclamados, escribiendo en 
temas culturales y políticos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087027</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103764</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-process-of-coming-back-into-the-world-an-american-indian-movement-a-i-m-activist-advocates-cultural-and-political-unification</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
