<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108762</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108762</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209935</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Area of a trapezoid. Definition and formula</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bereich eines Paralleltrapezes. Definition 
und Formel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Zone d'un trapèze. Définition et formule</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Área de um trapezoid. Definição e 
fórmula</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Zona di un trapezio. Definizione e formula</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Περιοχή trapezoid. Καθορισμός και τύπος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Área de un trapezoide. Definición y 
fórmula</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A web page and interactive applet showing the ways to calculate the area of a trapezoid. The user can drag the vertices of the trapezoid and the other points change automatically to ensure it remains a trapezoid. A grid inside the shape allows students to estimate the area visually, then check against the actual computed area. The text on the page gives three different ways to calculate the area with a formula for each. The applet uses one of the methods to compute the area in real time, so it changes as the trapezoid is reshaped with the mouse. A companion page is http://www.mathopenref.com/trapezoid.html showing the definition and properties of a trapezoid Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Webseite und ein interaktiver applet, welche 
die Methoden zeigen, den Bereich eines Paralleltrapezes zu errechnen. 
Der Benutzer kann die Gipfel des Paralleltrapezes und der 
anderen Punktänderung automatisch schleppen, um ihm ein 
Paralleltrapez des Remains sicherzustellen. Ein Rasterfeld 
innerhalb der Form erlaubt Kursteilnehmern, den Bereich sichtlich zu 
schätzen, dann überprüft gegen den tatsächlichen Berechnungs- 
Bereich. Der Text auf der Seite gibt drei unterschiedliche 
Möglichkeiten, den Bereich mit einer Formel für jedes zu errechnen. 
Der applet verwendet eine der Methoden, um den Bereich in der 
Istzeit zu berechnen, also ändert er, während das Paralleltrapez mit
der Maus umgestaltet wird. Eine Begleiterseite ist darstellendes
http://www.mathopenref.com/trapezoid.html, daß die Definition und die
Eigenschaften eines Paralleltrapez applet zum vollen Bildumfang für 
Gebrauch mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden können.
Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von 
jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den 
benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein 
Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven 
Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une page Web et un applet interactif montrant 
les voies de calculer la zone d'un trapèze. L'utilisateur peut 
traîner les sommets du trapèze et de l'autre changement de points 
automatiquement pour lui assurer un trapèze des restes. Une 
grille à l'intérieur de la forme permet à des étudiants d'estimer 
la zone visuellement, puis contrôle contre la zone calculée réelle.
Le texte à la page donne trois voies différentes de calculer 
la zone avec une formule pour chacun. L'applet emploie une des 
méthodes pour calculer la zone en temps réel, ainsi il change 
pendant que le trapèze est restructuré avec la souris. Une 
page de compagnon est http://www.mathopenref.com/trapezoid.html 
montrant que la définition et les propriétés d'un applet de 
trapèze peuvent être agrandies à la taille de plein écran pour 
l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de classe. Le après 
utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant peut lui accéder 
encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la maison ou dans la 
bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion exigée. Cette 
ressource est un composant du projet interactif de manuel de la 
géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um Web page e um applet interativo que mostram as 
maneiras calcular a área de um trapezoid. O usuário pode 
arrastar os vertices do trapezoid e da outra mudança dos pontos 
automaticamente para assegurar-lhe um trapezoid do remains. Uma 
grade dentro da forma permite que os estudantes estimem a área 
visualmente, a seguir verifica-os de encontro à área computada real.
O texto na página dá três maneiras diferentes calcular a 
área com uma fórmula para cada um. O applet usa um dos 
métodos computar a área no tempo real, assim que muda enquanto o 
trapezoid reshaped com o rato. Uma página do companheiro é 
http://www.mathopenref.com/trapezoid.html que mostra que a definição
e as propriedades de um applet do trapezoid podem ser ampliadas ao 
tamanho de tela cheia para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. 
O depois de uso na sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la 
outra vez de todo o web browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum 
início de uma sessão requerido. Este recurso é um componente 
do projeto interativo do textbook da geometria da referência aberta 
do math em http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un Web page e un applet interattivo che mostrano i
modi calcolare la zona di un trapezio. L'utente può trascinare 
automaticamente i vertici del trapezio e dell'altro cambiamento dei 
punti per accertargli un trapezio del remains. Una griglia 
all'interno della figura permette che gli allievi valutino visivamente
la zona, quindi che controlla contro la zona computata reale. Il
testo alla pagina dà tre modi differenti calcolare la zona con una 
formula per ciascuno. Il applet usa uno dei metodi per computare
la zona in tempo reale, in modo da cambia mentre il trapezio è 
rimodellato con il mouse. Una pagina del compagno è 
http://www.mathopenref.com/trapezoid.html che mostra che la 
definizione e le proprietà di un applet del trapezio possono essere 
ingrandite al formato di schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore 
dell'aula. La post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può 
accederle ancora da tutto il web browser nel paese o nella libreria 
senza l'inizio attività richiesto. Questa risorsa è un 
componente del progetto interattivo del manuale della geometria di 
riferimento aperto di per la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ιστοσελίδας και διαλογικό ένα applet που εμφανίζουν
τους τρόπους να υπολογιστεί η περιοχή trapezoid. Ο 
χρήστης μπορεί να σέρει vertices trapezoid και τα άλλα 
σημεία αλλάζουν αυτόματα για να εξασφαλίσουν ότι παραμένει 
trapezoid. Ένα πλέγμα μέσα στη μορφή επιτρέπει στους 
σπουδαστές για να υπολογίσει την περιοχή οπτικά, κατόπιν έλεγχος
ενάντια στην πραγματική υπολογισμένη περιοχή. Το κείμενο 
στη σελίδα δίνει τρεις διαφορετικούς τρόπους να υπολογιστεί η 
περιοχή με έναν τύπο για κάθε έναν. Το applet 
χρησιμοποιεί μιας από τις μεθόδους για να υπολογίσει την περιοχή 
στον πραγματικό χρόνο, έτσι αλλάζει όπως trapezoid 
αναδιαμορφώνεται με το ποντίκι. Μια σελίδα συντρόφων είναι 
http://www.mathopenref.com/trapezoid.html εμφανίζοντας τον 
καθορισμό και οι ιδιότητες trapezoid Applet μπορούν να 
διευρυνθούν στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με έναν 
προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο 
σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε 
ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια 
εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς 
είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος εγχειριδίων 
γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un Web page y un applet interactivo que muestran 
las maneras de calcular el área de un trapezoide. El utilizador
puede arrastrar las cimas del trapezoide y del otro cambio de las 
puntas automáticamente para asegurarle un trapezoide del restos. 
Una rejilla dentro de la dimensión de una variable permite que 
los estudiantes estimen el área visualmente, después controla contra
el área computada real. El texto en la paginación da tres 
diversas maneras de calcular el área con un fórmula para cada uno. 
El applet utiliza uno de los métodos para computar el área en 
tiempo real, así que cambia mientras que el trapezoide se restructura
con el ratón. Una paginación del compañero es 
http://www.mathopenref.com/trapezoid.html que muestra que la 
definición y las características de un applet del trapezoide se 
pueden agrandar a la talla de la pantalla completa para el uso con un 
proyector de la sala de clase. El uso posterior en la sala de 
clase, estudiante puede tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier web 
browser en el país o en la biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. 
Este recurso es un componente del proyecto interactivo del libro
de textos de la geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas
en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209935</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108762</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/area-of-a-trapezoid-definition-and-formula</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
