<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103735</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103735</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087099</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"They Live Well in the Time of their Service": George Alsop Writes of Servants in Maryland, 1663</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"sie leben gut in der Zeit ihres Services": 
George Alsop schreibt von den Bediensteten in Maryland, 1663</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"ils vivent bien dans la période de leur service"
: George Alsop écrit des domestiques dans le Maryland, 
1663</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"vivem bem na época de seu serviço": 
George Alsop escreve dos empregados em Maryland, 1663</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"vivono bene nel periodo del loro servizio": 
George Alsop scrive dei servi in Maryland, 1663</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ζουν καλά στο χρόνο της υπηρεσίας τουσ": 
Θ*Γεοργε Alsop Writes των υπαλλήλων στη Μέρυλαντ, 
1663</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"viven bien en la época de su servicio": 
George Alsop escribe de criados en Maryland, 1663</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Lord Baltimore established the colony of Maryland in the upper part of Chesapeake Bay in the early 1630s as a refuge for his fellow Catholics. Baltimore's plans for a feudal system with labor performed by tenant farmers, along with many of the colonists' other high expectations, proved impossible to establish. The tobacco boom and offers of free land to Protestant and Catholic alike drew thousands of English immigrants to Virginia and Maryland. Over three quarters of the migrants to the seventeenth-century Chesapeake arrived as indentured servants, financing their passage by signing indentures, or contracts, for four to seven years labor. Most had agricultural backgrounds and were also fleeing poverty and unemployment in  England . George Alsop was one such indentured servant, probably with experience as an artisan or mechanic. He offered an account that boasted of the favorable situation for servants, especially women, to counter other writers who compared conditions in the Chesapeake to slavery.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lord Baltimore stellte die Kolonie von Maryland im
oberen Teil der Chesapeake-Bucht im frühen 1630s als Schutz für 
seine Gefährtekatholischen her. Pläne Baltimores für ein 
Feudalsystem mit Arbeit führten durch Pachtbauern, zusammen mit 
vielen anderer hoher Erwartungen der Kolonisten, prüften unmögliches
herzustellen durch. Die Tabakhochkonjunktur und die Angebote des
freien Landes zu protestierendem und katholischem gleich zeichneten 
Tausenden der englischen Immigranten zu Virginia und zu Maryland. 
Über drei Vierteln der Wanderer zum Seventeenthjahrhundert kam 
der Chesapeake wie indentured die Bediensteten an und finanzierte 
ihren Durchgang, indem er errichtete Urkunden unterzeichnete, oder 
Verträge, für vier bis sieben Jahre bearbeiten. Die meisten 
hatten landwirtschaftliche Hintergründe und flohen auch Armut und 
Arbeitslosigkeit in England. George Alsop war eins, das so 
Bediensteten indentured, vermutlich mit Erfahrung als Handwerker oder 
Mechaniker. Er bot ein Konto, das der vorteilhaften Situation 
für Bedienstete sich rühmte, besonders Frauen an, um anderen 
Verfassern zu widersprechen, die Bedingungen im Chesapeake mit 
Sklaverei verglichen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Seigneur Baltimore a établi la colonie du 
Maryland dans la partie supérieure du compartiment de chesapeake dans
le 1630s tôt comme refuge pour ses catholiques de camarade. Les
plans de Baltimore pour un système féodal avec le travail ont 
exécuté par des exploitants-locataires, avec plusieurs d'autres 
espérances élevées des colons, ont prouvé impossible pour 
établir. La perche de tabac et les offres de la terre libre à 
semblable protestant et catholique ont dessiné des milliers 
d'immigrés anglais à la Virginie et au Maryland. Plus de trois
quarts des migrants au dix-septième-siècle le chesapeake est arrivé
comme indentured des domestiques, finançant leur passage en signant 
des contrat synallagmatique bilatéraux, ou les contrats, pendant 
quatre à sept années travaillent. Les la plupart ont eu les 
milieux agricoles et se sauvaient également la pauvreté et le 
chômage en Angleterre. George Alsop était un que tels 
indentured l'domestique, probablement avec l'expérience en tant qu'un
artisan ou mécanicien. Il a offert un compte qui s'est vanté 
de la situation favorable pour des domestiques, particulièrement 
femmes, pour parer d'autres auteurs qui ont comparé des conditions 
dans le chesapeake à l'esclavage.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O senhor Baltimore estabeleceu a colônia de 
Maryland na parte superior da baía de chesapeake no 1630s adiantado 
como um refúgio para seus catholics do companheiro. As plantas 
de Baltimore para um sistema feudal com trabalho executaram por 
fazendeiros de tenant, junto com muitas de outras expectativas 
elevadas dos colonos, provaram impossível estabelecer. O 
crescimento do tabaco e as ofertas da terra livre a semelhante 
protestant e catholic desenharam milhares de immigrants ingleses a 
Virgínia e a Maryland. Sobre três quartos dos emigrantes ao 
décimo-século o chesapeake chegou como indentured os empregados, 
financiando sua passagem assinando indentures, ou os contratos, por 
quatro a sete anos trabalham. A maioria tiveram fundos 
agriculturais e fujiam também a pobreza e o desemprego em Inglaterra.
George Alsop era um que tais indentured o empregado, 
provavelmente com experiência como um artisan ou um mecânico. 
Ofereceu um cliente que boasted da situação favorável para 
empregados, especial mulheres, opôr outros escritores que compararam 
condições no chesapeake ao slavery.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il signore Baltimora ha stabilito la colonia di 
Maryland nella parte superiore della baia di chesapeake nel 1630s 
iniziale come rifugio per i suoi cattolici del collega. I 
programmi de Baltimora per un sistema feudal con il lavoro hanno
effettuato dagli affittuarii, con molte di altre alte aspettative dei 
colonizzatori, hanno dimostrato impossible stabilire. L'asta del
tabacco e le offerte di terra libera a simile protestante e cattolico 
hanno dissipato i migliaia degli immigranti inglesi alla Virginia ed a
Maryland. Oltre tre quarti dei migranti al 
diciassettesimo-secolo il chesapeake è arrivato come indentured 
servi, finanzianti il loro passaggio firmando i indentures, o i 
contratti, per di lavoro quattro - sette anni. La maggior 
parte hanno avuti ambiti di provenienza agricoli ed egualmente stavano
fuggendo la povertà e la disoccupazione in Inghilterra. George 
Alsop era uno che tali indentured il servo, probabilmente con 
esperienza come un artigianale o meccanico. Ha offerto un 
cliente che si è vantato della situazione favorevole per i servi, 
particolarmente donne, per ricambiare altri produttori che hanno 
confrontato i termini nel chesapeake a slavery.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο Λόρδος Baltimore καθιέρωσε την αποικία της 
Μέρυλαντ στο ανώτερο μέρος chesapeake του κόλπου στο πρόωρο 
1630s ως καταφύγιο για τους συντροφικούς Καθολικούς του. 
Τα σχέδια της Βαλτιμόρης για ένα φεουδαρχικό σύστημα με την
εργασία που εκτελέσθηκε από τους αγρότες μισθωτών, μαζί με 
πολλές από τις άλλες υψηλές προσδοκίες των αποίκων, 
αποδείχθηκαν αδύνατα να καθιερώσουν. Ο βραχίονας καπνών και
οι προσφορές του ελεύθερου εδάφους προτεσταντικό και καθολικό σε 
όμοιο έσυραν χιλιάδες αγγλικοί μετανάστες στη Βιρτζίνια και τη 
Μέρυλαντ. Πάνω από τρία τέταρτα των μεταναστών 
chesapeake δέκατος-αιώνα έφθασαν όπως υπάλληλοι, που 
χρηματοδοτούν τη μετάβασή τους με την υπογραφή των indentures, 
ή των συμβάσεων, για τέσσερα έως επτά έτη εργασίας. Οι 
περισσότεροι είχαν τα γεωργικά υπόβαθρα και έφευγαν επίσης την 
ένδεια και την ανεργία στην Αγγλία. Θ*Γεοργε Alsop ήταν 
ένα τέτοιοι ο υπάλληλος, πιθανώς με την εμπειρία ως 
χειροτεχνικός ή μηχανικός. Πρόσφερε έναν απολογισμό που 
καυχήθηκε της ευνοϊκής κατάστασης για τους υπαλλήλους, ειδικά 
γυναίκες, για να αντιμετωπίσει άλλους συγγραφείς που σύγκριναν 
τους όρους chesapeake με τη σκλαβιά.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Señor Baltimore estableció a colonia de Maryland
en la parte superior de la bahía de chesapeake en el 1630s temprano 
como refugio para sus católicos del compañero. Los planes de 
Baltimore para un sistema feudal con el trabajo se realizaron por los 
granjeros de arrendatario, junto con muchas de otras altas 
expectativas de los colonos, probaron imposible establecer. El 
auge del tabaco y las ofertas de la pista libre a semejante 
protestante y católico trazaron a millares de inmigrantes ingleses a 
Virginia y a Maryland. Sobre tres cuartos de los nómadas al 
decimose'ptimo-siglo el chesapeake llegó como indentured los criados,
financiando su paso firmando contratos, o los contratos, por cuatro a 
siete años trabajan. La mayoría tenían fondos agrícolas y 
también huían pobreza y el desempleo en Inglaterra. George 
Alsop era uno que tal indentured a criado, probablemente con 
experiencia como un artesano o mecánico. Él ofreció una 
cuenta que se jactó de la situación favorable para los criados, 
especialmente mujeres, para contradecir a otros programas de escritura
que compararon condiciones en el chesapeake a la esclavitud.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087099</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103735</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/they-live-well-in-the-time-of-their-service-george-alsop-writes-of-servants-in-maryland-1663</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
