<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105098</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105098</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086207</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Good Neighbors and Bad: Religious Differences on the Plains in the Early 20th century</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gute Nachbarn und Schlechtes: Fromme 
Unterschiede auf den Ebenen im frühen 20. Jahrhundert</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bons voisins et mauvais : Différences 
religieuses sur les plaines en début du 20ème siècle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Vizinhos bons e bad: Diferenças religiosas 
nas planícies no 20o século adiantado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Buoni vicinoi e Male: Differenze religiose 
sulle pianure nell'inizio del 20esimo secolo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Καλοί γείτονες και κακός: Θρησκευτικές διαφορές
στις πεδιάδες στις αρχές του 20ού αιώνα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Buenos vecinos y malo: Diferencias religiosas
en los llanos en el vigésimo siglo temprano</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The harmony of rural life is often romanticized, but differences among neighbors, whether ethnic, religious or political, could often lead to tension, especially as new groups emigrated west. Ezra and Dan Miller were born in a sod house in North Dakota but migrated with a group of Amish Mennonites to Montana. In this 1981 interview, conducted by Laurie Mercier for the Montana Historical Society, they described how local cowboys reacted to the influx of Amish farmers.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Harmonie der landwirtschaftlichen Lebensdauer 
ist romanticized häufig, aber Unterschiede unter Nachbarn, ob 
ethnisch, fromm oder politisch, konnten zu Spannkraft, besonders als 
neue Gruppen häufig führen auswanderten nach Westen. Ezra und 
Dan Miller wurden getragen, in einem Grasschollehaus in North Dakota 
aber fortgezogen mit einer Gruppe von amischem Mennonites nach 
Montana. In diesem Interview 1981 geleitet worden mit Laurie 
Mercier für die Montana historische Gesellschaft, beschrieben sie, 
wie lokale Cowboys zum Zufluß der amischen Landwirte reagierten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'harmonie de la vie rurale est romanticized 
souvent, mais les différences parmi des voisins, si ethniques, 
religieuses ou politiques, pourraient souvent mener à la tension, 
particulièrement en tant que nouveaux groupes ont émigré à 
l'ouest. Ezra et Dan Miller ont été soutenus dans une maison 
de gazon au Dakota du nord mais passés avec un groupe de 
Mennonites amish vers le Montana. Dans cette entrevue 1981, 
conduite par Laurie Mercier pour la société historique du Montana, 
ils ont décrit comment les cowboys locaux ont réagi à l'afflux des 
fermiers amish.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A harmonia da vida rural é romanticized 
frequentemente, mas as diferenças entre vizinhos, se étnicas, 
religiosas ou políticas, poderiam frequentemente conduzir à tensão,
especial como grupos novos emigrated para o oeste. Ezra e Dan 
Moleiro foram carregados em uma casa do sod em dakota norte mas 
migrados com um grupo de Mennonites amish a Montana. Nesta 
entrevista 1981, conduzida por Laurie Mercier para a sociedade 
histórica de Montana, descreveram como os vaqueiros locais reagiram 
ao influx de fazendeiros amish.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'armonia di vita rurale è spesso romanticized, 
ma le differenze fra i vicinoi, se etniche, religiose o politiche, 
potrebbero condurre spesso a tensionamento, particolarmente come nuovi
gruppi hanno emigrato verso ovest. Ezra e Dan Mugnaio sono stati
sopportati in una casa della piota nel Dakota del Nord ma sono stati 
migrati con un gruppo di Mennonites amish nel Montana. In questa
intervista 1981, condotta da Laurie Mercier per la società storica 
del Montana, hanno descritto come i cowboys locali hanno reagito 
all'afflusso dei coltivatori amish.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η αρμονία της αγροτικής ζωής είναι συχνά, αλλά 
διαφορές μεταξύ των γειτόνων, είτε εθνικών, θρησκευτικών είτε 
πολιτικών, θα μπορούσε συχνά να οδηγήσει στην ένταση, ειδικά ως 
νέες ομάδες μετανάστευσε δύση. Το Ezra και Dan 
Miller γεννήθηκαν σε ένα σπίτι γρασιδιών στη βόρεια Ντακότα 
αλλά μετανάστευσαν με μια ομάδα Amish Mennonites στη 
Μοντάνα. Σε αυτήν την συνέντευξη του 1981, που 
πραγματοποιήθηκε από Laurie Mercier για την ιστορική 
κοινωνία της Μοντάνα, περιέγραψαν πώς οι τοπικοί κάουμπου! 
αντέδρασαν στην εισροή των αγροτών Amish.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La armonía de la vida rural es romanticized a 
menudo, solamente las diferencias entre vecinos, es étnica, religioso
o político, podría conducir a menudo a la tensión, especialmente 
como nuevos grupos emigrados al oeste. Ezra y Dan 
Molinero fueron llevados en una casa del césped en Dakota del Norte 
pero emigrados con un grupo de Mennonites amish a Montana. En 
esta entrevista 1981, conducida por Laurie Mercier para la sociedad 
histórica de Montana, describieron cómo los vaqueros locales 
reaccionaron a la afluencia de granjeros amish.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086207</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105098</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/good-neighbors-and-bad-religious-differences-on-the-plains-in-the-early-20th-century</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
