<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108655</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108655</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086706</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Our Misery and Despair": Kearney Blasts Chinese Immigration</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"unser Elend und Verzweiflung": Kearney 
Sprengt Chinesische Immigration</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"notre misère et désespoir" : Kearney 
Souffle l'Immigration Chinoise</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"nossos miséria e desespero": Kearney 
Explode O Immigration Chinês</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la nostre miseria e disperazione": Kearney 
Fa saltare L'Immigrazione Cinese</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η δυστυχία και η απελπισία μασ": Το Kearney 
ανατινάζει την κινεζική μετανάστευση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"nuestra miseria y desesperación": Kearney 
Arruina La Inmigración China</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Anti-Asian agitation characterized politics in the American West, particularly labor politics, in the late-19th century. Labor leaders like Denis Kearney and H. L. Knight of California's Workingmen's Party often resorted to popular racist arguments to justify the exclusion of Chinese immigrants. In this 1878 address, Kearney and Knight described the Chinese as a race of "cheap working slaves" who undercut American living standards and thus should be banished from America's shores. While rare, some in the labor movement challenged the racist appeals of leaders like Kearney and Knight.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Anti-Asiatische Bewegung kennzeichnete Politik im 
amerikanischen Westen, besonders Arbeitspolitik, im des späten 19. 
jahrhunderts Jahrhundert. Gewerkschaftsführer wie Denis Kearney
und H. L. Knight der Partei der Workingmens Kaliforniens 
griffen häufig auf populäre rassistische Argumente zurück, um den 
Ausschluß der chinesischen Immigranten auszuschließen. In 
dieser Adresse 1878 beschrieben Kearney und Ritter die Chinesen, wie 
ein Rennen "des preiswerten Arbeitens" schuftet, wer amerikanische 
lebende Standards unterschneiden und von den Ufern Amerikas folglich 
verbannt werden sollten. Wenn selten, forderten einige in der 
Arbeiterbewegung die rassistischen Anklänge der Führer wie Kearney 
und des Ritters heraus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'agitation Anti-Asiatique a caractérisé la 
politique dans l'ouest américain, en particulier la politique de 
travail, en fin du 19me siècle. Les dirigeants syndicaux comme 
Denis Kearney et H. L. Knight de la partie des ouvriers de la 
Californie ont souvent recouru aux arguments racistes populaires pour 
justifier l'exclusion des immigrés chinois. Dans cette adresse 
1878, Kearney et chevalier ont décrit les Chinois comme une course 
"de travailler bon marché asservit" qui dégagent des normes vivantes
américaines et devraient être banis ainsi des rivages de 
l'Amérique. Tandis que rares, certains dans le mouvement de 
travail ont défié les appels racistes des amorces comme Kearney et 
du chevalier.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O agitation Anti-anti-Asian caracterizou a 
política no oeste americano, particularmente política labor, no 
século late-19th. Os líderes labor como Denis Kearney e H. L. 
Knight do partido dos workingmen de Califórnia recorreram 
frequentemente aos argumentos racist populares para justificar a 
exclusão de immigrants chineses. Neste endereço 1878, Kearney 
e o knight descreveram os chineses como uma raça "de trabalhar barato
slaves" quem undercut padrões vivos americanos e assim devem banished
das costas de América. Quando raros, alguns no movimento labor 
desafiaram as apelações racist dos líderes como Kearney e do 
knight.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'agitazione Anti-Asiatica ha caratterizzato la 
politica nell'ovest americano, specialmente politica di lavoro, nel 
fine del 19esimo secolo. I capi di lavoro come Denis 
Kearney e H. L. Knight del partito dei workingmen della California 
hanno ricorso spesso agli argomenti razzisti popolari per giustificare
l'esclusione degli immigranti cinesi. In questo indirizzo 
1878, Kearney ed il cavaliere hanno descritto il cinese come una 
corsa "di funzionamento poco costoso assoggetta" chi tagliano gli 
standard viventi americani e dovrebbero banished così dai puntelli 
dell'America. Mentre rari, alcuni nel movimento di lavoro hanno
sfidato gli appelli razzisti dei capi come Kearney e del 
cavaliere.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αντι-ασιατικά η αναταραχή χαρακτήρισε την πολιτική 
στην αμερικανική δύση, ιδιαίτερα πολιτική εργασίας, στο 
late-19th αιώνα. Οι ηγέτες εργασίας όπως Denis 
Kearney και Χ. Λ. Knight του συμβαλλόμενου μέρους 
Workingmen Καλιφόρνιας προσέφυγαν συχνά στα δημοφιλή 
ρατσιστικά ορίσματα να δικαιολογηθεί ο αποκλεισμός των κινεζικών 
μεταναστών. Σε αυτήν την διεύθυνση 1878, Kearney και ο 
ιππότης περιέγραψαν τους Κινέζους ως φυλή των "φτηνών 
εργαζόμενων σκλάβων" ποιοι περικόπτουν το αμερικανικό βιοτικό 
επίπεδο και πρέπει έτσι να είναι από τις ακτές της Αμερικής. 
Ενώ σπάνιοι, μερικοί στη μετακίνηση εργασίας προκάλεσαν 
τις ρατσιστικές εκκλήσεις των ηγετών όπως Kearney και του 
ιππότη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La agitación Contra-Asia'tica caracterizó la 
política en el oeste americano, determinado política de trabajo, en 
el siglo de fines del siglo diecinueve. Los arranques de cinta 
de trabajo como Denis Kearney y H. L. Knight del partido de los 
workingmen de California recurrieron a menudo a los argumentos racist 
populares para alinear la exclusión de inmigrantes chinos. En 
este direccionamiento 1878, Kearney y el caballero describieron a 
chinos como esclaviza una raza del "trabajo barato" quiénes socavan 
estándares vivos americanos y se deben banished así de las orillas 
de América. Mientras que son raros, algunos en el movimiento de
trabajo desafiaron las súplicas racist de arranques de cinta como 
Kearney y del caballero.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086706</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108655</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/our-misery-and-despair-kearney-blasts-chinese-immigration</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
