<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106603</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106603</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087322</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"A Most Awkward, Ridiculous Appearance": Benjamin Franklin Enters Philadelphia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Ein Unbeholfenstes, Lächerlichstes Aussehen": 
Benjamin Franklin Betritt Philadelphia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Un Aspect Le plus maladroit et Le plus ridicule" :
Benjamin Franklin Entre dans Philadelphie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Uma Aparência A mais inábil, A mais ridiculous":
Benjamin Franklin Entra Em Filadélfia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Un'Apparenza La più scomoda E La più 
ridiculous": Benjamin Franklin Entra In Filadelfia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Μια πιό αδέξια, γελοία εμφάνιση": Θ*Ψενιαμην 
Franklin Enters Φιλαδέλφεια</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Un Aspecto Más torpe, Más ridículo": 
Benjamin Franklin Entra en Philadelphia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">When Boston native Benjamin Franklin entered Philadelphia in 1723, he had few coins in his pocket and scarce entrepreneurial skills. However, Franklin did have valuable training as a printer, and he came armed with some significant introductions to local printers. Printers and other craftsmen relied upon a network of masters, journeymen, and patrons to learn the craft and support themselves. Colonial printers needed expensive imported equipment, yet they had to make do with a limited market for their services--perhaps publishing a newspaper, an occasional pamphlet, or government publication. Franklin wrote his autobiography, from which this account is excerpted, many years after his career as an active printer had ended and his renown as a statesmen, scientist, and moral philosopher had spread.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Als Boston gebürtiger Benjamin Franklin 
Philadelphia 1723 kam, hatte er wenige Münzen in seiner Tasche und in
knappen unternehmerischen Fähigkeiten. Jedoch hatte Franklin 
wertvolles Training als Drucker, und er kam bewaffnet mit etwas 
bedeutenden Einleitungen zu den lokalen Druckern. Drucker und 
andere Handwerker bauten auf ein Netz der Meister, der Facharbeiter 
und der Gönner, um die Fertigkeit zu erlernen und sich zu 
unterstützen. Kolonialdrucker benötigten kostspielige 
importierte Ausrüstung, dennoch mußten sie mit einem begrenzt 
aufnahmefähigen Markt für ihre Dienstleistungen sich zufriedengeben 
-- eine Zeitung, eine gelegentliche Flugschrift oder Regierung 
Publikation möglicherweise, veröffentlichend. Franklin schrieb
seine Autobiographie, von der dieses Konto excerptiert wird, viele 
Jahre nach seiner Karriere, da ein aktiver Drucker und sein 
Renommee beendet hatte, während Staatsmänner, Wissenschaftler 
und moralischer Philosoph verbritten hatten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Quand Boston Benjamin indigène Franklin est 
entré dans Philadelphie en 1723, il a eu peu de pièces de monnaie 
dans sa poche et qualifications entreprenantes rares. Cependant,
Franklin a eu la formation valable comme imprimante, et il est venu 
armé avec quelques introductions significatives aux imprimantes 
locales. Les imprimantes et d'autres artisans ont compté sur un
réseau des maîtres, des compagnons, et des patrons pour apprendre le
métier et pour se supporter. Les imprimantes coloniales ont eu 
besoin de matériel importé cher, pourtant elles ont dû se contenter
d'un marché limité pour leurs services -- peut-être éditant un 
journal, une brochure occasionnelle, ou la publication de 
gouvernement. Franklin a écrit son autobiographie, dont ce 
compte est extrait, beaucoup d'années après sa carrière car une 
imprimante active avait terminé et sa renommée pendant que les 
hommes d'État, le scientifique, et le philosophe moral avaient écarté.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quando Boston Benjamin nativo Franklin entrou em 
Filadélfia em 1723, teve poucas moedas em seus bolso e habilidades 
entrepreneurial escassas. Entretanto, Franklin teve o 
treinamento valioso como uma impressora, e veio armado com algumas 
introduções significativas às impressoras locais. As 
impressoras e outros artesãos confiaram em uma rede dos mestres, dos 
journeymen, e dos patrons para aprender o ofício e para suportar-se. 
As impressoras coloniais necessitaram o equipamento importado 
caro, contudo tiveram que contentar de um mercado limitado para seus 
serviços -- talvez publicando um jornal, um panfleto ocasional, ou a 
publicação do governo. Franklin escreveu seu autobiography, de
que este cliente excerpted, muitos anos após sua carreira porque uma 
impressora ativa tinha terminado e seu renown enquanto os statesmen, o
cientista, e o filósofo moral tinham espalhado.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Quando Boston Benjamin natale Franklin ha 
entrato in Filadelfia in 1723, ha avuto poche monete nella sue tasca 
ed abilità imprenditoriali limitate. Tuttavia, Franklin ha 
avuto addestramento importante come stampante ed è venuto munito con 
alcune introduzioni significative alle stampanti locali. I 
tipografi ed altri artigiani hanno contato su una rete dei 
supervisori, degli operai qualificati e dei patroni per imparare il 
mestiere e per sostenersi. Le stampanti coloniali hanno avuto 
bisogno dell'apparecchiatura importata costosa, tuttavia hanno dovuto 
accontentarsi di un mercato limitato per i loro servizi -- forse 
pubblicando un giornale, un opuscolo occasionale, o la pubblicazione 
di governo. Franklin ha scritto il suo autobiography, da cui 
questo cliente è stralciato, molti anni dopo la sua carriera poichè 
una stampante attiva si era conclusa ed il suo renown mentre gli 
statisti, lo scienziato ed il filosofo morale si erano sparsi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Όταν η Βοστώνη εγγενής Benjamin Franklin μπήκε 
στη Φιλαδέλφεια το 1723, είχε λίγα νομίσματα στην τσέπη και 
τις λιγοστές επιχειρηματικές δεξιότητές του. Εντούτοις, 
Franklin είχε την πολύτιμη κατάρτιση ως εκτυπωτή, και ήρθε 
οπλισμένος με μερικές σημαντικές εισαγωγές στους τοπικούς 
εκτυπωτές. Οι εκτυπωτές και άλλοι βιοτέχνες στηρίχθηκαν 
επάνω σε ένα δίκτυο των κυρίων, των τεχνιτών, και των προστατών 
για να μάθουν την τέχνη και να υποστηριχθούν. Οι αποικιακοί 
εκτυπωτές χρειάστηκαν τον ακριβό εισαγόμενο εξοπλισμό, όμως 
έπρεπε να αρκεσθούν σε μια περιορισμένη αγορά για τις υπηρεσίες 
τους -- ίσως δημοσιεύοντας μια εφημερίδα, ένα περιστασιακό 
τεύχος, ή την κυβερνητική δημοσίευση. Το Franklin έγραψε
την αυτοβιογραφία του, από την οποία αυτός ο απολογισμός είναι, 
πολλά έτη μετά από τη σταδιοδρομία του δεδομένου ότι ένας 
ενεργός εκτυπωτής είχε τελειώσει και η φήμη του ως τους 
πολιτικούς, επιστήμονας, και ο ηθικός φιλόσοφος είχε διαδώσει.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cuando Boston Benjamin nativo Franklin entró en 
Philadelphia en 1723, él tenía pocas monedas en su bolsillo y 
habilidades emprendedoras escasas. Sin embargo, Franklin tenía 
entrenamiento valioso como impresora, y él vino armado con algunas 
introducciones significativas a las impresoras locales. Las 
impresoras y otros artesanos confiaron en una red de amos, de 
oficiales, y de patrón para aprender el arte y para utilizarse. 
Las impresoras coloniales necesitaron el equipo importado 
costoso, con todo tuvieron que conformar con un mercado limitado para 
sus servicios -- quizás publicando un periódico, un folleto 
ocasional, o la publicación del gobierno. Franklin escribió su
autobiografía, de la cual se extracta esta cuenta, muchos años 
después de su carrera pues una impresora activa había terminado y su
renombre mientras que los estadistas, el científico, y el filósofo
moral se habían separado.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087322</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106603</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-most-awkward-ridiculous-appearance-benjamin-franklin-enters-philadelphia</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
