<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107015</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107015</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213126</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">We're in Hot Water Now: Hydrothermal Vents</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wir sind im Heißwasser jetzt: Hydrothermale
Entlüftungsöffnungen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Nous sommes en eau chaude maintenant : 
Évents Hydrothermiques</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nós estamos na água quente agora: 
Respiradouros Hydrothermal</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Siamo ora in acqua calda: Sfiati 
Idrotermali</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Είμαστε στο καυτό ύδωρ τώρα: Υδροθερμικές 
διέξοδοι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ahora estamos en agua caliente: Respiraderos
Hidrotérmicos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this National Geographic lesson, students will use National Geographic's Yellowstone internet module to learn about the processes that drive geysers. The activity involves learning about hydrothermal vents and uniquely adapted animals that live near the vents with the aid of pictures and maps. The activity concludes with an opportunity to create an aquarium exhibit which showcases some of these animals and their special adaptations. The website also includes related links and extensions for the project.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In dieser nationalen geographischen Lektion 
benutzen Kursteilnehmer nationales geographisches Yellowstone 
Internet-Modul, um über die Prozesse zu erlernen, die Geysire 
antreiben. Die Aktivität bezieht mit ein, über hydrothermale 
Entlüftungsöffnungen und eindeutig angepaßte Tiere zu erlernen, die
nahe den Entlüftungsöffnungen mit dem Hilfsmittel der Abbildungen 
und der Karten leben. Die Aktivität folgert mit einer 
Gelegenheit, eine Aquariumausstellung zu erstellen, die einige dieser 
Tiere und ihrer speziellen Anpassungen zur Schau stellt. Die Web
site schließt auch in Verbindung stehende Links und Extensionen für 
das Projekt ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cette leçon géographique nationale, les 
étudiants utiliseront le module géographique national d'Internet de 
Yellowstone pour se renseigner sur les processus qui pilotent des 
geysers. L'activité implique de se renseigner sur les évents 
hydrothermiques et les animaux seulement adaptés qui vivent près des
évents à l'aide des images et des cartes. L'activité conclut 
avec une occasion de créer un objet exposé d'aquarium qui présente 
certains de ces animaux et de leurs adaptations spéciales. Le 
site Web inclut également des liens et des extensions relatifs pour 
le projet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta lição geográfica nacional, os estudantes 
usarão o módulo geográfico nacional do Internet de Yellowstone 
aprender sobre os processos que dirigem geysers. A atividade 
envolve aprender sobre os respiradouros hydrothermal e os animais 
excepcionalmente adaptados que vivem perto dos respiradouros com o dae
(dispositivo automático de entrada) dos retratos e dos mapas. A
atividade concli com uma oportunidade de criar uma exibição do 
aquário que showcases algumas destes animais e de suas adaptações 
especiais. O Web site inclui também as ligações e extensões 
relacionadas para o projeto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questa lezione geografica nazionale, gli 
allievi utilizzeranno il modulo geografico nazionale del Internet di 
Yellowstone per imparare circa i processi che guidano i geyser. 
L'attività coinvolge imparare circa gli sfiati idrotermali e 
gli animali unicamente adattati che vivono vicino agli sfiati con 
l'aiuto delle immagini e dei programmi. L'attività conclude con
un'occasione creare un'esposizione dell'acquario che montra 
alcuni di questi animali e dei loro adattamenti speciali. Il Web
site egualmente include i collegamenti e le estensioni relativi per il
progetto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτό το εθνικό γεωγραφικό μάθημα, οι σπουδαστές θα
χρησιμοποιήσουν την εθνική γεωγραφική ενότητα Yellowstone 
Διαδίκτυο που μαθαίνει για τις διαδικασίες που οδηγούν geysers.
Η δραστηριότητα περιλαμβάνει την εκμάθηση για τις 
υδροθερμικές διεξόδους και τα μεμονωμένα προσαρμοσμένα ζώα που 
ζουν κοντά στις διεξόδους με την ενίσχυση των εικόνων και των 
χαρτών. Η δραστηριότητα ολοκληρώνει με μια ευκαιρία να 
δημιουργηθεί ένα έκθεμα ενυδρείων που επιδεικνύει μερικών από 
αυτά τα ζώα και τις ειδικές προσαρμογές τους. Ο ιστοχώρος 
περιλαμβάνει επίσης τις σχετικές συνδέσεις και τις επεκτάσεις για
το πρόγραμμα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta lección geográfica nacional, los 
estudiantes utilizarán el módulo geográfico nacional del Internet 
de Yellowstone para aprender sobre los procesos que conducen los 
géiseres. La actividad implica el aprender sobre los 
respiraderos hidrotérmicos y los animales únicamente adaptados que 
viven cerca de los respiraderos con la ayuda de cuadros y de 
correspondencias. La actividad concluye con una oportunidad de 
crear un objeto expuesto del acuario que showcases algunas de estos 
animales y de sus adaptaciones especiales. El Web site también 
incluye conexiones y las extensiones relacionadas para el proyecto.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:NATIONAL GEOGRAPHIC XPEDITIONS
FN:NATIONAL GEOGRAPHIC XPEDITIONS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213126</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107015</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/were-in-hot-water-now-hydrothermal-vents</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
