<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105390</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105390</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205856</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Huntington Archive of Buddhist and Related Art</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Huntington Archiv der buddhistischen und in 
Verbindung stehenden kunst</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Archives de Huntington d'art bouddhiste et 
relatif</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Arquivo de Huntington da arte buddhist e 
relacionada</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Archivio di Huntington di arte buddista e 
relativa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αρχείο Huntington της βουδιστικής και σχετικής 
τέχνης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Archivo de Huntington del arte budista y 
relacionado</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">contains nearly 300,000 slides and photos of Asian art and architecture. Materials are predominantly Buddhist but include Hindu, Jain, Islamic, and other works (dating back to 2500 BC). This archive is the most comprehensive collection of its kind. It includes the largest photo archive of Nepali art and architecture in the world and represents the only formal collection that photographically records Nepali's artistic heritage.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">enthält fast 300.000 Plättchen und Fotos 
asiatische kunst und Architektur. Materialien sind, überwiegend
buddhistisch aber enthalten Hindu, Jain, islamisch, und anderes 
arbeitet (BC zurückgehend bis 2500). Dieses Archiv ist die 
kompletteste Ansammlung seiner Art. Es enthält das größte 
Fotoarchiv der Nepali kunst und der Architektur in der Welt und stellt
die einzige formale Ansammlung dar, die photographisch Nepalis 
künstlerisches Erbe speichert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">contient presque 300.000 glissières et photos 
d'art et d'architecture asiatiques. Les matériaux sont 
principalement bouddhistes mais incluent l'hindou, Jain, islamique, et
autre fonctionne (remontant à 2500 BC). Ces archives sont la 
collection la plus complète de sa sorte. Elles incluent les 
plus grandes archives de photo de l'art et de l'architecture de Nepali
dans le monde et représentent la seule collection formelle qui 
enregistre photographiquement l'héritage artistique de Nepali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">contem quase 300.000 corrediças e fotos da arte e
da arquitetura asian. Os materiais são predominantly buddhist 
mas incluem o hindu, Jain, islamic, e outros trabalham (datando para 
trás a 2500 BC). Este arquivo é a coleção a mais detalhada 
de seu tipo. Inclui o arquivo o maior da foto da arte e da 
arquitetura de Nepali no mundo e representa a única coleção formal 
que grava fotogràfica o heritage artístico de Nepali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">contiene quasi 300.000 scorrevoli e foto dell'arte
e dell'architettura asiatiche. I materiali sono principalmente 
buddisti ma includono il hindu, Jain, islamico ed altro funziona 
(datando da 2500 BC). Questo archivio è l'accumulazione più 
completa del relativo genere. Include il più grande archivio 
della foto dell'arte e dell'architettura di Nepali nel mondo e 
rappresenta l'unica accumulazione convenzionale che registra 
fotograficamente l'eredità artistica del Nepali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">περιέχει σχεδόν 300.000 φωτογραφικές διαφάνειες και
φωτογραφίες της ασιατικών τέχνης και της αρχιτεκτονικής. Τα 
υλικά είναι κυρίως βουδιστικά αλλά περιλαμβάνουν ινδό, Jain,
ισλαμικούς, και άλλες εργασίες (που χρονολογούνται από 2500 
Π.Χ.). Αυτό το αρχείο είναι η περιεκτικότερη συλλογή του 
είδους του. Περιλαμβάνει το μεγαλύτερο αρχείο φωτογραφιών 
της τέχνης Nepali και της αρχιτεκτονικής στον κόσμο και 
αντιπροσωπεύει τη μόνη επίσημη συλλογή που καταγράφει 
φωτογραφικά την καλλιτεχνική κληρονομιά Nepali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">contiene casi 300.000 diapositivas y fotos de arte
y de configuración asiáticos. Los materiales son predominante 
budistas pero incluyen a hindu, Jain, islámico, y otro trabaja 
(fechando de nuevo a 2500 A.C.). Este archivo es la colección 
más comprensiva de su clase. Incluye el archivo más grande de 
la foto del arte y de la configuración de Nepali en el mundo y 
representa la única colección formal que registra fotográficamente 
la herencia artística de Nepali.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205856</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105390</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/huntington-archive-of-buddhist-and-related-art</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
