<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103610</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103610</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086396</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Laying Close Siege to the Enemy": Joseph Plumb Martin at the Battle of Yorktown, 1781</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">", nahe Belagerung zum Feind legend": Joseph
senkrechter Martin an der Schlacht von Yorktown, 1781</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"étendant le siège étroit à l'ennemi" : 
Joseph Martin à plomb à la bataille de Yorktown, 1781</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"colocando o siege próximo ao inimigo": 
Joseph Martin a prumo na batalha de Yorktown, 1781</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"ponendo siege vicino al nemico": Joseph 
Martin plumb alla battaglia di Yorktown, 1781</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Βάζοντας τη στενή πολιορκία στον εχθρό": 
Θ*Ιοσεπχ Plumb Martin στη μάχη Yorktown, 1781</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"poniendo sitio cercano al enemigo": José 
Martin vertical en la batalla de Yorktown, 1781</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the war for independence, the life of a common soldier was a rough one. Soldiers served relatively short periods in state militias or longer periods in the Continental Army, raised by Congress. About two hundred thousand men enlisted for one period or another. Militias supplied the greatest number of soldiers, comprised of farmers, artisans, and some professionals. The Continental Congress recruited the young and those with fewer resources, such as apprentices or laborers. Some enlisted voluntarily while others were drafted; the more affluent hired paid substitutes. All faced war's hardships of severe food shortages, discomfort, low morale, and danger. Joseph Plumb Martin, born in western Massachusetts, joined the militia in 1776 before his 16th birthday and served in the Continental Army from 1777 to 1783. In 1830, he wrote a colorful portrayal of the life of a common soldier,  Some of the Adventures, Dangers and Sufferings of a Revolutionary Soldier . In this excerpt, Plumb described the British surrender at Yorktown in October 1781.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im Krieg für Unabhängigkeit, war das Leben eines
gemeinen Soldaten ein rauhes. Soldaten dienten 
verhältnismäßig kurze Perioden in den Zustandmilizen oder längere 
Perioden in der kontinentalen Armee, angehoben von Congress. 
Ungefähr zweihundert tausend Männer trugen für eine Periode 
oder andere ein. Milizen gaben die größte Zahl Soldaten an, 
enthalten von den Landwirten, Handwerkern und einigen Fachleuten. 
Der kontinentale Kongreß zog die Junge und die mit wenigen 
Betriebsmitteln, wie Lehrlingen oder Arbeitern ein. Einige 
trugen freiwillig ein, während andere gezeichnet wurden; der 
reichlichere angestellte zahlende Ersatz. Alle stellten Härten 
des Krieges der strengen Nahrungsmittelmängel, der Unannehmlichkeit, 
der niedrigen Moral und der Gefahr gegenüber. Joseph 
senkrechter Martin, geboren in Westmassachusetts, verbunden der Miliz 
1776 vor seinem 16. Geburtstag und in der kontinentalen Armee von 1777
bis 1783 gedient. 1830 schrieb er eine bunte Schilderung des 
Lebens eines gemeinen Soldaten, der einiger der Abenteuer, der 
Gefahren und der Sufferings eines revolutionären Soldaten. In 
diesem Excerpt plombieren Sie beschrieben der britischen Auslieferung 
bei Yorktown im Oktober 1781.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans la guerre pour l'indépendance, la vie d'un 
soldat commun était rugueuse. Les soldats ont servi des 
périodes relativement courtes dans des milices d'état ou de plus 
longues périodes dans l'armée continentale, élevée par Congress. 
Environ deux cents mille hommes ont enrôlé pour une période 
ou une autre. Les milices ont fourni le plus grand nombre de 
soldats, consisté en les fermiers, d'artisans, et de quelques 
professionnels. Le congrès continental a recruté les jeunes et
ceux avec peu de ressources, telles que des apprentis ou des 
travailleurs. Certains ont enrôlé volontairement tandis que 
d'autres étaient dessinés ; les produits de remplacement 
payés loués plus riches. Tous ont fait face aux difficultés 
de la guerre des manques graves de nourriture, du malaise, du bas 
moral, et du danger. Joseph Martin à plomb, né dans le 
Massachusetts occidental, jointif la milice en 1776 avant son 16ème 
anniversaire et servi dans l'armée continentale de 1777 à 1783. 
En 1830, il a écrit une représentation colorée de la vie d'un
soldat commun, de certaines des aventures, des dangers et des douleurs
d'un soldat révolutionnaire. Dans cet extrait, mettez d'aplomb 
décrit la reddition britannique chez Yorktown en octobre 1781.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Na guerra para a independência, a vida de um 
soldado comum era áspera. Os soldados serviram a períodos 
relativamente curtos em milícias do estado ou a uns períodos mais 
longos no exército continental, levantado por Congress. 
Aproximadamente dois cem mil homens alistaram-se para um 
período ou outro. As milícias forneceram o número o mais 
grande dos soldados, compreendido dos fazendeiros, dos artisans, e dos
alguns profissionais. O congress continental recrutou os jovens 
e aqueles com poucos recursos, tais como aprendizes ou laborers. 
Alguns alistaram-se voluntàriamente quando outros foram 
esboçados; os substitutos pagos empregados mais afluentes. 
Todos enfrentaram hardships da guerra de faltas severas do 
alimento, de discomfort, do morale baixo, e do perigo. Joseph 
Martin a prumo, carregado em Massachusetts ocidental, juntado a 
milícia em 1776 antes de seu 1õ aniversário e servido no exército 
continental de 1777 a 1783. Em 1830, escreveu um portrayal 
colorido da vida de um soldado comum, de algumas das aventuras, de 
perigos e de sofrimentos de um soldado revolucionário. Neste 
excerpt, sonde descrito a rendição britânica em Yorktown em outubro
1781.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nella guerra per indipendenza, la vita di un 
soldato comune era di massima. I soldati hanno servito i periodi
relativamente corti dentro dichiarano le milizie o i periodi più
lunghi nell'esercito continentale, alzato di Congress. Circa 
duecento mila uomini hanno arruolato per un periodo o un altro. 
Le milizie hanno fornito il numero più grande di soldati, 
formato dai coltivatori, di artigianale e di alcuni professionisti. 
Il congresso continentale ha reclutato i giovani e quelli con 
poche risorse, quali gli apprendisti o i lavoratori. Alcuni 
hanno arruolato volontariamente mentre altri sono stati disegnati; 
i sostituti paid assunti più ricchi. Tutti hanno 
affrontato le difficoltà della guerra delle scarsità severe 
dell'alimento, del disagio, del morale basso e del pericolo. 
Joseph Martin plumb, sopportato in Massachusetts occidentale, 
unito la milizia in 1776 prima del suo sedicesimo compleanno e servito
nell'esercito continentale da 1777 a 1783. In 1830, ha scritto 
una rappresentazione colorful della vita di un soldato comune, alcune 
delle avventure, di pericoli e di sufferings di un soldato 
rivoluzionario. In questo brano, plumb descritto la resa 
britannica a Yorktown nel mese di ottobre del 1781.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στον πόλεμο για την ανεξαρτησία, η ζωή ενός κοινού 
στρατιώτη ήταν τραχιά. Οι στρατιώτες εξυπηρέτησαν τις 
σχετικά μικρές χρονικές περιόδους στις κρατικές πολιτοφυλακές ή
τις πιό μεγάλες περιόδους στον ηπειρωτικό στρατό, που αυξήθηκαν 
από το συνέδριο. Περίπου διακόσιες χιλιάες άτομα που 
στρατολογούνται για κάποια περίοδο. Οι πολιτοφυλακές 
παρείχαν το μέγιστο αριθμό στρατιωτών, που αποτελέσθηκε από τους
αγρότες, artisans, και μερικούς επαγγελματίες. Το 
ηπειρωτικό συνέδριο στρατολόγησε τις νεολαίες και εκείνους με 
λιγότερα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς, όπως οι μαθητευόμενοι ή τα 
laborers. Μερικοί στρατολόγησαν εθελοντικά ενώ άλλοι 
συντάχθηκαν  τα πιό εύπορα μισθωμένα πληρωμένα 
υποκατάστατα. Όλοι αντιμετώπισαν τις πολεμικές δυσκολίες 
των αυστηρών ελλείψεων τροφίμων, της ταλαιπωρίας, του χαμηλού 
ηθικού, και του κινδύνου. Θ*Ιοσεπχ Plumb Martin, 
γεννημένος στη δυτική Μασαχουσέτη, προσχώρησε στην πολιτοφυλακή 
το 1776 πριν από τα 16$α γενέθλιά του και εξυπηρέτησε στον 
ηπειρωτικό στρατό από 1777 έως 1783. Το 1830, 
έγραψε μια ζωηρόχρωμη απεικόνιση της ζωής ενός κοινού 
στρατιώτη, μερικές από τις περιπέτειες, των κινδύνων και των 
βασάνων ενός επαναστατικού στρατιώτη. Σε αυτό το 
απόσπασμα, το βαρίδι περιέγραψε τη βρετανική παράδοση σε 
Yorktown τον Οκτώβριο του 1781.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En la guerra para la independencia, la vida de un 
soldado común era áspera. Los soldados sirvieron períodos 
relativamente cortos en milicias del estado o períodos más largos en
el ejército continental, levantado por Congress. Cerca de 
doscientos mil hombres alistaron para un período u otro. Las 
milicias proveieron el número más grande de soldados, abarcado de 
granjeros, de artesanos, y de algunos profesionales. El congreso
continental reclutó los jóvenes y ésos con pocos recursos, tales 
como aprendices o trabajadores. Algunos alistaron 
voluntariamente mientras que otros fueron bosquejados; los 
substitutos pagados empleados más afluentes. Todos hicieron 
frente a las dificultades de la guerra de las escaseces severas del 
alimento, del malestar, de la moral baja, y del peligro. José 
Martin vertical, llevado en Massachusetts occidental, unido la milicia
en 1776 antes de su décimosexto cumpleaños y servido en el ejército
continental a partir de 1777 a 1783. En 1830, él escribió una 
representación colorida de la vida de un soldado común, de algo de 
las aventuras, de peligros y de sufrimientos de un soldado 
revolucionario. En este extracto, sondee descrito la entrega 
británica en Yorktown en octubre de 1781.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086396</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103610</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/laying-close-siege-to-the-enemy-joseph-plumb-martin-at-the-battle-of-yorktown-1781</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
