<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107212</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107212</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203636</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Learning about Climate</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lernen über Klima</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Se renseigner sur le climat</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Aprendizagem sobre o clima</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Imparando circa il clima</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εκμάθηση για το κλίμα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El aprender sobre clima</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site is the first in a series of websites by Geosource which provide general information about climate and past climates for K-5 teachers and students. The series provides a basic introduction to topics such as the difference between weather and climate, factors that effect climate, and what is a climate proxy (e.g. ice cores). The sites also feature colored illustrations and figures.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site ist die erste in einer Reihe von Web 
site durch Geosource, die allgemeine Informationen über Klima und 
hinter Klimata für Lehrer K-5 und Kursteilnehmer zur Verfügung 
stellen. Die Serie stellt eine grundlegende Einleitung zu den 
Themen wie dem Unterschied zwischen Wetter und Klima, Faktoren zur 
Verfügung, die Klima bewirken, und was eine Klimavollmacht ist (z.B. 
Eiskerne). Die Sites kennzeichnen auch farbige Abbildungen und 
Abbildungen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site est le premier dans une série de sites Web
par Geosource qui fournissent des informations générales au sujet du
climat et après des climats pour les professeurs K-5 et les 
étudiants. La série fournit une introduction de base aux 
sujets tels que la différence entre survit à et le climat, 
facteurs qui effectuent le climat, et ce qui est une procuration de 
climat (par exemple noyaux de glace). Les sites comportent 
également les illustrations et les figures colorées.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local é o primeiro em uma série dos Web site
por Geosource que fornecem a informação geral sobre o clima e após 
climas para os professores K-5 e os estudantes. A série fornece
uma introdução básica aos tópicos tais como a diferença entre o 
tempo e o clima, fatores que efetuam o clima, e o que é um proxy do 
clima (por exemplo núcleos do gelo). Os locais caracterizam 
também ilustrações e figuras coloridas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo è il primo di una serie di Web site 
da Geosource che forniscono le generalità sul clima ed oltre i climi 
per gli insegnanti K-5 e gli allievi. La serie fornisce 
un'introduzione di base ai soggetti quale la differenza fra tempo ed 
il clima, fattori che effettuano il clima e che cosa è una procura di
clima (per esempio nuclei del ghiaccio). I luoghi egualmente 
caratterizzano le illustrazioni e le figure colorate.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή είναι η πρώτη σε μία σειρά των 
ιστοχώρων από Geosource που παρέχουν τις γενικές πληροφορίες 
για τα κλίματα κλίματος και παρελθόντος για Κ-5 δασκάλους και 
σπουδαστές. Η σειρά παρέχει μια βασική εισαγωγή στα θέματα
όπως η διαφορά μεταξύ του καιρού και του κλίματος, παράγοντες 
που επηρεάζουν το κλίμα, και τι είναι ένα πληρεξούσιο κλίματος 
(π.χ. πυρήνες πάγου). Οι περιοχές χαρακτηρίζουν επίσης τις 
έγχρωμες εικονογραφήσεις και τους αριθμούς.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio es el primer en una serie de Web site de
Geosource que proporcionen a la información de carácter general 
sobre clima y más allá de los climas para los profesores K-5 y los 
estudiantes. La serie proporciona a una introducción básica a 
los asuntos tales como la diferencia entre el tiempo y el clima, 
factores que efectúen clima, y cuál es un poder del clima (e.g. 
memorias del hielo). Los sitios también ofrecen ilustraciones y
figuras coloreadas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:AMERICAN GEOLOGICAL INSTITUTE
FN:AMERICAN GEOLOGICAL INSTITUTE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203636</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107212</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/learning-about-climate</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
