<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107462</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107462</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087097</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"They Are Mostly All Foreigners on Strike": Joseph Fish Speaks on the 1919 Steel Strike</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"sie sind meistens alle Ausländer auf Schlag": 
Joseph Fisch spricht über den Stahlschlag 1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"elles sont la plupart du temps tous les 
Étrangers en grève" : Le poisson de Joseph parle de la grève 
1919 en acier</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"são na maior parte todos os estrangeiros na 
batida": O peixe de Joseph fala na batida 1919 de aço</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"sono principalmente tutti gli stranieri sul 
colpo": Il pesce del Joseph parla sul colpo d'acciaio 1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Είναι συνήθως όλοι οι αλλοδαποί στην απεργία": 
Θ*Ιοσεπχ Fish Speaks στην απεργία χάλυβα του 1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"son sobre todo todos los extranjeros en huelga": 
El pescado de José habla en la huelga de acero 1919</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the dramatic 1919 steel strike, 350,000 workers walked off their jobs and crippled the industry. The U.S. Senate Committee on Education and Labor set out to investigate the strike while it was still in progress. In his testimony before the committee, Homestead, Pennsylvania, steelworker Joseph Fish described conditions in the steel mills as good and maintained that only "one or two" Americans have joined the strike.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im drastischen 1919 Stahlschlag gingen 350.000 
Arbeiter weg von ihren Jobs und verkrüppelten die Industrie. 
Der VEREINIGTE STAATEN Senat-Ausschuß für Ausbildung und 
Arbeit legte dar, um den Schlag nachzuforschen, während er noch in 
Bewegung war. In seinem Zeugnis vor dem Ausschuß, beschrieb 
Gehöft, Pennsylvania, Steelworker Joseph Fisch Bedingungen in den 
Stahltausendsteln als gutes und beibehalten, daß nur "ein oder zwei" 
Amerikaner den Schlag verbunden haben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans les 1919 grèves en acier excessive, 350.000 
ouvriers ont marché outre de leurs travaux et ont estropié 
l'industrie. Le comité de sénat des ETATS-UNIS de l'éducation
et du travail s'est mis à étudier la grève tandis qu'elle était 
encore en marche. Dans son témoignage devant le comité, la 
ferme, Pennsylvanie, poisson de Joseph de travailleur dans l'industrie
sidérurgique a décrit des conditions dans les aciéries en tant que 
bon et mises à jour que seulement "un ou deux" Américains ont joint 
la grève.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nas 1919 batidas de aço dramática, 350.000 
trabalhadores andaram fora de seus trabalhos e aleijaram a indústria.
O comitê do senate de ESTADOS UNIDOS na instrução e no 
trabalho ajustou-se para fora para investigar a batida quando era 
ainda em andamento. Em seu testimony antes do comitê, o 
homestead, Pensilvânia, peixe de Joseph do steelworker descreveu 
condições nos moinhos de aço como bom e mantidos que os somente "um
ou dois" americanos juntaram a batida.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nei 1919 colpi d'acciaio drammatico, 350.000 
operai hanno camminato fuori dei loro lavori ed hanno paralizzato 
l'industria. Il comitato del senato degli STATI UNITI di 
formazione e del Lavoro ha precisato per studiare il colpo mentre
era ancora in progresso. Nella sua testimonianza prima del 
comitato, la fattoria, Pensilvania, pesce del Joseph dell'addetto alla
lavorazione dell'acciaio ha descritto i termini nelle acciaierie come 
buon ed effettuate che soltanto "uno o due" Americano ha unito il 
colpo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στη δραματική απεργία χάλυβα του 1919, 350.000 
εργαζόμενοι περπάτησαν από τις εργασίες τους και ακρωτηρίασαν τη 
βιομηχανία. Η Επιτροπή ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ Συγκλήτου της 
εκπαίδευσης και η εργασία καθόρισαν να ερευνήσουν την απεργία 
ενώ ήταν ακόμα υπό εξέλιξη. Στην κατάθεσή του ενώπιον 
της επιτροπής, αγροτικό σπίτι, Πενσυλβανία, ο σιδηρουργός 
Joseph Fish περιέγραψε τους όρους στους μύλους χάλυβα ως 
καλούς και υποστήριξε ότι μόνο "ένας ή δύο" Αμερικανοί έχουν 
ενώσει την απεργία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En las 1919 huelgas de acero dramática, 350.000 
trabajadores recorrieron de sus trabajos y lisiaron la industria. 
El comité del senado de ESTADOS UNIDOS sobre la educación y el
trabajo precisó para investigar la huelga mientras que todavía 
estaba en marcha. En su testimonio ante el comité, la granja, 
Pennsylvania, pescado de José del trabajador siderúrgico describió 
condiciones en los molinos de acero como bueno y mantenidos que los 
solamente "un o dos" americanos han ensamblado la huelga.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087097</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107462</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/they-are-mostly-all-foreigners-on-strike-joseph-fish-speaks-on-the-1919-steel-strike</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
