<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104732</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104732</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086448</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">MacColl and the Modern Spirit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">MacColl und der moderne Geist</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">MacColl et l'esprit moderne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">MacColl e o espírito moderno</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">MacColl e lo spirito moderno</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">MacColl και το σύγχρονο πνεύμα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">MacColl y el alcohol moderno</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In February and March 1913, the "International Exhibition of Modern Art" opened at New York City's 69th Regiment Armory. After a tour of the U.S., a half million people had seen the exhibit--one of the most influential in American art history. The self-consciously "modern" Armory show, organized by art patron Arthur B. Davies, challenged the artistic establishment. Two-thirds of the 1,600 works were by Americans, and the Europeans whose works were exhibited--Picasso, Matisse, Seurat, Van Gogh, Gaughin, and Duchamp among them--were far from the conservatives that Americans were used to. "We want this old show of ours," declared one of the organizers, "to mark the starting point of a new spirit in art, at least as far as America is concerned." The show raised the hackles of many critics (one newspaper offered a reward to any schoolchild who could find the nude in the show's most controversial painting, Duchamp's "Nude Descending a Staircase"). But art critic W.D. MacColl praised the Armory Show's avant-garde spirit in this  Forum  magazine review from July 1913.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im Februar und März 1913, öffnete sich die 
"internationale Ausstellung der modernen kunst" an der 
Regiment-Waffenkammer der New York Stadt 69th. Nachdem eine Tour
der VEREINIGTEN STAATEN, halbe Million Leute die Ausstellung -- eine 
von den einflußreichsten in der amerikanischen kunstgeschichte 
gesehen hatte. Das selbstbewußt "moderne" 
Waffenkammererscheinen, organisiert vom kunstgönner Arthur B. Davies,
forderte die künstlerische Einrichtung heraus. Zweidrittel der 
1.600 Arbeiten waren durch Americans, und die Europäer deren Arbeiten
ausgestellt wurden -- Picasso, Matisse, Seurat, Van Gogh, Gaughin und 
Duchamp unter ihnen -- waren weit von die Konservativen, daß 
Amerikaner an waren. "wir wünschen dieses alte Erscheinen von 
unseren," erklärte einen der Organisatoren, "den Ausgangspunkt eines 
neuen Geistes in der kunst kennzeichnen, mindestens insoweit Amerika."
Das Erscheinen hob die Hecheln vieler Kritiker an (eine Zeitung 
bot eine Belohnung jedem möglichem Schulkind, das den Nude im 
umstrittensten Anstrich des Erscheinens finden könnte, Duchamps an ",
das ein Treppenhaus absteigend" Nude ist). Aber kunstkritiker 
W.D. MacColl pries den des Waffenkammer-Avantgardegeist Erscheinens in
dieser Forumzeitschrift Zusammenfassung von einem Juli 1913.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En février et mars 1913, "l'exposition 
internationale de l'art moderne" s'est ouverte à l'arsenal du 
régiment de la ville soixante-neuvième de New York. Après 
qu'une excursion des ETATS-UNIS, demi million de personnes ait vu 
l'objet exposé -- un des plus influente dans l'histoire américaine 
d'art. L'exposition "moderne" d'arsenal de 
art de l'auto-portrait-consciously, organisée par le patron Arthur B. Davies 
d'art, a défié l'établissement artistique. Deux-tiers des 
1.600 travaux étaient par Americans, et les Européens dont les 
travaux ont été montrés -- Picasso, Matisse, Seurat, Van Gogh, 
Gaughin, et Duchamp parmi eux -- étaient loin des conservateurs que 
des Américains ont été utilisés à. "nous voulons cette 
vieille exposition à nous," a déclaré un des organisateurs, "pour 
marquer le point de départ d'un nouvel esprit dans l'art, du moins en
ce qui concerne l'Amérique." L'exposition a soulevé les plumes
de cou de beaucoup de critiques (un journal a offert une récompense 
à n'importe quel écolier qui pourrait trouver la nudité dans la 
peinture la plus controversée de l'exposition, Duchamp "nu descendant
un escalier"). Mais le critique W.D. MacColl d'art a félicité 
l'esprit de l'avant-garde de l'exposition d'arsenal dans cette revue 
de magasin de forum à partir de juillet 1913.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em fevereiro e em março 1913, "o exhibition 
internacional da arte moderna" abriu no armory do regiment da cidade 
69th de New York. Depois que uma excursão dos ESTADOS UNIDOS, 
uns meio milhão povos tinha visto a exibição -- um do mais 
influential no history americano da arte. A mostra 
self-consciously "moderna" do armory, organizada pelo patron Arthur B.
Davies da arte, desafiou o estabelecimento artístico. Dois 
terços dos 1.600 trabalhos eram por Americano, e os Europeus cujos os
trabalhos foram exibidos -- Picasso, Matisse, Seurat, Camionete Gogh, 
Gaughin, e Duchamp entre eles -- eram longe dos conservadores que os 
americanos estiveram usados a. "nós queremos esta mostra velha 
de nossos," declarou um dos organizers, "marcar o ponto começar de um
espírito novo na arte, ao menos tanto quanto América." A 
mostra levantou as penugens do pescoço de muitos críticos (um jornal
ofereceu uma recompensa a todo o schoolchild que poderia encontrar o 
nude na pintura a mais controversa da mostra, Duchamp "nude descendo 
um staircase"). Mas o crítico W.D. MacColl da arte elogiou o 
espírito do avant-garde da mostra do armory nesta revisão do 
compartimento do forum de julho 1913.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nel mese di febbraio e marzo del 1913, "la mostra 
internazionale dell'arte moderna" si è aperta all'arsenale del 
regiment della città sessantanovesima de New York. Dopo che un 
giro degli STATI UNITI, milione di persone mezzo veda l'esposizione --
una degli più influenti nella storia americana di arte. 
L'esposizione self-consciously "moderna" dell'arsenale, 
organizzata dal patrono Arthur B. Davies di arte, ha sfidato 
l'istituzione artistica. Due terzi del 1.600 impianto era da 
Americans e gli Europei di cui gli impianti sono stati esibiti -- 
Picasso, Matisse, Seurat, Van Gogh, Gaughin e Duchamp fra loro -- 
erano lontano dai conservatori che gli Americani sono stati usati a. 
"desideriamo questa vecchia esposizione di il nostro," ha 
dichiarato uno degli organizzatori, "per contrassegnare il punto di 
partenza di nuovo spirito nell'arte, almeno per quanto l'America." 
L'esposizione ha alzato le piume del collo di molti critici (un 
giornale ha offerto una ricompensa a tutto lo scolaro che potrebbe 
trovare il nude nella pittura più discutibile dell'esposizione, 
Duchamp "nude discendendo una scala"). Ma il critico W.D. 
MacColl di arte ha elogiato lo spirito del avant-garde 
dell'esposizione dell'arsenale in questa revisione dello scomparto 
della tribuna da luglio del 1913.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τον Φεβρουάριο και τον Μάρτιο του 1913, η "διεθνής 
έκθεση της μοντέρνας τέχνησ" άνοιξε της Νέας Υόρκης οπλοστάσιο 
συντάγματος της πόλης στο 69ο. Μετά από έναν γύρο των ΗΠΑ,
μισοί από εκατομμύριο ανθρώπους είχαν δει το έκθεμα
-- ένας από τον επιδρύτερο στην αμερικανική ιστορία τέχνης. 
Το μόνος-συνειδητά "σύγχρονο" οπλοστάσιο εμφανίζει, 
οργανωμένος από τον προστάτη αρθούρος B. Davies τέχνης, 
προκάλεσε την καλλιτεχνική καθιέρωση. Τα δύο τρίτα των 
1.600 εργασιών ήταν από Αμερικανούς, και οι Ευρωπαίοι οι των 
οποίων εργασίες εκτέθηκαν -- Πικάσο, Matisse, Seurat, Van
Gogh, Gaughin, και Duchamp μεταξύ τους -- ήταν μακριά από
τα συντηρητικά έως τα οποία Αμερικανοί χρησιμοποιήθηκαν. 
"Θέλουμε αυτήν την παλαιά επίδειξη δικών μας," δηλωμένος 
ένας από τους διοργανωτές, "για να χαρακτηρίσουμε την αφετηρία 
ενός νέου πνεύματος στην τέχνη, τουλάχιστον όσον αφορά στην 
Αμερική." Η επίδειξη αύξησε hackles πολλών κριτικών (μια
εφημερίδα πρόσφερε μια ανταμοιβή σε οποιοδήποτε μαθητή που θα 
μπορούσε να βρεί nude στην πιό αμφισβητούμενη ζωγραφική της 
επίδειξης, Duchamp "nude κατεβαίνοντας μια σκάλα"). 
Αλλά ο κριτικός W.D. MacColl τέχνης εγκωμίασε το 
πνεύμα πρωτοπορίας της επίδειξης οπλοστάσιων σε αυτήν την 
αναθεώρηση περιοδικών φόρουμ από τον Ιούλιο του 1913.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En febrero y marcha de 1913, la "exposición 
internacional del arte moderno" se abrió en el arsenal del regimiento
de la ciudad 69.a de Nueva York. Después de que un viaje de los
ESTADOS UNIDOS, medio millones de personas de hubiera considerado el 
objeto expuesto -- uno del más influyente de historia americana del 
arte. La demostración tímidamente "moderna" del arsenal, 
ordenada por el patrón Arturo B. Davies del arte, desafió el 
establecimiento artístico. Dos tercios de los 1.600 trabajos 
estaba por americans, y los europeos que trabajos fueron exhibidos -- 
Picasso, Matisse, Seurat, Van Gogh, Gaughin, y Duchamp entre ellos -- 
eran lejos de los conservadores que utilizaron a los americanos a. 
"deseamos esta vieja demostración el nuestros," declaró a uno 
de los organizadores, "para marcar el punto de partida de un nuevo 
alcohol en arte, por lo menos por lo que América." La 
demostración levantó las plumas del cuello de muchos críticos (un 
periódico ofreció una recompensa a cualquier alumno que podría 
encontrar el nude en la pintura más polémica de la demostración, 
Duchamp "desnudo descendiendo una escalera"). Pero el crítico 
W.D. MacColl del arte elogió el alcohol vanguardista de la 
demostración del arsenal en esta revisión del compartimiento del 
foro a partir de julio de 1913.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086448</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104732</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/maccoll-and-the-modern-spirit</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
