<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106892</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106892</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212911</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Undersea Landscapes: Bay of Fundy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Unterseeische Landschaften: Bucht von Fundy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Horizontaux Sous-marins : Compartiment de 
Fundy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Paisagens Submarinas: Baía de Fundy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Paesaggi Subacquei: Baia di Fundy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Υποθαλάσσια τοπία: Κόλπος Fundy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Paisajes Submarinos: Bahía de Fundy</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site uses text and photos to explain how the physical characteristics of the Bay of Fundy create the unique tides that occur there. It also explains how the extreme tides affect nutrient cycling and plankton in the Bay, mudflats, and salt marshes. A static 3D map shows the areal extent of the Bay and an interactive 3D map explains the concept of vertical exaggeration. A short movie shows real footage of the rise and fall of the legendary tide in one local harbor.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site benutzt Text und Fotos, um zu 
erklären, wie die körperlichen Eigenschaften der Bucht von Fundy die
eindeutigen Gezeiten erstellen, die dort auftreten. Sie 
erklärt auch, wie die extremen Gezeiten das Nährradfahren und 
Plankton in der Bucht, in den mudflats und in den Salzsümpfen 
beeinflussen. Eine statische Karte 3D stellt dar, daß der areal
Umfang der Bucht und der interaktiven Karte 3D das Konzept der 
vertikalen Übertreibung erklärt. Ein kurzer Film zeigt reale 
Gesamtlänge des Anstiegs und des Falles der legendären 
Gezeiten in einem lokalen Hafen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site emploie le texte et les photos pour 
expliquer comment les caractéristiques physiques du compartiment de 
Fundy créent les seules marées qui se produisent là. Il 
explique également comment les marées extrêmes affectent le cycle 
nutritif et le plancton dans le compartiment, les mudflats, et les 
marais de sel. Une carte 3D statique montre que l'ampleur 
régionale du compartiment et d'une carte 3D interactive explique le 
concept de l'exagération verticale. Un film court montre la 
vraie longueur de l'élévation et de la chute de la marée 
légendaire dans un port local.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local usa o texto e as fotos explicar como as
características físicas da baía de Fundy críam as marés originais
que ocorrem lá. Explica também como as marés extremas afetam 
dar um ciclo nutriente e plankton na baía, nos mudflats, e nos 
pântanos de sal. Um mapa 3D de estática mostra que a extensão
areal da baía e de um mapa 3D interativo explica o conceito do 
exaggeration vertical. Um filme curto mostra o footage real da 
ascensão e da queda da maré legendária em um porto local.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo usa il testo e le foto per spiegare 
come le caratteristiche fisiche della baia di Fundy creano le maree 
uniche che accadono là. Egualmente spiega come le maree estreme
interessano ciclare nutriente ed il plancton nella baia, nei mudflats 
e nelle paludi d'acqua salata. Un programma statico 3D mostra 
che il limite areale della baia e di un programma interattivo 3D 
spiega il concetto dell'esagerazione verticale. Un film 
corto mostra il metraggio reale dell'aumento e della caduta della 
marea leggendaria in un porto locale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή χρησιμοποιεί το κείμενο και τις 
φωτογραφίες για να εξηγήσει πώς τα φυσικά χαρακτηριστικά του 
κόλπου Fundy δημιουργούν τις μοναδικές παλίρροιες που 
εμφανίζονται εκεί. Εξηγεί επίσης πώς οι ακραίες 
παλίρροιες έχουν επιπτώσεις στη θρεπτική ανακύκλωση και το 
πλαγκτόν στον κόλπο, mudflats, και τα αλατισμένα έλη. 
Ένας στατικός τρισδιάστατος χάρτης εμφανίζει τοπική 
έκταση του κόλπου και ένας διαλογικός τρισδιάστατος χάρτης 
εξηγεί την έννοια της κάθετης υπερβολής. Ένας κοντός 
κινηματογράφος εμφανίζει πραγματικό μήκος σε πόδηα της ανόδου 
και της πτώσης της θρυλικής παλίρροιας σε ένα τοπικό λιμάνι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio utiliza el texto y las fotos para 
explicar cómo las características físicas de la bahía de Fundy 
crean las mareas únicas que ocurren allí. También explica 
cómo las mareas extremas afectan completar un ciclo nutriente y el 
plancton en la bahía, los mudflats, y los pantanos de sal. Una 
correspondencia estática 3D muestra que el fragmento regional de la 
bahía y de una correspondencia interactiva 3D explica el concepto de 
la exageración vertical. Una película corta muestra la 
cantidad verdadera de la subida y de la caída de la marea legendaria 
en un puerto local.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212911</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106892</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/undersea-landscapes-bay-of-fundy</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
