<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107899</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107899</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211172</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Geologic Puzzles: Morrison Formation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geologische Puzzlespiele: Morrison Anordnung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Puzzles Géologiques : Formation de Morrison</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Enigmas Geologic: Formação De Morrison</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Puzzle Geologici: Formazione Di Morrison</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γεωλογικοί γρίφοι: Σχηματισμός Morrison</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Rompecabezas Geológicos: Formación De 
Morrison</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Outcrop images (faulted strata, inter-bedded shale and limestone beds that have been tilted, beach rocks of different lithologies) can be used to bring the field into the geoscience classroom, giving students practice in doing what geoscientists do when they are in the field. This Starting Point activity uses images of outcrops to teach students to make observations, interpret those observations and pose questions for further information. This site provides examples of pictures of geologic puzzles, learning goals and context for the activity, teaching notes (including links to information on think-pair-share), and links to additional resources and references.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zutageliegenbilder (bemängelte Schichten, 
inter-bedded Schiefer und Kalksteinbetten, die gekippt worden sind, 
Strandfelsen der unterschiedlichen Lithologien) können verwendet 
werden, um auffangene in das geoscience Klassenzimmer zu holen und 
Kursteilnehmern Praxis geben, wenn man tut, welche geoscientists tun, 
wenn sie in auffangene sind. Diese Ausgangspunktaktivität 
verwendet Bilder des Zutageliegens, um Kursteilnehmer zu unterrichten,
Beobachtungen zu bilden, jene Beobachtungen zu deuten und Fragen für 
weitere Informationen aufzuwerfen. Diese Site stellt Beispiele 
der Abbildungen der geologischen Puzzlespiele, der erlernenziele und 
des Kontextes für die Aktivität zur Verfügung und unterrichtet 
Anmerkungen (einschließlich Links zu den Informationen über 
Denken-Paaranteil) und Links zu den zusätzlichen Betriebsmitteln und 
zu den Referenzen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Des images d'affleurement (strates censurées, 
schiste et lits intercalés de pierre à chaux qui ont été 
inclinés, roches de plage de différentes lithologies) peuvent être 
employées pour introduire la zone dans la salle de classe de 
geoscience, donnant à des étudiants la pratique en faisant quels 
geoscientists font quand ils sont dans le domaine. Cette 
activité de point de départ emploie des images des affleurements 
pour enseigner des étudiants à faire des observations, à 
interpréter ces observations et à poser des questions pour de plus 
amples informations. Ce site fournit des exemples des images des
puzzles géologiques, des buts d'étude et du contexte pour 
l'activité, enseignant des notes (liens y compris à l'information 
sur la penser-paire-part), et des liens aux ressources et aux 
références supplémentaires.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As imagens do outcrop (strata criticados, xisto e 
as camas inter-bedded da pedra calcária que foram inclinadas, as 
rochas da praia de lithologies diferentes) podem ser usadas trazer o 
campo na sala de aula do geoscience, dando a estudantes a prática em 
fazer que geoscientists fazem quando estão no campo. Esta 
atividade do ponto começar usa imagens dos outcrops ensinar 
estudantes fazer observações, interpretar aquelas observações e 
pose perguntas para uma informação mais adicional. Este local 
fornece exemplos dos retratos de enigmas geologic, de objetivos de 
aprendizagem e de contexto para a atividade, ensinando notas 
(ligações including à informação na pens-par-parte), e ligações
aos recursos e às referências adicionais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le immagini dell'affioramento (strati incolpati, 
argilla friabile e basi inter-bedded del calcare che sono state 
inclinate, roccie della spiaggia delle litologie differenti) possono 
essere usate per introdurre il campo nell'aula di geoscience, dante ad
allievi la pratica nel fare che geoscientists fanno quando sono nel 
campo. Questa attività del punto di partenza usa le immagini 
degli affioramenti per insegnare gli allievi fare le osservazioni, 
interpretare quelle osservazioni e porre le domande per ulteriori 
informazioni. Questo luogo fornisce gli esempi delle immagini 
dei puzzle geologici, degli obiettivi imparanti e del contesto per 
l'attività, insegnando le note (collegamenti compresi alle 
informazioni sulla pens-accoppi-parte) ed i collegamenti alle risorse 
ed ai riferimenti supplementari.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι εικόνες επανθίσεων (στρώματα, διά-τοποθετημένοι 
στο κρεβάτι σχιστόλιθος και κρεβάτια ασβεστόλιθων που έχουν 
γείρει, βράχοι παραλιών των διαφορετικών λιθολογιών) μπορούν να 
χρησιμοποιηθούν για να φέρουν το πεδίο στην τάξη geoscience, 
που δίνει την πρακτική σπουδαστών να κάνουν ποια geoscientists 
κάνουν όταν είναι στο πεδίο. Αυτή η δραστηριότητα 
αφετηρίας χρησιμοποιεί τις εικόνες των επανθίσεων για να διδάξει 
τους σπουδαστές για να κάνει τις παρατηρήσεις, να ερμηνεύσει 
εκείνες τις παρατηρήσεις και να θέσει τις ερωτήσεις για 
περισσότερες πληροφορίες. Αυτή η περιοχή παρέχει τα 
παραδείγματα των εικόνων των γεωλογικών γρίφων, των στόχων 
εκμάθησης και του πλαισίου για τη δραστηριότητα, διδασκαλικός τις 
σημειώσεις (συμπεριλαμβανομένων των συνδέσεων με τις πληροφορίες 
για το σκέφτομαι-ζευγάρι-μερίδιο), και τις συνδέσεις με τα 
πρόσθετα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς και τις αναφορές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las imágenes del afloramiento (estratos 
criticados, pizarra y las camas inter-bedded de la piedra caliza se 
han inclinado que, rocas de la playa de diversos lithologies) se 
pueden utilizar para traer el campo en la sala de clase del 
geoscience, dando a estudiantes práctica en hacer qué geoscientists 
hacen cuando están en el campo. Esta actividad del punto de 
partida utiliza imágenes de afloramientos para enseñar a estudiantes
a hacer observaciones, a interpretar esas observaciones y a plantear 
las preguntas para la información adicional. Este sitio 
proporciona a ejemplos de los cuadros de rompecabezas geológicos, de 
metas que aprenden y del contexto para la actividad, enseñando notas 
(conexiones incluyendo a la información sobre la pensar-par-parte), y
conexiones a los recursos y a las referencias adicionales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:HEATHER MACDONALD
FN:HEATHER MACDONALD
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211172</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107899</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/geologic-puzzles</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
