<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106899</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106899</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087127</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"To Live in Health and in General Conformity with the Mores of Her Group": Defining a Minimum-Adequate Standard of Living</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"in der Gesundheit und in der allgemeinen 
Übereinstimmung mit dem Mores ihrer Gruppe leben": Definieren 
eines Minimum-Ausreichenden Standards des Lebens</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"pour vivre dans la santé et en général la 
conformité avec le Mores de son groupe" : Définir un niveau 
Minimum-Adéquat la vie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"para viver na saúde e no conformity geral com o 
Mores de seu grupo": Definindo um padrão Mínimo-Adequado de 
viver</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"per vivere nella salute e nella conformità 
generale con il Mores del suo gruppo": Definizione del livello 
Minimo-Sufficiente of vivere</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Για να ζήσει στην υγεία και στη γενική συμμόρφωση με 
το Mores της ομάδας τησ": Καθορισμός ενός 
ελάχιστο-επαρκούς βιοτικού επιπέδου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"para vivir en salud y en conformidad general con 
el Mores de su grupo": Definir un estándar Mi'nimo-Adecuado 
vivir</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1937, the Supreme Court reversed a position taken in 1923 that a state minimum wage law was unconstitutional. The following year, the Fair Labor Standards Act was signed into law outlawing child labor and guaranteeing covered workers a minimum wage of 40 cents an hour and a maximum 40-hour work week. Although more than 22 million workers benefited, conservative forces in Congress saw to it that the Act exempted many others from its provisions. Due to the persistence of low wages during the Depression, the Federal government charged three agencies, including the Women's Bureau of the Department of Labor, to recommend procedures to determine cost-of-living budgets so that adequate minimum wage legislation could be written. In the following document, the Women's Bureau devised budgets for self-supporting women without dependents living in a variety of states and defined a "minimum-adequate standard of living" distinct from a subsistence or luxury standard. In doing so they took into consideration specific cultural, sociological, and psychological factors. They reasoned that wage standards should enable "conformity with group-approved habits or behavior patterns" in the area in which an individual lives so that persons affected can feel that they "belong" to their group. The document was included in the record of Senate hearings in 1949 to amend the Fair Labor Standards Act.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1937 hob das Höchste Gericht eine Position auf, 
die 1923 genommen wurde, daß ein Gesetz des minimalen Lohnes des 
Zustandes verfassungswidrig war. Das folgende Jahr, wurde die 
angemessene Richtlinie- für angemessene Arbeitsbedingungentat in das 
Gesetz unterzeichnet, das Kinderarbeit ächtet und das Garantieren 
bedeckte Arbeiter ein minimaler Lohn von 40 Cents ein Stunde und eine 
Woche Arbeit des Maximums 40-hour. Obgleich mehr als 22 Million 
Arbeiter förderten, achteten konservative Kräfte im Kongreß es, 
daß die Tat viele andere von seinen Bestimmungen befreite. 
Wegen der Ausdauer der niedrigen Löhne während des Tiefstands,
lud die Bundesregierung drei Agenturen, einschließlich das Büro der 
Frauen des Arbeitsministeriums auf, Prozeduren zu empfehlen, um 
Lebenshaltungskostenetats festzustellen, damit ausreichende 
Gesetzgebung des minimalen Lohnes geschrieben werden konnte. Im 
folgenden Dokument plante das Büro der Frauen Etats für 
selbsttragende Frauen ohne die Abhängigen, die in einer Vielzahl der 
Zustände leben und definierte einen "Minimum-ausreichenden Standard 
des Lebens" eindeutig von einem Erwerbsmittel oder von einem 
Luxuxstandard. Wenn sie so tun, nahmen sie in Erwägung 
spezifische kulturelle, soziologische und psychologische Faktoren. 
Sie folgerten, daß Lohnstandards "Übereinstimmung mit 
Gruppe-anerkannten Gewohnheiten aktivieren sollten, oder Verhalten" im
Bereich patterns, in dem eine Einzelperson lebt, damit die 
beeinflußten Personen glauben können, daß sie ihrer Gruppe 
"gehören". Das Dokument war im Satz der Senathörfähigkeiten 
1949 eingeschlossen, um die angemessene Richtlinie- für angemessene 
Arbeitsbedingungentat zu ändern.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1937, la cour suprême a renversé une position
prise en 1923 qu'une loi de salaire minimum d'état était 
inconstitutionnelle. L'année suivante, l'acte juste de normes 
de travail a été signé dans la loi proscrivant le travail des 
enfants et garantissant les ouvriers couverts un salaire minimum de 40
cents par heure et une semaine de travail du maximum 40-hour. 
Bien que plus de 22 millions d'ouvriers aient bénéficié, les 
forces conservatrices dans le congrès ont assuré la Loi a exempté 
beaucoup d'autres de ses dispositions. En raison de la 
persistance de bas salaires pendant la dépression, le gouvernement 
fédéral a chargé trois agences, y compris le bureau des femmes du 
service du travail, de recommander des procédures pour déterminer 
les budgets du coût de la vie de sorte que la législation adéquate 
de salaire minimum ait pu être écrite. Dans le document 
suivant, le bureau des femmes budgets conçus pour des femmes de 
art de l'auto-portrait-supporting sans personnes à charge vivant dans une variété
d'états et définie "un niveau minimum-adéquat la vie" distincte 
d'une subsistance ou d'une norme de luxe. De cette manière 
elles ont pris dans des facteurs culturels de considération, 
sociologiques, et psychologiques spécifiques. Elles raison pour
laquelle les normes de salaire devraient permettre la "conformité 
avec des habitudes groupe-approuvées ou le comportement a modelé" 
dans la zone dans laquelle un individu vit de sorte que les personnes 
affectées puissent estimer qu'elles "appartiennent" à leur groupe. 
Le document a été inclus dans l'enregistrement des auditions 
de sénat en 1949 pour modifier l'acte juste de normes de travail.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1937, a corte suprema inverteu uma posição 
feita exame em 1923 que uma lei do salário mínimo do estado era 
unconstitutional. O seguinte ano, o ato justo dos padrões labor
foi assinado na lei que outlawing o trabalho de criança e garantir 
cobriu trabalhadores um salário mínimo de 40 centavos um a hora e 
uma semana do trabalho do máximo 40-hour. Embora mais de 22 
milhão trabalhadores se beneficiassem, as forças conservadoras no 
congress viram-lhe que o ato exempted muito outro de suas provisões. 
devido ao persistence de salários baixos durante o depression,
o governo federal carregou três agências, including o departamento 
das mulheres do departamento de trabalho, recomendar procedimentos 
determinar orçamentos do custo de vida de modo que a legislação 
adequada do salário mínimo pudesse ser escrita. No seguinte 
original, o departamento das mulheres planejou orçamentos para 
mulheres self-supporting sem dependentes que vivem em uma variedade 
dos estados e definiu "um padrão mínimo-adequado de viver" distinto 
de um subsistence ou de um padrão luxuoso. Em fazer assim 
fizeram exame em fatores cultural da consideração, sociological, e 
psicológicos específicos. Raciocinaram que os padrões do 
salário devem permitir o "conformity com hábitos grupo-aprovados ou 
o comportamento modelou" na área em que um indivíduo vive de modo 
que as pessoas afetadas possam sentir que "pertencem" a seu grupo. 
O original foi incluído no registro de hearings do senate em 
1949 para emendar o ato justo dos padrões labor.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1937, la Corte suprema ha invertito una 
posizione presa in 1923 che una legge dello stipendio minimo di 
dichiarare era inconstituzionale. Il seguente anno, la Legge 
Di lavoro giusta di standard è stata firmata nel lavoro del 
bambino di proscrizione di legge e garantire gli operai coperti uno 
stipendio minimo di 40 centesimi un l'ora e una settimana del lavoro 
di massimo 40-hour. Anche se più di 22 milione operai si sono 
avvantaggiati, le forze conservatrici nel congresso si sono assicurate 
che la Legge esentasse molti altre dalle relative disposizioni. dovuto la persistenza degli stipendi bassi durante la depressione, il 
governo federale ha caricato tre agenzie, compreso l'ufficio delle 
donne del reparto del Lavoro, suggerire le procedure per 
determinare i preventivi cost-of-living in modo che la legislazione 
sufficiente dello stipendio minimo potesse essere scritta. Nel 
seguente documento, l'ufficio delle donne preventivi inventati per le 
donne autosufficienti senza dipendenti che vivono in una varietà di 
dichiara e definito "un livello minimo-sufficiente of vivere" 
distinto da una sussistenza o da uno standard di lusso. In tal 
modo hanno preso nei fattori culturali di considerazione, sociologici 
e psicologici specifici. Ragione per cui gli standard dello 
stipendio dovrebbero permettere "la conformità con le abitudini 
gruppo-approvate o il comportamento ha modellato" nella zona in cui un
individuo vive in moda da potere ritenere le persone influenzate che 
"appartengono" al loro gruppo. Il documento è stato incluso nel
record delle udienze del senato in 1949 per emendare la Legge 
Di lavoro giusta di standard.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1937, το ανώτατο δικαστήριο αντέστρεψε μια θέση 
που υποστηρίχτηκε το 1923 ότι ένας νόμος κρατικών βασικών 
μισθών ήταν αντισυνταγματικός. Το επόμενο έτος, ο δίκαιος 
νόμος προτύπων εργασίας υπογράφηκε στο νόμο που προγράφει την 
παιδική εργασία και που εγγυάται στους καλυμμένους εργαζομένους 
έναν βασικό μισθό 40 σεντ μια ώρα και μια μέγιστη εβδομάδα 
εργασίας 40-ώρας. Αν και περισσότεροι από 22 εκατομμύριο
εργαζόμενοι ωφελήθηκαν, οι συντηρητικές δυνάμεις στο συνέδριο 
εβλέίδαν σε τον ότι ο νόμος απάλλαξε πολλοί άλλοι από 
τις παροχές του. Λόγω στην εμμονή των χαμηλών αμοιβών κατά
τη διάρκεια της κατάθλιψης, η ομοσπονδιακή κυβέρνηση ανέθεσε σε 
τρεις αντιπροσωπείες, συμπεριλαμβανομένου του γραφείου των 
γυναικών του τμήματος εργασίας, για να συστήσει τις διαδικασίες 
για να καθορίσει τους προϋπολογισμούς κόστους ζωής έτσι ώστε η 
επαρκής νομοθεσία βασικών μισθών να μπορεί να γραφτεί. Στο
ακόλουθο έγγραφο, το γραφείο των γυναικών επινόησε τους 
προϋπολογισμούς για τις αυτοφερόμενες γυναίκες χωρίς υποτελείς 
που ζουν σε ποικίλα κράτη και καθόρισε ένα "ελάχιστο-επαρκές 
βιοτικό επίπεδο" ευδιάκριτο από πρότυπα επιβίωσης ή 
πολυτέλειας. Με αυτό τον τρόπο έλαβαν υπόψη τους ειδικούς 
πολιτιστικούς, κοινωνιολογικούς, και ψυχολογικούς παράγοντες. 
Διαλογίστηκαν ότι τα πρότυπα αμοιβών πρέπει να επιτρέψουν 
"τη συμμόρφωση με τις ομάδα-εγκεκριμένα συνήθειες ή τα πρότυπα 
συμπεριφοράσ" στην περιοχή στην οποία ένα άτομο ζει έτσι ώστε 
τα πρόσωπα επηρεασθέντα μπορούν να θεωρήσουν ότι "ανήκουν" στην 
ομάδα τους. Το έγγραφο περιλήφθηκε στο αρχείο των ακροάσεων
Συγκλήτου το 1949 για να τροποποιήσει το δίκαιο νόμο προτύπων 
εργασίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1937, el Tribunal Supremo invirtió una 
posición tomada en 1923 que una ley del salario mínimo del estado 
era inconstitucional. El año siguiente, el acto justo de los 
estándares de trabajo fue firmado en la ley que proscribía el 
trabajo de niño y que garantizaba a trabajadores cubiertos un salario
mínimo de 40 centavos por hora y una semana del trabajo del máximo 
40-hour. Aunque más de 22 millones de trabajadores 
beneficiaron, las fuerzas conservadoras en congreso consideraron a él
que el acto eximió muchos otros de sus provisiones. debido a 
la persistencia de salarios bajos durante la depresión, el gobierno 
federal cargó a tres agencias, incluyendo la oficina de las mujeres 
del departamento del trabajo, que recomendaran procedimientos para 
determinar presupuestos de costo de vida de modo que la legislación 
adecuada del salario mínimo pudiera ser escrita. En el 
documento siguiente, la oficina de las mujeres presupuestos ideados 
para las mujeres autosuficientes sin los dependientes que viven en una
variedad de estados y definida un "estándar mi'nimo-adecuado vivir" 
distinto de una subsistencia o de un estándar de lujo. En hacer
tan tomaron en factores culturales de la consideración, 
sociológicos, y psicologicos específicos. Razonaron que los 
estándares del salario deben permitir "conformidad con hábitos 
grupo-aprobados o el comportamiento modeló" en el área en la cual un
individuo vive de modo que las personas afectadas puedan sentirse que 
"pertenecen" a su grupo. El documento fue incluido en el 
expediente de las audiencias del senado en 1949 para enmendar el acto 
justo de los estándares de trabajo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087127</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106899</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/to-live-in-health-and-in-general-conformity-with-the-mores-of-her-group-defining-a-minimum-adequate-standard-of-living</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
