<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107229</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107229</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086277</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Climbed Poles, I Ran Cable, I Ran a Jackhammer:" Faith Robinson Describes Harassment On the Job</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ich kletterte Polen, ich laufen ließ Kabel, ich 
laufen ließ einen Jackhammer:" Glaube Robinson beschreibt 
Belästigung auf dem Job</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"je suis monté Polonais, j'ai exécuté le câble,
j'ai exécuté un jackhammer :" La foi Robinson décrit le 
Harcèlement sur le travail</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"eu escalei Pólos, mim funcionei o cabo, mim 
funcionei um jackhammer:" A fé Robinson descreve o harassment 
no trabalho</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"ho arrampicato Pali, io ho fatto funzionare il 
cavo, io ho fatto funzionare un jackhammer:" La fede Robinson 
descrive il harassment sul lavoro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Αναρριχήθηκα σε Πολωνούς, έτρεξα το καλώδιο, έτρεξα 
ένα Jackhammer:" Η πίστη Robinson περιγράφει την 
παρενόχληση στην εργασία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"subí a postes, yo ejecuté el cable, yo ejecuté 
un martillo perforador:" La fe Robinson describe el 
hostigamiento en el trabajo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The women's movement of the 1970's had a far-reaching impact that was felt in every recess of American society. Working class women began to enter non-traditional jobs in trades and craft unions, and lesbians found a larger community in which to express their sexuality. In both cases, women faced resistance and sometimes violence as they charted new gender territory. Faith Robinson, one of those brave enough to break the gender barrier in the predominantly male telephone technician field, was also a lesbian _ she faced a particularly difficult challenge. Robinson remembered one incident in 1979 in which anti-gay talk escalated to violence on the job site.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Bewegung der Frauen der siebziger Jahre hatte 
eine weitreichende Auswirkung, die in jede Aussparung der 
amerikanischen Gesellschaft geglaubt wurde. Funktion Kategorie 
Frauen fingen an, nicht traditionele Jobs in Handel und in 
Handwerker-Gewerkschaften einzutragen, und Lesbier fanden eine 
größere Gemeinschaft, in der ihre Sexualität ausdrücken. 
In beiden Fällen stellten Frauen Widerstand und manchmal 
Gewalttätigkeit gegenüber, während sie neue Geschlechtgegend 
entwarfen. Glaube Robinson, eins von jenen tapferen genug, zum 
der Geschlechtsperre im überwiegend männlichen Telefontechniker zu 
brechen fangen auf, waren auch _ sie gegenüberstellte eine 
besonders schwierige Herausforderung ein lesbisches. Robinson 
erinnerte sich an ein Ereignis 1979, in dem Anti-homosexuelles 
Gespräch zur Gewalttätigkeit auf der Jobsite sich entwickelte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le mouvement des femmes des années 70 a eu un 
impact de grande envergure qui a été senti dans chaque cavité de la
société américaine. Les femmes de classe ouvrière ont 
commencé à écrire les travaux non traditionnels dans les commerces 
et des syndicats de métier, et les lesbiennes ont trouvé une plus 
grande communauté dans laquelle pour exprimer leur sexualité. 
Dans les deux cas, les femmes ont fait face à la résistance et
parfois à la violence pendant qu'elles dressaient une carte le 
nouveau territoire de genre. La foi Robinson, un de ceux 
bravent assez pour casser la barrière de genre dans le 
domaine principalement mâle de technicien de téléphone, était 
également une lesbienne _ elle a relevé un défi particulièrement 
difficile. Robinson s'est rappelé un incident en 1979 l'où 
l'entretien anti-gai a escaladé à la violence sur le site du 
travail.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O movimento das mulheres dos 1970's teve um impacto
far-reaching que fosse sentido em cada rebaixo da sociedade americana.
As mulheres da classe de funcionamento começaram a incorporar 
trabalhos non-traditional aos comércios e às uniões de ofício, e 
os lesbians encontraram uma comunidade maior em que para expressar seu
sexuality. Em ambos os casos, as mulheres enfrentaram a 
resistência e às vezes a violência enquanto fizeram um mapa do 
território novo do gender. A fé Robinson, um daqueles bravos 
bastante para quebrar a barreira do gender no campo predominantly 
masculino do técnico do telefone, era também uma lesbian _ ela 
enfrentou um desafio particularmente difícil. Robinson recordou
um incident em 1979 em que a conversa anti-anti-gay escalou à 
violência no local do trabalho.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il movimento delle donne degli anni 70 ha avuto un 
effetto ampio che è stato ritenuto in ogni incavo della società 
americana. Le donne del codice categoria di funzionamento hanno 
cominciato a fornire i lavori non tradizionali nei commerci e nei 
sindacati di mestiere e le lesbiche hanno trovato una più grande 
Comunità in cui esprimere il loro sexuality. In entrambi i 
casi, le donne hanno affrontato la resistenza ed a volte la violenza 
mentre hanno progettato il nuovo territorio di genere. La fede 
Robinson, uno di quei abbastanza brave per eliminare la barriera di 
genere nel campo principalmente maschio del tecnico del telefono, era 
egualmente un lesbico _ lei ha affrontato una sfida particolarmente 
difficile. Robinson si è ricordato di un avvenimento in 1979 in
où il colloquio di anti-gay ha intensificato la violenza sul 
luogo di lavoro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το κίνημα των γυναικών της δεκαετίας του '70 άσκησε 
εκτεταμένη επίδραση που έγινε αισθητή σε κάθε κοιλότητα της 
αμερικανικής κοινωνίας. Οι γυναίκες εργατικής τάξης 
άρχισαν να εισάγουν τις μη παραδοσιακές εργασίες στα εμπόρια και 
τις ενώσεις τεχνών, και οι λεσβίες βρήκαν μια μεγαλύτερη 
κοινότητα στην οποία να εκφράσει τη σεξουαλικότητά τους. 
Και στις δύο περιπτώσεις, οι γυναίκες αντιμετώπισαν την 
αντίσταση και μερικές φορές τη βία δεδομένου ότι σχεδίασαν το 
νέο έδαφος γένους. Η πίστη Robinson, ένας από εκείνο 
τον αρκετά γενναίο να σπάσει το εμπόδιο γένους στο κυρίως 
αρσενικό πεδίο τηλεφωνικών τεχνικών, ήταν επίσης λεσβία _ που 
αντιμετώπισε μια ιδιαίτερα δύσκολη πρόκληση. Το Robinson 
θυμήθηκε ένα γεγονός το 1979 στο οποίο η αντι-εύθυμη συζήτηση
κλιμάκωσε στη βία στην περιοχή εργασίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El movimiento de las mujeres de los años 70 tenía
un impacto de gran envergadura que era sentido en cada receso de la 
sociedad americana. Las mujeres de la clase obrera comenzaron a 
incorporar trabajos no tradicionales a comercios y a uniones de arte, 
y las lesbianas encontraron a comunidad más grande en quien expresar 
su sexualidad. En ambos casos, las mujeres hicieron frente a 
resistencia y a veces a violencia mientras que planearon el territorio
nuevo del género. La fe Robinson, uno de esos bastante 
valientes para romper la barrera del género en el campo predominante 
masculino del técnico del teléfono, era también una lesbiana _ ella
hizo frente a un desafío determinado difícil. Robinson 
recordó un incidente en 1979 en el cual la charla de anti-gay se
extendió a la violencia en el sitio del trabajo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086277</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107229</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-climbed-poles-i-ran-cable-i-ran-a-jackhammer-faith-robinson-describes-harassment-on-the-job</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
