<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105902</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105902</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087417</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Babes on bayonets."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Babys auf Bajonetten."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"bébés sur des baïonnettes."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"babes em baionetas."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"babes sulle baionette."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Babes στις ξιφολόγχες."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"bebés en las bayonetas."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1914, during World War I, the German army passed through neutral Belgium to attack France. Afterward, many U.S. newspapers and magazines featured pro-war cartoons depicting alleged German atrocities in Belgium, particularly the killing of innocent women and children. This cartoon appeared in a 1915 edition of the weekly humor magazine  Life . The slaughter in Belgium did not actually occur; but by 1915 tens of thousands of Africans had died in the Belgian Congo, victims of Belgium's ruthless exploitation of its colony's resources.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1914 während des Ersten Weltkrieges, überschritt die 
deutsche Armee durch Nullbelgien zum Angriff Frankreich. Danach 
kennzeichneten viele VEREINIGTE STAATEN Zeitungen und Zeitschriften 
die Pro-Krieg Karikaturen, die behauptete deutsche Grausamkeiten in 
Belgien, besonders die Tötung von den unschuldigen Frauen und von den
Kindern bildlich darstellen. Diese Karikatur erschien in einer 
Ausgabe 1915 der wöchentlichen Stimmungzeitschrift Lebensdauer. 
Das Gemetzel in Belgien nicht wirklich trat auf; aber 
durch 1915 10 Tausenden Afrikaner war im belgischen Kongo, Opfer von 
Belgiens unbarmherziger Ausnutzung der Betriebsmittel seiner Kolonie 
gestorben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1914, pendant la Première Guerre Mondiale, l'armée 
allemande a traversé la Belgique neutre à l'attaque France. 
Après, beaucoup de journaux des ETATS-UNIS et magasins ont 
comporté des dessins animés de pro-guerre dépeignant les atrocités
allemandes alléguées en Belgique, en particulier le massacre des 
femmes et des enfants innocents. Ce dessin animé est apparu 
dans une édition 1915 de la vie hebdomadaire de magasin d'humeur. 
L'abattage en Belgique ne s'est pas produit réellement ; 
mais par 1915 dizaines de milliers d'Africains était mort au 
Congo belge, victimes de l'exploitation impitoyable de la Belgique des
ressources de sa colonie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1914, durante o world.war.i, o exército alemão passou
através de Bélgica neutra ao ataque France. Mais tarde, muitos
jornais de ESTADOS UNIDOS e compartimentos caracterizaram os cartoons 
da pro-guerra que descrevem atrocities alemães alegados em Bélgica, 
particularmente a matança de mulheres e de crianças inocentes. 
Este cartoon apareceu em uma edição 1915 da vida semanal do 
compartimento do humor. O slaughter em Bélgica não ocorreu 
realmente; mas por 1915 dez dos milhares dos africanos tinha 
morrido no Congo belga, vítimas da exploração ruthless de Bélgica 
de recursos da sua colônia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1914, durante il world.war.i, l'esercito tedesco ha 
attraversato il Belgio neutro all'attacco Francia. In seguito, 
molti giornali degli STATI UNITI e scomparti hanno caratterizzato i 
fumetti di pro-guerra che descrivono le atrocità tedesche 
dichiarate nel Belgio, specialmente l'uccisione delle donne e dei 
bambini non colpevoli. Questo fumetto è comparso in un'edizione
1915 della vita settimanale dello scomparto di umore. Il macello
nel Belgio realmente non ha accaduto; ma da 1915 dieci dei 
migliaia degli Africani era morto nel Congo belga, vittime di 
sfruttamento ruthless del Belgio delle risorse della relativa colonia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1914, κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου Ι,
το γερμανικό στρατό που περνούν μέσω του ουδέτερου Βελγίου στην 
επίθεση Γαλλία. Κατόπιν, πολλά ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΕΣ εφημερίδες και 
χαρακτηρισμένα περιοδικά υπέρ-πολεμικά κινούμενα σχέδια που 
απεικονίζουν τις υποτιθέμενες γερμανικές αγριότητες στο Βέλγιο, 
ιδιαίτερα η δολοφονία των αθώων γυναικών και των παιδιών. 
Αυτά τα κινούμενα σχέδια εμφανίστηκαν σε μια έκδοση του 
1915 της εβδομαδιαίας ζωής περιοδικών χιούμορ. Η σφαγή 
στο Βέλγιο δεν εμφανίστηκε πραγματικά  αλλά μέχρι το 
1915 οι δεκάδες χιλιάδων Αφρικανοί είχαν πεθάνει στο βελγικό 
Κογκό, θύματα της άσπλαχνης εκμετάλλευσης του Βελγίου των 
στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς της αποικίας της.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1914, durante Primera Guerra Mundial, el ejército 
alemán pasó a través de Bélgica neutral al ataque Francia. 
Luego, muchos periódicos de ESTADOS UNIDOS y compartimientos 
ofrecieron las historietas de la favorable-guerra que representaban 
las atrocidades alemanas alegadas en Bélgica, determinado la matanza 
de mujeres y de niños inocentes. Esta historieta apareció en 
una edición 1915 de la vida semanal del compartimiento del humor. 
La matanza en Bélgica no ocurrió realmente; pero por 
1915 diez de millares de africanos había muerto en el Congo belga, 
víctimas de la explotación despiadada de Bélgica de los recursos de
su colonia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087417</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105902</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/babes-on-bayonets</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
