<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108086</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108086</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087330</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"A Rale Boost to Lithrachoor": A Humorist Lampoons Libraries</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"eine Rale Erhöhung zu Lithrachoor": Ein 
Humorist Verspottet Bibliotheken</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"une poussée de Rale à Lithrachoor" : Un 
Humoriste Lance des satires des Bibliothèques</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"um impulso de Rale a Lithrachoor": Um 
Humorist Lampoons Bibliotecas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"una spinta di Rale a Lithrachoor": Un 
Humorist Lampoons Le Librerie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Μια ώθηση Rale σε Lithrachoor": Ένας 
ευθυμογράφος σατυρίζει τις βιβλιοθήκες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"un alza de Rale a Lithrachoor": Un 
Humorista Lampoons Bibliotecas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The founders of the great libraries of the 19th century were often ambivalent about whether their goal was to disseminate or conserve knowledge. They were also uncertain about the intended audience. John Cotton Dana of the Newark Public Library was atypical in his populist stance that "it is a proper function of a library to amuse." He argued that a "shallow mind" was better than an "empty one." Other librarians preferred to see themselves as cultivators of public taste and their buildings as uplifting houses of culture. The stuffiness and remoteness of late nineteenth-century libraries provoked satires such as this imaginary dialogue between a bartender (Mr. Dooley) and customer (Mr. Hennessy) in an Irish pub. Humorist Peter Finley Dunne published the piece in  Dissertations by Mr. Dooley  in 1906. Dunne's famous dialogues drew upon prevalent ethnic stereotypes that were a staple of late nineteenth-century humor. Dunne set his exchanges in an Irish bar, but other humorists of this era drew on German, Jewish, and black caricatures.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Gründer der großen Bibliotheken des 19. 
Jahrhunderts waren häufig ungefähr ambivalent, ob ihr Ziel, Wissen 
zu verbreiten oder zu konservieren war. Sie waren auch über die
beabsichtigten Publikum unsicher. John Baumwolle Dana der Newark
allgemeinen Bibliothek war in seiner Volksposition atypisch, die "es 
eine korrekte Funktion einer zu unterhalten ist Bibliothek." Er 
argumentierte, daß ein "flacher Verstand" besser war, als "leert 
ein." Andere Librarian zogen es vor, sich wie Landwirte des 
allgemeinen Geschmacks und ihrer Gebäude als emporhebende Häuser der
Kultur zu sehen. Der Stuffiness und die Entferntheit der späten
19.-Jahrhundert Bibliotheken erregten Satiren wie dieser 
eingebildete Dialog zwischen einem Barmixer (Herr Dooley) und Kunden 
(Herr Hennessy) in einer irischen Publikation. Humorist Peter 
Finley Dunne veröffentlichte das Stück in den Abhandlungen durch 
Herrn Dooley 1906. Dunnes berühmte Dialoge zeichneten nach 
überwiegenden ethnischen Stereotypen, die eine Heftklammer der 
späten 19.-Jahrhundert Stimmung waren. Dunne stellte seine 
Austäusche in einem irischen Stab ein, aber andere Humoristen dieser 
Ära zeichneten auf die deutschen, jüdischen und schwarzen 
Karikaturen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les fondateurs des grandes bibliothèques du 
19ème siècle étaient souvent ambivalents environ si leur but était
de diffuser ou économiser la connaissance. Ils étaient 
également incertains au sujet des assistances destinées. Le 
coton Dana de John de la bibliothèque publique de Newark 
était atypique dans sa position populiste que "c'est une fonction 
appropriée d'une bibliothèque à amuser." Il a argué du fait 
que "un esprit peu profond" était meilleur que "vident un." 
D'autres bibliothécaires ont préféré se voir comme des 
cultivateurs de goût public et de leurs bâtiments en tant que 
maisons élevantes de culture. Le manque d'air et l'éloignement
des bibliothèques en retard de dix-neuvième-siècle ont provoqué 
des satires telles que ce dialogue imaginaire entre un barman (M.
Dooley) et le client (M. Hennessy) dans une publication irlandaise. 
L'humoriste Peter Finley Dunne a édité le morceau en 
dissertations par M. Dooley en 1906. Les dialogues célèbres de
Dunne ont utilisé les stéréotypes ethniques répandus qui étaient 
une agrafe d'humeur en retard de dix-neuvième-siècle. Dunne a 
placé ses échanges d'une barre irlandaise, mais d'autres humoristes 
de cette ère ont dessiné sur les caricatures allemandes, juives, et 
noires.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os founders das bibliotecas grandes do 1ø século
eram frequentemente ambivalent aproximadamente se seu objetivo era 
disseminate ou conservar o conhecimento. Eram também incertos 
sobre as audiências pretendidas. O algodão Dana de John da 
biblioteca pública de Newark era atypical em seu stance populist que 
"é uma função apropriada de uma biblioteca a divertir." 
Discutiu que "uma mente rasa" era melhor do que "esvazía um." 
Outros bibliotecários preferiram ver-se como cultivadores do 
gosto público e dos seus edifícios como casas uplifting da cultura. 
O stuffiness e o remoteness de bibliotecas atrasadas de 
décimo-século provocaram satires tais como este diálogo imaginário
entre um bárman (Sr. Dooley) e o cliente (Sr. Hennessy) em uma 
publicação irish. O humorist Peter Finley Dunne publicou a 
parte nos dissertations pelo Sr. Dooley em 1906. Os diálogos 
famosos de Dunne desenharam em cima dos stereotypes étnicos prevalent
que eram um grampo de um humor atrasado de décimo-século. 
Dunne ajustou suas trocas em uma barra irish, mas outros 
humorists desta era desenharam em caricatures alemães, jewish, e 
pretos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I fondatori delle librerie grandi del 
diciannovesimo secolo erano spesso ambivalent circa se il loro 
obiettivo era di diffondere o conservare la conoscenza. Erano 
egualmente incerte circa i pubblici progettati. Il cotone Dana 
del John della biblioteca pubblica de Newark era atipico nella sua 
posizione populistica che "è una funzione adeguata di una libreria da
divertire." Ha sostenuto che "una mente poco profonda" era 
migliore di "svuota uno." Altri bibliotecari hanno preferito 
vedersi come coltivatori di gusto pubblico e delle loro costruzioni 
come case uplifting di coltura. Lo stuffiness e la distanza 
delle librerie ritardate di diciannovesimo-secolo hanno provocato i 
satires quale questo dialogo immaginario fra un barista (sig. Dooley) 
ed il cliente (sig. Hennessy) in una pubblicazione irlandese. Il
humorist Peter Finley Dunne ha pubblicato la parte in dissertazioni 
dal sig. Dooley in 1906. I dialoghi famosi del Dunne hanno 
dissipato sugli stereotipi etnici prevalenti che erano una graffetta 
di umore ritardato di diciannovesimo-secolo. Dunne ha regolato i
suoi scambi in una barra irlandese, ma altri humorists di questa era 
hanno dissipato sui caricatures tedeschi, ebrei e neri.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι ιδρυτές των μεγάλων βιβλιοθηκών του 19$ου αιώνα 
ήταν συχνά αμφίθυμοι για εάν ο στόχος τους ήταν να διαδώσουν ή
να συντηρήσουν τη γνώση. Ήταν επίσης αβέβαιοι για το 
προοριζόμενο ακροατήριο. Θ*Ιοχν Cotton Dana της 
δημόσιας βιβλιοθήκης του Newark ήταν άτυπος στη λαϊκιστική 
θέση του ότι "είναι μια κατάλληλη λειτουργία μιας βιβλιοθήκης 
για να διασκεδάσει." Υποστήριξε ότι ένα "ρηχό μυαλό" ήταν
καλύτερο από "κενό ένα." Αλλοι βιβλιοθηκάριοι προτίμησαν 
να δουν ως καλλιεργητές της δημόσιας προτίμησης και τα 
κτήριά τους ως τα σπίτια του πολιτισμού. Το stuffiness 
και η απόσταση των πρόσφατων βιβλιοθηκών δέκατος-αιώνα 
προκάλεσαν τις σάτυρες όπως αυτό το φανταστικό διαλογικό 
παράθυρο μεταξύ bartender (ο κ. Dooley) και του πελάτη (ο κ. 
Hennessy) σε ένα ιρλανδικό μπαρ. Ο ευθυμογράφος Peter 
Finley Dunne δημοσίευσε το κομμάτι στις διατριβές από τον κ.
Dooley σε 1906, διάσημα διαλογικά παράθυρα Dunne 
βασίστηκε στα επικρατόντα εθνικά στερεότυπα που ήταν μια βάση 
του πρόσφατου χιούμορ δέκατος-αιώνα. Το Dunne έθεσε τις 
ανταλλαγές του σε μια ιρλανδική ράβδο, αλλά άλλοι ευθυμογράφοι 
αυτής της εποχής επέσυραν την προσοχή στις γερμανικές, 
εβραϊκές, και μαύρες καρικατούρες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los fundadores de las grandes bibliotecas del 
diecinueveavo siglo eran a menudo ambivalentes alrededor si su meta 
era diseminar o conservar conocimiento. Eran también incierta 
sobre las audiencias previstas. El algodón Dana de Juan de la 
biblioteca pública de Newark era anormal en su postura populista que 
"es una función apropiada de una biblioteca a divertirse." Él 
discutió que una "mente baja" fuera mejor que "vacia uno." 
Otros bibliotecarios prefirieron verse como los cultivadores del
gusto público y de sus edificios como casas que elevaban de la 
cultura. La congestión y el alejamiento las últimas de las 
sátiras provocadas del diecinueveavo-siglo bibliotecas tales como 
este diálogo imaginario entre un camarero (Sr. Dooley) y el cliente 
(Sr. Hennessy) en un Humorista irlandés Peter Finley de la 
publicación Dunne publicaron el pedazo en disertaciones de Sr. Dooley
en 1906. Los diálogos famosos de Dunne trazaron sobre los 
estereotipos étnicos frecuentes que eran una grapa del último humor 
del diecinueveavo-siglo. Dunne fijó sus intercambios en una 
barra irlandesa, pero otros humoristas de esta era trazaron en 
caricatures alemanes, judíos, y negros.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087330</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108086</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-rale-boost-to-lithrachoor-a-humorist-lampoons-libraries</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
