<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108459</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108459</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206303</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Soil Science and Technology Home Page</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Boden-Wissenschaft und Technologie-Home Page</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Science du sol et Home Page de technologie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência de solo e Home Page da tecnologia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Geologia e Home Page di tecnologia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αρχική σελίδα εδαφολογικών επιστήμης και τεχνολογίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia de suelo y Home Page de la tecnología</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">looks at soil fertility, nitrogen in soil, soil chemistry, soils as electrical systems, soils as filters, soil physics and particle sizes (silt, sand, and clay), microorganisms in soil, nutrients that plants need, soil morphology, judging soil by feel, structures and shapes of soil, and soil profile images from Arizona, Florida, Michigan, and other states. Learn how soil is formed and how long it takes to create an inch of soil.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">betrachtet Bodenfruchtbarkeit, Stickstoff im 
Boden, in der Bodenchemie, im Boden während elektrische Systeme, im 
Boden als Filter, in der Bodenphysik und in den Teilchengrößen 
(Feinkohle, Sand und Lehm), Mikroorganismen im Boden, Nährstoffe, die
Betriebe benötigen, die Bodenmorphologie und Boden durch Gefühl, 
Strukturen und Formen der Boden- und Bodenprofilbilder vom Arizona, 
von Florida, von Michigan und von anderen Zuständen beurteilt. 
Erlernen Sie, wie Boden gebildet wird und wie lang er nimmt, um 
einen Zoll Boden herzustellen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">regarde la fertilité du sol, azote dans le sol, 
la chimie du sol, les sols pendant que les systèmes électriques, les
sols comme filtres, la physique de sol et les dimensions particulaires
(vase, sable, et argile), micro-organismes dans le sol, aliments dont 
les usines ont besoin, morphologie de sol, jugeant le sol par 
sensation, les structures et les formes des images de sol, et de 
profil de sol d'Arizona, la Floride, du Michigan, et d'autres états. 
Apprenez comment le sol est formé et combien de temps il prend 
pour créer pouce de sol.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">olha a fertilidade de solo, nitrogênio no solo, 
no chemistry de solo, nos solos enquanto sistemas elétricos, nos 
solos como filtros, na física do solo e nos tamanhos de partícula 
(silt, areia, e argila), microorganisms no solo, nutrientes que as 
plantas necessitam, morfologia do solo, julgando o solo pela 
sensação, as estruturas e as formas de imagens do solo, e do perfil 
do solo do arizona, do Florida, do Michigan, e dos outros estados. 
Aprenda como o solo é dado forma e quanto tempo faz exame para 
criar uma polegada do solo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">guarda la fertilità di terreno, azoto in terreno,
la chimica del terreno, terreni mentre i sistemi elettrici, i terreni 
come filtri, la fisica del terreno e le dimensioni delle particelle 
(limo, sabbia ed argilla), microorganismi in terreno, sostanze 
nutrienti di che le piante hanno bisogno, la morfologia del terreno, 
giudicante il terreno dal tatto, le strutture e le figure delle 
immagini di profilo del terreno e del terreno dall'Arizona, da 
Florida, dal Michigan e da altro dichiara. Impari come il
terreno è formato e quanto tempo prende per creare un pollice di 
terreno.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει την εδαφολογική γονιμότητα, άζωτο στο χώμα, 
την εδαφολογική χημεία, τα χώματα ως ηλεκτρικά συστήματα, τα 
χώματα ως φίλτρα, την εδαφολογική φυσική και τα μεγέθη μορίων 
(βούρκος, άμμος, και άργιλος), μικροοργανισμοί στο χώμα, 
θρεπτικές ουσίες που φυτεύει την ανάγκη, εδαφολογική μορφολογία,
που κρίνει το χώμα από την αίσθηση, τις δομές και τις μορφές του
χώματος, και τις εικόνες εδαφοτομής από την Αριζόνα, τη Φλώριδα,
το Μίτσιγκαν, και άλλα κράτη. Μάθετε πώς το χώμα 
διαμορφώνεται και πόσο καιρό πολύ παίρνει για να δημιουργήσει 
μια ίντσα του χώματος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">mira la fertilidad de suelo, nitrógeno de suelo, 
química de suelo, suelos mientras que los sistemas eléctricos, 
suelos como filtros, la física del suelo y tamaños de partícula 
(légamo, arena, y arcilla), microorganismos en suelo, los alimentos 
que las plantas necesitan, morfología del suelo, juzgando el suelo 
por la sensación, las estructuras y las dimensiones de una variable 
de las imágenes del suelo, y del perfil del suelo del Arizona, de la 
Florida, de Michigan, y de otros estados. Aprenda cómo se forma
el suelo y cuánto tiempo toma para crear una pulgada de suelo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206303</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108459</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/soil-science-and-technology-home-page</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
