<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104425</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104425</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087189</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"We Do Our Part."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Wir Tun Unser Teil."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Nous Faisons Notre Partie."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Nós Fazemos Nossa Parte."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Facciamo La Nostra Parte."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Κάνουμε το μέρος μας."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Hacemos Nuestra Parte."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The National Recovery Administration (NRA) was one of a constellation of federal agencies that made up President Franklin D. Roosevelt's New Deal program to help Americans recover from the Great Depression. Established in 1933 in an effort to spur industrial recovery, the NRA sought to use government power to restrain competition and end the downward cycle of wage cuts and price reductions, without abolishing the free market. The administration asked businesses, labor, and consumers to help write new codes for hour limits, minimum wages, and production standards. To encourage voluntary adoption of these new codes, participating businesses were allowed to display a blue eagle logo, and consumers were urged to spend money only where the symbol was displayed. This photograph captures three unlikely spots for the display of the otherwise ubiquitous NRA eagle.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die nationale Wiederanlauf-Leitung (NRA) war eine einer 
Konstellation Bundesämter, die Präsident Franklin D. Roosevelts 
Programm des neuen Abkommens bildeten, um Amerikanern zu helfen, von 
dem großen Tiefstand zu erholen. Hergestellt 1933 in einer 
Bemühung, industriellen Wiederanlauf anzutreiben, suchte das NRA, 
Regierung Energie zu verwenden, Konkurrenz zurückzuhalten und die 
abwärts Schleife der Lohnschnitte und der Preisverkleinerungen zu 
beenden, ohne den freien Markt abzuschaffen. Die Leitung bat um 
um Geschäfte, Arbeit, und Verbraucher zur Hilfe schreiben neue Codes 
für Stunde Begrenzungen, minimale Löhne und Produktion Standards. 
Um freiwillige Annahme dieser neuen Codes anzuregen, wurden 
teilnehmende Geschäfte ein blaues Adlerfirmenzeichen anzeigen 
gelassen, und Verbraucher wurden gedrängt Geld auszugeben nur in dem 
das Symbol angezeigt wurde. Diese Fotographie erfaßt drei 
unwahrscheinliche Punkte für die Bildschirmanzeige des anders 
überall vorhandenen NRA Adlers.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La gestion nationale de reprise (NRA) était une d'une 
constellation d'agences fédérales qui ont composé le programme de 
nouvelle affaire du Président Franklin D. Roosevelt's pour aider des 
Américains à récupérer de la grande dépression. Établi en 
1933 dans un effort de stimuler la reprise industrielle, le NRA a 
recherché à utiliser la puissance de gouvernement de retenir la 
concurrence et de terminer le cycle de haut en bas des réductions de 
salaire et des baisses des prix, sans supprimer le marché libre. 
La gestion a demandé des entreprises, travail, et les 
consommateurs à l'aide écrivent de nouveaux codes pour des limites 
d'heure, des salaires minima, et des normes de production. Pour 
encourager l'adoption volontaire de ces nouveaux codes, des 
entreprises participantes ont été permises d'afficher un logo bleu 
d'aigle, et des consommateurs ont été invités à dépenser l'argent
seulement où le symbole a été affiché. Cette photographie 
capture trois taches peu probables pour l'affichage de l'aigle 
autrement omniprésent de NRA.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A administração nacional da recuperação (NRA) era uma 
de uma constelação das agências federais que compuseram o programa 
do negócio novo do presidente Franklin D. Roosevelt para ajudar a 
americanos recuperar do depression grande. Estabelecido em 1933 
em um esforço spur a recuperação industrial, o NRA procurou usar a 
potência do governo conter a competição e terminar o ciclo 
descendente de cortes de salário e de reduções de preço, sem 
abolishing o mercado livre. A administração pediu negócios, 
trabalho, e os consumidores à ajuda escrevem códigos novos para 
limites da hora, salários mínimos, e padrões de produção. 
Para incentivar o adoption voluntário destes códigos novos, os
negócios participando foram permitidos indicar um logo azul da 
águia, e os consumidores foram incitados gastar o dinheiro somente 
onde o símbolo foi indicado. Esta fotografia captura três 
pontos improváveis para o indicador da águia de outra maneira 
ubiquitous de NRA.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La gestione nazionale di recupero (NRA) era una di una 
costellazione degli enti federali che hanno composto il programma di 
nuovo affare del presidente Franklin D. Roosevelt per aiutare gli 
Americani a recuperare dalla depressione grande. Stabilito in 
1933 in uno sforzo stimolare il recupero industriale, il NRA ha 
cercato di usare l'potenza di governo trattenere la concorrenza e 
concludere il ciclo in discesa dei tagli di stipendio e delle 
riduzioni di prezzi, senza abolire il mercato libero. La 
gestione ha chiesto i commerci, lavoro ed i consumatori ad aiuto 
scrivono i nuovi codici per i limiti di ora, gli stipendi minimi e gli
standard di produzione. Per consigliare all'approvazione 
volontaria di questi nuovi codici, i commerci di partecipazione sono 
stati permessi visualizzare un marchio blu dell'aquila ed i 
consumatori sono stati invitati a spendere i soldi soltanto in
cui il simbolo è stato visualizzato. Questa fotografia blocca 
tre punti improbabili per la visualizzazione dell'aquila al contrario 
ubiquista di NRA.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η εθνική διοίκηση αποκατάστασης (ΕΚΑ) ήταν ένας από 
έναν αστερισμό των ομοσπονδιακών αντιπροσωπειών που αποτέλεσαν το
πρόγραμμα New διαπραγμάτευσης Προέδρου Franklin D. 
Roosevelt's για να βοηθήσουν Αμερικανούς να ανακτήσουν από τη 
μεγάλη οικονομική κρίση. Καθιερωμένη το 1933 σε μια 
προσπάθεια να κεντριστεί η βιομηχανική αποκατάσταση, η ΕΚΑ 
επιδίωξε να χρησιμοποιήσει την κυβερνητική δύναμη να σταματήσει 
τον ανταγωνισμό και να τελειώσει τον προς τα κάτω κύκλο των 
αποκοπών αμοιβών και των μειώσεων τιμών, χωρίς κατάργηση της 
ελεύθερης αγοράς. Η διοίκηση ζήτησε από τις επιχειρήσεις, 
την εργασία, και τους καταναλωτές για να βοηθήσει να γράψει τους 
νέους κώδικες για τα όρια ώρας, τους βασικούς μισθούς, και τα 
πρότυπα παραγωγής. Για να ενθαρρύνουν την εθελοντική 
υιοθέτηση αυτών των νέων κωδίκων, οι συμμετέχουσες επιχειρήσεις 
επιτράπηκαν για να παρουσιάσουν ένα μπλε λογότυπο αετών, και οι 
καταναλωτές ωθήθηκαν για να ξοδεψουν τα χρήματα μόνο όπου το 
σύμβολο παρουσιάστηκε. Αυτή η φωτογραφία συλλαμβάνει τρία 
απίθανα σημεία για την παρουσίαση του ειδάλλως πανταχού παρόντος
αετού ΕΚΑ.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La administración nacional de la recuperación (NRA) era 
una de una constelación de agencias federales que compusieron 
programa del nuevo reparto de presidente Franklin D. Roosevelt para 
ayudar a americanos a recuperarse de la gran depresión. 
Establecido en 1933 en un esfuerzo de estimular la recuperación
industrial, el NRA intentó utilizar potencia del gobierno de refrenar
la competición y de terminar el ciclo hacia abajo de los cortes de 
salario y de las reducciones de precio, sin la supresión del mercado 
libre. La administración pidió los negocios, trabajo, y los 
consumidores a la ayuda escriben los nuevos códigos para los límites
de la hora, los salarios mínimos, y los estándares de producción. 
Para animar la adopción voluntaria de estos nuevos códigos, 
los negocios que participaban fueron permitidos visualizar una 
insignia azul del águila, e impulsaron a los consumidores pasar el 
dinero solamente donde el símbolo fue visualizado. Esta 
fotografía captura tres puntos inverosímiles para la visualización 
del águila de otra manera ubicua de NRA.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087189</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104425</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/we-do-our-part</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
