<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106085</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106085</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087094</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"There Wasn't a Mine Runnin' a Lump O' Coal": A Kentucky Coal Miner Remembers the Influenza Pandemic of 1918-1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"es gab nicht eine Grube Runnin ' ein Klumpen O ' 
Kohle": Ein Kentucky Kohle-Bergmann erinnert sich die an Grippe 
Pandemic von 1918-1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"il n'y avait pas une mine Runnin 'un morceau O 
'charbon" : Un mineur du Kentucky se rappelle la Pandémie de 
grippe de 1918-1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"não havia uma mina Runnin ' uma protuberância O 
' carvão": Um mineiro de carvão de Kentucky recorda o 
influenza Pandemic de 1918-1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"ci non era una miniera Runnin 'un grumo la O 
'carbone": Un minatore delle miniere di carbone del Kentucky si 
ricorda della riossidazione Pandemic di 1918-1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Δεν υπήρξε ένα ορυχείο Runnin" ένα κομμάτι ο 
"άνθρακασ": Ένας ανθρακωρύχος του Κεντάκυ θυμάται την 
πανδημία γρίπης του 1918-1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"no había una mina Runnin ' un terrón O ' 
carbón": Un minero de carbón de Kentucky recuerda la gripe 
Pandemic de 1918-1919</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1918 the Spanish influenza hit the United States and then the rest of the world with such swiftness that it sometimes went unnoticed until it had already passed. By mid-1919 it had killed more people than any other disease in a similar period in the history of the world. Kentucky coal miner Teamus Bartley was interviewed at ninety-five years of age and vividly recalled the impact of the flu pandemic on his community. With a dearth of healthy laborers, the mines shut down for six weeks in 1918 and miners went from digging coal to digging graves.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In 1918 schlug die Spanischgrippe die Vereinigten 
Staaten und dann den Rest der Welt mit solchem swiftness, daß sie 
manchmal unbemerkt ging, bis sie bereits überschritten hatte. 
Durch mid-1919 hatte sie mehr Leute als jede mögliche andere 
Krankheit in einer ähnlichen Periode in der Geschichte der Welt 
beendet. Kentucky Kohlebergmann Teamus Bartley wurde bei 
fünfundneunzig Jahren des Alters interviewt und vividly die 
Auswirkung der Grippe erinnerte an, die auf seine Gemeinschaft 
pandemic ist. Zu einem Mangel der gesunden Arbeiter, gehörten 
die Gruben abgeschaltet für sechs Wochen 1918 und die Bergmänner von
grabender Kohle zu grabenden Gräbern.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans 1918 la grippe d'Espagnol a frappé les 
Etats-Unis et puis le reste du monde avec un tel swiftness qu'elle est
parfois passée inapperçue jusqu'à ce qu'elle ait déjà passé. 
Par mid-1919 elle avait détruit plus de personnes que n'importe
quelle autre maladie dans une période semblable dans l'histoire du 
monde. Le mineur du Kentucky Teamus Bartley a été interviewé 
à quatre-vingt-quinze ans et a vividly rappelé l'impact de la 
pandémie de grippe sur sa communauté. La pénurie de 
travailleurs en bonne santé, les mines étant arrêté pendant six 
semaines en 1918 et les mineurs sont allés du charbon creusant aux 
tombes creusantes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1918 o influenza do espanhol bateu os estados 
unidos e então o rest.of.the.world com tal swiftness que foi às 
vezes despercebido até que passou já. Por mid-1919 tinha 
matado mais povos do que toda a outra doença em um período similar 
no history do mundo. O mineiro de carvão Teamus de Kentucky 
Bartley foi entrevistado em ninety-five anos de idade e recordou 
vividly o impacto do flu pandemic em sua comunidade. Com um 
dearth de laborers saudáveis, as minas fechadas para baixo por seis 
semanas em 1918 e os mineiros foram do carvão escavando às 
sepulturas escavando.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1918 lo Spagnolo che la riossidazione ha colpito
unito Dichiara ed allora il resto del mondo con tale swiftness 
che a volte ha passato inosservato fino a che già non abbia passato. 
Da mid-1919 aveva ucciso più gente che qualunque altra malattia
in un periodo simile nella storia del mondo. Il minatore delle 
miniere di carbone del Kentucky Teamus Bartley è stato intervistato a
novantacinque anni e vividly ha ricordato l'effetto del flu pandemic 
sulla sua Comunità. Con una penuria di lavoratori in buona 
salute, le miniere hanno interrotto per sei settimane in 1918 ed i 
minatori sono andato da carbone di scavatura alle tombe di scavatura.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1918 η ισπανική γρίπη χτύπησε τις Ηνωμένες 
Πολιτείες και έπειτα κόσμος με τέτοια ταχύτητα ότι επέρασε 
μερικές φορές απαρατήρητη έως ότου είχε περάσει ήδη. 
Από τα μέσα του 1919 είχε σκοτώσει περισσότερους 
ανθρώπους από οποιαδήποτε άλληδήποτε ασθένεια σε παρόμοια 
περίοδο στην ιστορία του κόσμου. Ο ανθρακωρύχος Teamus 
Bartley του Κεντάκυ πέρασε από συνέντευξη ενενήντα πέντε 
ετών και υπενθύμισε ζωντανά τον αντίκτυπο της πανδημίας γρίπης 
στην κοινότητά του. Με μια έλλειψη των υγιών laborers, το
κλείσιμο ορυχείων για έξι εβδομάδες το 1918 και τους 
ανθρακωρύχους πήγε από το σκάψιμο του άνθρακα στο σκάψιμο των 
τάφων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1918 la gripe del español golpeó los Estados 
Unidos y entonces el resto del mundo con tal swiftness que iba a veces
inadvertida hasta que había pasado ya. Por mid-1919 había 
matado a más gente que cualquier otra enfermedad en un período 
similar en la historia del mundo. El minero de carbón de 
Kentucky Teamus Bartley fue entrevistado con en noventa y cinco años 
de la edad y vividly recordó el impacto de la gripe pandemic en su 
comunidad. Con una penuria de trabajadores sanos, las minas 
cerrada por seis semanas en 1918 y los mineros fueron del carbón que 
cavaba a los sepulcros que cavaban.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087094</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106085</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/there-wasnt-a-mine-runnin-a-lump-o-coal-a-kentucky-coal-miner-remembers-the-influenza-pandemic-of-1918-1919</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
