<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103545</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103545</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087017</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Paterson Strike Pageant Program</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Paterson Schlagpageant-Programm</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Programme de Reconstitution historique de 
Grève de Paterson</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Programa Do Pageant Da Batida De Paterson</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Programma Di Spettacolo Di Colpo Di Paterson</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το πρόγραμμα θεάματος απεργίας Paterson</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Programa Del Desfile De la Huelga De Paterson</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1913, John Reed (later famous for his firsthand account of the Russian Revolution) met Bill Haywood, a leader of the Industrial Workers of the World (Wobblies). Reed ventured to Paterson, New Jersey, to learn about the Wobbly-led silk workers' strike then in progress and decided to mount a massive public pageant to publicize the strike and raise money for the strikers. He won financial backing from art patron Mabel Dodge and enlisted artists such as John Sloan, who painted a ninety-foot backdrop depicting the Paterson silk mills. The pageant opened on June 7 in Madison Square Garden and ended with the workers and the audience triumphantly singing the "Internationale," the anthem of international socialism. Unfortunately, neither the pageant nor the strike ended on a triumphant note. The pageant lost money while the strike ended in defeat after five months. Nonetheless, the pageant represented an important moment in the alliance between modern art and labor radicalism.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1913 traf das John Schilf (später berühmt für 
seins aus erster Hand bezogenes Konto der russischen Umdrehung) 
Rechnung Haywood, ein Führer der industriellen Arbeiter der Welt 
(Wobblies). Schilf riskiert zu Paterson, Neu-Jersey, um über 
den Wobbly-führenden silk Schlag der Arbeiter zu erlernen dann in 
Bewegung und entschieden, um einen massiven allgemeinen Pageant 
einzuhängen, um den Schlag zu publizieren und Geld für die 
Schlaggeräte anzuheben. Er gewann finanziellen Schutzträger 
vom kunstgönner Mabel raschen Ausweichen und trug Künstler wie John 
Sloan ein, der einen Neunzigfuß Hintergrund malte, der die Paterson 
Seidetausendstel bildlich darstellt. Der Pageant öffnete sich 
an Juni 7 Madison im quadratischen Garten und beendete mit den 
Arbeitern und den Publikum, die triumphierend das "Internationale," 
die Hymne des internationalen sozialismus singen. 
Leider weder beendeten der Pageant noch der Schlag auf einer 
triumphierenden Anmerkung. Der Pageant verlor Geld, während der
Schlag in der Niederlage nach fünf Monaten beendete. 
Nichtsdestoweniger stellte der Pageant einen wichtigen Moment im
Bündnis zwischen moderner kunst und Arbeit Radikalismus dar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1913, le roseau de John (plus tard célèbre 
pour le sien compte de première main de la révolution russe) a 
rencontré la facture Haywood, une amorce des ouvriers industriels du 
monde (Wobblies). Roseau essayé à Paterson, New Jersey, pour 
se renseigner sur la grève des ouvriers en soie Wobbly-menés puis en
marche et décidé pour monter une reconstitution historique publique 
massive pour donner de la publicité à la grève et pour soulever 
l'argent pour les butées. Il a gagné l'aide financière du 
détour de Mabel de patron d'art et a enrôlé des artistes tels que 
John Sloan, qui a peint un contexte de quatre-vingt-dix-pied 
dépeignant les moulins de soie de Paterson. La reconstitution 
historique s'est ouverte juin 7 dans le jardin carré de Madison et a 
terminé avec les ouvriers et les assistances chantant triomphantement
l'"Internationale," le hymne du socialisme international. 
Malheureusement, ni la reconstitution historique ni la grève 
n'a terminé sur une note triomphante. La reconstitution 
historique a détruit l'argent tandis que la grève terminait dans la 
défaite après cinq mois. Néanmoins, la reconstitution 
historique a représenté un moment important dans l'alliance entre 
l'art et le radicalisme modernes de travail.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1913, a lingüeta de John (mais tarde famosa 
para his cliente firsthand da volta russian) encontrou-se com a conta 
Haywood, um líder dos trabalhadores industriais do mundo (Wobblies). 
Lingüeta arriscada a Paterson, Novo-Jersey, aprender sobre a 
batida dos trabalhadores de seda Wobbly-conduzidos então em andamento
e decidida montar um pageant público maciço para publicize a batida 
e para levantar o dinheiro para os grevistas. Ganhou o 
revestimento protetor financeiro do rodeio de Mabel do patron da arte 
e alistou artistas tais como John Sloan, que pintou um backdrop de 
ninety-pé que descreve os moinhos da seda de Paterson. O 
pageant abriu junho em 7 no jardim quadrado de Madison e terminou com 
os trabalhadores e as audiências que cantam triunfante o 
"Internationale," o anthem do socialismo internacional. 
Infelizmente, nem o pageant nem a batida terminaram em uma nota 
triunfante. O pageant perdeu o dinheiro quando a batida terminou
na derrota após cinco meses. Nonetheless, o pageant representou
um momento importante no alliance entre a arte e o radicalism modernos
do trabalho.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1913, la canna del John (più successivamente 
famosa per sua cliente di prima mano della rivoluzione russa) ha 
venuto a contatto della fattura Haywood, un capo dei lavoratori
dell'industria del mondo (Wobblies). Canna tentata a Paterson, 
Nuovo-Jersey, per imparare circa il colpo degli operai di seta 
Wobbly-condotti allora in progresso e decisa per montare uno 
spettacolo pubblico voluminoso per divulg il colpo e per alzare soldi
per i percussori. Ha vinto la protezione finanziaria 
dall'espediente di Mabel del patrono di arte ed ha arruolato gli 
artisti quale John Sloan, che ha verniciato un contesto del 
novanta-piede che descrive i laminatoi della seta di Paterson. 
Lo spettacolo si è aperto il 7 giugno nel giardino quadrato de
Madison e si è concluso con gli operai ed i pubblici che cantano 
trionfalmente "il Internationale," il anthem del socialism 
internazionale. Purtroppo, nè lo spettacolo nè il colpo si 
è concluso su una nota trionfante. Lo spettacolo ha perso i 
soldi mentre il colpo si è concluso nella sconfitta dopo cinque mesi.
Ciò nonostante, lo spettacolo ha rappresentato un momento 
importante nell'alleanza fra l'arte ed il radicalism moderni di 
lavoro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1913, John Reed (αργότερα διάσημος για τον 
από πρώτο χέρι απολογισμό του της ρωσικής επανάστασης) 
συνάντησε Bill Haywood, ένας ηγέτης των βιομηχανικών 
εργατών του κόσμου (wobblies). Ο κάλαμος αποτόλμησε σε 
Paterson, Νιου Τζέρσεϋ, να μάθει για την ωοψψλυ-οδηγημένη 
απεργία των εργαζομένων μεταξιού έπειτα υπό εξέλιξη και 
αποφάσισε να επικολλήσει ένα ογκώδες δημόσιο θέαμα για να 
κοινοποιήσει την απεργία και να συγκεντρώσει τα χρήματα για τους 
απεργούς. Κέρδισε την οικονομική υποστήριξη από το 
τέχνασμα Mabel προστατών τέχνης και στρατολόγησε τους 
καλλιτέχνες όπως John Sloan, ο οποίος χρωμάτισε ένα φόντο 
ενενήντα-ποδιών απεικονίζοντας τους μύλους μεταξιού Paterson. 
Το θέαμα άνοιξε στις 7 Ιουνίου στον τετραγωνικό κήπο του 
Μάντισον και τελείωσε με τους εργαζομένους και το ακροατήριο που 
τραγουδούν triumphantly το "Internationale," ο ύμνος του 
διεθνούς σοσιαλισμού. Δυστυχώς, ούτε το θέαμα ούτε η 
απεργία δεν τελείωσε σε μια θριαμβευτική σημείωση. Το θέαμα
έχασε τα χρήματα ενώ η απεργία τελείωσε στην ήττα μετά από 
πέντε μήνες. Εν τούτοις, το θέαμα αντιπροσώπευσε μια 
σημαντική στιγμή στη συμμαχία μεταξύ της μοντέρνων τέχνης και 
της ριζοσπαστισμού εργασίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1913, la caña de Juan (más adelante famosa 
por la suya cuenta de primera mano de la revolución rusa) resolvió 
la cuenta Haywood, arranque de cinta de los trabajadores industriales 
del mundo (Wobblies). Caña aventurada a Paterson, Nuevo-Jersey,
para aprender sobre la huelga de los trabajadores de seda 
Wobbly-conducidos entonces en marcha y decidida para montar un desfile
público masivo para publicar la huelga y para levantar el dinero para
los huelguistas. Él ganó el forro financiero del regate de 
Mabel el patrón del arte y alistó a artistas tales como Juan Sloan, 
que pintó un contexto del noventa-pie que representaba los molinos de
la seda de Paterson. El desfile se abrió 7 de junio en el 
jardín cuadrado de Madison y terminó con los trabajadores y las 
audiencias que cantaban triunfante el "Internationale," el himno del 
socialismo internacional. Desafortunadamente, ni el desfile ni 
la huelga terminó en una nota triunfante. El desfile perdió el
dinero mientras que la huelga terminó en derrota después de cinco 
meses. No obstante, el desfile representó un momento importante
en la alianza entre el arte y el radicalismo modernos del trabajo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087017</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103545</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-paterson-strike-pageant-program</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
