<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104402</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104402</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206521</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Immigration</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Immigration</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Immigration</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Immigration</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Immigrazione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μετανάστευση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Inmigración</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">looks at European and Chinese immigration to the U.S., early 20th century immigration documents, 350 years of Jewish life in America, America as a religious refuge (17th century), Irish words, the Tenement Museum in New York City, and the first Yiddish cookbook in America. The website includes images of Ellis Island and the Statue of Liberty, stories of immigrants, and interactive timelines and maps showing immigration patterns.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Blicke auf europäische und chinesische 
Immigration in die VEREINIGTEN STAATEN, früh 20. 
Jahrhundertimmigrationdokumente, 350 Jahre jüdische Lebensdauer in 
Amerika, Amerika als frommer Schutz (17. Jahrhundert), irische 
Wörter, das Wohnung-Museum in New York City und das erste Yiddish 
Kochbuch in Amerika. Die Web site schließt Bilder von Ellis 
Island und Freiheitsstatue, Geschichten der Immigranten und 
interaktive timelines und die Karten, die Immigrationmuster zeigen 
ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">regards à l'immigration européenne et chinoise 
vers les ETATS-UNIS, début du 20ème documents d'immigration de 
siècle, 350 ans de la vie juive en Amérique, Amérique comme refuge 
religieux (17ème siècle), mots irlandais, musée d'appartement à 
New York City, et premier livre de cuisine de Yiddish en Amérique. 
Le site Web inclut des images d'île d'Ellis et la statue de la 
liberté, les histoires des immigrés, et les chronologies interactives
et les cartes montrant des configurations d'immigration.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">olhares no immigration europeu e chinês aos 
ESTADOS UNIDOS, cedo 20os originais do immigration do século, 350 
anos da vida jewish em América, América como um refúgio religioso 
(17o século), palavras irish, o museu do tenement em New York City, e
o primeiro cookbook de Yiddish em América. O Web site inclui 
imagens do console de Ellis e a estátua de liberdade, histórias dos 
immigrants, e timelines interativos e os mapas que mostram testes 
padrões do immigration.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">sguardi ad immigrazione europea e cinese negli
STATI UNITI, inizio del 20esimo documenti di immigrazione di secolo, 
350 anni di vita ebrea in America, America come un rifugio religioso 
(diciassettesimo secolo), le parole irlandesi, il museo 
dell'appartamento a New York City ed il primo cookbook di Yiddish in 
America. Il Web site include le immagini dell'isola di Ellis e 
la statua della libertà, storia degli immigranti e timelines 
interattivi e programmi che mostrano i modelli di immigrazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει την ευρωπαϊκή και κινεζική μετανάστευση στις
ΗΠΑ, του 20ού νωρίς έγγραφα μετανάστευσης αιώνα, 350 έτη 
εβραϊκής ζωής στην Αμερική, Αμερική ως θρησκευτικό καταφύγιο 
(17$ος αιώνας), ιρλανδικές λέξεις, μουσείο κατοικιών στην πόλη 
της Νέας Υόρκης, και πρώτο γίντις cookbook στην Αμερική. 
Ο ιστοχώρος περιλαμβάνει τις εικόνες του νησιού Ellis και
του αγάλματος της ελευθερίας, τις ιστορίες των μεταναστών, και τις
διαλογικές υποδείξεις ως προς το χρόνο και τους χάρτες που 
εμφανίζουν πρότυπα μετανάστευσης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">miradas en la inmigración europea y china a los 
ESTADOS UNIDOS, temprano vigésimos documentos de la inmigración del 
siglo, 350 años de vida judía en América, América como un refugio 
religioso (17mo siglo), las palabras irlandesas, el museo de la 
vivienda en New York City, y el primer cookbook de Yiddish en 
América. El Web site incluye imágenes de la isla de Ellis y la
estatua de la libertad, las historias de inmigrantes, y los timelines 
interactivos y las correspondencias que muestran modelos de la 
inmigración.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206521</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104402</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/immigration</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
