<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105874</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105874</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209900</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Concave Polygon </string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Konkaves Polygon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Polygone Concave</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Polygon Côncavo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Poligono Concavo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοίλο πολύγωνο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Polígono Cóncavo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate the concept of a concave polygon - one where at least one interior angle is greater than 180 degrees. The applet shows an irregular polygon initially with one interior angle greater than 180 degrees. The user can drag any vertex and change the number of sides in the range 3..99. When the polygon is concave, the angles that make it so are drawn in red. The goal is to show through experimentation what the concept of concavity really means. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die das Konzept eines konkaven Polygons - eins zeigen, wo 
mindestens ein Innenwinkel grösser als 180 Grad ist. Der applet
zeigt einem unregelmäßigen Polygon zuerst mit einem Innenwinkel 
grösser als 180 Grad. Der Benutzer kann jeden möglichen Gipfel
schleppen und die Zahl Seiten in der Strecke 3..99 ändern. Wenn
das Polygon konkav ist, die Winkel, die es also bilden, in Rot 
gezeichnet werden. Das Ziel ist, durch Experimentieren zu 
zeigen, was das Konzept der Konkavität wirklich bedeutet. 
Applet kann zum vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit einem 
Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. Nachgebrauch im 
Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von jedem möglichem web 
browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den benötigten LOGON 
wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Bestandteil des 
Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent le concept d'un polygone concave - un où au moins un 
angle intérieur est des 180 degrés plus grands que. L'applet 
montre un polygone irrégulier au commencement avec degrés plus 
grands que d'un angle intérieur des 180. L'utilisateur peut 
traîner n'importe quel sommet et changer le nombre de côtés dans 
l'intervalle 3..99. Quand le polygone est concave, les angles 
qui le font ainsi sont dessiné dans le rouge. Le but est de 
montrer par l'expérimentation ce que signifie vraiment le concept de 
la concavité. L'applet peut être agrandi à la taille de plein
écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de classe. Le 
après utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant peut lui 
accéder encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la maison ou 
dans la bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion exigée. 
Cette ressource est un composant du projet interactif de manuel 
de la géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem o conceito de um polygon côncavo - um onde ao menos um 
ângulo interior é mais grande de 180 graus. O applet mostra a 
um polygon irregular inicialmente com um ângulo interior mais 
extremamente de 180 graus. O usuário pode arrastar todo o 
vertex e mudar o número dos lados na escala 3..99. Quando o 
polygon é côncavo, os ângulos que o fazem assim que estão 
desenhados no vermelho. O objetivo é mostrar com a 
experimentação o que o conceito do concavity significa realmente. 
O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de tela cheia para o uso 
com um projetor da sala de aula. O depois de uso na sala de 
aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo o web browser na 
HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma sessão requerido. 
Este recurso é um componente do projeto interativo do textbook 
da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano il concetto di un poligono concavo - uno dove almeno un 
angolo interno è più grande di 180 gradi. Il applet mostra ad 
un poligono irregolare inizialmente con un angolo interno più 
notevolmente di 180 gradi. L'utente può trascinare tutto il 
vertice e cambiare il numero di lati nella gamma 3..99. Quando 
il poligono è concavo, gli angoli che lo fanno in modo da sono 
dissipati nel colore rosso. L'obiettivo è di mostrare con 
esperimento che cosa il concetto della concavità realmente significa.
Il applet può essere ingrandito al formato di schermo pieno per
uso con un proiettore dell'aula. La post-utilizzazione 
nell'aula, allievo può accederle ancora da tutto il web browser nel 
paese o nella libreria senza l'inizio attività richiesto. 
Questa risorsa è un componente del progetto interattivo del 
manuale della geometria di riferimento aperto di per la matematica a 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν την έννοια ενός κοίλου πολυγώνου - ένα όπου 
τουλάχιστον μια εσωτερική γωνία είναι μεγαλύτερη από 180 
βαθμούς. Το applet εμφανίζει ανώμαλο πολύγωνο αρχικά με 
μια εσωτερική γωνία μεγαλύτερη από 180 βαθμούς. Ο 
χρήστης μπορεί να σέρει οποιοδήποτε vertex και να αλλάξει τον 
αριθμό πλευρών στη σειρά 3,,99. Όταν το πολύγωνο είναι 
κοίλο, οι γωνίες που κάνουν αυτό έτσι σύρονται στο κόκκινο. 
Ο στόχος είναι να εμφανιστεί μέσω του πειραματισμού τι η 
έννοια concavity σημαίνει πραγματικά. Το Applet μπορεί
να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με έναν 
προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο 
σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε 
ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια 
εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς 
είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος εγχειριδίων 
γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran el concepto de un polígono cóncavo - uno donde por lo 
menos está mayor un ángulo interior de 180 grados. El applet 
muestra a polígono irregular inicialmente con un ángulo interior 
mayor de 180 grados. El utilizador puede arrastrar cualquier 
cima y cambiar el número de caras en el rango 3..99. Cuando el 
polígono es cóncavo, los ángulos que lo hacen así que se trazan en
rojo. La meta es mostrar con la experimentación lo que 
significa el concepto de la concavidad realmente. El applet se 
puede agrandar a la talla de la pantalla completa para el uso con un 
proyector de la sala de clase. El uso posterior en la sala de 
clase, estudiante puede tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier web 
browser en el país o en la biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. 
Este recurso es un componente del proyecto interactivo del libro
de textos de la geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas
en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209900</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105874</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/concave-polygon</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
