<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107581</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107581</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212176</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Solar Physics: The Sun Spot Cycle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Solarphysik: Die Sonne-Punkt-Schleife</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Physique Solaire : Le Cycle de Tache du 
Soleil</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Física Solar: O Ciclo Do Ponto Do Sol</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fisica Solare: Il Ciclo Del Punto Del Sole</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ηλιακή φυσική: Ο κύκλος σημείων ήλιων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Física Solar: El Ciclo Del Punto Del Sol</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This NASA website contains extensive information on sun spots and sun spot prediction. Users have access to several forms of graphical and numerical data such as sun spot numbers, the Maunder minimum, the Butterfly diagram, the Greenwich sunspot data and sun spot cycle predictions. The site also includes a wealth of information about the sun and NASA's ongoing sun research.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese die NASA Web site enthält umfangreiche 
Informationen über Sonnepunkte und Sonnepunktvorhersage. 
Benutzer haben Zugriff zu einigen Formularen von graphischem und
numerische Daten wie Sonne beschmutzen Zahlen, das Maunder Minimum, 
das Basisrecheneinheit Diagramm, die Greenwich Sunspotdaten und die 
Sonnepunktschleifevorhersagen. Die Site schließt auch eine 
Fülle der Informationen Forschung über die der Sonne und 
fortwährende der Sonne der NASAS ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site Web de la NASA contient l'information 
étendue sur des taches du soleil et la prévision de tache du soleil.
Les utilisateurs ont accès à plusieurs formes de graphique et 
les données numériques telles que le soleil repèrent des nombres, 
le minimum de Maunder, le diagramme de papillon, les données de tache
solaire de Greenwich et des prévisions de cycle de tache du soleil. 
Le site inclut également une richesse d'informations la 
recherche continue sur soleil et du soleil de la NASA.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Web site da NASA contem a informação 
extensiva em pontos do sol e em predição do ponto do sol. Os 
usuários têm o acesso a diversos formulários de gráfico e os dados
numéricos tais como o sol mancham números, o mínimo de Maunder, o 
diagrama da borboleta, os dados do sunspot de Greenwich e predições 
do ciclo do ponto do sol. O local inclui também uma riqueza da 
informação sobre a pesquisa ongoing do sol e do sol da NASA.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Web site della NASA contiene le vaste 
informazioni sui punti del sole e sulla previsione del punto del sole.
Gli utenti hanno accesso a parecchie forme di grafico ed i dati 
numerici quale il sole macchiano i numeri, il minimo di Maunder, lo 
schema della farfalla, i dati di sunspot de Greenwich e le previsioni 
del ciclo del punto del sole. Il luogo egualmente include una 
ricchezza delle informazioni sulla ricerca continua del sole della 
NASA e del sole.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος της NASA περιέχει τις εκτενείς 
πληροφορίες επιτόπου ήλιων και την πρόβλεψη σημείων ήλιων. 
Οι χρήστες έχουν πρόσβαση σε διάφορες μορφές των γραφικών 
και αριθμητικών στοιχείων όπως οι αριθμοί σημείων ήλιων, το 
ελάχιστο Maunder, το διάγραμμα πεταλούδων, τα στοιχεία ηλιακής
κηλίδας του Γκρήνουιτς και οι προβλέψεις κύκλων σημείων ήλιων. 
Η περιοχή περιλαμβάνει επίσης έναν πλούτο των πληροφοριών 
για την έρευνα ήλιων και τρέχουσα ήλιων της NASA.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este Web site de la NASA contiene la información 
extensa sobre puntos del sol y la predicción del punto del sol. 
Los utilizadores tienen acceso a varias formas de gráfico y los
datos numéricos tales como sol manchan números, el mínimo de 
Maunder, el diagrama de la mariposa, los datos de la mancha solar de 
Greenwich y las predicciones del ciclo del punto del sol. El 
sitio también incluye una abundancia de la información sobre la 
investigación en curso del sol y del sol de la NASA.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:DAVID HATHAWAY
FN:DAVID HATHAWAY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212176</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107581</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/solar-physics-the-sun-spot-cycle</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
