<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103252</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103252</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200393</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Algebra IB</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Algebra IB</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Algèbre IB</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Álgebra IB</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Algebra IB</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αλγεβρα IB</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Álgebra IB</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Welcome to the NROC Introductory Algebra course. This curriculum emphasizes a multi-representational approach to algebra, with concepts, results, and problems being expressed graphically, analytically, and verbally. It develops algebraic fluency by providing students with the skills needed to solve equations and perform important manipulations with numbers, variables, equations, and inequalities. In addition, the course develops proficiency with operations involving monomial and polynomial expressions. The main unifying themes of the course include understanding, writing, solving, and graphing linear equations, systems of linear equations and inequalities, quadratic equations, and rational equations.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Willkommen zum NROC einleitenden Algebrakurs. 
Dieser Lehrplan hebt eine multi-representational Annäherung zur
Algebra, mit Konzepten, zu den Resultaten und zu den Problemen 
graphisch, analytisch und, die mündlich ausgedrückt werden hervor. 
Er entwickelt algebraische Flußigkeit, indem er Kursteilnehmer 
mit den Fähigkeiten versieht, die benötigt werden, um Gleichungen zu
lösen und wichtige Handhabungen mit Zahlen, Variablen, Gleichungen 
und Verschiedenheiten durchzuführen. Zusätzlich entwickelt der
Kurs Leistungsfähigkeit mit den Operationen, die Eingliedriges und 
polynomische Ausdrücke mit einbeziehen. Die 
Hauptvereinheitlichenthemen des Kurses enthalten das Verstehen, das 
Schreiben, das Lösen und die graphischee Darstellung der linearen 
Gleichungen, der Systeme der linearen Gleichungen und der 
Verschiedenheiten, der quadratischen Gleichungen und der rationalen 
Gleichungen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bienvenue au cours préliminaire d'algèbre de 
NROC. Ce programme d'études souligne une approche de 
multi-représentatif à l'algèbre, avec des concepts, aux résultats, et 
aux problèmes étant exprimés graphiquement, analytiquement, et 
verbalement. Il développe la maîtrise algébrique en 
fournissant à des étudiants les qualifications requises pour 
résoudre des équations et pour exécuter des manipulations 
importantes avec des nombres, des variables, des équations, et des 
inégalités. En outre, le cours développe la compétence avec 
des exécutions impliquant le monôme et les expressions polynômes. 
Les thèmes principaux d'unification du cours incluent 
l'arrangement, écriture, résolvant, et représentant graphiquement 
des équations linéaires, des systèmes des équations et des 
inégalités linéaires, des équations quadratiques, et des 
équations raisonnables.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Boa vinda ao curso introdutório da álgebra de 
NROC. Este curriculum emfatiza uma aproximação do 
multi-representational à álgebra, com conceitos, aos resultados, e 
aos problemas que estão sendo expressados gràfica, analìticamente, 
e verbal. Desenvolve o fluency algébrico fornecendo estudantes 
com as habilidades necessitadas resolver equações e executar 
manipulações importantes com os números, as variáveis, as 
equações, e os desigualdades. Além, o curso desenvolve a 
proficiência com as operações que envolvem o monômio e expressões
polynomial. Os temas principais unifying do curso incluem a 
compreensão, a escrita, resolver, e representar graficamente de 
equações lineares, de sistemas de equações e de desigualdades 
lineares, de equações quadráticas, e de equações racionais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Benvenuto al corso introduttivo di algebra di 
NROC. Questo programma di studi dà risalto ad un metodo di 
multi-representational ad algebra, con i concetti, ai risultati ed ai 
problemi che sono espressi graficamente, analiticamente e verbalmente.
Sviluppa il fluency algebrico fornendo agli allievi le abilità 
state necessarie per risolvere le equazioni e realizzare le 
manipolazioni importanti con i numeri, le variabili, le equazioni e le
diseguaglianze. In più, il corso sviluppa la competenza con i 
funzionamenti che coinvolgono il monomial e le espressioni 
polinomiali. I temi principali di unificazione del corso 
includono capire, la scrittura, risolvere e rappresentare graficamente
le equazioni lineari, i sistemi delle equazioni e delle diseguaglianze
lineari, le equazioni quadratiche e delle equazioni razionali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Υποδοχή στην εισαγωγική σειρά μαθημάτων άλγεβρας 
NROC. Αυτό το πρόγραμμα σπουδών υπογραμμίζει μια 
πολυ-αντιπροσωπευτική προσέγγιση στην άλγεβρα, με τις έννοιες, τα 
αποτελέσματα, και τα προβλήματα που εκφράζονται γραφικά, 
αναλυτικά, και προφορικά. Αναπτύσσει την αλγεβρική άνεση με
την παροχή των σπουδαστών τις δεξιότητες που απαιτούνται για να 
λύσουν τις εξισώσεις και να εκτελέσουν τους σημαντικούς 
χειρισμούς με τους αριθμούς, τις μεταβλητές, τις εξισώσεις, και 
τις ανισότητες. Επιπλέον, η σειρά μαθημάτων αναπτύσσει την 
ικανότητα με τις διαδικασίες που περιλαμβάνουν τις monomial και 
πολυωνυμικές εκφράσεις. Τα βασικά ενοποιώντας θέματα της 
σειράς μαθημάτων περιλαμβάνουν την κατανόηση, το γράψιμο, την 
επίλυση, και να δώσουν με γραφική παράσταση των γραμμικών 
εξισώσεων, των συστημάτων των γραμμικών εξισώσεων και των 
ανισοτήτων, των δευτέρου βαθμού εξισώσεων, και των λογικών 
εξισώσεων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Recepción al curso introductorio de la álgebra 
de NROC. Este plan de estudios acentúa un acercamiento del 
multi-representational a la álgebra, con conceptos, a los resultados,
y a los problemas que son expresados gráficamente, analíticamente, y
verbalmente. Desarrolla fluidez algebraica proveiendo de 
estudiantes las habilidades necesitadas para solucionar ecuaciones y 
para realizar manipulaciones importantes con números, variables, 
ecuaciones, y desigualdades. Además, el curso desarrolla 
habilidad con las operaciones que implican monomio y expresiones 
polinómicas. Los temas principales de la unificación del curso
incluyen entender, escribir, solucionar, y la representación gráfica
de ecuaciones lineares, de los sistemas de ecuaciones y de 
desigualdades lineares, de las ecuaciones cuadráticas, y de las 
ecuaciones gra'ficamente racionales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MONTEREY INSTITUTE FOR TECHNOLOGY AND EDUCATION AND UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA
FN:MONTEREY INSTITUTE FOR TECHNOLOGY AND EDUCATION AND UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200393</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103252</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/algebraib</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
