<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105251</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105251</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086703</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Our First Poll Tax Drive": The American G.I. Forum Fights Disenfranchisement of Mexican Americans in Texas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Unser Erstes Gemeindeabgabe-Laufwerk": 
Amerikanische G.I. Forum Fights Disenfranchisement der 
mexikanischen Amerikaner in Texas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Notre Premier Lecteur d'Impôt local" : 
G.I. Forum Fights américain Disenfranchisement des Américains 
mexicains dans le Texas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Nossa Primeira Movimentação Do Imposto De 
Votação": O G.I. americano Forum Luta Disenfranchisement de 
americanos mexicanos em Texas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Il Nostro Primo Azionamento Di Imposta Di 
Scrutinio": Il G.I. Forum Fights americano Disenfranchisement 
degli Americani messicani nel Texas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το "πρώτο Drive κεφαλικού φόρου μασ": Οι 
αμερικανικές G.I. πάλες Disenfranchisement φόρουμ 
μεξικάνικων Αμερικανών στο Τέξας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Nuestro Primer Mecanismo impulsor Del Impuesto 
De Encuesta": El G.I. americano Forum Fights Disenfranchisement 
de americanos mexicanos en Tejas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">With the annexation of Texas in 1848 at the end of the Mexican-American War, Tejanos--Texans of Mexican descent--lost property rights and political power in a society dominated by Anglos. Through discriminatory practices and violent force, Tejanos were kept at the bottom of the new political and socio-cultural order. From 1900-1930, as an influx of immigrants from Mexico came north to meet a growing demand for cheap labor in the developing commercial agriculture industries, Tejanos experienced continued discrimination in employment, housing, public facilities, the judicial system, and educational institutions. In addition, Texas joined the other former Confederate states in 1902, legislating a poll tax requirement that, with the implementation of all-white primaries in 1904, effectively disenfranchised African Americans and many Tejano citizens. The struggle of Mexican Americans to end discriminatory practices accelerated following World War II. In 1948, the American G.I. Forum was formed as an advocacy group by Mexican American veterans. In 1949 and 1950, they began local "pay your poll tax" drives to register Tejano voters. Although they failed in repeated efforts to repeal the tax, a 1955-56 drive in the Rio Grande Valley resulted in the first majority Mexican American electorate in the area. In 1960, Viva Kennedy Clubs, administered by the Forum and others, contributed to the future president's narrow victory in Texas that helped win the national election. Ratification of the 24th Amendment finally abolished the poll tax requirement for Federal elections in 1964. In 1966, the tax was eliminated in all state and local elections by a Supreme Court ruling. In the following interview, Ed Idar, of the Forum, related incidents in the persistent drive by the organization and its leader, Dr. Hector P. Garcia, to increase the number of registered Mexican American voters.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mit der Annexion von Texas 1848 am Ende des
Mexikanisch-Amerikanischen Krieges, des Tejanos -- des Texans des 
mexikanischen Abfalls -- verlorene Eigentumsrechte und politische 
Energie in einer Gesellschaft beherrscht von Anglos. Durch 
diskriminierende Praxis und heftige Kraft wurden Tejanos an der 
Unterseite der neuen politischen und soziologisch-kulturellen Ordnung 
gehalten. Von 1900-1930 während ein Zufluß der Immigranten von
Mexiko nördlich kam, eine steigende Nachfrage nach preiswerter Arbeit
in den sich entwickelnden kommerziellen Landwirtschaft Industrien zu 
treffen, erfuhr Tejanos anhaltende Unterscheidung in der 
Beschäftigung, im Gehäuse, in den allgemeinen Teildiensten, im 
Gerichtssystem und in den pädagogischen Anstalten. Zusätzlich 
verband Texas die anderen ehemaligen verbündeten Zustände 1902 und 
gab eine Gemeindeabgabeanforderung Gesetze, die, mit der 
Implementierung der all-weißen Primärstromkreise 1904, effektiv 
afrikanische Amerikaner und viele Tejano Bürger entrechtete. 
Der Kampf der mexikanischen Amerikaner, zum der 
diskriminierenden Praxis zu beenden beschleunigte folgenden Weltkrieg 
II. 1948 wurde der Amerikaner G.I. Forum als Befürwortung 
Gruppe Mexican American von den Veteranen gebildet. 1949 und 
1950 fingen sie die Laufwerke lokal "Bezahlung Ihrer Gemeindeabgabe" 
an, zum der Tejano Wähler zu registrieren. Obgleich sie in 
wiederholten Bemühungen, die Steuer zu widerrufen ausfielen, ergab 
ein Laufwerk 1955-56 in der Rio Grande Senke die erste Majorität 
mexikanischen amerikanischen Wählerschaften im Bereich. 1960 
Viva Kennedy übten Vereine, durch das Forum und andere aus, 
beigetragen zum zukünftigen schmalen Sieg des Präsidenten in Texas, 
das Gewinn die nationale Wahl half. Bestätigung der 24. 
Änderung schuf schließlich die Gemeindeabgabeanforderung für 
Bundeswahlen 1964 ab. 1966 wurde die Steuer in allem Zustand und
in lokalen Wahlen durch ein Gerichtanordnen beseitigt. Im 
folgenden Interview, in der ED Idar, des Forums, der in Verbindung 
gestandenen Ereignisse im hartnäckigen Laufwerk durch die 
Organisation und seines Führers, Dr. Tyrann P. Garcia, die Zahl 
eingetragenen mexikanischen amerikanischen Wählern erhöhen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Avec l'annexation du Texas en 1848 à la fin de la
guerre, du Tejanos Mexicain-Américains -- Texan de descente 
mexicaine -- droites de propriété perdues et puissance politique 
dans une société dominée par Anglos. Par les pratiques 
discriminatoires et la force violente, Tejanos ont été maintenus au 
bas de la nouvelle commande politique et socio-culturelle. De 
1900-1930, pendant qu'un afflux des immigrés du Mexique venait au 
nord pour satisfaire une demande croissante en main d'oeuvre à prix 
réduit dans les industries commerciales se développantes 
d'agriculture, Tejanos a éprouvé la discrimination continue dans 
l'emploi, le logement, les équipements publics, le système 
juridique, et les établissements éducatifs. En outre, le Texas
a adhéré aux autres anciens états confédérés en 1902, 
légiférant une condition d'impôt local qui, avec la mise en place 
des primaires tout-blanches en 1904, ait pertinemment privé des 
droits civiques les Américains africains et beaucoup de citoyens de 
Tejano. La lutte des Américains mexicains pour terminer des 
pratiques discriminatoires a accéléré la deuxième guerre mondiale 
suivante. En 1948, l'Américain G.I. Forum a été formé en 
tant que groupe de recommandation par des vétérans de Mexican 
American. En 1949 et 1950, ils des lecteurs ont commencé local 
"salaire votre impôt local" pour enregistrer des électeurs de 
Tejano. Bien qu'ils aient échoué dans des efforts répétés 
d'abroger l'impôt, un lecteur 1955-56 dans la vallée de Rio Grande a
eu comme conséquence l'électorat américain mexicain de la première
majorité dans la zone. En 1960, les clubs de Viva Kennedy, 
ont géré par le forum et d'autres, contribué du futur à la 
victoire étroite président dans le Texas qui a aidé la victoire 
l'élection nationale. La ratification du 24ème amendement a 
finalement supprimé la condition d'impôt local pour des élections 
fédérales en 1964. En 1966, on a éliminé l'impôt dans tous 
les état et élections locales par régner de cour suprême. 
Dans l'entrevue, l'ED suivants Idar, du forum, des incidents 
associés dans le lecteur persistant par l'organisation et de son 
amorce, Dr. fanfaron P. Garcia, pour augmenter le nombre d'électeurs 
américains mexicains enregistrés.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Com o annexation de Texas em 1848 no fim da 
guerra, do Tejanos -- o Texans Mexicano-Americanos da descida mexicana
-- direitas de propriedade perdidas e potência política em uma 
sociedade dominada por Anglos. Através das práticas 
discriminatory e da força violenta, Tejanos foi mantido no fundo da 
ordem política e socio-socio-cultural nova. De 1900-1930, 
enquanto um influx dos immigrants de México veio para o norte se 
encontrar com uma demanda de crescimento para o trabalho barato nas 
indústrias comerciais se tornando da agricultura, Tejanos 
experimentou a discriminação continuada no emprego, na carcaça, em 
facilidades públicas, no sistema judicial, e em instituições 
educacionais. Além, Texas juntou os outros estados confederate 
anteriores em 1902, legislating uma exigência do imposto de votação
que, com a execução dos primaries todo-brancos em 1904, 
disenfranchised eficazmente americanos africanos e muitos cidadãos de
Tejano. O esforço dos americanos mexicanos para terminar 
práticas discriminatory acelerou seguinte segunda guerra mundial. 
Em 1948, o americano G.I. Forum foi dado forma como um grupo do 
advocacy por veterans de Mexicano Americano. Em 1949 e em 1950, 
começaram local "pagamento as movimentações do seu imposto de 
votação" para registar eleitores de Tejano. Embora falhassem 
em esforços repetidos repeal o imposto, uma movimentação 1955-56 no
vale de Rio Grande resultou no eleitorado americano mexicano da 
primeira maioria na área. Em 1960, os clubes de Viva Kennedy, 
administraram pelo forum e por outro, contribuído à vitória 
estreita do presidente futuro em Texas que ajudou à vitória a 
eleição nacional. O ratification da 2â emenda abolished 
finalmente a exigência do imposto de votação para eleições 
federais em 1964. Em 1966, o imposto foi eliminado em todo o 
estado e eleições locais governar da corte suprema. Na 
seguintes entrevista, Ed Idar, do forum, dos incidents relacionados na
movimentação persistente pela organização e de seu líder, Dr. 
hector P. Garcia, para aumentar o número de eleitores americanos 
mexicanos registados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Con il annexation del Texas in 1848 alla 
conclusione della guerra di messicano-american, del Tejanos -- il 
Texans della discesa messicana -- diritti di proprietà persi e 
potenza politica in una società dominata da Anglos. Attraverso 
le pratiche discriminatorie e la forza violenta, Tejanos è stato 
mantenuto alla parte inferiore di nuovo ordine politico e 
socio-culturale. Da 1900-1930, mentre un afflusso degli 
immigranti dal Messico è venuto a nord venire a contatto di una 
domanda crescente del lavoro poco costoso nelle industrie 
commerciali di sviluppo di agricoltura, Tejanos ha avvertito la 
distinzione continuata nell'occupazione, in alloggiamento, nelle 
attrezzature pubbliche, nel sistema giudiziario e negli istituti 
scolastici. In più, il Texas ha aderito all'altro ex 
confederato dichiara in 1902, legiferando una condizione di 
imposta di scrutinio che, con l'implementazione delle cose principali 
tutto-bianche in 1904, disenfranchised efficacemente gli Americani 
africani e molti cittadini di Tejano. La lotta degli Americani 
messicani per concludere le pratiche discriminatorie ha accelerato 
la seguente seconda guerra mondiale. In 1948, l'americano G.I. 
Forum è stato formato come gruppo di avvocatura dai veterani 
americani messicani. In 1949 ed in 1950, hanno cominciato 
locale "paga azionamenti della vostra imposta di scrutinio" per 
registrare gli elettori di Tejano. Anche se sono venuto a 
mancare negli sforzi ripetuti abrogare la tassa, un azionamento 
1955-56 nella valle de Rio Grande ha provocato l'elettorato americano 
messicano di prima maggioranza nella zona. In 1960, i randelli
di Viva Kennedy, hanno amministrato dalla tribuna e da altre, 
contribuito alla vittoria stretta del presidente futuro nel Texas che 
ha aiutato la vittoria l'elezione nazionale. La ratifica della 
ventiquattresima correzione infine ha abolito il requisito di imposta 
di scrutinio delle elezioni federali in 1964. In 1966, la tassa 
è stata eliminata in tutto dichiara ed elezioni locali da un 
regolamento della Corte suprema. Nell'intervista, nel Ed 
seguenti Idar, della tribuna, degli avvenimenti riferiti 
nell'azionamento persistente dall'organizzazione e del relativo 
capo, Dott. tormentatore P. Garcia, aumentare il numero di 
elettori americani messicani registrati.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Με την προσάρτηση του Τέξας το 1848 στο τέλος του 
Μεξικανοαμερικάνύ πολέμου, Tejanos -- Texans της μεξικάνικης
καταγωγής -- έχασαν τα δικαιώματα ιδιοκτησιών και την πολιτική 
δύναμη σε μια κοινωνία που εξουσιάστηκε από Anglos. Μέσω
των μεροληπτικών πρακτικών και της βίαιας δύναμης, Tejanos 
κρατήθηκε στο κατώτατο σημείο της νέας πολιτικής και 
κοινωνικοπολιτιστικής κατάταξης. Από το 1900-1930, καθώς 
μια εισροή των μεταναστών από το Μεξικό ήρθε βόρεια να 
ικανοποιήσει μια αυξανόμενη ζήτηση για τη φτηνή εργασία στις 
αναπτυσσόμενες εμπορικές βιομηχανίες γεωργίας, Tejanos 
δοκίμασε τη συνεχή διάκριση στην απασχόληση, την κατοικία, τις 
δημόσιες εγκαταστάσεις, το δικαστικό σύστημα, και τα εκπαιδευτικά
όργανα. Επιπλέον, το Τέξας προσχώρησε στα άλλα 
προηγούμενα ομόσπονδα κράτη το 1902, που νομοθετούν μια 
απαίτηση κεφαλικού φόρου ότι, με την εφαρμογή των όλος-άσπρων 
κωπαίων πτερών το 1904, αποτελεσματικά αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί 
και πολλοί πολίτες Tejano. Η προσπάθεια μεξικάνικων 
Αμερικανών να τελειώσουν τις μεροληπτικές πρακτικές επιτάχυνε 
μετά από τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο ΙΙ. Το 1948, το 
αμερικανικό G.I. φόρουμ διαμορφώθηκε ως ομάδα υπεράσπισης από
τους μεξικάνικους αμερικανικούς παλαιμάχους. Το 1949 και 
το 1950, άρχισαν τις τοπικές κινήσεις "πληρώνουν του κεφαλικού
φόρου σασ" στους ψηφοφόρους Tejano καταλόγων. Αν και 
απέτυχαν στις επαναλαμβανόμενες προσπάθειες να ακυρωθεί ο φόρος, 
μια κίνηση του 1955-56 στην κοιλάδα του Ρίο Grande οδήγησε 
στο πρώτο μεξικάνικο αμερικανικό εκλογικό σώμα πλειοψηφίας στην 
περιοχή. Το 1960, τις λέσχες Viva Kennedy, που 
χορηγούνται από το φόρουμ και άλλα, που συμβάλλουν στη στενή 
νίκη του μελλοντικού Προέδρου στο Τέξας που βοήθησε να κερδίσει 
την εθνική εκλογή. Η επικύρωση της 24$ης τροποποίησης 
κατάργησε τελικά την απαίτηση κεφαλικού φόρου για τις 
ομοσπονδιακές εκλογές το 1964. Το 1966, ο φόρος 
αποβλήθηκε σε όλες το κράτος και τις τοπικές εκλογές με μια 
απόφαση του ανώτατου δικαστηρίου. Στην ακόλουθη συνέντευξη,
οι ΕΔ Idar, του φόρουμ, αφορούσαν τα γεγονότα στην επίμονη 
κίνηση από την οργάνωση και τον ηγέτη του, ο Δρ Hector P. 
Garcia, για να αυξήσουν τον αριθμό εγγραμμένων μεξικάνικων 
αμερικανικών ψηφοφόρων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Con la anexión de Tejas en 1848 en el final de 
la guerra, del Tejanos -- el Texans Mexicano-Americanos de la 
pendiente mexicana -- las derechas de característica perdidas y 
potencia política en una sociedad dominada por Anglos. A 
través de prácticas discriminatorias y de fuerza violenta, Tejanos 
fue guardado en el fondo de la nueva orden política y socio-cultural.
A partir de 1900-1930, como una afluencia de inmigrantes de 
México vino al norte resolver una demanda creciente para el trabajo 
barato en las industrias comerciales de la agricultura que se 
convertían, Tejanos experimentó la discriminación continuada en el 
empleo, la cubierta, los recursos públicos, el sistema judicial, e 
instituciones educativas. Además, Tejas ensambló los otros 
estados confederados anteriores en 1902, legislando un requisito del 
impuesto de encuesta que, con la puesta en práctica de las primarias 
todo-blancas en 1904, disenfranchised con eficacia a americanos 
africanos y a muchos ciudadanos de Tejano. La lucha de los 
americanos mexicanos para terminar prácticas discriminatorias 
aceleró la Segunda Guerra Mundial siguiente. En 1948, a los 
veteranos mexican american formó al americano G.I. Forum como grupo 
de la defensa. En 1949 y 1950, comenzaron local "paga los 
mecanismos impulsores de su impuesto de encuesta" para colocar a 
votantes de Tejano. Aunque fallaron en esfuerzos relanzados de 
abrogar el impuesto, un mecanismo impulsor 1955-56 en el valle de Río
Grande dio lugar al electorado americano mexicano de la primera 
mayoría en el área. En 1960, los clubs de Viva Kennedy, 
administraron por el foro y otros, contribuido a la victoria estrecha 
del presidente futuro en Tejas que ayudó a triunfo la elección 
nacional. La ratificación de la 24ta enmienda finalmente 
suprimió el requisito del impuesto de encuesta para las elecciones 
federales en 1964. En 1966, el impuesto fue eliminado en todo el
estado y elecciones locales por una decisión del Tribunal Supremo. 
En la entrevista, el Ed siguientes Idar, del foro, de los 
incidentes relacionados en el mecanismo impulsor persistente por la 
organización y de su arranque de cinta, el Dr. matón P. Garcia, 
aumentar el número de votantes americanos mexicanos registrados.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086703</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105251</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/our-first-poll-tax-drive-the-american-g-i-forum-fights-disenfranchisement-of-mexican-americans-in-texas</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
