<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107291</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107291</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086190</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">George Kills in Sight Describes the Death of Indian Leader Crazy Horse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">George Abbrüche im Anblick beschreibt den Tod des
indischer Führer-verrückten Pferds</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les mises à mort de George en vue décrit la 
mort du cheval fou du Chef indien</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As matanças de George na vista descrevem a morte 
do cavalo louco do líder indian</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le uccisioni di George in vista descrive la morte 
del cavallo pazzesco del Capo indiano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θ*Γεοργε Kills στη θέα περιγράφει το θάνατο του 
ινδικού τρελλού αλόγου ηγετών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las matanzas de George en vista describen la 
muerte del caballo loco del arranque de cinta indio</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">One of the most notable Indian warriors of the post-Civil War era was Crazy Horse (Tashunka Witko), a military leader of the Teton Sioux. In the aftermath of Custer's defeat by Crazy Horse and Sitting Bull at the Little Big Horn in June 1876, U.S. troops relentlessly pursued both Indian leaders. Crazy Horse was arrested in September, taken to Fort Robinson (in what is now northwestern Nebraska), and ultimately killed by a soldier, perhaps after the Indian warrior resisted being locked in a guardhouse. One of the many versions of Crazy Horse's death and secret burial can be heard in this interview with George Kills in Sight, which was done by Joseph Cash of the University of South Dakota in 1967 when Kills in Sight was in his seventies. Kills in Sight's family--his father's mother was Crazy Horse's cousin and learned about Crazy Horse from his grandfather, Big Crow--taught him to revere Crazy Horse as a heroic figure. Kills in Sight concludes by describing how his grandfather and others took the body and secretly buried it.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Einer der bemerkenswertesten indischen 
Krieger der PfostenZivilkriegära war verrücktes Pferd 
(Tashunka Witko), ein militärischer Führer des Teton Sioux. In
der Nachmahd von Niederlage Custers durch Crazy Horse und Sitting Bull
am kleinen grossen Horn im Juni 1876, übten VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Truppen unnachgiebig beide indischen Führer aus. Verrücktes 
Pferd wurde im September festgehalten, genommen zum Fort Robinson (in,
was jetzt nordwestliches Nebraska ist) und beendet schließlich von 
einem Soldaten, möglicherweise nach indischer Krieger 
widerstandenen in eine Wachstube gesperrt werden. Eine der 
vielen Versionen des Todes des verrückten Pferds und der 
Geheimnisbeerdigung kann in diesem Interview mit George Abbrüchen im 
Anblick gehört werden, der von Joseph Cash der Universität von South
Dakota 1967 erfolgt wurde, als Abbrüche im Anblick in seinen 
Siebzigern waren. Abbrüche in der Familie des Anblicks -- 
Mutter seines Vaters war Vetter des verrückten Pferds und erlernt 
über verrücktes Pferd von seinem Großvater, grosse Krähe -- ihn 
revere dem verrückten Pferd als heroische Abbildung unterrichtet. 
Abbrüche im Anblick folgert, indem sie beschreiben, wie sein 
Großvater und andere den Körper nahmen und ihn geheim begruben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un des guerriers indiens les plus notables de 
l'ère poteau-Civile de guerre était cheval fou (Tashunka Witko), une
amorce militaire du Teton Sioux. Au lendemain de la défaite de 
Custer par Crazy Horse et séance Bull au petit grand klaxon en juin 
1876, les troupes des ETATS-UNIS ont implacablement poursuivi les deux
amorces indiennes. Le cheval fou a été arrêté en septembre, 
pris au fort Robinson (dans ce qui est maintenant le Nébraska du 
nord-ouest), et finalement a été détruit par un soldat, peut-être 
après l'verrouillage résisté par guerrier indien dans un corps de 
garde. Une des nombreuses versions de la mort du cheval fou et 
de l'enterrement de secret peut être entendue dans cette entrevue 
avec des mises à mort de George en vue, qui a été fait par 
Joseph Cash de l'université du Dakota du sud en 1967 où les 
mises à mort en vue avaient lieu en quelques ses années '70. 
Mises à mort dans la famille de la vue -- la mère de son père
était le cousin du cheval fou et renseigné sur le cheval fou de son 
grand-père, grande corneille -- enseignée le pour vénérer 
le cheval fou comme figure héroïque. Les mises à mort en vue 
conclut en décrivant comment son grand-père et d'autres ont pris le 
corps et l'ont secrètement enterré.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um dos guerreiros indian os mais notáveis da era 
borne-Civil da guerra era cavalo louco (Tashunka Witko), um líder 
militar do Teton Sioux. No aftermath da derrota de Custer por 
Louco Cavalo e assento Bull no chifre grande pequeno em junho 1876, as
tropas de ESTADOS UNIDOS perseguiram relentlessly ambos os líderes 
indian. O cavalo louco foi prendido em setembro, feito exame ao 
fort Robinson (em o que é agora Nebraska do noroeste), e matado 
finalmente por um soldado, talvez após guerreiro indian ser travado 
resistido em um guardhouse. Uma de muitas versões da morte do 
cavalo louco e do enterro do segredo pode ser ouvido nesta entrevista 
com matanças de George na vista, que foi feita por Joseph Dinheiro da
universidade de Dakota sul em 1967 em que as matanças na vista se 
realizavam em seus seventies. Matanças na família da vista -- 
matriz do seu pai era o primo do cavalo louco e aprendido sobre o 
cavalo louco de seu avô, corvo grande -- ensinada o ao cavalo louco 
do revere como uma figura heroic. As matanças na vista conclem 
descrevendo como seu avô e outro fizeram exame do corpo e o 
enterraram secreta.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Uno dei guerrieri indiani più notevoli dell'era 
alberino-Civile di guerra era cavallo pazzesco (Tashunka Witko), un 
capo militare del Teton Sioux. Nel guaime della sconfitta
del Custer da Crazy Horse e la seduta Bull al corno grande piccolo nel
mese di giugno del 1876, le truppe degli STATI UNITI hanno perseguito 
relentlessly entrambi i capi indiani. Il cavallo pazzesco
è stato arrestato in settembre, è stato preso a Robinson Forte 
(in che cosa ora è il Nebraska nordoccidentale) ed infine è stato 
ucciso da un soldato, forse dopo il bloccaggio resistito a guerriero 
indiano in un guardhouse. Una delle molte versioni della morte 
del cavallo pazzesco e della sepoltura di segreto può essere sentita 
in questa intervista con le uccisioni di George in vista, che è stato
fatto da Joseph Cash dell'università di Dakota del Sud in 1967 in cui
le uccisioni in vista avevano luogo nei suoi anni settanta. 
Uccisioni nella famiglia della vista -- madre del suo padre era 
il cugino del cavallo pazzesco ed imparato circa il cavallo pazzesco 
dal suo nonno, corvo grande -- insegnata lui al cavallo pazzesco del 
revere come figura eroica. Le uccisioni in vista conclude 
descrivendo come il suo nonno ed altri hanno preso il corpo e 
segretamente lo hanno sepolto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένας από τους πιό ξεχωριστούς ινδικούς πολεμιστές 
της μετα-αστικής πολεμικής εποχής ήταν τρελλό άλογο (Tashunka
Witko), ένας στρατιωτικός ηγέτης του Teton Σιού. Στη 
συνέπεια της ήττας Custer από το τρελλό άλογο και της 
συνεδρίασης Bull στο μικρό μεγάλο κέρατο τον Ιούνιο του 
1876, τα ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΑ στρατεύματα ακολούθησαν αδυσώπητα και τους 
δύο ινδικούς ηγέτες. Το τρελλό άλογο συλλήφθηκε το 
Σεπτέμβριο, λήφθηκε στο οχυρό Robinson (σε αυτό που είναι 
τώρα βορειοδυτική Νεμπράσκα), και σκοτώθηκε τελικά από έναν 
στρατιώτη, ίσως μετά από το ινδικός επικριμένο πολεμιστής 
κλείσιμο σε ένα guardhouse. Μια από τις πολλές εκδόσεις 
του μυστικού ενταφιασμού του τρελλού αλόγου του θανάτου και 
μπορεί να ακουστεί σε αυτήν την συνέντευξη με George Kills 
στη θέα, η οποία έγινε από Joseph Cash του πανεπιστημίου 
της νότιας Ντακότας το 1967 όταν ήταν οι θανατώσεις στη θέα 
στη δεκαετία του '70 του. Οι θανατώσεις στην οικογένεια της 
θέας -- η μητέρα του πατέρα του ήταν ξάδελφος του τρελλού 
αλόγου και έμαθε για το τρελλό άλογο από τον παππού του, 
μεγάλος κόρακας -- τον δίδαξαν για να σεβαστούν το τρελλό άλογο 
ως ηρωικό αριθμό. Οι θανατώσεις στη θέα ολοκληρώνουν με την
περιγραφή πώς ο παππούς του και άλλοι πήραν το σώμα και το 
έθαψαν κρυφά.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Uno de los guerreros indios más notables de la 
era poste-Civil de la guerra era caballo loco (Tashunka Witko), 
arranque de cinta militar del Teton Sioux. En las consecuencias 
de la derrota de Custer de Crazy Horse y sentada Bull en el pequeño 
cuerno grande en junio de de 1876, las tropas de ESTADOS UNIDOS 
persiguieron implacablemente a ambos arranques de cinta indios. 
El caballo loco fue arrestado en septiembre, llevado la 
fortaleza Robinson (en cuál ahora es Nebraska del noroeste), y matado
en última instancia por un soldado, quizás después de ser bloqueado
resistido guerrero indio en un guardhouse. Una de las muchas 
versiones de la muerte del caballo loco y del entierro del secreto se 
puede oír en esta entrevista con las matanzas de George en la vista, 
que fue hecha por José Cash de la universidad de Dakota del Sur en 
1967 en que las matanzas en vista eran en sus años 70. Matanzas
en la familia de la vista -- madre de su padre era el primo del 
caballo loco y aprendido sobre el caballo loco de su abuelo, cuervo 
grande -- enseñada lo para venerar el caballo loco como 
figura heroica. Las matanzas en vista concluyen describiendo 
cómo su abuelo y otros tomaron el cuerpo y lo enterraron 
secretamente.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086190</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107291</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/george-kills-in-sight-describes-the-death-of-indian-leader-crazy-horse</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
