<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106675</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106675</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085259</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Watts</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Watt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Watts</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Watts</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Watt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θ*Ωαττ</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Vatios</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">By the late 1960s, despite the ongoing Civil Rights movement, frustration over poverty, discrimination, injustice, and high unemployment among African Americans helped fuel unrest in many poor, black urban areas. On August 11, 1965, sparked by an angry confrontation between a white police officer and an African American motorcyclist, the Watts neighborhood in Los Angeles erupted in a large-scale civil disorder that lasted for six days and became known as the Watts Riots. Thirty-four people were reported killed, 4,000 were arrested, and 600 buildings were damaged or destroyed. Similar riots erupted in many American cities after Martin Luther King, Jr., was assassinated in April 1968. Recovery from the riots was slow. Photographs taken two months later show a woman and her baby on the sidewalk, in front of rotting furniture; and a young man standing in front of a burned-out store near his home. Other photographs, taken seven months after the riots, reflect the racial tension that remained between police and residents after the riots ? images of armed officers on patrol and officers frisking black suspects for weapons. And another photograph, taken two years later, shows people walking by a row of still-abandoned apartment buildings. The riots got the attention of politicians. California Governor Pat Brown (1959_1967) and Los Angeles Mayor Sam Yorty are shown leaving a post-riot conference in March 1966. The people in the Watts community didn't wait for the politicians; they made great efforts at renewal after the riots. Two photographs portray African American girls and boys walking to their summer jobs in Watts. Another image depicts a man handing out shovels and street cleaning supplies to boys ready to help in a clean-up drive. The Watts community also attempted to reinvigorate its neighborhood by holding parades and local celebrations. In one image, the Queen of the Watts Christmas Parade waves to the crowd; in another, Roosevelt Grier, a popular professional football player for the Los Angeles Rams, shakes hands with children at the Watts Summer Festival. And boxer Muhammad Ali leads the Watts Summer Festival in an open convertible. Other important local figures shown here include activist Ron Karenga, (now Dr. Maulana Karenga, the founder of the holiday Kwanzaa); and Italian American artist Simon Rodia, with his famous ?outsider? sculpture known as the Watts Towers, which is still a central attraction in Watts today.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bis zum den späten sechziger Jahren trotz der 
fortwährenden Zivilrechtbewegung, Frustration schwärzt Überarmut, 
Unterscheidung, Unrecht, und hohe Arbeitslosigkeit unter afrikanischen
Amerikanern half Kraftstoffruhelosigkeit in vielen schlechten, 
städtische Bereiche. An August 11, 1965, gefunkt durch eine 
verärgerte Konfrontation zwischen einem weißen Polizeioffizier und 
einem afrikanischen amerikanischen Motorradfahrer, brach die 
Wattnachbarschaft in Los Angeles in einer großräumigen Zivilstörung
aus, die für sechs Tage dauerte und als die Watt-Aufstände bekannt 
wurde. Thirty-four Leuten wurden beendet berichtet, wurden 4.000
festgehalten, und 600 Gebäude wurden beschädigt oder zerstört. 
Ähnliche Aufstände brachen in vielen amerikanischen Städte 
nach Martin Luther König, jr., wurden ermordet im April 1968 aus. 
Wiederanlauf von den Aufständen war langsam. Die 
Fotographien, die zwei Monate später genommen werden, zeigen eine 
Frau und ihr Baby auf dem Bürgersteig, vor Verrottenmöbeln; 
und ein junger Mann, der vor einem gebrannten-heraus Speicher 
nahe seinem Haus steht. Andere Fotographien, sieben Monate nach 
den Aufständen gedauert, reflektieren die rassische Spannkraft, die 
zwischen Polizei und Bewohnern nach den Aufständen blieb? 
Bilder der bewaffneten Offiziere auf Patrouille und der 
Offiziere hüpfenden Schwarzverdächtigen für Waffen. Und eine 
andere Fotographie, zwei Jahre später genommen, Erscheinen 
bevölkeren das Gehen durch eine Reihe der noch-verlassenen 
Wohnanlagen. Die Aufstände erhielten die Aufmerksamkeit der 
Politiker. Das Kalifornien Regler-Klaps-Braun (1959_1967) und 
Los Angeles Bürgermeister Sam Yorty werden eine Pfosten-Aufstand 
Konferenz im März 1966 lassend gezeigt. Die Leute in der 
Wattgemeinschaft warteten nicht die Politiker; sie bildeten 
große Bemühungen an der Erneuerung nach den Aufständen. Zwei 
Fotographien schildern afrikanische amerikanischen Mädchen und die 
Jungen, die zu ihren Sommerjobs in den Watt gehen. Ein anderes 
Bild stellt einen Mann bildlich dar, der Schaufeln und Straße 
Reinigung Zubehör zu den Jungen austeilt, die betriebsbereit sind, in
einem Reinigunglaufwerk zu helfen. Die Wattgemeinschaft 
versuchte auch, seine Nachbarschaft neu zu  beleben, indem 
sie Paraden und lokale Feiern anhielt. In einem Bild bewegt die 
Königin der Watt-Weihnachtsparade zur Masse wellenartig; in 
anderen rüttelt Roosevelt Grier, ein populärer professioneller 
Fußballspieler für die Los Angeles RAMAS, Hände mit Kindern am 
Watt-Sommer-Festival. Und Boxer Muhammad Ali führt das 
Watt-Sommer-Festival in einem geöffneten Kabriolett. Andere 
wichtige lokale Abbildungen, die hier gezeigt werden, enthalten 
Aktivisten Ron Karenga, (jetzt Dr. Maulana Karenga, der Gründer des 
Feiertags Kwanzaa); und italienischer amerikanischer Künstler 
Simon Rodia, mit seinem berühmten?outsider? die Skulptur, die 
als die Watt bekannt ist, Towers, die noch eine zentrale Anziehung in 
den Watt heute ist.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Par les années 60 en retard, en dépit du 
mouvement continu de droits civiques, la pauvreté finie 
d'anéantissement, discrimination, injustice, et le chômage élevé 
parmi les Américains africains a aidé le malaise de carburant dans 
beaucoup de pauvres, noircissent des zones urbaines. Août 11, 
1965, étincelé par une confrontation fâchée entre un officier de 
police blanc et un motocycliste américain africain, le voisinage de 
watts à Los Angeles a éclaté dans un désordre civil de grande 
puissance qui a duré pendant six jours et est devenu notoire comme 
émeutes de watts. Des personnes de Thirty-four ont été 
enregistrées détruites, 4.000 ont été arrêtés, et 600 bâtiments
ont été endommagés ou détruits. Les émeutes semblables ont 
éclaté dans beaucoup de villes américaines après le roi de Martin 
Luther, Jr., ont été assassinées en avril 1968. La reprise 
des émeutes était lente. Les photographies prises deux mois 
plus tard montrent une femme et son bébé sur le trottoir, devant des
meubles de décomposition ; et un jeune homme se tenant devant 
une mémoire brûlée-dehors près de sa maison. D'autres 
photographies, prises sept mois après les émeutes, reflètent la 
tension raciale qui est demeurée entre la police et les résidants 
après les émeutes ? images des officiers armés sur les 
suspects gambadants de noir de patrouille et d'officiers pour des 
armes. Et une autre photographie, prise deux ans après, des 
expositions peuplent la marche par une ligne des immeubles 
encore-abandonnés. Les émeutes ont obtenu l'attention des 
politiciens. Le brun de tapotement du Gouverneur de la 
Californie (1959_1967) et le maire Sam Yorty de Los Angeles sont 
montrés laissant une conférence de poteau-émeute en mars 1966. 
Les personnes dans la communauté de watts n'ont pas attendu les
politiciens ; elles ont fait de grands efforts au renouvellement
après les émeutes. Deux photographies dépeignent les filles 
africaines et les garçons américains marchant à leurs travaux 
d'été en watts. Une autre image dépeint un homme 
distribuerant des pelles et des approvisionnements de nettoyage de rue
aux garçons prêts à aider dans un lecteur de nettoyage. La 
communauté de watts a également essayé de revigorer son 
voisinage en tenant des défilés et des célébrations locales. 
Dans une image, la reine du défilé de Noël de watts ondule à
la foule ; dans des autres, Roosevelt Grier, un joueur 
professionnel populaire de football pour les mémoires vives de Los 
Angeles, serre la main aux enfants au festival d'été de watts. 
Et le boxeur Muhammad Ali mène le festival d'été de watts 
dans un convertible ouvert. D'autres chiffres locaux importants 
montrés ici incluent l'activiste Ron Karenga, (maintenant Dr. 
Maulana Karenga, le fondateur des vacances Kwanzaa) ; et artiste
américain italien Simon Rodia, avec son ?outsider célèbre ? 
la sculpture connue sous le nom de watts domine, qui est 
toujours une attraction centrale en watts aujourd'hui.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Pelos 1960s atrasados, apesar do movimento ongoing
das direitas civis, a pobreza excedente da frustração, 
discriminação, injustice, e o desemprego elevado entre americanos 
africanos ajudou ao unrest do combustível em muitos deficientes, 
enegrece áreas urbanas. Agosto em 11, 1965, acendido por um 
confrontation irritado entre um oficial de polícias branco e um 
motorcyclist americano africano, a vizinhança dos watts em Los 
Angeles erupted em um disorder civil em grande escala que durasse por 
seis dias e se tornasse sabido como os motins dos watts. Os 
povos de Thirty-four foram relatados matados, 4.000 foram prendidos, e
600 edifícios foram danificados ou destruídos. Os motins 
similares erupted em muitas cidades americanas após o rei de Martin 
Luther, Jr., assassinated em abril 1968. A recuperação dos 
motins era lenta. As fotografias feitas exame dois meses mais 
tarde mostram uma mulher e seu bebê no sidewalk, na frente do 
furniture rotting; e um homem novo que está na frente de uma 
loja queimada-para fora perto de sua HOME. Outras fotografias, 
feitas exame sete meses após os motins, refletem a tensão racial que
remanesceu entre polícias e residentes após os motins? imagens
de oficiais armados em suspeitos frisking do preto da patrulha e dos 
oficiais para armas. E uma outra fotografia, feita exame dois 
anos mais tarde, mostras povoa andar por uma fileira de edifícios de 
apartamento ainda-abandonados. Os motins começaram a atenção 
dos políticos. O marrom do pat do regulador de Califórnia 
(1959_1967) e o mayor Sam Yorty de Los Angeles são mostrados que 
deixam uma conferência do borne-motim em março 1966. Os povos 
na comunidade dos watts não esperaram os políticos; fizeram 
esforços grandes na renovação após os motins. Duas 
fotografias portray meninas africanas e os meninos americanos que 
andam a seus trabalhos do verão nos watts. Uma outra imagem 
descreve um homem que entrega para fora dos shovels e das fontes da 
limpeza da rua aos meninos prontos para ajudar em uma movimentação 
do clean-up. A comunidade dos watts tentou também ao 
reinvigorate sua vizinhança prendendo paradas e celebrations locais. 
Em uma imagem, a rainha da parada do christmas dos watts acena 
à multidão; em outras, Roosevelt Grier, um jogador 
profissional popular do football para as ram de Los Angeles, agita as 
mãos com as crianças no festival do verão dos watts. E o 
boxer Muhammad Ali conduz ao festival do verão dos watts em um 
convertible aberto. Outras figuras locais importantes mostradas 
aqui incluem a activista Ron Karenga, (agora Dr. Maulana Karenga, 
founder do feriado Kwanzaa); e artista americano italiano Simon 
Rodia, com seu?outsider famoso? o sculpture sabido como os watts
eleva-se, que é ainda uma atração central nos watts hoje.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Entro gli anni 60 tardi, malgrado il movimento 
continuo di diritti civili, la povertà eccessiva di frustrazione, la 
distinzione, injustice e l'alta disoccupazione fra gli Americani 
africani ha aiutato l'agitazione del combustibile in molti 
povero, annerisce le aree urbane. Il 11 agosto 1965, 
scintillato tramite un confronto arrabbiato fra un ufficiale di 
polizia bianco e un motorcyclist americano africano, la vicinanza di 
watt a Los Angeles ha scoppiato in un disordine civile su 
grande scala che ha durato sei giorni ed è stato conosciuto come i 
tumulti di watt. La gente di Thirty-four è stata segnalata 
uccisa, 4.000 sono stati arrestati e 600 costruzioni sono state 
danneggiate o distrutto state. I tumulti simili hanno 
scoppiato in molte città americane dopo il re del Martin 
Luther, Jr., sono stati assassinati nel mese di aprile del 1968. 
Il recupero dai tumulti era lento. Le fotografie prese due
mesi più successivamente mostrano una donna ed il suo bambino sul 
marciapiede, davanti la mobilia di decomposizione; e un giovane 
che si leva in piedi davanti un deposito bruciato -fuori vicino alla 
sua sede. Altre fotografie, occors sette mesi dopo i tumulti, 
riflettono il tensionamento razziale che è rimasto fra la polizia ed 
i residenti dopo i tumulti? immagini degli ufficiali muniti sui 
sospetti frisking di nero degli ufficiali e della pattuglia per le 
armi. E un'altra fotografia, presa due anni più 
successivamente, esposizioni popola camminare da una fila delle 
costruzioni di appartamento ancora-abbandonate. I tumulti hanno 
ottenuto l'attenzione dei politici. Il colore marrone del 
picchiettio del regolatore della California (1959_1967) ed il sindaco 
Sam Yorty de Los Angeles sono indicati che lasciano un congresso di 
alberino-tumulto nel mese di marzo del 1966. La gente nella 
Comunità di watt non ha aspettato i politici; ha fatto gli 
sforzi grandi al rinnovamento dopo i tumulti. Due fotografie 
ritraggono le ragazze africane ed i ragazzi americani che camminano ai
loro lavori di estate nei watt. Un'altra immagine descrive un 
uomo che passa verso l'esterno le pale e le forniture di pulizia della
via ai ragazzi aspettano per aiutare in un azionamento di 
pulizia. La Comunità di watt egualmente ha tentato a 
reinvigorate la relativa vicinanza tramite le parate della 
tenuta e le celebrazioni locali. In un'immagine, la regina
della parata di Natale di watt fluttua alla folla; in un 
altro, Roosevelt Grier, un giocatore professionale popolare di gioco 
del calcio per le ram de Los Angeles, agita le mani con i bambini al 
Festival di estate di watt. Ed il boxer Muhammad Ali conduce
il Festival di estate di watt in un convertibile aperto. 
Altre cifre locali importanti indicate qui includono 
l'attivista Ron Karenga, (ora Dott. Maulana Karenga, il fondatore 
della festa Kwanzaa); ed artista americano italiano Simon Rodia,
con il suo?outsider famoso? la scultura conosciuta come i watt 
torreggia su, che è ancora oggi un'attrazione centrale nei watt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μέχρι την πρόσφατη δεκαετία του '60, παρά την 
τρέχουσα μετακίνηση αστικών δικαιωμάτων, η απογοήτευση πέρα από
την ένδεια, η διάκριση, η αδικία, και η υψηλή ανεργία μεταξύ 
αφρικανικών Αμερικανών βοήθησαν την ανησυχία καυσίμων σε πολλές 
φτωχές, μαύρες αστικές περιοχές. Στις 11 Αυγούστου 
..1965, σπινθηρισμένοση από μια αντιπαράθεση μεταξύ ενός 
λευκού αστυνομικού και ενός αφρικανικού αμερικανικού 
μοτοσυκλετιστή, η γειτονιά Watt στο Λος Αντζελες εξερράγη σε 
μια μεγάλης κλίμακας αστική αναταραχή που διάρκεσε για έξι 
ημέρες και έγινε γνωστή ως ταραχές Watt. Τριάντα 
τέσσερις άνθρωποι αναφέρθηκαν σκοτωμένος, 4.000 συλλήφθηκαν, 
και 600 κτήρια ήταν χαλασμένα ή καταστρεμμένα. Οι 
παρόμοιες ταραχές ξέσπασαν σε πολλές αμερικανικές πόλεις μετά 
από Martin Luther King, νεώτερος, δολοφονήθηκαν που τις 
1968, Απριλίου αποκατάσταση από τις ταραχές ήταν αργά. 
Οι φωτογραφίες που λαμβάνονται δύο μήνες εμφανίζουν 
αργότερα μια γυναίκα και μωρό της στο πεζοδρόμιο, μπροστά από τα
σαπίζοντας έπιπλα  και ένας νεαρός άνδρας που στέκεται 
μπροστά από ένα καμένο κατάστημα κοντά στο σπίτι του. 
Αλλες φωτογραφίες, που λαμβάνονται επτά μήνες μετά από 
τις ταραχές, απεικονίζουν τη φυλετική ένταση που παρέμεινε 
μεταξύ της αστυνομίας και των κατοίκων μετά από τις ταραχές; 
εικόνες των οπλισμένων ανώτερων υπαλλήλων στην περίπολο και
των ανώτερων υπαλλήλων poy οι μαύροι ύποπτοι για τα όπλα. 
Και μια άλλη φωτογραφία, που λαμβάνεται δύο έτη αργότερα, 
εμφανίζει ανθρώπους που περπατούν από μια σειρά των 
ακόμα-εγκαταλειμμένων κτηρίων διαμερισμάτων. Οι ταραχές 
πήραν την προσοχή των πολιτικών. Το ελαφρύ κτύπημα 
κυβερνητών Καλιφόρνιας καφετί (1959_1967) και το Λος Αντζελες 
δήμαρχος Sam Yorty εμφανίζονται αποχωρώντας από μια 
διάσκεψη μετα-ταραχής τον Μάρτιο του 1966. Οι άνθρωποι 
στην κοινότητα Watt δεν περίμεναν τους πολιτικούς  
κατέβαλαν μεγάλες προσπάθειες στην ανανέωση μετά από τις 
ταραχές. Δύο φωτογραφίες απεικονίζουν τα αφρικανικά 
αμερικανικά κορίτσια και τα αγόρια που περπατούν στις θερινές 
εργασίες τους στα Watt. Μια άλλη εικόνα απεικονίζει ένα 
άτομο που διανέμει τα φτυάρια και οι καθαρίζοντας προμήθειες 
οδών στα αγόρια αναμένουνε για να βοηθήσουν σε μια κίνηση 
καθαρισμού. Η κοινότητα Watt προσπάθησε επίσης να 
αναζωογονήσει τη γειτονιά της με το κράτημα των παρελάσεων και των
τοπικών εορτασμών. Σε μια εικόνα, η βασίλισσα των κυμάτων 
παρελάσεων Χριστουγέννων Watt στο πλήθος  σε άλλος, 
Roosevelt Grier, ένας δημοφιλής επαγγελματικός παίκτης 
ποδοσφαίρου για τους κριούς του Λος Αντζελες, τινάζει τα χέρια με
τα παιδιά στο θερινό φεστιβάλ Watt. Και ο μπόξερ 
Muhammad Ali οδηγεί το θερινό φεστιβάλ Watt ανοικτό σε 
έναν μετατρέψιμο. Αλλοι σημαντικοί τοπικοί αριθμοί που 
εμφανίζονται εδώ περιλαμβάνουν το ενεργό στέλεχος Ron 
Karenga, (τώρα ο Δρ Maulana Karenga, ο ιδρυτής των 
διακοπών Kwanzaa)  και ιταλικός αμερικανικός καλλιτέχνης 
simon Rodia, με το διάσημο ?outsider του; γλυπτό 
γνωστό ως πύργοι Watt, το οποίο είναι ακόμα μια κεντρική 
έλξη στα Watt σήμερα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Por los últimos años 60, a pesar de el 
movimiento en curso de las derechas civiles, la pobreza excesiva de la
frustración, discriminación, injusticia, y el alto desempleo entre 
americanos africanos ayudó a malestar del combustible en muchos 
pobres, ennegrece áreas urbanas. 11 de agosto de 1965, 
chispeado por una confrontación enojada entre un oficial de policía 
blanco y un motorista americano africano, la vecindad de los vatios 
en Los Ángeles entró en erupción en un desorden civil en grande que
duró por seis días y se conocía como los alborotos de los vatios. 
Señalaron la gente de Thirty-four matada, 4.000 fueron 
arrestados, y 600 edificios fueron dañados o destruidos. Los 
alborotos similares entraron en erupción en muchas ciudades 
americanas después del rey de Martin Luther, Jr., fueron asesinados 
en abril de 1968. La recuperación de los alborotos era lenta. 
Las fotografías tomadas dos meses más adelante muestran a una 
mujer y a su bebé en la acera, delante de los muebles de la 
descomposición; y un hombre joven que está parado delante de 
un almacén quemado -hacia fuera cerca de su hogar. ¿Otras 
fotografías, tomadas siete meses después de los alborotos, reflejan 
la tensión racial que seguía habiendo entre el policía y los 
residentes después de los alborotos? imágenes de oficiales 
armados en los sospechosos del negro de la patrulla que brincan y de 
los oficiales para las armas. Y otra fotografía, tomada dos 
años más tarde, las demostraciones puebla recorrer por una fila de 
los edificios de apartamento au'n-abandonados. Los alborotos 
consiguieron la atención de políticos. Muestran el marrón de 
la palmadita del gobernador de California (1959_1967) y alcalde Sam 
Yorty de Los Ángeles que dejan una conferencia del poste-alboroto en 
marcha de 1966. La gente en la comunidad de los vatios no 
esperó a políticos; ella hizo grandes esfuerzos en la 
renovación después de los alborotos. Dos fotografías retratan
a muchachas africanas y a muchachos americanos que recorren a sus 
trabajos del verano en vatios. Otra imagen representa a hombre 
que reparte las palas y las fuentes de la limpieza de la calle a los 
muchachos listos ayudar en un mecanismo impulsor de la limpieza. 
La comunidad de los vatios también procuró al reinvigorate su 
vecindad celebrando desfiles y celebraciones locales. En una 
imagen, la reina del desfile de Navidad de los vatios agita a la 
muchedumbre; en otras, Roosevelt Grier, jugador profesional 
popular del balompié para las RAM de Los Ángeles, sacudare las manos
con los niños en el festival del verano de los vatios. Y el 
boxeador Muhammad Ali conduce el festival del verano de los vatios en 
un convertible abierto. Otras figuras locales importantes 
mostradas aquí incluyen a activista Ron Karenga, (ahora el Dr. 
Maulana Karenga, el fundador del día de fiesta Kwanzaa); ¿y 
artista americano italiano Simon Rodia, con su?outsider famoso? 
la escultura conocida como los vatios se eleva, que sigue siendo
una atracción central en vatios hoy.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085259</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106675</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/watts</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
