<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107185</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107185</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087260</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"You Would Never Hear People Complain": Elfido Lpez Recalls Rural Mexican-American Life in the Late 19th century</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Sie Würden Nie Leute Hören Sich Zu beschweren":
Elfido Lpez erinnert an landwirtschaftliche 
Mexikanisch-Amerikanische Lebensdauer im des späten 19. jahrhunderts 
Jahrhundert</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Vous N'entendriez jamais des Personnes Se 
plaindre" : Elfido Lpez rappelle la vie Mexicain-Américaine 
rurale vers la fin du 19ème siècle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Você Nunca Ouviria Povos Queixar-se": 
Elfido Lpez recorda a vida Mexicano-Americana rural no 1ø 
século atrasado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Non sentireste Mai La Gente Protestare": 
Elfido Lpez ricorda la vita rurale di messicano-american verso 
la fine del diciannovesimo secolo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Δεν θα ακούγατε ποτέ ότι οι άνθρωποι 
παραπονιούνται": Το Elfido Lpez υπενθυμίζει την 
αγροτική Μεξικανοαμερικάή ζωή προς το τέλος του 19$ου αιώνα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Usted Nunca Oiría A Gente Quejarse": 
Elfido Lpez recuerda vida Mexicano-Americana rural en la a fines
del siglo XIX</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The arrival of the railroad in the Southwest in the early 1870s transformed the area's economy and the lives of its residents. Long-time Mexican residents of the area were quickly drawn into the region's expanding wage economy. In this selection from his handwritten memoir from 1937 Elfido Lpez recalled his childhood on his family's modest homestead and his father's decision to move the family to a small railroad town, and a life of wages, in southern Colorado in 1876.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Ankunft der Eisenbahn im Südwesten im frühen
1870s wandelte des die Wirtschaft und die Leben Bereiches seiner 
Bewohner um. Langfristige mexikanische Bewohner des Bereiches 
wurden schnell in die erweiternlohnwirtschaft der Region gezeichnet. 
In dieser Auswahl von seiner handgeschriebenen Abhandlung von 
Elfido 1937 erinnerte an Lpez seine Kindheit auf Entscheidung des 
bescheidenen Gehöfts seiner Familie und seines Vaters, um die Familie
auf eine kleine Eisenbahnstadt zu verschieben und eine Lebensdauer der
Löhne, in Südkolorado 1876.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'arrivée du chemin de fer dans le sud-ouest dans
le 1870s tôt a transformé l'économie et les vies de la zone de ses 
résidants. Des résidants mexicains à long terme de la zone 
ont été rapidement dessinés dans l'économie d'extension du salaire
de la région. Cette sélection à partir de son mémoire 
manuscrit d'Elfido 1937 Lpez a rappelé son enfance sur la décision 
de la ferme modeste de sa famille et de son père pour déplacer la 
famille à une petite ville de chemin de fer, et une vie des salaires,
dans le Colorado méridional en 1876.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A chegada da estrada de ferro no sudoeste no 1870s
adiantado transformou a economia e as vidas da área de seus 
residentes. Os residentes mexicanos long-time da área foram 
desenhados rapidamente na economia de expansão do salário da 
região. Nesta seleção de seu memoir escrito à mão de Elfido
1937 Lpez recordou sua infância na decisão do homestead modesto da 
sua família e do seu pai para mover a família para uma cidade 
pequena da estrada de ferro, e uma vida dos salários, em Colorado do 
sul em 1876.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'arrivo della ferrovia nel sud-ovest nel 1870s 
iniziale ha trasformato l'economia e le vite della zona dei relativi 
residenti. I residenti messicani long-time della zona sono 
stati dissipati rapidamente nell'economia d'espansione dello stipendio
della regione. In questa selezione dalla sua memoria scritta a 
mano da Elfido 1937 Lpez ha ricordato la sua infanzia sulla decisione 
della fattoria modesta della sua famiglia e del suo padre per spostare
la famiglia verso una piccola città della ferrovia e una durata degli
stipendi, in Colorado del sud in 1876.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η άφιξη του σιδηροδρόμου στο νοτιοδυτικό σημείο στις 
αρχές 1870s μετασχημάτισε την οικονομία της περιοχής και ζωή 
των κατοίκων της. Οι μακροπρόθεσμοι μεξικάνικοι κάτοικοι της
περιοχής σύρθηκαν γρήγορα στην επεκτειμένος οικονομία αμοιβών 
της περιοχής. Σε αυτήν την επιλογή από τα χειρόγραφα 
απομνημονεύματά του από το 1937 Elfido Lpez υπενθύμισε 
την παιδική ηλικία του στην απόφαση μέτριων αγροτικών σπιτιών 
της οικογένειάς του και του πατέρα του να κινηθεί η οικογένεια 
προς μια μικρή πόλη σιδηροδρόμου, και μια ζωή των αμοιβών, στο 
νότιο Κολοράντο το 1876.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La llegada del ferrocarril en el sudoeste en el 
1870s temprano transformó las vidas del área la economía y de sus 
residentes. Trazaron a los residentes mexicanos de largo plazo 
del área rápidamente dentro de la economía del salario de la 
región que se ampliaba. En esta selección de su memoria 
manuscrita a partir de Elfido la 1937 Lpez recordó su niñez en la 
decisión de la granja modesta de su familia y de su padre para mover 
a la familia a una ciudad pequeña del ferrocarril, y una vida de 
salarios, en Colorado meridional en 1876.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087260</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107185</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/you-would-never-hear-people-complain-elfido-lpez-recalls-rural-mexican-american-life-in-the-late-19th-century</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
