<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103813</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103813</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206817</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Chinese in California, 1850-1925</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Chinese in Kalifornien, 1850-1925</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Chinois en Californie, 1850-1925</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O chinês em Califórnia, 1850-1925</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il cinese in California, 1850-1925</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι Κινέζοι σε Καλιφόρνια, 1850-1925</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El chino en California, 1850-1925</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">presents 8,000 photos, paintings, letters, diary excerpts, pamphlets, and speeches that portray the experiences of Chinese immigrants in California during that time period. Contributions of Chinese immigrants to commerce and business, architecture and art, agriculture and other industries are described. Chinatown in San Francisco receives special treatment as the oldest and largest community of Chinese in the U.S.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt 8.000 Fotos, Anstriche, Zeichen, 
Tagebuchexcerpts, Flugschriften und Reden dar, die die Erfahrungen der
chinesischen Immigranten in Kalifornien während dieses Zeitabschnitts
schildern. Beiträge der chinesischen Immigranten zum Handel und
Geschäft, Architektur und kunst, Landwirtschaft und andere Industrien
werden beschrieben. Chinatown in San Francisco empfängt 
spezielle Behandlung als die älteste und größte Gemeinschaft des 
Chinesen in den US.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">présente 8.000 photos, peintures, lettres, 
extraits d'agenda, brochures, et discours qui dépeignent les 
expériences des immigrés chinois en Californie pendant cette 
période de temps. Des contributions des immigrés chinois au 
commerce et les affaires, l'architecture et l'art, l'agriculture et 
d'autres industries sont décrites. Chinatown dans San 
Francisco reçoit le traitement spécial en tant que communauté la 
plus âgée et plus grande de Chinois aux États-Unis.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">apresenta 8.000 fotos, pinturas, letras, excerpts 
do diário, panfletos, e discursos que portray as experiências de 
immigrants chineses em Califórnia durante esse período de tempo. 
As contribuições de immigrants chineses ao comércio e o 
negócio, a arquitetura e a arte, a agricultura e as outras 
indústrias são descritas. Chinatown em San Francisco recebe o 
tratamento especial como a comunidade a mais velha e a maior do 
chinês nos E. U..</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">presenta 8.000 foto, pitture, lettere, brani del 
diario, opuscoli e discorsi che ritraggono le esperienze negli 
immigranti cinesi nella California durante quel periodo di tempo.
I contributi degli immigranti cinesi al commercio ed il 
commercio, architettura e l'arte, l'agricoltura ed altre industrie 
sono descritti. Chinatown a San Francisco riceve il trattamento 
speciale come la Comunità più anziana e più grande del cinese
negli Stati Uniti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρουσιάζει τις 8.000 φωτογραφίες, τα έργα 
ζωγραφικής, τις επιστολές, τα αποσπάσματα ημερολογίων, τεύχη, και
ομιλίες που απεικονίζουν την εμπειρία των κινεζικών μεταναστών σε
Καλιφόρνια κατά τη διάρκεια εκείνου του χρονικού διαστήματος. 
Οι συνεισφορές των κινεζικών μεταναστών στο εμπόριο και την 
επιχείρηση, την αρχιτεκτονική και την τέχνη, τη γεωργία και άλλες
βιομηχανίες περιγράφονται. Το Chinatown στο Σαν Φρανσίσκο 
λαμβάνει την ειδική επεξεργασία ως παλαιότερη και μεγαλύτερη 
κοινότητα των κινέζικων στις ΗΠΑ</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">presenta 8.000 fotos, pinturas, cartas, extractos 
del diario, folletos, y discursos que retraten las experiencias de 
inmigrantes chinos en California durante ese período. Las 
contribuciones de inmigrantes chinos al comercio y negocio, 
configuración y arte, agricultura y otras industrias se describen. 
Chinatown en San Francisco recibe el tratamiento especial como 
la más vieja y más grande comunidad del chino en los E.E.U.U..</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206817</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103813</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-chinese-in-california-1850-1925</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
