<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105864</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105864</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086760</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Pride and Joy: Specialists in Breaking Strikes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Stolz und Freude: Fachleute in brechenden 
Schlägen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Fierté et joie : Spécialistes dans des 
grèves de rupture</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Orgulho e alegria: Specialists em batidas 
quebrando</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Orgoglio e gioia: Esperti nei colpi 
rompentesi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Υπερηφάνεια και χαρά: Ειδικοί στο σπάσιμο των 
απεργιών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Orgullo y alegría: Especialistas en huelgas
que se rompen</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">By Around 1903, employers began to mount organized campaigns to break the power of labor unions, particularly in the metal trades. Employers had a broad array of weapons in their arsenal, including blacklists, strikebreakers, and court injunctions against strikers' use of boycotts and sympathy strikes. Although early twentieth-century employers had reliable allies in state police forces and tightly controlled local police, they continued to hire their own private police--detective agencies that used secret operatives to disrupt unions and supplied thugs to protect strikebreakers during strikes. This 1917 ad for the Cleveland-based Joy Detective Agency appeared in  American Industries , the official publication of the National Association of Manufacturers.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bis zum herum 1903 fingen Arbeitgeber an, 
organisierte Kampagnen einzuhängen, um die Energie der 
Arbeiterverbände, besonders im Metallhandel zu brechen. 
Arbeitgeber hatten eine ausgedehnte Reihe Waffen in ihrem 
Arsenal, einschließlich schwarze Listen, in den Streikbrechern und in
den Gerichtinjunktionen gegen Gebrauch der Schlaggeräte von Boykotts 
und Sympathieschlägen. Obgleich frühe Zwanzigstjahrhundert 
Arbeitgeber zuverlässige Verbündete im Zustand polizeilich 
überwachen Kräfte hatten und fest gesteuerte lokale Polizei, fuhren 
sie fort, ihre eigene private Polizei anzustellen -- Detektivbüros, 
die geheime Arbeiter verwendeten, um Anschlüße zu stören und 
Schurkeen angaben, um Streikbrecher während der Schläge zu 
schützen. Diese Anzeige 1917 für das Cleveland-gegründete 
Freude Detektivbüro erschien in den amerikanischen Industrien, die 
amtliche Publikation der nationalen Verbindung der Hersteller.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">D'ici environ 1903, les employeurs ont commencé 
à organiser des campagnes organisées pour casser la puissance des 
syndicats, en particulier dans les commerces en métal. Les 
employeurs ont eu un large alignement d'armes dans leur arsenal, y 
compris des listes noires, briseurs de grève, et injonctions de cour 
contre l'utilisation des butées des boycotts et des grèves de 
sympathie de solidarité. Bien que les premiers employeurs de 
vingtième-siècle aient eu les alliés dignes de confiance dans 
l'état maintiennent l'ordre des forces et police locale étroitement 
commandée, ils ont continué à louer leur propre police privée -- 
les agences de détectives qui ont utilisé les employés secrets pour
perturber des syndicats et ont fourni des gangsters pour protéger des
briseurs de grève pendant les grèves. Cette annonce 1917 pour 
l'agence de détectives Cleveland-basée de joie est apparue dans les 
industries américaines, la publication officielle de l'association 
nationale des constructeurs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Por ao redor 1903, os empregadores começaram a 
montar campanhas organizadas para quebrar a potência de uniões 
labor, particularmente nos comércios do metal. Os empregadores 
tiveram uma disposição larga das armas em seu arsenal, including 
listas negras, em strikebreakers, e em injunctions da corte de 
encontro ao uso dos grevistas dos boycotts e das batidas de sympathy. 
Embora os empregadores adiantados de vigésimo-século tivessem 
aliados de confiança no estado policiassem forças e polícias locais
firmemente controladas, continuaram a empregar suas próprias 
polícias confidenciais -- as agências detective que usaram 
operatives secretos disrupt uniões e forneceram thugs para proteger 
strikebreakers durante batidas. Este anúncio 1917 para a 
agência detective Cleveland-baseada da alegria apareceu nas 
indústrias americanas, a publicação oficial da associação 
nacional dos fabricantes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Entro intorno 1903, i datori di lavoro hanno 
cominciato ad organizzare le campagne organizzate per rompere 
l'potenza dei sindacati di lavoro, specialmente nei commerci del 
metallo. I datori di lavoro hanno avuti un vasto allineamento 
delle armi nel loro arsenale, compreso le liste nere, in crumiri e 
nelle ingiunzioni della corte contro uso dei percussori dei 
boicottaggi e dei colpi di compassione. Anche se i datori di 
lavoro in anticipo di ventesimo-secolo hanno fatti dichiarare 
agli alleati certi dentro le forze della polizia e la polizia locale 
strettamente gestita, hanno continuato ad assumere la loro propria 
polizia riservata -- agenzie detective che hanno usato gli operatori 
segreti per interrompere i sindacati ed hanno fornito i thugs per 
proteggere i crumiri durante i colpi. Questo annuncio 1917 per 
l'agenzia detective Cleveland-basata di gioia è comparso nelle 
industrie americane, la pubblicazione ufficiale dell'associazione 
nazionale dei fornitori.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μέχρι περίπου το 1903, οι εργοδότες άρχισαν να 
επικολλούν τις οργανωμένες εκστρατείες για να σπάσουν τη δύναμη 
των εργατικών συνδικάτων, ιδιαίτερα στα εμπόρια μετάλλων. 
Οι εργοδότες είχαν μια ευρεία σειρά όπλων στο οπλοστάσιό 
τους, συμπεριλαμβανομένων των μαύρων λιστών, strikebreakers, και
των εντολών δικαστηρίων ενάντια στη χρήση των απεργών των 
μποϊκοταρισμάτων και των απεργιών συμπόνοιας. Αν και οι 
πρώτοι εργοδότες εικοστός-αιώνα είχαν τους αξιόπιστους 
συμμάχους στις δυνάμεις κρατικής αστυνομίας και τη στενά 
ελεγχόμενη τοπική αστυνομία, συνέχισαν να μισθώνουν την ιδιωτική
αστυνομία τους -- αντιπροσωπείες ιδιωτικών αστυνομικών που 
χρησιμοποίησαν τους μυστικούς χειριστές για να αναστατώσουν τις 
ενώσεις και παρείχαν τους κακοποιούς για να προστατεύσουν 
strikebreakers κατά τη διάρκεια των απεργιών. Αυτή η 
αγγελία του 1917 για την Κλήβελαντ-βασισμένη στην αντιπροσωπεία
ιδιωτικών αστυνομικών χαράς εμφανίστηκε στις αμερικανικές 
βιομηχανίες, η Επίσημη Έκδοση της εθνικής ένωσης των 
κατασκευαστών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Por alrededor 1903, los patrones comenzaron a 
montar campañas ordenadas para romper la potencia de sindicatos, 
determinado en los comercios del metal. Los patrones tenían un 
amplio arsenal de armas en su arsenal, incluyendo listas negras, 
rompehuelgas, y prescripciones de la corte contra el uso de los 
huelguistas de boicoteos y de huelgas de condolencia. Aunque los
patrones tempranos del vige'simo-siglo tenían aliados confiables en 
estado limpian fuerzas y policía local firmemente controlado, 
continuaron empleando a su propio policía privado -- las agencias 
detectives que utilizaron a operarios secretos para interrumpir 
uniones y proveieron a gamberros para proteger a rompehuelgas durante 
huelgas. Este anuncio 1917 para la agencia detective 
Cleveland-basada de la alegría apareció en las industrias 
americanas, la publicación oficial de la asociación nacional de 
fabricantes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086760</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105864</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/pride-and-joy-specialists-in-breaking-strikes</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
