<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105842</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105842</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087153</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Unequal pay is immoral": Debating the Equal Pay Act of 1963</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ungleiche Bezahlung ist" unmoralisch: 
Debattieren der gleiche Bezahlung Tat von 1963</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"le salaire inégal est immoral" : Discussion
de l'acte d'égalité de salaires de 1963</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"o pagamento desigual é immoral": Debatendo 
o ato do pagamento igual de 1963</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la paga disuguale è immorale": Dibattere la
Legge di parità salariale di 1963</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ανισος πληρώστε είναι ανήθικοσ": Συζήτηση του 
νόμου ίσης αμοιβής του 1963</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">la "paga desigual es inmoral": Discutir el 
acto de la igualdad de salario de 1963</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Recommendations by the National War Labor Board during World War II to pay male and female workers equal wages yielded few changes in the gender wage gap. Women continued to receive less money for comparable work, and into the 1960s want ads characterized jobs as "male" or "female" with resulting salary differences based on gender. The Equal Pay Act (EPA) made it illegal to pay men and women differently for similar work. Although the EPA was passed in 1963, it was debated in workplaces and courtrooms for decades thereafter. In this passionately argued Senate hearing testimony, Caroline Davis, Director of the United Automobile, Aerospace, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America (UAW) Women's Department declared wage discrimination immoral and inefficient. She rebutted EPA's critics who claimed that women were more expensive to employ than men and compared unequal pay based on gender to workplace discrimination against immigrants, African Americans, industrial workers, and workers in colonial societies.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Empfehlungen durch das nationale Krieg-Arbeit Brett
während des Zweiten Weltkrieges, die männlichen und weiblichen 
Arbeiter zu zahlen gleiche Löhne erbrachten wenige Änderungen im 
Geschlechtlohnabstand. Frauen fuhren fort, weniger Geld für 
vergleichbare Arbeit zu empfangen, und in die sechziger Jahre 
wünschen Sie ADS gekennzeichnete Jobs als "Mann" oder "Frau" mit den 
resultierenden Gehalt Unterschieden, die auf Geschlecht basieren. 
Die gleiche Bezahlung Tat (EPA) bildete es ungültig, Männer 
und Frauen für ähnliche Arbeit anders als zu zahlen. Obgleich 
das EPA 1963 geführt wurde, wurde es in den Arbeitsplätzen und in 
den Gerichtssälen für Dekaden danach debattiert. 
Diesbezüglich argumentierte leidenschaftlich 
Senathörfähigkeit Zeugnis, Caroline Davis, Direktor des vereinigten 
Automobils, des Aerospaces, und landwirtschaftlichen der 
Werkzeug-Arbeiter Amerika (UAW) erklärten unmoralischen und 
wirkungslosen Lohnunterscheidung der Frauen der Abteilung. Sie 
widerlegte Kritiker EPAs, die behaupteten, daß Frauen kostspieliger 
waren als Männer zu beschäftigen und verglichen die ungleiche 
Bezahlung, die auf Geschlecht mit Arbeitsplatzdiskriminierung gegen 
Immigranten, afrikanische Amerikaner, industrielle Arbeiter und 
Arbeiter in den Kolonialgesellschaften basierte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les recommandations par l'office national de 
travail de guerre pendant la deuxième guerre mondiale de payer les 
ouvriers de sexe masculin et féminins les salaires égaux ont 
rapporté peu de changements de l'écart salarial de genre. Les 
femmes ont continué à recevoir moins d'argent pour le travail 
comparable, et dans les années 60 voulez les travaux caractérisés 
par ADS en tant que le "mâle" ou "femelle" avec des différences 
résultantes de salaire basées sur le genre. La Loi d'égalité
de salaires (EPA) l'a rendu illégal pour payer des hommes et des 
femmes différemment le travail semblable. Bien que l'EPA ait 
été passé en 1963, il a été discuté dans les lieux de travail et
les auditoires de tribunal pendant des décennies ensuite. En 
cela a passionément discuté le témoignage d'audition de sénat, 
Caroline Davis, directeur de l'automobile unie, de l'espace, et des 
ouvriers agricoles d'instrument de la discrimination du salaire 
avouée par service des femmes de l'Amérique (t.u.a.) immorale et 
inefficace. Elle a réfuté les critiques d'EPA qui ont 
réclamé que les femmes étaient plus chères d'utiliser que des 
hommes et ont comparé le salaire inégal basé sur le genre à la 
discrimination de lieu de travail contre des immigrés, des 
Américains africains, des ouvriers industriels, et des ouvriers dans 
les sociétés coloniales.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As recomendações pela placa nacional do trabalho 
da guerra durante a segunda guerra mundial pagar os trabalhadores 
masculinos e fêmeas salários iguais renderam poucas mudanças na 
abertura de salário do gender. As mulheres continuaram a 
receber menos dinheiro para o trabalho comparável, e nos 1960s queira
trabalhos caracterizados ads como o "macho" ou a "fêmea" com as 
diferenças resultantes do salário baseadas no gender. O ato do
pagamento igual (EPA) fêz ilegal para pagar diferentemente homens e 
mulheres pelo trabalho similar. Embora o EPA fosse passado em 
1963, foi debatido nos workplaces e nos courtrooms por décadas depois
disso. Neste discutiu passionately o testimony do hearing do 
senate, Caroline Davis, diretor do automóvel unido, do aeroespaço, e
dos trabalhadores agriculturais do instrumento da discriminação 
declarada departamento do salário das mulheres de América (UAW) 
immoral e inefficient. Rebutted os críticos de EPA que 
reivindicaram que as mulheres eram mais caras empregar do que homens e
compararam o pagamento desigual baseado no gender à discriminação 
do workplace de encontro aos immigrants, aos americanos africanos, aos
trabalhadores industriais, e aos trabalhadores em sociedades 
coloniais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le raccomandazioni dal Bordo Di lavoro di 
guerra nazionale durante la seconda guerra mondiale pagare gli operai 
maschii e femminili stipendi uguali hanno reso pochi cambiamenti nello
spacco di stipendio di genere. Le donne hanno continuato a 
ricevere meno soldi per lavoro paragonabile e negli anni 60 desideri i
lavori caratterizzati ads come "il maschio" o "femmina" con le 
differenze risultanti di stipendio basate sul genere. La Legge 
di parità salariale (EPA) lo ha reso illegale per pagare diversamente
gli uomini e le donne lavoro simile. Anche se il EPA è stato 
passato in 1963, è stato dibattuto da allora in poi in posti di 
lavoro ed in aule di tribunale per le decadi. In questa ha discusso 
appassionato la testimonianza di udienza del senato, Caroline Davis, 
direttore dell'automobile unita, dell'aerospazio e degli operai 
agricoli dello strumento di distinzione dello stipendio dichiarata 
reparto delle donne dell'America (UAW) immorale ed inefficiente. 
Ha rifiutato i critici del EPA che hanno sostenuto che le donne 
erano più costose impiegare che gli uomini ed hanno confrontato la 
paga disuguale basata sul genere a distinzione del posto di lavoro 
contro gli immigranti, gli Americani africani, i lavoratori 
dell'industria e gli operai nelle società coloniali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι συστάσεις από το εθνικό συμβούλιο πολεμικής 
εργασίας κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ για να 
πληρώσουν στους άνδρες και γυναίκες εργαζομένους τις ίσες 
αμοιβές παρήγαγαν λίγες αλλαγές στο χάσμα αμοιβών γένους. 
Οι γυναίκες συνέχισαν να λαμβάνουν τα λιγότερα χρήματα για 
τη συγκρίσιμη εργασία, και στη δεκαετία του '60 θελήστε 
χαρακτηρισμένες τις αγγελίες εργασίες ως "αρσενικό" ή "θηλυκό" 
με τις προκύπτουσες διαφορές μισθών βασισμένες στο γένος. Ο
νόμος ίσης αμοιβής (EPA) το κατέστησε παράνομο να πληρώσει 
τους άνδρες και τις γυναίκες διαφορετικά για την παρόμοια 
εργασία. Αν και το EPA πέρασαν το 1963, συζητήθηκε 
στους εργασιακούς χώρους και τα δικαστήρια για δεκαετίες έκτοτε. 
Σε αυτήν την παθιασμένα υποστηριγμένη κατάθεση ακρόασης 
Συγκλήτου, η Caroline Davis, σκηνοθέτης του ενωμένου 
αυτοκινήτου, αεροδιάστημα, και γεωργικός εφαρμόζει τους 
εργαζομένους δηλωμένης διάκρισης αμοιβών των γυναικών της 
Αμερικής (UAW) της τμήμα ανήθικης και ανεπαρκούς. 
Αντέκρουσε τους κριτικούς EPA που υποστήριξαν ότι οι 
γυναίκες ήταν ακριβότερες να υιοθετήσουν από τους άνδρες και 
συγκρινόμενος άνισος πληρώνουν βασισμένος στο γένος στη διάκριση
εργασιακών χώρων ενάντια στους μετανάστες, αφρικανικούς 
Αμερικανούς, τους βιομηχανικούς εργάτες, και τους εργαζομένους 
στις αποικιακές κοινωνίες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las recomendaciones por la tarjeta nacional del 
trabajo de la guerra durante la Segunda Guerra Mundial de pagar a 
trabajadores masculinos y femeninos los salarios iguales rindieron 
pocos cambios en el boquete de salario del género. Las mujeres 
continuaron recibiendo menos dinero para el trabajo comparable, y en 
los años 60 desee los trabajos caracterizados ads como "varón" o 
"hembra" con las diferencias del sueldo que resultan basadas en 
género. El acto de la igualdad de salario (EPA) hizo ilegal 
pagar hombres y a mujeres diferentemente trabajo similar. Aunque
el EPA fue pasado en 1963, fue discutido en lugares de trabajo y 
salas de tribunal por décadas después de eso. En esto discutió 
apasionado el testimonio de la audiencia del senado, Caroline Davis, 
director del automóvil unido, del espacio aéreo, y de los 
trabajadores agrícolas del instrumento de la discriminación 
declarada departamento del salario de las mujeres de América (UAW) 
inmoral e ineficaz. Ella refutó a críticos de EPA que 
demandaron que las mujeres eran más costosas emplear que hombres y 
compararon la paga desigual basada en género a la discriminación del
lugar de trabajo contra inmigrantes, americanos africanos, 
trabajadores industriales, y trabajadores en sociedades coloniales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087153</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105842</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/unequal-pay-is-immoral-debating-the-equal-pay-act-of-1963</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
