<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106321</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106321</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206856</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Disability Studies for Teachers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Unfähigkeit-Studien für Lehrer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Études d'incapacité pour des professeurs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Estudos da inabilidade para professores</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi di inabilità per gli insegnanti</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μελέτες ανικανότητας για τους δασκάλους</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Estudios de la inhabilidad para los profesores</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">offers lesson plans and essays on disability studies -- the examination of disability as a social, cultural, and political phenomenon. Among the topics: a history of deaf education, efforts to reform poorhouses in the 1840s and 1850s, P.T. Barnum and freak shows, and conscientious objectors during World War II who exposed horrific conditions at state institutions, and an introduction to disability studies.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Angebotlektionpläne und Versuche auf 
Unfähigkeitstudien -- die Prüfung der Unfähigkeit als Sozial-, 
kulturelles und politisches Phänomen. Unter den Themen: 
eine Geschichte der tauben Ausbildung, Bemühungen, poorhouses 
im 1840s und im 1850s, P.T zu verbessern. Barnum und 
ungewöhnliche Erscheinen und Kriegsdienstverweigerer aus 
Gewissensgründen während des Zweiten Weltkrieges, der entsetzliche 
Bedingungen an den Zustandanstalten herausstellte und einer Einleitung
in eine Unfähigkeit studiert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">plans de leçon d'offres et essais sur des 
études d'incapacité -- l'examen de l'incapacité comme phénomène 
social, culturel, et politique. Parmi les sujets : une 
histoire d'éducation sourde, efforts de reformer des poorhouses dans 
le 1840s et le 1850s, P.T. Barnum et expositions anormales, et 
protestataires consciencieux pendant la deuxième guerre mondiale qui 
a exposé des conditions terrifiantes aux établissements d'état, et 
une introduction à l'incapacité étudie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">plantas da lição das ofertas e essays em 
estudos da inabilidade -- a examinação da inabilidade como um 
fenômeno social, cultural, e político. Entre os tópicos: 
um history da instrução surda, esforços reformar poorhouses 
no 1840s e no 1850s, P.T. Barnum e as mostras freak, e os 
objectors conscienciosos durante a segunda guerra mundial que expôs 
circunstâncias horrific em instituições do estado, e uma 
introdução à inabilidade estudam.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">programmi di lezione di offerte e saggi sugli 
studi di inabilità -- l'esame dell'inabilità come fenomeno sociale, 
culturale e politico. Fra i soggetti: una storia di 
formazione sorda, sforzi riformare i poorhouses nel 1840s e nel 1850s,
P.T. Barnum e le esposizioni strane ed i objectors coscienziosi 
durante la seconda guerra mondiale a che ha esposto i termini horrific
dichiarano le istituzioni e un'introduzione all'inabilità 
studia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">προσφέρει τα σχέδια και τα δοκίμια μαθήματος στις 
μελέτες ανικανότητας -- η εξέταση της ανικανότητας ως κοινωνικό, 
πολιτιστικό, και πολιτικό φαινόμενο. Μεταξύ των θεμάτων: 
μια ιστορία της κωφών εκπαίδευσης, των προσπαθειών να 
μεταρρυθμίσει poorhouses στο 1840s και 1850s, P.T. 
Barnum και φρικτός εμφανίζει, και ευσυνείδητοι ενιστάμενοι 
κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ ποιος εξέθεσε τους 
φρικιαστικούς όρους στα κρατικά όργανα, και μια εισαγωγή 
στις μελέτες ανικανότητας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">planes y ensayos en estudios de la inhabilidad --
la examinación de la lección de las ofertas de la inhabilidad como 
fenómeno social, cultural, y político. Entre los asuntos: 
una historia de la educación sorda, esfuerzos de reformar 
poorhouses en el 1840s y el 1850s, P.T. Barnum y las 
demostraciones anormales, y los objetores concienzudos durante la 
Segunda Guerra Mundial que expuso condiciones horrific en las 
instituciones del estado, y una introducción a la inhabilidad 
estudia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206856</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106321</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/disability-studies-for-teachers</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
