<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105869</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105869</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086810</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Selfish wealth is never good": A Worker's Definition of Success</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"egoistische Fülle ist nie" gut: Definition
eines Arbeiters des Erfolges</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"la richesse égoïste n'est jamais bonne" : 
La définition d'un ouvrier du succès</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"a riqueza selfish é nunca boa": 
Definição de um trabalhador do sucesso</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la ricchezza egoista non è mai buona": 
Definizione dell'operaio di successo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο "εγωιστικός πλούτος δεν είναι ποτέ καλόσ": Ο 
καθορισμός ενός εργαζομένου της επιτυχίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">la "abundancia egoísta nunca es buena": 
Definición de un trabajador del éxito</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The ideology of success--the notion that anyone could make it with enough hard work--was widely promoted in Gilded Age America. One of its most famous proponents was the author Horatio Alger, whose novels showed how poor boys could move from "rags to respectability" through "pluck and luck." Between the late 1860s and his death in 1899, Alger published more than 100 of these formulaic stories about poor boys who made good more often because of fortunate accidents than because of hard work and denial. Not all Americans, however, bought into this ideology of success. This 1884 editorial in the  Firemen's Magazine , the journal of the Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen, challenged the equation of success with wealth and raised broader questions about the meaning of success.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Ideologie des Erfolges -- der Begriff, die 
jedermann bilden könnte es mit genügender harten Arbeit -- wurde 
weit in vergoldetem Alter Amerika gefördert. Einer seiner 
berühmtesten Antragsteller war der Autor Horatio Alger, dessen Romane
zeigten, wie arme Jungen umziehen konnten von "Lappen zu 
Respectability" durch "zupfen und Glück." Zwischen dem späten 
1860s und seinem Tod 1899, veröffentlichte Alger mehr als 100 dieser 
formulaic Geschichten über arme Jungen, die gut häufig wegen der 
glücklichen Unfälle als wegen der harten Arbeit und der Ablehnung 
bildeten. Nicht alle Amerikaner jedoch akzeptiert diese 
Ideologie des Erfolges. Dieser Leitartikel 1884 in der 
Zeitschrift der Feuerwehrmänner, das Journal der Bruderschaft der 
sich fortbewegenden Feuerwehrmänner, forderte die Gleichung des 
Erfolges mit Fülle heraus und warf ausgedehntere Fragen über die 
Bedeutung des Erfolges auf.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'idéologie du succès -- la notion que n'importe
qui pourrait lui faire avec assez de travail dur -- a été largement 
favorisée dans l'âge doré Amérique. Un de ses partisans plus
célèbres était l'auteur Horatio Alger, dont les romans ont montré 
"par" comment les pauvres garçons pourraient se déplacer des 
"chiffons à la respectabilité plument et chance." Entre le 
1860s en retard et sa mort en 1899, Alger a édité plus de 100 de ces
histoires formulaic au sujet des pauvres garçons qui ont réparé 
plus souvent en raison des accidents chanceux qu'en raison du travail 
dur et du démenti. Non tous les Américains, cependant, 
achetés dans cette idéologie de succès. Cet éditorial 1884 
dans le magazine des pompiers, le journal de la confrérie des 
pompiers locomotifs, a défié l'équation du succès avec la richesse
et a soulevé de plus larges questions au sujet de la signification du
succès.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O ideology do sucesso -- a noção que qualquer um
poderia lhe fazer com bastante trabalho duro -- foi promovido 
extensamente na idade gilded América. Um de seus proponents 
mais famosos era o autor Horatio Alger, cujas as novelas mostraram 
como os meninos deficientes poderiam se mover dos "panos ao 
respectability" com "arrancam e sorte." Entre o 1860s atrasado e
sua morte em 1899, Alger publicou mais de 100 destas histórias 
formulaic sobre os meninos deficientes que fizeram bom mais 
frequentemente por causa dos acidentes afortunados do que por causa do
trabalho duro e da negação. Não todos os americanos, 
entretanto, comprados neste ideology do sucesso. Este editorial 
1884 no compartimento dos firemen, o jornal do brotherhood de firemen 
locomotive, desafiou a equação do sucesso com riqueza e levantou 
umas perguntas mais largas sobre o meaning do sucesso.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'ideologia di successo -- la nozione che chiunque
potrebbe rendergli con abbastanza lavoro duro -- ampiamente è stata 
promossa nell'età gilded America. Uno dei relativi fautori più
famosi era l'autore Horatio Alger, di cui i romanzi hanno mostrato 
come i poveri ragazzi potrebbero muoversi "dai panni a 
respectability" con "colgono e fortuna." Fra il 1860s ritardato 
e la sua morte in 1899, Alger ha pubblicato più di 100 di queste 
storia formulaic circa i poveri ragazzi che hanno compensato più 
spesso a causa degli incidenti fortunati che a causa di lavoro duro e 
della smentita. Non tutti gli Americani, tuttavia, comprati in 
questa ideologia di successo. Questo editoriale 1884 nello 
scomparto dei vigili del fuoco, il giornale della fratellanza dei 
vigili del fuoco locomotivi, ha sfidato l'equazione di successo con 
ricchezza ed ha sollevato le più vaste questioni circa il significato
del successo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ιδεολογία της επιτυχίας -- η έννοια ότι καθεμία θα 
μπορούσε να την κάνει με αρκετή σκληρή εργασία -- προωθήθηκε 
ευρέως στην επιχρυσωμένη ηλικία Αμερική. Ένας από τους 
διασημότερους υπερασπιστές του ήταν ο συντάκτης Horatio 
Alger, τα ο οποίος μυθιστορήματα επέδειξαν πώς τα φτωχά 
αγόρια θα μπορούσαν να κινηθούν από "τα κουρέλια στη 
σεβασμιότητα" μέσω "μαδούν και τύχη." Μεταξύ του πρόσφατου
1860s και του θανάτου του το 1899, Alger δημοσίευσε 
περισσότερο από 100 αυτών των formulaic ιστοριών για τα 
φτωχά αγόρια που έκαναν καλός συχνότερα λόγω των τυχερών 
ατυχημάτων απ'ό,τι λόγω της σκληρής εργασίας και της άρνησης. 
Όχι όλοι οι Αμερικανοί, εντούτοις, αγόρασαν σε αυτήν την 
ιδεολογία της επιτυχίας. Αυτό το κύριο άρθρο 1884 στο 
περιοδικό των πυροσβεστών, το περιοδικό της αδελφοσύνης των 
κινητήριων πυροσβεστών, προκάλεσε την εξίσωση της επιτυχίας με 
τον πλούτο και έθεσε τις ευρύτερες ερωτήσεις για την έννοια της 
επιτυχίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La ideología del éxito -- la noción que 
cualquier persona podría hacerle con bastante trabajo duro -- fue 
promovida extensamente en la edad dorada América. Uno de sus 
autores más famosos era el autor Horatio Alger, que novelas mostraron
"con" cómo los muchachos pobres podrían moverse desde los "trapos a 
la respetabilidad despluman y suerte." Entre el último 1860s y 
su muerte en 1899, Alger publicó más de 100 de estas historias 
formulaic sobre los muchachos pobres que hicieron bueno más a menudo 
debido a accidentes afortunados que debido a trabajo duro y la 
negación. No todos los americanos, sin embargo, comprados en 
esta ideología del éxito. Este editorial 1884 en el 
compartimiento de los bomberos, el diario de la fraternidad de 
bomberos locomotores, desafió la ecuación del éxito con abundancia 
y planteó preguntas más amplias sobre el significado del éxito.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086810</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105869</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/selfish-wealth-is-never-good-a-workers-definition-of-success</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
