<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103838</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103838</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205899</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Smithsonian: Art and Design</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Smithsonian: Kunst und Design</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Smithsonien : Art et conception</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Smithsonian: Arte e projeto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Smithsonian: Arte e disegno</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σμιθσονιτικός: Τέχνη και σχέδιο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Smithsonian: Arte y diseño</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features modern portrait drawings, historical portraits of famous Americans, African and Asian art, modern Japanese prints, works of Latino artists, illustrated manuscripts of Persian lyrical poetry, paintings by James Whistler and Gerhard Richter, lighthouse postcards, lunch containers, Tibetan healing mandalas, photos of famous 20th-century American women, and the Smithsonian's blog, Eye Level, which looks at how art reflects our history and culture.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">kennzeichnet moderne Portraitzeichnungen, 
historische Portraits der berühmten Amerikaner, afrikanische und 
asiatische kunst, moderne Japanerdrucke, Arbeiten der Latino 
Künstler, erläuterte Manuskripte der persischen lyrical Poesie, 
Anstriche durch James Whistler und Gerhard Richter, 
Leuchtturmpostkarten, Mittagessenbehälter, tibetanische heilende 
mandalas, Fotos der berühmten amerikanischen Frauen 20th-century und 
das Smithsonian blog, Augenhöhe, die betrachtet, wie kunst unsere 
Geschichte und Kultur reflektiert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">comporte les schémas modernes de verticale, les 
verticales historiques des Américains célèbres, l'art africain et 
asiatique, les copies modernes de Japonais, les travaux des artistes 
latins, les manuscrits illustrés de la poésie lyrique persane,
les peintures par James Whistler et Gerhard Richter, 
les cartes postales de phare, les récipients de déjeuner, les 
mandalas curatifs tibétains, les photos des femmes 20th-century 
américaines célèbres, et le blog Smithsonien, la hauteur d'oeil, 
qui regarde comment l'art reflète notre histoire et culture.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">caracteriza desenhos modernos do retrato, retratos
históricos de americanos famosos, arte africana e asian, cópias 
modernas do japonês, trabalhos de artistas de Latino, manuscritos 
ilustrados da poesia lyrical persa, pinturas por James Whistler e por 
Gerhard Richter, postcards do farol, recipientes do lunch, mandalas 
healing tibetanos, fotos das mulheres 20th-century americanas famosas,
e o blog smithsonian, o nível de olho, que olha como a arte reflete 
nossos history e cultura.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">caratterizza le illustrazioni moderne del 
ritratto, ritratti storici degli Americani famosi, l'arte 
africana ed asiatica, stampe moderne del giapponese, impianti degli 
artisti di Latino, manoscritti illustrati della poesia lyrical 
persiana, pitture da James Whistler e da Gerhard Richter, cartoline 
del faro, contenitori del pranzo, mandalas healing tibetani, foto 
delle donne americane famose 20th-century ed il blog smithsonian, 
altezza d'occhio, che guarda come l'arte riflette la nostre storia e 
coltura.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χαρακτηρίζει τα σύγχρονα σχέδια πορτρέτου, τα 
ιστορικά πορτρέτα διάσημων Αμερικανών, την αφρικανική και 
ασιατική τέχνη, τις σύγχρονες ιαπωνικές τυπωμένες ύλες, τις 
εργασίες των λατίνων καλλιτεχνών, τα διευκρινισμένα χειρόγραφα 
της περσικής λυρικής ποίησης, τα έργα ζωγραφικής από james 
Whistler και Gerhard Richter, τις κάρτες φάρων, τα 
εμπορευματοκιβώτια μεσημεριανού γεύματος, τα θιβετιανά mandalas
θεραπείας, τις φωτογραφίες των διάσημων αμερικανικών γυναικών 
20ός-αιώνα, και το σμιθσονιτικό blog, επίπεδο ματιών, το 
οποίο εξετάζει το πώς η τέχνη απεικονίζει την ιστορία και τον 
πολιτισμό μας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece gráficos modernos del retrato, los 
retratos históricos de americanos famosos, arte africano y asiático,
las impresiones modernas del japonés, los trabajos de los artistas de
Latino, los manuscritos ilustrados de la poesía lírica persa, las 
pinturas por James Whistler y Gerhard Richter, las postales del faro, 
los envases del almuerzo, los mandalas curativos tibetanos, las fotos 
de las mujeres americanas famosas 20th-century, y el blog smithsonian,
el nivel del ojo, que mira cómo el arte refleja nuestra historia y 
cultura.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205899</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103838</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/smithsonian-art-and-design</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
