<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104234</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104234</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085239</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Native American Assimilation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gebürtige Amerikanische Assimilation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Assimilation Américaine Indigène</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Assimilation Americano Nativo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Assimilazione Americana Natale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εγγενής αμερικανική αφομοίωση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Asimilación Americana Nativa</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Beginning in the 1700s, the Spaniards built the California Missions to make contact with Native Americans in the hope of converting them to Christianity. One painting by a Russian artist depicts a group of Native Americans dancing in front of Mission Dolores in San Francisco; a later photograph shows a group of nuns with westernized native children in front of the Pala Mission in Southern California. As European Americans continued to migrate West throughout the 1800s, they came into conflict with the native peoples who lived there. Native Americans were increasingly pushed off their lands and forced onto reservations. At the same time, whites pressured Native Americans to assimilate. Native American children were sent away to boarding schools with the goal of socializing them and teaching them ?white ways.? Several photographs depict young Native American children wearing western dress in boarding school settings. Some of the photographs taken in the mid-1800s show Native Americans wearing traditional clothing (including "Jicarilla Apache Brave and Squaw, lately wedded," "Coyotero Apache Scouts," and "Group of Apaches, in front of the Wick-8-ups [sic]"). Photographs taken at the turn of the 20th century, such as "Pummuke" and "Chief Chepah, his wife, son, and daughter-in-law," indicate that by then even older Native Americans were adopting Western dress. Several photographs in this topic are from government-sponsored survey expeditions launched in the early 1870s to chart western lands and native peoples. These expeditions coincided with the beginning of anthropology as a science. In 1879, Congress created the Bureau of Ethnology to study and document the native people and their cultures. Included here are three portraits taken for these ethnographic field studies, and a painting of Sitting Bull, the famous Sioux medicine chief. Native Americans clashed violently and repeatedly with the white European Americans moving into their territory. The whites wanted to push the Indians off their land and onto reservations, but the Indians often refused to go. The Lakota branch of the Sioux tribe was one such group, and in 1875 their refusal resulted in the Lakota War. A famous battle in the Lakota War took place at the Little Bighorn River in Montana in 1876; there, US forces under General George Armstrong Custer attacked Crazy Horse and hundreds of Lakota and Northern Cheyenne warriors. In the battle, which came to be known as Custer's Last Stand, Custer's men were outnumbered four to one and every white man was killed. A drawing and a color lithograph show versions of this battle. Some Crow served as scouts for General Custer in the 7th Cavalry. One stereoscopic view shows "Curley" ? the only Indian survivor fighting on Custer's side ? wearing a buffalo coat and sitting astride a horse.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Anfangend im 1700s, bauten die Spaniards die 
Kalifornien Missionen auf, um Kontakt mit gebürtigen Amerikanern in 
der Hoffnung des Umwandelns sie in Christentum zu bilden. Ein 
Anstrich durch einen russischen Künstler stellt eine Gruppe 
gebürtige Amerikaner bildlich dar, die vor Mission Dolores in San 
Francisco tanzen; eine neuere Fotographie stellt dar, daß eine 
Gruppe Nonnen mit gebürtige Kinder vor der Pala Mission in 
Südkalifornien westernized. Während europäische Amerikaner 
fortfuhren, während des 1800s nach Westen fortzuziehen, kamen sie in 
$überschneidung mit den gebürtigen Völkern, die dort lebten. 
Gebürtige Amerikaner wurden in zunehmendem Maße weg von ihren 
Ländern gedrückt und erzwungen auf Reservierungen. 
Gleichzeitig drueckte Weiß gebürtige Amerikaner, um 
anzupassen. Gebürtige amerikanische Kinder wurden weg zu 
Internaten mit dem Ziel des Sozialisierens sie und des Unterrichtens 
ihnen von von?white Methoden geschickt? Einige Fotographien 
stellen die jungen gebürtigen amerikanischen Kinder bildlich dar, die
westliches Kleid in den Internateinstellungen tragen. Einige der
Fotographien, die auf die mid-1800s Erscheinen gebürtigen Amerikaner 
tragen die traditionellen Kleidung genommen werden (einschließlich 
"Jicarilla tapferer Apache und Squaw, wedded kürzlich," "Coyotero 
Apache Pfadfinder," und "Gruppe Apaches, vor dem Wick-8-ups [ sic ]").
Fotographien, die an der Jahrhundertwende 20., wie "Pummuke" und 
"Hauptchepah, seine Frau, Sohn und Schwiegertochter genommen werden," 
zeigen an, daß bis dahin ältere gebürtige Amerikaner annahmen 
westliches Kleid glätten Sie. Einige Fotographien in diesem 
Thema sind von den staatlich geförderten Übersicht Expeditionen, die
in das frühe 1870s ausgestoßen werden, um westliche Länder und 
gebürtige Völker zu entwerfen. Diese Expeditionen stimmten mit
dem Anfang von Anthropologie als Wissenschaft überein. 1879 
erstellte Kongreß das Büro von Ethnologie, um die gebürtigen Leute 
und ihre Kulturen zu studieren und zu dokumentieren. Hier 
geschlossen drei Portraits ein, die für diese ethnographischen 
genommen werden, auffangen Studien und einen Anstrich von 
Sitting Bull, der berühmte Sioux Medizinleiter. Gebürtige 
Amerikaner heftig und wiederholt zusammengestoßen mit den weißen 
europäischen Amerikanern, die in ihre Gegend umziehen. Das 
Weiß wollte die Inder weg von ihrem Land und auf Reservierungen 
drücken, aber die Inder lehnten häufig ab zu gehen. Der Lakota
Zweig des Sioux Stammes war eine solche Gruppe, und in 1875 ergab ihre
Ablehnung den Lakota Krieg. Eine berühmte Schlacht im Lakota 
Krieg fand am kleiner Bighorn-Fluß in Montana 1876 statt; dort 
nahmen US Kräfte unter General George Armstrong Custer verrücktes 
Pferd und Hunderte Lakota und Nordcheyenne Krieger in Angriff. 
In der Schlacht die kam, als Custers letzter Standplatz bekannt,
wurden Männer Custers vier bis eins gewesen und jeder weiße Mann 
wurde beendet. Eine Zeichnung und eine Farbe Lithographie zeigen
Versionen dieser Schlacht. Irgendeine Krähe diente als 
Pfadfinder für General Custer in der 7. Kavallerie. Eine 
stereoskopische Ansicht zeigt "Curley"? der einzige indische 
Überlebende, der auf Seite Custers kämpft? das Tragen eines 
Büffels beschichten und das Sitzen rittlings auf einem Pferd.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Commençant dans le 1700s, les Espagnols ont 
établi les missions de la Californie pour faire le contact avec les 
Américains indigènes dans l'espoir de les convertir en 
christianisme. Une peinture par un artiste russe dépeint un 
groupe d'Américains indigènes dansant devant la mission Dolores dans
San Francisco ; une photographie postérieure montre un groupe
de nonnes avec les enfants indigènes occidentalisés devant la mission 
de Pala dans Californie méridionale. Pendant que les 
Américains européens continuaient à passer à l'ouest dans tout le 
1800s, ils ont hérité le conflit avec les indigènes qui ont vécu 
là. Des Américains indigènes ont été de plus en plus 
poussés outre de leurs terres et forcés sur des réservations. 
En même temps, les blancs ont pressurisé les Américains 
indigènes pour assimiler. Des enfants américains indigènes 
ont été envoyés loin aux internats avec le but de les socialiser et
de leur enseigner des voies de ?white ? Plusieurs photographies 
dépeignent de jeunes enfants américains indigènes portant la robe 
occidentale dans des configurations d'internat. Certaines des 
photographies prises dans les Américains indigènes d'exposition de 
mid-1800s portant photographies traditionnelles d'habillement (les 
"Jicarilla y compris Apache Bravent et Squaw, 
wedded récemment," des "scouts de Coyotero Apache," et "groupe 
d'apaches, devant le Wick-8-ups [ sic ]"). prises à la fin du 20ème 
siècle, tel que "Pummuke" et "Chepah en chef, son épouse, fils, et 
belle-fille," indiquent qu'encore d'ici là des Américains indigènes
plus âgés adoptaient la robe occidentale. Plusieurs 
photographies dans ce sujet sont des expéditions commanditées par le
gouvernement d'étude lancées dans le 1870s tôt pour dresser une 
carte les terres occidentales et les indigènes. Ces 
expéditions ont coïncidé avec le début de l'anthropologie comme 
science. En 1879, le congrès a créé le bureau de 
l'éthnologie pour étudier et documenter les indigènes et leurs 
cultures. Incluses ici sont trois verticales prises pour ces 
études sur le terrain ethnographiques, et une peinture de la séance 
Bull, le chef célèbre de médecine de Sioux. Américains 
indigènes opposés violemment et à plusieurs reprises avec les 
Américains européens blancs entrant dans leur territoire. Les 
blancs ont voulu pousser les Indiens outre de leur terre et sur des 
réservations, mais les Indiens ont souvent refusé d'aller. Le 
branchement de Lakota de la tribu de Sioux était un tel groupe, et en
1875 leur refus a eu comme conséquence la guerre de Lakota. Une
bataille célèbre dans la guerre de Lakota a eu lieu au fleuve de 
Little Bighorn au Montana en 1876 ; là, les forces des USA sous 
George général Armstrong Custer ont attaqué le cheval fou et 
les centaines de Lakota et guerriers nordiques de Cheyenne. Dans
la bataille, qui est venue pour être connue comme dernier stand de 
Custer, les hommes de Custer ont été dépassés en nombre quatre à 
un et chaque homme blanc a été détruit. Un schéma et une 
lithographie de couleur montrent des versions de cette bataille. 
Une certaine corneille a servi de scouts au Général Custer 
dans la 7ème cavalerie. Une vue stéréoscopique montre 
"Curley" ? le seul survivant indien combattant du côté de 
Custer ? le port d'un buffle enduisent et se reposer à cheval 
sur un cheval.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Começando no 1700s, os spaniards construíram as 
missões de Califórnia para fazer o contato com os americanos nativos
na esperança de convertê-los ao christianity. Uma pintura por 
um artista russian descreve um grupo dos americanos nativos que 
dançam na frente da missão Dolores em San Francisco; uma 
fotografia mais atrasada mostra que um grupo dos nuns com westernized 
crianças nativas na frente da missão de Pala em Califórnia do sul. 
Enquanto os americanos europeus continuaram a migrar para o 
oeste durante todo o 1800s, vieram no conflito com os povos nativos 
que viveram lá. Os americanos nativos foram empurrados cada vez
mais fora de suas terras e forçados em reservations. Ao mesmo 
tempo, os brancos exerceram pressão sobre americanos nativos para 
assimilate. As crianças americanas nativas foram emitidas 
afastado às escolas boarding com o objetivo de socializá-las e de 
ensinar-lhes maneiras do?white? Diversas fotografias descrevem 
as crianças americanas nativas novas que desgastam o vestido 
ocidental em ajustes da escola boarding. Algumas das fotografias
feitas exame nos americanos nativos da mostra de mid-1800s que 
desgastam as fotografias tradicionais da roupa ("Jicarilla including 
Apache bravo e Squaw, wedded ultimamente," de "scouts Coyotero 
Apache," e "grupo dos apaches, na frente do Wick-8-ups [ sic ]"). 
feitas exame na volta do 20o século, tal como "Pummuke" e "Chepah 
principal, sua esposa, filho, e nora," indicam que aquela então mesmo
por uns americanos nativos mais velhos adotava o vestido ocidental. 
Diversas fotografias neste tópico são das expedições 
government-sponsored do exame lançadas no 1870s adiantado para fazer 
um mapa de terras ocidentais e de povos nativos. Estas 
expedições coincidiram com o começo do anthropology como uma 
ciência. Em 1879, o congress criou o departamento do ethnology 
para estudar e documentar os povos nativos e suas culturas. São
incluídos aqui três retratos feitos exame para estes estudos de 
campo ethnographic, e uma pintura do assento Bull, chefe famoso da 
medicina de Sioux. Americanos nativos clashed violentamente e 
repetidamente com os americanos europeus brancos que movem-se em seu 
território. Os brancos quiseram empurrar os indians fora de sua
terra e em reservations, mas os indians recusaram frequentemente ir. 
A filial de Lakota do tribe de Sioux era um tal grupo, e em 1875
sua recusa resultou na guerra de Lakota. Uma batalha famosa na 
guerra de Lakota ocorreu no rio do veado selvagem pequeno em Montana 
em 1876; lá, as forças dos E. U. sob o general George 
Armstrong Custer atacaram o cavalo louco e as centenas de Lakota e de 
guerreiros do norte de Cheyenne. Na batalha, que veio ser sabida
como o último carrinho de Custer, os homens de Custer outnumbered 
quatro a um e cada homem branco foi matado. Um desenho e um 
lithograph da cor mostram versões desta batalha. Algum corvo 
serviu como scouts para o general Custer na 7a cavalaria. Uma 
vista stereoscopic mostra "Curley"? o único sobrevivente indian
que luta no lado de Custer? desgastar um búfalo revestem e 
sentar-se montado em um cavalo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Cominciando nel 1700s, gli spaniards hanno 
sviluppato le missioni della California per stabilire il contatto con 
gli Americani natali nella speranza di convertirli in christianity. 
Una pittura da un artista russo descrive un gruppo degli 
Americani natali che ballano davanti la missione Dolores a San 
Francisco; una fotografia successiva mostra che un gruppo dei 
nuns con westernized i bambini natali davanti la missione di Pala 
nella California del sud. Mentre gli Americani europei hanno 
continuato a migrare verso ovest durante il 1800s, hanno entrato nel 
conflitto con le popolazioni autoctone che hanno vissuto là. 
Gli Americani natali sempre più sono stati spinti fuori delle 
loro terre e sono stati forzati sulle prenotazioni. Allo stesso 
tempo, i bianchi pressured gli Americani natali per assimilare. 
I bambini americani natali sono stati trasmessi via ai collegi 
con l'obiettivo di socializzarli e di istruzione loro dei modi 
del?white? Parecchie fotografie descrivono i bambini americani 
natali giovani che portano il vestito occidentale nelle regolazioni 
del collegio. Alcune delle fotografie prese negli Americani 
natali di esposizione di mid-1800s che portano le fotografie 
tradizionali dei vestiti ("Jicarilla compreso Apache brave e Squaw, 
ultimamente wedded," "esploratori di Coyotero Apache," e "gruppo dei 
apaches, davanti il Wick-8-ups [ sic ]"). prese alla fine del 
ventesimo secolo, quali "Pummuke" e "Chepah principale, la sua moglie,
il figlio ed il daughter-in-law," indicano che per allora ancora gli 
Americani natali più anziani stavano adottando il vestito 
occidentale. Parecchie fotografie in questo soggetto provengono 
dalle spedizioni government-sponsored di indagine lanciate nel 1870s 
iniziale per progettare le terre occidentali e le popolazioni 
autoctone. Queste spedizioni hanno coinciso con l'inizio 
dell'antropologia come scienza. In 1879, il congresso ha creato 
l'ufficio dell'etnologia per studiare e documentare le popolazioni 
autoctone e le loro colture. Sono inclusi qui tre ritratti 
presi per questi studi diretti ethnographic e una pittura della seduta
Bull, il capo famoso della medicina del Sioux. Americani natali 
clashed violentemente e ripetutamente con gli Americani europei 
bianchi che entrano nel loro territorio. I bianchi hanno 
desiderato spingere gli indiani fuori della loro terra e sulle 
prenotazioni, ma gli indiani hanno rifiutato spesso di andare. 
Il ramo di Lakota della tribù del Sioux era un tale gruppo ed 
in 1875 il loro rifiuto ha provocato la guerra di Lakota. Una 
battaglia famosa nella guerra di Lakota ha avvenuto al fiume del 
bighorn piccolo nel Montana in 1876; là, le forze degli Stati 
Uniti sotto il General George Armstrong Custer hanno attacato il 
cavallo pazzesco e le centinaia di Lakota e dei guerrieri nordici de 
Cheyenne. Nella battaglia, che è venuto essere conosciuta come 
ultimo basamento del Custer, gli uomini del Custer sono stati 
oltrepassati quattro - uno ed ogni uomo bianco è stato ucciso. 
Un'illustrazione e una litografia di colore mostrano le versioni
di questa battaglia. Un certo corvo ha servito da esploratori 
per il General Custer nel settimo cavalry. Una vista 
stereoscopica mostra "Curley"? l'unico combattimento indiano del 
superstite dal lato del Custer? l'uso del bufalo ricoprono e 
sedersi da ambo i lati di un cavallo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αρχίζοντας στο 1700s, οι Ισπανοί έχτισαν τις 
αποστολές Καλιφόρνιας για να κάνουν την επαφή με εγγενείς 
Αμερικανούς με την ελπίδα της μετατροπής τους στο χριστιανισμό. 
Το ένα που χρωματίζει από έναν ρωσικό καλλιτέχνη 
απεικονίζει μια ομάδα εγγενών Αμερικανών που χορεύουν μπροστά 
από την αποστολή Dolores στο Σαν Φρανσίσκο  μια πιό 
πρόσφατη φωτογραφία εμφανίζει μια ομάδα καλογριών με τα 
εξευρωπαϊσμένα εγγενή παιδιά μπροστά από την αποστολή Pala 
σε νότια Καλιφόρνια. Δεδομένου ότι ευρωπαϊκοί Αμερικανοί 
συνέχισαν να μεταναστεύουν δύση σε όλο το 1800s, μπήκαν στη 
σύγκρουση με τους εγγενείς λαούς που έζησαν εκεί. Εγγενείς
Αμερικανοί ωθήθηκαν όλο και περισσότερο από τα εδάφη τους και 
αναγκάστηκαν επάνω στις επιφυλάξεις. Συγχρόνως, τα λευκά 
πίεσαν εγγενείς Αμερικανούς που αφομοιώνουν. Τα εγγενή 
αμερικανικά παιδιά στάλησαν μακριά στα σχολεία τροφής με το 
στόχο τους και τους ?white τους τρόπους; Διάφορες 
φωτογραφίες απεικονίζουν τα νέα εγγενή αμερικανικά παιδιά που 
φορούν το δυτικό φόρεμα στις σχολικές τιμές των παραμέτρων 
τροφής. Μερικές από τις φωτογραφίες που λαμβάνονται στα 
μέσα της 1800s εμφανίζουν εγγενείς Αμερικανούς που φορούν τον 
παραδοσιακό ιματισμό (συμπεριλαμβανομένου "Jicarilla Apache 
γενναίο και η ινδιάνα, πρόσφατα," "ανιχνεύσεις Coyotero 
Apache," και "ομάδα Apaches, μπροστά από το φυτίλι-8-UPS 
[ SIC ]"). φωτογραφίες που λαμβάνονται στο γύρισμα του 
20ού αιώνα, όπως "Pummuke" και "Προϊστάμενος Chepah, η 
σύζυγός του, γιος, και η νύφη," δείχνει ότι έως τότε ακόμα 
παλαιότεροι εγγενείς Αμερικανοί υιοθετούσαν το δυτικό φόρεμα. 
Διάφορες φωτογραφίες σε αυτό το θέμα είναι από τις 
χρηματοδοτούμενες από την κυβέρνηση αποστολές ερευνών που 
προωθούνται στις αρχές 1870s στα δυτικά εδάφη διαγραμμάτων και
τους εγγενείς λαούς. Αυτές οι αποστολές συνέπεσαν με την 
αρχή της ανθρωπολογίας ως επιστήμη. Το 1879, το συνέδριο 
δημιούργησε το γραφείο της εθνολογίας στη μελέτη και τεκμηριώνει 
τους εγγενείς ανθρώπους και τους πολιτισμούς τους. 
Συμπεριλαμβανόμενα εδώ είναι τρία πορτρέτα που λαμβάνονται
για αυτές τις εθνογραφικές μελέτες πεδίων, και μια ζωγραφική της 
συνεδρίασης Bull, η διάσημη σιού ιατρική προϊστάμενος. 
Εγγενείς Αμερικανοί διαφώνησαν βίαια και επανειλημμένα με 
τους λευκούς ευρωπαϊκούς Αμερικανούς που κινούνται στο έδαφός 
τους. Τα λευκά θέλησαν να ωθήσουν τους Ινδούς από το 
έδαφός τους και επάνω στις επιφυλάξεις, αλλά οι Ινδοί αρνήθηκαν
συχνά να πάνε. Ο κλάδος Lakota της σιού φυλής ήταν μια 
τέτοια ομάδα, και το 1875 η άρνησή τους οδήγησε στον πόλεμο 
Lakota. Μια διάσημη μάχη στον πόλεμο Lakota 
πραγματοποιήθηκε στο μικρό ποταμό Bighorn στη Μοντάνα το 
1876  εκεί, οι αμερικανικές δυνάμεις κάτω από το 
στρατηγό George Armstrong Custer επιτέθηκαν στο τρελλό 
άλογο και τις εκατοντάδες Lakota και των βόρειων πολεμιστών του
Cheyenne. Στη μάχη, που ήρθε να μαθευτεί όπως Custer 
στέκεται στο τέλος, τα άτομα Custer ξεπεράστηκαν αριθμητικώς 
τέσσερα έως ένα και κάθε λευκό άτομο σκοτώθηκε. Ένα 
σχέδιο και lithograph χρώματος εμφανίζουν εκδόσεις αυτής της 
μάχης. Κάποιος κόρακας που εξυπηρετείται όπως για το 
στρατηγό Custer στο 7ο ιππικό. Μια στερεοσκοπική όψη 
εμφανίζει "Curley"; ο μόνος ινδικός επιζών που παλεύει 
από την πλευρά Custer; φθορά ενός παλτού βούβαλων και 
κάθισμα καβάλλα σε ένα άλογο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Comenzando en el 1700s, los españoles 
construyeron las misiones de California para hacer el contacto con los
americanos nativos en la esperanza de convertirlos al cristianismo. 
Una pintura de un artista ruso representa a grupo de americanos 
nativos que bailan delante de la misión Dolores en San Francisco; 
una fotografía más última muestra que un grupo de monjas con 
westernized a niños nativos delante de la misión de Pala en 
California meridional. A medida que los americanos europeos 
continuaron emigrando al oeste a través del 1800s, vinieron en 
conflicto con los indígenas que vivieron allí. Empujaron de 
sus pistas y fueron forzados a los americanos nativos cada vez más 
sobre reservaciones. En el mismo tiempo, los blancos ejercieron 
presión sobre a americanos nativos para asimilar. ¿Enviaron los
niños americanos nativos lejos a los colegios de internos con la meta
de socializarlos y de enseñarles maneras del?white? Varias 
fotografías representan a niños americanos nativos jóvenes que 
desgastan la alineada occidental en configuraciones del colegio de 
internos. Algunas de las fotografías tomadas en los americanos 
nativos de la demostración de mid-1800s que desgastan las 
fotografías tradicionales de la ropa ("Jicarilla incluyendo Apache 
valiente y Squaw, wedded últimamente," los "exploradores de Coyotero 
Apache," y "grupo de apaches, delante del Wick-8-ups [ sic ]"). 
tomadas al final del vigésimo siglo, tal como "Pummuke" y "principal 
Chepah, su esposa, hijo, y nuera," indican que para entonces iguale a 
más viejos americanos nativos adoptaban la alineada occidental. 
Varias fotografías en este asunto son de las expediciones 
government-sponsored de la encuesta lanzadas en el 1870s temprano para
planear pistas occidentales y a indígenas. Estas expediciones 
coincidieron con el principio de la antropología como ciencia. 
En 1879, el congreso creó la oficina de la etnología para 
estudiar y para documentar los indígenas y sus culturas. Se 
incluyen aquí tres retratos tomados para estos estudios en el campo 
etnográficos, y una pintura de la sentada Bull, el jefe famoso de la 
medicina de Sioux. Americanos nativos clashed violentamente y en
varias ocasiones con los americanos europeos blancos que se mueven en 
su territorio. Los blancos desearon empujar a los indios de su 
pista y sobre reservaciones, pero los indios rechazaron a menudo ir. 
La ramificación de Lakota de la tribu de Sioux era un tal 
grupo, y en 1875 su denegación dio lugar a la guerra de Lakota. 
Una batalla famosa en la guerra de Lakota ocurrió en el río 
del pequeño carnero con grandes cuernos en Montana en 1876; 
allí, las fuerzas de los E.E.U.U. bajo general George Armstrong
Custer atacaron el caballo loco y centenares de Lakota y de los 
guerreros norteños de Cheyenne. En la batalla, que vino ser 
conocida como soporte pasado de Custer, excedieron en número a los 
hombres de Custer cuatro a uno y mataron a cada hombre blanco. 
Un gráfico y una litografía del color muestran versiones de 
esta batalla. Algún cuervo sirvió como exploradores para 
general Custer en la 7ma caballería. ¿Una visión 
estereoscópica muestra "Curley"? ¿el único sobreviviente indio
que lucha en la cara de Custer? desgastar un búfalo cubren y el
sentarse a horcajadas en un caballo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085239</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104234</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/native-american-assimilation</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
