<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105359</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105359</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087302</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"A German Beer Garden on Sunday Evening."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ein deutscher Bier-Garten am Sonntag Abend."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"un jardin allemand de bière dimanche soirée."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"um jardim alemão da cerveja na noite de 
domingo."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"un giardino tedesco della birra sulla sera di 
domenica."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ένας γερμανικός κήπος μπύρας την Κυριακή βράδυ."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"un jardín alemán de la cerveza el la tarde de 
domingo."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Between 1820 and 1860, 1,500,000 immigrants arrived in America from Germany. Many of the new arrivals who settled in cities such as New York worked as shopkeepers and skilled tradesmen, although many more worked as employees in construction, brewing, and manufacturing. Although German immigrants did not mix politics and liquor, reformers were disconcerted by the atmosphere of their social establishments. Unlike the bars in Irish neighborhoods, the beer gardens catered to whole families. As this 1859 engraving shows, public drinking was only one attraction at a beer garden; but to reformers the presence of women and children suggested immorality.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zwischen 1820 und 1860 kamen 1.500.000 Immigranten in 
Amerika aus Deutschland an. Viele der neuen Ankünfte, die in 
den Städte wie New York vereinbarten, arbeiteten als Ladenbesitzer 
und erfahrene Händler, obgleich viel mehr als Angestellte im 
Aufbau arbeiteten und brauten, und die Produktion. Obgleich 
deutsche Immigranten nicht Politik und Alkohol mischten, wurden 
Reformer durch die Atmosphäre ihrer Sozialeinrichtungen 
beunruhigt. Anders als die Stäbe in den irischen 
Nachbarschaften, boten die Biergärten vollständigen Familien. 
Da dieser Stich 1859 darstellt, Öffentlichkeit war das Trinken 
nur eine Anziehung an einem Biergarten; aber zu den 
Reformern schlug die Anwesenheit der Frauen und der Kinder 
Unmoral vor.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Entre 1820 et 1860, 1.500.000 immigrés sont arrivés en 
Amérique d'Allemagne. Plusieurs des nouvelles arrivées qui ont
arrangé dans les villes telles que New York ont fonctionné comme 
commerçants et marchands habiles, bien que beaucoup plus aient 
fonctionné comme employés dans la construction, brassant, et la 
fabrication. Bien que les immigrés allemands n'aient pas 
mélangé la politique et la boisson alcoolisée, des réformateurs ont
été déconcertés par l'atmosphère de leurs établissements 
sociaux. À la différence des barres dans les voisinages 
irlandais, les jardins de bière ont approvisionné aux familles 
entières. Car cette gravure 1859 montre, le boire de public 
était seulement une attraction à un jardin de bière ; mais 
aux réformateurs la présence des femmes et des enfants a suggéré 
l'immoralité.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Entre 1820 e 1860, 1.500.000 immigrants chegaram em 
América de Germany. Muitas das chegadas novas que se 
estabeleciram nas cidades tais como New York trabalharam como os 
shopkeepers e os tradesmen hábeis, embora muito mais trabalhassem 
como empregados na construção, brewing, e manufaturar. Embora 
os immigrants alemães não misturassem a política e o licor, os 
reformers disconcerted pela atmosfera de seus estabelecimentos 
sociais. Ao contrário das barras em vizinhanças irish, os 
jardins da cerveja catered às famílias inteiras. Porque este 
engraving 1859 mostra, beber do público era somente uma atração em 
um jardim da cerveja; mas aos reformers a presença das mulheres
e das crianças sugeriu o immorality.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fra 1820 e 1860, 1.500.000 immigrante è arrivato in 
America dalla Germania. Molti di nuovi arrivi che si sono 
depositati in città quale New York hanno funzionato come i 
commercianti ed in commercianti esperti, anche se molto hanno 
funzionato come impiegati nella costruzione, fermentanti e produrre. 
Anche se gli immigranti tedeschi non hanno mescolato la politica
ed il liquore, i reformers disconcerted dall'atmosfera delle loro 
imprese sociali. Diverso delle barre in vicinanze irlandesi, i 
giardini della birra hanno approvvigionato alle famiglie intere. 
Poichè questa incisione 1859 mostra, bere del pubblico era 
soltanto un'attrazione ad un giardino della birra; ma ai 
reformers la presenza delle donne e dei bambini ha suggerito il 
immorality.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μεταξύ 1820 και 1860, 1.500.000 μετανάστες 
έφθασαν στην Αμερική από τη Γερμανία. Πολλές από τις νέες
αφίξεις που εγκατέστησαν στις πόλεις όπως η Νέα Υόρκη 
ελειτούργησαν ως καταστηματάρχες και ειδικευμένοι έμποροι, αν και 
πολύ περισσότεροι ελειτούργησαν ως υπάλληλοι στην κατασκευή, την 
παρασκευή, και την κατασκευή. Αν και οι γερμανικοί 
μετανάστες δεν ανάμιξαν την πολιτική και το ποτό, οι 
μεταρρυθμιστές ανατρέφθηκαν από την ατμόσφαιρα των κοινωνικών 
ιδρυμάτων τους. Αντίθετα από τις ράβδους στις ιρλανδικές 
γειτονιές, οι κήποι μπύρας τροφοδότησαν σε ολόκληρες τις 
οικογένειες. Όπως αυτά τα 1859 που χαράσσουν εμφανίζουν,
η δημόσια κατανάλωση ήταν μόνο μια έλξη σε έναν κήπο μπύρας  
αλλά στους μεταρρυθμιστές η παρουσία γυναικών και παιδιών 
πρότεινε την ανηθικότητα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Entre 1820 y 1860, 1.500.000 inmigrantes llegaron en 
América de Alemania. Muchas de las nuevas llegadas que 
colocaron en ciudades tales como Nueva York trabajaron como los 
comerciantes y comerciantes expertos, aunque muchos más trabajaron 
como empleados en la construcción, elaborando cerveza, y la 
fabricación. Aunque los inmigrantes alemanes no mezclaron 
política y el licor, los reformadores disconcerted por la atmósfera 
de sus establecimientos sociales. Desemejante de las barras en 
vecindades irlandesas, los jardines de la cerveza abastecieron a las 
familias enteras. Pues este grabado 1859 muestra, el beber del 
público era solamente una atracción en un jardín de la cerveza; 
pero a los reformadores la presencia de mujeres y de niños 
sugirió inmoralidad.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087302</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105359</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-german-beer-garden-on-sunday-evening</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
