<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108597</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108597</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203795</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Mark Twain at Mono Lake: Chapters 38 and 39 of Mark Twain's Roughing It</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kennzeichnen Sie Twain am Monosee: Kapitel 
38 und 39 von Roughing Markierung Twains es</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Marquez Twain au lac mono : Chapitres 38 et 
39 du dégrossissage de Twain de marque il</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Marque Twain no lago mono: Capítulos 38 e 
39 do roughing de Twain da marca ele</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Contrassegni Twain nel mono lago: Capitoli 
38 e 39 di sgrossatura del Twain del contrassegno esso</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θ*Μαρκ Twain στη μονο λίμνη: Κεφάλαια 38 και
39 του χοντροδουλέματος Mark Twain αυτό</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Marque Twain en el mono lago: Capítulos 38 
y 39 de desbaste de Twain de la marca él</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This book excerpt is from Roughing It, Mark Twain's humorous account of his western travels in the late 1860's. The excerpt includes Chapters 38 and 39, which account for Twain's visit to Mono Lake. While the text contains exaggerations (often deliberate) and some factual errors, it is an enjoyable historical reference. This Mono Basin Clearinghouse site provides a menu of additional Mono Lake related webpages including reports and studies database, reports and studies online, raw data, field notes, photos, legal resources, current ongoing research, chronologies and timelines, geographic information systems, and links.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Buchexcerpt ist vom Roughing es, Markierung
Twains humorvolles Konto von seinen westlichen Spielräumen im späten
1860's. Das Excerpt schließt Kapitel 38 und 39 ein, die Besuch 
Twains zum Monosee erklären. Während der Text Übertreibungen 
(überlegen Sie häufig) und einige auf Tatsachen beruhende Fehler 
enthält, es eine erfreuliche historische Referenz ist. Diese 
Monobassin-Verrechnungszentralesite liefert ein Menü der 
zusätzlicher Monosee in Verbindung gestandenen Webseiten 
einschließlich Reports und studiert die Datenbank, Reports und 
Studien, die, rohe Daten Online sind, fängt Anmerkungen, 
Fotos, zugelassene Betriebsmittel, aktuelle fortwährende Forschung, 
Chronologien und timelines, geographische Informationssysteme und 
Links auf.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cet extrait de livre est de dégrossissage lui, le
compte plein d'humour de Twain de marque de ses voyages occidentaux 
vers la fin de 1860's. L'extrait inclut les chapitres 38 et 39, 
qui expliquent la visite de Twain au lac mono. Tandis que le 
texte contient des exagérations (délibérez souvent) et quelques 
erreurs effectives, c'est une référence historique agréable. 
Ce site mono de chambre de compensation de bassin fournit un 
menu des pages Web associées par lac mono supplémentaire 
comprenant des états et étudie la base de données, les états et 
les études en ligne, les données brutes, les notes de zone, les 
photos, les ressources légales, la recherche continue actuelle, les 
chronologies et les chronologies, les systèmes d'information 
géographiques, et les liens.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este excerpt do livro é do roughing ele, cliente 
humorous de Twain da marca de seus cursos ocidentais no 1860's 
atrasado. O excerpt inclui os capítulos 38 e 39, que esclarecem
a visita de Twain ao lago mono. Quando o texto contiver 
exaggerations (delibere frequentemente) e alguns erros factual, é uma
referência histórica agradável. Este local mono do 
clearinghouse da bacia fornece um menu lago mono adicional de Web 
pages relacionados including relatórios e estuda a base de dados, os 
relatórios e os estudos em linha, dados crus, notas do campo, fotos, 
recursos legais, pesquisa ongoing atual, chronologies e timelines, 
sistemas de informação geográficos, e ligações.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo brano del libro proviene da sgrossatura 
esso, cliente divertente del Twain del contrassegno delle sue corse 
occidentali verso la fine di 1860's. Il brano include i capitoli
38 e 39, che rappresentano la chiamata del Twain al mono lago. 
Mentre il testo contiene le esagerazioni (rifletta spesso) ed 
alcuni errori effettivi, è un riferimento storico divertente. 
Questo mono luogo della stanza di compensazione del bacino 
fornisce un menu mono dei Web pagi riferiti lago supplementare 
compreso i rapporti e studia la base di dati, rapporti e studi in 
linea, dati grezzi, note del campo, foto, risorse legali, ricerca 
continua corrente, le cronologie e timelines, sistemi d'informazione 
geografici e collegamenti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το απόσπασμα βιβλίων είναι από το χοντροδούλεμα
αυτό, χιουμοριστικός απολογισμός Mark Twain των δυτικών 
ταξιδιών του προς το τέλος 1860's. Το απόσπασμα 
περιλαμβάνει τα κεφάλαια 38 και 39, τα οποία αποτελούν την 
επίσκεψη Twain στη μονο λίμνη. Ενώ το κείμενο περιέχει 
τις υπερβολές (συχνά σκόπιμες) και μερικά πραγματικά σφάλματα, 
είναι μια ευχάριστη ιστορική αναφορά. Αυτή η μονο περιοχή 
γραφείων συμψηφισμού λεκανών παρέχει έναν κατάλογο επιλογής των
πρόσθετων μονο σχετικών με τη λίμνη webpages 
συμπεριλαμβανομένων των εκθέσεων και μελετά τη βάση δεδομένων, 
τις εκθέσεις και τα σε απευθείας σύνδεση, ακατέργαστα στοιχεία 
μελετών, τις σημειώσεις πεδίων, τις φωτογραφίες, τα νομικά 
στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς, την παρούσα τρέχουσα έρευνα, τις 
χρονολογίες και τις υποδείξεις ως προς το χρόνο, τα γεωγραφικά 
συστήματα πληροφοριών, και τις συνδέσεις.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este extracto del libro es de desbaste él, cuenta
chistosa de Twain de la marca de sus recorridos occidentales en el 
último 1860's. El extracto incluye los capítulos 38 y 39, que 
explican la visita de Twain al mono lago. Mientras que el texto 
contiene exageraciones (delibere a menudo) y algunos errores 
efectivos, es una referencia histórica agradable. Este mono 
sitio de la cámara de compensación del lavabo proporciona a un menú
mono de Web pages relacionados lago adicional incluyendo informes y 
estudia la base de datos, los informes y los estudios en línea, las 
informaciones en bruto, las notas del campo, las fotos, los recursos 
legales, investigación en curso actual, las cronologías y los 
timelines, los sistemas de información geográficos, y las 
conexiones.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MARK TWAIN
FN:MARK TWAIN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MONO BASIN CLEARINGHOUSE
FN:MONO BASIN CLEARINGHOUSE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203795</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108597</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/mark-twain-at-mono-lake-chapters-38-and-39-of-mark-twains-roughing-it</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
