<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104709</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104709</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086841</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Sometime Soon . . . the Free Nations Must Make Their Choice": A Foreign Correspondent Analyzes U.S. Cold War Failures</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Einmal Bald. . . die freien 
Nationen müssen ihre Wahl treffen ": Ein Auslandskorrespondent 
Analysiert VEREINIGTE STAATEN Kalter Krieg-Ausfälle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Autrefois Bientôt. . . les 
nations libres doivent faire leur choix ": Un Correspondant 
Étranger Analyse des Pannes de Guerre Froide des ETATS-UNIS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Sometime Logo. . . as nações 
livres devem fazer sua escolha ": Um Correspondente Extrangeiro 
Analisa Falhas Da Guerra Fria de ESTADOS UNIDOS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Un momento Presto. . . le 
nazioni libere devono fare la loro scelta ": Un Corrispondente 
Straniero Analizza I Guasti Di Guerra Fredda degli STATI UNITI</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Κάποτε σύντομα. .. τα ελεύθερα έθνη 
πρέπει να κάνουν την επιλογή τους ": Ένας ξένος 
ανταποκριτής αναλύει τις αποτυχίες ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΥ ψυχρού πολέμου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Alguna vez Pronto. . . las 
naciones libres deben hacer su opción ": Un Correspondiente No 
nativo Analiza Incidentes De la Guerra Fría de ESTADOS UNIDOS</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Truman Administration's Cold War policy of containment advocated confronting the Soviet Union, in the words of diplomat George F. Kennan, "with unalterable counterforce at every point where they show signs of encroaching upon the interests of a peaceful and stable world." In 1952, during the Korean War stalemate, John Foster Dulles authored the Republican Party platform's foreign policy plank condemning containment. Dulles instead supported the "liberation" of countries within the communist sphere using any means "short of war." When Republican nominee General Dwight D. Eisenhower won the presidency and Dulles became his secretary of state, however, containment remained the official U.S. policy. In 1954, as France was losing its battle to regain control of its prewar colony of Indochina--a war funded substantially with U.S. dollars--Congressional leaders refused to support an Eisenhower-Dulles resolution to intervene militarily. In the following opinion piece published just after the French defeat, correspondent Edgar Ansel Mowrer, who won the Pulitzer Prize in 1933 for reporting on the rise of Hitler, offered a critique of containment and an analysis of U.S. options for fighting the Cold War. A great admirer of Dulles, Mowrer believed hopes for peaceful coexistence to be "the opium of the West."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die der Truman Politik des kalten Krieges Leitung 
der Eindämmung befürwortete das Konfrontieren des 
Sowjet-Anschlußes, in den Wörtern des Diplomaten George F. Kennan, 
"mit unalterable counterforce an jedem Punkt, in dem sie zeigen 
Zeichen des Eingreifens nach den Interessen einer ruhigen und 
beständigen Welt." 1952 während des Stillstands des 
koreanischen Krieges, schrieb John Pflegedulles die der 
Republikanische Parteiverurteilende Eindämmung der Planke der fremden Politik 
plattform. Dulles unterstützte anstatt die "Befreiung" der 
Länder innerhalb des kommunistischen Bereichs mit allen möglichen 
Mitteln ", die kurz sind vom Krieg." Als republikanischer 
Kandidat General Dwight D. Eisenhower gewann, standen der Vorsitz und 
das Dulles seinem Staatssekretär, jedoch blieb Eindämmung die 
amtliche VEREINIGTE STAATEN Politik. 1954 während Frankreich 
seine Schlacht verlor, um Steuerung seiner Vorkriegskolonie von 
Indochina -- ein Krieg im wesentlichen finanziert mit VEREINIGTE 
STAATEN Dollar wiederzugewinnen -- die Kongreßführer, die abgelehnt 
wurden, um eine Eisenhower-Dulles Zerlegung zu unterstützen, 
militärisch einzugreifen. In folgender Meinung veröffentlichte
das Stück gleich nach der französischen Niederlage, entsprechendes 
Edgar Ansel Mowrer, das den Pulitzer Preis 1933 für den Bericht über
den Anstieg von Hitler gewann, anbot eine Kritik der Eindämmung und 
eine Analyse der VEREINIGTE STAATEN Optionen für das Kämpfen des 
kalten Krieges. Ein großer Bewunderer von Dulles, Mowrer 
glaubte Hoffnungen, damit ruhige Koexistenz ist "das Opium des 
Westens."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La politique de la guerre froide de la gestion de 
Truman de la retenue a préconisé confronter Union Soviétique, dans les 
mots du diplomate George F. Kennan, "avec la contre-force 
immuable à chaque point où elles montrent des signes de 
l'empiétement sur les intérêts d'un monde paisible et stable." 
En 1952, pendant l'impasse de guerre coréenne, John Dulles 
adoptif a écrit la retenue de condamnation de planche de la politique
étrangère de la plateforme de partie républicaine. Dulles a 
à la place supporté la "libération" des pays dans la sphère 
communiste en utilisant tous les moyens "courts de la guerre." 
Quand le Général républicain Dwight D. Eisenhower de 
dénommé a gagné la présidence et le Dulles sont allés bien à son
secrétaire d'état, cependant, la retenue est demeurée la politique 
officielle des ETATS-UNIS. En 1954, pendant que la France 
détruisait sa bataille pour regagner la commande de sa colonie 
d'avant-guerre de l'Indochine -- une guerre placée sensiblement avec 
des dollars des ETATS-UNIS -- les amorces congressionnelles refusées 
pour supporter une résolution d'Eisenhower-Dulles d'intervenir 
militairement. Dans l'opinion suivante le morceau a édité 
juste aprés la défaite française, Edgar correspondant Ansel Mowrer,
qui a gagné le prix de Pulitzer en 1933 pour rendre compte de 
l'élévation de Hitler, a offert une critique de retenue et une 
analyse des options des ETATS-UNIS pour combattre la guerre froide. 
Un grand admirateur de Dulles, Mowrer a cru des espoirs pour que
la coexistence paisible soit "l'opium de l'ouest."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A política da guerra fria da administração de 
Truman do containment advogou confrontar a Soviete-união, nas 
palavras do diplomata George F. Kennan, "com counterforce unalterable 
em cada ponto onde mostram sinais de encroaching em cima dos 
interesses de um mundo calmo e estável." Em 1952, durante o 
empate da guerra korean, John Dulles foster foi o autor do containment
condemning da prancha da política extrangeira da plataforma do 
partido republicano. Dulles suportou preferivelmente o 
"liberation" dos países dentro da esfera comunista usando todos os 
meios "curtos da guerra." Quando o general republicano Dwight D.
Eisenhower do nominee ganhou o presidency e o Dulles assentaram bem em
sua secretária de estado, entretanto, o containment remanesceu a 
política oficial de ESTADOS UNIDOS. Em 1954, enquanto France 
perdia sua batalha para regain o controle de sua colônia prewar de 
Indochina -- uma guerra financiada substancialmente com os dólares de
ESTADOS UNIDOS -- os líderes congressionais recusados suportar uma 
definição de Eisenhower-Dulles intervir militar. Em seguinte 
opinião a parte publicou imediatamente depois da derrota francesa, 
Edgar correspondente Ansel Mowrer, que ganhou o prêmio de Pulitzer em
1933 para relatar na ascensão de Hitler, ofereceu uma crítica do 
containment e uma análise de opções de ESTADOS UNIDOS para lutar a 
guerra fria. Um admirador grande de Dulles, Mowrer acreditou 
esperanças para que o coexistence calmo seja "o opium do oeste."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La politica di guerra fredda della gestione di 
Truman del contenimento ha sostenuto il confronto dell'Soviet-unione, 
nelle parole del diplomatico George F. Kennan, "con counterforce 
unalterable ad ogni punto in cui mostrano i segni dell'invasione sugli
interessi di un mondo pacifico e stabile." In 1952, durante 
l'impasse di guerra coreana, John Dulles adottivo ha creato il 
contenimento di condanna della piattaforma del partito della plancia 
Repubblicana di politica straniera. Dulles preferibilmente ha 
sostenuto "la liberazione" dei paesi all'interno della sfera comunista
usando tutti i mezzi "corti della guerra." Quando il General 
Repubblicano Dwight D. Eisenhower del nominee ha vinto la presidenza ed 
il Dulles hanno stato bene alla sua segretaria di dichiarano, 
tuttavia, il contenimento è rimasto la politica ufficiale degli STATI
UNITI. In 1954, mentre la Francia stava perdendo la relativa 
battaglia per riguadagnare il controllo della relativa colonia 
prebellica del Indochina -- una guerra costituita un fondo per 
sostanzialmente con i dollari degli STATI UNITI -- capi 
congressuali rifiutati per sostenere una risoluzione di 
Eisenhower-Dulles intervenire militarmente. Nella seguente 
opinione la parte ha pubblicato subito dopo la sconfitta francese, 
Edgar corrispondente Ansel Mowrer, che ha vinto il premio di Pulitzer 
in 1933 per la segnalazione sull'aumento di Hitler, ha offerto una 
valutazione del contenimento e un'analisi delle opzioni degli STATI 
UNITI per combattimento la guerra fredda. Un ammiratore grande di 
Dulles, Mowrer ha creduto le speranze affinchè la coesistenza 
pacifica sia "l'oppio dell'ovest."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η πολιτική ψυχρού πολέμου της κυβέρνησης Truman του
περιεχομένου που υποστηρίζεται αντιμετώπιση της Σοβιετικής 
Ένωσης, στις λέξεις του διπλωμάτη George F. Kennan, "με 
αναλλοίωτο counterforce σε κάθε σημείο όπου εμφανίζουν 
σημάδια της καταπάτησης επάνω στα ενδιαφέροντα ενός ειρηνικού 
και σταθερού κόσμου." Το 1952, κατά τη διάρκεια του 
κορεατικού πολεμικού αδιεξόδου, John Foster Dulles το να 
καταδικάσει σανίδων εξωτερικής πολιτικής της δημοκρατικής 
πλατφόρμας συμβαλλόμενου μέρους περιεχόμενο. Θ*Δuλλες 
υποστήριξε αντ' αυτού τη "απελευθέρωση" των χωρών μέσα στην 
κομμουνιστική σφαίρα χρησιμοποιώντας οποιαδήποτε μέσα "απότομα 
του πολέμου." Όταν ο δημοκρατικός υποψήφιος General 
Dwight Δ. Eisenhower κέρδισε την προεδρία και Dulles έγινε
ο γραμματέας κράτους του, εντούτοις, το περιεχόμενο παρέμεινε η 
επίσημη ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ πολιτική. Το 1954, δεδομένου ότι η 
Γαλλία έχανε τη μάχη της για να επανακτήσει τον έλεγχο της 
προπολεμικής αποικίας Indochina της -- ένας πόλεμος που 
χρηματοδοτείται ουσιαστικά με τα ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΑ δολάρια -- οι του 
Κογκρέσου ηγέτες αρνήθηκαν να υποστηρίξουν ένα ψήφισμα 
Eisenhower-$l*Dulles για να επεμβουν στρατιωτικά. Στο 
ακόλουθο κομμάτι άποψης που δημοσιεύθηκε αμέσως μετά από τη 
γαλλική ήττα, ο αντίστοιχος Edgar Ansel Mowrer, που 
κέρδισε το βραβείο Pulitzer το 1933 για την υποβολή έκθεσης 
σχετικά με την άνοδο hitler, πρόσφερε μια κριτική του 
περιεχομένου και μια ανάλυση των ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΩΝ προαιρετικών 
δυνατοτήτων για τον ψυχρό πόλεμο. Ένας μεγάλος θαυμαστής 
Dulles, Mowrer που θεωρείται ελπίζει για την ειρηνική 
συνύπαρξη να είναι "το όπιο της δύσης."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La política de la guerra fría de la 
administración de Truman de la contención abogó el enfrentamiento 
de la Soviet-unio'n, en las palabras del diplomata George F. Kennan, 
"con el counterforce unalterable en cada punta donde muestran muestras
de la usurpación sobre los intereses de un mundo pacífico y 
estable." En 1952, durante el estancamiento de la guerra 
coreana, Juan Dulles foster fue autor de la contención de 
condenación del tablón de la política no nativa de la plataforma 
del partido republicano. Dulles en lugar de otro utilizó la 
"liberación" de países dentro de la esfera comunista usando 
cualquier medio "corto de guerra." Cuando general republicano 
Dwight D. Eisenhower del candidato ganó la presidencia y el Dulles 
sintieron bien a su secretaria del estado, sin embargo, la contención
seguía siendo la política oficial de ESTADOS UNIDOS. En 1954, 
mientras que Francia perdía su batalla para recuperar control de su 
colonia de la preguerra de Indochina -- una guerra financiada 
substancialmente con los dólares de ESTADOS UNIDOS -- los arranques 
de cinta del congreso rechazados para utilizar una resolución de 
Eisenhower-Dulles de intervenir militar. En la opinión 
siguiente el pedazo publicó enseguida después de la derrota 
francesa, Edgar correspondiente Ansel Mowrer, que ganó el premio de 
Pulitzer en 1933 para señalar sobre la subida de Hitler, ofreció una
crítica de la contención y un análisis de las opciones de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS para luchar la guerra fría. Un gran admirador de Dulles,
Mowrer creyó las esperanzas para que la coexistencia pacífica sea 
"el opio del oeste."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086841</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104709</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/sometime-soon-the-free-nations-must-make-their-choice-a-foreign-correspondent-analyzes-u-s-cold-war-failures</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
