<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105639</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105639</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974030</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Selenium: A Window on Wetlands Activity</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Selen: Ein Fenster auf 
Sumpfgebiet-Aktivität</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sélénium : Une fenêtre sur l'activité de
Marécages</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Selênio: Uma janela na atividade de 
Wetlands</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Selenio: Una finestra su attività di 
Wetlands</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σελήνιο: Ένα παράθυρο στη δραστηριότητα 
υγρότοπων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Selenio: Una ventana en la actividad de 
Wetlands</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Wetlands are natural recycling plants, but they are often endangered by the waste people put there. Understanding the complex processes that enable a marsh to clean water, recycle nutrients, and immobilize toxic elements will help us protect these diminishing resources. Bring the scientific research done at the the Advanced Light Source into your classroom using this complete teaching module.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sumpfgebiete sind natürliche 
Abfallverwertungsanlage, aber sie werden häufig von den 
überschüssigen Leuten gefährdet, die dort gesetzt werden. Das
Verstehen der Komplexprozesse, die einen Sumpf aktivieren, Wasser zu 
säubern, Nährstoffe aufzubereiten und giftige Elemente 
stillzustellen, hilft uns, diese vermindernden Betriebsmittel zu 
schützen. Holen Sie die wissenschaftliche Forschung, die an der
hochentwickelten Lichtquelle in Ihr Klassenzimmer mit diesem 
kompletten unterrichtenden Modul erfolgt ist.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les marécages sont les usines de réutilisation
normales, mais ils sont souvent mis en danger par les personnes de 
rebut mises là. L'arrangement les processus de complexe qui 
permettent à un marais de nettoyer l'eau, de réutiliser des 
aliments, et d'immobiliser les éléments toxiques nous aidera à 
protéger ces ressources diminuantes. Apportez la recherche 
scientifique faite l'à la source lumineuse avançée dans votre salle
de classe à l'aide de ce module d'enseignement complet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Wetlands é plantas recycling naturais, mas são 
postos em perigo frequentemente pelos povos waste postos lá. 
Compreender os processos do complexo que permitem um pântano de
limpar a água, recycle nutrientes, e de immobilize elementos tóxicos
ajudar-nos-á proteger estes recursos diminuindo. Traga a 
pesquisa científica feita o na fonte clara avançada em sua sala de 
aula usando este módulo ensinando completo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Wetlands è piante di riciclaggio naturali, ma 
sono messe spesso dalla gente residua messa là. Capire i 
processi del complesso che permettono ad una palude di pulire l'acqua,
riciclare le sostanze nutrienti e di immobilizzare gli elementi 
tossici li aiuterà a proteggere queste risorse diminuenti. 
Porti la ricerca scientifica fatta alla fonte di luce avanzata 
nella vostra aula per mezzo di questo modulo d'istruzione completo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι υγρότοποι είναι φυσικές εγκαταστάσεις ανακύκλωσης,
αλλά διακυβεύονται συχνά από τους ανθρώπους αποβλήτων που 
τίθενται εκεί. Η κατανόηση των σύνθετων διαδικασιών που 
επιτρέπουν σε ένα έλος για να καθαρίσουν το ύδωρ, να 
ανακυκλώσουν τις θρεπτικές ουσίες, και να ακινητοποιήσουν τα 
τοξικά στοιχεία θα μας βοηθήσει να προστατεύσουμε αυτά τα 
μικραίνοντας στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς. Φέρτε την επιστημονική 
έρευνα που γίνεται στην προηγμένη πηγή φωτός στην τάξη σας 
χρησιμοποιώντας αυτήν την πλήρη ενότητα διδασκαλίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Wetlands es plantas de reciclaje naturales, pero 
son puestas en peligro a menudo por la gente inútil puesta allí. 
Entender los procesos del complejo que permiten a un pantano 
limpiar el agua, reciclar los alimentos, e inmovilizar elementos 
tóxicos nos ayudará a proteger estos recursos que disminuyen. 
Traiga la investigación científica hecha en el fuente de luz 
avanzada en su sala de clase usando este módulo de enseñanza 
completo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974030</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105639</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/selenium-a-window-on-wetlands-activity</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
