<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107511</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107511</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086723</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Penny pictures.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Pennyabbildungen.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Images de penny.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Retratos da moeda de um centavo.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Immagini del penny.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εικόνες πενών.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cuadros del penique.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The  New York Herald , more than any other of the penny newspapers, published topical pictures. Most of the time, the pictures were simple maps or crude portraits of people in the news. Occasionally, special events received greater pictorial coverage. But when the  Herald  published five detailed pictures on its cover showing New York's 1845 funeral procession honoring Andrew Jacksonthe first full-page cover devoted to pictures ever to appear in a U.S. daily newspaperrival newspapers charged that the same engravings had been used to illustrate Queen Victoria's coronation, William Henry Harrison's funeral, and the celebration of the opening of the Croton reservoir. The  Herald  discontinued illustrating the news after 1850, leaving that task to the weekly illustrated press.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der New York Verkünder, mehr als irgendeine andere der 
Pennyzeitungen, veröffentlichte aktuelle Abbildungen. Die 
meisten der Zeit, die Abbildungen waren einfache Karten oder grobe 
Portraits der Leute in den Nachrichten. Gelegentlich empfingen 
spezielle Fälle grössere bildhafte Dichte. Aber, als der 
Verkünder fünf genau geschilderte Abbildungen auf seiner Abdeckung 
veröffentlichte, welche New York 1845 die Begräbnisprozession zeigt,
welche zuerst Andrew Jacksonthe die ganzseitige Abdeckung ehrt, die 
überhaupt Abbildungen gewidmet wurde, um VEREINIGTE STAATEN in den 
täglichen newspaperrival Zeitungen zu erscheinen aufgeladen dem, 
waren die gleichen Stiche benutzt worden, um Krönung der Königin 
Victorias, Begräbnis William Henry-Harrison und die Feier der 
Öffnung des Croton Vorratsbehälter zu veranschaulichen. Der 
Verkünder stellte ein, die Nachrichten nach 1850 zu veranschaulichen 
und verließ der wöchentlichen erläuterten Presse daß Aufgabe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le héraut de New York, plus que tout autre des journaux 
de penny, a édité les images topiques. La majeure partie du 
temps, les images était les cartes simples ou les verticales brutes 
des personnes dans les nouvelles. De temps en temps, les 
événements spéciaux ont reçu une plus grande assurance imagée. 
Mais quand le héraut a édité cinq images détaillées sur sa 
couverture montrant le cortège de l'enterrement de New York 1845 
honorant la couverture sur une page entière d'Andrew Jacksonthe 
d'abord consacrée aux images jamais pour apparaître en journaux 
newspaperrival quotidiens des ETATS-UNIS chargé cela les mêmes 
gravures avaient été employées pour illustrer le couronnement de la
Reine Victoria, l'enterrement de Harrison d'Henry de William, et la 
célébration de l'ouverture du réservoir de Croton. Le héraut
a cessé d'illustrer les nouvelles après 1850, partant qui 
chargent à la presse illustrée hebdomadaire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O herald de New York, mais do que qualquer outros dos 
jornais da moeda de um centavo, publicou retratos tópicos. Na 
maioria das vezes, os retratos eram mapas simples ou retratos crus dos
povos na notícia. Ocasionalmente, os eventos especiais 
receberam uma cobertura pictorial mais grande. Mas quando o 
herald publicou cinco retratos detalhados em sua tampa que mostra a 
procissão do funeral de New York 1845 que honra a tampa full-page de 
Andrew Jacksonthe primeiramente devotada aos retratos sempre para 
aparecer em jornais newspaperrival diários de uns ESTADOS UNIDOS 
carregado isso os mesmos engravings tinham sido usados ilustrar o 
coronation da rainha Victoria, o funeral de Harrison do Henry de 
William, e o celebration da abertura do reservatório de Croton. 
O herald interrompeu ilustrar a notícia após 1850, saindo que 
tarefa à imprensa ilustrada semanal.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il herald de New York, più di qualsiasi altro dei 
giornali del penny, ha pubblicato le immagini d'attualità. La 
maggior parte del tempo, le immagini erano programmi semplici o 
ritratti grezzi della gente nelle notizie. Occasionalmente, 
gli eventi speciali hanno ricevuto il riempimento pittorico più 
grande. Ma quando il herald ha pubblicato cinque immagini 
dettagliate sulla relativa copertura che mostra il procession di 
funerale de New York 1845 che honoring la copertura fuori testo del 
Andrew Jacksonthe in primo luogo dedicata mai alle immagini per 
comparire in giornali newspaperrival quotidiani degli STATI UNITI 
caricato quello le stesse incisioni erano state usate per illustrare 
il coronation della regina Victoria, il funerale del Harrison di henry
del William e la celebrazione dell'apertura del serbatoio di Croton. 
Il herald ha discontinuato illustrare le notizie dopo 1850, 
andando che operazione alla pressa illustrata settimanale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η Νέα Υόρκη ανακοινώνει, περισσότερο από οποιους 
δήποτε άλλους των εφημερίδων πενών, τις δημοσιευμένες επίκαιρες 
εικόνες. Τις περισσότερες φορές, οι εικόνες ήταν απλοί 
χάρτες ή ακατέργαστα πορτρέτα των ανθρώπων στις ειδήσεις. 
Περιστασιακά, τα ειδικά γεγονότα έλαβαν τη μεγαλύτερη 
εικονογραφική κάλυψη. Αλλά όταν Herald δημοσίευσε πέντε
λεπτομερείς εικόνες στην κάλυψή της που εμφανίζει σε 1845 της 
Νέας Υόρκης νεκρική πομπή που τιμά τον Andrew Jacksonthe 
πρώτα ολόκληρης σελίδας κάλυψη που αφιερώθηκε στις εικόνες για 
να εμφανιστούν πάντα στις καθημερινές newspaperrival εφημερίδες
ΗΠΑ χρέωσαν ότι οι ίδιες χαράξεις ήταν χρησιμοποιημένων για να 
επεξηγήσουν coronation βασίλισσας Victoria's, την κηδεία 
William Henry Harrison's, και τον εορτασμό του ανοίγματος 
της δεξαμενής Croton. Herald διέκοψε τις ειδήσεις 
μετά από 1850, αφήνοντας ότι στοιχειώδης εργασία στον 
εβδομαδιαία διευκρινισμένο Τύπο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El herald de Nueva York, más que cualquier otro de los 
periódicos del penique, publicó cuadros tópicos. La mayoría 
del tiempo, los cuadros era correspondencias simples o retratos crudos
de la gente en las noticias. De vez en cuando, los 
acontecimientos especiales recibieron mayor cobertura ilustrada. 
Pero cuando el herald publicó cinco cuadros detallados en su 
cubierta que mostraba a la procesión del entierro de Nueva York 1845 
que honraba la cubierta full-page de Andrew Jacksonthe primero 
dedicada a los cuadros siempre para aparecer en los periódicos 
newspaperrival diarios de ESTADOS UNIDOS cargado eso los mismos 
grabados habían sido utilizados para ilustrar la coronación de la 
reina Victoria, el entierro de Harrison del Henrio de Guillermo, y la 
celebración de la apertura del depósito de Croton. El herald 
continuó el ilustrar de las noticias después de 1850, yéndose que 
tarea a la prensa ilustrada semanal.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086723</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107511</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/penny-pictures</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
