<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108214</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108214</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206708</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">FSA/OWI Color Photographs Collection, 1939-1945</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">FSA/OWI Farbe Fotographien Ansammlung, 1939-1945</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Collection de Photographies de Couleur de FSA/OWI,
1939-1945</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Coleção Das Fotografias Da Cor de FSA/OWI, 
1939-1945</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Accumulazione Delle Fotografie Di Colore di 
FSA/OWI, 1939-1945</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Συλλογή φωτογραφιών χρώματος FSA/$l*OWI, 
1939-1945</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Colección De las Fotografías Del Color de 
FSA/OWI, 1939-1945</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">presents 1,600 color photos -- rural and small-town life, migrant labor, the Great Depression, railroads, military training, aircraft manufacturing, and mobilizing for World War II. A special feature, Collection Connections, provides ideas for learning about women in the war effort, New Deal work programs, farm workers, relief programs, and military training.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geschenke 1.600 Farbe Fotos -- landwirtschaftlich 
und Kleinstadtleben, Wander- Arbeit, der große Tiefstand, die 
Eisenbahnen, militärisches Training, Flugzeugherstellung und 
Mobilisieren für den Zweiten Weltkrieg. Ein spezielles Merkmal,
Ansammlung Anschlüsse, stellt Ideen für das Lernen über Frauen in 
den Kriegbemühung, Arbeit des neuen Abkommens Programmen, in den 
Landarbeitern, in den Entlastung Programmen und im militärischen 
Training zur Verfügung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">présents 1.600 photos de couleur -- rurales et 
vie de petit-ville, main-d'oeuvre saisonnière, la grande dépression,
les chemins de fer, formation militaire, fabrication d'avion, et 
mobilisation pour la deuxième guerre mondiale. Usage spécial, 
connexions de collection, fournit des idées pour se renseigner sur 
des femmes dans les programmes d'effort de guerre, de travail de 
nouvelle affaire, des ouvriers de ferme, des programmes de 
soulagement, et la formation militaire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">presentes 1.600 fotos da cor -- rurais e vida da 
pequeno-cidade, trabalho emigrante, o depression grande, as estradas 
de ferro, treinamento militar, manufacturing do avião, e mobilizing 
para a segunda guerra mundial. Uma característica especial, 
conexões da coleção, fornece idéias aprendendo sobre mulheres nos 
programas do esforço da guerra, de trabalho do negócio novo, em 
trabalhadores de fazenda, em programas do relevo, e no treinamento 
militar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">presenti 1.600 foto di colore -- rurale e vita 
della piccolo-città, lavoro migratore, la depressione grande, le
ferrovie, addestramento militare, manufacturing del velivolo e 
mobilitare per la seconda guerra mondiale. Una caratteristica 
speciale, collegamenti dell'accumulazione, fornisce le idee per 
imparare circa le donne nei programmi di sforzo di guerra, di lavoro 
di nuovo affare, nella manodopera agricola, nei programmi di rilievo e
nell'addestramento militare.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρουσιάζει 1.600 φωτογραφίες χρώματος -- αγροτική 
και μικρού χωριού ζωή, αποδημητική εργασία, η μεγάλη οικονομική
κρίση, σιδηρόδρομοι, στρατιωτική κατάρτιση, αεροσκάφη που 
κατασκευάζουν, και που κινητοποιούν για τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο ΙΙ. 
Ένα ειδικό χαρακτηριστικό γνώρισμα, συνδέσεις συλλογής, 
παρέχει τις ιδέες για την εκμάθηση για τις γυναίκες στην πολεμική
προσπάθεια, τα νέα προγράμματα εργασίας διαπραγμάτευσης, τους 
αγρότες, τα προγράμματα ανακούφισης, και τη στρατιωτική 
κατάρτιση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">presentes 1.600 fotos del color -- rurales y vida 
de la pequeño-ciudad, trabajo migratorio, la gran depresión, los 
ferrocarriles, entrenamiento militar, fabricación del avión, y 
movilización para la Segunda Guerra Mundial. Una 
característica especial, conexiones de la colección, proporciona a 
las ideas para aprender sobre mujeres en los programas del esfuerzo de
la guerra, de trabajo del nuevo reparto, los trabajadores de granja, 
los programas de la relevación, y el entrenamiento militar.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206708</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108214</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/fsa-owi-color-photographs-collection-1939-1945</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
