<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106828</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106828</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202537</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Shark Net: A Discipline Database</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Haifisch-Netz: Eine Disziplin-Datenbank</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Filet de Requin : Une Base de données De
Discipline</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A Rede Do Tubarão: Uma Base de dados Da 
Disciplina</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Rete Dello Squalo: Una Base di dati Di 
Disciplina</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το δίκτυο καρχαριών: Μια βάση δεδομένων 
πειθαρχίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Red Del Tiburón: Una Base de datos De la
Disciplina</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Shark Net is a database, set up by the teacher, where students keep records of all discipline interactions, of leaving the room, and of outstanding work. It includes fields for first name, last name, date, block, problem code, comments by students, time out, and time in. At two-week intervals students filter their records to calculate class participation grades. The class participation grade counts 10 percent of the total class grade. Students with the highest-class participation grades are rewarded with special activities such as ice cream parties, cookouts, field trips, etc. Students are required to filter and print the report for progress reports, report cards, and any time a parent/teacher or student/teacher conference is planned. This activity helps the teacher keep an accurate discipline record and to maintain discipline with minimal effort. It also helps the students understand how to use a database.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Haifisch-Netz ist eine Datenbank, aufgestellt 
vom Lehrer, in dem Kursteilnehmer Sätze aller Disziplininteraktionen,
des Verlassens des Raumes und der hervorragenden Arbeit halten. 
Es schließt auffängt für Vornamen, letzten Namen, 
Datum, Block, Problemcode, Kommentar durch Kursteilnehmer, Zeit heraus
und Zeit innen ein. In zweiwöchigen Abständen filtern 
Kursteilnehmer ihre Sätze, um Kategorie Teilnahmegrade zu errechnen. 
Der Kategorie Teilnahmegrad zählt 10 Prozent des 
Gesamtkategorie Grades. Kursteilnehmer mit den Hochkategorie 
Teilnahmegraden werden mit speziellen Aktivitäten wie 
EiscremeParteien, cookouts, auffangen Reisen, usw. 
belohnt. Kursteilnehmer werden benoetigt, den Report für 
Zwischenberichte zu filtern und zu drucken, Reportkarten und immer 
wenn eine parent/teacher oder student/teacher Konferenz geplant wird. 
Diese Aktivität hilft dem Lehrer, einen genauen Disziplinsatz 
zu halten und Disziplin mit minimaler Bemühung aufrechtzuerhalten. 
Sie hilft auch den Kursteilnehmern, zu verstehen, wie man eine 
Datenbank benutzt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le filet de requin est une base de données, 
installation par le professeur, où les étudiants enregistrent de 
toutes les interactions de discipline, de partir de la salle, et le 
travail exceptionnel. Il inclut des zones pour le prénom, le 
dernier nom, la date, le bloc, le code de problème, les commentaires 
par des étudiants, le temps dehors, et le temps dedans. À 
intervalles de deux semaines les étudiants filtrent leurs 
enregistrements pour calculer des catégories de participation de 
classe. La catégorie de participation de classe compte 10 pour 
cent de toute la catégorie de classe. Des étudiants avec les 
catégories de participation de haut-classe sont récompensés avec 
des activités spéciales telles que des parties de crême glacée, 
des cookouts, des voyages de zone, etc... Des étudiants sont 
requis de filtrer et imprimer l'état pour des rapports sur l'état 
d'avancement, des cartes d'état, et quand une conférence de 
parent/teacher ou de student/teacher est projetée. Cette 
activité aide le professeur à garder un enregistrement précis de 
discipline et à mettre à jour la discipline avec l'effort minimal. 
Elle aide également les étudiants à comprendre comment 
utiliser une base de données.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A rede do tubarão é uma base de dados, ajustada 
acima pelo professor, onde os estudantes mantêm registros de todas as
interações da disciplina, de sair do quarto, e do trabalho 
proeminente. Inclui campos por o primeiro nome, o último nome, 
a data, o bloco, o código do problema, os comentários por 
estudantes, o tempo para fora, e o tempo dentro. Em intervalos 
two-week os estudantes filtram seus registros para calcular classes da
participação da classe. A classe da participação da classe 
conta 10 por cento da classe total da classe. Os estudantes com 
as classes da participação da elevado-classe são recompensados com 
atividades especiais tais como partidos do creme de gelo, cookouts, 
desengates de campo, etc.. Os estudantes estão requeridos 
filtrar e imprimir o relatório para relatórios de progresso, 
cartões do relatório, e quando uma conferência de parent/teacher ou
de student/teacher está planeada. Esta atividade ajuda ao 
professor manter um registro exato da disciplina e manter a disciplina
com esforço mínimo. Ajuda também aos estudantes compreender 
como usar uma base de dados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La rete dello squalo è una base di dati, messa a 
punto dall'insegnante, in cui gli allievi registrano di tutte le 
interazioni di disciplina, di lasciare la stanza e lavoro eccezionale.
Include i campi per il nome, l'ultimo nome, la data, il blocco, 
il codice di problema, le osservazioni dagli allievi, il tempo fuori 
ed il tempo dentro. A intervalli di due settimane gli allievi 
filtrano i loro record per calcolare i gradi di partecipazione del 
codice categoria. Il grado di partecipazione del codice 
categoria conta 10 per cento del grado totale del codice categoria. 
Gli allievi con i gradi di partecipazione del alto-codice 
categoria sono ricompensati con le attività speciali quali i partiti 
del gelato, i cookouts, i viaggi di campo, ecc. Gli allievi sono
tenuti a filtrare e stampare il rapporto per le relazioni sullo stato 
di avanzamento, schedi di rapporto e qualunque momento un congresso di
student/teacher o di parent/teacher è progettato. Questa 
attività aiuta l'insegnante a mantenere un record esatto di 
disciplina ed ad effettuare la disciplina con sforzo minimo. 
Egualmente aiuta gli allievi a capire come usare una base di 
dati.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το δίκτυο καρχαριών είναι μια βάση δεδομένων, που 
ιδρύεται από το δάσκαλο, όπου οι σπουδαστές διατηρούν τα αρχεία
όλων των αλληλεπιδράσεων πειθαρχίας, της αναχώρησης του δωματίου,
και της σημαντικής εργασίας. Περιλαμβάνει τα πεδία για 
όνομα, τελευταίο όνομα, ημερομηνία, ομάδα δεδομένων, κώδικα 
προβλήματος, σχόλια από τους σπουδαστές, χρόνο αδράνειας, και 
χρόνο μέσα. Στο δεκαπενθήμερο φίλτρο σπουδαστών 
διαστημάτων τα αρχεία τους για να υπολογίσει τους βαθμούς 
συμμετοχής κλάσης. Ο βαθμός συμμετοχής κλάσης μετρά 10 
τοις εκατό του συνολικού βαθμού κλάσης. Οι σπουδαστές με 
τους βαθμούς συμμετοχής υψηλός-κλάσης ανταμείβονται με τις 
ειδικές δραστηριότητες όπως τα συμβαλλόμενα μέρη παγωτού, 
cookouts, ταξίδια πεδίων, οι σπουδαστές κ.λπ. απαιτούνται στο 
φίλτρο και τυπώνουν την έκθεση για τις εκθέσεις προόδου, 
έλεγχοι, και οποτεδήποτε προγραμματίζεται μια διάσκεψη 
γονέων/δασκάλων ή σπουδαστών/δασκάλων. Αυτή η 
δραστηριότητα βοηθά το δάσκαλο να διατηρήσει ένα ακριβές αρχείο
πειθαρχίας και για να διατηρήσει την πειθαρχία με την ελάχιστη 
προσπάθεια. Βοηθά επίσης τους σπουδαστές να καταλάβουν πώς
να χρησιμοποιήσει μια βάση δεδομένων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La red del tiburón es una base de datos, 
instalada por el profesor, donde los estudiantes guardan los 
expedientes de todas las interacciones de la disciplina, de salir del 
cuarto, y del trabajo excepcional. Incluye los campos por el 
nombre, el nombre pasado, la fecha, el bloque, el código del 
problema, comentarios de los estudiantes, tiempo hacia fuera, y tiempo
adentro. En los intervalos de dos semanas los estudiantes 
filtran sus expedientes para calcular grados de la participación de 
la clase. El grado de la participación de la clase cuenta 10 
por ciento del grado total de la clase. Recompensan los 
estudiantes con los grados de la participación de la alto-clase con 
actividades especiales tales como partidos del helado, cookouts, 
disparos al campo, etc. Requieren a los estudiantes filtrar e 
imprimir el informe para los informes sobre la marcha de los trabajos,
las tarjetas del informe, y cualquier momento se planea una 
conferencia de parent/teacher o de student/teacher. Esta 
actividad ayuda al profesor a guardar un expediente exacto de la 
disciplina y a mantener disciplina con esfuerzo mínimo. 
También ayuda a los estudiantes a entender cómo utilizar una 
base de datos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CALVIN EVANS
FN:CALVIN EVANS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202537</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106828</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-shark-net-a-discipline-database</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
