<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108357</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108357</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203564</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Just-in-Time Teaching (JiTT) WarmUp Activity: Cambrian Explosion</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gerade-in-Zeit Unterricht (JiTT) Vorwärmung 
Aktivität: Cambrian Explosion</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Activité De Préchauffage d'Enseignement de 
Juste-dans-Temps (JiTT) : Explosion Cambrienne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Atividade Do WarmUp Do Ensino Do Apenas-em-Tempo 
(JiTT): Explosão Cambrian</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Attività Di Preriscaldamento Di Insegnamento Di 
Appena-in-Tempo (JiTT): Esplosione Cambriana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πάνω στην ώρα δραστηριότητα WarmUp διδασκαλίας 
(JiTT): Κάμβρια έκρηξη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Actividad Del Calentamiento De la Enseñanza Del 
Apenas-en-Tiempo (JiTT): Explosión Cambriana</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site from SERC's Just-in-Time Teaching (JiTT) module presents JiTT warm up questions about the Cambrian Explosion. The questions examine dating techniques, information used to date the first branch of life, evidence against the Cambrian Explosion, and what is responsible for the huge expansion in size, complexity and body architecture of animals during this age.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site Unterricht Gerade-in-Zeit SERCs (JiTT) 
vom Modul stellt JiTT Vorwärmung Fragen über die Cambrian Explosion 
dar. Die Fragen überprüfen die Datierung der Techniken, 
Informationen benutzten bis jetzt den ersten Zweig des Lebens, Beweis 
gegen die Cambrian Explosion, und was für die sehr große Expansion 
in der Größe, in der Kompliziertheit und in der Körperarchitektur 
der Tiere während dieses Alters verantwortlich ist.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site du module d'enseignement du 
Juste-dans-Temps de SERC (JiTT) présente des questions de 
préchauffage de JiTT au sujet de l'explosion cambrienne. Les 
questions examinent dater des techniques, l'information ont utilisé 
jusqu'ici le premier branchement de la vie, évidence contre 
l'explosion cambrienne, et ce qui est responsable de l'expansion 
énorme dans la taille, la complexité et l'architecture de corps des 
animaux pendant cet âge.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local dos presentes JiTT do módulo do ensino
do Apenas-em-Tempo de SERC (JiTT) aquece acima perguntas sobre a 
explosão cambrian. As perguntas examinam datar técnicas, 
informação usada datar a primeira filial da vida, evidência de 
encontro à explosão cambrian, e o que é responsável para a 
expansão enorme no tamanho, na complexidade e na arquitetura do corpo
dos animais durante esta idade.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo dal modulo di insegnamento di 
Appena-in-Tempo dello SERC (JiTT) presenta le domande di 
preriscaldamento di JiTT circa l'esplosione cambriana. Le 
domande esaminano datare le tecniche, le informazioni hanno usato fin 
qui il primo ramo di vita, prova contro l'esplosione cambriana e che 
cosa è responsabile dell'espansione enorme nel formato, nella 
complessità e nell'architettura del corpo degli animali durante 
questa età.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή από την πάνω στην ώρα ενότητα 
διδασκαλίας SERC (JiTT) παρουσιάζει τις ερωτήσεις 
προθέρμανσης JiTT για την κάμβρια έκρηξη. Οι ερωτήσεις 
εξετάζουν τη χρονολόγηση των τεχνικών, οι πληροφορίες 
χρησιμοποίησαν μέχρι σήμερα τον πρώτο κλάδο της ζωής, στοιχεία 
ενάντια στην κάμβρια έκρηξη, και τι είναι αρμόδιος για την 
τεράστια επέκταση στο μέγεθος, την πολυπλοκότητα και την 
αρχιτεκτονική σωμάτων των ζώων κατά τη διάρκεια αυτής της 
ηλικίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio del módulo de la enseñanza del 
Apenas-en-Tiempo de SERC (JiTT) presenta preguntas del calentamiento 
de JiTT sobre la explosión cambriana. Las preguntas examinan 
fechar las técnicas, información utilizaron hasta la fecha la 
primera ramificación de la vida, evidencia contra la explosión 
cambriana, y cuál es responsable de la extensión enorme de tamaño, 
complejidad y la configuración del cuerpo de animales durante esta 
edad.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:LAURA GUERTIN
FN:LAURA GUERTIN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CATHY MANDUCA
FN:CATHY MANDUCA
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203564</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108357</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/just-in-time-teaching-jitt-warmup-activity-cambrian-explosion</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
