<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104115</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104115</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205681</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Frederic Remington: The Color of Night</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Frederic Remington: Die Farbe der Nacht</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Frederic Remington : La couleur de la nuit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Frederic Remington: A cor da noite</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Frederic Remington: Il colore della notte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θ*Φρεδερηθ Remington: Το χρώμα της νύχτας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Frederic Remington: El color de la noche</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is the first exhibition devoted to the nocturnes, or night paintings, of one of America's most gifted interpreters of the Frontier West. Twenty-nine paintings are organized around Remington's life and career?his early years as an illustrator, his stint as a war correspondent, and the artistic experiments that led to his nocturnes. These works explore the challenges of painting darkness yet are filled with color and light?moonlight, firelight, and candlelight.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist die erste Ausstellung, die den Notturnos 
gewidmet werden, oder die Nachtanstriche, von einem von Amerikas 
begabtesten Interpreters des Grenzwestens. Twenty-nine Anstriche
werden um das Leben Remingtons organisiert und career?his frühe Jahre
als Illustrator, sein Pensum als Kriegskorrespondent und die 
künstlerischen Experimente, die das zu seine Notturnos führte. 
Diese Arbeiten erforschen, die Herausforderungen der 
Anstrichschwärzung dennoch werden mit Farbe und light?moonlight, 
Feuerschein und Kerzenlicht gefüllt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est la première exposition consacrée aux 
nocturnes, ou les peintures de nuit, d'un des interprètes les plus 
doués de l'Amérique de l'ouest de frontière. Des peintures de
Twenty-nine sont organisées autour de la vie de Remington et de 
premières années de career?his en tant qu'illustrateur, son travail 
assigné en tant que correspondant de guerre, et les expériences 
artistiques que cela a menées à ses nocturnes. Ces travaux 
explorent les défis de l'obscurité de peinture pourtant sont remplis
de couleur et light?moonlight, lumière du feu, et lueur de chandelle.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">são o primeiro exhibition devotado aos nocturnes,
ou as pinturas da noite, de um dos intérpretes os mais gifted de 
América do oeste da fronteira. As pinturas de Twenty-nine são 
organizadas em torno da vida de Remington e anos adiantados dos 
career?his como um illustrator, seu stint como um correspondente de 
guerra, e as experiências que artísticas isso conduziu a seus 
nocturnes. Estes trabalhos exploram os desafios da escuridão da
pintura contudo são enchidos com a cor e o light?moonlight, o 
firelight, e o candlelight.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è la prima mostra dedicata ai nocturnes, o le 
pitture di notte, di uno degli interpretatori più dotati dell'America
dell'ovest di frontiera. Le pitture di Twenty-nine sono 
organizzate intorno a vita del Remington e primi anni di career?his 
come illustrator, il suo stint come corrispondente di guerra e gli 
esperimenti che artistici quello ha condotto ai suoi nocturnes. 
Questi impianti esplorano le sfide di nerezza della pittura 
tuttavia sono riempiti di colore e light?moonlight, firelight e 
candlelight.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι η πρώτη έκθεση που αφιερώνεται στα nocturnes,
ή έργα ζωγραφικής νύχτας, ένας από τους πιό ταλαντούχους 
διερμηνείς της Αμερικής της συνοριακής δύσης. Είκοσι εννέα
έργα ζωγραφικής οργανώνονται γύρω στη ζωή και τα career?his 
Remington στις αρχές ετών ως εικονογράφος, το όριό του ως 
πολεμικός ανταποκριτής, και τα καλλιτεχνικά πειράματα που οδήγησε
στα nocturnes του. Αυτές οι εργασίες ερευνούν τις 
προκλήσεις του σκοταδιού ζωγραφικής ακόμα γεμίζουν με το χρώμα 
και light?moonlight, firelight, και το φως ιστιοφόρου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es la primera exposición dedicada a los 
nocturnes, o las pinturas de la noche, de uno de los intérpretes más
dotados de América del oeste de la frontera. Las pinturas de 
Twenty-nine se ordenan alrededor de la vida de Remington y los años 
de los career?his como ilustrador, su restricción como correspondiente 
de guerra, y los experimentos artísticos que eso condujo a sus 
nocturnes. Estos trabajos exploran los desafíos de la oscuridad
de la pintura con todo se llenan de color y light?moonlight, 
firelight, y candlelight.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205681</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104115</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/frederic-remington-the-color-of-night</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
