<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105690</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105690</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213048</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Vostok Ice Core Excel Activity</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Vostok Eis-Kern Übertreffen Aktivität</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Noyau de Glace de Vostok Excellent l'Activité</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Núcleo Do Gelo De Vostok Excel A Atividade</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Nucleo Del Ghiaccio Di Vostok Eccelle 
L'Attività</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δραστηριότητα Excel πυρήνων πάγου Vostok</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Base Del Hielo De Vostok Sobresale Actividad</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">With this exercise, students use Excel to graph and analyze Vostok ice core data (160,000 years of Ice core data from Vostok Station). Data includes ice age, ice depth, carbon dioxide, methane, dust, and deuterium isotope relative abundance (dD). Students learn about ice cores and what they can tell us about past atmospheric conditions, learn about past atmospheric concentrations of CO2 and CH4 and about the climate and ice age cycle for the past 160,000 years. This is a complete activity that requires a working knowledge of Excel (see teaching notes and tips). This activity can be used as a homework assignment or lab activity in an introductory geoscience course with climate change content. The Vostok ice core data may also be used to make graphs for interactive lecture or other graphical analysis activities. This site also contains teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment idea and additional resources on the Vostok ice core and world climates. This activity is part of the Starting Point Collection: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mit dieser Übung übertrifft 
Kursteilnehmergebrauch, um Vostok Eis-Kerndaten graphisch darzustellen
und zu analysieren (160.000 Jahre Eis entkernen Daten von der Vostok 
Station). Daten schließen Eiszeit, Eistiefe, Kohlendioxyd, 
Methan, Staub und relativen Überfluß des Deuteriumisotops ein (DD). 
Kursteilnehmer erlernen über Eiskerne und was sie uns hinter 
atmosphärischen Bedingungen ungefähr erklären können, ungefähr 
hinter atmosphärischen Konzentrationen von CO2 und von CH4 und über 
das Klima und die Eiszeitschleife für die letzten 160.000 Jahre 
erlernen Sie. Dieses ist eine komplette Aktivität, dessen 
Arbeitswissen übertreffen benötigt (sehen Sie unterrichtende 
Anmerkungen und neigt). Diese Aktivität kann als Heimarbeit 
Anweisung oder Laboraktivität in einem einleitenden geoscience Kurs 
mit Klimaänderung Inhalt verwendet werden. Die Vostok 
Eis-Kerndaten können auch verwendet werden, um Diagramme für 
interaktiven Vortrag oder andere graphische Analyse Aktivitäten zu 
bilden. Diese Site enthält auch unterrichtende Anmerkungen und 
Spitzen, Lehrmittel, Einschätzung Idee und zusätzliche 
Betriebsmittel auf Vostok Eiskern und den Weltklimata. Diese 
Aktivität ist ein Teil der Ausgangspunkt-Ansammlung: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Avec cet exercice, l'utilisation d'étudiants 
excellent pour représenter graphiquement et analyser des données de 
noyau de glace de Vostok (160.000 ans de glace creusent des données 
de station de Vostok). Les données incluent la période 
glaciaire, la profondeur de glace, l'anhydride carbonique, le 
méthane, la poussière, et l'abondance relative d'isotope de 
deutérium (densité double). Les étudiants se renseignent sur 
des noyaux de glace et ce qu'ils peuvent nous dire environ après des 
conditions atmosphériques, apprenez environ après des concentrations
atmosphériques du CO2 et du CH4 et au sujet du climat et du cycle de 
période glaciaire pendant les 160.000 dernières années. C'est
une activité complète dont exige une connaissance fonctionnante 
excellent (voir les notes d'enseignement et incline). Cette 
activité peut être utilisée comme affectation de travail ou 
activité de laboratoire dans un cours préliminaire de geoscience 
avec le contenu de changement de climat. Les données de noyau 
de glace de Vostok peuvent également être employées pour faire des 
graphiques pour la conférence interactive ou d'autres activités 
graphiques d'analyse. Ce site contient également les notes et 
les extrémités d'enseignement, le matériel didactique, l'idée 
d'évaluation et les ressources supplémentaires sur le noyau de glace
de Vostok et les climats du monde. Cette activité fait partie 
de la collection de point de départ : 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Com este exercício, o uso dos estudantes excel 
para representar graficamente e analisar dados do núcleo do gelo de 
Vostok (160.000 anos do gelo retiram o núcleo de dados da estação 
de Vostok). Os dados incluem a idade de gelo, a profundidade do 
gelo, o dióxido de carbono, o methane, a poeira, e a abundância 
relativa do isotope do deuterium (dD). Os estudantes aprendem 
sobre núcleos do gelo e o que podem nos dizer aproximadamente após 
circunstâncias atmosféricas, aprenda aproximadamente após 
concentrações atmosféricas do CO2 e do CH4 e sobre o clima e o 
ciclo da idade de gelo por os 160.000 anos passados. Esta é uma
atividade completa de que requeira um conhecimento trabalhando excel 
(veja notas ensinando e as derrube). Esta atividade pode ser 
usada como uma atribuição do homework ou uma atividade do 
laboratório em um curso introdutório do geoscience com índice da 
mudança do clima. Os dados do núcleo do gelo de Vostok podem 
também ser usados fazer gráficos para o lecture interativo ou outras
atividades gráficas da análise. Este local contem também 
notas e pontas ensinando, materiais de ensino, idéia da avaliação e
recursos adicionais no núcleo do gelo de Vostok e nos climas do 
mundo. Esta atividade é parte da coleção do ponto começar: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Con questa esercitazione, l'uso degli allievi 
eccelle per rappresentare graficamente ed analizzare i dati di nucleo 
del ghiaccio di Vostok (160.000 anni di ghiaccio estraggono la parte 
centrale dai dati dalla stazione di Vostok). I dati includono 
l'età di ghiaccio, la profondità del ghiaccio, l'anidride carbonica,
il metano, la polvere e l'abbondanza relativa dell'isotopo del 
deuterio (dD). Gli allievi imparano circa i nuclei del ghiaccio 
e che cosa possono dirci circa oltre le circostanze atmosferiche, 
impari circa oltre le concentrazioni atmosferiche di CO2 e di CH4 e 
circa il clima ed il ciclo di età di ghiaccio per i 160.000 anni 
scorsi. Ciò è un'attività completa di che richiede una 
conoscenza di funzionamento eccellono (veda le note d'istruzione e si 
capovolge). Questa attività può essere usata come 
un'assegnazione di lavoro o attività del laboratorio in un corso 
introduttivo di geoscience con il soddisfare del cambiamento di clima.
I dati di nucleo del ghiaccio di Vostok possono anche essere 
usati per fare i grafici per la conferenza interattiva o altre 
attività grafiche di analisi. Questo luogo egualmente contiene 
le note e punte d'istruzione, materiali didattici, idea di valutazione
e risorse supplementari sul nucleo del ghiaccio di Vostok e sui climi 
del mondo. Questa attività fa parte dell'accumulazione del 
punto di partenza: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Με αυτήν την άσκηση, οι σπουδαστές χρησιμοποιούν 
Excel στη γραφική παράσταση και αναλύουν τα στοιχεία πυρήνων 
πάγου Vostok (160.000 έτη στοιχείων πυρήνων πάγου από το 
σταθμό Vostok). Το στοιχείο περιλαμβάνει την ηλικία 
πάγου, το βάθος πάγου, το διοξείδιο του άνθρακα, το μεθάνιο, τη 
σκόνη, και τη σχετική αφθονία ισοτόπων δευτέριου (dD). 
Οι σπουδαστές μαθαίνουν για τους πυρήνες πάγου και τι 
μπορούν να μας πουν για τις ατμοσφαιρικές συνθήκες παρελθόντος, να
μάθουμε για τις ατμοσφαιρικές συγκεντρώσεις παρελθόντος του CO2
και του CH4 και για το κλίμα και τον κύκλο ηλικίας πάγου για τα
προηγούμενα 160.000 έτη. Αυτό είναι μια πλήρης 
δραστηριότητα που απαιτεί γνώση εργασίας Excel 
(δείτε τις σημειώσεις και τις άκρες διδασκαλίας). 
Αυτή η δραστηριότητα μπορεί να χρησιμοποιηθεί ως ανάθεση 
εργασίας ή δραστηριότητα εργαστηρίων σε μια εισαγωγική σειρά 
μαθημάτων geoscience με το περιεχόμενο αλλαγής κλίματος. 
Τα στοιχεία πυρήνων πάγου Vostok μπορούν επίσης να 
χρησιμοποιηθούν για να κάνουν τις γραφικές παραστάσεις για τη 
διαλογική διάλεξη ή άλλες γραφικές δραστηριότητες ανάλυσης. 
Αυτή η περιοχή περιέχει επίσης τις σημειώσεις και τις 
άκρες διδασκαλίας, τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, την ιδέα αξιολόγησης 
και τα πρόσθετα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς στα κλίματα πυρήνων και 
κόσμων πάγου Vostok. Αυτή η δραστηριότητα είναι μέρος 
της συλλογής αφετηρίας: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Con este ejercicio, el uso de los estudiantes 
sobresale para representar y para analizar datos de la base 
gra'ficamente del hielo de Vostok (160.000 años de hielo quitan el 
corazón a datos de la estación de Vostok). Los datos incluyen 
edad de hielo, profundidad del hielo, el bióxido de carbono, el 
metano, el polvo, y la abundancia relativa del isótopo del deuterio 
(DD). Los estudiantes aprenden sobre memorias del hielo y qué 
pueden decirnos alrededor más allá de condiciones atmosféricas, 
aprenda alrededor más allá de concentraciones atmosféricas del CO2 
y de CH4 y sobre el clima y el ciclo de la edad de hielo por los 
últimos 160.000 años. Ésta es una actividad completa de la 
cual requiere un conocimiento de trabajo sobresalen (véase las notas 
de enseñanza e inclina). Esta actividad se puede utilizar como 
una asignación de la preparación o actividad del laboratorio en un 
curso introductorio del geoscience con el contenido del cambio del 
clima. Los datos de la base del hielo de Vostok se pueden 
también utilizar para hacer los gráficos para la conferencia 
interactiva u otras actividades gráficas del análisis. Este 
sitio también contiene notas y las extremidades de enseñanza, los 
materiales didácticos, idea del gravamen y los recursos adicionales 
en base del hielo de Vostok y los climas del mundo. Esta 
actividad es parte de la colección del punto de partida: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213048</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105690</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/vostok-ice-core-excel-activity</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
