<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108574</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108574</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213163</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Where is North?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wo ist Nord?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Où est du nord ?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Onde é norte?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dove è del nord?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πού είναι ο Βορράς;</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿Donde es del norte?</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this activity, students use a microcomputer connected to a magnetic field sensor to measure the magnitude and direction of their local magnetic field. On this Starting Point page, users can access information about the exercise's learning goals, context for use, teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment ideas, references and topics covered.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In dieser Aktivität benutzen Kursteilnehmer einen 
Mikrocomputer, der an ein magnetisches angeschlossen wird, 
auffangen Sensor, um die Größe zu messen und Richtung von 
ihrem lokalen magnetischen fangen auf. Auf dieser 
Ausgangspunktseite können Benutzer auf Informationen über die 
erlernenziele der Übung, Kontext für Gebrauch-, die 
Unterrichtenumfaßten anmerkungen und Spitzen, Lehrmittel, 
Einschätzung Ideen, Referenzen und Themen zugreifen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cette activité, les étudiants utilisent un 
micro-ordinateur relié à un capteur de champ magnétique pour 
mesurer l'importance et la direction de leur champ magnétique local. 
À cette page de point de départ, les utilisateurs peuvent 
accéder aux informations sur les buts d'étude de l'exercice, 
contexte pour les extrémités d'utilisation, d'enseignement les notes
et, le matériel didactique, les idées d'évaluation, les 
références et les sujets couverts.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta atividade, os estudantes usam um microcomputer 
conectado a um sensor do campo magnético para medir o valor e o 
sentido de seu campo magnético local. Nesta página do ponto 
começar, os usuários podem alcançar a informação sobre os 
objetivos de aprendizagem do exercício, contexto para as pontas do 
uso, ensinar as notas e, os materiais de ensino, as idéias da 
avaliação, as referências e os tópicos cobertos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questa attività, gli allievi utilizzano un 
microcomputer collegato ad un sensore del campo magnetico per misurare
la grandezza ed il senso del loro campo magnetico locale. A 
questa pagina del punto di partenza, gli utenti possono accedere alle 
informazioni sugli obiettivi imparanti dell'esercitazione, contesto 
per le punte di istruzione, di uso note e, i materiali didattici, le 
idee di valutazione, i riferimenti ed i soggetti coperti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτήν την δραστηριότητα, οι σπουδαστές 
χρησιμοποιούν έναν μικροϋπολογιστή που συνδέεται με έναν 
αισθητήρα μαγνητικών πεδίων για να μετρήσει το μέγεθος και την 
κατεύθυνση του τοπικού μαγνητικού πεδίου τους. Σε αυτήν την
σελίδα αφετηρίας, οι χρήστες μπορούν να έχουν πρόσβαση στις 
πληροφορίες για τους στόχους εκμάθησης της άσκησης, πλαίσιο για 
τη χρήση, τις σημειώσεις και τις άκρες διδασκαλίας, τα 
εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, τις ιδέες αξιολόγησης, τις αναφορές και τα 
θέματα που καλύπτονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta actividad, los estudiantes utilizan un 
microordenador conectado con un sensor del campo magnético para medir
la magnitud y la dirección de su campo magnético local. En 
esta paginación del punto de partida, los utilizadores pueden tener 
acceso a la información sobre las metas que aprenden del ejercicio, 
contexto para las extremidades del uso, de la enseñanza las notas y, 
los materiales didácticos, las ideas del gravamen, las referencias y 
los asuntos cubiertos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ROBYN JOHNSON
FN:ROBYN JOHNSON
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:GRETCHEN DEMOSS
FN:GRETCHEN DEMOSS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:RICHARD SORENSEN
FN:RICHARD SORENSEN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213163</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108574</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/where-is-north</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
