<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106586</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106586</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086950</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Greatest Tyrant in the State of Pennsylvania": A Late Nineteenth-Century Rail Worker Describes Management</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"das größte Tyrant im Zustand von Pennsylvania":
Ein Später 19.-Jahrhundert Schiene Arbeiter Beschreibt 
Management</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"le plus grand Tyran dans l'état de la 
Pennsylvanie" : Un Défunt Ouvrier de Rail de 
Dix-neuvième-Siècle Décrit La Gestion</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"o Tyrant o mais grande no estado de 
Pensilvânia": Um Trabalhador Atrasado Do Trilho De 
Décimo-Século Descreve A Gerência</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"il Tyrant più grande nel Dichiarare della 
Pensilvania": Un Operaio Ritardato Della Guida Di 
Diciannovesimo-Secolo Descrive La Gestione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ο μέγιστος τύραννος στο κράτος της Πενσυλβανίασ": 
Ένας πρώην εργαζόμενος ραγών δέκατος-αιώνα περιγράφει τη 
διαχείριση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"el Tyrant más grande del estado de 
Pennsylvania": Un Último Trabajador Del Carril Del 
Diecinueveavo-Siglo Describe A Gerencia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Although publicists for the Gilded Age corporations celebrated efficiency and the science of management, their employees did not always join the celebration. What looked like careful and disciplined management from one perspective was often viewed as petty tyranny from below. While some workers assailed upper management for this abuse others experienced the tyranny more directly in their day-to-day work lives. In this transcript taken from testimony before the U. S. House of Representatives in the late 1880s, Joseph P. Cahill, a worker in the freight department of the Philadelphia and Reading Railroad Company, described the petty tyrannies inflicted on workingmen by the company dispatcher.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Obgleich Publizisten für die vergoldete Alter 
Korporationen gefeierte Leistungsfähigkeit und die Wissenschaft des 
Managements, ihre Angestellten nicht immer die Feier verbanden. 
Von unterhalb was ausgesehen wie vorsichtiges und 
diszipliniertes Management von einer Perspektive häufig als 
geringfügige Tyrannei angesehen wurde. Während einige Arbeiter
oberes Management für diesen Mißbrauch angriffen, erfuhren andere 
die Tyrannei direkt in ihren Alltagsarbeit Lebensdauern. In 
dieser Abschrift, die vom Zeugnis vor dem USREPRÄSENTANTENHAUS im 
späten 1880s genommen wurde, beschrieben Joseph P. Cahill, ein 
Arbeiter in der Frachtabteilung des Philadelphias und Reading Railroad
Company, die geringfügigen tyrannies, die auf Workingmen vom 
Firmaverteiler zugefügt wurden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bien que les publicistes pour l'efficacité 
célébrée par sociétés dorée d'âge et la science de la gestion, 
leurs employés n'aient pas toujours joint la célébration. De 
dessous ce que ressemblé à la gestion soigneuse et disciplinée 
d'une perspective a été souvent visualisé en tant que tyrannie 
petite. Tandis que quelques ouvriers envahissaient la gestion 
supérieure pour cet abus d'autres ont éprouvé la tyrannie plus 
directement dans leurs vies de jour en jour de travail. Dans 
cette transcription prise du témoignage avant la chambre des 
représentants des États-Unis vers la fin de 1880s, Joseph P. Cahill,
un ouvrier dans le service de fret de Philadelphie et de Reading 
Railroad Company, ont décrit les tyrannies petits infligés sur des 
ouvriers par l'expéditeur de compagnie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Embora os publicists para a eficiência comemorada
corporation gilded da idade e a ciência da gerência, seus empregados
não juntassem sempre o celebration. O que olhado como a 
gerência cuidadosa e disciplinada de um perspective foi visto 
frequentemente como o tyranny petty abaixo. Quando alguns 
trabalhadores assailed a gerência superior para este abuso outros 
experimentaram o tyranny mais diretamente em suas vidas cotidianas do 
trabalho. Neste transcript feito exame do testimony antes da 
casa dos E. U. de representantes no 1880s atrasado, Joseph P. Cahill, 
um trabalhador no departamento do frete da Filadélfia e da Leitura 
Estrada de ferro Companhia, descreveram os tyrannies petty inflicted 
em workingmen pelo expedidor da companhia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Anche se i publicists per il risparmio di temi 
celebrato società gilded di età e la scienza della gestione, i loro 
impiegati non hanno unito sempre la celebrazione. Che cosa 
assomigliato alla gestione attenta e disciplinata da una prospettiva 
è stato osservato spesso come tirannia piccola da sotto. Mentre
alcuni operai hanno assalito la gestione superiore per questo abuso 
altri hanno avvertito la tirannia più direttamente nelle loro vite 
giornaliere del lavoro. In questa trascrizione presa dalla 
testimonianza prima della Camera dei rappresentanti degli Stati Uniti 
verso la fine di 1880s, Joseph P. Cahill, un operaio nel reparto del 
trasporto di Filadelfia e della Reading Railroad Company, hanno 
descritto i tyrannies piccoli inflitti sui workingmen dallo 
spedizioniere dell'azienda.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αν και οι πολιτικοί αρθρογράφοι για τις επιχρυσωμένες 
εταιρίες ηλικίας γιόρτασαν την αποδοτικότητα και την επιστήμη της
διαχείρισης, οι υπάλληλοί τους όχι πάντα ένωσαν τον εορτασμό. 
Αυτό που εμοίασε με την προσεκτική και πειθαρχημένη 
διαχείριση από μια προοπτική εμφανίστηκε συχνά ως ασήμαντη 
τυραννία από κάτω από. Ενώ μερικοί εργαζόμενοι 
επιτέθηκαν την ανώτερη διαχείριση για αυτήν την κατάχρηση άλλοι 
δοκίμασαν την τυραννία αμεσότερα στις καθημερινές ζωές εργασίας 
τους. Σε αυτό το αντίγραφο που λήφθηκε από την κατάθεση 
πριν από τον οίκο του Θ*u. Θ*ς. των αντιπροσώπων προς το τέλος 
1880s, Joseph P. Cahill, ένας εργαζόμενος στο τμήμα 
φορτίου της Φιλαδέλφειας και Reading Railroad Company, 
περιέγραψαν τα ασήμαντα tyrannies που επιβλήθηκαν από τον 
αποστολέα επιχείρησης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Aunque los publicistas para la eficacia celebrada 
las corporaciones dorada de la edad y la ciencia de la gerencia, sus 
empleados no ensamblaron siempre la celebración. Qué parecida 
la gerencia cuidadosa y disciplinada a partir de una perspectiva fue 
visto a menudo como tiranía pequeña debajo. Mientras que 
algunos trabajadores invadieron a gerencia superior para este abuso 
otros experimentaron la tiranía más directamente en sus vidas 
cotidianas del trabajo. En esta transcripción tomada de 
testimonio antes de la cámara de los E.E.U.U. de representantes en el
último 1880s, José P. Cahill, un trabajador en el departamento de la
carga de la Philadelphia y de la Reading Railroad Company, 
describieron los tyrannies pequeños infligidos en workingmen por el 
repartidor de la compañía.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086950</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106586</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-greatest-tyrant-in-the-state-of-pennsylvania-a-late-nineteenth-century-rail-worker-describes-management</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
