<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104617</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104617</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209801</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Arc Length</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bogen-Länge</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Longueur d'Arc</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Comprimento Do Arco</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lunghezza Dell'Arco</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μήκος τόξων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Longitud Del Arco</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate the concept of arc length. The applet shows a circle with part of its circumference highlighted and the central angle shown. As the user drags either end of the arc it is redrawn and the calculation for arc length changes as you drag. The text on the web page gives the formula for calculating the arc length. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die das Konzept der Bogenlänge zeigen. Der applet 
zeigt einen Kreis mit Teil seines Umkreises, der markiert werden und 
des zentralen gezeigten Winkels. Da der Benutzer jedes Ende des 
Bogens schleppt, ist es redrawn und die Berechnung für Bogenlänge 
ändert, während Sie schleppen. Der Text auf der Webseite gibt 
die Formel für die Berechnung der Bogenlänge. Applet kann zum 
vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor 
vergrößert werden. Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, 
Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause 
oder in der Bibliothek ohne den benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. 
Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes 
Bezugsinteraktiven Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent le concept de la longueur d'arc. L'applet montre
un cercle avec une partie de sa circonférence mise en valeur et de 
l'angle central montré. Car l'utilisateur traîne l'une ou 
l'autre extrémité de l'arc c'est redrawn et le calcul pour la 
longueur d'arc change pendant que vous traînez. Le texte sur la
page Web donne la formule pour calculer la longueur d'arc. 
L'applet peut être agrandi à la taille de plein écran pour 
l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de classe. Le après 
utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant peut lui accéder 
encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la maison ou dans la 
bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion exigée. Cette 
ressource est un composant du projet interactif de manuel de la 
géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem o conceito do comprimento do arco. O applet mostra um
círculo com parte de sua circunferência destacada e do ângulo 
central mostrado. Porque o usuário arrasta uma ou outra 
extremidade do arco é redrawn e o cálculo para o comprimento do arco
muda enquanto você arrasta. O texto no Web page dá a fórmula 
para calcular o comprimento do arco. O applet pode ser ampliado 
ao tamanho de tela cheia para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. 
O depois de uso na sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la 
outra vez de todo o web browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum 
início de uma sessão requerido. Este recurso é um componente 
do projeto interativo do textbook da geometria da referência aberta 
do math em http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano il concetto della lunghezza dell'arco. Il applet 
mostra un cerchio con la parte della relativa circonferenza 
evidenziata e dell'angolo centrale indicato. Poichè l'utente 
trascina la una o la altra estremità dell'arco è redrawn ed il 
calcolo per la lunghezza dell'arco cambia mentre vi trascinate. 
Il testo sul Web page dà la formula per la calcolazione della 
lunghezza dell'arco. Il applet può essere ingrandito al formato
di schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore dell'aula. La 
post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può accederle ancora da tutto 
il web browser nel paese o nella libreria senza l'inizio attività 
richiesto. Questa risorsa è un componente del progetto 
interattivo del manuale della geometria di riferimento aperto di per 
la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν την έννοια του μήκους τόξων. Το applet 
εμφανίζει έναν κύκλο με μέρος της περιφέρειάς του που 
τονίζονται και της κεντρικής γωνίας που εμφανίζεται. 
Δεδομένου ότι ο χρήστης σέρνει καθένα τέλος του τόξου 
αποσύρεται και ο υπολογισμός για τις αλλαγές μήκους τόξων καθώς 
σέρνετε. Το κείμενο ιστοσελίδας δίνει τον τύπο για τον 
υπολογισμό του μήκους τόξων. Το Applet μπορεί να 
διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με έναν 
προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο 
σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε 
ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια 
εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς 
είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος εγχειριδίων 
γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran el concepto de la longitud del arco. El applet 
muestra un círculo con la parte de su circunferencia destacada y del 
ángulo central mostrado. Pues el utilizador arrastra cualquier 
extremo del arco es redrawn y el cálculo para la longitud del arco 
cambia mientras que usted arrastra. El texto en el Web page da 
el fórmula para calcular la longitud del arco. El applet se 
puede agrandar a la talla de la pantalla completa para el uso con un 
proyector de la sala de clase. El uso posterior en la sala de 
clase, estudiante puede tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier web 
browser en el país o en la biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. 
Este recurso es un componente del proyecto interactivo del libro
de textos de la geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas
en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209801</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104617</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/arc-length</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
