<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106521</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106521</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087248</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Work and labor in this new and wild land are very hard": A German Migrant in Philadelphia, 1750</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Arbeit und Arbeit in diesem neuen und wilden Land
sind" sehr hart: Ein deutscher Wanderer in Philadelphia, 1750</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">le "travail et le travail dans cette nouvelle et 
sauvage terre sont très durs" : Un migrant allemand à 
Philadelphie, 1750</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">o "trabalho e o trabalho nesta terra nova e 
selvagem são muito duros": Um emigrante alemão em Filadélfia,
1750</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"il lavoro ed il lavoro in questa nuova e 
terra selvaggia sono molto duri": Un migrante tedesco a 
Filadelfia, 1750</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η εργασία και η εργασία σε αυτό το νέο και άγριο 
έδαφος είναι πολύ σκληρέσ": Ένας γερμανικός μετανάστης 
στη Φιλαδέλφεια, 1750</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">el "trabajo y el trabajo en esta pista nueva y 
salvaje son muy duros": Un nómada alemán en Philadelphia, 
1750</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">William Penn's colony of Pennsylvania, founded in 1681, attracted many poor European migrants. Many colonists financed their migration by arriving as indentured servants. Indentured servants were an important source of labor in the colonies; those arriving in the 17th century usually signed contracts (known as indentures) for a fixed term and upon completion received their freedom and a suit of clothes, a similar practice to apprenticeship. However, the Germans whom Gottlieb Mittelberger observed in the mid-18th century had no formal contracts; instead they were auctioned off to he highest bidder upon arrival, a practice that Mittleberger labeled as barbaric, and "a sale in human beings." Mittelberger, an organist and schoolmaster, found much in North America not to his taste, and returned to Germany in a few years where he wrote a book warning Germans of the dangers of emigration to the New World.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">William Penns die Kolonie von Pennsylvania, 
gegründet 1681, zog viele arme europäische Wanderer an. Viele 
Kolonisten finanzierten ihre Migration, indem sie wie ankamen, 
indentured Bedienstete. Indentured Bedienstete waren eine 
wichtige Quelle der Arbeit in den Kolonien; die, die in den 17. 
unterzeichneten Verträgen des Jahrhunderts normalerweise ankommen 
(bekannt als errichtete Urkunden) für eine örtlich festgelegte 
Bezeichnung und nach Beendigung empfingen ihre Freiheit und eine Klage
von Kleidung, eine ähnliche Praxis zur Lehre. Jedoch hatten die
Deutschen, die Gottlieb Mittelberger im mid-18th Jahrhundert 
beobachtete, keine Formverträge; stattdessen waren sie weg 
stark versteigert er Bewerber nach Ankunft, üblich, die 
Mittleberger beschriftete, wie barbarisch, und "ein Verkauf in den 
Menschen." Mittelberger, ein Organist und Schoolmaster, fand 
viel in Nordamerika nicht zu seinem Geschmack und ging nach 
Deutschland in einigen Jahren zurück, in dem er einem Buch warnende 
Deutsche der Gefahren der Auswanderung zur neuen Welt schrieb.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La colonie de William Penn de la Pennsylvanie, 
fondée en 1681, a attiré beaucoup de pauvres migrants européens. 
Beaucoup de colons ont financé leur transfert par l'arrivée 
comme indentured des domestiques. Les domestiques d'Indentured 
étaient une source importante de travail dans les colonies ; 
ceux arrivant dans les 17èmes contrats habituellement signés 
de siècle (connus sous le nom de contrat synallagmatique bilatéraux)
pour une limite fixe et sur l'accomplissement ont reçu leur liberté 
et un costume des vêtements, une pratique semblable à 
l'apprentissage. Cependant, les Allemands que Gottlieb 
Mittelberger a observés en siècle de mid-18th n'ont eu aucun contrat
formel ; au lieu de cela ils n'étaient pas en ligne vendus aux enchères
il le plus haut soumissionnaire sur l'arrivée, une pratique que 
Mittleberger a étiquetées comme barbare, et "une vente dans les 
êtres humains." Mittelberger, un organiste et maître, a 
trouvé beaucoup en Amérique du nord pas à son goût, et est 
revenu à l'Allemagne en quelques années où il a écrit à un livre 
les Allemands d'avertissement des dangers de l'émigration au nouveau 
monde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A colônia de William Penn de Pensilvânia, 
fundada em 1681, atraiu muitos emigrantes europeus deficientes. 
Muitos colonos financiaram sua migração chegando como 
indentured empregados. Os empregados de Indentured eram uma 
fonte importante do trabalho nas colônias; aqueles que chegam 
nos 17os contratos geralmente assinados do século (sabidos como 
indentures) para um termo fixo e em cima da conclusão receberam sua 
liberdade e um terno da roupa, uma prática similar ao apprenticeship.
Entretanto, os alemães quem Gottlieb Mittelberger observou no 
século de mid-18th não tiveram nenhum contrato formal; instead
eram auctioned fora o o mais altamente licitante em cima da chegada, 
de uma prática que Mittleberger etiquetou como barbaric, e "de uma 
venda em seres humanos." Mittelberger, um organist e 
schoolmaster, encontrou muito em America do Norte não a seu gosto, e 
retornou a Germany em alguns anos onde escreveu a um livro alemães de
advertência dos perigos do emigration ao mundo novo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La colonia del William Penn della Pensilvania, 
fondata in 1681, ha attratto molti poveri migranti europei. 
Molti colonizzatori hanno finanziato la loro espansione 
arrivando come indentured servi. I servi di Indentured erano una
sorgente importante del lavoro nelle colonie; quelli che 
arrivano nel diciassettesimo secolo solitamente hanno firmato i 
contratti (conosciuti come i indentures) per un termine fisso ed a 
completamento hanno ricevuto la loro libertà e un vestito dei 
vestiti, una pratica simile ad apprendistato. Tuttavia, i 
tedeschi quale Gottlieb Mittelberger ha osservato nel secolo di 
mid-18th non hanno avuti contratti convenzionali; invece erano 
auctioned fuori lui il più su offerente sull'arrivo, su una pratica 
che Mittleberger ha identificato come barbaric e "su una vendita in 
esseri umani." Mittelberger, un organist e schoolmaster, ha 
trovato molto in America del Nord non al suo gusto ed ha ritornato in 
Germania durante alcuni anni in cui ha scritto ad un libro i tedeschi 
d'avvertimento dei pericoli di emigrazione al nuovo mondo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η αποικία William Penn's της Πενσυλβανίας, που 
ιδρύθηκε το 1681, προσέλκυσε πολλούς φτωχούς ευρωπαϊκούς 
μετανάστες. Πολλοί άποικοι χρηματοδότησαν τη μετανάστευσή 
τους με την άφιξη όπως υπάλληλοι. Οι υπάλληλοι Indentured
ήταν μια σημαντική πηγή εργασίας στις αποικίες  εκείνοι 
που φθάνουν στο 17$ο αιώνα υπέγραψαν συνήθως τις συμβάσεις 
(γνωστές ως indentures) για έναν σταθερό όρο και με την 
ολοκλήρωση έλαβαν την ελευθερία τους και ένα κοστούμι των 
ενδυμάτων, μια παρόμοια πρακτική στη μαθητεία. Εντούτοις, 
οι Γερμανοί που Gottlieb Mittelberger παρατήρησε στο 
μέσος-18$ο αιώνα δεν είχαν καμία επίσημη σύμβαση  αντ' 
αυτού ήταν δημοπρατημένος μακριά αυτός υψηλότερος πλειοδότης 
επάνω στην άφιξη, μια πρακτική που Mittleberger ονόμασε όπως 
βαρβαρικό, και "μια πώληση στα ανθρώπινα οντα." Το 
Mittelberger, ένας οργανοπαίκτης και schoolmaster, βρήκαν 
πολύ στη Βόρεια Αμερική όχι στην προτίμησή του, και επέστρεψαν 
στη Γερμανία σε μερικά έτη όπου έγραψε μια προειδοποίηση 
Γερμανοί βιβλίων των κινδύνων της αποδημίας στο νέο κόσμο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La colonia de Guillermo Penn de Pennsylvania, 
fundada en 1681, atrajo a muchos nómadas europeos pobres. 
Muchos colonos financiaron su migración llegando como 
indentured los criados. Los criados de Indentured eran una 
fuente importante del trabajo en las colonias; ésos que 
llegaban en los 17mos contratos generalmente firmados del siglo 
(conocidos como contratos) para un término fijo y sobre la 
terminación recibieron su libertad y un juego de ropas, una práctica
similar al aprendizaje. Sin embargo, los alemanes a que Gottlieb
Mittelberger observó en el siglo de mid-18th no tenían ningún 
contrato formal; en lugar estaban auctioned apagado lo lo más 
arriba posible licitador sobre la llegada, una práctica que 
Mittleberger etiquetó como barbárico, y "una venta en seres 
humanos." Mittelberger, organist y profesor, encontró mucho en 
Norteamérica no a su gusto, y volvió a Alemania en algunos años en 
donde él escribió a libro los alemanes amonestadores de los peligros
de la emigración al mundo nuevo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087248</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106521</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/work-and-labor-in-this-new-and-wild-land-are-very-hard-a-german-migrant-in-philadelphia-1750</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
