<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108045</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108045</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086896</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Ballad of Bonnie and Clyde" by Bonnie Parker</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die Ballade von Bonnie und von Clyde" durch 
Bonnie Parker</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"la ballade de Bonnie et de Clyde" par Bonnie 
Parker</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"o ballad de Bonnie e de Clyde" por Bonnie Parker</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"il ballad di Bonnie e di Clyde" da Bonnie Parker</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η μπαλάντα Bonnie και Clyde" από Bonnie 
Parker</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"la balada de Bonnie y de Clyde" por Bonnie 
Parker</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">To many ordinary citizens during the Great Depression, bank robbers were seen as victims of injustice driven to commit crimes, folk heroes wreaking vengeance on a callous economic system. The notoriety of the Barrow Gang ("Bonnie and Clyde") was bolstered by wild shootouts with police, spectacular car chases, and the romance of two lovers outside the law. In turn, they courted publicity and cultivated the image of misfit-heroes. Bonnie and Clyde's "aspirations" were low: they preferred raiding small, isolated banks and did not hesitate to prey on modest stores and marginal businesses. Bonnie Parker sent poems and photographs to newspapers, heralding the Barrow Gang's exploits and defending her honor. This poem, by Parker, depicted the pair as populist desperadoes, misunderstood and star-crossed lovers driven to a life of crime. Bonnie and Clyde remained at large until a Texas posse ambushed them on May 23, 1934. Dying together in a proverbial hail of bullets--the Texas lawmen pumped some 187 rounds into the couple--helped perpetuate the romance surrounding their short, desperate, and destructive lives.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zu vielen gewöhnlichen Bürgern während des 
großen Tiefstands, wurden Bankräuber als Opfer des Unrechts 
angetrieben, um Verbrechen, die Volkshelder festzulegen gesehen, die 
vengeance auf einem verhärteten Wirtschaftssystem wreaking sind. 
Die Allbekanntheit der Karren-Gruppe ("Bonnie und Clyde") wurde 
durch wilde shootouts mit Polizei, großartigen Autoverfolgungen und 
dem Romanze von zwei Geliebten außerhalb des Gesetzes gepolstert. 
Der Reihe nach umwarben sie Werbung und kultivierten das Bild 
der Stück-Helder. Bonnie und Clydes "Aspirationen" waren 
niedrig: sie zogen es vor, die kleinen, lokalisierten Bänke zu 
überfallen und zögerten nicht prey auf bescheidenen Speichern und 
begrenzten Geschäften. Bonnie Parker gesendete Gedichte und 
Fotographien zu den Zeitungen, die Großtaten der Karren-Gruppe 
ankündigend und verteidigen ihre Ehre. Dieses Gedicht, durch 
Parker, stellte das Paar als Volksdesperadoes, mißverstandene und 
Stern-gekreuztes Geliebte bildlich dar, die zu einer Lebensdauer des 
Verbrechens angetrieben wurden. Bonnie und Clyde blieben an 
großem, bis eine Texas Gruppe sie an Mai 23, 1934 ambushed. In 
einem sprichwörtlichen Hagel der Gewehrkugeln -- die Texas Lawmen 
zusammen sterben pumpte ca. 187 Umläufe in die Paare -- geholfen, das
Romanze zu verewigen, ihre kurzen, hoffnungslosen und zerstörenden 
Lebensdauern umgebend.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">À beaucoup de citoyens ordinaires pendant la 
grande dépression, des voleurs de banque ont été vus comme victimes
de l'injustice pilotées pour commettre des crimes, héros 
folkloriques assouvissant la vengeance sur un système 
économique dur. La notoriété de la troupe de brouette 
("Bonnie et Clyde") a été soutenue par des échanges de tirs sauvages 
avec la police, les chasses spectaculaires de voiture, et le roman de 
deux amoureux en dehors de la loi. Alternativement, ils sont 
allés au devant de la publicité et ont cultivé l'image des 
vêtement-héros. Les "aspirations" de Bonnie et de Clyde 
étaient basses : elles ont préféré piller de petites, 
d'isolement banques et n'ont pas hésité à attaquer sur les 
mémoires modestes et les entreprises marginales. Poésies et 
photographies envoyées par Parker de Bonnie aux journaux, annonçant 
les exploits de la troupe de brouette et défendant son honneur. 
Cette poésie, par Parker, a dépeint la paire en tant que 
desperadoes populistes, mal comprise et des amoureux de 
tenir le premier rôle-crossed pilotés à une vie de crime. Bonnie et Clyde 
sont restés à grand jusqu'à ce qu'une bande du Texas les ait 
attirées dans un guet-apens 23 mai 1934. Mourant ensemble dans une 
grêle proverbiale des balles -- les représentants de la loi du Texas a pompé 
environ 187 séries dans les couples -- aidées à perpétuer le roman
entourant leurs vies courtes, désespérées, et destructives.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A muitos cidadãos ordinários durante o 
depression grande, os salteadores do banco foram vistos como as 
vítimas do injustice dirigidas para cometer crimes, heróis populares
que wreaking o vengeance em um sistema econômico callous. O 
notoriety do grupo do carrinho de mão ("Bonnie e Clyde") bolstered 
por shootouts selvagens com polícias, perseguições espectaculares 
do carro, e o romance de dois amantes fora da lei. Por sua vez, 
cortejaram o publicity e cultivaram a imagem dos desajuste-heróis. 
Os "aspirations" de Bonnie e de Clyde eram baixos: 
preferiram invadir bancos pequenos, isolados e não hesitate 
rapinar em lojas modestas e em negócios marginais. Poemas e 
fotografias emitidos Parker de Bonnie aos jornais, heralding as 
façanhas do grupo do carrinho de mão e defendendo sua honra. 
Este poema, por Parker, descreveu o par como os amantes populist
dos desperadoes, entendido mal e estrela-cruzado dirigidos a uma vida 
do crime. Bonnie e Clyde remanesceram em grande até que um 
posse de Texas ambushed o maio em 23, 1934. Morrendo junto em 
uma saraiva proverbial das balas -- lawmen de Texas bombeou uns 187 
círculos nos pares -- ajudadas perpetuate o romance cercando suas 
vidas curtas, desesperadas, e destrutivas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">A molti cittadini ordinari durante la depressione 
grande, i ladri della banca sono stati visti come vittime di 
injustice guidate per commettere i crimini, eroi pieghi che 
wreaking il vengeance su un sistema economico callous. Il 
notoriety del gruppo della carriola ("Bonnie e Clyde") è stato 
sostenuto dagli shootouts selvaggi con la polizia, gli inseguimenti 
spettacolari dell'automobile ed il romanzesco di due amanti 
fuori della legge. A loro volta, hanno sollecitato la 
pubblicità ed hanno coltivato l'immagine di misfit-eroe. 
"le aspirazioni" del Clyde e di Bonnie erano basse: hanno 
preferito raiding la piccola, banca isolata e non hanno esitato
a predare ai depositi modesti ed ai commerci marginali. Bonnie 
Parker ha trasmesso i poems e le fotografie ai giornali, annunzianti 
le imprese del gruppo della carriola e difendenti il suo honor. 
Questo poem, da Parker, ha descritto l'accoppiamento come 
amanti compreso male e stella-attraversata populistici dei 
desperadoes, guidati ad una durata del crimine. Bonnie e Clyde 
sono rimasto a grande fino a che un posse del Texas non ambushed loro 
maggio su 23, 1934. Morendo insieme nella grandine proverbial 
delle pallottole -- i lawmen del Texas ha pompato circa 187 tondi 
nelle coppie -- contribuite a perpetuare il romanzesco circondando le 
loro vite corte, disperate e distruttive.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε πολλούς απλούς πολίτες κατά τη διάρκεια της 
μεγάλης οικονομικής κρίσης, οι ληστές τραπεζών εβλέίδαν 
ως θύματα της αδικίας που οδηγήθηκε για να διαπράξει τα 
εγκλήματα, λαϊκοί ήρωες που λαμβάνουν την εκδίκηση σε ένα 
τυλώδες οικονομικό σύστημα. Η κακή φήμη της συμμορίας 
χειραμάξιων ("Bonnie και Clyde") υποστηρίχτηκε από τα άγρια 
shootouts με την αστυνομία, τα θεαματικά αυλακώματα 
αυτοκινήτων, και το ρωμανικό δύο εραστών έξω από το νόμο. 
Στη συνέχεια, φλέρταραν τη δημοσιότητα και καλλιέργησαν την 
εικόνα των απροσάρμοστος-ηρώων. Οι "φιλοδοξίεσ" Bonnie 
και Clyde ήταν χαμηλές: προτίμησαν να επιτεθούν τις 
μικρές, απομονωμένες τράπεζες και δεν δίστασαν στο θήραμα στα 
μέτρια καταστήματα και τις οριακές επιχειρήσεις. Το 
Bonnie Parker έστειλε τα ποιήματα και τις φωτογραφίες στις 
εφημερίδες, που ανακοινώνουν τους άθλους της συμμορίας 
χειραμάξιων και που υπερασπίζουν την τιμή της. Αυτό το 
ποίημα, από Parker, απεικόνισε το ζευγάρι ως λαϊκιστικά 
desperadoes, παρανοημένους και αστέρι-διασχισμένους εραστές που
οδηγήθηκαν σε μια ζωή του εγκλήματος. Το Bonnie και 
Clyde παρέμειναν σε μεγάλο έως ότου ένα Τέξας posse αυτοί
σε Μάιος 23, 1934, πεθαίνοντας μαζί σε ένα παροιμιακό 
χαλάζι των σφαιρών -- το Τέξας αντλημένος περίπου 187 κύκλους
στο ζεύγος -- που ενισχύθηκε να διαιωνίσει το ρωμανικό περιβάλλων
τις σύντομες, απελπισμένες, και καταστρεπτικές ζωές τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">A muchos ciudadanos ordinarios durante la gran 
depresión, vieron a los ladrones de la batería como víctimas de la 
injusticia conducidas para confiar los crímenes, héroes populares 
wreaking venganza en un sistema económico callous. La 
notoriedad de la cuadrilla de la carretilla ("Bonnie y Clyde") fue 
alentada por los shootouts salvajes con policía, persecuciones 
espectaculares del coche, y el romance de dos amantes fuera de la 
ley. Alternadamente, cortejaron publicidad y cultivaron la 
imagen de cosa-he'roes. Las "aspiraciones" de Bonnie y de Clyde 
eran bajas: prefirieron el atacar de las baterías pequeñas, 
aisladas y no vacilaron cazar en almacenes modestos y negocios 
marginales. Poemas y fotografías enviados Parker de Bonnie a 
los periódicos, anunciando las hazañas de la cuadrilla de la 
carretilla y defendiendo su honor. Este poema, por Parker, 
representó el par como amantes populistas de los desperadoes, 
entendido mal y estrella-cruzado conducidos a una vida del crimen. 
Bonnie y Clyde permanecían en grande hasta que un posse de 
Tejas ambushed lo 23 de mayo de 1934. Muriendo junto en un 
granizo proverbial de los puntos negros -- los representantes de la 
ley de Tejas bombeó unos 187 redondos en los pares -- ayudados a 
perpetuar el romántico rodeando sus vidas cortas, desesperadas, y 
destructivas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086896</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108045</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-ballad-of-bonnie-and-clyde-by-bonnie-parker</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
