<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104543</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104543</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207083</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Hopewell Furnace: A Pennsylvania Iron-making Plantation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hopewell Ofen: Eine Pennsylvania 
Eisenproduktion-Plantage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Four de Hopewell : Une Plantation de 
Fabrication de fer de la Pennsylvanie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fornalha De Hopewell: Uma Plantação Do 
Iron-making De Pensilvânia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fornace Di Hopewell: Una Piantagione Di 
Fabbricazione del ferro Della Pensilvania</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Φούρνος Hopewell: Μια iron-making της 
Πενσυλβανίας φυτεία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Horno De Hopewell: Una Plantación De la 
Producción de hierro De Pennsylvania</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">tells the story of one of the 65 small ironworks operating in southeast Pennsylvania during the American Revolution. The Hopewell Furnace, located in forested hills and valleys along French Creek in Berks County, operated from 1771 to 1883. The furnace was the center of a self-contained hierarchical community of 200-300 people, all of whose work was related to the production of iron.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erklärt die Geschichte von einer der 65 kleinen 
Eisenarbeiten, die in Südostpennsylvania während der amerikanischen 
Umdrehung funktionieren. Der Hopewell Ofen, gelegen in den 
bewaldeten Hügeln und in den Senken entlang französischem Nebenfluß
in der Berks Grafschaft, funktionierte von 1771 bis 1883. Der 
Ofen war die Mitte einer selbständigen hierarchischen Gemeinschaft 
von 200-300 Leuten, alle von deren Arbeit mit der Produktion des 
Eisens zusammenhing.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dit l'histoire d'une des 65 petites usines sidérurgiques 
fonctionnant en Pennsylvanie du sud-est pendant la révolution 
américaine. Le four de Hopewell, situé dans les collines et 
les vallées couvertes de forêts le long de la crique française dans
le comté de Berks, a fonctionné à partir de 1771 à 1883. Le 
four était le centre d'une communauté hiérarchique de 
art de l'auto-portrait-contained de 200-300 personnes, toutes ce que du travail a 
été lié à la production du fer.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">diz a história de um dos 65 ironworks pequenos 
que operam-se em Pensilvânia do sudeste durante a volta americana. 
A fornalha de Hopewell, situada em montes e em vales forested ao
longo do creek francês no condado de Berks, operou-se de 1771 a 1883.
A fornalha era o centro de uma comunidade hierárquica 
self-contained de 200-300 povos, tudo cujo do trabalho foi relacionado
à produção do ferro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">dice alla storia di uno dei 65 piccoli ironworks 
che funzionano in Pensilvania sudorientale durante la rivoluzione 
americana. La fornace di Hopewell, situata in colline ed in 
valli forested lungo insenatura francese nella contea di Berks, ha 
funzionato a partire da 1771 a 1883. La fornace era il centro di
una Comunità gerarchica autonoma di 200-300 genti, tutta di cui di 
lavoro fosse collegato con la produzione di ferro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">λέει την ιστορία ένα από τα 65 μικρά σιδηρουργεία
λειτουργώ στη νοτιοανατολική Πενσυλβανία κατά τη διάρκεια της 
αμερικανικής επανάστασης. Ο φούρνος Hopewell, που βρέθηκε
στους δασικούς λόφους και τις κοιλάδες κατά μήκος του γαλλικού 
κολπίσκου στο νομό Berks, λειτούργησε από 1771 έως 1883.
Ο φούρνος ήταν το κέντρο μιας ανεξάρτητης ιεραρχικής 
κοινότητας 200-300 ανθρώπων, όλης η των οποίων εργασία 
αφορούσε την παραγωγή του σιδήρου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">cuenta la historia de uno de los 65 ironworks 
pequeños que funcionan en Pennsylvania suroriental durante la 
revolución americana. El horno de Hopewell, situado en colinas 
y valles forested a lo largo del cala francés en el condado de Berks,
funcionó a partir de 1771 a 1883. El horno era el centro de una
comunidad jerárquica autónoma de 200-300 personas, todas que de 
trabajo fue relacionado con la producción del hierro.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207083</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104543</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/hopewell-furnace-a-pennsylvania-iron-making-plantation</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
