<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108290</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108290</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086671</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">No Way Out: Two New York City Firemen Testify about the 1911 Triangle Shirtwaist Fire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kein Ausweg: Zwei New York City 
Feuerwehrmänner bezeugen über das Dreieck Shirtwaist Feuer 1911</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Aucune Sortie : Deux pompiers de New York 
City témoignent au sujet du feu 1911 de Chemisier de triangle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nenhuma Maneira Para fora: Dois firemen de 
New York City testify sobre o fogo 1911 de Shirtwaist do triângulo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nessun'Uscita: Due vigili del fuoco de New 
York City testimoniano circa il fuoco 1911 di Shirtwaist del 
triangolo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Καμία έξοδος: Δύο πυροσβέστες πόλεων της Νέας 
Υόρκης πιστοποιούν για την πυρκαγιά μπλουζών τριγώνων του 1911</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ninguna Salida: Dos bomberos de New York 
City atestiguan sobre el fuego 1911 de Shirtwaist del triángulo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">One of the greatest industrial tragedies in U.S. history occurred on March 26, 1911, when 146 workers, mostly young immigrant women, died in a fire at the Triangle Shirtwaist company in New York City. In this brief excerpt from their testimony before the Factory Investigation Commission, New York City Fire Chief Edward F. Croker and Fire Marshall William Beers commented on the safety lapses--the locking of an exit door, the inadequate fire escapes, and the overcrowded factory floor--that led to the deaths of the Triangle workers.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine der größten industriellen Tragödien in der
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Geschichte trat an März 26, 1911, als 146 
Arbeiter, meistens die jungen einwandernden Frauen auf, gestorben in 
einem Feuer bei der Dreieck Shirtwaist Firma in New York City. 
In diesem kurzen Excerpt von ihrem Zeugnis vor der 
Fabrik-Untersuchung Kommission, führten New York City Feuer 
Hauptedward F. Croker und Feuer-Marschall William, den Biere die 
Sicherheit Versehen kommentierten -- das Sperrung einer Ausgang Tür, 
der unzulänglichen Feuerentweichen und des überfüllten 
Fabrikfußbodens -- das, zu die Todesfälle der Dreieckarbeiter.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une des plus grandes tragédies industrielles dans
l'histoire des ETATS-UNIS s'est produite 26 mars 1911, quand 146 
ouvriers, la plupart du temps jeunes femmes immigrées, mortes dans un
feu à la compagnie de Chemisier de triangle à New York City. 
Dans ce bref extrait de leur témoignage devant la Commission de
recherche d'usine, le feu Edouard en chef F. Croker de New York 
City et le maréchal du feu que les bières de William ont présenté 
leurs observations sur les fautes de sûreté -- le verrouillage d'une
porte de sortie, des évasions insatisfaisantes du feu, et de l'étage
surchargé d'usine -- cela ont mené aux décès des ouvriers de 
triangle.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uma das tragédias industriais as mais grandes no 
history de ESTADOS UNIDOS ocorreu março em 26, 1911, quando 146 
trabalhadores, na maior parte mulheres immigrant novas, morridas em um
fogo na companhia de Shirtwaist do triângulo em New York City. 
Neste excerpt breve de seu testimony antes do commission da 
investigação da fábrica, o fogo Edward principal F. Croker de New 
York City e o marshall do fogo as cervejas de William que comentaram 
nos lapsos de segurança -- travar de uma porta da saída, dos escapes
inadequados do fogo, e do assoalho overcrowded da fábrica -- isso 
conduziram às mortes dos trabalhadores do triângulo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Una delle tragedie industriali più grandi nella 
storia degli STATI UNITI si è presentata il 26 marzo 1911, quando 146
operai, principalmente donne immigrate giovani, morte in un fuoco 
all'azienda di Shirtwaist del triangolo a New York City. In 
questo breve brano dalla loro testimonianza prima della Commissione di
ricerca della fabbrica, il fuoco Edward principale F. Croker de New 
York City ed il marshall del fuoco le birre del William che hanno 
commentato gli intervalli di sicurezza -- il bloccaggio di un portello
dell'uscita, delle fughe inadeguate del fuoco e del pavimento 
sovraccaricato della fabbrica -- quello hanno condotto alle morti 
degli operai del triangolo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια από τις μέγιστες βιομηχανικές τραγωδίες στην 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ ιστορία εμφανίστηκε στις 26 Μαρτίου ..1911, όταν
πέθαναν 146 εργαζόμενοι, συνήθως νέες που έχουν μεταναστεύσει
γυναίκες, σε μια πυρκαγιά στην επιχείρηση μπλουζών τριγώνων στην 
πόλη της Νέας Υόρκης. Σε αυτό το συνοπτικό απόσπασμα από 
την κατάθεσή τους προτού να τακτοποιήσουν η Επιτροπή έρευνας 
εργοστασίων, η πυρκαγιά Προϊστάμενος Edward F. Croker πόλεων
της Νέας Υόρκης και η πυρκαγιά William Beers σχολίασε τα 
σφάλματα ασφάλειας -- το κλείδωμα μιας πόρτας εξόδων, των 
ανεπαρκών εξόδων κινδύνου, και του επιβαρυνμένου πατώματος 
εργοστασίων -- που οδήγησαν στους θανάτους των εργαζομένων 
τριγώνων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una de las tragedias industriales más grandes de 
la historia de ESTADOS UNIDOS ocurrió de marcha la 26 de 1911, cuando
146 trabajadores, sobre todo mujeres inmigrantes jóvenes, muertas en 
un fuego en la compañía de Shirtwaist del triángulo en New York 
City. En este extracto abreviado de su testimonio ante la 
Comisión de la investigación de la fábrica, el fuego principal 
Edward F. Croker de New York City y el ordenar del fuego que las 
cervezas de Guillermo comentaron respecto a los lapsos de seguridad --
el bloquear de una puerta de la salida, de los escapes inadecuados del
fuego, y del suelo atestado de la fábrica -- eso condujeron a las 
muertes de los trabajadores del triángulo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086671</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108290</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/no-way-out-two-new-york-city-firemen-testify-about-the-1911-triangle-shirtwaist-fire</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
