<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105379</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105379</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086702</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Orgies of Ruthlessness": Bishop Quayle on German Atrocities During World War I</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Orgien von Ruthlessness": Bishop Quayle auf
deutschen Grausamkeiten während des Ersten Weltkrieges</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"orgies de cruauté" : Évêque Quayle sur 
les atrocités allemandes pendant la Première Guerre Mondiale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"orgies do ruthlessness": Bishop Quayle em 
atrocities alemães durante o world.war.i</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"orgies di ruthlessness": Bishop Quayle 
sulle Atrocità tedesche durante il world.war.i</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Όργια της ασπλαχνίασ": Επίσκοπος Quayle στις 
γερμανικές αγριότητες κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου Ι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"orgías de la crueldad": Obispo Quayle en 
Atrocidades alemanas durante Primera Guerra Mundial</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the early 20th century, German Americans remained the largest immigrant group, as well as one of the most highly regarded. Thus the vicious nativist attack on the loyalty of German Americans that emerged before and during World War I was particularly remarkable. When the German government began submarine warfare, resulting in American deaths, the intensity of attacks increased. Bishop William A. Quayle, a prominent Methodist clergyman, did not directly attack German Americans but insisted that America's fight was directly with the German people and not just their leaders. In an essay in the  Northwestern Christian Advocate , Quale provided lurid (and vastly exaggerated) stories of German atrocities. Such stories heightened the suspicion directed at German Americans.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im frühen 20. Jahrhundert blieben deutsche 
Amerikaner die größte einwandernde Gruppe, sowie eine von in hohem 
Grade betrachtet. So war der schändliche nativist Angriff auf 
der Loyalität der deutschen Amerikaner, denen vor und während des 
Ersten Weltkrieges auftauchte, besonders bemerkenswert. Als die 
deutsche Regierung Unterwasserkriegsführung anfing, und das 
resultiert in den amerikanischen Todesfällen, die Intensität der 
Angriffe erhöht. Bishop William A. Quayle, ein vorstehendes 
methodistisches Geistliches, nicht direkt griff an, deutsche 
Amerikaner aber beharrte, daß Kampf Amerikas direkt mit den deutschen
Leuten und nicht gerade ihren Führern war. In einem Versuch im 
nordwestlichen christlichen Fürsprecher, stellte Quale lurid (und 
übertrieb in beträchtlichem Ausmaß), Geschichten der deutschen 
Grausamkeiten zur Verfügung. Solche Geschichten erhöhten das 
Misstrauen, das an den deutschen Amerikanern verwiesen wurde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En début du 20ème siècle, les Américains 
allemands sont restés le plus grand groupe immigré, comme un de le 
plus fortement considéré. Ainsi l'attaque nativiste méchante 
sur la fidélité des Américains allemands avant lesquels a émergé 
et pendant la Première Guerre Mondiale était particulièrement 
remarquable. Quand le gouvernement allemand a commencé la 
guerre submersible, ayant pour résultat les décès américaines, 
l'intensité des attaques accrues. Évêque William A. Quayle, 
un ecclésiastique méthodiste en avant, n'a pas directement attaqué 
les Américains allemands mais a insisté sur le fait que le combat de
l'Amérique était directement avec les  allemands et pas simplement 
leurs amorces. Dans un essai dans l'avocat chrétien du 
nord-ouest, Quale a fourni (et a énormément exagéré) des histoires
sinistres des atrocités allemandes. De telles histoires ont 
intensifié le soupçon dirigé aux Américains allemands.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No 20o século adiantado, os americanos alemães 
remanesceram o grupo immigrant o maior, assim como um do considerado o
mais altamente. Assim o ataque nativist vicious na lealdade dos 
americanos alemães de que emergiu antes e durante o world.war.i era 
particularmente notável. Quando o governo alemão começou a 
guerra submarina, tendo por resultado mortes americanas, a intensidade
dos ataques aumentados. O bishop William A. Quayle, um clérigo 
methodist proeminente, não atacou diretamente americanos alemães mas
insistiu que a luta de América era diretamente com os povos alemães 
e não apenas seus líderes. Em um essay no advogado christian 
do noroeste, Quale forneceu (e exaggerated vastamente) histórias 
lurid de atrocities alemães. Tais histórias heightened a 
suspeita dirigida em americanos alemães.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nell'inizio del 20esimo secolo, gli Americani 
tedeschi sono rimasto il più grande gruppo immigrato, come pure uno 
del il più altamente considerato. Così l'attacco nativist 
vizioso alla lealtà degli Americani tedeschi di che è emerso prima e
durante il world.war.i era particolarmente notevole. Quando il 
governo tedesco ha cominciato la guerra sottomarina, con conseguente 
morti americane, l'intensità degli attacchi aumentati. Il 
bishop William A. Quayle, un sacerdote methodist prominente, 
direttamente non ha attacato gli Americani tedeschi ma ha insistito 
che la lotta dell'America era direttamente con la gente tedesca e non 
appena i loro capi. In un saggio nel fautore cristiano 
nordoccidentale, Quale ha fornito (ed ha esagerato notevolmente) le 
storia lurid delle atrocità tedesche. Tali storia hanno 
intensificato il sospetto diretto agli Americani tedeschi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στις αρχές του 20ού αιώνα, γερμανικοί Αμερικανοί 
παρέμειναν η μεγαλύτερη που έχουν μεταναστεύσει ομάδα, καθώς 
επίσης και μια από ο πιό ιδιαίτερα θεωρημένη. Κατά 
συνέπεια η κακοήθης επίθεση nativist στην πίστη γερμανικών 
Αμερικανών που προέκυψαν πριν από και κατά τη διάρκεια του 
παγκόσμιου πολέμου ήμουν ιδιαίτερα αξιοπρόσεκτος. Όταν η 
γερμανική κυβέρνηση άρχισε την υποβρύχια εχθροπραξία, με 
συνέπεια τους αμερικανικούς θανάτους, την ένταση των επιθέσεων 
αυξανόμενων. Bishop William Α. Quayle, προεξέχον 
μεθοδιστές clergyman, δεν επιτέθηκε άμεσα σε γερμανικούς 
Αμερικανούς αλλά επέμεινε ότι η πάλη της Αμερικής ήταν άμεσα 
με τους Γερμανούς και όχι μόνο τους ηγέτες τους. Σε ένα 
δοκίμιο στο βορειοδυτικό χριστιανικό συνήγορο, Quale παρείχε 
τις εντυπωσιακές (και υπερβάλλων απέραντα) ιστορίες των 
γερμανικών αγριοτήτων. Τέτοιες ιστορίες ύψωσαν την υποψία 
που κατευθύνθηκε σε γερμανικούς Αμερικανούς.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Del vigésimo siglo temprano, los americanos 
alemanes seguían siendo el grupo inmigrante más grande, tan bien 
como uno de mirado lo más altamente posible. Así el ataque 
nativista vicioso contra la lealtad de los americanos alemanes antes 
de quienes emergió y durante Primera Guerra Mundial era determinado 
notable. Cuando el gobierno alemán comenzó la guerra 
submarina, dando por resultado muertes americanas, la intensidad de 
los ataques crecientes. Obispo Guillermo A. Quayle, clérigo 
methodist prominente, no atacó directamente a americanos alemanes 
sino insistió que la lucha de América estaba directamente con la 
gente alemana y no apenas sus arranques de cinta. En un ensayo 
en el abogado cristiano del noroeste, Quale proporcionó (y exageró 
sumamente) a historias espeluznantes de atrocidades alemanas. 
Tales historias aumentaron la suspicacia dirigida en los 
americanos alemanes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086702</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105379</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/orgies-of-ruthlessness-bishop-quayle-on-german-atrocities-during-world-war-i</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
