<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108758</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108758</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206000</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Imagine the Universe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Stellen Sie sich das Universum vor</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Imaginez l'univers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Imagine o universo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Immagini l'universo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Φανταστείτε τον κόσμο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Imagine el universo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">includes lesson plans on wavelengths and frequencies, sizes of stars, gamma-ray bursts, the binary number system, the probability of life elsewhere in the universe, constructing and analyzing images from digital satellite data, measuring periodic behavior, logarithmic plotting and classification of objects by their mathematical behavior, the origin of the elements and their identification in supernova remnants, and identifying elements using spectroscopy.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">schließt Lektionpläne auf Wellenlängen und 
Frequenzen, Größen der Sterne, Gammastrahlimpulse, das Binärsystem,
die Wahrscheinlichkeit des Lebens anderwohin im Universum ein und 
konstruiert und analysiert Bilder von den digitalen Satellitendaten, 
messendes periodisches Verhalten, logarithmisches Plotten und 
Klassifikation der Nachrichten durch ihr mathematisches Verhalten, der
Ursprung der Elemente und ihr Kennzeichen in den Supernovaresten und 
Kennzeichnen der Elemente mit Spektroskopie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">inclut des plans de leçon sur des longueurs 
d'onde et les fréquences, tailles de tient le premier rôle, des éclats de 
rayons gamma, le système de numération binaire, la probabilité de 
la vie ailleurs dans l'univers, construisant et analysant des images 
des données satellites digitales, comportement périodique de mesure,
traçage et classification logarithmique des objets par leur 
comportement mathématique, l'origine des éléments et leur 
identification dans des restes de supernova, et identification des 
éléments en utilisant la spectroscopie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">inclui plantas da lição em wavelengths e 
freqüências, tamanhos das estrelas, estouros do gamma-ray, o sistema
de número binário, a probabilidade da vida em outra parte no 
universo, construindo e analisando imagens dos dados satellite 
digitais, comportamento periódico de medição, traçar e 
classificação logarítmica dos objetos por seu comportamento 
matemático, a origem dos elementos e sua identificação em restos do
supernova, e identificar elementos usando o spectroscopy.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">include i programmi di lezione sulle lunghezze 
d'onda e frequenze, i formati delle stelle, i bursts dei raggi gamma, 
il sistema di numero binario, la probabilità di vita altrove 
nell'universo, costruente ed analizzante le immagini dai dati 
satelliti digitali, comportamento periodico di misurazione, tracciato 
e classificazione logaritmica degli oggetti tramite il loro 
comportamento matematico, l'origine degli elementi e la loro 
identificazione nei resti del supernova ed identificare gli elementi 
usando la spettroscopia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">περιλαμβάνει τα σχέδια μαθήματος για τα μήκη κύματος 
και τις συχνότητες, μεγέθη των αστεριών, gamma-ray εκρήξεις, το
σύστημα δυαδικού αριθμού, η πιθανότητα της ζωής αλλού στον 
κόσμο, που κατασκευάζουν και που αναλύουν τις εικόνες από τα 
ψηφιακά δορυφορικά στοιχεία, που μετρούν την περιοδική 
συμπεριφορά, τη λογαριθμική χάραξη και την ταξινόμηση των 
αντικειμένων από τη μαθηματική συμπεριφορά τους, την προέλευση 
των στοιχείων και του προσδιορισμού τους στα υπόλοιπα σουπερνοβών,
και τον προσδιορισμό των στοιχείων χρησιμοποιώντας τη 
φασματοσκοπία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">incluye planes de la lección en longitudes de 
onda y las frecuencias, tallas de estrellas, explosiones del rayo 
gama, el sistema de número binario, la probabilidad de la vida a otra
parte en el universo, construyendo y analizando imágenes de datos 
basados en los satélites digitales, comportamiento periódico que 
mide, el trazar y clasificación logarítmica de objetos por su 
comportamiento matemático, el origen de los elementos y su 
identificación en remanente de la supernova, e identificar elementos 
usando la espectroscopia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206000</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108758</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/imagine-the-universe</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
