<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102915</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102915</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205742</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Florida Folklife from the WPS Collections, 1937-1942</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Florida Folklife von den WPS Ansammlungen, 
1937-1942</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Floride Folklife des collections de WPS, 
1937-1942</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Florida Folklife das coleções de WPS, 1937-1942</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Florida Folklife dalle collezioni di WPS, 
1937-1942</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Φλώριδα Folklife από τις WPS συλλογές, 
1937-1942</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Florida Folklife de las colecciones de WPS, 
1937-1942</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a multi-format ethnographic field collection documenting African-American, Arabic, Bahamian, British-American, Cuban, Greek, Italian, Minorcan, Seminole, and Slavic cultures throughout Florida during the New Deal era. It features folksongs and folktales, including blues and work songs from menhaden fishing boats, railroad gangs, and turpentine camps; children's songs, dance music, and religious music; and interviews.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist ein ethnographisches Multiformat 
auffangen Ansammlung die Afrikanisch-Amerikanische, 
arabische, Bahamian, Britisch-Amerikanische, kubanische, griechische, 
italienische, Minorcan, Seminole- und Slavickulturen Dokumentierens in
Florida während der Ära des neuen Abkommens. Es kennzeichnet 
folksongs und folktales, einschließlich Blau und Arbeit Liede von 
Fischerbooten des Menhadens, von den Eisenbahngruppen und von den 
Terpentinlagern; Liede der Kinder, Tanzmusik und fromme Musik; 
und Interviews.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est une collection ethnographique de zone de 
multi-format documentant l'Afro-Américain, l'arabe, le Bahamien, 
Britannique-Américain, cubain, grec, italien, Minorcan, seminole, et 
cultures slaves dans l'ensemble de la Floride pendant l'ère de
nouvelle affaire. Elle comporte des folksongs et des folktales, 
y compris des bleus et des chansons de travail des bateaux de pêche 
de menhaden, des troupes de chemin de fer, et des camps de 
térébenthine ; les chansons des enfants, la musique de danse, 
et la musique religieuse ; et entrevues.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">são as culturas documentar ethnographic da 
coleção do campo do multi-formato Africano-Americanas, árabes, de 
Bahamian, Britânico-Americanas, cuban, gregas, italianas, de 
Minorcan, de seminole, e de Slavic durante todo Florida durante a era 
do negócio novo. Caracteriza folksongs e folktales, including 
azuis e canções do trabalho dos barcos pescando da savelha, dos 
grupos da estrada de ferro, e dos acampamentos do turpentine; 
canções das crianças, música de dança, e música religiosa;
e entrevistas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è le colture Africano-Americane, delle arabe, di 
Bahamian, Britannico-Americane, cuban, greche, italiane, di Minorcan, 
del seminole e di Slavic di multi-formato del campo di documentazione 
ethnographic dell'accumulazione durante Florida durante l'era di nuovo
affare. Caratterizza i folksongs ed i folktales, compreso gli 
azzurri e le canzoni del lavoro dai pescherecci del pesce dei 
clupeidi, dai gruppi della ferrovia e dagli accampamenti della 
trementina; canzoni dei bambini, musica di ballo e musica 
religiosa; ed interviste.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι μια εθνογραφική συλλογή πεδίων πολυ-μορφής 
τεκμηριώνοντας αφρικανικός-Αμερικανό, Αραβικά, Μπαχάμιο, 
βρετανικός-Αμερικανό, Κουβανό, ελληνικά, ιταλικά, minorcan, 
Seminole, και τους σλαβικούς πολιτισμούς σε όλη τη Φλώριδα 
κατά τη διάρκεια της νέας εποχής διαπραγμάτευσης. 
Χαρακτηρίζει folksongs και folktales, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένων των μπλε και των τραγουδιών εργασίας από 
menhaden τα αλιευτικά σκάφη, των συμμοριών σιδηροδρόμου, και 
των στρατόπεδων τερεβινθίνης  τραγούδια παιδιών, μουσική 
χορού, και θρησκευτική μουσική  και συνεντεύξεις.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">son las culturas Africano-Americanas, árabes, de 
Bahamian, Brita'nico-Americanas, cubanos, griegas, italianas, de 
Minorcan, del seminole, y de Slavic del multi-formato del campo de una
documentación etnográfica de la colección a través de la Florida 
durante la era del nuevo reparto. Ofrece folksongs y folktales, 
incluyendo azul y canciones del trabajo de los barcos de pesca del 
menhaden, de las cuadrillas del ferrocarril, y de los campos de la 
trementina; canciones de los niños, música de danza, y música
religiosa; y entrevistas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205742</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102915</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/florida-folklife-from-the-wps-collections-1937-1942</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
