<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107310</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107310</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087014</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Origins of Puerto Rican Migration: U.S. Employment Service Bulletin (1918)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Ursprung Puerto Rican der Migration: 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Beschäftigung-Dienstbericht (1918)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les origines du transfert de Puerto Rican : 
Bulletin de Service d'Emploi des ETATS-UNIS (1918)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As origens da migração de Puerto Rican: 
Boletim De Serviço Do Emprego de ESTADOS UNIDOS (1918)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le origini di espansione di Puerto Rican: 
Bollettino Di Servizio Di Occupazione degli STATI UNITI (1918)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η προέλευση της μετανάστευσης Puerto Rican: 
Δελτίο υπηρεσιών ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ απασχόλησης (1918)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los orígenes de la migración de Puerto Rican: 
Boletín De Servicio Del Empleo de ESTADOS UNIDOS (1918)</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1898 the United States acquired Puerto Rico, a Caribbean island 1,000 miles southeast of Miami, after victory in the Spanish-Cuban-American War. After an initial military occupation, the United States granted Puerto Rico limited local autonomy. In 1917, the U.S. responded to local pressure for independence by declaring Puerto Ricans citizens of the United States--a "gift" that many Puerto Ricans resented. Large, corporate-financed sugar plantations transformed Puerto Rico's agricultural economy and displaced thousands of subsistence farmers from their own land, forcing them into the rural wage labor force. These dramatic changes in the rural economy in the years before World War I pushed unemployment levels in Puerto Rico to crisis proportions. At the same time, American entry into the war created labor shortages in many industries on the mainland. This Labor Department bulletin from May 1918 set out plans for bringing more than 10,000 Puerto Rican laborers to the U.S. to work on war-related projects.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In 1898 die Vereinigten Staaten erworbenes Puerto 
Rico, eine karibische Insel 1.000 Meilen Südosten von Miami, nach 
Sieg im Spanisch-Kubaner-Amerikanischen Krieg. Nach einer 
militärischen zuerstbesetzung bewilligten die Vereinigten Staaten 
Puerto Rico begrenzte lokale Autonomie. 1917 reagierten die 
VEREINIGTEN STAATEN auf lokalen Druck für Unabhängigkeit, indem sie 
Puerto Ricans Bürger der Vereinigten Staaten -- ein "Geschenk" 
erklärten, das viel Puerto Ricans übelnahm. Großen, 
korporativ-finanzierten Zuckerplantagen umgewandelten Puertos Rico 
landwirtschaftliche Wirtschaft und verlegte Tausenden 
Erwerbsmittellandwirte von ihrem eigenen Land, sie in die 
Arbeitskräfte des landwirtschaftlichen Lohnes erzwingend. Diese
drastischen Änderungen in der Agrarwirtschaft in den Jahren vor dem 
Ersten Weltkrieg drückten Arbeitslosigkeit Stufen in Puerto Rico zu 
den Krise Anteilen. Gleichzeitig erstellte amerikanischer 
Eintrag in den Krieg Mangel an Arbeitskräften in vielen Industrien 
auf dem Festland. Diese Arbeitsabteilung Nachricht von einem Mai
1918 legte Pläne für das Holen von von mehr als 10.000 Puerto Rican 
Arbeitern in die VEREINIGTEN STAATEN, auf Krieg-in Verbindung 
stehenden Projekten zu arbeiten dar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans 1898 les Etats-Unis le Porto Rico saisi, une 
île des Caraïbes 1.000 milles de sud-est de Miami, après victoire 
dans la guerre Espagnol-Cubain-Américaine. Après un premier 
métier militaire, les Etats-Unis ont accordé le Porto Rico autonomie
locale limitée. En 1917, les ETATS-UNIS ont répondu à la 
pression locale pour l'indépendance en déclarant des citoyens de 
Puerto Ricans des Etats-Unis -- un "cadeau" que beaucoup de Puerto 
Ricans était offensé par. L'économie agricole et les milliers
déplacés du grand, de corporation-financé Porto Rico transformé 
par plantations de sucre de fermiers de subsistance de leur propre 
terre, les forçant dans la main-d'oeuvre de salaire rural. Ces 
changements excessifs de l'économie rurale en années avant la 
Première Guerre Mondiale ont poussé des niveaux du chômage au Porto
Rico aux proportions de crise. En même temps, l'entrée 
américaine dans la guerre a créé les pénuries de la main-d'oeuvre 
dans beaucoup d'industries sur le continent. Ce bulletin de 
travail de service à partir de mai 1918 a visé des plans pour 
apporter plus de 10.000 travailleurs de Puerto Rican aux ETATS-UNIS 
travailler sur des projets guerre-connexes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1898 os estados unidos adquiriram Puerto Rico, 
um console do Cararibe 1.000 milhas de sudeste de Miami, após a 
vitória na guerra Espanhol-Cubano-Americana. Após uma 
ocupação militar inicial, os estados unidos concederam Puerto Rico 
autonomia local limitada. Em 1917, os ESTADOS UNIDOS responderam
à pressão local para a independência declarando cidadãos de Puerto
Ricans dos estados unidos -- um "presente" por que muito Puerto Ricans
se ressentisse. Economia agricultural de Puerto Rico 
transformado plantações grande, incorporado-financiado do açúcar e
milhares deslocados de fazendeiros do subsistence de sua própria 
terra, forçando os na força labor do salário rural. Estas 
mudanças dramáticas na economia rural nos anos antes do world.war.i 
empurraram níveis do desemprego em Puerto Rico para proporções da 
crise. Ao mesmo tempo, a entrada americana na guerra criou 
faltas labor em muitas indústrias no mainland. Este boletim 
labor do departamento de maio 1918 ajustado para fora das plantas para
trazer mais de 10.000 laborers de Puerto Rican aos ESTADOS UNIDOS 
trabalhar em projetos guerra-relacionados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1898 uniti Dichiara il Porto Rico 
acquistato, un'isola caraibica 1.000 miglio di sud-est di Miami, dopo 
la vittoria nella guerra Spagnolo-Cubano-Americana. Dopo 
un'occupazione militare iniziale, unito Dichiara il Porto Rico 
assegnato autonomia locale limitata. In 1917, gli STATI UNITI 
hanno risposto a pressione locale per indipendenza dichiarando i 
cittadini di Puerto Ricans del unito Dichiarano -- il a "regalo" 
di che molto Puerto Ricans si è risentito. Economia agricola e 
migliaia spostati del grande, Porto Rico trasformato piantagioni 
corporativo-finanziato dello zucchero dei coltivatori di sussistenza 
dalla loro propria terra, forzante li nella forza rurale di 
lavoro dello stipendio. Questi cambiamenti drammatici 
nell'economia rurale durante gli anni prima del world.war.i hanno 
spinto i livelli di disoccupazione nel Porto Rico nelle proporzioni di
crisi. Allo stesso tempo, l'entrata americana nella guerra ha 
creato le scarsità di lavoro in molte industrie sul continente. 
Questo bollettino Di lavoro di reparto da maggio 1918 ha 
precisato i programmi per portare più di 10.000 lavoratori di Puerto 
Rican negli STATI UNITI lavorare ai progetti guerra-relativi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1898 το επίκτητο οι Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες Πουέρτο 
Ρίκο, ένα καραϊβικό νησί 1.000 μίλια νοτιοανατολικά του 
Μαϊάμι, μετά από νίκη στον ισπανικός-κουβανικός-αμερικανικό 
πόλεμο. Μετά από ένα αρχικό στρατιωτικό επάγγελμα, οι 
Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες που χορηγούνται το Πουέρτο Ρίκο την 
περιορισμένη τοπική αυτονομία. Το 1917, οι ΗΠΑ 
αποκρίθηκαν στην τοπική πίεση για την ανεξαρτησία με τη δήλωση 
πολίτης Puerto Ricans των Ηνωμένων Πολιτειών -- ένα "δώρο" 
που πολύ Puerto Ricans αγανάκτησε με. Οι μεγάλες, 
εταιρικός-χρηματοδοτημένες φυτείες ζάχαρης μετασχημάτισαν τη 
γεωργική οικονομία του Πουέρτο Ρίκο και μετατόπισαν χιλιάδες 
αγρότες επιβίωσης από το έδαφός τους, που αναγκάζουν τους στο 
αγροτικό εργατικό δυναμικό αμοιβών. Αυτές οι δραματικές 
αλλαγές στην αγροτική οικονομία στα έτη πριν από τον παγκόσμιο 
πόλεμο ώθησα τα επίπεδα ανεργίας στο Πουέρτο Ρίκο στις 
αναλογίες κρίσης. Συγχρόνως, η αμερικανική είσοδος μέσα σε
τον πόλεμο δημιούργησε τις ελλείψεις εργασίας σε πολλές 
βιομηχανίες στην ηπειρωτική χώρα. Αυτό το δελτίο τμήματος 
εργασίας από Μάιος το 1918 καθόρισε τα σχέδια για να 
φέρει περισσότερα από 10.000 laborers Puerto Rican στις
ΗΠΑ για να εργαστεί στα πόλεμος-σχετικά με την προγράμματα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1898 los Estados Unidos Puerto Rico adquirido, 
una isla del Caribe 1.000 millas de sureste de Miami, después de la 
victoria en la guerra Español-Cubano-Americana. Después de una
ocupación militar inicial, los Estados Unidos concedieron Puerto Rico
autonomía local limitada. En 1917, los ESTADOS UNIDOS 
respondieron a la presión local para la independencia declarando a 
ciudadanos de Puerto Ricans de los Estados Unidos -- un "regalo" que 
mucho Puerto Ricans se resentía. Economía agrícola y millares
desplazados de Puerto Rico transformado plantaciones grande, 
corporativo-financiado del azúcar de granjeros de la subsistencia de 
su propia pista, forzándolos en la mano de obra rural del salario. 
Estos cambios dramáticos en la economía rural en los años 
antes de la Primera Guerra Mundial empujaron niveles del desempleo en 
Puerto Rico a las proporciones de la crisis. En el mismo tiempo,
la entrada americana en la guerra creó escaseces de trabajo en muchas
industrias en el continente. Este boletín de trabajo del 
departamento a partir de mayo 1918 precisó los planes para traer a 
más de 10.000 trabajadores de Puerto Rican a los ESTADOS UNIDOS 
trabajar en proyectos guerra-relacionados.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087014</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107310</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-origins-of-puerto-rican-migration-u-s-employment-service-bulletin-1918</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
