<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104349</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104349</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212861</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Transforming the Future of Flight</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Umwandeln der Zukunft des Fluges</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Transformation du futur du vol</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Transformando o futuro do vôo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Trasformazione del futuro del volo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μετασχηματισμός του μέλλοντος της πτήσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Transformar el futuro del vuelo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this video segment adapted from NASA, learn how engineers are transforming the future of flight by designing airplanes based on principles found in nature. In the early 1900s, the Wright Brothers found inspiration for their first airplane in nature. Their "Flyer," which was modeled on a bird's flexible wing design, was steered and stabilized by pulleys and cables that twisted the wingtips. Despite its success, this control strategy quickly vanished from aviation. Instead, stiff wings capable of withstanding the greater forces associated with increased aircraft weights and flying speeds became the standard. In this video segment adapted from NASA, learn how designs found in nature have inspired today's aerospace engineers as they conceive the next-generation of flying machines. Grades 3-12.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In diesem Bildschirm paßte sich Segment von der 
NASA, erlernen an, wie Ingenieure die Zukunft des Fluges umwandeln, 
indem sie die Flugzeuge konzipieren, die auf den Grundregeln basieren,
die in der Natur gefunden werden. In den frühen 1900s fanden 
die Wright Brüder Inspiration für ihr erstes Flugzeug in der Natur. 
Ihr "Flieger,", der auf flexiblem Flügeldesign eines Vogels 
geformt wurde gesteuert und stabilisiert wurde, durch Riemenscheiben 
und Kabel, die die Flügelspitzen verdrehten. Trotz seines 
Erfolges verschwand diese Steuerstrategie schnell von der Luftfahrt. 
Stattdessen verbanden die steifen Flügel, die zum Widerstehen 
der grösseren Kräfte fähig sind, mit erhöhten Flugzeuggewichten 
und fliegende Geschwindigkeiten wurden der Standard. In diesem 
Bildschirm paßte sich Segment von der NASA, erlernen an, wie Designs 
in der Natur haben angespornt heutige Luftfahrtingenieure fanden, wie 
sie das zukünftige der Fliegenmaschinen begreifen. Grade 3-12.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans ce vidéo le segment s'est adapté de la 
NASA, apprennent comment les ingénieurs transforment le futur du vol 
en concevant des avions basés sur des principes trouvés en nature. 
Au début des années 1900, les frères de Wright ont trouvé 
l'inspiration pour leur premier avion en nature. Leur "insecte,"
qui a été modelé sur la conception flexible de l'aile d'un oiseau, 
a été orienté et stabilisé par les poulies et les câbles qui ont 
tordu les saumons d'aile. En dépit de son succès, cette 
stratégie de commande a rapidement disparu de l'aviation. Au 
lieu de cela, les ailes raides capables de résister aux forces plus 
grandes se sont associées aux masses avion accrues et les vitesses 
volantes sont devenues la norme. Dans ce vidéo le segment s'est
adapté de la NASA, apprennent comment les conceptions ont trouvé en 
nature ont inspiré les ingénieurs aérospatiaux d'aujourd'hui comme 
elles conçoivent le de la deuxième génération des machines de vol.
Catégories 3-12.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Neste vídeo o segmento adaptou-se da NASA, 
aprende como os coordenadores estão transformando o futuro do vôo 
projetando os aviões baseados nos princípios encontrados na 
natureza. Nos 1900s adiantados, os irmãos de Wright encontraram
a inspiração para seu primeiro avião na natureza. Seu 
"insecto," que foi modelado no projeto flexível da asa de um 
pássaro, dirigido e estabilizado pelas polias e pelos cabos que 
torceram os wingtips. Apesar de seu sucesso, esta estratégia do
controle desapareceu rapidamente da aviação. Instead, as asas 
duras capazes de suportar as forças mais grandes associaram com os 
pesos de avião aumentados e as velocidades voando transformaram-se o 
padrão. Neste vídeo o segmento adaptou-se da NASA, aprende 
como os projetos encontraram na natureza inspiraram coordenadores 
aeroespaciais de hoje como conceive o next-generation de máquinas do 
vôo. Classes 3-12.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questo video segmento si è adattato dalla 
NASA, impara come gli assistenti tecnici stanno trasformando il futuro
del volo progettando gli aeroplani basati per principii trovati in 
natura. All'inizio degli anni 1900, i fratelli di Wright hanno 
trovato l'ispirazione per il loro primo aeroplano in natura. La 
loro "aletta di filatoio," che è stata modellata sul disegno 
flessibile dell'ala dell'uccello, è stata diretta e stabilizzato 
stata dalle pulegge e dai cavi che hanno torto i wingtips. 
Malgrado il relativo successo, questa strategia di controllo ha 
sparito rapidamente da aeronautica. Invece, le ale rigide capaci
di sostenere le forze più grandi si sono associate con i pesi di 
velivolo aumentati e le velocità di volata si sono transformate in 
nello standard. In questo video segmento si è adattato dalla 
NASA, impara come i disegni hanno trovato in natura hanno ispirato gli
odierni assistenti tecnici aerospaziali come concepiscono il 
next-generation delle macchine di volo. Gradi 3-12.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτό το τηλεοπτικό τμήμα μνήμης που προσαρμόζεται 
από τη NASA, μάθετε πώς οι μηχανικοί μετασχηματίζουν το 
μέλλον της πτήσης με το σχεδιασμό των αεροπλάνων βασισμένων στις 
αρχές που βρίσκονται στη φύση. Στις αρχές των δεκαετιών του
20ου αιώνα, οι αδελφοί Wright βρήκαν την έμπνευση για το πρώτο
αεροπλάνο τους στη φύση. "Το ιπτάμενό τους," που 
διαμορφώθηκε σύμφωνα με το εύκαμπτο σχέδιο φτερών ενός πουλιού,
οδηγήθηκε και σταθεροποιήθηκε από τις τροχαλίες και τα καλώδια 
που έστριψαν τα wingtips. Παρά την επιτυχία της, αυτή η 
στρατηγική ελέγχου εξαφανίστηκε γρήγορα από την αεροπορία. 
Αντ' αυτού, τα δύσκαμπτα φτερά ικανά τις μεγαλύτερες 
δυνάμεις που συνδέθηκαν με τα αυξανόμενες βάρη αεροσκαφών και τις
ταχύτητες πετάγματος έγιναν τα πρότυπα. Σε αυτό το 
τηλεοπτικό τμήμα μνήμης που προσαρμόζεται από τη NASA, μάθετε
πώς τα σχέδια που βρίσκονται στη φύση έχουν εμπνεύσει τους 
σημερινούς αεροδιαστημικούς μηχανικούς δεδομένου ότι 
συλλαμβάνουν την επόμενος-παραγωγή των πετώντας μηχανών. 
Βαθμοί 3-12.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En este vídeo el segmento se adaptó de la NASA, 
aprende cómo los ingenieros están transformando el futuro del vuelo 
diseñando los aeroplanos basados en los principios encontrados en 
naturaleza. En los 1900s tempranos, los hermanos de Wright 
encontraron la inspiración para su primer aeroplano en naturaleza. 
Su "aviador," que fue modelado en el diseño flexible del ala de
un pájaro, dirigido y estabilizado por las poleas y los cables que 
torcieron los extremos del ala. A pesar de su éxito, esta 
estrategia del control desapareció rápidamente de la aviación. 
En lugar, las alas derechas capaces de soportar las mayores 
fuerzas se asociaron a los pesos de avión crecientes y las 
velocidades que volaban se convirtieron en el estándar. En este
vídeo el segmento se adaptó de la NASA, aprende cómo los diseños 
encontraron en naturaleza han inspirado a ingenieros aeroespaciales de
hoy como conciben el next-generation de las máquinas del vuelo. 
Grados 3-12.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:WGBH EDUCATIONAL FOUNDATION
FN:WGBH EDUCATIONAL FOUNDATION
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212861</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104349</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/transforming-the-future-of-flight</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
