<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106698</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106698</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087444</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Booker T. Washington Delivers the 1895 Atlanta Compromise Speech</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Booker T. Washington liefert die Atlanta 
Kompromiss-Rede 1895</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Booker T. Washington fournit le discours 1895 de 
compromis d'Atlanta</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Booker T. Washington entrega o discurso 1895 do 
acordo de Atlanta</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Booker T. Washington trasporta il discorso 1895 di
compromesso de Atlanta</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Booker Τ. Ουάσιγκτον παραδίδει την ομιλία 
συμβιβασμού 1895 Ατλάντα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Booker T. Washington entrega el discurso 1895 del 
compromiso de Atlanta</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">On September 18, 1895, African-American spokesman and leader Booker T. Washington spoke before a predominantly white audience at the Cotton States and International Exposition in Atlanta. His "Atlanta Compromise" address, as it came to be called, was one of the most important and influential speeches in American history. Although the organizers of the exposition worried that "public sentiment was not prepared for such an advanced step," they decided that inviting a black speaker would impress Northern visitors with the evidence of racial progress in the South. Washington soothed his listeners' concerns about "uppity" blacks by claiming that his race would content itself with living "by the productions of our hands."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Auf September 18, 1895, Afrikanisch-Amerikanischem
Wortführer und Führer Booker T. Washington Speiche vor einem 
überwiegend weißen Publikum an den Baumwollzuständen und 
internationaler Ausstellung in Atlanta. Seine "Atlanta 
Kompromiß" Adresse, da sie kam benannt zu werden, war eine der 
wichtigsten und einflußreichsten Reden in der amerikanischen 
Geschichte. Obgleich die Organisatoren der Ausstellung sich 
sorgten, daß "allgemeines Gefühl nicht für solch einen 
hochentwickelten Jobstep vorbereitet wurde," entschieden sie, daß dem
das Einladen eines schwarzen Lautsprechers Nordbesucher mit dem Beweis
des rassischen Fortschritts im Süden beeindrucken würde. 
Washington beruhigte Interessen seiner Zuhörer über "uppity" 
Schwarze, indem es behauptete, daß sein Rennen würde sich 
zufriedenstellen mit dem Leben "durch die Produktionen unserer 
Hände."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">18 septembre 1895, porte-parole afro-américain et 
rai de Booker T. Washington du Chef devant une assistance 
principalement blanche aux états de coton et exposition 
internationale à Atlanta. Sa adresse "de compromis d'Atlanta", 
car elle est venue pour s'appeler, était l'un des discours les plus 
importants et les plus influents dans l'histoire américaine. 
Bien que les organisateurs de l'exposition se soient inquiétés
que "le sentiment public n'ait pas été préparé pour une étape si 
avançée," ils ont décidé que cela l'invitation d'un haut-parleur 
noir impressionnerait les visiteurs nordiques avec l'évidence du 
progrès racial dans les Sud. Washington a apaisé les 
soucis de ses auditeurs concernant des noirs d'"uppity" en réclamant 
que sa course se contenterait avec la vie "à côté des productions 
de nos mains."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Setembro em 18, 1895, no spokesman e no raio 
Africano-Americano de Booker T. Washington do líder antes de uma 
audiência predominantly branca nos estados do algodão e na 
exposição internacional em Atlanta. Seu de "endereço do 
acordo Atlanta", porque veio ser chamado, era um dos discursos os mais
importantes e os mais influential no history americano. Embora 
os organizers da exposição se preocupassem que "o sentiment público
não estêve preparado para uma etapa tão avançada," decidiram-se 
que isso convidar um altofalante preto imprimiria visitantes do norte 
com a evidência do progresso racial no sul. Washington soothed 
interesses dos seus ouvintes sobre pretos do "uppity" reivindicando 
que sua raça se satisfaria com viver "pelas produções de nossas 
mãos."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il 18 settembre 1895, il portavoce 
Africano-Americano e lo spoke di Booker T. Washington del capo 
prima che un pubblico principalmente bianco al cotone Dichiari
ed esposizione internazionale a Atlanta. Il suo "indirizzo di 
compromesso de Atlanta", poichè è venuto essere chiamato, era uno 
dei discorsi più importanti e più influenti nella storia americana. 
Anche se gli organizzatori dell'esposizione si sono preoccupati 
che "il sentimento pubblico non è stato preparato per così punto 
avanzato," hanno deciso che quello invitare un altoparlante nero 
impressionerebbe gli ospiti nordici con la prova di progresso razziale
nel sud. Washington soothed le preoccupazioni dei suoi 
ascoltatori circa i neri "di uppity" sostenendo che la sua corsa si 
soddisfarebbe con vivere "dalle produzioni delle nostre mani."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στις 18 Σεπτεμβρίου ..1895, τον 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικούς εκπρόσωπο και τον ηγέτη Booker Τ. 
Ουάσιγκτον μίλησε πριν από ένα κυρίως άσπρο ακροατήριο στα 
κράτη βαμβακιού και τη διεθνή έκθεση στην Ατλάντα. Η 
διεύθυνση "συμβιβασμού της Ατλάντας του", καθώς ήρθε να κληθεί, 
ήταν μια από τις σημαντικότερες και επιδρούσες ομιλίες στην 
αμερικανική ιστορία. Αν και οι διοργανωτές της έκθεσης 
ανησύχησαν ότι το "δημόσιο συναίσθημα δεν προετοιμάστηκε για ένα
τέτοιο προηγμένο βήμα," αποφάσισαν ότι η πρόσκληση ενός μαύρου
ομιλητή θα εντυπωσίαζε τους βόρειους επισκέπτες με τα στοιχεία 
της φυλετικής προόδου στο νότο. Η Ουάσιγκτον ανησυχίες των 
ακροατών του "για τους Μαύρουσ" uppity "με τον ισχυρισμό ότι η 
φυλή του θα ικανοποιούταν με τη διαβίωση" από τις παραγωγές των 
χεριών μας."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">18 de septiembre de 1895, el portavoz y el rayo
Africano-Americano de Booker T. Washington del arranque de cinta ante 
una audiencia predominante blanca en los estados del algodón y la 
exposición internacional en Atlanta. Su "direccionamiento del 
compromiso de Atlanta", pues vino ser llamado, era uno de los 
discursos más importantes y más influyentes de la historia 
americana. Aunque los organizadores de la exposición se 
preocuparon que el "sentimiento público no fue preparado para un paso
de progresión tan avanzado," decidían que eso la invitación de un 
altavoz negro impresionaría a visitantes norteños con la evidencia 
del progreso racial en el sur. Washington calmó las 
preocupaciones de sus módulos de escucha por negros del "uppity" 
demandando que su raza se contentaría con vivir "por las producciones
de nuestras manos."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087444</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106698</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/booker-t-washington-delivers-the-1895-atlanta-compromise-speech</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
