<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105331</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105331</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201290</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Disaster Dynamics</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Unfall-Dynamik</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dynamique de Désastre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Dinâmica Do Disastre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dynamics Di Disastro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δυναμική καταστροφής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Dinámica Del Desastre</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Disaster Dynamics project is a learning environment for the study of the unique challenges surrounding natural disasters. By focusing on dynamics, this project emphasizes the complex and emergent interplay between different aspects of the design activities and the extreme event. The website has several educational role-playing simulation games such as decision making under uncertainty, complex systems and emergent properties, understanding design decisions and fostering collaborations.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Unfall-Dynamikprojekt ist eine 
erlernenumgebung für die Studie der eindeutigen Herausforderungen, 
die Naturkatastrophen umgeben. Indem es auf Dynamik 
konzentriert, hebt dieses Projekt die komplizierte und emergent 
Wechselwirkung zwischen unterschiedlichen Aspekten der Entwurfsphasen 
und dem extremen Fall hervor. Die Web site hat einige 
pädagogische Rolle spielende Simulation Spiele wie Beschlußfassung 
unter Ungewißheit, komplexen Systemen und emergent Eigenschaften, 
verstehende Designentscheidungen und Fördern collaborations.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le projet de dynamique de désastre est un 
environnement d'étude pour l'étude des seuls défis entourant des 
désastres normaux. En se concentrant sur la dynamique, ce 
projet souligne l'effet complexe et émergent entre différents 
aspects des activités de conception et l'événement extrême. 
Le site Web a plusieurs jeux jouants un rôle éducatifs de 
simulation tels que la prise de décision sous l'incertitude, les 
systèmes complexes et les propriétés émergentes, décisions de 
conception d'arrangement et des collaborations de stimulation.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O projeto da dinâmica do disastre é um ambiente 
de aprendizagem para o estudo dos desafios originais que cercam 
disastres naturais. Focalizando na dinâmica, este projeto 
emfatiza o interplay complexo e emergent entre aspectos diferentes das
atividades de projeto e o evento extremo. O Web site tem 
diversos jogos role-playing educacionais da simulação tais como 
fazer de decisão sob a incerteza, sistemas complexos e propriedades 
emergent, decisões compreensivas do projeto e collaborations 
promover.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il progetto di dynamics di disastro è un ambiente
imparante per lo studio sulle sfide uniche che circondano i disastri 
naturali. Mettendo a fuoco sul dynamics, questo progetto dà 
risalto all'interazione complessa ed emergente fra le funzioni 
differenti delle attività di disegno e l'evento estremo. Il Web
site ha parecchi giochi d'atteggiamento educativi di simulazione quale
risoluzione sotto incertezza, i sistemi complessi e le proprietà 
emergenti, decisioni capenti di disegno e collaborations di 
promozione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το πρόγραμμα δυναμικής καταστροφής είναι ένα 
μαθησιακό περιβάλλον για τη μελέτη των μοναδικών προκλήσεων που 
περιβάλλουν τις φυσικές καταστροφές. Με την εστίαση στη 
δυναμική, αυτό το πρόγραμμα υπογραμμίζει τη σύνθετη και 
προκύπτουσα αλληλεπίδραση μεταξύ των διαφορετικών πτυχών των 
δραστηριοτήτων σχεδίου και του ακραίου γεγονότος. Ο 
ιστοχώρος έχει διάφορα εκπαιδευτικά ρόλος-παίζοντας παιχνίδια 
προσομοίωσης όπως η λήψη απόφασης στο πλαίσιο της αβεβαιότητας, 
των σύνθετων συστημάτων και των προκυπτουσών ιδιοτήτων, που 
καταλαβαίνουν τις αποφάσεις σχεδίου και που ενθαρρύνουν τις 
συνεργασίες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El proyecto de la dinámica del desastre es un 
ambiente que aprende para el estudio de los desafíos únicos que 
rodean desastres naturales. Centrándose en dinámica, este 
proyecto acentúa la interacción compleja e inesperada entre diversos
aspectos de las actividades de diseño y el acontecimiento extremo. 
El Web site tiene varios juegos de actuación de papeles 
educativos de la simulación tales como toma de decisión bajo la 
incertidumbre, los sistemas complejos y características inesperadas, 
decisiones del diseño que entienden y los collaborations el fomentar.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ERIC SCHARFF
FN:ERIC SCHARFF
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:SETH MCGINNIS
FN:SETH MCGINNIS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201290</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105331</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/disaster-dynamics</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
