<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103161</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103161</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974099</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Indigenous Peoples</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eingeborene Völker</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Peuple Autochtone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Povos Indígenos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gente Indigena</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γηγενείς λαοί</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Gente Indígena</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Five teaching units focus on nonviolence, respect for human rights and dignity, social justice and civic responsibility, global awareness, and environmental sustainability. This site has been designed to help students and educators celebrate the International Day of the World's Indigenous People through active learning. The learning activities presented in each section are student-centered. They are designed as informal, participatory exercises or suggestions for students to take further action. With a little teacher ingenuity, however, these activities could easily be adapted as formal lesson plans.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Fünf unterrichtender Maßeinheiten Fokus auf 
Gewaltlosigkeiten, Respekt für menschliche Rechte und Würde, 
Sozialgerechtigkeit und bürgerliche Verantwortlichkeit, globales 
Bewußtsein und Klimasustainability. Diese Site ist konzipiert 
worden, um Kursteilnehmern und Erziehern zu helfen, den 
internationalen Tag der eingeborenen Völker der Welt durch das aktive
Lernen zu feiern. Die Lernenaktivitäten, die in jedem Kapitel 
dargestellt werden, werden Kursteilnehmer-zentriert. Sie sind 
als formlose, teilnehmende Übungen oder Vorschläge konzipiert, damit
Kursteilnehmer weitere Maßnahmen ergreifen. Mit einem wenig 
Lehrerscharfsinn jedoch konnten diese Aktivitäten als formale 
Lektionpläne leicht angepaßt werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Foyer d'enseignement de cinq unités sur le 
nonviolence, respect pour des droits de l'homme et dignité, justice 
sociale et responsabilité civique, conscience globale, et durabilité 
environnementale. Ce site a été conçu pour aider des 
étudiants et des éducateurs à célébrer le jour international du 
peuple autochtone du monde par l'étude active. L'étude 
présentée dans chaque section étudiant-est centrée. Elle est
conçue en tant que des exercices ou suggestions sans cérémonie et 
participatoires pour que des étudiants prennent davantage de mesure. 
Avec une petite ingéniosité de professeur, cependant, ces 
activités ont pu facilement être adaptées en tant que plans formels
de leçon.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Foco ensinando de cinco unidades no nonviolence, 
respeito para direitas humanas e dignidade, justiça social e 
responsabilidade civic, consciência global, e sustainability 
ambiental. Este local foi projetado ajudar a estudantes e a 
educadores comemorar o dia internacional dos povos indígenos do mundo
com da aprendizagem ativa. As atividades de aprendizagem 
apresentadas em cada seção estudante-são centradas. São 
projetados como exercícios ou sugestões informais, participatory 
para que os estudantes façam exame de uma ação mais adicional. 
Com um ingenuity pequeno do professor, entretanto, estas 
atividades podiam fàcilmente ser adaptadas como plantas formais da 
lição.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un fuoco d'istruzione delle cinque unità sul 
nonviolence, rispetto per i diritti dell'uomo e dignità, giustizia 
sociale e responsabilità civica, consapevolezza globale e 
sustainability ambientale. Questo luogo è stato destinato per 
aiutare gli allievi e gli educatori a celebrare il giorno 
internazionale della gente indigena del mondo con imparare attivo. 
Le attività imparanti presentate in ogni sezione allievo-sono 
centrate. Sono progettate come le esercitazioni o suggerimenti 
informali e partecipi affinchè gli allievi intraprendano ulteriore 
azione. Con un'ingegnosità piccola dell'insegnante, tuttavia, 
queste attività hanno potuto essere adattate facilmente come 
programmi convenzionali di lezione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εστίαση πέντε μονάδων διδασκαλίας στην πολιτική της 
μη βίας, σεβασμός των ανθρώπινων δικαιωμάτων και της 
αξιοπρέπειας, κοινωνική δικαιοσύνη και πολιτική ευθύνη, σφαιρική
συνειδητοποίηση, και περιβαλλοντική ικανότητα υποστήριξης. 
Αυτή η περιοχή έχει σχεδιαστεί για να βοηθήσει τους 
σπουδαστές και τους εκπαιδευτικούς να γιορτάσουν τη διεθνή ημέρα 
των παγκόσμιων γηγενών ανθρώπων μέσω της ενεργού εκμάθησης. 
Οι δραστηριότητες εκμάθησης που παρουσιάζονται σε κάθε 
τμήμα είναι σπουδαστής-κεντροθετημένες. Σχεδιάζονται όπως 
τις άτυπες, συμμετέχουσες ασκήσεις ή προτάσεις για τους 
σπουδαστές να λάβουν περαιτέρω μέτρα. Με λίγη ευστροφία 
δασκάλων, εντούτοις, αυτές οι δραστηριότητες θα μπορούσαν εύκολα
να προσαρμοστούν ως επίσημα σχέδια μαθήματος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Foco de enseñanza de cinco unidades en 
nonviolence, respecto por derechos humanos y dignidad, justicia social
y responsabilidad cívica, conocimiento global, y sustainability 
ambiental. Este sitio se ha diseñado para ayudar a estudiantes 
y a educadores a celebrar el día internacional de la gente indígena 
del mundo con aprender activo. Las actividades que aprenden 
presentadas en cada sección estudiante-se centran. Se diseñan 
como ejercicios o sugerencias informales, participantes para que a los
estudiantes tomen la acción adicional. Con una pequeña 
ingeniosidad del profesor, sin embargo, estas actividades se podían 
adaptar fácilmente como planes formales de la lección.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974099</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103161</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/indigenous-peoples</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
