<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106040</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106040</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203381</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">International Shark Attack File</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Internationale Haifisch-Angriff Datei</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Fichier International d'Attaque de Requin</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Lima Internacional Do Ataque Do Tubarão</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Archivio Internazionale Di Attacco Dello Squalo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διεθνές αρχείο επίθεσης καρχαριών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fichero Internacional Del Ataque Del Tiburón</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Department of Ichthyology at the Florida Museum of Natural History administers the International Shark Attack File (ISAF), a compilation of all known shark attacks. More than 3,200 individual investigations are currently housed in the File, covering the period from mid-1500's to present. Users can access maps, graphs and statistics on worldwide shark attacks, great white attack and attacks on divers. The ISAF also provides information on the relative risk of shark attacks, how to reduce the risk of shark attacks and how, where and when shark attacks typically happen. This is a useful site for users interested in finding comprehensive information regarding worldwide shark attacks.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Abteilung von Ichthyologie am Florida Museum 
der Naturgeschichte übt die internationale Haifisch-Angriff Datei 
(ISAF), eine Kompilation aller bekannten Haifischangriffe aus. 
Mehr als 3.200 einzelne Untersuchungen werden aktuell in der 
Datei untergebracht und umfassen die Periode von mid-1500's, um sich 
darzustellen. Benutzer können Karten, Diagramme und Statistiken
über weltweite Haifischangriffe erreichen, großer weißer Angriff 
und Angriffe auf Tauchern. Das ISAF stellt auch Informationen 
auf der relativen Gefahr der Haifischangriffe zur Verfügung, wie man 
die Gefahr der Haifischangriffe und wie, wo verringert und wenn 
Haifischangriffe gewöhnlich geschehen. Dieses ist eine 
nützliche Site für die Benutzer, die an dem Finden der kompletten 
Informationen betreffend sind weltweite Haifischangriffe interessiert 
werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le service de l'ichtyologie au musée de la 
Floride de l'histoire naturelle gère le fichier international 
d'attaque de requin (ISAF), une compilation de toutes les 
attaques connues de requin. Plus de 3.200 différentes 
investigations sont actuel logées dans le fichier, couvrant la 
période de mid-1500's pour présenter. Les utilisateurs peuvent
accéder à des cartes, des graphiques et des statistiques sur des 
attaques mondiales de requin, grande attaque blanche et des attaques 
sur des plongeurs. L'ISAF fournit également des 
informations sur le risque relatif d'attaques de requin, comment 
réduire le risque d'attaques de requin et comment, où et quand les 
attaques de requin se produisent typiquement. C'est un site 
utile pour des utilisateurs intéressés à trouver l'information 
complète concernant des attaques mondiales de requin.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O departamento do ichthyology no museu de Florida 
do history natural administra a lima internacional do ataque do 
tubarão (ISAF), uma compilação de todos os ataques sabidos do 
tubarão. Mais de 3.200 investigações individuais são 
abrigadas atualmente na lima, cobrindo o período de mid-1500's para 
apresentar-se. Os usuários podem alcançar mapas, gráficos e 
statistics em ataques worldwide do tubarão, ataque branco grande e 
ataques em mergulhadores. O ISAF fornece também a informação 
no risco relativo de ataques do tubarão, como reduzir o risco de 
ataques do tubarão e como, onde e quando os ataques do tubarão 
acontecerem tipicamente. Este é um local útil para os 
usuários interessados em encontrar a informação detalhada a 
respeito dos ataques worldwide do tubarão.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il reparto dell'ittiologia al museo della Florida 
di storia naturale amministra l'archivio internazionale di attacco 
dello squalo (ISAF), una compilazione di tutti gli attacchi conosciuti
dello squalo. Più di 3.200 diverse indagini attualmente sono 
alloggiate nell'archivio, per il periodo da mid-1500's presentarsi. 
Gli utenti possono accedere ai programmi, grafici e le 
statistiche sugli attacchi in tutto il mondo dello squalo, attacco 
bianco grande ed attacchi ai tuffatori. Il ISAF egualmente 
fornisce le informazioni sul rischio relativo di attacchi dello 
squalo, come ridurre il rischio di attacchi dello squalo e come, dove 
e quando gli attacchi dello squalo accadono tipicamente. Ciò è
un luogo utile per gli utenti interessati a trovare le informazioni 
complete per quanto riguarda gli attacchi in tutto il mondo dello 
squalo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το τμήμα ichthyology στο μουσείο της Φλώριδας της 
φυσικής ιστορίας διαχειρίζεται το διεθνές αρχείο επίθεσης 
καρχαριών (ISAF), μια μεταγλώττιση όλων των γνωστών επιθέσεων 
καρχαριών. Περισσότερες από 3.200 μεμονωμένες έρευνες 
στεγάζονται αυτήν την περίοδο στο αρχείο, που καλύπτει την 
περίοδο από τα μέσα της 1500's στο παρόν. Οι χρήστες 
μπορούν να έχουν πρόσβαση στους χάρτες, τις γραφικές παραστάσεις
και τις στατιστικές όσον αφορά τις παγκόσμιες επιθέσεις 
καρχαριών, τη μεγάλες άσπρες επίθεση και τις επιθέσεις στους 
δύτες. Το ISAF παρέχει επίσης τις πληροφορίες για το 
σχετικό κίνδυνο επιθέσεων καρχαριών, πώς να μειώσει τον κίνδυνο
επιθέσεων καρχαριών και πώς, όπου και πότε οι επιθέσεις 
καρχαριών συμβαίνουν χαρακτηριστικά. Αυτό είναι μια 
χρήσιμη περιοχή για τους χρήστες ενδιαφερόμενους στην εύρεση των 
εκτενών πληροφοριών σχετικά με τις παγκόσμιες επιθέσεις 
καρχαριών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El departamento de la ictiología en el museo de 
la Florida de la historia natural administra el fichero internacional 
del ataque del tiburón (ISAF), una compilación de todos los ataques 
sabidos del tiburón. Más de 3.200 investigaciones individuales
se contienen actualmente en el fichero, cubriendo el período de 
mid-1500's para presentar. Los utilizadores pueden tener acceso 
a correspondencias, los gráficos y estadística sobre ataques 
mundiales del tiburón, gran ataque blanco y los ataques contra 
zambullidores. El ISAF también proporciona a la información en
el riesgo relativo de los ataques del tiburón, cómo reducir el 
riesgo de los ataques del tiburón y cómo, donde y cuando suceden los
ataques del tiburón típicamente. Esto es un sitio útil para 
los utilizadores interesados en encontrar la información comprensiva 
con respecto a ataques mundiales del tiburón.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:GEORGE BURGESS
FN:GEORGE BURGESS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JAMES ALBERT
FN:JAMES ALBERT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ROBERT ROBINS
FN:ROBERT ROBINS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203381</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106040</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/international-shark-attack-file</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
