<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103290</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103290</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087443</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Bombed Last Night": Singing at the Front in World War I</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Bombardiertes Gestern Abend": Singen an der
Frontseite im Ersten Weltkrieg</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"La Nuit Passée Bombardée" : Chant à 
l'avant dans la Première Guerre Mondiale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Última Noite Bombardeada": Cantar na parte
dianteira no world.war.i</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Notte scorsa Bombardata": Cantando alla 
parte anteriore nel world.war.i</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Βομβαρδισμένος χτες τη νύχτα": Τραγούδι στο 
μέτωπο στον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Ayer por la noche Bombardeado": El cantar 
en el frente en Primera Guerra Mundial</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">For soldiers in World War I, as in other wars, songs provided diversion and expression of common sentiments. Four song lyrics included here recorded soldiers' responses, both to the new horrors of modern warfare and to the more general disillusion of men in combat. "Bombed Last Night" uses gallows humor to tame the dread of poison gas. "A Poor Aviator Lay Dying" uses the same kind of morbid humor to portray an aviator entangled with his plane, gallantly pleading for his comrades to salvage the parts, rebuild the engine, and keep on fighting. The lyrics to "Sittin' in De Cotton" and "Tell Me Now" expressed, in the ostensible dialect of the southern African American, the widely shared sentiment of the soldier--the disillusion with war and will to survive.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Für Soldaten im Ersten Weltkrieg, wie in anderen 
Kriegen, in Liede zur Verfügung gestellter Ablenkung und in Ausdruck 
der geläufigen Gefühle. Vier LiedLyriken schlossen 
speicherten hier Antworten der Soldaten, zu den neuen Grausigkeiten 
der modernen Kriegsführung und zur allgemeineren Desillusion der 
Männer im Kampf ein. "bombardierte gestern Abend" 
GebrauchGalgenstimmung, um die Angst des Giftgases zu zähmen. 
"ein armer Flieger gelegtes Sterben" verwendet die gleiche Art 
der krankhaften Stimmung, um einen Flieger zu schildern, der mit 
seiner Fläche verwickelt wird und tapfer plädiert, damit seine 
Kameraden die Teile retten, die Maschine umbauen und auf dem Kämpfen 
halten. Die Lyriken zu "Sittin ' in De Cotton" und 
"erklären mir" jetzt ausgedrückt, im scheinbaren Dialekt des 
südlichen afrikanischen Amerikaners, im weit geteilten Gefühl des 
Soldaten -- die Desillusion mit Krieg und im Willen, um zu überleben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pour des soldats dans la Première Guerre 
Mondiale, comme dans d'autres guerres, transfert et expression fournis
par chansons des sentiments communs. Quatre lyriques de chanson 
ont inclus ont ici enregistré les réponses des soldats, aux 
nouvelles horreurs de la guerre moderne et à la désillusion plus 
générale des hommes dans le combat. humeur de potence 
d'utilisations "a bombardé nuit passée" pour apprivoiser la crainte 
du gaz de poison. "une mort étendue pauvre par aviateur" 
emploie le même genre d'humeur morbide pour dépeindre un aviateur 
empêtré avec son avion, parlant en faveur vaillamment pour que ses 
camarades récupèrent les pièces, pour reconstruisent le moteur, et 
pour continuer au combat. Le lyrique à "Sittin 'en de Cotton" 
et "m'indique maintenant" exprimé, en dialecte apparent de 
l'Américain africain méridional, sentiment largement partagé du 
soldat -- la désillusion avec la guerre et volonté pour survivre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Para soldados no world.war.i, como em outras 
guerras, na diversão e na expressão fornecidas canções de 
sentiments comuns. Quatro lyrics da canção incluíram gravaram
aqui respostas dos soldados,  aos horrors novos da guerra moderna e ao
disillusion mais geral dos homens no combate. "bombardeou humor 
do gallows dos usos da última noite" para domesticar o dread do gás 
do veneno. "aviador deficiente morrer colocado" usa o mesmo tipo
do humor morbid portray um aviador entangled com seu plano, pleading 
gallantly para que seus camaradas salvem as peças, reconstruam o 
motor, e mantenham-se na luta. Os lyrics a "Sittin ' em De 
Algodão" e "dizem-me agora" expressado, no dialect ostensible do 
americano africano do sul, no sentiment extensamente compartilhado do 
soldado -- o disillusion com guerra e na vontade para sobreviver.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Per i soldati nel world.war.i, come in altre 
guerre, canzoni ha fornito la diversione e l'espressione dei 
sentimenti comuni. Quattro lyrics di canzone hanno incluso qui 
hanno registrato le risposte dei soldati, sia ai nuovi orrori di 
guerra moderna che alla disillusione più generale degli uomini nel 
combattimento. "ha bombardato umore del gallows di usi di notte 
scorsa" per addomesticare il terrore del gas del veleno. "morire
posto Povero aviator" usa lo stesso genere di umore morboso per 
ritrarre un aviator impigliato con il suo aereo, gallantly supplicante
affinchè i suoi camerati salvi le parti, per ricostruire il motore e 
per mantenere su combattimento. I lyrics "a Sittin 'in De Cotton" 
e "mi dicono ora" espresso, nel dialetto apparente dell'americano 
africano del sud, nel sentimento ampiamente comune del soldato -- la 
disillusione con la guerra e nella volontà per sopravvivere.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Για τους στρατιώτες στον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι, όπως σε 
άλλους πολέμους, τα τραγούδια παρείχαν την παρεκτροπή και την 
έκφραση των κοινών συναισθημάτων. Τέσσερα λυρικά ποιήματα 
τραγουδιού περιέλαβαν τις εδώ καταγραμμένες απαντήσεις των 
στρατιωτών, και στις νέες φρίκες της σύγχρονης εχθροπραξίας και 
στη γενικότερη απομυθοποίηση των ατόμων στον αγώνα. 
"Βομβαρδισμένος χτες τη νύχτα" χρησιμοποιεί το χιούμορ 
αγχονών για να εξημερώσει το φόβο του δηλητήριου αέριο. 
"Ένας φτωχός αεροπόρος βάζει το θάνατο" χρησιμοποιεί το 
ίδιο είδος morbid χιούμορ για να απεικονίσει έναν αεροπόρο 
που μπλέκεται με το αεροπλάνο του, παρακαλώντας ευγενικά για τους 
συντρόφους του για να σώσει τα μέρη, να επανοικοδομήσει τη 
μηχανή, και να κρατήσει στην πάλη. Τα λυρικά ποιήματα "σε 
Sittin" σε de Cotton "και" με λένε τώρα "εξέφρασαν, στη 
φαινομενική διάλεκτο του νότιου αφρικανικού Αμερικανού, το 
ευρέως κοινό συναίσθημα του στρατιώτη -- η απομυθοποίηση με τον 
πόλεμο και θα επιζήσουν.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Para los soldados en Primera Guerra Mundial, como 
en otras guerras, la diversión y la expresión proporcionadas 
canciones de sentimientos comunes. Cuatro líricas de la 
canción incluyeron aquí registraron las respuestas de los soldados, 
a los nuevos horrores de la guerra moderna y a la desilusión más 
general de hombres en combate. "bombardeó humor de la horca de 
las aplicaciones del ayer por la noche" para domesticar el pavor del 
gas del veneno. "el morir puesto aviador pobre" utiliza la misma
clase de humor mórbido para retratar a un aviador enredado con su 
plano, galantemente abogando por para que sus camaradas salven las 
piezas, reconstruyan el motor, y guarden en luchar. Las líricas
a "Sittin ' en De Cotton" y "me dicen ahora" expresado, en el dialecto
aparente del americano africano meridional, el sentimiento 
extensamente compartido del soldado -- la desilusión con guerra y la 
voluntad para sobrevivir.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087443</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103290</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/bombed-last-night-singing-at-the-front-in-world-war-i</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
