<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105039</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105039</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086491</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Much Blood May be Shed Ere Liberty be Firmly Established": Benjamin Franklin Bache Defends the French Revolution, 1792-93</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"viel Blut mag Halle bevor Freiheit sein wird 
hergestellt fest": Benjamin Franklin Bache verteidigt die 
Französische Revolution, 1792-93</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"beaucoup de sang peut être hangar avant la 
liberté soit fermement établi" : Benjamin Franklin Bache 
défend la révolution française, 1792-93</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"muito sangue pode ser vertente ere a liberdade 
seja estabelecido firmemente": Benjamin Franklin Bache defende a
volta francesa, 1792-93</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"molta anima può essere tettoia ere la libertà 
saldamente è stabilita": Benjamin Franklin Bache difende la 
rivoluzione francese, 1792-93</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Πολύ αίμα Μάιος είναι ριγμένη ελευθερία Ere 
καθιερώνεται σταθερά": Θ*Ψενιαμην Franklin Bache 
Defends η γαλλική επανάσταση, 1792-93</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"mucha sangre puede ser vertiente ere libertad se 
establezca firmemente": Benjamin Franklin Bache defiende la 
revolución francesa, 1792-93</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Americans keenly followed the events of the French Revolution. Reactions to the growing violence and social upheaval split along emerging party lines--Federalists expressed horror while Democratic Republicans were more sympathetic. Benjamin Franklin Bache, grandson of Benjamin Franklin, was a journalist, the founder of the Philadelphia  General Advertiser , and supporter of Jefferson's Republican party. In these two pieces he sympathetically summarized the situation in France during the period when Louis XVI was put on trial and executed. He defended the actions of the revolutionaries on the grounds that they were merely responding to the provocations of nobles and other "traitors." Newspapers in the 1790s quickly became party organs and contributors to the fierce polemics of this factious era. Bache was no exception. He attacked the Federalists mercilessly and was arrested under the Sedition Act, an act of Congress passed by Federalists to prosecute government critics for seditious speech or writings.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Amerikaner folgten scharf den Fällen der 
Französischen Revolution. Reaktionen auf die wachsende 
Gewalttätigkeit und Sozialdie umwälzungspalte entlang auftauchenden 
Parteizeilen -- Föderalisten drückten Grausigkeit aus, während 
demokratische Republikaner sympatischer waren. Benjamin Franklin
Bache, Enkel von Benjamin Franklin, war ein Journalist, der Gründer 
des Philadelphia Generals Advertiser und Verfechter von Jeffersons 
republikanischer Partei. In diesen zwei Stücken faßte 
er sympathetically die Situation in Frankreich während der Periode 
zusammen, als Louis XVI auf Versuch gesetzt wurde und durchgeführt. 
Er verteidigte die Tätigkeiten der Revolutionäre, mit der 
Begründung daß sie reagierten bloß auf die Provokationen der 
Adliger und anderer "Traitors." Zeitungen im 1790s standen 
schnell Parteiorganen und -mitwirkenden zur heftigen Polemik 
dieser uneinigen Ära. Bache war keine Ausnahme. Er griff 
die Föderalisten gnadenlos an und wurde unter der Sedition-Tat 
festgehalten, eine Tat des Kongresses geführt von Federalists, um 
Regierung Kritiker für seditious Rede oder Schreiben zu verfolgen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Américains ont profondément suivi les 
événements de la révolution française. Réactions à la 
violence croissante et au fractionnement social de bouleversement le 
long des lignes naissantes de partie -- les fédéralistes ont 
exprimé l'horreur tandis que les républicains démocratiques 
étaient plus bien disposés. Benjamin Franklin Bache, 
petit-fils de Benjamin Franklin, était un journaliste, le fondateur 
du Général annonceur de Philadelphie, et défenseur de la partie 
républicaine de Jefferson. Dans ces deux morceaux il a 
sympathique récapitulé la situation en France pendant la période 
où Louis XVI a été mis sur l'épreuve et exécuté. Il a 
défendu les actions des révolutionnaires parce qu'elles répondaient
simplement aux provocations des nobles et d'autres "traîtres." 
Les journaux dans le 1790s sont rapidement allés bien à des 
organes et à des contribuants de partie à la polémique féroce de 
cette ère factice. Bache n'était aucune exception. Il a 
attaqué les fédéralistes impitoyablement et a été arrêté sous 
la Loi de sedition, un acte du congrès passé par Federalists pour 
poursuivre des critiques de gouvernement pour le discours séditieux 
ou les écritures.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os americanos seguiram afiada os eventos da volta 
francesa. Reações à violência crescente e ao split social do
upheaval ao longo das linhas de partido emergentes -- os federalistas 
expressaram o horror quando os republicanos democráticos eram mais 
sympathetic. Benjamin Franklin Bache, neto de Benjamin Franklin,
era um journalist, o founder do general Advertiser de Filadélfia, e 
supporter do partido republicano de Jefferson. Nestas duas 
partes sumariou sympathetically a situação em France durante o 
período em que Louis XVI foi posto sobre a experimentação e 
executado. Defendeu as ações dos revolucionários nas terras 
que estavam respondendo meramente aos provocations dos nobres e dos 
outros "traitors." Os jornais no 1790s assentaram bem 
rapidamente em órgãos e em contribuinte do partido aos polemics 
ferozes desta era factious. Bache não era nenhuma exceção. 
Atacou os federalistas mercilessly e foi prendido sob o ato do 
sedition, um ato do congress passado por Federalista para prosecute 
críticos do governo para o discurso ou escritas seditious.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli Americani hanno seguito acutamente gli eventi 
della rivoluzione francese. Reazioni alla violenza crescente ed 
alla spaccatura sociale di sollevazione seguendo le righe d'emersione 
del partito -- i federalisti hanno espresso l'orrore mentre i 
Repubblicani democratici erano più simpatici. Benjamin 
Franklin Bache, nipote di Benjamin Franklin, era un giornalista, il 
fondatore del General Advertiser de Filadelfia e sostenitore del 
partito Repubblicano del Jefferson. In queste due parti ha 
ricapitolato in modo comprensivo la situazione in Francia durante il 
periodo in cui Louis XVI è stato messo sulla prova ed è stato 
eseguito. Ha difeso le azioni dei rivoluzionari considerando che
soltanto stavano rispondendo ai provocations dei nobili e di altri 
"traitors." I giornali nel 1790s hanno stato bene rapidamente 
agli organi ed ai contributori del partito ai polemics feroci di 
questa era factious. Bache faceva eccezione. Ha attacato 
mercilessly i federalisti ed è stato arrestato a norma della legge di
sedition, un atto del congresso passato da Federalists per proseguire 
i critici di governo per discorso o scritture seditious.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αμερικανοί ακολούθησαν έντονα τα γεγονότα της 
γαλλικής επανάστασης. Οι αντιδράσεις στην αυξανόμενη βία 
και την κοινωνική αναταραχή χώρισαν σύμφωνα με τις αναδυόμενες 
γραμμές συμβαλλόμενων μερών -- εκφρασμένη ομοσπονδιακοί φρίκη 
ενώ οι δημοκρατικοί Δημοκρατικοί ήταν πιό συμπονετικοί. 
Θ*Ψενιαμην Franklin Bache, εγγονός Benjamin 
Franklin, ήταν δημοσιογράφος, ο ιδρυτής του γενικού δηαφημιστή
της Φιλαδέλφειας, και υποστηρικτής του δημοκρατικού κόμματος 
Jefferson. Σε αυτά τα δύο κομμάτια συνόψισε με κατανόηση
την κατάσταση στη Γαλλία κατά τη διάρκεια της περιόδου όταν 
τέθηκε ο Louis XVI στη δοκιμή και εκτελέσθηκε. 
Υπεράσπισε τις ενέργειες των revolutionaries λόγω του ότι
αποκρίνονταν μόνο στις προκλήσεις των nobles και άλλων 
"προδοτών." Οι εφημερίδες στο 1790s έγιναν γρήγορα 
όργανα και συνεισφέροντες συμβαλλόμενων μερών στις άγριες 
πολεμικές αυτής της φατριαστικής εποχής. Το Bache δεν 
ήταν καμία εξαίρεση. Επιτέθηκε στους ομοσπονδιακούς 
ανελέητα και συλλήφθηκε στο πλαίσιο του νόμου στασιασμού, μια 
πράξη του συνεδρίου από οι ομοσπονδιακοί που πέρασε για να 
διώξει ποινικώς τους κυβερνητικούς κριτικούς για την ανατρεπτικές
ομιλία ή τις γραφές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los americanos siguieron afilado los 
acontecimientos de la revolución francesa. Reacciones a la 
violencia cada vez mayor y a la fractura social de la agitación a lo 
largo de líneas de partido que emergen -- los federalistas expresaron
horror mientras que los republicanos democráticos eran más 
comprensivos. Benjamin Franklin Bache, nieto de Benjamin 
Franklin, era periodista, el fundador del general Advertiser de 
Philadelphia, y partidario del partido republicano de Jefferson. 
En estos dos pedazos él resumió sympathetically la situación 
en Francia durante el período en que Louis XVI fue puesto en ensayo y
ejecutado. Él defendió las acciones de los revolucionarios 
considerando que respondían simplemente a los provocations de nobles 
y de otros "traidores." Los periódicos en el 1790s sintieron 
bien rápidamente a órganos y a contribuidores del partido a las 
polémicas feroces de esta era facciosa. Bache no era ninguna 
anomalía. Él atacó a federalistas sin piedad y fue arrestado 
bajo acto de la sedición, un acto del congreso pasado por Federalists
para procesar a críticos del gobierno para el discurso o las 
escrituras seditious.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086491</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105039</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/much-blood-may-be-shed-ere-liberty-be-firmly-established-benjamin-franklin-bache-defends-the-french-revolution-1792-93</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
