<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108754</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108754</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086412</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Like One Big Family": A Former Textile Worker Describes the Closeness of the Southern Mill Village in the 1920s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Wie Eine Grosse Familie": Ein ehemaliger 
Textilarbeiter beschreibt die Nähe des südlichen Tausendstel-Dorfs 
in den zwanziger Jahren</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Comme Une Grande Famille" : Un ancien 
ouvrier de textile décrit la proximité du village méridional de 
moulin dans les années 20</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Como Uma Família Grande": Um trabalhador 
anterior de textile descreve o closeness da vila do sul do moinho nos 
1920s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Come Una Famiglia Grande": Un ex operaio 
della tessile descrive la prossimità del villaggio del sud del 
laminatoio negli anni 20</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Όπως μια μεγάλη οικογένεια": Ένας προηγούμενος
υφαντικός εργαζόμενος περιγράφει τη στενότητα του νότιου χωριού 
μύλων στη δεκαετία του '20</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Como Una Familia Grande": Un trabajador 
anterior del textil describe la proximidad de la aldea meridional del 
molino en los años 20</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The southern textile mills, which had expanded dramatically during World War I, faced serious decline in the 1920s. New tariffs, the growth of textile manufacturing in other parts of the world and the shorter skirt lengths of the 1920s, which required less fabric, exacerbated the problems brought on by wartime overexpansion. Textile manufacturers responded by trying to cut wages and increase workloads. Nevertheless, textile workers often look back at the 1920s with genuine affection and nostalgia. In this 1979 interview with historian James Leloudis, Edna Y. Hargett, a former textile worker, described the closeness of the mill village and the "love offering": a collection for sick workers to replace lost wages in an era when there was no sick leave.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die südlichen Textiltausendstel, die drastisch 
während des Ersten Weltkrieges erweitert hatten, stellten ernste 
Abnahme in den zwanziger Jahre neuen Tarifen, das Wachstum der 
Textilherstellung in anderen Teilen der Welt und die kürzeren 
Rocklängen der zwanziger Jahre, die weniger Gewebe benötigten, 
verbitterten die Probleme gegenüber, die an durch Krieg overexpansion
geholt wurden. Textilhersteller reagierten, indem sie auf 
geschnittene Löhne und Zunahmearbeitsbelastungen versuchten. 
Dennoch betrachten Textilarbeiter häufig zurück den zwanziger 
Jahren mit echter Neigung und Nostalgie. In diesem 
Interview 1979 mit Historiker James Leloudis, Edna Y. Hargett, ein 
ehemaliger Textilarbeiter, beschrieb die Nähe des Tausendsteldorfs 
und der "Liebe, die" anbieten: eine Ansammlung, damit kranke 
Arbeiter verlorene Löhne in einer Ära ersetzen, als es keinen 
kranken Urlaub gab.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les moulins méridionaux de textile, qui avaient 
augmenté excessivement pendant la Première Guerre Mondiale, ont fait
face au déclin sérieux dans les années 20. Les nouveaux 
tarifs, la croissance de la fabrication de textile dans d'autres 
régions du monde et les durée plus courtes de jupe les années 20, 
qui ont exigé moins de tissu, ont aggravé les problèmes apportés 
en fonction par sur-expansion de temps de guerre. Les 
constructeurs de textile ont répondu par l'essai aux salaires et aux 
charges de travail coupés d'augmentation. Néanmoins, les 
ouvriers de textile regardent souvent en arrière les années 20 avec 
l'affection et la nostalgie véritables. Dans cette entrevue 
1979 avec l'historien James Leloudis, Edna Y. Hargett, un ancien
ouvrier de textile, a décrit la proximité du village de moulin et du
l'"amour offrant" : une collection pour que les ouvriers malades
substituent les salaires perdus dans une ère où il n'y avait aucun 
congé de maladie de maladie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os moinhos do sul de textile, que tinham expandido
dramàtica durante o world.war.i, enfrentaram o declínio sério nas 
tarifas novas dos 1920s., o crescimento do manufacturing de textile em
outras partes do mundo e os comprimentos mais curtos da saia dos 
1920s, que requereram menos tela, exacerbated os problemas trazidos 
sobre pelo overexpansion do wartime. Os fabricantes de textile 
responderam tentando aos salários e aos workloads cortados do 
aumento. Não obstante, os trabalhadores de textile olham 
frequentemente para trás nos 1920s com afeição e nostalgia 
genuínas. Nesta entrevista 1979 com historian James Leloudis, 
Edna Y. Hargett, um trabalhador anterior de textile, descreveu o 
closeness da vila do moinho e do "amor que oferecem": uma 
coleção para que os trabalhadores doentes substituam salários 
perdidos em uma era em que não houver nenhuma licença doente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I laminatoi del sud della tessile, che si erano 
espansi drammaticamente durante il world.war.i, hanno affrontato il 
declino serio nelle nuove tariffe degli anni 20, lo sviluppo di 
manufacturing della tessile in altre parti del mondo e le lunghezze 
più corte del pannello esterno degli anni 20, che hanno richiesto 
meno tessuto, hanno esacerbato i problemi portati sopra dal 
overexpansion di wartime. I fornitori della tessile hanno 
risposto provando agli stipendi ed alle quote di lavoro tagliati di 
aumento. Tuttavia, gli operai della tessile osservano spesso 
indietro gli anni 20 con affetto e nostalgia genuini. In questa 
intervista 1979 con lo storico James Leloudis, Edna Y. Hargett, un ex 
operaio della tessile, ha descritto la prossimità del villaggio del 
laminatoio e "dell'amore che offrono": una collezione affinchè 
operai ammalati sostituiscano gli stipendi persi in un'era in cui non 
ci era congedo per malattia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι νότιοι υφαντικοί μύλοι, που είχαν επεκταθεί 
εντυπωσιακά κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου Ι, 
αντιμετώπισαν τη σοβαρή πτώση στα νέα δασμολόγια της δεκαετίας 
του '20, η αύξηση της υφαντικής κατασκευής σε άλλα μέρη του 
κόσμου και τα πιό σύντομα μήκη φουστών της δεκαετίας του '20, 
που απαίτησε το λιγότερο ύφασμα, επιδείνωσαν τα προβλήματα που 
παρουσιάστηκαν επάνω από την εν καιρώ πολέμου υπερβολική 
επέκταση. Οι υφαντικοί κατασκευαστές αποκρίθηκαν με την 
προσπάθεια να κοπούν οι αμοιβές και να αυξηθούν οι φόρτοι 
εργασίας. Εντούτοις, οι υφαντικοί εργαζόμενοι εξετάζουν 
συχνά πίσω τη δεκαετία του '20 με τη γνήσιες αγάπη και τη 
νοσταλγία. Σε αυτήν την συνέντευξη του 1979 με τον 
ιστορικό james Leloudis, Edna Υ. Hargett, ένας 
προηγούμενος υφαντικός εργαζόμενος, περιέγραψε τη στενότητα του 
χωριού μύλων και της "αγάπης που προσφέρουν": μια συλλογή 
για τους άρρωστους εργαζομένους που αντικαθιστούν έχασε τις 
αμοιβές σε μια εποχή όταν δεν υπήρξε καμία άδεια για λόγους 
υγείας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los molinos meridionales del textil, que se 
habían ampliado dramáticamente durante Primera Guerra Mundial, 
hicieron frente a la declinación seria en las nuevas tarifas de los 
años 20, al crecimiento de la fabricación del textil en otras partes
del mundo y a las longitudes más cortas de la falda de los años 20, 
que requirieron menos tela, exacerbaron los problemas traídos 
encendido por el overexpansion del tiempo de guerra. Los 
fabricantes del textil respondieron intentando a los salarios y a las 
cargas de trabajo cortados del aumento. Sin embargo, los 
trabajadores del textil miran a menudo detrás los años 20 con el 
afecto y la nostalgia genuinos. En esta entrevista 1979 con el 
historiador James Leloudis, Edna Y. Hargett, trabajador anterior del 
textil, describió la proximidad de la aldea del molino y del "amor 
que ofrecían": una colección para que trabajadores enfermos 
substituyan salarios perdidos en una era en que no había licencia 
enferma.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086412</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108754</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/like-one-big-family-a-former-textile-worker-describes-the-closeness-of-the-southern-mill-village-in-the-1920s</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
