<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104634</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104634</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086842</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Sounding the Depths: The  Times  and the Sinking of the  Maine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Klingen der Tiefen: Die Zeiten und das 
Sinken des Maines</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Retentir les profondeurs : Les temps et la 
descente du Maine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Soando as profundidades: Os tempos e 
afundar-se do Maine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sondaggio delle profondità: I tempi e 
l'abbassamento della Maine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ήχος των βαθών: Οι χρόνοι και η βύθιση του 
Maine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sonar las profundidades: Los tiempos y el 
hundirse del Maine</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">On February 15, 1898, an explosion ripped through the American battleship  Maine , anchored in Havana Harbor, sinking the ship and killing 260 sailors. Americans responded with outrage, assuming that Spain, which controlled Cuba as a colony, had sunk the ship. A great deal of the American public's outrage was generated by media coverage--newspapers and the emerging film industry--of the incident. The Biograph Company renamed its film  The Battleships "Iowa" and "Massachusetts"  the  Battleships "Maine" and "Iowa,"  and immediately released it to theaters. It played to cheering audiences. Newspapers, like those published by William Randolph Hearst and Joseph Pulitzer, were even more influential in stirring American public opinion into a frenzy over the sinking of the  Maine . In contrast to more sensational accounts of the  Maine  explosion, the staid New York  Times  cautiously reported on February 17, 1898, that there "was no evidence to prove or disprove treachery" as a factor in the sinking of the battleship.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Auf Februar 15, 1898, einer Explosion zerrissen 
durch das amerikanische Linienschiff Maine, befestigt im Havana Hafen,
das Schiff sinkend und beenden 260 Seeleute. Amerikaner 
reagierten mit dem Verbrechen und nahmen dieses Spanien an, dem 
kontrolliertes Kuba als Kolonie, das Schiff gesunken hatte. 
Verbrechen der vielen wurde das amerikanischen Öffentlichkeit 
durch Mediadichte -- Zeitungen und die auftauchende Filmindustrie -- 
des Ereignisses festgelegt. Biograph Company, die seinen Film 
die Linienschiffe "Iowa" und "Massachusetts" die Linienschiffe "Maine"
und "Iowa," und gab umbenannt wurde ihn sofort, zu den Theatern frei. 
Es spielte zu zujubelnden Publikum. Zeitungen, wie die, 
die von William Randolph Hearst und von Joseph Pulitzer 
veröffentlicht wurden, waren sogar einflußreicher, wenn sie 
amerikanische öffentliche Meinung in einen Rasereiüberschuß das 
Sinken des Maines rührten. Im Gegensatz zu mehr sensational 
Konten der Maine Explosion, berichteten die staid New York Zeiten 
vorsichtig über Februar 17, 1898, daß es "keinen Beweis gab, zum von
von Treachery" als Faktor im Sinken des Linienschiffs zu prüfen oder 
zu widerlegen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">15 février 1898, une explosion déchirée par le
cuirassé américain Maine, ancré dans le port de La Havane, 
descendant le bateau et détruisant 260 marins. Les Américains 
ont répondu avec l'outrage, assumant la cette Espagne, que le Cuba 
commandé en tant que colonie, était descendu le bateau. 
L'outrage de la majeure partie de public américain a été 
produit par couverture médiatique -- journaux et l'industrie 
naissante de film -- de l'incident. Biograph Company renommée 
son film les cuirassés "Iowa" et le "Massachusetts" les cuirassés 
"Maine" et "Iowa," et l'a immédiatement libéré aux théâtres. 
Il a joué aux assistances encourageantes. Les journaux, 
comme ceux édités par William Randolph Hearst et Joseph Pulitzer, 
étaient bien plus influents en remuant l'opinion publique américain 
dans un excédent de frénésie la descente du Maine. 
Contrairement à des comptes plus sensationnels de l'explosion du 
Maine, les temps sérieux de New York ont avec précaution rendu 
compte 17 février 1898, qu'il "n'y avait aucune évidence pour 
prouver ou réfuter la trahison" comme facteur dans la descente du 
cuirassé.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fevereiro em 15, 1898, em uma explosão rasgada 
através do cruzador de batalha americano Maine, escorado no porto de 
Havana, afundando o navio e matando 260 sailors. Os americanos 
responderam com o ultraje, supondo esse Spain, que Cuba controlada 
como uma colônia, tinha afundado o navio. O ultraje do público
americano muito foi gerado pela cobertura de media -- jornais e a 
indústria emergente da película -- do incident. O Biograph 
Companhia rebatizada sua película os cruzadores de batalha "Iowa" e 
"Massachusetts" os cruzadores de batalha "Maine" e "Iowa," e liberou-a
imediatamente aos teatros. Jogou às audiências cheering. 
Os jornais, como aqueles publicados por William Randolph Hearst 
e por Joseph Pulitzer, eram mesmo mais influential em agitar a 
opinião pública americana em um excesso do frenzy afundar-se do 
Maine. No contraste a mais clientes do sensational da explosão 
de Maine, os tempos de New York do staid relataram cautelosamente 
fevereiro em 17, 1898, que "não havia nenhuma evidência para provar 
ou disprove o treachery" como um fator em se afundar do cruzador de 
batalha.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il 15 febbraio 1898, un'esplosione strappata 
tramite il battleship americano Maine, ancorata nel porto de Avana, 
affondante la nave e mortale 260 marinai. Gli Americani hanno 
risposto con l'oltraggio, ammettente la quella Spagna, che la Cuba 
controllata come colonia, aveva affondato la nave. L'oltraggio 
del moltissimo pubblico americano è stato generato da riempimento di 
media -- giornali e l'industria d'emersione della pellicola -- 
dell'avvenimento. Il Biograph Company ha cambiato titolo la 
relativa pellicola i battleships "Iowa" e "Massachusetts" i 
battleships "Maine" e "Iowa," ed immediatamente la ha liberata ai 
teatri. Ha giocato ai pubblici incoraggianti. I giornali, 
come quelli pubblicati da William Randolph Hearst e da Joseph 
Pulitzer, erano ancor più influenti nella mescolatura dell'opinione 
pubblica americana in un'eccedenza di frenzy l'abbassamento della 
Maine. Contrariamente a più clienti di sensational 
dell'esplosione della Maine, i tempi de New York dello staid hanno 
segnalato prudentemente il 17 febbraio 1898, che non ci "era prova per
dimostrare o confutare il treachery" come fattore nell'abbassamento 
del battleship.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στις 15 Φεβρουαρίου ..1898, μια έκρηξη που 
σχίζεται μέσω του αμερικανικού θωρηκτού Maine, που δένεται στο
λιμάνι της Αβάνας, που βυθίζει το σκάφος και που σκοτώνει 260 
ναυτικούς. Αμερικανοί αποκρίθηκαν με την προσβολή, 
υποθέτοντας ότι η Ισπανία, που έλεγξε την Κούβα ως αποικία, 
είχε βυθίσει το σκάφος. η προσβολή Πολύ αμερικανικού 
κοινού παρήχθη από την κάλυψη μέσων -- εφημερίδες και η 
αναδυόμενη βιομηχανία ταινιών -- του γεγονότος. Η 
επιχείρηση Biograph μετονόμασε την ταινία της τα θωρηκτά 
"Iowa" και "Μασαχουσέτη" τα θωρηκτά "Maine" και "Iowa," και
την εξέδωσε αμέσως στα θέατρα. Έπαιξε στα ενθαρρυντικά 
ακροατήρια. Οι εφημερίδες, όπως εκείνους που δημοσιεύθηκαν 
από William Randolph Hearst και Joseph Pulitzer, ήταν
ακόμα επιδρύτερες στο ανακάτωμα της αμερικανικής κοινής γνώμης 
σε έναν παροξυσμό πέρα από τη βύθιση του Maine. Σε 
αντίθεση με περισσότερους συγκλονιστικούς απολογισμούς της 
έκρηξης του Maine, οι σοβαροί New York Times υπέβαλαν 
έκθεση προσεκτικά σχετικά με στις 17 Φεβρουαρίου ..1898, ο 
οποίος "δεν υπήρξαν κανένα στοιχείο για να αποδειχθεί ή να 
ανασκευαστεί η προδοσία" ως παράγοντα στη βύθιση του θωρηκτού.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">15 de febrero de 1898, una explosión rasgada a
través del acorazado americano Maine, asegurado en el puerto de La 
Habana, hundiendo la nave y matando a 260 marineros. Los 
americanos respondieron con el ultraje, si se asume esa España, que 
Cuba controlada como colonia, había hundido la nave. El ultraje
del público americano mucho fue generado por la cobertura de media --
periódicos y la industria de la película que emerge -- del 
incidente. El Biograph Company retituló su película los 
acorazados "Iowa" y "Massachusetts" los acorazados "Maine" y "Iowa," y
release/versión inmediatamente la a los teatros. Jugó a las 
audiencias que animaban. Los periódicos, como ésos publicados 
por Guillermo Randolph Hearst y José Pulitzer, eran aún más 
influyentes en el revolvimiento de la opinión pública americana en 
un excedente del frenesí el hundirse del Maine. En contraste 
con más cuentas del sensational de la explosión de Maine, los 
tiempos de Nueva York del staid señalaron cautelosomente de febrero 
el 17 de 1898, que "no había evidencia para probar o para refutar la 
traición" como factor en hundirse del acorazado.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086842</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104634</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/sounding-the-depths-the-times-and-the-sinking-of-the-maine</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
