<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105990</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105990</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087159</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Unlimited Possibilities for Evil": Hollywood Resists Daylight Saving</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"unbegrenzte Möglichkeiten für Übel": 
Hollywood Widersteht Tageslicht-Einsparung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"possibilités illimitées pour le mal" : 
Hollywood Résiste À l'Économie de Jour</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"possibilidades ilimitadas para o evil": 
Hollywood Resiste O Saving Da Luz do dia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"possibilità illimitate per la malvagità": 
Hollywood Resiste Al Saving Di Luce del giorno</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Απεριόριστες δυνατότητες για το κακό": Το 
Hollywood αντιστέκεται στην αποταμίευση φωτός της ημέρας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"posibilidades ilimitadas del mal": Hollywood
Resiste El Ahorro De la Hora solar</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The quest for efficiency touched nearly every aspect of American life during World War I, including the nation's clocks. Daylight saving first appeared during the war years as an experiment to save fuel. Theoretically, people would use less artificial light in the evenings thanks to the extra hour of daylight. Urban dwellers, and those working regular hours in factories and offices, generally delighted in the "extra hour," but protests by farmers and other rural citizens brought the experiment to an end after only a year. For most of the 20th century, however, the push for or against daylight saving came from businesses. The makers of sporting goods, charcoal briquettes, and mosquito repellents continued to fund a "National Daylight Saving Coalition" to lobby for an extended period of "fast time." The movie industry, however, long resisted daylight saving. In this 1930 letter to E. B. Duerr of Path Studios, the president of Fox West Coast Theaters warned of dire economic consequences for the motion picture industry if California adopted daylight saving.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Suche nach Leistungsfähigkeit berührte fast 
jeden Aspekt der amerikanischen Lebensdauer während des Ersten 
Weltkrieges, einschließlich die Taktgeber der Nation. 
Tageslichteinsparung schien zuerst während der Kriegsjahre wie 
ein Experiment, Kraftstoff zu sichern. Theoretisch würden Leute
weniger künstliches Licht in den Abenddank die Überstunde des 
Tageslichts benutzen. Städtische Bewohner und die arbeitende 
regelmäßige Stunden in den Fabriken und in Büros, im Allgemeinen 
erfreut in der "Überstunde," aber in den Protesten von den Landwirten
und in anderen landwirtschaftlichen Bürgern holten das Experiment zu 
einem Ende nach nur einem Jahr. Für die meisten des 20. 
Jahrhunderts, jedoch, des Stosses für oder gegen Tageslichteinsparung
kam von den Geschäften. Die Hersteller von sporting Waren, von 
Holzkohlebriketts und von Moskitoabwehrmitteln fuhren fort, eine 
"nationale Tageslicht-Einsparung-Koalition" zu finanzieren, um 
während einer ausgedehnten Periode "der schnellen Zeit zu 
beeinflussen." Die Filmindustrie jedoch widerstand lang 
Tageslichteinsparung. In diesem Zeichen 1930 zu E. B. Duerr der 
Pfad-Studios, warnte der Präsident Fuchs-der Westküste-Theater von 
den entsetzlichen ökonomischen Konsequenzen für die Bewegung 
Abbildung Industrie, wenn Kalifornien Tageslichteinsparung annahm.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La recherche pour l'efficacité a touché presque 
chaque aspect de vie américaine pendant la Première Guerre Mondiale,
y compris les horloges de la nation. L'économie de jour a 
semblé la première fois pendant les années de guerre comme une 
expérience sauvegarder le carburant. Théoriquement, les gens 
utiliseraient moins de lumière artificielle dans grâce de soirées 
à l'heure supplémentaire du jour. Les habitants urbains, et 
ceux des heures régulières travaillantes dans les usines et les 
bureaux, généralement ravis dans "l'heure supplémentaire," mais des
protestations par des fermiers et d'autres citoyens ruraux ont 
apporté l'expérience à une extrémité après seulement une année.
Pour la majeure partie du 20ème siècle, cependant, de la 
poussée pour ou contre l'économie de jour est venu des entreprises. 
Les générateurs des marchandises, des briquettes de charbon de
bois, et des révulsifs sportifs de moustique ont continué à placer 
"une coalition nationale d'économie de jour" pour inciter pendant une
période étendue "de temps rapide." L'industrie de film, 
cependant, a longtemps résisté à l'économie de jour. Dans 
cette lettre 1930 à E. B. Duerr des studios de voie d'accès, le 
président des théâtres occidentaux de côte de renard a averti de 
grandes conséquences économiques pour l'industrie de film 
cinématographique si la Californie adoptait l'économie de jour.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O quest para a eficiência tocou em quase cada 
aspecto da vida americana durante o world.war.i, including os pulsos 
de disparo da nação. O saving da luz do dia pareceu 
primeiramente durante os anos de guerra como uma experiência 
conservar o combustível. Teòrica, os povos usariam menos luz 
artificial nos agradecimentos das noites à hora extra da luz do dia. 
Os moradores urbanos, e aqueles horas regulares trabalhando nas 
fábricas e nos escritórios, deleitados geralmente "na hora extra," 
mas em protestos por fazendeiros e em outros cidadãos rurais 
trouxeram a experiência a uma extremidade após somente um ano. 
Para a maioria do 20o século, entretanto, do impulso para ou de
encontro ao saving da luz do dia veio dos negócios. Os 
fabricantes de bens, de briquettes do carvão de lenha, e de 
repellents ostentando do mosquito continuaram a financiar "um 
coalition nacional do saving da luz do dia" para lobby por um período
prolongado "do tempo rápido." A indústria do filme, 
entretanto, resistiu por muito tempo o saving da luz do dia. 
Nesta letra 1930 a E. B. Duerr de estúdios do trajeto, o 
presidente dos teatros ocidentais da costa da raposa advertiu de 
conseqüências econômicas dire para a indústria de retrato de 
movimento se Califórnia adotasse o saving da luz do dia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La ricerca per risparmio di temi ha toccato quasi 
ogni funzione di vita americana durante il world.war.i, compreso gli 
orologi della nazione. Il saving di luce del giorno in primo 
luogo è sembrato durante gli anni di guerra come un esperimento 
salvare il combustibile. Teoricamente, la gente userebbe meno 
luce artificiale in grazie di sere all'ora supplementare di luce del 
giorno. Gli abitanti urbani e quelli ore normali di 
funzionamento in fabbriche ed in uffici, contentissimi generalmente 
"nell'ora supplementare," ma nelle proteste dai coltivatori ed in 
altri cittadini rurali hanno portato l'esperimento ad un'estremità 
dopo soltanto un anno. Per la maggior parte del ventesimo 
secolo, tuttavia, della spinta per o contro il saving di luce del 
giorno è venuto dai commerci. I creatori delle merci, delle 
mattonelle del carbone di legna e delle cose repellenti di sport della
zanzara hanno continuato a costituire un fondo per "una coalizione 
nazionale di saving di luce del giorno" per incitare per un periodo 
esteso "di tempo veloce." L'industria di film, tuttavia, 
lungamente ha resistito al saving di luce del giorno. In questa 
lettera 1930 a E. B. Duerr degli studi del percorso, il presidente dei
teatri ad ovest del litorale della volpe ha avvertito delle 
conseguenze economiche dire per l'industria cinematografica se la 
California adottasse il saving di luce del giorno.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η αναζήτηση για την αποδοτικότητα άγγιξε σχεδόν κάθε 
πτυχή της αμερικανικής ζωής κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου 
πολέμου Ι, συμπεριλαμβανομένων των ρολογιών του έθνους. Η 
αποταμίευση φωτός της ημέρας εμφανίστηκε αρχικά κατά τη 
διάρκεια των πολεμικών ετών σαν ένα πείραμα να σώζει τα 
καύσιμα. Θεωρητικά, οι άνθρωποι θα χρησιμοποιούσαν το 
λιγότερο τεχνητό φως τα βράδια χάρι στην πρόσθετη ώρα του φωτός
της ημέρας. Οι αστικοί κάτοικοι, και εκείνες οι κανονικές 
ώρες εργασίας στα εργοστάσια και τα γραφεία, ευχαρίστησαν γενικά
στη "πρόσθετη ώρα," αλλά οι διαμαρτυρίες από τους αγρότες και 
άλλους αγροτικούς πολίτες έθεσαν τέλος στο πείραμα μετά από 
μόνο ένα έτος. Για τον μεγαλύτερο μέρος του 20ού αιώνα, 
εντούτοις, η ώθηση για ή ενάντια στην αποταμίευση φωτός της 
ημέρας προήλθε από τις επιχειρήσεις. Οι κατασκευαστές των 
αθλητικών αγαθών, των ανθρακόπλινθων ξυλάνθρακα, και των 
απωθητικών ουσιών κουνουπιών συνέχισαν να χρηματοδοτούν έναν 
"εθνικό συνασπισμό αποταμίευσης φωτός της ημέρασ" για να πιέσουν
για μια εκτεταμένη περίοδο "γρήγορου χρόνου." Η βιομηχανία 
κινηματογράφων, εντούτοις, μακροχρόνια επικριμένη αποταμίευση 
φωτός της ημέρας. Σε αυτήν την επιστολή του 1930 σε Ε. Β.
Duerr των στούντιο μονοπατιών, ο Πρόεδρος των θεάτρων δυτικών 
ακτών αλεπούδων που προειδοποιείται για τις τρομερές οικονομικές 
συνέπειες για τη βιομηχανία ταινιών εάν Καλιφόρνια υιοθέτησε την
αποταμίευση φωτός της ημέρας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La búsqueda para la eficacia tocó casi cada 
aspecto de la vida americana durante Primera Guerra Mundial, 
incluyendo los relojes de la nación. El ahorro de la hora solar
primero aparecía durante los años de guerra como un experimento 
salvar el combustible. Teóricamente, la gente utilizaría menos
luz artificial en los gracias de las tardes a la hora adicional de la 
hora solar. Los habitantes urbanos, y ésos las horas regulares 
de trabajo en las fábricas y las oficinas, encantadas generalmente la
"hora adicional," pero protestas por los granjeros y otros ciudadanos 
rurales trajeron el experimento a un extremo después solamente de un 
año. Para la mayoría del vigésimo siglo, sin embargo, del 
empuje para o contra el ahorro de la hora solar vino de negocios. 
Los fabricantes de mercancías, de briquetas del carbón de 
leña, y de repulsivo del mosquito que se divertían continuaron 
financiando "una coalición nacional del ahorro de la hora solar" para
cabildear por un período extendido del "tiempo rápido." La 
industria de la película, sin embargo, resistió de largo el ahorro 
de la hora solar. En esta carta 1930 a E. B. Duerr de los 
estudios del camino, el presidente de los teatros del oeste de la 
costa del zorro advirtió de las consecuencias económicas calamitosas
para la industria de película si California adoptó el ahorro de la 
hora solar.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087159</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105990</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/unlimited-possibilities-for-evil-hollywood-resists-daylight-saving</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
