<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103103</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103103</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087050</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Shame of the Cities: Steffens on Urban Blight</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Schande der Städte: Steffens auf 
städtischer Trockenfäule</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La honte des villes : Steffens sur la rouille
urbaine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O shame das cidades: Steffens no blight 
urbano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Vergogna delle città: Steffens su 
ruggine urbana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ντροπή των πόλεων: Steffens στην αστική 
σήψη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La vergüenza de las ciudades: Steffens en 
destrozo urbano</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the 1890s, changes in printing technology made possible inexpensive magazines that could appeal to a broader and increasingly more literate middle-class audience. Given the reform impulses popular in the early 20th century, many of these magazines featured reform-oriented investigative reporting that became known as "muckraking" (so named by President Theodore Roosevelt after the muckrake in Bunyan's  Pilgrim's Progress  who could "look no way but downward, with a muckrake in his hands"). In October 1902  McClure's   Magazine  published what many consider the first muckraking article, Lincoln Steffens' "Tweed Days in St. Louis." The "muckrakers" wrote on many subjects, such as child labor, prisons, religion, corporations, and insurance companies. But urban political corruption remained a particularly popular target, and in 1904 Steffens collected and published his writings on St. Louis, Minneapolis, Pittsburgh, Philadelphia, Chicago, and New York as  The Shame of the Cities . The Introduction, below, suggested his overall conclusions about political corruption.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im 1890s bildeten Änderungen in 
druckentechnologie mögliche billige Zeitschriften, die einem 
ausgedehnteren und in zunehmendem Maße gebildeteren 
Mittelklassepublikum gefallen konnten. Die Verbesserungantriebe 
gegeben, die im frühen 20. Jahrhundert populär sind, kennzeichneten 
viele dieser Zeitschriften verbessern-orientiertes Untersuchungs, 
über das berichtend, wurden bekannt, wie "muckraking" (also benannt 
durch Präsidenten Theodore Roosevelt nach dem muckrake im Fortschritt
des Pilgrims Bunyans, der "keine Methode schauen könnte aber 
abwärts, mit einem muckrake in seinen Händen"). Im Oktober 
1902 McClures veröffentlichte Zeitschrift was viele für den ersten 
muckraking Artikel halten, Lincoln Steffens' "Tweed-Tage in St. 
Louis." Die "muckrakers" schrieben auf viele Themen, wie 
Kinderarbeit, Gefängnisse, Religion, Korporationen und 
Versicherungsgesellschaften. Aber städtische politische 
Korruption blieb ein besonders populäres Ziel, und 1904 sammelte 
Steffens und veröffentlichte seine Schreiben auf St. Louis, 
Minneapolis, Pittsburgh, Philadelphia, Chicago und New York als die 
Schande der Städte. Die Einleitung schlug unten seine gesamten 
Zusammenfassungen über politische Korruption vor.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans le 1890s, les changements de la technologie 
d'impression ont fait les magasins peu coûteux possibles qui 
pourraient faire appel à une plus large et de plus en plus plus 
instruite assistance de classe moyenne. Etant donné les 
impulsions de réforme populaires en début du 20ème siècle, 
plusieurs de ces magasins ont comporté investigateur 
reformer-orienté enregistrant cela sont devenus notoires comme 
"muckraking" (ainsi nommé par le Président Theodore Roosevelt après
le muckrake dans le progrès du pélerin de Bunyan qui ne pourrait 
"regarder aucune voie mais en bas, avec un muckrake dans des ses 
mains"). En octobre 1902 McClure le magasin a édité ce que 
beaucoup considèrent le premier article muckraking, jours de tweed de
Lincoln Steffens des "à St Louis." Les "muckrakers" ont écrit 
sur beaucoup de sujets, tels que le travail des enfants, prisons, 
religion, sociétés, et compagnies d'assurance. Mais la 
corruption politique urbaine est demeurée une cible particulièrement
populaire, et en 1904 Steffens a rassemblé et a édité ses 
écritures sur St Louis, Minneapolis, Pittsburgh, Philadelphie, 
Chicago, et New York comme honte des villes. L'introduction, 
ci-dessous, a suggéré ses conclusions générales au sujet de la 
corruption politique.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No 1890s, as mudanças na tecnologia imprimindo 
fizeram os compartimentos baratos possíveis que poderiam apelar a uma
audiência mais larga e cada vez mais mais literate do middle-class. 
Dado os impulsos da reforma populares no 20o século adiantado, 
muitos destes compartimentos caracterizaram investigative 
reform-orientado relatando isso tornaram-se sabidos como "muckraking" 
(assim que nomeado pelo presidente Theodore Roosevelt após o muckrake
no progresso do pilgrim de Bunyan que não poderia "não olhar nenhuma
maneira mas para baixo, com um muckrake em suas mãos"). Em 
outubro 1902 McClure o compartimento publicou o que muitos consideram 
o primeiro artigo muckraking, dias tweed de Lincoln Steffens' do "em 
St. Louis." Os "muckrakers" escreveram em muitos assuntos, tais 
como o trabalho de criança, em prisões, em religião, em 
corporation, e em companhias de seguro. Mas o corruption 
político urbano remanesceu um alvo particularmente popular, e em 1904
Steffens coletou e publicou suas escritas em St. Louis, Minneapolis, 
Pittsburgh, Filadélfia, Chicago, e New York como o shame das cidades.
A introdução, abaixo, sugeriu suas conclusões totais sobre o 
corruption político.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nel 1890s, i cambiamenti nella tecnologia di stampa
hanno fatto gli scomparti economici possibili che potrebbero fare 
appello ad un più vasto e pubblico sempre più più literate della 
classe media. Dato gli impulsi di riforma popolari nell'inizio 
del 20esimo secolo, molti di questi scomparti hanno caratterizzato 
investigativo riform-orientato segnalando quello sono stato conosciuti
come "muckraking" (in modo da chiamato dal presidente Theodore 
Roosevelt dopo il muckrake nel progresso del pilgrim del Bunyan che 
non potrebbe "non osservare modo ma verso il basso, con un muckrake in
sue mani"). Nel mese di ottobre 1902 McClure lo scomparto ha 
pubblicato che cosa molti considerano il primo articolo muckraking, 
giorni del tweed de Lincoln Steffens "a St. Louis." "i 
muckrakers" hanno scritto su molti oggetti, quale il lavoro del 
bambino, sulle prigioni, sulla religione, sulle società e sulle 
società di assicurazioni. Ma la corruzione politica urbana è 
rimasto un obiettivo particolarmente popolare ed in 1904 Steffens ha 
raccolto e pubblicato le sue scritture su St. Louis, su Minneapolis, 
su Pittsburgh, su Filadelfia, su Chicago e su New York come la 
Vergogna delle città. L'introduzione, sotto, ha suggerito le
sue conclusioni generali circa la corruzione politica.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στο 1890s, οι αλλαγές στην τεχνολογία εκτύπωσης 
έκαναν τα πιθανά ανέξοδα περιοδικά που θα μπορούσαν να 
απευθυνθούν σε ένα ευρύτερο και όλο και περισσότερο περισσότερο 
εγγράμματο ακροατήριο μεσαίων τάξεων. Λαμβάνοντας υπόψη 
τις ωθήσεις μεταρρύθμισης δημοφιλείς στις αρχές του 20ού αιώνα, 
πολλά από αυτά τα περιοδικά χαρακτήρισαν την 
μεταρρύθμιση-προσανατολισμένη στον εξεταστική υποβολή έκθεσης που
έγινε γνωστή όπως "muckraking" (έτσι ονομασμένος από τον 
Πρόεδρο Theodore Roosevelt μετά από το muckrake στην 
πρόοδο του προσκυνητή Bunyan που δεν θα μπορούσε "να φανεί 
κανένας τρόπος αλλά προς τα κάτω, με ένα muckrake στα χέρια 
του"). Στο περιοδικό McClure's Οκτωβρίου 1902 που 
δημοσιεύεται τι πολλοί θεωρούν το πρώτο muckraking άρθρο, 
ημέρες τουίντ του Λίνκολν Steffens "στο ST Louis." 
Τα "muckrakers" έγραψαν σε πολλά θέματα, όπως η παιδική 
εργασία, τις φυλακές, τη θρησκεία, τις εταιρίες, και τις 
ασφαλιστικές εταιρείες. Αλλά η αστική πολιτική δωροδοκία 
παρέμεινε ένας ιδιαίτερα δημοφιλής στόχος, και το 1904 
Steffens συνέλεξε και δημοσίευσε τις γραφές του στο ST 
Louis, Μινεάπολη, Πίτσμπουργκ, Φιλαδέλφεια, Σικάγο, και Νέα 
Υόρκη ως ντροπή των πόλεων. Η εισαγωγή, κατωτέρω, πρότεινε
τα γενικά συμπεράσματά του για την πολιτική δωροδοκία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En el 1890s, los cambios en tecnología de 
impresión hicieron los compartimientos baratos posibles que podrían 
abrogar a una audiencia más amplia y cada vez más más que sabe leer
y escribir de la clase media. Dado los impulsos de la reforma 
populares en el vigésimo siglo temprano, muchos de estos 
compartimientos ofrecieron investigador reformar-orientada señalando 
eso se conocían como "muckraking" (así que nombrado por presidente 
Theodore Roosevelt después del muckrake en el progreso del peregrino 
de Bunyan que no podría "mirar ninguna manera pero hacia abajo, con 
un muckrake en sus manos"). En octubre 1902 de McClure el 
compartimiento publicó lo que consideran muchos el primer artículo 
muckraking, días del tweed de Lincoln Steffens los "en St. Louis." 
Los "muckrakers" escribieron en muchos temas, tales como trabajo
de niño, prisiones, la religión, corporaciones, y compañías de 
seguros. Pero la corrupción política urbana seguía siendo una
blanco determinado popular, y en 1904 Steffens recogió y publicó sus
escrituras en St. Louis, Minneapolis, Pittsburgh, Philadelphia, 
Chicago, y Nueva York como la vergüenza de las ciudades. La 
introducción, abajo, sugirió sus conclusiones totales sobre la 
corrupción política.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087050</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103103</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-shame-of-the-cities-steffens-on-urban-blight</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
