<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108676</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108676</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087306</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"A harvest of death, Gettysburg, July 1863."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"eine Ernte des Todes, Gettysburg, Juli 1863."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"une moisson de la mort, Gettysburg, juillet 
1863."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"uma colheita da morte, Gettysburg, julho 1863."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"una raccolta della morte, Gettysburg, luglio del 
1863."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Μια συγκομιδή του θανάτου, Gettysburg, Ιούλιος 
1863."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"una cosecha de la muerte, Gettysburg, julio de 
1863."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Photographers covered the Civil War, following the Union Army in wagons that served as traveling darkrooms. Their equipment was bulky and the exposures had to be long, so they could not take action photographs during battle. But photography was graphic; this picture taken on the morning of July 4th, 1863 after three days of heavy fighting during the Battle of Gettysburg, showed the northern public that dying in battle lacked the gallantry often represented in paintings and prints.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Photographen umfaßten den Bürgerkrieg und folgten der 
Anschluß-Armee in den Lastwagen, die als reisende Dunkelkammern 
dienten. Ihre Ausrüstung war umfangreich und die Berührungen 
mußten lang sein, also konnten sie nicht Tätigkeit Fotographien 
während der Schlacht nehmen. Aber Fotographie war graphisch; 
dieses Photo, das auf den Morgen von Juli 4., 1863 nach drei 
Tagen des schweren Kämpfens während der Schlacht von Gettysburg 
gemacht wurde, zeigte der Nordöffentlichkeit, daß das Sterben in der
Schlacht den Edelmut ermangelte, der häufig in den Anstrichen und in 
den Drucken dargestellt wurde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les photographes ont couvert la guerre civile, suivant 
l'armée des syndicats dans des chariots qui ont servi de cabinets 
noirs de déplacement. Leur matériel était encombrant et les 
expositions ont dû être longues, ainsi elles ne pourraient pas agir 
des photographies pendant la bataille. Mais la photographie 
était graphique ; cette photo prise le matin du 4 juillet, 1863
après trois jours de combat lourd pendant la bataille de Gettysburg, 
a prouvé au public nordique que la mort dans la bataille a manqué de
la galantery souvent représentée dans les peintures et les copies.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os fotógrafos cobriram a guerra civil, seguindo o 
exército de união nos vagões que serviram como câmaras escuras 
viajando. Seu equipamento era volumoso e as exposições tiveram
que ser longas, assim que não poderiam fazer exame de fotografias da 
ação durante a batalha. Mas a fotografia era gráfica; 
este retrato feito exame na manhã julho de ô, 1863 após três
dias da luta pesada durante a batalha de Gettysburg, mostrou ao 
público do norte que morrer na batalha faltou o gallantry 
representado frequentemente nas pinturas e nas cópias.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I photographers hanno riguardato la guerra civile, 
seguente l'esercito del sindacato in vagoni che hanno servito da 
darkrooms mobili. La loro apparecchiatura era ingombrante e le 
esposizioni hanno dovuto essere lunghe, in modo da non potrebbero 
agire le fotografie durante la battaglia. Ma la fotographia era 
grafica; questa immagine presa sulla mattina del de 4 luglio 
1863 dopo tre giorni di combattimento pesante durante la battaglia di 
Gettysburg, ha indicato al pubblico nordico che morire nella battaglia
difettava del gallantry rappresentato spesso nelle pitture ed in 
stampe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι φωτογράφοι κάλυψαν τον εμφύλιο πόλεμο, μετά από 
το στρατό ένωσης στα βαγόνια εμπορευμάτων που εξυπηρέτησαν όπως 
διακινούμενους σκοτεινούς θαλάμους. Ο εξοπλισμός τους ήταν 
ογκώδης και οι εκθέσεις έπρεπε να είναι μακροχρόνιες, έτσι δεν 
μπόρεσαν να πάρουν τις φωτογραφίες ενέργειας κατά τη διάρκεια 
της μάχης. Αλλά η φωτογραφία ήταν γραφική  αυτή η 
εικόνα που λήφθηκε στο πρωί της 4$ης Ιουλίου, 1863 μετά από 
τρεις ημέρες της βαριάς πάλης κατά τη διάρκεια της μάχης 
Gettysburg, εμφάνισε βόρειο κοινό που ο θάνατος στη μάχη 
στερήθηκε τον gallantry που αντιπροσωπεύθηκε συχνά στα έργα 
ζωγραφικής και τις τυπωμένες ύλες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los fotógrafos cubrieron la guerra civil, siguiendo al 
ejército de unión en los carros que sirvieron como cuartos oscuros 
que viajaban. Su equipo era abultado y las exposiciones tuvieron
que ser largas, así que no podrían tomar las fotografías de la 
acción durante batalla. Pero la fotografía era gráfica; 
este cuadro adquirido la mañana del de julio 4 de 1863 después
de tres días de luchar pesado durante la batalla de Gettysburg, 
mostró a público norteño que el morir en batalla faltó el 
gallantry representado a menudo en pinturas e impresiones.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087306</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108676</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-harvest-of-death-gettysburg-july-1863</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
