<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105397</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105397</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203048</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">HABHRCA: The Harmful Algal Bloom and Hypoxia Research and Control Act</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">HABHRCA: Die schädliche Algenblüte und die
Hypoxie-Forschung und Steuertat</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">HABHRCA : La fleur et Loi des recherches et 
de la commande d'algues nocives d'hypoxie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">HABHRCA: Ato a flor e da pesquisa e do 
controle algal prejudiciais do hypoxia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">HABHRCA: Legge la fioritura e di ricerca e 
di controllo d'alghe nocivi di ipossia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">HABHRCA: Νόμος η επιβλαβούς φυκώδους άνθιση 
και hypoxia της έρευνας και ελέγχου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">HABHRCA: Acto la floración y de la 
investigación y del control algal dañosos del hypoxia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This website describes HABHRCA, a legislative Act that authorizes funding for research on harmful algal blooms (HABs) and hypoxia to advance scientific understanding and our ability to detect, assess, predict, control, and mitigate events. The site discusses the Act, gives an overview of The Interagency Task Force on Harmful Algal Blooms and Hypoxia, and features links to past plans and reports called for by HABHRCA 1998. It also serves as a jumping point to conferences and workshops, pertinent documents, and other informational resources.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Web site beschreibt HABHRCA, eine 
gesetzgebende Tat, die die Finanzierung autorisiert für Forschung auf
schädlicher Algenblüte (HABs) und Hypoxie, zum des 
Wissenschaftsverständnisses und unserer Fähigkeit vorzurücken, 
Fälle zu entdecken, festzusetzen, vorauszusagen, zu steuern und 
abzuschwächen. Die Site behandelt die Tat, gibt einen 
Überblick über die Vermittlungsagentur-Task Force auf schädlicher 
Algenblüte und Hypoxie und kennzeichnet Links zu den letzten Plänen 
und zu den Reports, die von HABHRCA 1998 verlangt werden. Sie 
dient auch als springender Punkt zu den Konferenzen und Werkstätten, 
passende Dokumente und andere informatorische Betriebsmittel.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site Web décrit HABHRCA, une Loi législative 
qui autorise le placement pour la recherche sur les fleurs d'algues 
nocives (HABs) et l'hypoxie pour avancer l'arrangement scientifique 
et notre capacité de détecter, évaluer, prévoir, contrôler, et 
atténuer des événements. Le site discute l'acte, donne une 
vue d'ensemble de la médiation Chargent la force sur les 
fleurs et l'hypoxie d'algues nocives, et comportent des liens aux 
plans passés et aux états nécessités par HABHRCA 1998. Il 
sert également de point branchant aux conférences et les ateliers, 
les documents convenables, et d'autres ressources informationnelles.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Web site descreve HABHRCA, um ato legislativo
que autorize financiar para a pesquisa sobre flores algal prejudiciais
(HABs) e hypoxia para avançar a compreensão científica e a nossa 
abilidade de detectar, avaliar, predizer, controlar, e mitigate 
eventos. O local discute o ato, dá uma vista geral da força de
tarefa do interagency em flores e no hypoxia algal prejudiciais, e 
caracteriza as ligações às plantas passadas e aos relatórios 
chamados para por HABHRCA 1998. Serve também como um ponto 
saltando às conferências e as oficinas, originais pertinentes, e 
outros recursos informativos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Web site descrive HABHRCA, una Legge 
legislativa che autorizza costituire un fondo per per la ricerca sulle
fioriture d'alghe nocive (HABs) e sull'ipossia per avanzare la 
conoscenza scientifica e la nostra capacità di rilevare, valutare, 
predire, gestire ed attenuare gli eventi. Il luogo discute la 
Legge, dà una descrizione del gruppo di esperti di mediazione sulle 
fioriture e sull'ipossia d'alghe nocive e caratterizza i collegamenti 
ai programmi passati ed ai rapporti richiesti da HABHRCA 1998. 
Egualmente serve da punto di salto ai congressi e workshop, 
documenti pertinenti ed altre risorse informative.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος περιγράφει HABHRCA, ένας 
νομοθετικός νόμος που επιτρέπει στη χρηματοδότηση για την έρευνα 
για τις επιβλαβείς φυκώδεις ανθίσεις (HABs) και hypoxia για 
να προωθήσει την επιστημονική κατανόηση και τη δυνατότητά μας να 
ανιχνεύσουμε, να αξιολογήσουμε, να προβλέψουμε, να ελέγξουμε, και 
να μετριάσουμε τα γεγονότα. Η περιοχή συζητά το νόμο, 
δίνει μια επισκόπηση της ομάδας εργασίας οργανισμού 
διαμεσολάβησης στις επιβλαβή φυκώδη ανθίσεις και hypoxia, και 
χαρακτηρίζει τις συνδέσεις με τα προηγούμενα σχέδια και τις 
εκθέσεις που απαιτούνται από HABHRCA το 1998. 
Χρησιμεύει επίσης ως ένα πηδώντας σημείο στις διασκέψεις 
και τα εργαστήρια, τα σχετικά έγγραφα, και άλλα ενημερωτικά 
στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este Web site describe HABHRCA, un acto 
legislativo que autorice el financiamiento para la investigación 
sobre las floraciones algal dañosas (HABs) y el hypoxia para avanzar 
la comprensión científica y nuestra capacidad de detectar, de 
evaluar, de predecir, de controlar, y de atenuar acontecimientos. 
El sitio discute el acto, da una descripción del destacamento 
de fuerzas de la interagencia en las floraciones y el hypoxia algal 
dañosos, y ofrece conexiones a los últimos planes y a los informes 
llamados para por HABHRCA 1998. También sirve como punta que 
salta a las conferencias y los talleres, los documentos pertinentes, y
otros recursos informativos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR SPONSORED COASTAL OCEAN RESEARCH (CSCOR)
FN:CENTER FOR SPONSORED COASTAL OCEAN RESEARCH (CSCOR)
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:NOAA
FN:NOAA
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203048</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Public Domain</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105397</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/habhrca-the-harmful-algal-bloom-and-hypoxia-research-and-control-act</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
