<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103149</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103149</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086991</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Molly Maguires.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Molly Maguires.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Molly Maguires.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Molly Maguires.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Molly Maguires.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Molly Maguires.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Molly Maguires.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the winter of 1876, testimony from a Pinkerton Detective Agency operative was used to destroy the Pennsylvania miners union, as 20 miners were accused of membership in a militant Irish organization called the Molly Maguires, convicted of murder, and hanged. The negative publicity from the trial effectively killed unionism in Pennsylvania mining for twenty years. This picture illustrated  The Mollie Maguires and the Detectives , Allan Pinkerton's self-serving account of his detective agency's infiltration of the secret society of miners. Pinkerton's work in the service of the Reading Railroad typified the widespread use of private police and organized violence by railroads and other businesses to suppress unions.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im Winter von 1876, wurde Zeugnis von einem Pinkerton 
Detektivbüroarbeiter verwendet, um den Pennsylvania Bergmananschluß 
zu zerstören, da 20 Bergmänner von der Mitgliedschaft in einer 
militanten irischen genannten den Molly Maguires beschuldigt wurden, 
überführten des Mordes, und gehangenen Organisation. Die 
negative Werbung vom Versuch beendete effektiv unionism in 
Pennsylvania, das nach Zwanzig Jahren gewinnt. Diese Abbildung 
veranschaulichte das Mollie Maguires und die Detektive, Allan 
Pinkertons self-serving Konto von seiner Infiltration des 
Detektivbüros der geheimen Gesellschaft der Bergmänner. Arbeit
Pinkertons im Service der Leseeisenbahn verkörperte den 
weitverbreiteten Gebrauch von privater Polizei und organisierte 
Gewalttätigkeit durch Eisenbahnen und andere Geschäfte, um 
Anschlüße zu unterdrücken.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En hiver de 1876, le témoignage d'un employé d'agence de
détectives de Pinkerton a été employé pour détruire l'union de 
mineurs de la Pennsylvanie, car 20 mineurs ont été accusés de 
l'adhésion dans une organisation irlandaise militante appelée le 
molly Maguires, condamnée du meurtre, et arrêtée. La 
publicité négative de l'épreuve a pertinemment détruit le 
syndicalisme en Pennsylvanie extrayant pendant vingt années. 
Cette image a illustré le Mollie Maguires et les détectives, 
compte de art de l'auto-portrait-serving de Allan Pinkerton de sa infiltration de 
l'agence de détectives de la société secrète des mineurs. Le
travail de Pinkerton dans le service du chemin de fer de lecture a 
caractérisé l'utilisation répandue de la police privée et a 
organisé la violence par des chemins de fer et d'autres entreprises 
pour supprimer des syndicats.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No inverno de 1876, o testimony de um operative da 
agência detective de Pinkerton foi usado destruir a união dos 
mineiros de Pensilvânia, porque 20 mineiros foram acusados da 
sociedade em uma organização irish militant chamada o molly 
Maguires, convicted do assassinato, e pendurada. O publicity 
negativo da experimentação matou eficazmente o unionism em 
Pensilvânia que mina por vinte anos. Este retrato ilustrou o 
Mollie Maguires e detetives, cliente self-serving de Allan Pinkerton 
de seu infiltration de agência detective da sociedade secreta dos 
mineiros. O trabalho de Pinkerton no serviço da estrada de 
ferro da leitura typified o uso difundido de polícias confidenciais e
organizou a violência por estradas de ferro e por outros negócios 
para suprimir uniões.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nell'inverno di 1876, la testimonianza da un operatore 
dell'agenzia detective di Pinkerton è stata usata per 
distruggere l'unione dei minatori della Pensilvania, poichè 20 
minatori sono stati accusati dell'insieme dei membri in 
un'organizzazione irlandese del militante chiamata il molly 
Maguires, condannata dell'omicidio ed appesa. La pubblicità 
negativa dalla prova ha ucciso efficacemente il unionism in 
Pensilvania che estrae venti anni. Questa immagine ha illustrato
il Mollie Maguires ed i detectivi, cliente self-serving del Allan 
Pinkerton della sua infiltrazione dell'agenzia detective della 
società segreta dei minatori. Il lavoro del Pinkerton nel 
servizio della ferrovia della lettura ha caratterizzato l'uso molto 
diffuso della polizia riservata ed ha organizzato la violenza dalle 
ferrovie e da altri commerci per sopprimere i sindacati.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το χειμώνα 1876, η κατάθεση από έναν χειριστή 
αντιπροσωπείας ιδιωτικών αστυνομικών Pinkerton χρησιμοποιήθηκε 
για να καταστρέψει την ένωση ανθρακωρύχων της Πενσυλβανίας, όπως 
20 ανθρακωρύχοι κατηγορήθηκαν για την ιδιότητα μέλους σε μια 
στρατευμένη ιρλανδική οργάνωση αποκαλούμενη Molly Maguires, 
που καταδικάστηκε της δολοφονίας, και που κρεμάστηκε. Η 
αρνητική δημοσιότητα από τη δοκιμή σκότωσε αποτελεσματικά το 
συνδικαλισμό στη μεταλλεία της Πενσυλβανίας για είκοσι έτη. 
Αυτή η εικόνα επεξήγησε το Mollie Maguires και τους 
ιδιωτικούς αστυνομικούς, μόνος-εξυπηρετώντας απολογισμός του 
Allan Pinkerton's της διήθησης της αντιπροσωπείας ιδιωτικών 
αστυνομικών του της μυστικής κοινωνίας των ανθρακωρύχων. Η 
εργασία του Pinkerton στην υπηρεσία του σιδηροδρόμου ανάγνωσης 
απεικόνισε τη διαδεδομένη χρήση της ιδιωτικής αστυνομίας και 
οργάνωσε τη βία από τους σιδηροδρόμους και άλλες επιχειρήσεις 
για να καταστείλει τις ενώσεις.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En el invierno de 1876, el testimonio de un operario de la
agencia detective de Pinkerton fue utilizado para destruir la unión 
de los mineros de Pennsylvania, pues acusaron a 20 mineros de calidad 
de miembro en una organización irlandesa militante llamada el molly
Maguires, condenada por asesinato, y colgada. La publicidad 
negativa del ensayo mató con eficacia a unionism en Pennsylvania que 
minaba por veinte años. Este cuadro ilustró el Mollie Maguires
y los detectives, cuenta self-serving de Allan Pinkerton de su 
infiltración de la agencia detective de la sociedad secreta de 
mineros. El trabajo de Pinkerton en el servicio del ferrocarril 
de la lectura caracterizó el uso extenso del policía privado y 
ordenó violencia por los ferrocarriles y otros negocios para suprimir
uniones.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086991</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103149</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-molly-maguires</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
