<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106640</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106640</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206172</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Exploring Earth: Visualizations</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erforschende Masse: Sichtbarmachungen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Terre L'explorant : Visualisations</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Terra Explorando: Visualizations</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Terra D'Esplorazione: Visualizzazioni</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εξερεύνηση της γης: Απεικονίσεις</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Tierra Que explora: Visualizaciones</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features over 100 animations and images that illuminate key concepts in earth science. Examples are: coal formation, nuclear fission, growth of a continent, tectonic plate movement, volcanoes and earthquakes, fault motion, geyser eruption, wave motion, tornadoes, hurricanes, and more. Students can observe a single place on earth from multiple views, 3-D models of water and common molecules, different climate zones, and seasonal changes in the amount of sunlight reaching locations on earth.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Merkmale über 100 Animationen und Bildern, die 
Schlüsselkonzepte in der Geowissenschaft belichten. Beispiele 
sind: Kohleanordnung, Kernspaltung, Wachstum einer continent, 
tectonic Platte Bewegung, der Vulkane und der Erdbeben, der Störung 
Bewegung, der Geysireruption, der Welle Bewegung, der Tornados, der 
Hurrikane und mehr. Kursteilnehmer können einen einzelnen Platz
auf Masse von den mehrfachen Ansichten, von den Modellen 3-D des 
Wassers und der geläufigen Moleküle, von den unterschiedlichen 
Klimazonen und von den Saisonänderungen in der Menge der erreichenden
Standorte des Tageslichtes auf Masse beobachten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dispositifs plus de 100 animations et images qui 
illuminent les concepts principaux en science de la terre. Les 
exemples sont : formation de charbon, fission nucléaire, 
croissance d'un mouvement de plat, des volcans et des tremblements de 
terre, d'un mouvement de défaut, d'une éruption de geyser, d'un 
mouvement de vague, des tornades, des ouragans, et d'un plus 
continents et tectoniques. Les étudiants peuvent observer un 
endroit simple sur terre des vues multiples, des modèles 3-D de l'eau
et des molécules communes, de différentes zones de climat, et des 
changements saisonniers de la quantité d'emplacements d'atteinte de 
lumière du soleil sur terre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">características sobre 100 animations e imagens 
que iluminam os conceitos chaves na ciência de terra. Os 
exemplos são: formação de carvão, fission nuclear, 
crescimento de um movimento da placa, de uns vulcões e de uns 
terremotos, de um movimento da falha, de um eruption do geyser, de um 
movimento da onda, de uns furacões, de uns furacões, e de um mais 
continent, tectonic. Os estudantes podem observar um único 
lugar na terra das vistas múltiplas, dos modelos 3-D da água e de 
moléculas comuns, das zonas diferentes do clima, e das mudanças 
seasonal na quantidade de posições alcançando da luz solar na 
terra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">caratteristiche oltre 100 animazioni ed immagini 
che illuminano i concetti chiave nelle scienze della terra. Gli 
esempi sono: formazione del carbone, fissione nucleare, sviluppo
di un movimento della piastra, dei vulcani e dei terremoti, di un 
movimento del difetto, di un eruption del geyser, di un movimento 
dell'onda, dei cicloni, degli uragani e di un più continent e 
tettonici. Gli allievi possono osservare un singolo posto su 
terra dalle viste multiple, dai modelli 3-D di acqua e delle molecole 
comuni, dalle zone differenti di clima e dai cambiamenti stagionali 
nella quantità di posizioni raggiungenti di luce solare su terra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα άνω των 100 ζωτικοτήτων 
και εικόνων που φωτίζουν τις βασικές έννοιες στη γήινη επιστήμη.
Τα παραδείγματα είναι: σχηματισμός άνθρακα, πυρηνική 
διάσπαση, αύξηση μιας ηπείρου, μιας τεκτονικής μετακίνησης 
πιάτων, των ηφαιστείων και των σεισμών, της κίνησης βλαβών, 
geyser της έκρηξης, της κίνησης κυμάτων, των ανεμοστροβίλων, 
των τυφώνων, και περισσότεροι. Οι σπουδαστές μπορούν να 
παρατηρήσουν μια ενιαία θέση στη γη από τις πολλαπλάσιες όψεις, 
τα τρισδιάστατα μοντέλα του ύδατος και των κοινών μορίων, τις 
διαφορετικές ζώνες κλίματος, και τις εποχιακές αλλαγές στο ποσό 
φωτός του ήλιου που φθάνει στις θέσεις στη γη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">características sobre 100 animaciones e imágenes
que iluminan los conceptos dominantes en geología. Los ejemplos
son: formación del carbón, fisión nuclear, crecimiento de un 
movimiento de la placa, de volcanes y de terremotos, de un movimiento 
del incidente, de una erupción del géiser, de un movimiento de la 
onda, de tornados, de huracanes, y más continentes, tectónicos. 
Los estudiantes pueden observar un solo lugar en la tierra de 
vistas múltiples, de los modelos 3-D del agua y de las moléculas 
comunes, de diversas zonas del clima, y de cambios estacionales en la 
cantidad de localizaciones que alcanzan de la luz del sol en la 
tierra.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206172</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106640</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/exploring-earth-visualizations-1</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
