<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103681</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103681</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204347</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Practicing Elaboration in a Problem/Solution Essay</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Übende Ausarbeitung in einem Problem/Solution 
Versuch</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Élaboration de pratique dans un essai de 
Problem/Solution</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Elaboration praticando em um essay de 
Problem/Solution</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Elaborazione esercitantesi in un saggio di 
Problem/Solution</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επεξεργασία άσκησης σε ένα δοκίμιο προβλήματος/λύσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Elaboración practicante en un ensayo de 
Problem/Solution</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">One theory suggests that students tend to list in an essay because they lack the tools to elaborate. Because they do not have the strategies, they attempt to fill up the empty space by introducing new primary ideas instead of fleshing out the ideas they have already presented. This activity attempts to make students aware of the need to elaborate and to provide students with some workable strategies for elaborating. Using a PowerPoint presentation, the teacher demonstrates the necessity for elaboration in a problem/solution essay. Students then choose a particular point in the PowerPoint presentation to expand through elaboration.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Theorie schlägt vor, daß Kursteilnehmer 
neigen, in einem Versuch auszudrucken, weil sie die Hilfsmittel 
ermangeln, um auszuarbeitn. Weil sie nicht die Strategien haben,
versuchen sie, den leeren Platz oben zu füllen, indem sie neue 
Primärideen anstelle von der Ausfleischung aus den Ideen vorstellen, 
die sie bereits sich dargestellt haben. Diese Aktivität 
versucht, Kursteilnehmer bewußt zu bilden der Notwendigkeit, und 
Kursteilnehmer mit etwas bearbeitbaren Strategien zu versehen 
auszuarbeitn am Ausarbeitn. Mit einer PowerPoint Darstellung 
demonstriert der Lehrer die Notwendigkeit für Ausarbeitung in einem 
problem/solution Versuch. Kursteilnehmer beschließen dann einen
bestimmten Punkt in der PowerPoint Darstellung, um durch Ausarbeitung 
zu erweitern.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une théorie suggère que les étudiants tendent 
à énumérer dans un essai parce qu'ils manquent des outils pour 
élaborer. Puisqu'ils n'ont pas les stratégies, ils essayent de
remplir l'espace vide en présentant de nouvelles idées primaires au 
lieu de l'écharnage hors des idées qu'ils ont déjà présentées. 
Cette activité essaye de mettre au courant des étudiants du 
besoin d'élaborer et de fournir à des étudiants quelques 
stratégies réalisables de l'élaboration. En utilisant une 
présentation de PowerPoint, le professeur démontre la nécessité 
pour l'élaboration dans un essai de problem/solution. Les 
étudiants choisissent alors un point particulier dans la 
présentation de PowerPoint pour augmenter par l'élaboration.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uma teoria sugere que os estudantes tendem a 
alistar em um essay porque faltam as ferramentas para elaborar. 
Porque não têm as estratégias, tentam encher acima o espaço 
vazio introduzindo idéias preliminares novas em vez do fleshing para 
fora das idéias que se têm apresentado já. Esta atividade 
tenta fazer estudantes cientes da necessidade elaborar e fornecer 
estudantes com algumas estratégias workable para elaborar. 
Usando uma apresentação de PowerPoint, o professor demonstra a
necessidade para o elaboration em um essay de problem/solution. 
Os estudantes escolhem então um ponto particular na 
apresentação de PowerPoint expandir com o elaboration.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Una teoria suggerisce che gli allievi tendono ad 
elencare in un saggio perché difettano degli strumenti per elaborare.
Poiché non hanno le strategie, tentano di riempire in su lo 
spazio vuoto introducendo le nuove idee primarie anziché la 
scarnatura verso l'esterno le idee che già si sono presentati. 
Questa attività tenta di informare gli allievi della necessità
di elaborare e fornire agli allievi alcune strategie realizzabili per 
elaborare. Usando una presentazione del PowerPoint, l'insegnante
dimostra la necessità per elaborazione in un saggio di 
problem/solution. Gli allievi allora scelgono un punto 
particolare nella presentazione del PowerPoint per espandersi con 
elaborazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια θεωρία προτείνει ότι οι σπουδαστές τείνουν να 
εμφανίσουν λίστα σε ένα δοκίμιο επειδή στερούνται τα εργαλεία 
για να διαμορφώσουν. Επειδή δεν έχουν τις στρατηγικές, 
προσπαθούν να γεμίσουν επάνω το κενό διάστημα με την εισαγωγή 
των νέων αρχικών ιδεών αντί να σκληραγωγήσουν έξω τις ιδέες που
έχουν παρουσιάσει ήδη. Αυτή η δραστηριότητα προσπαθεί να 
καταστήσει τους σπουδαστές ενήμερους για την ανάγκη να 
διαμορφωθούν και να παρασχεθούν οι σπουδαστές μερικές εφαρμόσιμες
στρατηγικές για. Χρησιμοποιώντας μια παρουσίαση 
PowerPoint, ο δάσκαλος καταδεικνύει την ανάγκη για την 
επεξεργασία σε ένα δοκίμιο προβλήματος/λύσης. Οι 
σπουδαστές επιλέγουν έπειτα ένα ιδιαίτερο σημείο στην 
παρουσίαση PowerPoint που επεκτείνεται μέσω της επεξεργασίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una teoría sugiere que los estudiantes tiendan 
para enumerar en un ensayo porque faltan las herramientas para 
elaborar. Porque no tienen las estrategias, procuran llenar para
arriba el espacio vacío introduciendo nuevas ideas primarias en vez 
de descarnadura fuera de las ideas que han presentado ya. Esta 
actividad procura hacer a estudiantes enterados de la necesidad de 
elaborar y de proveer de estudiantes algunas estrategias realizables 
de elaborar. Usando una presentación de PowerPoint, el profesor
demuestra la necesidad para la elaboración en un ensayo de 
problem/solution. Los estudiantes entonces eligen una punta 
determinada en la presentación de PowerPoint para ampliarse con la 
elaboración.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MARGARET RYAN
FN:MARGARET RYAN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204347</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103681</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/practicing-elaboration-in-a-problem-solution-essay</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
