<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106549</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106549</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211788</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Quahog Fact Sheet</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Quahog Tatsache Blatt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Fiche documentaire  De Quahog</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Folha Do Fato De Quahog</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Foglio Di Fatto Di Quahog</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Quahog ενημερωτικό δελτίο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Hoja Del Hecho De Quahog</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Rhode Island Sea Grant Fact Sheet describes quahogs, a type of shellfish, and their role in commercial fishery. It includes information about quahog physical description, habitat preference, and the rise of quahog harvests in Rhode Island. The Fact Sheet concludes with a section describing how to dig up your own quahogs, shuck (open) them, and eat them.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Rhode-Insel Seegrant Tatsache Blatt 
beschreibt quahogs, einen Typen Schalentiere und ihre Rolle in der 
kommerziellen Fischerei. Es schließt Informationen über quahog
körperliche Beschreibung, Lebensraumpräferenz und den Anstieg der 
quahog Ernten in der Rhode-Insel ein. Das Tatsache Blatt folgert
mit einem Kapitel, das wie man herauf Ihre eigenen quahogs beschreibt,
gräbt, (sich öffnen) sie schält und sie ißt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette fiche documentaire  de Grant de mer 
d'île de Rhode décrit des quahogs, un type de mollusques et 
crustacés, et leur rôle dans la pêche commerciale. Elle 
inclut des informations sur la description physique de quahog, la 
préférence d'habitat, et l'élévation de moissons de quahog dans 
île de Rhode. La fiche documentaire  conclut avec une section 
décrivant comment creuser vers le haut de vos propres quahogs, les 
écosser (s'ouvrir), et les manger.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta folha do fato de Grant do mar do console de 
Rhode descreve quahogs, um tipo de marisco, e seu papel no fishery 
comercial. Inclui a informação sobre a descrição física do 
quahog, a preferência do habitat, e a ascensão de colheitas do 
quahog no console de Rhode. A folha do fato concli com uma 
seção que descreve como escavar acima de seus próprios quahogs, 
shuck (para abrir) os, e comê-los.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo foglio di fatto del Grant del mare 
dell'Rhode-isola descrive i quahogs, un tipo di crostacei ed il loro 
ruolo nell'industria della pesca commerciale. Include le 
informazioni sulla descrizione fisica del quahog, sulla preferenza 
dell'habitat e sull'aumento delle raccolte del quahog in Rhode-isola. 
Il foglio di fatto conclude con una sezione che descrive come 
scavare sui vostri propri quahogs, sgusciarli (aprirsi) e mangiarli.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το ενημερωτικό δελτίο επιχορήγησης θάλασσας της 
Ρόδου περιγράφει quahogs, έναν τύπο οστρακόδερμων, και το 
ρόλο τους στην εμπορική αλιεία. Περιλαμβάνει τις 
πληροφορίες για quahog τη φυσική περιγραφή, την προτίμηση 
βιότοπων, και την άνοδο quahog των συγκομιδών στη Ρόδο. 
Το ενημερωτικό δελτίο ολοκληρώνει με ένα τμήμα 
περιγράφοντας πώς να σκάψει επάνω quahogs σας, να τα 
ξεφλουδίσει (να ανοίξουν), και να τα φάει.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta hoja del hecho de Grant del mar de la 
Rhode-isla describe quahogs, un tipo de crustáceos, y su papel en 
industria pesquera comercial. Incluye la información sobre la 
descripción física del quahog, la preferencia del habitat, y la 
subida de cosechas del quahog en la Rhode-isla. La hoja del 
hecho concluye con una sección que describe cómo cavar encima de sus
propios quahogs, desvainarlos (abrirse), y comerlos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ELEANOR ELY
FN:ELEANOR ELY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:RHODE ISLAND SEA GRANT
FN:RHODE ISLAND SEA GRANT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211788</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106549</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/quahog-fact-sheet</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
