<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104888</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104888</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207200</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Savannah, Georgia: The Lasting Legacy of Colonial City Planning</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Savanne, Georgia: Die dauerhafte Legacy der 
Kolonialstadt-Planung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Savane, La Géorgie : Le legs durable de 
la planification de ville coloniale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Savannah, Geórgia: O legacy durável do 
planeamento de cidade colonial</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Savanna, Georgia: L'eredità durevole della 
pianificazione di città coloniale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σαβάνα, Γεωργία: Η μόνιμη κληρονομιά του 
αποικιακού προγραμματισμού πόλεων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sabana, Georgia: La herencia duradera de las
hojas de operación (planning) de ciudad coloniales</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">describes the establishing of Georgia as a colony in America and the design of the settlement. When a friend in jail for debt died there, General James Oglethorpe, a member of the House of Commons, asked Parliament for an investigation into the suffering of debtors in London jails. A committee concluded that a colony should be established in America for the poor. Oglethorpe led a sea voyage of 114 men, women, and children who hoped for a better opportunity in America.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">beschreibt das Herstellen von Georgia als Kolonie 
in Amerika und das Design der Regelung. Als ein Freund im 
Gefängnis für Schuld dort starb, General James Oglethorpe, ein 
Bauteil des Unterhauses, Parlament um eine Untersuchung in den 
Suffering der Schuldner in den London Gefängnissen gebeten. Ein
Ausschuß stellte fest, daß eine Kolonie in Amerika für die Armen 
hergestellt werden sollte. Oglethorpe führte eine Sereise von 
114 Männern, von Frauen und von Kindern, die für eine bessere 
Gelegenheit in Amerika hofften.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">décrit l'établissement de la Géorgie en tant 
que colonie en Amérique et la conception du règlement. Quand 
un ami en prison pour la dette est mort là, James général 
Oglethorpe, un membre de la Chambre des Communes, demandée le 
Parlement une recherche sur la douleur des débiteurs en prisons de 
Londres. Un comité a conclu qu'une colonie devrait être 
établie en Amérique pour les pauvres. Oglethorpe a mené un 
voyage de mer de 114 hommes, femmes, et enfants qui ont espéré une 
meilleure occasion en Amérique.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">descreve o estabelecimento de Geórgia como uma 
colônia em América e o projeto do estabelecimento. Quando um 
amigo na cadeia para o débito morreu lá, general James Oglethorpe, 
um membro da casa de terras comuns, pedida parliament uma 
investigação no sofrimento dos devedores em cadeias de Londres. 
Um comitê concliu que uma colônia deve ser estabelecida em 
América para os pobres. Oglethorpe conduziu a uma viagem do mar
de 114 homens, mulheres, e crianças que esperaram para uma 
oportunidade melhor em América.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">descrive la stabilizzazione della Georgia come 
colonia in America ed il disegno dello stabilimento. Quando un 
amico in prigione per il debito è morto là, General James 
Oglethorpe, un membro della Camera dei Comuni, chiesta al Parlamento 
una ricerca sul suffering dei debitori nelle prigioni de Londra. 
Un comitato ha concluso che una colonia dovrebbe essere 
stabilita in America per il povero. Oglethorpe ha condotto 
un viaggio del mare di 114 uomini, donne e bambini che hanno sperato 
per un'occasione migliore in America.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">περιγράφει την καθιέρωση της Γεωργίας ως αποικία στην 
Αμερική και το σχέδιο της τακτοποίησης. Όταν ένας φίλος 
στη φυλακή για το χρέος πέθανε εκεί, στρατηγός james 
Oglethorpe, ένα μέλος της Βουλής των Κοινοτήτων, ρώτησε το 
Κοινοβούλιο για μια έρευνα σχετικά με το βάσανο των χρεωστών στις
φυλακές του Λονδίνου. Μια επιτροπή κατέληξε στο συμπέρασμα 
ότι μια αποικία πρέπει να καθιερωθεί στην Αμερική για τους 
φτωχούς. Το Oglethorpe οδήγησε ένα ταξίδι θάλασσας των 
114 ανδρών, γυναικών, και παιδιών που ήλπισαν για μια καλύτερη
ευκαιρία στην Αμερική.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">describe establecer de Georgia como colonia en 
América y el diseño del establecimiento. Cuando un amigo en la
cárcel para la deuda murió allí, general James Oglethorpe, miembro 
de la Cámara de los Comunes, pedida el parlamento una investigación 
en el sufrimiento de deudores en las cárceles de Londres. Un 
comité concluyó que una colonia debe ser establecida en América 
para los pobres. Oglethorpe condujo un viaje del mar de 114 
hombres, mujeres, y niños que esperaban una oportunidad mejor en 
América.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207200</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104888</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/savannah-georgia-the-lasting-legacy-of-colonial-city-planning</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
