<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103548</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103548</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086341</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Is Bryan Crazy?": The  Times  Makes a Diagnosis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Ist Verrücktes Bryan?": Die Zeiten bildet 
eine Diagnose</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Est Bryan Fou?" : Les temps fait un 
diagnostic</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"É Bryan Louco?": Os tempos fazem um 
diagnóstico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"È Bryan Pazzesco?": I tempi fa una 
diagnosi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Είναι ο Bryan Crazy;": Οι χρόνοι κάνουν 
μια διάγνωση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Es Bryan Loco?": Los tiempos hacen una 
diagnosis</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Professional psychiatry was only in its infancy at the end of the 19th century, and many physicians disputed its scientific basis. In 1896, psychiatrists--or alienists as they were then called--entered the political arena in a controversy over the sanity of Democratic presidential candidate William Jennings Bryan. Bryan was heartily disliked by many middle-class urban professionals, precisely the sort of people who became alienists. In a letter to the New York  Times  of September 27, 1896, a self-identified anonymous "Alienist" declared that Bryan was of a "mind not entirely sound." In this editorial, published the same day, the  Times  soberly endorsed the psychiatrist's diagnosis. A few days later, it polled nine New York alienists, among them the leaders of the psychiatric profession, on Bryan's sanity: two refused comment; three believed him to be of "sound mind;" and four agreed with the "Alienist's" original diagnosis.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Professionelle Psychiatrie war nur in seiner 
Kindheit am Ende des 19. Jahrhunderts, und viele Ärzte diskutierten 
seine wissenschaftliche Grundlage. 1896 betraten Psychiater 
-- or alienists, während sie dann angerufen wurden -- die politische 
Arena in einer Kontroverse über der validité des demokratischen 
Präsidentenanwärters William Jennings Bryan. Bryan wurde 
herzlich von vielen Mittelklassestädtischen Fachleuten, genau die 
Sortierung von den Leuten abgelehnt, die alienists wurden. In 
einem Zeichen zu den New York Zeiten von September 27, 1896, ein 
self-identified anonymes "Alienist" erklärte, daß Bryan war von 
einem "Verstand nicht völlig stichhaltig." In diesem 
Leitartikel veröffentlicht der gleiche Tag, indossierten die Zeiten 
soberly die Psychiaterdiagnose. Einige Tage später, stimmte sie
neun New York alienists, unter ihnen die Führer des psychiatrischen 
Berufs, auf validité Bryans ab: zwei abgelehnter Kommentar; 
drei glaubten ihm, "vom stichhaltigen Verstand zu sein;" 
und vier stimmten mit der "des Alienists" ursprünglichen 
Diagnose überein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La psychiatrie professionnelle était seulement 
dans sa petite enfance à la fin du 19ème siècle, et beaucoup de 
médecins ont contesté sa base scientifique. En 1896, les 
psychiatres -- ou les aliénistes pendant qu'ils s'appelaient alors 
-- sont entrés dans l'arène politique dans une polémique au-dessus 
de la validité du candidat présidentiel démocratique William 
Jennings Bryan. Bryan a été chaleureusement détesté par 
beaucoup de professionnels urbains de classe moyenne, avec précision 
le tri des personnes qui sont devenues des aliénistes. Dans 
une lettre aux temps de New York septembre de 27, 1896, un 
"Aliéniste" anonyme de art de l'auto-portrait-identified a déclaré que Bryan 
était d'un "esprit pas entièrement sain." En cet éditorial, 
édité le même jour, les temps ont soberly approuvé le diagnostic 
du psychiatre. Quelques jours plus tard, il a voté neuf 
aliénistes de New York, parmi eux les amorces de la profession 
psychiatrique, sur la validité de Bryan : commentaire refusé 
par deux ; trois l'ont pensé être "d'esprit sain;" et 
quatre étaient conformes au diagnostic initial des "Aliénistes".</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O psychiatry profissional estava somente em seu 
infancy no fim do 1ø século, e muitos médicos disputaram sua base 
científica. Em 1896, os psychiatrists -- ou os alienists 
enquanto foram chamados então -- entraram na arena política em uma 
controvérsia sobre o sanity do candidato presidencial democrático 
William Jennings Bryan. Bryan foi não gostado heartily por 
muitos profissionais urbanos do middle-class, precisamente a sorte dos
povos que se transformaram alienists. Em uma letra aos tempos de
New York setembro de 27, 1896, um "Alienist anonymous self-identified"
declarou que Bryan era de uma "mente não inteiramente sadia." 
Neste editorial, publicado o mesmo dia, os tempos endossaram 
soberly o diagnóstico do psychiatrist. Alguns dias mais tarde, 
polled nove alienists de New York, entre eles os líderes da 
profissão psychiatric, no sanity de Bryan: comentário recusado
dois; três acreditaram-no ser "da mente sadia;" e quatro 
concordaram com o diagnóstico original do "Alienist".</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La psichiatria professionale era soltanto nella 
relativa infanzia alla conclusione del diciannovesimo secolo e molti 
medici hanno disputato la relativa base scientifica. In 1896, 
gli psychiatrists -- o alienists mentre allora sono stati chiamati -- 
hanno entrato nell'arena politica in una polemica sopra il sanity del 
candidato presidenziale democratico William Jennings Bryan. 
Bryan caloroso è stato avuto antipatia per da molti 
professionisti urbani della classe media, precisamente l'ordinamento 
della gente che si è transformata in in alienists. In una 
lettera ai tempi de New York de 27 settembre 1896, "un Alienist" 
anonimo self-identified ha dichiarato che Bryan era "di una mente non 
interamente sana." In questo editoriale, pubblicato lo stesso 
giorno, i tempi soberly hanno firmato la diagnosi dello psychiatrist. 
Alcuni giorni più successivamente, ha votato loro nove 
alienists de New York, i capi della professione psichiatrica, 
su sanity del Bryan: commento rifiutato due; tre lo hanno 
creduto essere "della mente sana;" e quattro hanno 
accosentito con la diagnosi originale "del Alienist".</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η επαγγελματική ψυχιατρική ήταν μόνο στα σπάργανα στο
τέλος του 19$ου αιώνα, και πολλοί παθολόγοι αμφισβήτησαν την 
επιστημονική βάση του. Το 1896, οι ψυχίατροι -- ή 
ψυχίατροι όπως κλήθηκαν έπειτα -- εισήγαγαν τον πολιτικό χώρο 
σε μια διαμάχη πέρα από τη λογικότητα του δημοκρατικού 
προεδρικού υποψηφίου William Jennings Bryan. Ο 
Bryan αντιπαθήθηκε εγκάρδια από πολλούς αστικούς 
επαγγελματίες μεσαίων τάξεων, ακριβώς το είδος των ανθρώπων που 
έγιναν ψυχίατροι. Σε μια επιστολή στους New York 
Times της 27ης Σεπτεμβρίου ..1896, ένας 
μόνος-προσδιορισμένος ανώνυμος "ψυχίατροσ" δήλωσε ότι ο Bryan
ήταν ενός "μυαλού όχι εξ ολοκλήρου υγιής." Σε αυτό το 
κύριο άρθρο, που δημοσιεύθηκε την ίδια μέρα, οι χρόνοι 
επικύρωσαν soberly τη διάγνωση του ψυχιάτρου. Μερικές 
ημέρες αργότερα, ψήφισε εννέα ψυχιάτρους της Νέας Υόρκης, 
μεταξύ τους οι ηγέτες του ψυχιατρικού επαγγέλματος, στη 
λογικότητα του Bryan: δύο που απορρίπτονται το σχόλιο  
τρία τον θεώρησαν "υγιούς μυαλού" και τέσσερα που 
συμφωνούνται με την αρχική διάγνωση του "ψυχιάτρου".</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La psiquiatría profesional estaba solamente en su
infancia en el final del diecinueveavo siglo, y muchos médicos 
disputaron su base científica. En 1896, los siquiatras -- o los
alienists mientras que les entonces llamaron -- entraron en la arena 
política en una controversia sobre la cordura del candidato 
presidencial democrático Guillermo Jennings Bryan. Bryan 
caluroso fue tenido aversión por muchos profesionales urbanos de la 
clase media, exacto la clase de la gente que hizo alienists. En 
una carta a los tiempos de Nueva York del de septiembre 27 de 1896, un
"Alienist anónimo autodefinido" declaró que Bryan estaba de una 
"mente no enteramente sana." En este editorial, publicado el 
mismo día, los tiempos soberly endosaron la diagnosis del siquiatra. 
Algunos días más adelante, votó nueve alienists de Nueva 
York, entre ellos los arranques de cinta de la profesión 
psiquiátrica, en la cordura de Bryan: comentario rechazado dos;
tres lo creyeron estar de "mente sana;" y cuatro 
convinieron con la diagnosis original del "Alienist".</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086341</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103548</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/is-bryan-crazy-the-times-makes-a-diagnosis</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
