<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108469</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108469</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086178</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Frick's Fracas: Henry Frick Makes His Case</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Fracas Fricks: Henry Frick Bildet Seinen 
Fall</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Vacarme de Frick : Henry Frick Fait 
Son Cas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fracas De Frick: O Henry Frick Faz Seu Caso</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fracas Del Frick: Il Henry Frick Fa Il Suo 
Caso</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Fracas Frick: Θ*Χενρυ Frick Makes 
His Case</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fracas De Frick: El Henrio Frick Hace Su 
Caso</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">During the 1892 strike at the Homestead Steel Works, plant manager Henry Clay Frick attempted to defeat the strikers forcibly by hiring three hundred armed agents of the notorious Pinkerton Detective Agency. The strikers fought back, and, after casualties and deaths on both sides, the Pinkertons surrendered. In the aftermath of the Pinkerton debacle, Frick spoke with a reporter for the Pittsburgh  Post . He laid out his implacable opposition to dealing with the union, his belief that the Pennsylvania governor should send in troops, and his goal of reducing wages at the plant, the central issue in the conflict. Frick argued that the Homestead owners were not allowed to reap the fruits of their investment because of workers' inordinately high wage scales. The union, on the other hand, claimed that the cost of producing steel at Homestead was well below the industry standard, in large measure because the Homestead workers had cooperated in the recent mechanization of the plant.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während arbeitet der 1892 Schlag am 
Gehöft-Stahl, Betriebsleiter Henry-Lehm Frick, das versucht wird, um 
die Schlaggeräte gewaltsam zu besiegen, indem er drei hundert 
bewaffnete Mittel des notorischen Pinkerton Detektivbüros anstellt. 
Die Schlaggeräte kämpften zurück und, nach Unfall und 
Todesfällen auf beiden Seiten, das Pinkertons übergeben. In 
der Nachmahd des Pinkerton Durcheinanders, sprach Frick mit einem 
Reporter für den Pittsburgh Pfosten. Er britt seine implacable 
Opposition zum Beschäftigen den Anschluß, seinen Glauben, die der 
Pennsylvania Regler in Truppen senden sollte, und sein Ziel des 
Verringerns der Löhne am Betrieb, die zentrale Ausgabe in der 
$überschneidung aus. Frick argumentierte, daß den 
Gehöftinhabern nicht erlaubt wurden, die Früchte ihrer Investition 
wegen hohen Lohnskalen der Arbeiter zu ernten der ungeregelt. 
Der Anschluß behauptete andererseits, daß die Kosten des 
Produzierens des Stahls am Gehöft gut unterhalb des 
Industriestandards waren, in großem Umfang, weil die Gehöftarbeiter 
bei der neuen Mechanisierung des Betriebes zusammengearbeitet hatten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant les 1892 la grève à l'acier de ferme 
fonctionne, argile Frick d'Henry de directeur d'installation essayé 
pour défaire les butées de force en louant trois cents agents armés
de l'agence de détectives notoire de Pinkerton. Les grèvistes 
ont battu en retraite, et, après des accidents et des décès des 
deux côtés, le Pinkertons rendus. Au lendemain du débâcle de
Pinkerton, Frick a parlé avec un journaliste pour le poteau de 
Pittsburgh. Il a présenté son opposition implacable à traiter
l'union, sa croyance que le gouverneur de la Pennsylvanie devrait 
introduire les troupes, et son but de réduire des salaires à 
l'usine, l'issue centrale en conflit. Frick a argué du fait 
qu'on n'a pas permis aux les propriétaires de ferme de récolter les 
fruits de leur investissement en raison des échelles des salaires 
démesurément hautes des ouvriers. L'union, d'autre part, a 
réclamé que le coût de produire l'acier à la ferme était bien 
au-dessous de la norme d'industrie, dans une large mesure parce que 
les ouvriers de ferme avaient coopéré à la mécanisation récente 
de l'usine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Durante 1892 a batida no aço do homestead 
trabalha, argila Frick do Henry do gerente de planta tentado derrotar 
forçosamente os grevistas empregando três cem agentes armados da 
agência detective notorious de Pinkerton. Os grevistas lutaram 
para trás, e, após víctimas e mortes em ambos os lados, o 
Pinkertons rendidos. No aftermath do debacle de Pinkerton, Frick
falou com um repórter para o borne de Pittsburgh. Colocou para 
fora de sua oposição implacable a tratar da união, de sua opinião 
que o regulador de Pensilvânia deve emitir nas tropas, e de seu 
objetivo de reduzir salários na planta, a edição central no 
conflito. Frick discutiu que não estiveram permitidos aos 
proprietários do homestead reap as frutas de seu investimento por 
causa das escalas de salário inordinately elevadas dos trabalhadores.
A união, na outra mão, reivindicou que o custo de produzir o 
aço no homestead estava bem abaixo do padrão da indústria, na 
medida grande porque os trabalhadores do homestead tinham cooperado no
mechanization recente da planta.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Durante i 1892 il colpo all'acciaio della fattoria
funziona, argilla Frick di henry del direttore di stabilimento tentato
per sconfiggere con forza i percussori assumendo trecento agenti 
muniti dell'agenzia detective rinomata di Pinkerton. I 
percussori hanno combattuto indietro e, dopo gli incidenti e le morti 
da entrambi i lati, il Pinkertons ceduti. Nel guaime del debacle
di Pinkerton, Frick ha parlato con un reporter per l'alberino de 
Pittsburgh. Ha presentato la sua opposizione implacable ad 
occuparsi dell'unione, della sua credenza che il regolatore della 
Pensilvania dovrebbe introdurre truppe e del suo obiettivo di 
riduzione degli stipendi nella pianta, l'edizione centrale in 
conflitto. Frick ha sostenuto che ai proprietari della fattoria 
non sono stati permessi raccogliere le frutte del loro investimento a 
causa di scale di stipendio disordinatamente alte degli operai. 
L'unione, d'altra parte, ha sostenuto in una larga misura che il
costo di produrre l'acciaio alla fattoria era bene sotto lo standard 
di industria, perché gli operai della fattoria avevano cooperato 
nella meccanizzazione recente della pianta.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατά τη διάρκεια της απεργίας 1892 στις 
χαλυβουργικές εργασίες αγροτικών σπιτιών, ο διευθυντής 
εγκαταστάσεων Henry Clay Frick προσπάθησε να νικήσει τους 
απεργούς βίαια με τη μίσθωση τριακόσιων οπλισμένων πρακτόρων της
πασίγνωστης αντιπροσωπείας ιδιωτικών αστυνομικών Pinkerton. 
Οι απεργοί πάλεψαν πίσω, και, μετά από τα θύματα και τους 
θανάτους και στις δύο πλευρές, το Pinkertons που παραδόθηκε. 
Στη συνέπεια της καταστροφής Pinkerton, Frick μίλησε με
έναν δημοσιογράφο για το ταχυδρομείο του Πίτσμπουργκ. 
Σχεδίασε την αδιάλλακτη αντίθεσή του στην εξέταση της 
ένωσης, η πεποίθησή του που ο κυβερνήτης της Πενσυλβανίας πρέπει
να στείλει στα στρατεύματα, και το στόχο του τις αμοιβές στις 
εγκαταστάσεις, το κεντρικό ζήτημα σε σύγκρουση. Το Frick 
υποστήριξε ότι οι ιδιοκτήτες αγροτικών σπιτιών δεν είχαν την 
άδεια για να συγκεντρώσουν τους καρπούς της επένδυσής τους λόγω 
κλιμάκων αμοιβών των εργαζομένων των υπέρμετρα υψηλών. Η 
ένωση, αφ' ετέρου, υποστήριξε ότι το κόστος ο χάλυβας στο 
αγροτικό σπίτι ήταν αρκετά κάτω από τα πρότυπα βιομηχανίας, σε
μεγάλο βαθμό επειδή οι εργαζόμενοι αγροτικών σπιτιών είχαν 
συνεργαστεί στην πρόσφατη μηχανοποίηση των εγκαταστάσεων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Durante 1892 la huelga en el acero de la granja 
trabaja, arcilla Frick del Henrio del director de planta procurado 
para derrotar los huelguistas fuertemente empleando trescientos 
agentes armados de la agencia detective notoria de Pinkerton. 
Los huelguistas lucharon detrás, y, después de muertes y de 
muertes en ambas caras, el Pinkertons entregadas. En las 
consecuencias del desastre de Pinkerton, Frick habló con un 
reportero para el poste de Pittsburgh. Él presentó a su 
oposición implacable a ocuparse de la unión, de su creencia que el 
gobernador de Pennsylvania debe enviar en tropas, y de su meta de 
reducir salarios en la planta, la edición central en el conflicto. 
Frick discutió que no se permitiera a los propietarios de la 
granja cosechar las frutas de su inversión debido a las escalas de 
salario excesivo altas de los trabajadores. La unión, por otra 
parte, demandó que el coste de producir el acero en la granja estaba 
bien debajo del estándar de la industria, en medida grande porque los
trabajadores de la granja habían cooperado en la mecanización 
reciente de la planta.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086178</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108469</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/fricks-fracas-henry-frick-makes-his-case</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
