<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106945</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106945</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205838</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Circus in America: 1793-1940</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zirkus in Amerika: 1793-1940</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cirque en Amérique : 1793-1940</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Circus em América: 1793-1940</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Circus in America: 1793-1940</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τσίρκο στην Αμερική: 1793-1940</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Circo en América: 1793-1940</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">traces the history of the American circus since 1793, when British equestrian John Rickets presented the first circus in America. Learn about the acts, animals, people, music, and marketing of circuses -- and the impact of the circus on popular culture in America. Get an indepth look at six major circuses, including P.T. Barnum and the Ringling Brothers. A timeline and video clips are provided.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">vollzieht die Geschichte des amerikanischen 
Zirkusses seit 1793 nach, als britische Reiterjohn Rachitis den 
ersten Zirkus in Amerika darstellte. Erlernen Sie über 
die Taten, die Tiere, die Leute, die Musik und das Marketing der 
Zirkusse die -- und Auswirkung des Zirkusses auf populäre
Kultur in Amerika. Erhalten Sie einen eingehenden Blick bei 
sechs HauptZirkussen, einschließlich P.T. Barnum und die 
Ringling Brüder. Ein timeline und Bildschirmclips werden zur 
Verfügung gestellt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">trace l'histoire du cirque américain depuis 1793,
quand le rachitisme équestre britannique de John a présenté le 
premier cirque en Amérique. Renseignez-vous sur les actes, les 
animaux, les personnes, la musique, et le marketing des cirques 
l'impact -- et du cirque sur la culture populaire en Amérique. 
Atteignez un regard détaillé six cirques principaux, y compris
P.T. Barnum et les frères de Ringling. Une chronologie et des 
clips de vidéo sont fournis.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">segue o history do circus americano desde 1793, 
quando os rickets equestrian britânicos de John apresentaram o 
primeiro circus em América. Aprenda sobre os atos, os animais, 
os povos, a música, e o marketing dos circuses -- e o impacto do 
circus na cultura popular em América. Comece um olhar indepth 
em seis circuses principais, including P.T. Barnum e irmãos de 
Ringling. Um timeline e os grampos do vídeo são fornecidos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">segue la storia del circus americano dal 1793, 
quando il rachitismo equestrian britannico del John ha presentato il 
primo circus in America. Impari circa gli atti, gli animali, la 
gente, la musica e l'introduzione sul mercato dei circuses -- e 
l'effetto del circus su coltura popolare in America. Ottenga uno
sguardo approfondito a sei circuses importanti, compreso P.T. Barnum 
ed i fratelli di Ringling. Un timeline e le clip del video sono 
forniti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">επισημαίνει την ιστορία του αμερικανικού τσίρκου από 
1793, όταν παρουσίασε βρετανικός ιππικός John Rickets το 
πρώτο τσίρκο στην Αμερική. Μάθετε για τις πράξεις, τα ζώα,
τους ανθρώπους, τη μουσική, και το μάρκετινγκ των circuses ο -- 
και αντίκτυπος του τσίρκου στο δημοφιλή πολιτισμό στην Αμερική. 
Πάρτε ένα σε βάθος βλέμμα σε έξι σημαντικά circuses, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένου P.T. Barnum και των αδελφών Ringling. 
Μια υπόδειξη ως προς το χρόνο και τηλεοπτικοί συνδετήρες 
παρέχονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">rastrea la historia del circo americano desde 
1793, cuando el raquitismo ecuestre británico de Juan presentó el 
primer circo en América. Aprenda sobre los actos, los animales,
la gente, la música, y la comercialización de circos -- y el impacto
del circo en cultura popular en América. Consiga una mirada 
profundizada en seis circos importantes, incluyendo P.T. Barnum y los 
hermanos de Ringling. Se proporcionan un timeline y los clips 
del vídeo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205838</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106945</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/circus-in-america-1793-1940</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
