<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103641</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103641</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205684</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Neoclassicism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Neoclassicism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Neoclassicism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Neoclassicism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Neoclassicism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Neoclassicism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Neoclassicism</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is an exhibit that features the works of French artists who painted in the time of Napoleon. With the revolution, French painting resumed its moral and political purpose and embraced the style known as neoclassicism. After 1789, artists increasingly sought noble themes of public virtue and personal sacrifice from the history of ancient Greece or Rome.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist eine Ausstellung, die die Arbeiten der 
französischen Künstler kennzeichnet, die in der Zeit von Napoleon 
malten. Mit der Umdrehung nahm französischer Anstrich seinen 
moralischen und politischen Zweck wieder auf und umfaßte die Art, die
als neoclassicism bekannt ist. Nach 1789 suchten Künstler in 
zunehmendem Maße vortreffliche Themen der allgemeinen Tugend und des 
persönlichen Opfers von der Geschichte von altem Griechenland oder 
von Rom.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est un objet exposé qui comporte les travaux des 
artistes français qui ont peint dans la période de Napoleon. 
Avec la révolution, la peinture française a repris son but 
moral et politique et a embrassé le modèle connu sous le nom de 
neoclassicism. Après 1789, les artistes ont de plus en plus 
recherché des thèmes nobles de vertu publique et de sacrifice 
personnel de l'histoire de la Grèce ou de Rome antique.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é uma exibição que caracterize os trabalhos dos
artistas franceses que pintaram na época de Napoleon. Com a 
volta, a pintura francesa recomeçou sua finalidade moral e política 
e embraced o estilo sabido como o neoclassicism. Após 1789, os 
artistas procuraram cada vez mais temas nobres do virtue público e do
sacrifício pessoal do history de Greece ou de Roma antiga.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è un'esposizione che caratterizza gli impianti 
degli artisti francesi che hanno verniciato nel periodo di Napoleon. 
Con la rivoluzione, la pittura francese ha ripreso il relativo 
scopo morale e politico ed ha abbracciato lo stile conosciuto come il 
neoclassicism. Dopo 1789, gli artisti sempre più hanno cercato 
i temi nobili di virtù pubblica e del sacrificio personale dalla 
storia della Grecia o di Roma antica.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι ένα έκθεμα που χαρακτηρίζει τις εργασίες των 
γαλλικών καλλιτεχνών που χρωμάτισαν στο χρόνο Napoleon. 
Με την επανάσταση, η γαλλική ζωγραφική επανέλαβε τον ηθικό 
και πολιτικό σκοπό της και αγκαλίασε το ύφος γνωστό ως 
neoclassicism. Μετά από 1789, οι καλλιτέχνες επιδίωξαν
όλο και περισσότερο τα ευγενή θέματα της δημόσιας αρετής και της
προσωπικής θυσίας από την ιστορία της αρχαίας Ελλάδας ή της 
Ρώμης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es un objeto expuesto que ofrece los trabajos de 
los artistas franceses que pintaron en la época de Napoleon. 
Con la revolución, la pintura francesa reasumió su propósito 
moral y político y abrazó el estilo conocido como neoclassicism. 
Después de 1789, los artistas buscaron cada vez más temas 
nobles de la virtud pública y del sacrificio personal de la historia 
de Grecia o de Roma antigua.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205684</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103641</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/neoclassicism</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
