<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104485</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104485</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206454</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Santa Clara County, California's Historic Silicon Valley</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sankt Clara Grafschaft, Historisches Silicon 
Valley Kaliforniens</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Comté De Santa Clara, Silicon Valley Historique 
De la Californie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Condado De Santa Clara, Vale De Silicone Historic 
De Califórnia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Contea Della Santa Clara, Silicon Valley Storica 
Della California</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Santa Κλάρα County, ιστορική Σίλικον Βάλευ! 
Καλιφόρνιας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Condado De Santa Clara, Silicon Valley Histórico 
De California</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features 28 historic places that illustrate how this fertile valley blossomed from small agricultural towns linked by railroad into a center of technological innovation. Located south of San Francisco, the history of Santa Clara County is rich with stories of Spanish and Mexican settlement, the romance of the Gold-Rush era, the pastoral beauty of abundant orchards, of post-war suburbanization, the race to the moon, and the invention of the silicon chip.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">kennzeichnet 28 historische Plätze, die 
veranschaulichen, wie diese fruchtbare Senke von den kleinen 
landwirtschaftlichen Städten blühte, die durch Eisenbahn in eine 
Mitte der technologischen Innovation gebunden wurden. 
Lokalisierter Süden von San Francisco, die Geschichte Sankt 
Clara der Grafschaft ist mit Geschichten von spanischem reich und 
mexikanische Regelung, das Romanze von Gold-Hetzen Ära, die 
Schäferschönheit der reichlich vorhandenen Obstgärten, von 
Nachkriegssuburbanization, das Rennen zum Mond und die Erfindung des 
Silizium-Chips.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">comporte 28 endroits historiques qui illustrent 
comment cette vallée fertile a fleuri de petites villes agricoles 
jointes par le chemin de fer dans un centre d'innovation 
technologique. Le sud localisé de San Francisco, 
l'histoire du comté de Santa Clara est riche avec des histoires 
d'espagnol et le règlement mexicain, le roman du Or-Précipitent 
l'ère, la beauté pastorale des vergers abondants, du suburbanization
d'après-guerre, la course à la lune, et l'invention de la puce de 
silicone.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">caracteriza 28 lugares historic que ilustram como 
este vale fértil floresceu das cidades agriculturais pequenas ligadas
pela estrada de ferro em um centro da inovação technological. 
O sul encontrado de San Francisco, o history do condado de Santa
Clara é rico com histórias de espanhol e o estabelecimento mexicano,
o romance do Ouro-Apressa a era, a beleza pastoral de pomares 
abundantes, do suburbanization post-war, a raça à lua, e a 
invenção da microplaqueta de silicone.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">caratterizza 28 posti storici che illustrano come 
questa valle fertile è sbocciato dalle piccole città agricole 
collegate dalla ferrovia in un centro di innovazione tecnologica. 
Il sud individuato di San Francisco, la storia della contea 
della Santa Clara è ricco con le storia di spagnolo e lo stabilimento
messicano, il romanzesco del Oro-Scorre veloce l'era, la bellezza 
pastoral dei frutteti abbondanti, del suburbanization del dopoguerra, 
la corsa alla luna e l'invenzione della placchetta di silicio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χαρακτηρίζει 28 ιστορικές θέσεις που επεξηγούν πώς
αυτή η εύφορη κοιλάδα άνθισε από τις μικρές γεωργικές πόλεις 
που συνδέθηκαν από το σιδηρόδρομο σε ένα κέντρο της τεχνολογικής
καινοτομίας. Ο τοποθετημένος νότος του Σαν Φρανσίσκο, η 
ιστορία Santa Κλάρα County είναι πλούσιος με τις ιστορίες 
της ισπανικής και μεξικάνικης τακτοποίησης, το ρωμανικό της 
χρυσός-εσπευσμένης εποχής, την ποιμενική ομορφιά των άφθονων 
οπωρώνων, της μεταπολεμικής μετατροπής σε προάστειο, τη φυλή στο 
φεγγάρι, και την εφεύρεση του τσιπ πυριτίου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece 28 lugares históricos que ilustren cómo 
este valle fértil floreció de las ciudades agrícolas pequeñas 
conectadas por el ferrocarril en un centro de la innovación 
tecnológica. El sur localizado de San Francisco, la historia 
del condado de Santa Clara es rico con historias de español y el 
establecimiento mexicano, el romance del Oro-Acomete era, la 
belleza pastoral de huertas abundantes, del suburbanization de la 
posguerra, la raza a la luna, y la invención del chip de silicio.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206454</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104485</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/santa-clara-county-californias-historic-silicon-valley</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
