<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106063</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106063</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087194</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"We Have Got a Good Friend in John Collier": A Taos Pueblo Tries to Sell the Indian New Deal</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"wir haben einen guten Freund im John Collier": 
Ein Taos Pueblo-Versuche, zum des indischen neuen Abkommens zu 
verkaufen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"nous avons un bon ami en John Collier" : 
Essais d'un pueblo de Taos pour vendre la nouvelle affaire 
indienne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"nós começamos um amigo bom no collier de John":
Tentativas de um povoado indígino de Taos para vender o 
negócio novo indian</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"abbiamo ottenuto un buon amico in collier del 
John": Prove del pueblo di Taos per vendere il nuovo affare 
indiano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Έχουμε έναν καλό φίλο σε John Collier": 
Ένα Taos Pueblo προσπαθεί να πωλήσει την ινδική νέα 
διαπραγμάτευση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"tenemos un buen amigo en el collier de Juan": 
Intentos de un pueblo de Taos para vender el nuevo reparto 
indio</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Indian Reorganization Act of 1934, which became known as the Indian New Deal, dramatically changed the federal government's Indian policy. Although John Collier, the commissioner of Indian affairs who was responsible for the new policy, may have viewed Indians with great sympathy, not all Native Americans viewed his programs in equally positive terms. Antonio Luhan, the husband of the wealthy writer Mabel Dodge Luhan and a Taos Pueblo Indian, was a friend and supporter of John Collier. In this letter to Collier, which he dictated to his wife, he reported on his efforts to persuade other Indians that Collier was their friend and that the reorganization act would bring positive change.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die indische Reorganisierung-Tat von 1934, die als
das indische neue Abkommen bekannt wurde, indische Politik der 
drastisch geänderten die Bundesregierung. Obgleich John 
Collier, der Beauftragte der indischen Angelegenheiten, der für die 
neue Politik verantwortlich war, Inder mit großer Sympathie angesehen
haben kann, sahen nicht alle gebürtigen Amerikaner seine Programme in
den gleichmäßig positiven Bezeichnungen an. Antonio Luhan, der
Ehemann des wohlhabenden Verfasser Mabel raschen Ausweichens Luhan und
ein Taos Pueblo-Inder, war ein Freund und ein Verfechter von John 
Collier. In diesem Zeichen zum Collier, den er zu seiner Frau 
vorschrieb, berichtete er über seine Bemühungen, andere Inder zu 
überzeugen, daß Collier ihr Freund war und daß die 
Reorganisierungtat positive Änderung holen würde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Loi indienne de réorganisation de 1934, qui 
est devenue notoire comme nouvelle affaire indienne, la politique 
indienne de gouvernement fédéral excessivement changé. Bien 
que John Collier, commissaire des affaires indiennes qui était 
responsable de la nouvelle politique, ait pu avoir visualisé des 
Indiens avec la grande sympathie, non tous les Américains indigènes 
ont visualisé ses programmes en termes également positifs. 
Antonio Luhan, le mari du détour riche Luhan de Mabel 
d'auteur et un Indien de pueblo de Taos, était un ami et un 
défenseur de John Collier. Dans cette lettre à 
Collier, qu'il a dicté à son épouse, il a rendu compte de ses 
efforts de persuader d'autres Indiens que Collier était leur ami 
et que l'acte de réorganisation apporterait le changement positif.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O ato indian do reorganization de 1934, que se 
tornou sabido como o negócio novo indian, a política indian de 
governo federal dramàtica mudado. Embora o collier de John, 
comissário de casos indian que era responsável para a política 
nova, pudesse ter visto indians com sympathy grande, não todos os 
americanos nativos viram seus programas em termos ingualmente 
positivos. Antonio Luhan, marido do rodeio rico Luhan de Mabel 
do escritor e um indian do povoado indígino de Taos, era um amigo e 
um supporter do collier de John. Nesta letra ao collier, que 
ditou a sua esposa, relatou em seus esforços persuadir outros indians
que o collier era seu amigo e que o ato do reorganization traria a 
mudança positiva.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Legge indiana della riorganizzazione di 1934, 
che è stato conosciuta come il nuovo affare indiano, politica indiana
del governo federale drammaticamente cambiato. Anche se il 
collier del John, il commissario degli affari indiani che era 
responsabile di nuova politica, può osservare gli indiani con 
compassione grande, non tutti gli Americani natali hanno osservato i 
suoi programmi nei termini ugualmente positivi. Antonio Luhan, 
il marito dell'espediente ricco Luhan di Mabel del produttore e un 
indiano del pueblo di Taos, era un amico e un sostenitore del collier 
del John. In questa lettera al collier, che ha dettato alla sua 
moglie, ha segnalato sui suoi sforzi persaudere altri indiani che il 
collier era il loro amico e che l'atto della riorganizzazione 
porterebbe il cambiamento positivo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο ινδικός νόμος αναδιοργάνωσης του 1934, που έγινε 
γνωστός ως ινδική νέα διαπραγμάτευση, άλλαξε εντυπωσιακά την 
ινδική πολιτική της ομοσπονδιακής κυβέρνησης. Αν και John
Collier, ο Επίτροπος των ινδικών υποθέσεων που ήταν αρμόδιος 
για τη νέα πολιτική, μπορεί να είχε εμφανίσει Ινδούς με τη 
μεγάλη συμπόνοια, δεν εμφάνισαν όλοι οι εγγενείς Αμερικανοί τα 
προγράμματά του στους εξίσου θετικούς όρους. Το Antonio 
Luhan, ο σύζυγος του πλούσιου τεχνάσματος Luhan και ένα 
Taos Pueblo Ινδός Mabel συγγραφέων, ήταν φίλος και 
υποστηρικτής John Collier. Σε αυτήν την επιστολή στον 
ανθρακωρύχο, που υπαγόρευσε στη σύζυγό του, υπέβαλε έκθεση 
σχετικά με τις προσπάθειές του να πείσει άλλους Ινδούς ότι ο 
ανθρακωρύχος ήταν ο φίλος τους και ότι η πράξη αναδιοργάνωσης θα
έφερνε τη θετική αλλαγή.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El acto indio de la reorganización de 1934, que 
se conocía como el nuevo reparto indio, la política india del 
gobierno federal dramáticamente cambiante. Aunque el collier de
Juan, la comisión de asuntos indios que era responsable de la nueva 
política, pudo haber visto a indios con gran condolencia, no todos 
los americanos nativos vieron sus programas en términos igualmente 
positivos. Antonio Luhan, el marido del regate rico Luhan de 
Mabel del programa de escritura e indio del pueblo de Taos, era un 
amigo y un partidario del collier de Juan. En esta carta al 
collier, que él dictó a su esposa, él señaló sobre sus esfuerzos 
de persuadir a otros indios que el collier era su amigo y que el acto 
de la reorganización traería el cambio positivo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087194</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106063</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/we-have-got-a-good-friend-in-john-collier-a-taos-pueblo-tries-to-sell-the-indian-new-deal</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
