<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103329</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103329</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207027</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Wilbur and Orville Wright Papers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Wilbur und Orville Wright Papiere</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les papiers de Wilbur et d'Orville Wright</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os papéis de Wilbur e de Orville Wright</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le carte da Orville e da Wilbur Wright</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα έγγραφα Wilbur και Orville Wright</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los papeles de Wilbur y de Orville Wright</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">documents the Wright brothers' lives and their work that led to the world's first powered, controlled, and sustained flight. Nearly 50,000 digital images are provided?diaries, scrapbooks, drawings, photos, and more. Learn about the Wright brothers' boyhoods and early business ventures. See the famous glass-plate negative of the First Flight at Kitty Hawk on December 17, 1903. Read letters and diaries in which they recount the work leading up to that day.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">dokumentiert die Lebensdauern der Wright Brüder 
und ihr Arbeit, die das zu der angeschalteten Welt erster führte, 
Steuer- und unterstützter Flug. Fast 50.000 digitalisierte 
Bilder sind provided?diaries, Scrapbooks, Zeichnungen, Fotos und mehr.
Erlernen Sie über der die boyhoods Wright Brüder und frühen 
die Unternehmen. Sehen Sie das berühmte Glasplattenegativ des 
Erstfluges am Kitty-Falken an Dezember 17, 1903. Lesen Sie 
Briefe und Tagebücher, in denen sie die Arbeit nachzählen, die bis 
zu diesem Tag führt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">documente les vies des frères de Wright et leur 
vol de travail que cela a mené au monde premier actionné, 
contrôlé, et soutenu. Presque 50.000 images digitales sont des
provided?diaries, des albums, des schémas, des photos, et plus. 
Renseignez-vous sur les boyhoods des frères de Wright et les 
entreprises tôt d'affaires. Voyez le négatif célèbre de 
plaque de verre du premier vol au faucon de Kitty décembre 17, 
1903. Lisez les lettres et les agendas dans lesquels ils 
racontent le travail amenant à ce jour.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">documenta as vidas dos irmãos de Wright e seu 
vôo do trabalho que isso conduziu ao mundo primeiro powered, 
controlado, e sustentado. Quase 50.000 imagens digitais são 
provided?diaries, scrapbooks, desenhos, fotos, e mais. Aprenda 
sobre os boyhoods dos irmãos de Wright e os riscos de negócio 
adiantados. Veja o negativo famoso do glass-plate do primeiro 
vôo no falcão do kitty dezembro em 17, 1903. Leia as letras e 
os diários em que recount o trabalho que conduz a esse dia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">documenta le vite dei fratelli di Wright ed il 
loro volo gestito e e continuo del lavoro che quello ha condotto al 
mondo primo alimentato. Quasi 50.000 immagini digitali sono 
provided?diaries, album, illustrazioni, foto e più. Impari 
circa i boyhoods dei fratelli di Wright e le imprese iniziali di 
affari. Veda la negazione famosa della piastra di vetro del 
primo volo al hawk del kitty il 17 dicembre 1903. Legga le 
lettere ed i diari in cui raccontano il lavoro che porta a quel 
giorno.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">τεκμηριώνει τις ζωές των αδελφών Wright και την 
εργασία τους που οδήγησαν παγκόσμια πρώτη τροφοδοτημένη, 
ελεγχόμενος, και συνεχής πτήση. Σχεδόν 50.000 ψηφιακές 
εικόνες είναι provided?diaries, λευκώματα αποκομμάτων, σχέδια,
φωτογραφίες, και περισσότεροι. Μάθετε για τις παιδικές 
ηλικίες των αδελφών Wright και τις πρόωρες επιχειρησιακές 
επιχειρήσεις. Δείτε διάσημο glass-plate 
αρνητικό της πρώτης πτήσης στο γεράκι γατακιών στις 17 
Δεκεμβρίου, 1903, διαβασμένα επιστολές και ημερολόγια τους 
οποίους εξιστορούν την εργασία που καταλήγει σε εκείνη την 
ημέρα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">documenta las vidas de los hermanos de Wright y su
vuelo del trabajo que eso condujo al mundo primer accionado, 
controlado, y sostenido. Casi 50.000 imágenes digitales son 
provided?diaries, libros de recuerdos, gráficos, fotos, y más. 
Aprenda sobre las adolescencias de los hermanos de Wright y las 
empresas de negocio tempranas. Vea la negativa famosa de la 
placa de cristal del primer vuelo en el halcón del gatito de 
diciembre el 17 de 1903. Lea las letras y los diarios en los 
cuales contaron de nuevo el trabajo que conduce a ese día.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207027</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103329</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-wilbur-and-orville-wright-papers</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
