<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104913</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104913</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200458</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Animation Showing Growth of a Continent</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Animation, die Wachstum eines Kontinentes zeigt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Animation montrant la croissance d'un continent</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Animation que mostra o crescimento de um 
continente</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Animazione che mostra sviluppo di un continente</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ζωτικότητα που εμφανίζει αύξηση μιας ηπείρου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Animación que muestra crecimiento de un 
continente</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Flash animation illustrates continental growth. It shows a convergent boundary where a terrane on a subducting plate is fused to the edge of a continent. Users can stop, play, fast forward and rewind the animation at any time. This visualization is one of several animations in a series developed as a component of Exploring Earth, a website that supports the textbook Earth Science.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese grelle Animation veranschaulicht 
kontinentales Wachstum. Sie zeigt einer konvergenten Grenze, wo 
ein terrane auf einer subducting Platte zum Rand eines Kontinentes 
fixiert wird. Benutzer können stoppen, spielen, schnelles 
Vorwärts und die Animation jederzeit rückspulen. Diese 
Sichtbarmachung ist eine einiger Animationen in einer Serie, die als 
Bestandteil der erforschenden Masse, eine Web site entwickelt wird, 
die die Lehrbuch Geowissenschaft unterstützt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette animation instantanée illustre la 
croissance continentale. Elle montre à une borne convergente 
où un terrane d'un plat subducting est fondu au bord d'un continent. 
Les utilisateurs peuvent s'arrêter, jouer, vers l'avant rapide 
et rebobiner l'animation à tout moment. Cette visualisation est
l'une de plusieurs animations d'une série développée comme 
composant de la terre l'explorant, un site Web qui supporte la science
de la terre de manuel.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este animation flash ilustra o crescimento 
continental. Mostra a um limite convergent onde um terrane em 
uma placa subducting é fundido à borda de um continente. Os 
usuários podem parar, jogar, para diante rápido e rebobinar o 
animation em em qualquer altura que. Este visualization é um de
diversos animations em uma série desenvolvida como um componente da 
terra explorando, um Web site que suporte a ciência de terra do 
textbook.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa animazione istantanea illustra lo sviluppo 
continentale. Mostra ad un contorno convergente dove un terrane 
su una piastra subducting è fuso al bordo di un continente. Gli
utenti possono arrestarsi, giocare, di andata veloce e riavvolgere in 
qualunque momento la animazione. Questa visualizzazione è una 
di parecchie animazioni in serie sviluppata come componente di terra 
d'esplorazione, un Web site che sostiene le scienze della terra del 
manuale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η ζωτικότητα λάμψης επεξηγεί την ηπειρωτική 
αύξηση. Εμφανίζει συγκλίνον όριο όπου ένα terrane σε 
ένα αφαιρώντας πιάτο λιώνεται στην άκρη μιας ηπείρου. Οι 
χρήστες μπορούν να σταματήσουν, να παίξουν, να διαβιβάζουν 
γρήγορα και να ξανατυλίξουν τη ζωτικότητα οποιαδήποτε στιγμή. 
Αυτή η απεικόνιση είναι μια από διάφορες ζωτικότητες σε 
μια σειρά που αναπτύσσεται ως συστατικό τη γη, ένας ιστοχώρος που
υποστηρίζει τη γήινη επιστήμη εγχειριδίων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta animación de destello ilustra crecimiento 
continental. Muestra a límite convergente donde un terrane en 
una placa subducting está fundido al borde de un continente. 
Los utilizadores pueden parar, jugar, delantero rápido y 
rebobinar la animación en cualquier momento. Esta 
visualización es una de varias animaciones en una serie desarrollada 
como componente de la tierra que explora, un Web site que utilice la 
geología del libro de textos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200458</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104913</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/animation-showing-growth-of-a-continent</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
