<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106676</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106676</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086855</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Still Livin' Under the Bonds of Slavery": Minnie Whitney Describes Sharecropping at the Turn-of-the-Century</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"noch Livin ' unter den Bindungen der Sklaverei": 
Minnie Whitney beschreibt Sharecropping an der Jahrhundertwende</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"toujours Livin 'sous les Obligations de 
l'esclavage" : Minnie Whitney décrit le métayage au 
Tourner-de-le-Siècle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"ainda Livin ' sob as ligações do slavery": 
Minnie Whitney descreve o sharecropping no Gir-$$$-$$$-Século</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"ancora Livin 'sotto i legami di slavery": 
Minnie Whitney descrive la mezzadria al Gir-de-$$$-Secolo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ακόμα Livin" κάτω από τους δεσμούς της σκλαβιάς 
": Το Minnie whitney περιγράφει sharecropping στο 
στροφή-$$$-Ο-ΑΙΏΝΑ</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"aún Livin ' bajo enlaces de la esclavitud": 
Minnie Whitney describe aparcería en el Dar 
vuelta-de-$$$-Siglo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The emergence of the sharecropping system in the South in the last three decades of the 19th century rested on an uneasy compromise between black farming families and the white landowners on whose land they labored. Sharecropping was an oppressive system but the experience of sharecropping families varied. In this interview done by historian Charles Hardy in 1984, Minnie Whitney, born in 1902, described the determined efforts of more progressive farmers like her father, who along with her mother struggled to maintain some self-sufficiency in the face of white determination to enforce African-American dependence on the sharecropping system.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Hervortreten des Sharecroppingsystems im 
Süden in den letzten drei Dekaden des 19. Jahrhunderts stand auf 
einem unbehaglichen Kompromiß zwischen dem Schwarzen still, das 
Familien und die weißen Grundbesitzer auf deren Land sie, 
bewirtschaftet bearbeiteten. Sharecropping war ein bedrückendes
System, aber die Erfahrung der Sharecroppingfamilien veränderte sich.
In diesem Interview, das mit Historiker Charles robust ist 1984 
erfolgt war, beschrieb Minnie Whitney, getragen 1902, die 
entschlossenen Bemühungen der progressiveren Landwirte wie ihr Vater,
der zusammen mit ihrer Mutter kämpfte, um etwas Selbstüberhebung 
angesichts der weißen Ermittlung beizubehalten, um 
Afrikanisch-Amerikanische Abhängigkeit auf dem Sharecroppingsystem zu
erzwingen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'apparition du système de métayage dans les 
Sud dans les trois dernières décennies du 19ème siècle 
s'est reposée sur un compromis incommode entre le noir cultivant les 
familles et les propriétaires fonciers blancs sur lesquels la terre 
ils ont travaillé. Le métayage était un système accablant 
mais l'expérience des familles de métayage a changé. Dans 
cette entrevue faite par l'historien Charles robuste en 1984, Minnie 
Whitney, soutenu en 1902, a décrit les efforts déterminés des 
fermiers plus progressifs comme son père, qui avec sa mère a lutté 
pour mettre à jour un certain art de l'auto-portrait-sufficiency face à la 
détermination blanche pour imposer la dépendance afro-américaine à 
légard le système de métayage.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O emergence do sistema do sharecropping no sul nas
últimas três décadas do 1ø século descansou em um acordo inquieto
entre o preto que cultiva as famílias e os latifundiários brancos 
cuja na terra trabalharam. O sharecropping era um sistema 
oppressive mas a experiência de famílias do sharecropping variou. 
Nesta entrevista feita pelo historian Charles hardy em 1984, 
Minnie Whitney, carregado em 1902, descreveu os esforços determinados
de uns fazendeiros mais progressivos como seu pai, que junto com sua 
matriz se esforçou para manter algum self-sufficiency na cara da 
determinação branca para reforçar a dependência Africano-Americana
no sistema do sharecropping.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'emersione del sistema di mezzadria nel sud nelle
ultime tre decadi del diciannovesimo secolo si riposava su un 
compromesso uneasy fra nero che coltiva le famiglie ed i latifondisti 
bianchi di cui su terra hanno lavorato. La mezzadria era un 
sistema oppressive ma l'esperienza nelle famiglie di mezzadria ha 
variato. In questa intervista fatta dallo storico Charles hardy 
in 1984, Minnie Whitney, sopportato in 1902, ha descritto gli sforzi 
risoluti dei coltivatori più progressivi come il suo padre, che con 
la sua madre ha lottato per effettuare una certa autosufficienza di 
fronte a determinazione bianca per fare rispettare la dipendenza 
Africano-Americana dal sistema di mezzadria.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η εμφάνιση του sharecropping συστήματος στο νότο 
στις τελευταίες τρεις δεκαετίες του 19$ου αιώνα στηρίχτηκε σε 
έναν δύσκολο συμβιβασμό μεταξύ των καλλιεργώντας οικογενειών 
μαύρων και των λευκών landowners στο των οποίων έδαφος 
εργάστηκαν. Sharecropping ήταν ένα καταπιεστικό σύστημα
αλλά η εμπειρία sharecropping των οικογενειών ποίκιλε. Σε
αυτήν την συνέντευξη που έγινε από τον ιστορικό Charles 
Hardy το 1984, Minnie whitney, γεννημένο το 1902, 
περιέγραψε τις αποφασιστικές προσπάθειες των προοδευτικότερων 
αγροτών όπως τον πατέρα της, ο οποίος μαζί με τη μητέρα της 
αγωνίστηκε να διατηρήσει κάποια αυτάρκεια παρά την άσπρη 
αποφασιστικότητα να επιβληθεί η αφρικανικός-αμερικανική εξάρτηση 
στο sharecropping σύστημα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La aparición del sistema de la aparcería en el 
sur en las tres décadas pasadas del diecinueveavo siglo se basó 
sobre un compromiso inquieto entre el negro que cultivaba a las 
familias y a los terratenientes blancos en que pista trabajaron. 
La aparcería era un sistema opresivo pero la experiencia de las
familias de la aparcería varió. En esta entrevista hecha por 
el historiador Charles robusto en 1984, Minnie Whitney, llevado en 
1902, describió los esfuerzos resueltos de granjeros más progresivos
como su padre, que junto con su madre luchó para mantener una cierta 
autosuficiencia en la cara de la determinación blanca para hacer 
cumplir dependencia Africano-Americana del sistema de la aparcería.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086855</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106676</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/still-livin-under-the-bonds-of-slavery-minnie-whitney-describes-sharecropping-at-the-turn-of-the-century</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
