<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108510</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108510</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086053</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Damage":  Collier's  Assesses the Army-McCarthy Hearings</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Beschädigung": Des Colliers setzt die 
Armee-McCarthy Hörfähigkeiten fest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"dommages" : Collier évalue les 
auditions d'Armée-McCarthy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">os "danos": O collier avalia os hearings do 
Exército-McCarthy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"danni": Il collier valuta le udienze 
dell'Esercito-McCarthy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ζημία": Ο ανθρακωρύχος αξιολογεί τις ακροάσεις 
στρατός- McCarthy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"daños": El collier evalúa las audiencias 
del Eje'rcito-McCarthy</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Anticommunist crusader Senator Joseph R. McCarthy stepped into national prominence on February 9, 1950, when he mounted an attack on President Truman's foreign policy agenda. McCarthy charged that the State Department and its Secretary, Dean Acheson, harbored "traitorous" Communists. McCarthy's apocalyptic rhetoric--he portrayed the Cold War conflict as "a final, all-out battle between communistic atheism and Christianity"--made critics hesitate before challenging him. Those accused by McCarthy faced loss of employment, damaged careers, and in many cases, broken lives. After the 1952 election, in which the Republican Party won control of both branches of Congress, McCarthy became chairman of the Senate Committee on Government Operations and its Subcommittee on Investigations. McCarthy then extended his targets to include numerous government agencies, in addition to the broadcasting and defense industries, universities, and the United Nations. His dramatic hearings investigating purported Communist infiltration in the Army were televised live to the nation. The following editorial from the popular magazine  Collier's  assessed the damage to public perception of governmental institutions.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Anticommunist Kreuzfahrer Senator Joseph R. 
McCarthy trat in nationalen Vorsprung an Februar 9, 1950, als er einen
Angriff auf Präsident Trumans Tagesordnung der fremden Politik 
einhing. McCarthy lud auf, daß die Zustand-Abteilung und seine 
Sekretärin, Dekan Acheson, "traitorous" Kommunisten beherbargen. 
McCarthys apokalyptische Rhetorik -- er schilderte die 
$überschneidung des kalten Krieges als "abschließende, all-out 
Schlacht zwischen communistic Atheismus und Christentum" -- 
gebildete Kritiker zögern vor schwierigem er. Die, die von 
McCarthy beschuldigt wurden, stellten Verlust der Beschäftigung 
gegenüber, beschädigten die Karrieren und in vielen Fällen, 
gebrochen Leben. Nach der Wahl 1952 in der die Republikanische Partei 
Steuerung beider Zweige des Kongresses gewann, stand McCarthy 
Vorsitzendem des Senat-Ausschusses für Regierung Operationen und 
seiner Unterausschusses auf Untersuchungen. McCarthy dehnte dann
seine Ziele aus, um zahlreiche Regierungsagenturen, zusätzlich zu den
Sendung und Verteidigungindustrien, Universitäten und die Nationen zu
enthalten. Seine drastischen Hörfähigkeiten, die behauptete 
kommunistische Infiltration in der Armee nachforschen, waren zur 
Nation im Fernsehen übertragenes Phasen. Der folgende 
Leitartikel vom populären Zeitschrift Colliers festgesetzt der 
Beschädigung der allgemeinen Vorstellung der Regierungsanstalten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le sénateur Joseph R. McCarthy de croisé 
d'Anticommunist a fait un pas dans la proéminence nationale février 
9, 1950, quand il a monté une attaque à l'ordre du jour de politique
étrangère du Président Truman's. McCarthy a chargé que le 
service d'état et son secrétaire, doyen Acheson, ont hébergé les 
communistes "déloyaux". La rhétorique apocalyptique de 
McCarthy -- il a dépeint le conflit de guerre froide comme "bataille 
entre l'athéisme communisant et christianisme finals et globaux" -- 
les critiques faits hésitent avant provocant il. Ceux accusés 
par McCarthy ont fait face à la perte d'emploi, ont endommagé des 
carrières, et dans beaucoup de cas, cassées les vies. Après 
l'élection 1952, dans laquelle la partie républicaine a gagné la 
commande des deux branchements du congrès, McCarthy est allé bien au
Président du comité de sénat des exécutions de gouvernement et de 
son sous-comité sur des investigations. McCarthy a alors 
étendu ses cibles pour inclure de nombreux organismes 
gouvernementaux, en plus des industries de radiodiffusion et de 
défense, universités, et les Nations Unies. Ses auditions 
excessives étudiant l'infiltration communiste prétendue dans 
l'armée étaient de phase télévisé à la nation. 
L'éditorial suivant du magasin populaire Collier évalué 
les dommages à la perception publique des établissements 
gouvernementaux.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O senator Joseph R. McCarthy do cruzado de 
Anticommunist pisou no prominence nacional fevereiro em 9, 1950, 
quando montou um ataque na agenda da política extrangeira do 
presidente Truman. McCarthy carregou que o departamento do 
estado e sua secretária, decano Acheson, abrigaram comunistas 
"traitorous". O rhetoric apocalyptic de McCarthy -- portrayed o 
conflito da guerra fria como "uma batalha entre o atheism communistic 
e um christianity finais, all-out" -- críticos feitos hesitate antes 
de challenging ele. Aqueles acusados por McCarthy enfrentaram a 
perda do emprego, carreiras danificadas, e em muitas caixas, quebradas
vidas. Após a eleição 1952, em que o partido republicano 
ganhou o controle de ambas as filiais do congress, McCarthy assentou 
bem no presidente do comitê do senate em operações do governo e de 
sua subcomissão em investigações. McCarthy estendeu então 
seus alvos para incluir agências de governo numerosas, além às 
indústrias da transmissão e da defesa, às universidades, e às 
nações unidas. Seus hearings dramáticos que investigam o 
infiltration comunista purported no exército estavam vivos televised 
à nação. O seguinte editorial do collier popular do 
compartimento avaliado os danos à percepção pública de 
instituições governamentais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il senatore Joseph R. McCarthy del crociato di 
Anticommunist ha fatto un passo nella protuberanza nazionale il 9 
febbraio 1950, quando ha montato un attacco all'ordine del giorno di 
politica straniera del presidente Truman. McCarthy si è 
caricato che State Department e la relativa segretaria, il decano Acheson, 
harbored i comunisti "traitorous". La retorica apocalyptic del 
McCarthy -- ha ritratto il conflitto di guerra fredda come "una 
battaglia fra atheism communistic e christianity finali e con tutti i mezzi a disposizione" 
-- critici fatti esita prima di challenging lui. Quelli accusati
da McCarthy hanno affrontato la perdita di occupazione, hanno 
danneggiato le carriere ed in molti casi, rotte vite. Dopo 
l'elezione 1952, in cui il partito Repubblicano ha vinto il controllo 
di entrambi i rami del congresso, McCarthy ha stato bene al presidente
del comitato del senato dei funzionamenti di governo e del relativo 
sottocomitato sulle indagini. McCarthy allora ha esteso i suoi 
obiettivi per includere gli enti governativi numerosi, oltre che le 
industrie della difesa e di broadcasting, le università e le Nazioni 
Unite. Le sue udienze drammatiche che studiano l'infiltrazione 
comunista pretesa nell'esercito erano in tensione teletrasmesso alla 
nazione. Il seguente editoriale dal collier popolare dello 
scomparto valutato il danneggiamento della percezione pubblica delle 
istituzioni governative.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο αντικομμουνιστής σταυροφόρος γερουσιαστής Joseph 
R. McCarthy περπάτησε στην εθνική προεξοχή στις 9 
Φεβρουαρίου ..1950, όταν επικόλλησε μια επίθεση στην ημερήσια 
διάταξη εξωτερικής πολιτικής Προέδρου Truman's. McCarthy χρέωσε ότι το υπουργείο εξωτερικών και ο γραμματέας 
του, Dean Acheson, οι "προδοτικοί" κομμουνιστές. McCarthy's η αποκαλυπτική ρητορική -- απεικόνισε τη σύγκρουση 
ψυχρού πολέμου ως "τελική, ενθουσιώδη μάχη μεταξύ του 
κομμουνιστικού αθεϊσμού και χριστιανισμό" -- γίνονται κριτικοί 
διστάζει πρίν προκαλεί τον. Εκείνοι που κατηγορήθηκαν από 
McCarthy αντιμετώπισαν την απώλεια απασχόλησης, έβλαψαν τις 
σταδιοδρομίες, και σε πολλές περιπτώσεις, που έσπασαν ζωές. 
Μετά από την εκλογή του 1952, στην οποία το δημοκρατικό 
κόμμα κέρδισε τον έλεγχο και των δύο κλάδων του συνεδρίου, 
McCarthy έγινε πρόεδρος της Επιτροπής Συγκλήτου των 
κυβερνητικών διαδικασιών και της υποεπιτροπής του στις έρευνες. 
McCarthy επέκτεινε έπειτα τους στόχους του για να 
περιλάβει τις πολυάριθμες κυβερνητικές αντιπροσωπείες, εκτός από
τις βιομηχανίες ραδιοφωνικής αναμετάδοσης και υπεράσπισης, τα 
πανεπιστήμια, και τα Ηνωμένα Έθνη. Οι δραματικές ακροάσεις 
του που ερευνούν την ισχυρισμένη κομμουνιστική διήθηση στο στρατό
μεταδόθηκαν ζωντανός στο έθνος. Το ακόλουθο κύριο άρθρο 
από του δημοφιλούς ανθρακωρύχου περιοδικών που αξιολογείται τη 
ζημία στη δημόσια αντίληψη για τα κυβερνητικά όργανα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Senador José R. McCarthy del cruzado de 
Anticommunist caminó en prominencia nacional 9 de febrero de 1950,
cuando él montó un ataque contra agenda de la política no nativa de
presidente Truman. McCarthy cargó que el departamento y su 
secretaria, decano Acheson del estado, abrigaran comunistas 
"traidores". El retórico apocalíptico de McCarthy -- él 
retrató el conflicto de la guerra fría como "una batalla entre el 
ateismo comunista y cristianismo finales, totales" -- los 
críticos hechos vacila antes de desafiador él. Ésos acusados 
por McCarthy hicieron frente a la pérdida de empleo, dañaron las 
carreras, y en muchos casos, rotas las vidas. Después de la 
elección 1952, en la cual el partido republicano ganó el control de 
ambas ramificaciones del congreso, McCarthy sintió bien al presidente
del comité del senado sobre operaciones del gobierno y de su 
subcomité en investigaciones. McCarthy entonces extendió sus 
blancos para incluir las agencias de estatal numerosas, además de las
industrias de la difusión y de la defensa, las universidades, y los 
Naciones Unidas. Sus audiencias dramáticas que investigaban la 
infiltración comunista pretendida en el ejército eran vivas 
televisado a la nación. El editorial siguiente del collier 
popular del compartimiento evaluado el daño a la opinión pública de
instituciones gubernamentales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086053</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108510</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/damage-colliers-assesses-the-army-mccarthy-hearings</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
