<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106953</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106953</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209930</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Tangent to a circle </string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Tangente zu einem Kreis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Tangente à un cercle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Tangent a um círculo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Tangente ad un cerchio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εφαπτομένη σε έναν κύκλο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Tangente a un círculo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate a tangent to a circle. (not trig). The applet shows a circle and a tangent line. The center point and the tangent contact point are both draggable. As you drag each, the figure changes to ensure that the line is always tangential to the circle. The line from the center to the tangent point is shown and the angle is shown to be always 90 degrees no matter what you do. The perpendicular and its angle can be turned off for class discussion. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die eine Tangente zu einem Kreis zeigen (nicht Triglyzerid).
Der applet zeigt einen Kreis und eine Tangentezeile. Der 
Mittelpunkt und der Tangentekontaktpunkt sind beide draggable. 
Da Sie jedes schleppen, ändert die Abbildung, um sicherzugehen,
daß die Zeile immer zum Kreis tangential ist. Die Zeile von der
Mitte zum Tangentepunkt wird gezeigt und der Winkel wird gezeigt, um 
immer 90 Grad zu sein, egal was Sie. Das Senkrechte und sein 
Winkel können für Kategorie Diskussion abgestellt werden. 
Applet kann zum vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit einem 
Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. Nachgebrauch im 
Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von jedem möglichem web 
browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den benötigten LOGON 
wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Bestandteil des 
Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée
qui démontrent une tangente à un cercle (pas triglycéride). 
L'applet montre un cercle et une ligne de tangente. Le 
point central et le point de contact de tangente sont tous les deux 
draggable. Car vous traînez chacun, la figure change pour 
s'assurer que la ligne est toujours tangentielle au cercle. La 
ligne du centre au point de tangente est montrée et l'angle s'avère 
toujours 90 degrés n'importe ce que vous . La perpendiculaire 
et son angle peuvent être arrêtés pour la discussion de classe. 
L'applet peut être agrandi à la taille de plein écran pour 
l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de classe. Le après 
utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant peut lui accéder 
encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la maison ou dans la 
bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion exigée. Cette 
ressource est un composant du projet interactif de manuel de la 
géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem um tangent a um círculo (não trig). O applet mostra
um círculo e uma linha do tangent. O ponto center e o ponto de 
contato são ambos do tangent draggable. Porque você arrasta 
cada um, a figura muda para assegurar-se de que a linha seja sempre 
tangential ao círculo. A linha do centro ao ponto do tangent é
mostrada e o ângulo é mostrado para ser sempre 90 graus não importa
o que você . A perpendicular e seu ângulo podem ser desligados
para a discussão da classe. O applet pode ser ampliado ao 
tamanho de tela cheia para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. 
O depois de uso na sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la 
outra vez de todo o web browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum 
início de uma sessão requerido. Este recurso é um componente 
do projeto interativo do textbook da geometria da referência aberta 
do math em http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che
dimostrano una tangente ad un cerchio (non trigliceride). Il 
applet mostra un cerchio e una riga di tangente. Il punto 
concentr ed il punto di contatto di tangente sono entrambi draggable. 
Poichè trascinate ciascuno, la figura cambia per accertarsi che
la riga sia sempre tangenziale al cerchio. La riga dal centro al
punto di tangente è indicata e l'angolo è indicato per essere di 
sempre 90 gradi qualunque cosa. La perpendicolare ed il relativo
angolo possono essere spenti per la discussione del codice categoria. 
Il applet può essere ingrandito al formato di schermo pieno per
uso con un proiettore dell'aula. La post-utilizzazione 
nell'aula, allievo può accederle ancora da tutto il web browser nel 
paese o nella libreria senza l'inizio attività richiesto. 
Questa risorsa è un componente del progetto interattivo del 
manuale della geometria di riferimento aperto di per la matematica a 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν μια εφαπτομένη σε έναν κύκλο (μη trig). Το 
applet εμφανίζει έναν κύκλο και γραμμή εφαπτομένης. Το 
κεντρικό σημείο και το σημείο επαφής εφαπτομένης είναι και τα 
δύο draggable. Δεδομένου ότι σέρνετε κάθε ενός, ο 
αριθμός αλλάζει για να εξασφαλίσει ότι η γραμμή είναι πάντα 
εφαπτόμενη στον κύκλο. Η γραμμή από το κέντρο στο σημείο 
εφαπτομένης εμφανίζεται και η γωνία αποδεικνύεται για να είναι 
πάντα 90 βαθμοί των οποίων κάνετε. Η κάθετος και η 
γωνία της μπορούν να κλειθούν για τη συζήτηση κλάσης. Το 
Applet μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη 
χρήση με έναν προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση στην 
τάξη, ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από 
οποιοδήποτε ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς 
την άδεια εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο 
συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος 
εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran una tangente a un círculo (no trig). El applet 
muestra un círculo y una línea de la tangente. La punta de 
centro y la punta de contacto de la tangente son ambas draggable. 
Pues usted arrastra cada uno, la figura cambia para asegurarse 
de que la línea es siempre tangencial al círculo. La línea 
del centro a la punta de la tangente se muestra y el ángulo se 
muestra para ser siempre 90 grados no importa qué usted lo hace. 
El perpendicular y su ángulo se pueden dar vuelta apagado para 
la discusión de la clase. El applet se puede agrandar a la 
talla de la pantalla completa para el uso con un proyector de la sala 
de clase. El uso posterior en la sala de clase, estudiante puede
tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier web browser en el país o en la 
biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. Este recurso es un 
componente del proyecto interactivo del libro de textos de la 
geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas en 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209930</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106953</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/tangent-to-a-circle</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
