<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107897</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107897</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086211</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Hands across the water.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hände über dem Wasser.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mains à travers l'eau.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Mãos através da água.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Mani attraverso l'acqua.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Χέρια πέρα από το ύδωρ.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Manos a través del agua.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Women's suffrage activists used a variety of tactics during World War I to advance their cause. While the more conservative North American Woman Suffrage Association energetically supported the war by knitting socks, selling war bonds, and preparing Red Cross supplies, members of the more militant National Women's Party were arrested for picketing the White House. During a July, 1917, visit from representatives of the new Russian government, demonstrators in front of the White House appealed to the envoys to support suffrage for American women as a condition for Russia's remaining in the Allied camp. The banner roused the ire of patriotic passersby, and soon after this photograph was taken an angry crowd attacked the suffragists.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Stimmrechtaktivisten der Frauen verwendeten eine Vielzahl 
von Taktiken während des Ersten Weltkrieges, um ihre Ursache 
vorzurücken. Während die konservativere nordamerikanische 
Frau-Stimmrecht-Verbindung energisch den Krieg unterstützte, indem 
sie Socken strickte verkaufte, Kriegbindungen, und Zubehör des roten 
Kreuzes vorbereitete, wurden Bauteile der militanteren nationalen 
Partei der Frauen für das Einpfählen des Weißen Hauses 
festgehalten. Während eines Julis 1917, gefiel Besuch von den 
Repräsentanten der neuen russischen Regierung, Vorführer vor dem 
Weißen Haus den Abgesandten Unterstützungsstimmrecht für 
amerikanische Frauen als Bedingung für Rußland, das im verbündeten 
Lager restlich ist. Die Fahne roused das ire der patriotischen 
Passanten, und bald, nachdem diese Fotographie genommen wurde, nahm 
eine verärgerte Masse die suffragists in Angriff.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les activistes du suffrage des femmes avaient l'habitude 
une variété de la tactique pendant la Première Guerre Mondiale pour
avancer leur cause. Tandis que l'association américaine 
du nord plus conservatrice de suffrage de femme supportait 
énergétiquement la guerre en tricotant des chaussettes, en vendant 
des obligations de guerre, et en préparant des approvisionnements 
de croix rouge, des membres de plus de la partie militante de 
femmes nationales ont été arrêtés pour palissader la Maison 
Blanche . Pendant juillet, 1917, la visite des représentants du
nouveau gouvernement russe, programmes de démonstration devant la 
Maison Blanche  a lancé un appel les délégués le suffrage de 
support pour les femmes américaines comme condition pour la Russie 
restante dans le camp allié. Le drapeau a suscité la 
colère des passants patriotes, et peu après que cette 
photographie ait été prise une foule fâchée a attaqué les 
suffragettes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As activistas do suffrage das mulheres usaram uma 
variedade das táticas durante o world.war.i avançar sua causa. 
Quando a associação norte-americana mais conservadora do 
suffrage da mulher suportou energètica a guerra knitting socks, 
vendendo ligações de guerra, e preparando fontes da cruz vermelha, 
os membros do partido das mulheres nacionais mais militant foram 
prendidos picketing a casa branca. Durante um julho, 1917, a 
visita dos representantes do governo russian novo, demonstradores na 
frente da casa branca apelou aos envoys ao suffrage da sustentação 
para mulheres americanas como uma circunstância para Rússia restante
no acampamento aliado. A bandeira roused o ire de transeuntes 
patriotic, e logo depois que esta fotografia foi feita exame uma 
multidão irritada atacou os suffragists.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli attivisti di suffrage delle donne hanno usato una 
varietà di tattiche durante il world.war.i per avanzare la loro 
causa. Mentre di più l'associazione nordamericana conservatrice di
suffrage della donna energico sostenesse la guerra lavorando a maglia 
i calzini, vendendo i legami di guerra e preparando i rifornimenti 
della croce rossa, i membri del partito delle più donne nazionali del
militante sono stati arrestati per steccare la Casa Bianca. 
Durante luglio, del 1917, la chiamata dai rappresentanti di 
nuovo governo russo, dimostranti davanti la Casa Bianca ha fatto 
appello ai envoys a suffrage di sostegno per le donne americane come 
circostanza per la Russia restante nell'accampamento alleato. La
bandiera roused il ire dei passersby patriotic e presto dopo che 
questa fotografia fosse presa una folla arrabbiata ha attacato i 
suffragists.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα ενεργά στελέχη ψήφου των γυναικών χρησιμοποίησαν 
ποικίλη τακτική κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου Ι για να
προωθήσουν την αιτία τους. Ενώ η πιό συντηρητική 
βορειοαμερικανική ένωση ψήφου γυναικών υποστήριξε δραστήρια τον 
πόλεμο με το πλέξιμο των καλτσών, την πώληση των πολεμικών 
δεσμών, και την προετοιμασία των προμηθειών Ερυθρών Σταυρών, τα 
μέλη του των συμβαλλόμενου μέρους πιό στρατευμένων εθνικών 
γυναικών συλλήφθηκαν για να περιφράξουν το λευκό οίκο. 
Κατά τη διάρκεια ενός τον Ιουλίου, του 1917, επίσκεψη 
από τους αντιπροσώπους της νέας ρωσικής κυβέρνησης, οι 
επιδεικνύοντες μπροστά από το λευκό οίκο απευθύνθηκαν στα 
envoys στην ψήφο υποστήριξης για τις αμερικανικές γυναίκες ως 
όρος για την παραμονή της Ρωσίας στο συνδεμένο στρατόπεδο. 
Το έμβλημα παρακίνησε την οργή των πατριωτικών περαστικών, 
και σύντομα αφότου λήφθηκε αυτή η φωτογραφία ένα πλήθος 
επιτέθηκε suffragists.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los activistas del sufragio de las mujeres utilizaron una 
variedad de táctica durante Primera Guerra Mundial para avanzar su 
causa. Mientras que la asociación norteamericana más 
conservadora del sufragio de la mujer enérgio utilizó la guerra 
haciendo punto calcetines, vendiendo enlaces de guerra, y preparando 
fuentes de la Cruz Roja, arrestaron a los miembros del partido 
militante de las más mujeres nacionales para cercar con piquete la 
casa blanca. Durante un julio de 1917, la visita de los 
representantes del nuevo gobierno ruso, manifestantes delante de la 
casa blanca abrogó a los envoys al sufragio de la ayuda para las 
mujeres americanas como condición para Rusia restante en el campo 
aliado. La bandera roused la ira de traseúntes 
patrióticos, y pronto después de que esta fotografía fuera tomada 
una muchedumbre enojada atacó los suffragists.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086211</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107897</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/hands-across-the-water</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
