<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105641</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105641</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974016</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Gotham Gazette Games and Quizzes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gotham Zeitung-Spiele und Quizen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jeux et jeux de gazette de Gotham</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogos e quizzes do gazette de Gotham</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giochi e quiz del gazette di Gotham</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παιχνίδια και διαγωνισμοοι γνώσεων εφημερίδων Gotham</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Juegos y concursos de la gaceta de Gotham</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">These games will let you--the reader--make policy. What problems would you like to take on as a virtual policy-maker? The fate of the city's garbage? The right way to balance civil liberties and security in an Emergency? Developing a balanced land use plan for a neighborhood? Gotham Gazette is a Web site about the issues facing New York City.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Spiele lassen Sie -- der Leser -- Politik 
bilden. Welche Probleme wurden Sie mögen als virtueller 
maßgebender Politiker an nehmen? Das Schicksal des Abfalls der 
Stadt? Die rechte Methode, Zivilfreiheiten und Sicherheit im 
Notfall auszugleichen? Eine ausgeglichene Flächennutzung 
entwickelnd, planen Sie für eine Nachbarschaft? Gotham Zeitung 
ist eine Web site über die Ausgaben, die New York City 
gegenüberstellen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ces jeux vous laisseront -- le lecteur -- définir
la politique. Quels problèmes aimez-vous prendre en fonction en
tant que personne définissant la politique virtuelle ? Le 
destin des ordures de la ville ? La bonne voie d'équilibrer des
libertés civiles et la sécurité en cas d'urgence ? En 
développant une utilisation de la terre équilibrée projetez pour un
voisinage ? La gazette de Gotham est un site de Web au 
sujet des issues faisant face à New York City.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Estes jogos deixá-lo-ão -- o leitor -- fazer a 
política. Que problemas  você gosta de fazer exame sobre como 
um policy-maker virtual? O fate do lixo da cidade? A 
maneira direita balançar liberdades civis e segurança em uma 
emergência? Desenvolvendo um uso de terra equilibrado planeie 
para uma vizinhança? O gazette de Gotham é um Web site sobre 
as edições que enfrentam New York City.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questi giochi li lasceranno -- il lettore -- 
definire la politica. Che problemi gradite prendere sopra come 
politico virtuale? Il destino dell'immondizia della città? 
Il giusto modo equilibrare le libertà civili e sicurezza in 
caso d'urgenza? Sviluppando un'utilizzazione delle terre 
equilibrata progetti per una vicinanza? Il gazette di Gotham è 
un Web site circa le edizioni che affrontano New York City.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτά τα παιχνίδια θα σας αφήσουν -- ο αναγνώστης -- να
κάνετε την πολιτική. Ποια προβλήματα θα επιθυμούσατε να 
πάρετε ως εικονικό σχεδιαστή πολιτικής; Η μοίρα των 
απορριμάτων της πόλης; Ο σωστός τρόπος να ισορροπηθούν οι 
αστικές ελευθερίες και η ασφάλεια σε μια έκτακτη ανάγκη; 
Ανάπτυξη ενός ισορροπημένου σχεδίου χρήσης εδάφους για μια
γειτονιά; Η εφημερίδα Gotham είναι ένας ιστοχώρος για τα
ζητήματα που απασχολούν την πόλη της Νέας Υόρκης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Estos juegos le dejarán -- el programa de lectura
-- hacer la política. ¿Qué problemas  usted tiene gusto de 
tomar encendido como regidor virtual? ¿El sino de la basura de 
la ciudad? ¿La manera derecha de balancear libertades civiles y 
seguridad en una emergencia? ¿Desarrollando una utilización del
suelo equilibrada planee para una vecindad? La gaceta de Gotham 
es un sitio del Web sobre las ediciones que hacen frente a New 
York City.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:GAIL ROBINSON, EDITOR-IN-CHIEF
FN:GAIL ROBINSON, EDITOR-IN-CHIEF
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974016</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105641</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/gotham-gazette-games-and-quizzes</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
