<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107577</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107577</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086097</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Don[']t Have to Mister Every Little White Boy. . .": Black Migrants Write Home</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Don[']t müssen Junge des Herr-Every Little 
White. . ": Schwarze Wanderer Schreiben Nach Hause</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Don[']t doivent garçon de Monsieur Every Little 
White. . ": Les Migrants Noirs Écrivent À la maison</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Don[']t tem que menino do mister Cada Pequeno 
Branco. . ": Os Emigrantes Pretos Escrevem Para casa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Don[']t deve ragazzo del mister Every Little 
White. . ": I Migranti Neri Scrivono A casa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Don[']t πρέπει ο κύριος Every Little White 
αγόρι. . ": Οι μαύροι μετανάστες γράφουν τη "Οικία"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Don[']t tiene que muchacho de señor Every Little
White. . ": Los Nómadas Negros Escriben A casa</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The experiences of the half million Africans Americans from the South who headed North between 1916 and 1921 varied widely among individuals. Four letters by southern migrants who had settled in Philadelphia, Chicago, and East Chicago, Indiana, provided some insights into the diverse experiences migrants had in the North. Resettled southerners wrote to folks back home about "the true facts of the present condition of the north." These "facts" ranged from salaries, living conditions, and recent births and deaths, to the score of the latest Chicago White Sox baseball game. The letters, which were originally published in the Journal of Negro History , also described what it feels like to be out of the South: "don[']t have to mister every little white boy comes along."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Erfahrungen der halben Million 
Afrikaner-Amerikaner vom Süden, die nördlich zwischen 1916 und 1921 
vorangehen, schwankten weit unter Einzelpersonen. Vier Zeichen 
durch südliche Wanderer, die in Philadelphia, in Chicago und in 
Ostchicago, Indiana abgerechnet hatten, vorausgesetzt etwas Einblicke 
in die verschiedenen Erfahrungen Wanderer im Norden hatten. 
Wieder hergestellte southerners schrieben zum rückseitigen Haus
der Völker über "die zutreffenden Tatsachen der anwesenden Bedingung
des Nordens." Diese "Tatsachen" reichten von den Gehältern, 
lebende Bedingungen und neue Geburten und Todesfälle, bis zu der 
Kerbe des neuesten Chicago weißen Sox Baseballspiels. Die 
Zeichen, die ursprünglich im Journal der Schwarze-Geschichte 
veröffentlicht wurden, auch beschrieben, was es glaubt wie, um aus 
dem Süden heraus zu sein: "don[']t müssen Herr, den jeder 
kleine weiße Junge kommt entlang."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les expériences de demi de million d'Américains 
d'Africains des Sud qui dirigent le nord entre 1916 et 
1921 ont changé considérablement parmi des individus. Quatre 
lettres par les migrants méridionaux qui s'étaient établis à 
Philadelphie, Chicago, et Chicago est, Indiana, si quelques aperçus 
des migrants divers d'expériences avaient dans le nord. 
Les habitants du sud reclassés ont écrit à la maison arrière de 
gens au sujet "des faits vrais de la condition du nord." Ces 
"faits" se sont étendus des salaires, conditions vivantes, et des 
naissances et des décès récentes, aux points du dernier jeu blanc 
de base-ball de Chicago Sox. Les lettres, qui ont été 
initialement publiées au journal de l'histoire de nègre, ont 
également décrit comme ce qu'il se sent pour être hors des 
Sud : le "don[']t doivent Monsieur que chaque petit 
garçon blanc vient le long."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As experiências dos meios milhão americanos dos 
africanos do sul que dirigem para o norte entre 1916 e 1921 variaram 
extensamente entre indivíduos. Quatro letras pelos emigrantes 
do sul que se tinham estabelecido em Filadélfia, em Chicago, e em 
Chicago do leste, Indiana, desde que algumas introspecções nos 
emigrantes diversos das experiências tiveram no norte. Os 
southerners resettled escreveram à HOME traseira dos povos sobre "os 
fatos verdadeiros da condição atual do norte." Estes "fatos" 
variaram dos salários, circunstâncias vivas, e nascimentos e mortes 
recentes, à contagem do jogo branco o mais atrasado do baseball de 
Chicago Sox. As letras, que foram publicadas originalmente no 
jornal do history do negro, descreveram também o que sente como para 
ser fora do sul: o "don[']t tem que mister que cada menino 
branco pequeno vem longitudinalmente."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le esperienze nei milione Americani mezzi degli 
Africani dal sud che dirigono a nord fra 1916 e 1921 hanno variato 
ampiamente fra gli individui. Quattro lettere dai migranti del 
sud che si erano depositati a Filadelfia, Chicago e Chicago orientale,
Indiana, se alcune visioni dei migranti vari di esperienze avessero 
nel nord. I southerners riassestati hanno scritto alla sede 
posteriore della gente circa "i fatti allineare del termine attuale 
del nord." Questi "fatti" hanno variato dagli stipendi, 
circostanze di vita e nascite e morti recenti, al segno di ultimo 
gioco bianco di baseball del Chicago Sox. Le lettere, che 
originalmente sono state pubblicate nel giornale di storia del negro, 
egualmente hanno descritto che cosa ritiene come per essere dal sud: 
"il don[']t deve mister che ogni ragazzo bianco piccolo viene 
avanti."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η εμπειρία των μισών από εκατομμύριο Αφρικανούς 
Αμερικανοί από το νότο που διεύθυνε το Βορρά μεταξύ 1916 και 
1921 ποίκιλε ευρέως μεταξύ των ατόμων. Τέσσερις 
επιστολές από τους νότιους μετανάστες που είχαν εγκαταστήσει στη
Φιλαδέλφεια, το Σικάγο, και το ανατολικό Σικάγο, Ινδιάνα, υπό 
τον όρο ότι μερικές ιδέες στους διαφορετικούς μετανάστες 
εμπειρίας είχαν στο Βορρά. Οι επανεγκατεστημένοι νότιοι 
έγραψαν στους λαούς πίσω στο σπίτι για "τα αληθινά γεγονότα του 
παρόντος όρου του Βορρά." Αυτά τα "γεγονότα" κυμάνθηκαν 
από τους μισθούς, συνθήκες διαβίωσης, και πρόσφατοι γεννήσεις 
και θάνατοι, ως το αποτέλεσμα του πιό πρόσφατου παιχνιδιού 
μπέιζ-μπώλ Sox του Σικάγου άσπρου. Οι επιστολές, που 
δημοσιεύθηκαν αρχικά στο περιοδικό της ιστορίας νέγρων, 
περιέγραψαν επίσης τι αισθάνεται όπως για να είναι από το νότο:
"don[']t πρέπει ο κύριος που κάθε μικρό λευκό αγόρι 
έρχεται κατά μήκος."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las experiencias de medios millón de americanos 
de los africanos del sur que dirigieron al norte entre 1916 y 1921 
variaron extensamente entre individuos. Cuatro cartas por los 
nómadas meridionales que habían colocado en Philadelphia, Chicago, y
Chicago del este, Indiana, con tal que algunas penetraciones en los 
nómadas diversos de las experiencias tuvieran en el norte. Los 
southerners restablecidos escribieron al hogar posterior de la gente 
sobre "los hechos verdaderos de la actual condición del norte." 
Estos "hechos" se extendieron de los sueldos, condiciones vivas,
y los nacimientos y las muertes recientes, a la cuenta del juego 
blanco más último del béisbol de Chicago Sox. Las cartas, que
fueron publicadas originalmente en el diario de la historia del negro,
también describieron como lo que se siente para estar fuera del sur: 
el "don[']t tiene que señor que viene cada pequeño muchacho 
blanco adelante."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086097</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107577</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/don-t-have-to-mister-every-little-white-boy-black-migrants-write-home</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
