<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103255</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103255</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201835</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Play Ayiti: The Cost of Life</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spiel Ayiti: Die Kosten des Lebens</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jeu Ayiti : Le coût de la vie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogo Ayiti: O custo da vida</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gioco Ayiti: Il costo di vita</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παιχνίδι Ayiti: Το κόστος της ζωής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Juego Ayiti: El coste de vida</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Ayiti: The Cost of Life is a role-playing video game in which the player assumes the roles of family members living in rural Haiti. At the start of the game, the player chooses a primary goal for his/her family: achieve education, make money, stay healthy, or maintain happiness. During the course of the game, the player encounters unexpected events and must make decisions that contribute to or detract from achieving the chosen goal.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ayiti: Die Kosten des Lebens sind ein Rolle 
spielendes videospiel, in dem der Spieler die Rollen der Familie 
Bauteile annimmt, die in landwirtschaftlichem Haiti leben. Beim 
Anfang des Spiels, wählt der Spieler ein Primärziel für seine/ihr 
Familie: erzielen Sie Ausbildung, verdienen Sie Geld, bleiben 
Sie gesund oder behalten Sie Glück bei. Während des Spiels 
müssen die unerwarteten Fälle des Spielertreffens und Entscheidungen
treffen, die zu beitragen oder vom Erzielen des gewählten Ziels 
abziehen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ayiti : Le coût de la vie est un jeu vidéo
jouant un rôle en lequel le joueur assume les rôles des membres de 
famille vivant au Haïti rural. Au début du jeu, le joueur 
choisit un but primaire pour sa famille : réalisez 
l'éducation, faites l'argent, restez sain, ou mettez à jour le 
bonheur. Pendant le jeu, les événements inattendus de 
rencontre de joueur et doivent prendre les décisions qui contribuent 
à ou amoindrissent réaliser le but choisi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ayiti: O custo da vida é um jogo video 
role-playing em que o jogador supõe os papéis dos membros da 
família que vivem em Haiti rural. No início do jogo, o jogador
escolhe um objetivo preliminar para his/her família: consiga a 
instrução, faça o dinheiro, permaneça saudável, ou mantenha a 
felicidade. Durante o jogo, os eventos inesperados do encontro 
do jogador e devem fazer as decisões que contribuem a ou diminuem de 
conseguir o objetivo escolhido.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ayiti: Il costo di vita è un gioco video 
d'atteggiamento in cui il giocatore ammette i ruoli dei membri della 
famiglia che vivono in Haiti rurale. All'inizio del gioco, il 
giocatore sceglie un obiettivo primario per la sua famiglia: 
realizzi la formazione, faccia i soldi, rimanga sano, o effettui
la felicità. Durante il corso del gioco, gli eventi inattesi di
incontro del giocatore e devono prendere le decisioni che 
contribuiscono a o riducono realizzare l'obiettivo scelto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ayiti: Το κόστος της ζωής είναι ένα 
ρόλος-παίζοντας τηλεοπτικό παιχνίδι στο οποίο ο παίκτης 
υποθέτει τους ρόλους των οικογενειακών μελών που ζουν στην 
αγροτική Αϊτή. Στην έναρξη του παιχνιδιού, ο παίκτης 
επιλέγει έναν αρχικό στόχο για την οικογένειά του/της: 
επιτύχετε την εκπαίδευση, κάνετε τα χρήματα, μείνετε 
υγιής, ή διατηρήστε την ευτυχία. Κατά τη διάρκεια του 
παιχνιδιού, ο παίκτης αντιμετωπίζει τα απροσδόκητα γεγονότα και 
πρέπει να λάβει τις αποφάσεις που συμβάλλουν ή μειώνουν την 
επίτευξη του επιλεγμένου στόχου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ayiti: El coste de vida es un juego video de
actuación de papeles en el cual el jugador asume el papeles de los 
miembros de la familia que viven en Haití rural. En el comienzo
del juego, el jugador elige una meta fundamental para su familia: 
alcance la educación, haga el dinero, permanezca sano, o 
mantenga la felicidad. Durante el curso del juego, los 
acontecimientos inesperados del encuentro del jugador y deben tomar 
las decisiones que contribuyen a o detraen de alcanzar la meta 
elegida.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201835</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103255</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/play-ayiti-the-cost-of-life</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
