<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105475</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105475</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087501</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Complete Nudity Is Never Permitted": The Motion Picture Production Code of 1930</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Komplette Nacktheit Wird Nie" Die Erlaubnis 
gehabt: Der Bewegung Abbildung Produktion Code von 1930</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"La Nudité Complète N'est jamais autorisée" : 
Le code de production de film cinématographique de 1930</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"A Desnudez Completa É permitida Nunca": O 
código da produção do retrato de movimento de 1930</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Il Nudity Completo Non è consentito Mai": 
Il codice di produzione del cinema di 1930</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η "πλήρης γυμνότητα δεν επιτρέπεται ποτέ": Ο 
κώδικας παραγωγής ταινιών του 1930</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La "Desnudez Completa Nunca Se permite": El 
código de la producción de la película de 1930</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Mae West spent her career on the stage and screen skirting--and sometimes transgressing--the boundaries of sexual and moral propriety. In 1926 and 1927, she outraged some critics (and landed herself in jail) with two sensational Broadway productions,  Sex  (a play she wrote about a Montreal prostitute, in which she also starred) and  The Drag  (a "homosexual comedy-drama" that she wrote and staged). In 1928, New York police arrested her again, this time for her play about a troupe of female impersonators,  Pleasure Man . In 1932, she brought her brand of ribald humor to the movies. West's move from Broadway to Hollywood was surprising, given the substantially tighter moral scrutiny under which the film industry operated. Adopted in 1930 by the Association of Motion Picture Producers, the Motion Picture Production Code, excerpted below, spelled out in detail what was and was not permissible in the nation's most popular form of entertainment.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mae West wendete ihre Karriere auf dem Stadium und
dem Bildschirm auf, welche umsäumen -- und, die manchmal 
transgressing -- die Grenzen des sexuellen und moralischen Anstands. 
1926 und 1927 verletzte sie einige Kritiker (und landete sich im
Gefängnis), mit zwei sensational Broadway Produktionen, Geschlecht 
(ein Spiel, das sie über ein Montreal Prostituiertees schrieb, in dem
sie auch starred) und der Gegenkraft (ein "homosexuelles dieses 
Komödie-Drama" schrieb sie und inszenierte). 1928 hielt New 
York Polizei sie wieder, dieses mal für ihr Spiel über ein troupe 
der weiblichen Imitatoren, Vergnügen Mann fest. 1932 holte sie 
ihre Marke der ribald Stimmung zu den Filmen. Westbewegung von 
Broadway zu Hollywood war das Überraschen, die im wesentlichen 
festere moralische Nachforschung gegeben, unter der die Filmindustrie 
funktionierte. Angenommen 1930 bei der Verbindung der Bewegung 
Abbildung Produzenten, der Bewegung Abbildung Produktion Code, unten 
excerptiert, buchstabiert aus im Detail, was nicht in der populärsten
Form der Nation der Unterhaltung zulässig war und war.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'ouest de Mae a dépensé sa carrière sur les 
bornes de bordage de the d'étape et d'écran -- et parfois 
transgressant -- de la convenance sexuelle et morale. En 1926
et 1927, elle a outragé quelques critiques (et s'est débarqué en 
prison) avec deux productions sensationnelles de Broadway, sexe (un jeu
qu'elle a écrit au sujet d'une prostituée de Montréal, dans 
laquelle elle a également tenu le premier rôle) et la drague ("un 
comédie-drame homosexuel" ce elle a écrit et a mis en scène). 
En 1928, la police de New York l'a arrêtée encore, cette fois 
pour son jeu au sujet d'une troupe des imitateurs féminins, 
homme de plaisir. En 1932, elle a apporté sa marque d'humeur 
égrillarde aux films. Le mouvement occidental de Broadway 
à Hollywood était étonner, donné sensiblement plus serré examen
minutieux moral sous lequel l'industrie de film a fonctionné. 
Adopté en 1930 par l'association des producteurs de film 
cinématographique, le code de production de film cinématographique, 
extrait ci-dessous, défini en détail ce qui était et n'était pas 
permis sous la forme la plus populaire de la nation du divertissement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O oeste de Mae gastou sua carreira no estágio e 
na tela que contornam -- e que transgressing às vezes -- os limites 
do propriety sexual e moral. Em 1926 e em 1927, ultrajou alguns 
críticos (e se aterrou na cadeia) com duas produções de Broadway do
sensational, sexo (um jogo que escreveu sobre um prostitute de 
Montreal, em que starred também) e o arrasto ("um comedy-comedy-drama
homosexual" esse escreveu e encenou). Em 1928, as polícias de 
New York prenderam-na outra vez, esta hora para seu jogo sobre um 
troupe de impersonators fêmeas, homem do prazer. Em 1932, 
trouxe seu tipo do humor do ribald aos filmes. O movimento 
ocidental de Broadway a Hollywood era surpreender, dado o scrutiny 
moral substancialmente mais apertado sob que a indústria da película
se operou. Adotado em 1930 pela associação de produtores do 
retrato de movimento, o código da produção do retrato de movimento,
excerpted abaixo, soletrado para fora de em detalhe o que era e não 
era permissível no formulário o mais popular da nação do 
entertainment.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'ovest di Mae ha speso la sua carriera
sulla fase e sullo schermo che fiancheggiano -- ed a volte che 
transgressing -- i contorni della convenienza sessuale e morale. 
In 1926 ed in 1927, ha oltraggiato alcuni critici (e si è 
atterrato in prigione) con due produzioni di Broadway di sensational, 
il sesso (un gioco che ha scritto circa un prostitute de Montreal, in 
cui egualmente starred) e la resistenza ("un commedia-drama 
omosessuale" quel ha scritto ed organizzato). In 1928, la 
polizia de New York la ha arrestata ancora, questo volta per il suo 
gioco circa un troupe dei impersonators femminili, uomo di piacere. 
In 1932, ha portato la sua marca di umore del ribald ai 
film. Il movimento ad ovest da Broadway a Hollywood era 
sorpresere, data l'esame accurato morale sostanzialmente più stretto 
sotto cui l'industria della pellicola ha funzionato. Adottato in
1930 dall'associazione dei produttori del cinema, il codice di 
produzione del cinema, stralciato sotto, spiegato dettagliatamente che
cosa era e non era ammissibile nella forma più popolare della nazione
di intrattenimento.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η δύση Mae ξόδεψε τη σταδιοδρομία της στο στάδιο 
και την οθόνη που περιζώνουν -- και μερικές φορές που παραβιάζουν
-- τα όρια της σεξουαλικής και ηθικής ευπρέπειας. Το 1926
και το 1927, πρόσβαλε μερικούς κριτικούς (και προσγειώθηκε στη 
φυλακή) με δύο συγκλονιστικές παραγωγές Broadway, το φύλο 
(ένα παιχνίδι έγραψε για μια πόρνη του Μόντρεαλ, στο οποίο αυτή
επίσης έναστρη) και την έλξη (ένα "ομοφυλοφιλικό κωμωδία-δράμα"
που έγραψε και οργάνωσε). Το 1928, η αστυνομία της Νέας 
Υόρκης την συνέλαβε πάλι, αυτή τη φορά για το παιχνίδι της για 
ένα troupe των θηλυκών μιμητών, άτομο ευχαρίστησης. Το 
1932, έφερε το εμπορικό σήμα αχρείου χιούμορ της στους 
κινηματογράφους. Η δυτική κίνηση από Broadway σε 
Hollywood ήταν εκπληκτική, λαμβάνοντας υπόψη την ουσιαστικά 
σφιχτότερη ηθική διερεύνηση κάτω από την οποία η βιομηχανία 
ταινιών λειτούργησε. Υιοθετημένος το 1930 από την ένωση 
των παραγωγών ταινιών, ο κώδικας παραγωγής ταινιών, κατωτέρω, 
συλλαβισμένος έξω λεπτομερώς τι ήταν και δεν ήταν επιτρεπόμενος 
στη δημοφιλέστερη μορφή του έθνους της ψυχαγωγίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El oeste de Mae pasó su carrera en la etapa y la 
pantalla que bordeaban -- y transgressing a veces -- los límites de 
la propiedad sexual y moral. En 1926 y 1927, ella ultrajó a 
algunos críticos (y se aterrizó en cárcel) con dos producciones de 
Broadway del sensational, el sexo (un juego que ella escribió sobre 
una prostitute de Montreal, en quien ella también starred) y la 
fricción (un "comedia-drama homosexual" ese ella escribió y 
efectuó). En 1928, el policía de Nueva York la arrestó otra 
vez, este vez para su juego sobre una compañía de impersonators 
femeninos, hombre del placer. En 1932, ella trajo su marca de 
fábrica del humor del ribald a las películas. El movimiento 
del oeste de Broadway a Hollywood era el sorprender, dado el 
escrutinio moral substancialmente más apretado bajo el cual la 
industria de la película funcionó. Adoptado en 1930 por la 
asociación de los productores de la película, el código de la 
producción de la película, extractado abajo, explicado 
detalladamente cuál era y no era permitido en la forma más popular 
de la nación de hospitalidad.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087501</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105475</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/complete-nudity-is-never-permitted-the-motion-picture-production-code-of-1930</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
