<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103928</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103928</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087003</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Negro in the North": South African Novelist Alan Paton Dissects the Racial Situation Beyond the South</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"der Schwarze im Norden": Südafrikanischer 
Novelist Alan Paton zergliedert die rassische Situation über dem 
Süden hinaus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"le nègre dans le nord" : Le 
romancier africain du sud Alan Paton dissèque la situation
raciale au delà des Sud</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"o negro no norte": O novelist Alan Paton do
africano sul dissects a situação racial além do sul</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"il negro nel nord": Il Romanziere 
sudafricano Alan Paton disseca la situazione razziale oltre il sud</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ο νέγρος στο Βορρά": Νοτιοαφρικανικός 
μυθιστοριογράφος Alan Paton Dissects η φυλετική κατάσταση 
πέρα από το νότο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"el negro en el norte": El novelista 
surafricano Alan Paton diseca la situación racial más allá del sur</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Alan Paton's first novel, Cry, the Beloved Country (1948), communicated the tragic dimensions of South Africa's system of apartheid to a world audience. In 1954, Paton was asked by Collier's magazine to observe and interview Americans about this country's system of racial segregation. For this second of two articles, Paton, a co-founder and president of the Liberal Party of South Africa, traveled to urban areas in the West and North in order to relate personal stories behind practices such as the restrictive covenant in housing markets, mob violence against blacks in housing projects, and discrimination in employment. Despite the widespread racial injustice he found, Paton predicted that "segregation is dying" in the U.S. due in large part to the struggles of blacks themselves. He concluded that Americans could find hope in the "advance of the Negro" and the recent Supreme Court ruling in  Brown v. Board of Education .</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Alan Patons erster Roman, Schrei, geliebte Country
(1948), teilte die tragischen Maße von System Südafrikas von 
Apartheid zu einem Weltpublikum mit. 1954 wurde Paton durch 
Zeitschrift Colliers gebeten, Amerikaner über System dieses Landes 
der rassischen Abtrennung zu beobachten und zu interviewen. Für
diese Sekunde von zwei Artikeln, mob Paton, ein Co-Gründer und 
Präsident der liberalen Partei von Südafrika, gereist zu den
städtischen Bereichen im Westen und Nord, um persönliche Geschichten
hinter Praxis wie der einschränkenden Vereinbarung in den 
Gehäusemärkten in Verbindung zu stehen, Gewalttätigkeit gegen 
Schwarze in den Gehäuseprojekten und Unterscheidung in der 
Beschäftigung. Trotz des weitverbreiteten rassischen Unrechts, 
das er, Paton fand, sagte voraus, daß "Abtrennung" in den VEREINIGTEN
STAATEN stirbt, die in großem Teil zu den Kämpfen von Schwarzen 
selbst passend sind. Er stellte fest, daß die Amerikaner 
Hoffnung im "Fortschritt des Schwarzen" und des neuen Höchsten 
Gerichts finden konnten anordnend im braunen v. Brett der Ausbildung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le premier roman d'Alan Paton, cri, 
Country aimé (1948), a communiqué les dimensions tragiques du 
système du sud de l'Afrique de la ségrégation à une 
assistance du monde. En 1954, Paton a été invité par le 
magazine de Collier à observer et interviewer des Américains au 
sujet du système de ce pays de la ségrégation raciale. Pour 
cette seconde de deux articles, Paton, un co-fondateur et le président
du parti libéral de l'Afrique du sud, parcouru aux zones 
urbaines dans l'ouest et le nord afin d'associer des histoires 
personnelles derrière des pratiques telles que l'engagement 
restrictif sur des marchés du logement, assaillent la violence contre
des noirs dans des projets de logement, et la discrimination dans 
l'emploi. En dépit de l'injustice raciale répandue qu'il a 
trouvée, Paton a prévu que la "ségrégation meurt" aux ETATS-UNIS 
dus dans la grande partie des luttes des noirs elles-mêmes. Il 
a conclu que les Américains pourraient trouver l'espoir dans 
l'"avance du nègre" et de la cour suprême récente régnant dans le 
panneau brun de v. de l'éducation.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A primeira novela de Alan Paton, grito, País 
beloved (1948), comunicou as dimensões trágicas do sistema de 
África do Sul do apartheid a uma audiência do mundo. Em 1954, 
Paton foi pedido pelo compartimento de Collier para observar e 
entrevistar americanos sobre o sistema deste país do segregation 
racial. Para este segundo de dois artigos, Paton, um 
co-co-founder e o presidente do partido liberal de África do Sul, 
viajado às áreas urbanas no oeste e norte a fim relacionar 
histórias pessoais atrás das práticas tais como o convénio 
restritivo em mercados de carcaça, mob a violência de encontro aos 
pretos em projetos de carcaça, e a discriminação no emprego. 
Apesar do injustice que racial difundido encontrou, Paton 
predisse que o "segregation está morrendo" nos ESTADOS UNIDOS devidos
na parte grande aos esforços dos pretos ela mesma. Concliu que 
os americanos poderiam encontrar a esperança no "avanço do negro" e 
da corte suprema recente que governam na placa marrom do v. da 
instrução.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il primo romanzo di Alan Paton, Grida, 
il Country caro (1948), ha comunicato le dimensioni tragiche del 
sistema della Sudafrica di segregazione ad un pubblico del mondo. 
In 1954, Paton è stato chiesto dallo scomparto del Collier di 
osservare ed intervistare gli Americani circa il sistema di questo 
paese della segregazione razziale. Per questo secondo di due 
articoli, Paton, un co-fondatore ed il presidente del partito liberale
della Sudafrica, viaggiato alle aree urbane nell'ovest e del nord per 
collegare le storia personali dietro le pratiche quale il patto 
restrittivo nei mercati degli alloggi, mob la violenza contro i neri 
nei progetti di alloggiamento e la distinzione nell'occupazione. 
Malgrado il injustice che razziale diffuso ha trovato, Paton ha 
predetto che "la segregazione sta morendo" negli STATI UNITI dovuti 
nella grande parte alle lotte dei neri essi stessi. Ha concluso 
che gli Americani potrebbero trovare la speranza "nell'avanzamento del
negro" e della Corte suprema recente che regolano nel Bordo 
marrone del v. di formazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το πρώτο μυθιστόρημα του Alan Paton's, κραυγή, η 
αγαπημένη χώρα (1948), διαβίβασε τις τραγικές διαστάσεις του 
συστήματος της Νότιας Αφρικής του απαρτχάιντ σε ένα παγκόσμιο 
ακροατήριο. Το 1954, Paton κλήθηκε από το περιοδικό 
του ανθρακωρύχου να παρατηρήσει και να πάρει συνέντευξη από 
Αμερικανούς για το σύστημα αυτής της χώρας του φυλετικού 
διαχωρισμού. Για αυτό το δευτερόλεπτο δύο άρθρων, Paton,
ένας ομο-ιδρυτής και ένας Πρόεδρος του Φιλελεύθερου Κόμματος της
Νότιας Αφρικής, ταξίδεψαν στις αστικές περιοχές στη δύση και το 
Βορρά προκειμένου να αφοριούνται οι προσωπικές ιστορίες πίσω 
από τις πρακτικές όπως το περιοριστικό συμβόλαιο στις αγορές 
κατοικίας, η βία όχλου ενάντια στους Μαύρους στα προγράμματα 
κατοικίας, και η διάκριση στην απασχόληση. Παρά τη 
διαδεδομένη φυλετική αδικία που βρήκε, Paton πρόβλεψε ότι "ο 
διαχωρισμός πεθαίνει" στις ΗΠΑ που οφείλεται στο μεγάλο μέρος 
στις προσπάθειες των Μαύρων οι ίδιοι. Κατέληξε στο 
συμπέρασμα ότι Αμερικανοί θα μπορούσαν να βρούν την ελπίδα στη 
"πρόοδο του νέγρου" και την πρόσφατη απόφαση του ανώτατου 
δικαστηρίου Brown V. Board της εκπαίδευσης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La primera novela de Alan Paton, grito, Country 
querido (1948), comunicó las dimensiones trágicas del sistema de 
Suráfrica del apartheid a una audiencia del mundo. En 1954, 
Paton fue pedido por el compartimiento de Collier observar y 
entrevistarse con a americanos sobre el sistema de este país de la 
segregación racial. Para este segundo de dos artículos, Paton,
un co-fundador y el presidente del partido liberal de Suráfrica, 
viajado a las áreas urbanas en el oeste y del norte para relacionar 
historias personales detrás de prácticas tales como el convenio 
restrictivo en mercados de cubierta, atestan violencia contra negros 
en complejos de viviendas, y la discriminación en el empleo. A 
pesar de la injusticia racial extensa que él encontró, Paton predijo
que la "segregación está muriendo" en los ESTADOS UNIDOS debidos en 
la parte grande a las luchas de negros ellos mismos. Él 
concluyó que los americanos podrían encontrar esperanza en el 
"avance del negro" y del Tribunal Supremo reciente que gobernaban en 
la tarjeta marrón del v. de la educación.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087003</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103928</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-negro-in-the-north-south-african-novelist-alan-paton-dissects-the-racial-situation-beyond-the-south</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
