<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108414</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108414</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203932</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Mexico's Popocatepetl: To flee or not to flee</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Popocatepetl Mexikos: Fliehen oder nicht 
fliehen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Popocatepetl du Mexique : Pour se sauver ou 
pour ne pas se sauver</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Popocatepetl De México: Para fujir ou para 
não fujir</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Popocatepetl Del Messico: Per fuggire o non 
fuggire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Popocatepetl του Μεξικού: Για να φύγει ή για 
να μην φύγει</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Popocatepetl De México: Para huir o no 
huir</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This National Geographic news article from December 2001 outlines the eruptive progress of Popocatepetl volcano in Mexico. The article discusses the difficulties of evacuating locals during volcanic disasters because of their overall beliefs that the volcano is their "friend." Users can also link to other National Geographic news stories, special news series and the main National Geographic site.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser nationale geographische Nachrichten Artikel
von einem Dezember 2001 umreißt den eruptive Fortschritt des 
Popocatepetl Vulkans in Mexiko. Der Artikel behandelt die 
Schwierigkeiten der evakuierenden Einheimischer während der 
vulkanischen Unfälle wegen ihres gesamten Glaubens, daß der Vulkan 
ist ihr "Freund." Benutzer können mit anderen nationalen 
geographischen Nachrichten Geschichten, spezieller Nachrichten Serie 
und der nationalen geographischen hauptsächlichsite auch binden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cet article géographique national de nouvelles à
partir de décembre 2001 trace les grandes lignes du progrès éruptif
du volcan de Popocatepetl au Mexique. L'article discute les 
difficultés des gens du pays d'évacuation pendant des désastres 
volcaniques en raison de leur croyance globale que le volcan est leur 
"ami." Les utilisateurs peuvent également joindre à d'autres 
histoires géographiques nationales de nouvelles, séries spéciales 
de nouvelles et au site géographique national principal.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este artigo geográfico nacional da notícia de 
dezembro 2001 esboça o progresso eruptive do vulcão de Popocatepetl 
em México. O artigo discute as dificuldades de locals evacuando
durante disastres vulcânicos por causa de sua opinião total que o 
vulcão é seu "amigo." Os usuários podem também ligar às 
outras histórias geográficas nacionais da notícia, série especial 
da notícia e ao local geográfico nacional principal.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo articolo geografico nazionale di notizie da
dicembre 2001 descrive il progresso eruptive del vulcano di 
Popocatepetl nel Messico. L'articolo discute le difficoltà dei 
locals d'evacuamento durante i disastri vulcanici a causa della loro 
credenza generale che il vulcano è il loro "amico." Gli utenti 
possono anche collegarsi alle altra storia geografiche nazionali di 
notizie, serie speciale di notizie ed al luogo geografico nazionale 
principale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το εθνικό γεωγραφικό άρθρο ειδήσεων από τον 
Δεκέμβριο του 2001 περιγράφει τη eruptive πρόοδο του 
ηφαιστείου Popocatepetl στο Μεξικό. Το άρθρο συζητά τις 
δυσκολίες τα locals κατά τη διάρκεια των ηφαιστειακών 
καταστροφών λόγω των γενικών πεποιθήσεών τους ότι το ηφαίστειο 
είναι "ο φίλος τους." Οι χρήστες μπορούν επίσης να 
συνδέσουν με άλλη εθνικές γεωγραφικές ιστορίες ειδήσεων, ειδική
σειρά ειδήσεων και τη βασική εθνική γεωγραφική περιοχή.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este artículo geográfico nacional de las 
noticias a partir de diciembre 2001 contornea el progreso eruptivo del
volcán de Popocatepetl en México. El artículo discute las 
dificultades de locals que evacuan durante desastres volcánicos 
debido a su creencia total que el volcán es su "amigo." Los 
utilizadores pueden también conectar a las otras historias 
geográficas nacionales de las noticias, serie especial de las 
noticias y al sitio geográfico nacional principal.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203932</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108414</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/mexicos-popocatepetl-to-flee-or-not-to-flee</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
