<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106368</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106368</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973930</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Medicine Games: DNA Double Helix Game</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Medizin-Spiele: DNA Doppeltes Schneckenspiel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jeux de Médecine : Double Jeu de Spirale 
d'ADN</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogos Da Medicina: Jogo Dobro Da Hélice do 
Dna</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giochi Della Medicina: Doppio Gioco 
Dell'Elica del DNA</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παιχνίδια ιατρικής: Διπλό παιχνίδι ελίκων 
DNA</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Juegos De la Medicina: Juego Doble De la 
Hélice de la DNA</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Play a game and find out about a Nobel Prize awarded discovery or work! In the beginning of the 1950s, biologists knew that DNA carried the hereditary message. But how? The DNA molecule looks like a spiral ladder where the rungs are formed by base molecules, which occur in pairs. These sequences of base pairs represent the genetic information. In the game below, you can make copies of DNA molecules and find out which organism the genetic material belongs to!</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spielen Sie ein Spiel und finden Sie über eine 
zugesprochene Entdeckung oder eine Arbeit des Nobelpreises heraus! 
Am Anfang der fünfziger Jahre, wußten Biologen, daß DNA die 
erbliche Meldung trug. Aber wie? Das DNA Molekül sieht 
wie eine Spiralestrichleiter aus, in der die Rungs durch niedrige 
Moleküle gebildet werden, die in den Paaren auftreten. Diese 
Reihenfolgen der niedrigen Paare stellen die genetischen Informationen
dar. Im Spiel unten, können Sie Exemplare von den DNA 
Molekülen erstellen und herausfinden, denen Organismus das genetische
Material gehört!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jouez un jeu et découvrez au sujet d'une 
découverte ou d'un travail attribuée de prix Nobel ! Dans le 
début des années 50, les biologistes ont su que l'ADN a diffusé le 
message héréditaire. Mais comment ? La molécule d'ADN 
ressemble à une échelle en spirale où les échelons sont 
constitués par les molécules de base, qui se produisent dans les 
paires. Ces ordres des paires de base représentent 
l'information génétique. Dans le jeu ci-dessous, vous pouvez 
tirer des copies des molécules d'ADN et découvrir aux lesquelles 
l'organization le matériel génétique appartient !</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogue um jogo e encontre-o para fora sobre uma 
descoberta ou um trabalho concedido do prêmio de nobel! No 
começo dos 1950s, os biólogos souberam que o DNA carregou a mensagem
hereditary. Mas como? A molécula do DNA olha como uma 
escada espiral onde os rungs sejam dados forma pelas moléculas 
baixas, que ocorrem em pares. Estas seqüências de pares baixos
representam a informação genetic. No jogo abaixo, você pode 
fazer cópias das moléculas do DNA e encontrá-las para fora a que o 
organismo o material genetic pertence!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gioc un gioco e scopra circa una scoperta o un 
lavoro ricevuta del premio Nobel! Nell'inizio degli anni 50, i 
biologhi hanno saputo che il DNA ha trasportato il messaggio 
ereditario. Ma come? La molecola del DNA assomiglia ad una
scaletta a spirale in cui i rungs sono costituiti dalle molecole 
basse, che si presentano negli accoppiamenti. Queste sequenze 
degli accoppiamenti bassi rappresentano le informazioni genetiche. 
Nel gioco qui sotto, potete fare le copie delle molecole del DNA
e scoprire a cui l'organismo il materiale genetico appartiene!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παίξτε ένα παιχνίδι και ανακαλύψτε για μια 
απονεμημένη βραβείο ανακάλυψη ή μια εργασία Νόμπελ! Στην 
αρχή της δεκαετίας του '50, οι βιολόγοι ήξεραν ότι το DNA 
έφερε το κληρονομικό μήνυμα. Αλλά πώς; Το μόριο 
DNA μοιάζει με μια σπειροειδή σκάλα όπου οι βαθμίδες 
διαμορφώνονται από τα μόρια βάσεων, τα οποία εμφανίζονται ανά 
τα ζευγάρια. Αυτές οι ακολουθίες ζευγαριών βάσεων 
αντιπροσωπεύουν τις γενετικές πληροφορίες. Στο παιχνίδι 
κατωτέρω, μπορείτε να κάνετε τα αντίγραφα των μορίων DNA και 
να ανακαλύψετε ποιο οργανισμό το γενετικό υλικό ανήκεϊ</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Juegue un juego y descubra sobre un descubrimiento
o un trabajo concedido del premio Nobel! En el principio de los 
años 50, los biólogos sabían que la DNA llevó el mensaje 
hereditario. ¿Pero cómo? La molécula de la DNA parece 
una escala espiral donde los peldaños son formados por las moléculas
bajas, que ocurren en pares. Estas secuencias de pares bajos 
representan la información genética. ¡En el juego abajo, usted
puede hacer copias de las moléculas de la DNA y descubrir a las 
cuales el organismo el material genético pertenece!</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973930</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106368</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/medicine-games-dna-double-helix-game</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
