<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103971</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103971</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087029</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Pulpit Being My Great Design ": A Minister in Early 18th-Century New England.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Die Kanzel, die Mein Großes Design" Ist:
Ein Minister in frühem 18th-Century Neu-England.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Le Pupitre Étant Ma Grande Conception" : 
Un ministre dans 18th-Century tôt Nouvelle Angleterre.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"O Pulpit Que É Meu Projeto Grande": Um 
ministro em 18th-Century adiantado Nova Inglaterra.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Il Quadro di comando Che È Il Mio Disegno 
Grande": Un Ministro in 18th-Century iniziale Nuova 
Inghilterra.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Pulpit που είναι το μεγάλο σχέδιό μου": 
Ένας Υπουργός στον πρόωρο 18$ος-αιώνα Νέα Αγγλία.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"El Púlpito Que es Mi Gran Diseño": Un 
ministro en 18th-Century temprano Nueva Inglaterra.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Eighteenth-century New Englanders increasingly found themselves living within the imperial context of the European wars and Enlightenment ideas that flowed across the Atlantic. John Barnard, the long-time minister of Marblehead, Massachusetts, was influenced by those ideas. He took the traditional path toward becoming a Congregational minister by attending an English school, grammar school, and then Harvard College, the main supplier of the region's clergy and integral to its intellectual life. While Barnard held traditional providential beliefs in God's responsibility for events, his life history also revealed an increasing layer of newer scientific beliefs and values. Less isolated than their 17th-century predecessors, the New England ministry at the turn of the 18th century traveled to Europe and took part in the increasing English book trade that brought European ideas to them, as seen in Barnard's autobiography.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Achtzehnt-Jahrhundert neue Engländer fanden sich in 
zunehmendem Maße, innerhalb des imperialen Kontextes der 
europäischen Kriege und der Aufklärungideen zu leben, die über den 
Atlantik flossen. John Barnard, der langfristige Minister von 
Marblehead, Massachusetts, wurde durch jene Ideen beeinflußt. 
Er nahm den traditionellen Pfad in Richtung zum Werden ein 
Gemeindeminister, indem er eine englische Schule, Grammatikschule und 
dann Harvard Hochschule, den Hauptlieferanten des Klerus der Region 
und Integral um seine intellektuelle Lebensdauer bediente. 
Während Barnard traditionellen providential Glauben an 
Verantwortlichkeit des Gottes für Fälle anhielt, deckte seine 
Lebengeschichte auch eine zunehmende Schicht neueren 
wissenschaftlichen Glauben und Werte auf. Kleiner lokalisierte 
als ihre Vorgänger 17th-century, reiste das Neu-England Ministerium 
an der Jahrhundertwende 18. zu Europa und nahm am zunehmenden 
englischen Buchhandel, der ihnen europäische Ideen holte, wie in 
Autobiographie Barnards gesehen teil.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les nouveaux Anglais de Dix-huitième-siècle se sont de 
plus en plus trouvés vivre dans le contexte impérial des guerres et 
des idées européennes d'éclaircissement qui ont coulé à travers 
l'Océan atlantique. John Barnard, le ministre à long terme de 
Marblehead, le Massachusetts, a été influencé par ces idées. 
Il a pris la voie d'accès traditionnelle vers devenir un 
ministre en assemblée en assistant à une école anglaise, à 
l'école de grammaire, et puis à l'université de Harvard, au 
fournisseur principal du clergé de la région et à l'intégrale son 
vie intellectuelle. Tandis que Barnard tenait la croyance 
providentielle traditionnelle dans la responsabilité de Dieu des 
événements, sa histoire de la vie a également indiqué une couche 
croissante d'une plus nouvelles croyance et valeurs scientifiques. 
Moins a isolé que leurs prédécesseurs 17th-century, le 
ministère de la Nouvelle Angleterre à la fin du 18ème siècle a 
voyagé à l'Europe et a participé au commerce de livre anglais 
croissant qui leur a apporté des idées européennes, comme vu en 
autobiographie de Barnard.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">os englanders novos de Décimo-século encontraram-se cada
vez mais viver dentro do contexto imperial das guerras e das idéias 
européias do enlightenment que fluíram através do Atlântico. 
John Barnard, ministro long-time de Marblehead, Massachusetts, 
foi influenciado por aquelas idéias. Fêz exame do trajeto 
tradicional para transformar-se um ministro congregational atendendo a
uma escola inglesa, à escola da gramática, e então à faculdade de 
Harvard, ao fornecedor principal do clergy da região e à integral a 
sua vida intelectual. Quando Barnard prendeu a opinião 
providential tradicional na responsabilidade do deus para eventos, seu
history da vida revelou também uma camada crescente de uma opinião e
de uns valores científicos mais novos. Menos isolou-se do que 
seus predecessors 17th-century, o ministry de Nova Inglaterra na volta
do 18o século viajou a Europa e fêz exame da parte no comércio de 
livro inglês crescente que lhes trouxe idéias européias, como visto
no autobiography de Barnard.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">i nuovi englanders di Diciottesimo-secolo sempre più si 
sono scoperti che vivono all'interno del contesto imperiale delle 
guerre e delle idee europee di chiarimento che hanno fluito attraverso
l'Atlantico. John Barnard, il ministro long-time di 
Marblehead, Massachusetts, è stato influenzato da quelle idee. 
Ha preso il percorso tradizionale verso diventare un ministro
congregational assistendo ad una scuola inglese, alla scuola di 
grammatica ed allora all'università de Harvard, al fornitore 
principale del clergy della regione ed all'integrale alla relativa 
vita intellettuale. Mentre Barnard ha tenuto la credenza 
providential tradizionale nella responsabilità del dio degli eventi, 
la sua storia di vita egualmente ha rivelato uno strato aumentante di 
più nuovi credenza e valori scientifici. Di meno si è isolato 
che i loro predecessori 17th-century, il ministero della Nuova 
Inghilterra alla fine del diciottesimo secolo ha viaggiato ad Europa 
ed ha partecipato al commercio di libro inglese aumentante che ha 
portato le idee europee loro, come visto in autobiography del Barnard.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο δέκατος-αιώνας νέο Englanders βρέθηκε όλο και 
περισσότερο μέσα στο αυτοκρατορικό πλαίσιο των ευρωπαϊκών 
πολέμων και των ιδεών Διαφωτισμού που έρευσαν πέρα από τον 
Ατλαντικό. Θ*Ιοχν Barnard, ο μακροπρόθεσμος υπουργός 
Marblehead, Μασαχουσέτη, επηρεάστηκε από εκείνες τις ιδέες. 
Πήρε το παραδοσιακό μονοπάτι προς να γίνει εκκλησιαστικός 
υπουργός με την ανταπόκριση ενός αγγλικού σχολείου, του σχολείου
μέσης εκπαίδευσης, και έπειτα του κολλεγίου του Χάρβαρντ, του 
βασικού προμηθευτή της ιεροσύνης της περιοχής και του 
ολοκληρώματος στη διανοητική ζωή του. Ενώ Barnard 
κράτησε τις παραδοσιακές θεόσταλτες πίστεις στην ευθύνη του Θεού
για τα γεγονότα, η ιστορία ζωής του αποκάλυψε επίσης ένα 
αυξανόμενο στρώμα των νεώτερων επιστημονικών πεποιθήσεων και 
αξιών. Λιγότερο απομονωμένο από τους προκατόχους 
17$ος-αιώνα τους, το υπουργείο της Νέας Αγγλίας στο γύρισμα του 
18$ου αιώνα ταξίδεψε στην Ευρώπη και συμμετείχε στο αυξανόμενο 
αγγλικό εμπόριο βιβλίων που έφερε τις ευρωπαϊκές ιδέες σε τους,
όπως βλέπει στην αυτοβιογραφία Barnard.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">los nuevos ingleses del De'cimo octavo-siglo se 
encontraron cada vez más el vivir dentro del contexto imperial de las
guerras y de las ideas europeas de la aclaración que fluyeron a 
través del Atlántico. Esas ideas influenció a Juan Barnard, 
el ministro de largo plazo de Marblehead, Massachusetts. Él 
tomó el camino tradicional hacia hacer ministro congregational 
atendiendo a una escuela inglesa, a la escuela de la gramática, y 
entonces a la universidad de Harvard, al surtidor principal del clero 
de la región y al integral a su vida intelectual. Mientras que 
Barnard llevó a cabo creencia providential tradicional en la 
responsabilidad del dios de acontecimientos, su historia de la vida 
también reveló una capa de aumento de una más nuevos creencia y 
valores científicos. Menos aisló que sus precursores 
17th-century, el ministerio de Nueva Inglaterra al final del décimo 
octavo siglo viajó a Europa y participó en el comercio de libro 
inglés de aumento que les trajo ideas europeas, según lo considerado
en la autobiografía de Barnard.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087029</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103971</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-pulpit-being-my-great-design-a-minister-in-early-18th-century-new-england</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
