<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106890</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106890</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087381</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">American Soldiers in the Philippines Write Home about the War</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Amerikanische Soldaten in den Philippinen 
schreiben nach Hause über den Krieg</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les soldats américains aux Philippines écrivent 
à la maison au sujet de la guerre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os soldados americanos nas Filipinas escrevem para
casa sobre a guerra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I soldati americani nelle Filippine scrivono a 
casa circa la guerra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι αμερικανικοί στρατιώτες στις Φιλιππίνες γράφουν τη 
"Οικία" για τον πόλεμο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los soldados americanos en las Filipinas escriben 
a casa sobre la guerra</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">During the U.S. war in the Philippines between 1899 and 1904 (which grew out of the Spanish-American War that had erupted in 1898), ordinary American soldiers shared the nationalist zeal of their commanders and pursued the Filipino "enemy" with brutality and sometimes outright lawlessness. Racism, which flourished in the United States in this period, led American soldiers to repeatedly assert their desire "to get at the niggers." An anti-imperialist movement, which rejected annexation by the United States of former Spanish colonies like Puerto Rico and the Philippines, attempted to build opposition at home to the increasingly brutal war. Although few soldiers joined the anti-imperialist cause, their statements did sometimes provide ammunition for the opponents of annexation and war. In 1899, the Anti-Imperialist League published a pamphlet of  Soldiers Letters , with the provocative subtitle: "Being Materials for a History of a War of Criminal Aggression." Historian Jim Zwick notes that the publication "was immediately controversial. Supporters of the war discounted the accounts of atrocities as the boasting of soldiers wanting to impress their friends and families at home or, because the identities of some of the writers were withheld from publication, as outright fabrications." But the brutal portrayal of the war that is found in these letters (excerpts from twenty-seven of them are included here) is supported in other accounts.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während des VEREINIGTE STAATEN Krieges in den 
Philippinen zwischen 1899 und 1904 (die aus dem 
Spanisch-Amerikanischen Krieg heraus wuchsen, der 1898 ausgebrochen 
hatte), teilten gewöhnliche amerikanische Soldaten den 
nationalistischen Eifer ihrer Kommandanten und übten den Filipino 
"Feind" mit Brutalitäten und manchmal völligem Lawlessness aus. 
Rassismus, der in den Vereinigten Staaten in dieser Periode 
blühte, führende amerikanische Soldaten, zum ihres Wunsches 
wiederholt zu erklären ", an den niggers zu erhalten." Eine 
Anti-Imperialist Bewegung, die Annexion durch die Vereinigten 
Staaten der ehemaligen spanischen Kolonien wie Puerto Rico und der 
Philippinen zurückwies, versuchte, Opposition zum in zunehmendem 
Maße brutalen Krieg zu Hause aufzubauen. Obgleich wenige 
Soldaten die Anti-Imperialist Ursache verbanden, stellten ihre 
Anweisungen manchmal Munition für die Konkurrenten der Annexion
und des Krieges zur Verfügung. 1899 veröffentlichte die 
Anti-Imperialist Liga eine Flugschrift der Soldat-Zeichen, mit dem 
provozierenden Untertitel: "seiend Materialien für eine 
Geschichte eines Krieges des kriminellen Angriffs." Historiker 
Jim Zwick beachtet, daß die Publikation "sofort umstritten war. 
Verfechter des Krieges diskontierten die Konten der 
Grausamkeiten als das Rühmen der Soldaten, die ihre Freunde und 
Familien oder, weil die Identitäten von einigen der Verfasser von der
Publikation zurückgehalten wurden, als völlig Herstellungen zu Hause
beeindrucken wünschen." Aber die brutale Schilderung des 
Krieges, der in diesen Zeichen gefunden wird (Excerpts von 
twenty-seven von ihnen sind eingeschlossen hier) wird unterstützt in 
anderen Konten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant la guerre des ETATS-UNIS aux Philippines 
entre 1899 et 1904 (qui se sont développés hors de la guerre 
Espagnol-Américaine qui avait éclaté en 1898), les soldats 
américains ordinaires ont partagé l'ardeur nationaliste de leurs 
commandants et ont poursuivi l'"ennemi" philippin avec la brutalité 
et l'anarchie parfois pure. Racisme, qui s'est épanoui aux 
Etats-Unis dans cette période, soldats américains menés pour 
affirmer à plusieurs reprises leur désir "d'atteindre les niggers." 
Un mouvement d'anti-impérialiste, qui a rejeté l'annexation 
par les Etats-Unis d'anciennes colonies espagnoles comme le Porto Rico
et les Philippines, a essayé d'établir l'opposition à la maison à 
la guerre de plus en plus brutale. Bien que peu de soldats aient
joint la cause d'anti-impérialiste, leurs rapports ont parfois fourni
des munitions pour les adversaires de l'annexation et de la guerre. 
En 1899, la ligue d'Anti-Impérialiste a édité une brochure 
des lettres de soldats, avec le sous-titre provocateur : "étant
matériaux pour une histoire d'une guerre d'agression criminelle." 
L'historien Jim Zwick note que la publication "était 
immédiatement controversée. Les défenseurs de la guerre ont 
escompté les comptes des atrocités en tant que vantardise des 
soldats voulant impressionner leurs amis et familles à la maison ou, 
parce que les identités de certains des auteurs ont été retenues à
la publication, en tant que tout à fait fabrications." Mais la 
représentation brutale de la guerre qui est trouvée dans ces lettres
(des extraits de twenty-seven d'elles sont incluses ici) est 
supportée dans d'autres comptes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Durante a guerra de ESTADOS UNIDOS nas Filipinas 
entre 1899 e 1904 (que cresceram fora da guerra Espanhol-Americana que
erupted em 1898), os soldados americanos ordinários compartilharam do
zeal nacionalista de seus comandantes e perseguiram o "inimigo 
filipino" com brutality e lawlessness às vezes outright. 
Racism, que floresceu nos estados unidos neste período, 
soldados americanos conduzidos para afirmar repetidamente seu desejo 
"começar nos niggers." Um movimento do anti-anti-imperialist, 
que rejeite o annexation pelos estados unidos de colônias espanholas 
anteriores gosta de Puerto Rico e das Filipinas, tentou construir a 
oposição na HOME à guerra cada vez mais brutal. Embora poucos
soldados juntassem a causa do anti-anti-imperialist, suas indicações
forneceram às vezes a munição para os oponentes do annexation e da 
guerra. Em 1899, a liga do Anti-anti-Imperialist publicou um 
panfleto de letras dos soldados, com o subtítulo provocative: 
"sendo materiais para um history de uma guerra do aggression 
criminal." O historian Jim Zwick anota que a publicação "era 
imediatamente controversa. Os supporters da guerra discontaram 
os clientes dos atrocities como boasting dos soldados que querem 
imprimir outright seus amigos e famílias na HOME ou, porque as 
identidades de alguns dos escritores foram retidas da publicação, 
como fabricações." Mas o portrayal brutal da guerra que é 
encontrada nestas letras (excerpts de twenty-seven delas é incluído 
aqui) é suportado em outros clientes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Durante la guerra degli STATI UNITI nelle 
Filippine fra 1899 e 1904 (che si sono sviluppati dalla guerra 
Spagnolo-Americana che aveva scoppiato in 1898), i soldati 
americani ordinari hanno ripartito lo zelo nazionalista dei loro 
comandanti ed hanno perseguito "il nemico" filipino con il brutality 
ed il lawlessness a volte autentico. Il razzismo, che è fiorito
in unito Dichiara in questo periodo, soldati americani condotti
per asserire ripetutamente il loro desiderio "ottenere ai niggers." 
Un movimento del anti-anti-imperialist, che ha rifiutato il 
annexation dal unito Dichiara di ex colonie spagnole come il 
Porto Rico e le Filippine, ha tentato di sviluppare l'opposizione nel 
paese alla guerra sempre più brutale. Anche se pochi soldati 
hanno unito la causa del anti-anti-imperialist, le loro istruzione a 
volte hanno fornito le munizioni per gli avversari del annexation e 
della guerra. In 1899, la lega del Anti-anti-Imperialist ha 
pubblicato un opuscolo delle lettere dei soldati, con il sottotitolo 
provocatorio: "essendo materiali per una storia di una guerra di
aggressione criminale." Lo storico Jim Zwick nota che la 
pubblicazione "era immediatamente discutibile. I sostenitori 
della guerra hanno scontato i clienti delle atrocità come il vanto 
dei soldati che desiderano impressionare i loro amici e famiglie nel 
paese o, perché le identità di alcuni dei produttori sono state 
ritenute dalla pubblicazione, come completamente montaggi." Ma 
la rappresentazione brutale della guerra che è trovata in queste 
lettere (brani da twenty-seven di loro è inclusa qui) è sostenuta in
altri clienti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατά τη διάρκεια του ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΥ πολέμου στις 
Φιλιππίνες μεταξύ 1899 και 1904 (που αυξήθηκαν από το 
spanish-American πόλεμο που είχε εκραγεί 1898), οι 
συνηθισμένοι αμερικανικοί στρατιώτες μοιράστηκαν τον εθνικιστικό 
ζήλο των διοικητών τους και ακολούθησαν τον των Φηληππίνων 
"εχθρό" με τη βιαιότητα και μερικές φορές το ολοκληρωτικό 
lawlessness. Ο ρατσισμός, που άκμασε στις Ηνωμένες 
Πολιτείες σε αυτήν την περίοδο, οδήγησε τους αμερικανικούς 
στρατιώτες για να βεβαιώσει επανειλημμένα την επιθυμία τους 
"παίρνω στα niggers." Μια αντι-ιμπεριαλιστική μετακίνηση, 
που απέρριψε την προσάρτηση από τις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες των πρώην
ισπανικών αποικιών όπως το Πουέρτο Ρίκο και τις Φιλιππίνες, 
προσπάθησε να χτίσει αντίθεση στο σπίτι στον όλο και περισσότερο
βάναυσο πόλεμο. Αν και λίγοι στρατιώτες ένωσαν την 
αντι-ιμπεριαλιστική αιτία, οι δηλώσεις τους μερικές φορές 
παρείχαν τα πυρομαχικά για τους αντιπάλους της προσάρτησης και του
πολέμου. Το 1899, η ένωση αντι-ιμπεριαλιστών δημοσίευσε 
ένα τεύχος των επιστολών στρατιωτών, με τον προκλητικό υπότιτλο:
"Όντας υλικά για μια ιστορία ενός πολέμου της εγκληματικής
επιθετικότητας." Ο ιστορικός jim Zwick σημειώνει ότι η
δημοσίευση "ήταν αμέσως αμφισβητούμενη. Οι υποστηρικτές του
πολέμου απέρριψαν τους απολογισμούς των αγριοτήτων ως 
καυχησιολογία των στρατιωτών που θέλουν να εντυπωσιάσουν τους 
φίλους και τις οικογένειές τους στο σπίτι ή, επειδή οι 
ταυτότητες μερικοί από τους συγγραφείς παρακρατήθηκαν από τη 
δημοσίευση, ως ολοκληρωτικά fabrications." Αλλά η βάναυση
απεικόνιση του πολέμου που βρίσκεται σε αυτές τις επιστολές (τα 
αποσπάσματα από είκοσι επτά από τις συμπεριλαμβάνονται εδώ) 
υποστηρίζεται σε άλλους απολογισμούς.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Durante la guerra de ESTADOS UNIDOS en las 
Filipinas entre 1899 y 1904 (que crecieron fuera de la guerra 
Español-Americana que había entrado en erupción en 1898), los 
soldados americanos ordinarios compartieron el celo nacionalista de 
sus comandantes y persiguieron al "enemigo filipino" con brutalidad y 
anarquía a veces absoluta. Racismo, que prosperó en los 
Estados Unidos en este período, soldados americanos conducidos para 
afirmar en varias ocasiones su deseo "de conseguir en los niggers." 
Un movimiento del contra-imperialista, que rechazó la anexión 
de los Estados Unidos de colonias españolas anteriores como Puerto 
Rico y las Filipinas, procuró construir la oposición en el país a 
la guerra cada vez más brutal. Aunque pocos soldados 
ensamblaron la causa del contra-imperialista, sus declaraciones 
proporcionaron a veces a la munición para los opositores de la 
anexión y de la guerra. En 1899, la liga del 
Contra-Imperialista publicó un folleto de las cartas de los soldados,
con el subtítulo provocativo: "siendo materiales para una 
historia de una guerra de la agresión criminal." El historiador
Jim Zwick observa que la publicación "era inmediatamente polémica. 
Los partidarios de la guerra descontaron las cuentas de 
atrocidades como la jactancia de los soldados que deseaban impresionar
a sus amigos y familias en el país o, porque las identidades de 
algunos de los programas de escritura fueron retenidas de la 
publicación, como francamente fabricaciones." Pero la 
representación brutal de la guerra que se encuentra en estas cartas 
(los extractos de twenty-seven de ellas se incluye aquí) se utiliza 
en otras cuentas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087381</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106890</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/american-soldiers-in-the-philippines-write-home-about-the-war</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
