<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108475</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108475</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212632</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Living Edens: Virtual Yellowstone Tour</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Lebende Edens: Virtuelle Yellowstone 
Tour</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">l'Edens Vivant : Excursion Virtuelle de 
Yellowstone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Edens Vivo: Excursão Virtual De 
Yellowstone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Edens Vivente: Giro Virtuale Di 
Yellowstone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η διαβίωση Edens: Εικονικός γύρος 
Yellowstone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Edens Vivo: Viaje Virtual De Yellowstone</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Starting Point page describes a virtual tour of Yellowstone National Park in Wyoming featured on the Public Broadcasting Service (PBS) website. In this tour, students act as park rangers to research geological features of Yellowstone, locate these features on maps, and describe and define associated geologic terms. The features discussed include geysers, hot springs, canyons, waterfalls and mudpots. On this page, users can find learning goals, teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment hints and references and resources dealing with this exercise. It also describes the context in which the virtual tour is best used.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Ausgangspunktseite beschreibt eine virtuelle
Tour von Yellowstone Nationalpark in Wyoming, das auf der allgemeinen 
gekennzeichnet wird Web site des Sendedienstes (PBS). In dieser 
Tour dienen Kursteilnehmer als Parkförster, um geologische Merkmale 
von Yellowstone zu erforschen, diese Merkmale auf Karten zu 
lokalisieren, und verbundene geologische Bezeichnungen zu beschreiben 
und zu definieren. Die behandelten Merkmale schließen Geysire, 
heiße Frühlinge, Schluchten, Wasserfälle und mudpots ein. Auf
dieser Seite können Benutzer die erlernenziele, unterrichtende 
Anmerkungen und Spitzen, Lehrmittel, Einschätzung Tips und Referenzen
und Betriebsmittel beschäftigend diese Übung finden. Sie 
beschreibt auch den Kontext, in dem die virtuelle Tour gut verwendet 
wird.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette page de point de départ décrit une 
excursion virtuelle de parc national de Yellowstone au Wyoming décrit
sur le site Web public du service de radiodiffusion (PBS). Dans 
cette excursion, les étudiants agissent en tant que gardes 
forestières de parc pour rechercher les dispositifs géologiques de 
Yellowstone, pour localiser ces dispositifs sur des cartes, et pour 
décrire et définir des limites géologiques associées. Les 
dispositifs discutés incluent des geysers, des ressorts chauds, des 
gorges, des chutes d'eau et des mudpots. À cette page, les 
utilisateurs peuvent trouver des buts d'étude, des notes et des 
extrémités d'enseignement, matériel didactique, des conseils 
d'évaluation et des références et des ressources traitant cet 
exercice. Il décrit également le contexte dans lequel 
l'excursion virtuelle mieux est utilisée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta página do ponto começar descreve uma 
excursão virtual do parque nacional de Yellowstone em Wyoming 
caracterizado no Web site público do serviço de transmissão (PBS). 
Nesta excursão, os estudantes agem como rangers do parque para 
pesquisar características geological de Yellowstone, para encontrar 
estas características em mapas, e para descrever e definir termos 
geologic associados. As características discutidas incluem 
geysers, as molas quentes, as gargantas, as cachoeiras e os mudpots. 
Nesta página, os usuários podem encontrar os objetivos de 
aprendizagem, as notas e as pontas ensinando, os materiais de ensino, 
as sugestões da avaliação e as referências e os recursos tratando 
deste exercício. Descreve também o contexto em que a excursão
virtual é usada melhor.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa pagina del punto di partenza descrive un 
giro virtuale del parco nazionale di Yellowstone nel Wyoming descritto
sul Web site pubblico di servizio di broadcasting (PBS). In 
questo giro, gli allievi fungono da rangers del parco per ricercare le
caratteristiche geologiche di Yellowstone, per individuare queste 
caratteristiche sui programmi e per descrivere e definire i concetti 
geologici collegati. Le caratteristiche discusse includono i 
geyser, le molle calde, i canyon, le cascate ed i mudpots. A 
questa pagina, gli utenti possono trovare gli obiettivi imparanti, 
note e punte d'istruzione, materiali didattici, suggerimenti di 
valutazione e riferimenti e risorse occupantesi di questa 
esercitazione. Egualmente descrive il contesto in cui il giro 
virtuale è usato il più bene.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η σελίδα αφετηρίας περιγράφει έναν εικονικό 
γύρο του εθνικού πάρκου Yellowstone στο Wyoming που 
χαρακτηρίζεται στο δημόσιο ιστοχώρο υπηρεσιών ραδιοφωνικων 
αναμεταδόσεων (PBS). Σε αυτόν τον γύρο, οι σπουδαστές 
ενεργούν ως rangers πάρκων για να ερευνήσουν τα γεωλογικά 
χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα Yellowstone, να εντοπίσουν αυτά τα 
χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα στους χάρτες, και να περιγράψουν και να 
καθορίσουν τους σχετικούς γεωλογικούς όρους. Τα 
χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα που συζητούνται περιλαμβάνουν 
geysers, καυτά ελατήρια, φαράγγια, καταρράκτες και mudpots. 
Σε αυτήν την σελίδα, οι χρήστες μπορούν να βρούν τους 
στόχους εκμάθησης, τις σημειώσεις και τις άκρες διδασκαλίας, τα 
εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, τους υπαινιγμούς αξιολόγησης και τις αναφορές
και τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς εξετάζοντας αυτήν την άσκηση. 
Περιγράφει επίσης το πλαίσιο στο οποίο ο εικονικός γύρος 
χρησιμοποιείται καλύτερα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta paginación del punto de partida describe un 
viaje virtual del parque nacional de Yellowstone en Wyoming ofrecido 
en el Web site público del servicio de difusión (PBS). En este
viaje, los estudiantes actúan como guardabosques del parque para 
investigar características geológicas de Yellowstone, para localizar
estas características en correspondencias, y para describir y para 
definir términos geológicos asociados. Las características 
discutidas incluyen los géiseres, los resortes calientes, las 
barrancas, las cascadas y los mudpots. En esta paginación, los 
utilizadores pueden encontrar las metas que aprenden, las notas y las 
extremidades de enseñanza, los materiales didácticos, las indirectas
del gravamen y las referencias y los recursos ocupándose de este 
ejercicio. También describe el contexto en el cual el viaje 
virtual se utiliza lo más mejor posible.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PUBLIC BROADCASTING SERVICE
FN:PUBLIC BROADCASTING SERVICE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212632</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108475</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-living-edens-virtual-yellowstone-tour</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
