<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103574</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103574</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205677</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Broadway: The American Artsal</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Broadway: Das Amerikanische Artsal</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Broadway : l'Artsal Américain</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Broadway: O Artsal Americano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Broadway: Il Artsal Americano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Broadway: Το αμερικανικό Artsal</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Broadway: El Artsal Americano</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is the companion website for a film chronicling the evolution of the Broadway musical (1904-2004). Discover the historical, musical, and cultural influences of the Broadway musical. Learn about 100 performers, choreographers, writers, and designers. Explore 15 of the most influential and popular musicals, including Show Boat, Porgy and Bess, and The Producers. Lesson plans invite students to compare literary works and the musicals they inspired, and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist die Begleiterweb site für einen Film, der die
Entwicklung des Broadway Musikals (1904-2004) aufzeichnet. 
Entdecken Sie die historischen, musikalischen und kulturellen 
Einflüsse des Broadway Musikals. Erlernen Sie ungefähr 100 
Ausführende, Choreographen, Verfasser und Entwerfer. Erforschen
Sie 15 der einflußreichsten und populärsten Musikale, 
einschließlich Erscheinen-Boot, Porgy und Bess und die Produzenten. 
Lektionpläne laden Kursteilnehmer ein, um literarische Arbeiten
und die Musikale zu vergleichen, die sie anspornten und mehr.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est le site Web de compagnon pour un film faisant 
la chronique de l'évolution du musical de Broadway (1904-2004). 
Découvrez les influences historiques, musicales, et culturelles
du musical de Broadway. Apprenez environ 100 interprètes, 
chorégraphes, auteurs, et créateurs. Explorez 15 des musicaux 
les plus influents et les plus populaires, y compris le bateau 
d'exposition, le Porgy et le Bess, et les producteurs. Les
plans de leçon invitent des étudiants pour comparer les travaux 
littéraires et les musicaux qu'ils ont inspirés, et plus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é o Web site do companheiro para uma película 
que chronicling a evolução do musical de Broadway (1904-2004). 
Descubra as influências históricas, musicais, e cultural do 
musical de Broadway. Aprenda aproximadamente 100 performers, 
choreographers, escritores, e desenhadores. Explore 15 dos 
musicals os mais influential e os mais populares, including o barco da
mostra, o porgy e o Bess, e os produtores. As plantas da lição
convidam estudantes para comparar trabalhos literários e os musicals 
que inspiraram, e mais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è il Web site del compagno per una pellicola che 
chronicling lo sviluppo del musical di Broadway (1904-2004). 
Scopra le influenze storiche, musicali e culturali del musical 
di Broadway. Impari circa 100 esecutori, choreographers, 
produttori e progettisti. Esplori 15 dei musicals più influenti
e più popolari, compresi la barca di esposizione, porgy e Bess ed i 
produttori. I programmi di lezione invitano gli allievi per 
confrontare gli impianti letterari ed i musicals che hanno ispirato e 
più.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι ο ιστοχώρος συντρόφων για μια ταινία 
εξιστορώντας κατά γράμμα την εξέλιξη του Broadway μουσικού 
(1904-2004). Ανακαλύψτε τις ιστορικές, μουσικές, και 
πολιτιστικές επιρροές του Broadway μουσικού. Μάθετε τους 
περίπου 100 εκτελεστές, τα χορογράφος, συγγραφείς, και 
σχεδιαστές. Εξερευνήστε 15 των επιδρύτερων και δημοφιλών 
musicals, η συμπερίληψη εμφανίζει τη βάρκα, το φάγρο και 
Bess, και τους παραγωγούς. Τα σχέδια μαθήματος προσκαλούν
τους σπουδαστές για να συγκρίνουν τα λογοτεχνικά έργα και τα 
musicals που ενέπνευσαν, και περισσότεροι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es el Web site del compañero para una película 
chronicling la evolución del musical de Broadway (1904-2004). 
Descubra las influencias históricas, musicales, y culturales 
del musical de Broadway. Aprenda a cerca de 100 ejecutantes, 
coreógrafos, programas de escritura, y diseñadores. Explore 15 
de los musicals más influyentes y más populares, incluyendo el barco
de la demostración, porgy y Bess, y los productores. Los planes
de la lección invitan a estudiantes que comparen trabajos literarios 
y los musicals que inspiraron, y más.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205677</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103574</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/broadway-the-american-artsal</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
