<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105353</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105353</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087083</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The World Was at Stake": Three "Friendly" HUAC Hollywood Witnesses Assess Pro-Soviet Wartime Films</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die Welt stand" auf dem Spiel: Drei 
"Freundliche" HUAC Hollywood Zeugen Setzen Pro-Sowjet Krieg-Filme 
Fest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"le monde était en jeu" : Trois "" Les 
Témoins Amicaux de HUAC Hollywood Évaluent des Films de Temps de 
guerre de Pro-Soviétique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"o mundo estava na estaca": Três "" 
Testemunhas Amigáveis de HUAC Hollywood Avaliam Películas Do Wartime
Do Pro-Soviete</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"il mondo era in gioco": Tre "" Testimoni 
Amichevoli di HUAC Hollywood Valutano Le Pellicole Di Wartime Del 
Pro-Soviet</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ο κόσμος ήταν σε κίνδυνο": Τρεις "φιλικοί" 
μάρτυρες HUAC Hollywood αξιολογούν τις υπέρ-σοβιετικές εν 
καιρώ πολέμου ταινίες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"el mundo era en juego": Tres "" Los 
Testigos Cómodos de HUAC Hollywood Evalúan Las Películas Del Tiempo
de guerra Del Favorable-Soviet</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The House Committee on Un-American Activities (HUAC) held hearings in 1947 on Communist activity in Hollywood. Under J. Parnell Thomas, who became chairman after the Republican Party gained control of Congress in 1947, HUAC not only sought to identify so-called "subversives" in the industry, but also to investigate whether the Roosevelt administration had encouraged the production of pro-Soviet films during World War II. In the following testimony, three "friendly" witnesses--studio heads Jack L. Warner of Warner Bros. and Louis B. Mayer of M-G-M, and Russian-born novelist, screenwriter, and ideologue Ayn Rand--commented on specific wartime films.  Mission to Moscow  (1943), based on a memoir by Joseph E. Davies, U.S. Ambassador to the Soviet Union from 1936-1938, had been widely criticized for glorifying Stalin and for offering rationalizations for the Moscow purge trials and the non-aggression pact with Hitler.  Song of Russia  (1944), with a screenplay by "unfriendly" witnesses Paul Jarrico and Richard Collins, had undergone significant revisions due to complaints that it was too pro-Stalinist. Following the 1947 hearings, ten screenwriters and directors, who refused to cooperate with the Committee, were cited for contempt of Congress. After studio heads blacklisted the ten--who later served prison terms following the Supreme Court's refusal to hear their appeal--HUAC agreed to stop investigating studios and the content of films, and limited their inquiries to personnel. The subject matter of films, however, continued to be affected by the chilled Cold War climate to which HUAC contributed.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Haus-Ausschuß für Un-Amerikanische 
Aktivitäten (HUAC) hielt Hörfähigkeiten 1947 auf kommunistischer 
Aktivität in Hollywood an. Unter J. Parnell Thomas, das 
Vorsitzender wurde, nachdem die Republikanische Partei Steuerung des 
Kongresses 1947 gewann, suchte HUAC nicht nur, sogenannte 
"subversives" in der Industrie zu kennzeichnen, aber auch 
nachzuforschen, ob die Roosevelt Leitung die Produktion der Pro-Sowjet
Filme während des Zweiten Weltkrieges angeregt hatte. Im 
folgenden Zeugnis drei "freundliche" Zeugen -- Studioköpfe Jack L. 
Warner von Warner Bros. und Louis B. Mayer von M-G-M und 
Russisch-getragener Novelist, Drehbuchautor und Ideologe Ayn Rand -- 
kommentiert spezifische Kriegfilme. Mission nach Moskau (1943), 
basiert auf einer Abhandlung von Joseph E. Davies, VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Botschafter zum Sowjet-Anschluß von 1936-1938, war weit für das 
Glorifizieren von von Stalin und für anbietenrationalisierungen für 
die Moskau Löschenversuche und den Nichtangriff Pakt mit Hitler 
kritisiert worden. Lied von Rußland (1944), mit einem Drehbuch 
durch "unfreundliche" Zeugen Paul Jarrico und Richard Collins, hatte 
die bedeutenden Änderungen wegen der Beanstandungen durchgemacht, 
daß es zu Pro-Stalinist war. Nach den 1947 Hörfähigkeiten 
wurden 10 Drehbuchautoren und Direktoren, die ablehnten, mit dem 
Ausschuß zusammenzuarbeiten, für Verachtung des Kongresses zitiert. 
Nach Studio setzten Köpfe die 10 -- wer später die 
Gefängnisbezeichnungen dienten, die der Ablehnung des Höchsten 
Gerichts folgen, um ihren Anklang zu hören -- HUAC damit 
einverstandenSIND Studios, und den Inhalt der Filme nachzuforschen zu 
stoppen auf die schwarze Liste, und begrenzt ihren Anfragen auf 
Personal. Das Thema der Filme fuhr jedoch fort, durch das 
gekühlte Klima des kalten Krieges beeinflußt zu werden, zu dem HUAC 
beitrug.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le comité de Chambre des activités 
Un-Américaines (HUAC) a tenu des auditions en 1947 sur l'activité 
communiste dans Hollywood. Sous J. Parnell Thomas, qui est 
devenu Président après que la partie républicaine ait gagné la 
commande du congrès en 1947, HUAC a non seulement recherché à 
identifier de prétendus "subversives" dans l'industrie, mais à les 
étudier également si la gestion de Roosevelt avait encouragé la 
production des films de pro-Soviétique pendant la deuxième guerre 
mondiale. Dans le témoignage suivant, trois "" témoins amicaux
-- chefs Jack L. Warner de Warner Bros. et Louis B. Mayer de studio de
M-G-M, et romancier, scénariste, et couche-point Russe-soutenus d'Ayn
d'idéologue -- commentés les films spécifiques de temps de guerre. 
La mission vers Moscou (1943), basée sur un mémoire par Joseph
E. Davies, ambassadeur des ETATS-UNIS à Union Soviétique de 1936-1938, 
avait été largement critiquée pour améliorer Stalin et pour des 
rationalisations d'offre pour les épreuves de purge de Moscou et le 
pacte de non-aggression avec Hitler. La chanson de la Russie (1944), 
avec un scénario par les témoins "peu amicaux" Paul Jarrico et 
Richard Collins, avait subi des révisions significatives dues aux 
plaintes que c'était trop pro-Staliniste. Après les 1947 
auditions, dix scénaristes et directeurs, qui ont refusé de 
coopérer avec le Comité, ont été cités pour le mépris du 
congrès. Après studio les têtes ont mis les dix -- qui plus 
tard ont servi des limites de prison suivant le refus de cour suprême
pour entendre leur appel -- HUAC acceptent de cesser d'étudier les 
studios et la teneur des films, et limité leurs enquêtes au 
personnel. Les thèmes des films, cependant, ont continué à 
être affectés par le climat effrayant de guerre froide auquel HUAC a
contribué.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O comitê da casa nas atividades Un-Americanas 
(HUAC) prendeu hearings em 1947 na atividade comunista em Hollywood. 
Sob J. Parnell Thomas, que se transformou presidente depois que 
o partido republicano ganhou o controle do congress em 1947, HUAC 
procurado não somente identificar "subversives so-called" na 
indústria, mas investigá-los também se a administração de 
Roosevelt tinha incentivado a produção de películas do pro-Soviete 
durante a segunda guerra mundial. No seguinte testimony, três 
"" testemunhas amigáveis -- cabeças Jack L. Warner de Warner Bros. e
Louis B. Mayer do estúdio de M-G-M, e novelist, screenwriter, e 
margem Russian-carregados de Ayn do ideologue -- comentadas em 
películas específicas do wartime. A missão a Moscow (1943), 
baseado em um memoir por Joseph E. Davies, embaixador de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS à Soviete-união de 1936-1938, tinha sido criticada 
extensamente glorificando Stalin e para rationalizations oferecendo 
para as experimentações da remoção de Moscow e o pact do 
non-non-aggression com Hitler. A canção de Rússia (1944), com
um screenplay por testemunhas "hostis" Paul Jarrico e Richard Collins,
tinha-se submetido às revisões significativas  devido às queixas 
que era demasiado pro-Stalinist-Stalinist. Depois dos 1947 
hearings, dez screenwriters e diretores, que recusaram cooperar com o 
comitê, cited para o contempt de congress. Após o estúdio as 
cabeças puseram os dez -- quem serviram mais tarde aos termos da 
prisão que seguem a recusa de corte suprema para ouvir sua apelação
-- HUAC concordam parar de investigar estúdios e o índice das 
películas, e limitado seus inquéritos ao pessoal. A matéria 
sujeita das películas, entretanto, continuou a ser afetada pelo clima
chilled da guerra fria a que HUAC contribuiu.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il comitato della Camera delle attività 
ONU-Americane (HUAC) ha tenuto le udienze in 1947 su attività 
comunista in Hollywood. Sotto J. Parnell Thomas, che è 
diventato presidente dopo che il partito Repubblicano guadagni il 
controllo del congresso in 1947, HUAC cercato non soltanto per 
identificare i cosiddetti "subversives" nell'industria, ma anche per 
studiare se la gestione di Roosevelt aveva consigliato alla produzione
delle pellicole del pro-Soviet durante la seconda guerra mondiale. 
Nella seguente testimonianza, tre "" testimoni amichevoli -- 
teste Jack L. Warner di Warner Bros. e Louis B. Mayer dell'studio di 
M-G-M e romanziere, screenwriter e bordo Russo-sopportati di Ayn del 
ideologue -- commentati le pellicole specifiche di wartime. La 
missione a Mosca (1943), basata su una memoria da Joseph E. Davies, 
ambasciatore degli STATI UNITI all'Soviet-unione da 1936-1938, 
ampiamente era stata criticata per glorificare Stalin e per le 
razionalizzazioni d'offerta per le prove dell'eliminazione dei fogli 
inceppati de Mosca ed il patto di non-aggressione con Hitler. La
canzone della Russia (1944), con uno screenplay dai testimoni 
"unfriendly" Paul Jarrico e Richard Collins, aveva subito le revisioni
significative dovuto i reclami che era troppo pro-Stalinist. A 
seguito delle 1947 udienze, dieci screenwriters e direttori, che hanno
rifiutato di cooperare con il comitato, si sono citati per contempt 
del congresso. Dopo l'studio le teste hanno messo nei dieci -- 
chi più successivamente hanno servito i termini della prigione che 
seguono il rifiuto della Corte suprema per sentire il loro appello -- 
HUAC accosentito per smettere di studiare gli studi ed il 
contenuto delle pellicole e limitato le loro inchieste ai personali. 
Il tema delle pellicole, tuttavia, ha continuato ad essere 
influenzato dal clima raffreddato di guerra fredda a cui HUAC ha 
contribuito.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η Επιτροπή Βουλών των αντιαμερικανικών δραστηριοτήτων 
(HUAC) πραγματοποίησε τις ακροάσεις το 1947 για την 
κομμουνιστική δραστηριότητα σε Hollywood. Κάτω από Θ*ι. 
Parnell Thomas, που έγινε ο πρόεδρος μετά από το 
δημοκρατικό κόμμα κέρδισε τον έλεγχο του συνεδρίου το 1947, 
HUAC όχι μόνο που επιδιώχθηκαν για να προσδιορίσει τα 
αποκαλούμενα "subversives" στη βιομηχανία, αλλά και για να 
ερευνήσει εάν η κυβέρνηση Roosevelt είχε ενθαρρύνει την 
παραγωγή των υπέρ-σοβιετικών ταινιών κατά τη διάρκεια του 
παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ. Στην ακόλουθη κατάθεση, τρεις 
"φιλικοί" μάρτυρες -- κεφάλια Jack L. Warner Warner 
Bros. και Louis B. Mayer στούντιο του μ-γ-μ, και 
ρωσικός-γεννημένος μυθιστοριογράφος, screenwriter, και 
ideologue άκρη Ayn -- σχολίασαν τις συγκεκριμένες εν καιρώ 
πολέμου ταινίες. Η αποστολή στη Μόσχα (1943), βασισμένος
σε απομνημονεύματα από Joseph E. Davies, ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΣ 
πρεσβευτής στη Σοβιετική Ένωση από το 1936-1938, ήταν 
επικριμένη ευρέως για να δοξάσει το Στάλιν και για την προσφορά 
των αιτιολογήσεων για τις δοκιμές εκκαθαρίσεων της Μόσχας και του 
σύμφωνου μη βίας με hitler. Το τραγούδι της Ρωσίας 
(1944), με έναν screenplay από τους "μη φιλικούσ" μάρτυρες 
Paul Jarrico και Richard Collins, είχε υποβληθεί στις 
σημαντικές αναθεωρήσεις λόγω στις καταγγελίες ότι ήταν επίσης 
υπέρ-σταλινιστής. Μετά από τις ακροάσεις του 1947, 
δέκα screenwriters και σκηνοθέτες, που αρνήθηκαν να 
συνεργαστούν με την Επιτροπή, αναφέρθηκαν για την περιφρόνηση του 
συνεδρίου. Μετά από το στούντιο τα κεφάλια έβαλαν στη 
μαύρη λίστα τα δέκα -- ποιοι πιό πρόσφατες εξυπηρετούμενες 
θητείες φυλακών μετά από την άρνηση του ανώτατου δικαστηρίου να
ακούσει την έκκλησή τους -- HUAC συμφώνησε να σταματήσει τα 
στούντιο και το περιεχόμενο των ταινιών, και περιόρισε τις 
έρευνές τους στο προσωπικό. Το περιεχόμενο των ταινιών, 
εντούτοις, συνέχισε να επηρεάζεται από το κατεψυγμένο κλίμα 
ψυχρού πολέμου στο οποίο HUAC συνέβαλε.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El comité de la casa sobre las actividades 
Un-Americanas (HUAC) llevó a cabo audiencias en 1947 en actividad 
comunista en Hollywood. Bajo J. Parnell Thomas, que hizo 
presidente después de que el partido republicano ganara el control 
del congreso en 1947, HUAC intentado no sólo para identificar 
"subversives supuestos" en la industria, sino también para 
investigarlos si la administración de Roosevelt había animado la 
producción de las películas del favorable-Soviet durante la Segunda 
Guerra Mundial. En el testimonio siguiente, tres "" testigos 
cómodos -- estudio dirigieron a Gato L. Warner de Warner Bros. y 
Louis B. Mayer de M-G-M, y novelista, guionista, y Rand 
Ruso-llevados de Ayn del ideologue -- commented en las películas 
específicas del tiempo de guerra. La misión en Moscú (1943), 
basada en una memoria por José E. Davies, embajador de ESTADOS UNIDOS
a la Soviet-unio'n a partir de 1936-1938, había sido criticada 
extensamente para glorificar Stalin y para las racionalizaciones de 
ofrecimiento para los ensayos de la purgación de Moscú y el pacto de
la no-agresio'n con Hitler. La canción de Rusia (1944), con un 
guión de los testigos "antipáticos" Paul Jarrico y Richard Collins, 
había experimentado las revisiones significativas  debido a las 
quejas que era demasiado favorable-Stalinist. Después de las 
1947 audiencias, citaron a diez guionistas y directores, que 
rechazaron cooperar con el comité, para el desprecio del congreso. 
Después de estudio las pistas pusieron los diez -- quiénes 
sirvieron más adelante los términos de la prisión que seguían la 
denegación del Tribunal Supremo para oír su súplica -- HUAC 
acordaron parar el investigar de los estudios y del contenido de 
películas, y limitado sus preguntas al personal. El tema de 
películas, sin embargo, continuó siendo afectado por el clima 
enfriado de la guerra fría a el cual HUAC contribuyó.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087083</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105353</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-world-was-at-stake-three-friendly-huac-hollywood-witnesses-assess-pro-soviet-wartime-films</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
