<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104002</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104002</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209789</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Alternate Exterior Angles </string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wechselnde Außenwinkel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Angles Extérieurs Alternatifs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ângulos Exteriores Alternos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Angoli Esterni Alternati</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εναλλάσσομαι εξωτερικές γωνίες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ángulos Exteriores Alternos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate the alternate exterior angles that are formed where a transversal crosses two lines. The applets shows the two possible pairs of angles alternating when in animation mode. By dragging the three lines, it can be seen that the angles are congruent only when the lines are parallel. When not in animated mode, there is a button that alternates the two pairs of angles. The text on the page discusses the properties of the angle pairs both in the parallel and non-parallel cases. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die die wechselnden Außenwinkel zeigen, die wo transversale
Kreuze zwei Zeilen gebildet werden. Die applet zeigt die zwei 
möglichen Paare der wechselnden Winkel wenn im Animationmodus. 
Indem man die drei Zeilen schleppt, kann es gesehen werden, daß
die Winkel übereinstimmend sind, nur wenn die Zeilen parallel sind. 
Wenn nicht in lebhaftem Modus, gibt es eine Taste, die die zwei 
Paare von Winkeln wechselt. Der Text auf der Seite behandelt die
Eigenschaften der Winkelpaare in den parallelen und nicht parallelen 
Fällen. Applet kann zum vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit 
einem Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. Nachgebrauch 
im Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von jedem möglichem web 
browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den benötigten LOGON 
wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Bestandteil des 
Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent les angles extérieurs alternatifs qui sont formés 
où les croix transversales deux lignes. Les applet montre les 
deux paires possibles d'angles alternant quand en mode d'animation. 
En traînant les trois lignes, il peut voir que les angles sont 
conformes seulement quand les lignes sont parallèles. Quand pas
en mode animé, il y a un bouton qui alterne les deux paires d'angles.
Le texte à la page discute les propriétés des paires d'angle 
dans les cas parallèles et non-parallèles. L'applet peut être
agrandi à la taille de plein écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur 
de salle de classe. Le après utilisation dans la salle de 
classe, étudiant peut lui accéder encore de n'importe quel 
navigateur de Web à la maison ou dans la bibliothèque sans la 
procédure de connexion exigée. Cette ressource est un 
composant du projet interactif de manuel de la géométrie de 
référence ouverte de maths à http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem os ângulos exteriores alternos que são dados forma onde 
cruzes transversal duas linhas. Os applet mostrarem os dois 
pares possíveis dos ângulos que alternam quando na modalidade do 
animation. Arrastando as três linhas, pode-se ver que os 
ângulos são congruent somente quando as linhas estão paralelas. 
Quando não na modalidade animated, há uma tecla que alterne os
dois pares dos ângulos. O texto na página discute as 
propriedades dos pares do ângulo  nos casos paralelos e non-parallel.
O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de tela cheia para o uso 
com um projetor da sala de aula. O depois de uso na sala de 
aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo o web browser na 
HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma sessão requerido. 
Este recurso é um componente do projeto interativo do textbook 
da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano gli angoli esterni alternati che sono formati dove traverse
trasversali due righe. I applet mostra i due accoppiamenti 
possibili degli angoli che si alternano quando nel modo di animazione.
Trascinando le tre righe, può essere visto che gli angoli sono 
conformi soltanto quando le righe sono parallele. Quando non nel
modo animato, ci è un tasto che alterna i due accoppiamenti degli 
angoli. Il testo alla pagina discute le proprietà degli 
accoppiamenti di angolo sia nei casi paralleli che non paralleli. 
Il applet può essere ingrandito al formato di schermo pieno per
uso con un proiettore dell'aula. La post-utilizzazione 
nell'aula, allievo può accederle ancora da tutto il web browser nel 
paese o nella libreria senza l'inizio attività richiesto. 
Questa risorsa è un componente del progetto interattivo del 
manuale della geometria di riferimento aperto di per la matematica a 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν τις εναλλάσσομαι εξωτερικές γωνίες που 
διαμορφώνονται όπου τους εγκάρσιους σταυρούς δύο γραμμές. 
Τα applets εμφανίζουν δύο πιθανά ζευγάρια των γωνιών που
εναλλάσσονται όταν είναι στον τρόπο ζωτικότητας. Με το 
σύρσιμο των τριών γραμμών, μπορεί να δει ότι οι 
γωνίες είναι σύμφωνες μόνο όταν οι γραμμές είναι παράλληλες. 
Όταν όχι στο ζωντανεψοντα τρόπο, υπάρχει ένα κουμπί που 
εναλλάσσει τα δύο ζευγάρια των γωνιών. Το κείμενο στη 
σελίδα συζητά τις ιδιότητες των ζευγαριών γωνίας και στις 
παράλληλες και μη παράλληλες περιπτώσεις. Το Applet 
μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με 
έναν προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο 
σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε 
ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια 
εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς 
είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος εγχειριδίων 
γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran los ángulos exteriores alternos se forman que donde las 
cruces transversales dos líneas. Los applet muestran los dos 
pares posibles de ángulos que se alternan cuando en modo de la 
animación. Arrastrando las tres líneas, puede ser visto que 
los ángulos son congruentes solamente cuando las líneas son 
paralelas. Cuando no en modo animado, hay un botón que alterna 
los dos pares de ángulos. El texto en la paginación discute 
las características de los pares del ángulo en los casos paralelos y
no paralelos. El applet se puede agrandar a la talla de la 
pantalla completa para el uso con un proyector de la sala de clase. 
El uso posterior en la sala de clase, estudiante puede tenerle 
acceso otra vez de cualquier web browser en el país o en la 
biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. Este recurso es un 
componente del proyecto interactivo del libro de textos de la 
geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas en 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209789</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104002</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/alternate-exterior-angles</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
