<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106298</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106298</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087458</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Cain and Abel Revisited: A Case for Keeping thy Brother</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kain und Abel nochmals besucht: Ein Argument
für das Halten des thy Bruders</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Caïn et Abel revisités : Un point de droit
pour garder le frère thy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Cain e Abel revisitados: Um argumento para 
manter o irmão thy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Cain ed Abel rivisitati: Un argomento per 
mantenere fratello thy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Cain και Abel Revisited: Μια περίπτωση 
για τον αδελφό δικος σου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cain y Abel nuevos: Un caso para guardar a 
hermano thy</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In order to challenge the emphasis on extreme economic individualism espoused by Gilded Age industrialists and laissez-faire theorists, labor writers drew on diverse historical and religious traditions. Jose Gros, writing in  The   Carpenter  in 1895, turned to religious traditions, specifically the biblical parable of Cain and Abel. Gros used the parable's central question--"Am I my brother's keeper?"--to criticize economic individualism and make the case for cooperation and brotherhood.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Um das Hauptgewicht auf dem extremen 
Wirtschaftsindividualismus herauszufordern, der von vergoldeten Alter 
Industriellen und von Laissez-Faire Theoretikern unterstützt wurde, 
zeichneten Arbeitsverfasser auf verschiedene historische und fromme 
Traditionen. Jose Gros, schreibend in den Tischler 1895, wendete
an fromme Traditionen, spezifisch die biblische Parabel von Kain und 
Abel. Gros verwendete die zentrale Frage der Parabel -- "bin ich
keeper? meines Bruders" -- um Wirtschaftsindividualismus zu 
kritisieren und den Fall für Mitarbeit und Bruderschaft zu bilden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Afin de défier l'emphase sur l'individualisme 
économique extrême embrassé par les industriels d'âge et les 
théoriciens dorés de laissez-faire, les auteurs de travail ont 
dessiné sur des traditions historiques et religieuses diverses. 
Jose Gros, écrivant dans le charpentier en 1895, s'est 
tourné vers les traditions religieuses, spécifiquement la parabole 
biblique de Caïn et Abel. Gros a employé la question centrale 
de la parabole -- "suis je le keeper? de mon frère" -- pour critiquer
l'individualisme économique et pour faire le cas pour la coopération
et la confrérie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A fim desafiar a ênfase no individualism 
econômico extremo espoused por industrialistas da idade e por 
theorists gilded do laissez-faire, os escritores labor desenharam em 
tradições históricas e religiosas diversas. Jose Gros, 
escrevendo no carpinteiro em 1895, girou para tradições religiosas, 
especificamente o parable biblical de Cain e Abel. Gros usou a 
pergunta central do parable -- "sou eu keeper? do meu irmão" -- 
criticar o individualism econômico e fazer o caso para a cooperação
e o brotherhood.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Per sfidare l'enfasi su individualism economico 
estremo espoused dagli industriali di età e dai teorici gilded di 
"laissez faire", i produttori di lavoro hanno dissipato sulle 
tradizioni storiche e religiose varie. Jose Gros, scrivente nel 
carpentiere in 1895, si è girato verso le tradizioni religiose, 
specificamente il parable biblico di Cain ed Abel. Gros ha usato
la domanda centrale del parable -- "sono keeper? del mio fratello" -- 
per criticare il individualism economico e per dimostrare il 
fondatezza della cooperazione e della fratellanza.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Προκειμένου να προκληθεί η έμφαση στον ακραίο 
οικονομικό ατομικισμό που παντρεύτηκε από τους επιχρυσωμένους 
βιομηχάνους ηλικίας και τους θεωρητικούς ελεύθερης οικονομίας, οι
συγγραφείς εργασίας επέσυραν την προσοχή στις διαφορετικές 
ιστορικές και θρησκευτικές παραδόσεις. Ο Jose Gros, που
γράφει στον ξυλουργό το 1895, γύρισε στις θρησκευτικές 
παραδόσεις, συγκεκριμένα η βιβλική παραβολή Cain και Abel. 
Το Gros χρησιμοποίησε την κεντρική ερώτηση της παραβολής 
-- "είναι το ι του αδελφού μου keeper?" -- για να επικρίνει τον 
οικονομικό ατομικισμό και να δώσει τα επιχειρήματα για τη 
συνεργασία και την αδελφοσύνη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Para desafiar el énfasis en el individualismo 
económico extremo espoused por los industriales de la edad y los 
teóricos dorados del liberalismo, los programas de escritura de 
trabajo trazaron en tradiciones históricas y religiosas diversas. 
Jose Gros, escribiendo en el carpintero en 1895, dio vuelta a 
las tradiciones religiosas, específicamente a la parábola bíblica 
de Cain y a Abel. Gros utilizó la pregunta central de la 
parábola -- "soy el keeper? de mi hermano" -- para criticar 
individualismo económico y para hacer el caso para la cooperación y 
la fraternidad.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087458</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106298</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/cain-and-abel-revisited-a-case-for-keeping-thy-brother</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
