<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103069</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103069</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086862</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Such Was the Tumultation These Women Made": The Women of Marblehead Wreak Revenge Upon Indian Captors, 1677</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"so war das Tumultation diese gebildeten Frauen": 
Die Frauen von Marblehead Wreak Rache nach indischen Fängern, 
1677</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"tel était le Tumultation ces femmes faites" : 
Les femmes de Marblehead Assouvissent la vengeance sur les 
ravisseurs indiens, 1677</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"tal era o Tumultation estas mulheres feitas": 
As mulheres da vingança em cima dos captores indian, 1677 de 
Marblehead Wreak</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"tale era il Tumultation queste donne fatte": 
Le donne di vendetta sui rapitori indiani, 1677 di Marblehead 
Wreak</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Τέτοιο ήταν το Tumultation αυτές οι γυναίκες που 
έγιναν": Οι γυναίκες Marblehead έλαβαν την εκδίκηση 
επάνω στους ινδικούς αιχμαλωτίζοντες, 1677</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"tal era el Tumultation estas mujeres hechas": 
Las mujeres de la venganza sobre captores indios, 1677 de 
Marblehead Wreak</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Wampanoag Indians of New England began Metacom's War (also known as King Philip's War) in 1675 in an attempt to expel the English from the region. Metacom, leader of the Wampanoag, fashioned an alliance of many different groups, but Christian Indians and Iroquois who allied with the English proved to be a significant factor in the eventual colonial victory. In August 1676 colonial troops captured and killed Metacom, ending hostilities in southern New England. However, other Indians continued their attacks for another two years along the northern New England coast. In particular, they targeted fishing ketches operated out of Marblehead, Massachusetts. Mariner Robert Roules narrated one such incident in July 1677 when his boat was captured by Indians, then recaptured by the settlers. When the settlers sailed Roules' boat into Marblehead harbor, the women of Marblehead took bloody revenge upon the Indian captives.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Wampanoag Inder von Neu-England fingen Krieg 
Metacoms (alias König Philips War) 1675 an, um Englisch von der 
Region wegzutreiben. Metacom, Führer des Wampanoag, arbeitete 
ein Bündnis vieler unterschiedlicher Gruppen um, aber christliche 
Inder und Irokese, die mit Englisch verbanden, waren ein bedeutender 
Faktor im etwaigen Kolonialsieg. Im August 1676 erfaßten 
Kolonialtruppen und beendeten Metacom und beendeten Feindseligkeiten 
in Südneu-England. Jedoch setzten andere Inder ihre Angriffe 
für andere zwei Jahre entlang der Nordneu-England Küste fort. 
Insbesondere zielten sie die Fischen ketches, die aus Marblehead
heraus, Massachusetts bearbeitet wurden. Seemann Robert Roules 
berichtete ein solches Ereignis im Juli 1677, als sein Boot von 
Indians erfaßt wurde, dann wieder erlangt von den Siedleren. 
Als die Siedleren Boot Roules' in Marblehead Hafen segelten, 
nahmen die Frauen von Marblehead blutige Rache nach den indischen 
Gefangenen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Indiens de Wampanoag de la Nouvelle Angleterre
ont commencé la guerre de Metacom (également connue sous le nom de 
guerre de roi Philip) en 1675 afin d'essayer d'expulser l'anglais
de la région. Metacom, amorce du Wampanoag, mode une alliance 
de beaucoup de différents groupes, mais les Indiens et le Iroquois 
chrétiens qui se sont alliés avec l'anglais se sont avérés être 
un facteur significatif dans la victoire coloniale certaine. En 
août 1676 les troupes coloniales ont capturé et ont détruit 
Metacom, terminant des hostilités en Nouvelle Angleterre 
méridionale. Cependant, d'autres Indiens ont continué leurs 
attaques pendant encore deux années le long de la côte nordique de 
la Nouvelle Angleterre. En particulier, ils ont visé des 
ketches de pêche actionnés hors de Marblehead, le Massachusetts. 
Le marin Robert Roules a relaté un tel incident en juillet 1677
quand son bateau a été capturé par Indians, alors repris par les 
colons. Quand les colons ont navigué le bateau de Roules dans 
le port de Marblehead, les femmes de Marblehead ont pris la vengeance 
sanglante sur les captifs indiens.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os indians de Wampanoag de Nova Inglaterra 
começaram a guerra de Metacom (sabida também como Guerra do rei 
Philip) em 1675 em uma tentativa de expelir o inglês da região. 
Metacom, líder do Wampanoag, formou um alliance de muitos 
grupos diferentes, mas os indians e o iroquois christian que se 
aliaram com o inglês provaram ser um fator significativo na vitória 
colonial eventual. Em agosto 1676 as tropas coloniais capturaram
e mataram Metacom, terminando hostilidades em Nova Inglaterra do sul. 
Entretanto, outros indians continuaram seus ataques por outros 
dois anos ao longo da costa do norte de Nova Inglaterra. No 
detalhe, alvejaram os ketches operados fora de Marblehead, 
Massachusetts da pesca. O navegador Robert Roules narrou um tal 
incident em julho 1677 quando seu barco foi capturado por Indians, 
recapturado então pelos settlers. Quando os settlers sailed o 
barco de Roules' no porto de Marblehead, as mulheres de Marblehead 
fizeram exame da vingança sangrenta em cima dos cativos indian.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli indiani di Wampanoag della Nuova Inghilterra 
hanno cominciato la guerra del Metacom (anche conosciuta come War del 
re Philip) in 1675 nel tentativo d'espellere l'inglese dalla regione. 
Metacom, capo del Wampanoag, moda un'alleanza di molti 
gruppi differenti, ma gli indiani ed il iroquois cristiani che si sono
alleati con l'inglese sono risultato essere un fattore significativo 
nella vittoria coloniale finale. In agosto 1676 le truppe 
coloniali hanno bloccato ed ucciso Metacom, concludente le ostilità 
in Nuova Inghilterra del sud. Tuttavia, altri indiani hanno 
continuato i loro attacchi per altri due anni lungo il litorale 
nordico della Nuova Inghilterra. In particolare, hanno designato
i ketches come bersaglio funzionati da Marblehead, Massachusetts di 
pesca. Il mariner Robert Roules ha narrato un tale avvenimento 
nel mese di luglio del 1677 quando la sua barca è stata bloccata da 
Indians, allora ripreso dai settlers. Quando i settlers hanno 
navigato la barca del Roules nel porto di Marblehead, le donne di 
Marblehead hanno preso la vendetta sanguinante sui prigionieri 
indiani.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Wampanoag Ινδοί της Νέας Αγγλίας άρχισε τον 
πόλεμο Metacom (επίσης γνωστό ως πόλεμος του Philip 
βασιλιάδων) το 1675 σε μία προσπάθεια να αποβληθούν οι Αγγλοι 
από την περιοχή. Το Metacom, ηγέτης του Wampanoag, 
διαμόρφωσε μια συμμαχία πολλών διαφορετικών ομάδων, αλλά 
χριστιανικοί Ινδοί και iroquois που σύνδεσαν με τους Αγγλους 
αποδείχθηκαν ένας σημαντικός παράγοντας στην ενδεχόμενη 
αποικιακή νίκη. Τον Αύγουστο του 1676 τα αποικιακά 
στρατεύματα συνέλαβαν και σκότωσαν Metacom, τελειώνοντας τις 
εχθρότητες στη νότια Νέα Αγγλία. Εντούτοις, άλλοι Ινδοί 
συνέχισαν τις επιθέσεις τους για άλλα δύο έτη κατά μήκος της 
βόρειας ακτής της Νέας Αγγλίας. Ειδικότερα, στόχευσαν στην
αλιεία ketches που χρησιμοποιήθηκε από Marblehead, 
Μασαχουσέτη. Ο ναυτικός Robert Roules διηγήθηκε ένα 
τέτοιο γεγονός τον Ιούλιο του 1677 όταν συλλήφθηκε η βάρκα 
του από Ινδούς, κατόπιν συλλήφθηκε εκ νέου από τους αποίκους. 
Όταν οι άποικοι έπλευσαν τη βάρκα Roules στο λιμάνι 
Marblehead, οι γυναίκες Marblehead πήραν την αιματηρή 
εκδίκηση επάνω στους ινδικούς αιχμαλώτους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los indios de Wampanoag de Nueva Inglaterra 
comenzaron la guerra de Metacom (también conocida como War de rey 
Philip) en 1675 en una tentativa de expeler el inglés de la región. 
Metacom, arranque de cinta del Wampanoag, formó una alianza de 
muchos diversos grupos, pero los indios y el iroquois cristianos que 
se aliaron con el inglés demostraron ser un factor significativo en 
la victoria colonial eventual. En agosto 1676 las tropas 
coloniales capturaron y mataron a Metacom, terminando hostilidades en 
Nueva Inglaterra meridional. Sin embargo, otros indios 
continuaron sus ataques por otros dos años a lo largo de la costa 
norteña de Nueva Inglaterra. En detalle, apuntaron los ketches 
funcionados fuera de Marblehead, Massachusetts de la pesca. El 
mariner Roberto Roules narró un tal incidente en julio de 1677 cuando
su barco fue capturado por indians, entonces recobrado por los 
colonos. Cuando los colonos navegaron el barco de Roules en el 
puerto de Marblehead, las mujeres de Marblehead tomaron venganza 
sangrienta sobre los cautivos indios.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086862</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103069</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/such-was-the-tumultation-these-women-made-the-women-of-marblehead-wreak-revenge-upon-indian-captors-1677</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
