<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107662</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107662</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207049</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Photographs from the Chicago Daily News: 1902-1933</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Fotographien von den Chicago täglichen 
Nachrichten: 1902-1933</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Photographies des nouvelles quotidiennes de 
Chicago : 1902-1933</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fotografias da notícia diária de Chicago: 
1902-1933</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fotografie dalle notizie quotidiane del Chicago: 
1902-1933</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Φωτογραφίες από τις καθημερινές ειδήσεις του Σικάγου:
1902-1933</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fotografías de las noticias diarias de Chicago: 
1902-1933</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">comprises over 55,000 images of urban life captured on glass plate negatives between 1902 and 1933 by photographers employed by the Chicago Daily News, then one of Chicago's leading newspapers. The photographs illustrate the enormous variety of topics and events covered in the newspaper, although only about twenty percent of the images in the collection were published in the newspaper. Most of the photographs were taken in Chicago, Illinois, or in nearby towns, parks, or athletic fields.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">enthält über 55.000 Bildern der städtischen 
Lebensdauer erfaßt auf Glasplatte Negativen zwischen 1902 und 1933 
von den Photographen, die durch die Chicago täglichen Nachrichten, 
dann eins von Chicagos führenden Zeitungen beschäftigt werden. 
Die Fotographien veranschaulichen die enorme Vielzahl der Themen
und der Fälle, die in der Zeitung umfaßt werden, obgleich nur 
ungefähr Zwanzig Prozent der Bilder in der Ansammlung in der Zeitung 
veröffentlicht wurden. Die meisten Fotographien wurden in 
Chicago, Illinois genommen, oder in den nahe gelegenen Städten, 
fängt Parks oder athletisches auf.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">comporte plus de 55.000 images de la vie urbaine 
capturées sur des négatifs de glace entre 1902 et 1933 par des 
photographes employés par les nouvelles quotidiennes de Chicago, puis
un des principaux journaux de Chicago. Les photographies 
illustrent l'énorme variété de sujets et d'événements couverts 
dans le journal, bien que seulement environ vingt pour cent des images
dans la collection aient été édités dans le journal. La 
plupart des photographies ont été prises Chicago, l'Illinois, ou 
dans les villes voisines, les parcs, ou les domaines sportifs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">compreende sobre 55.000 imagens da vida urbana 
capturadas em negativos da placa de vidro entre 1902 e 1933 pelos 
fotógrafos empregados pela notícia diária de Chicago, então um de 
jornais principais de Chicago. As fotografias ilustram a 
variedade enorme dos tópicos e dos eventos cobertos no jornal, embora
somente aproximadamente vinte por cento das imagens na coleção sejam
publicados no jornal. A maioria das fotografias foram feitas 
exame em Chicago, Illinois, ou em cidades próximas, em parques, ou em
campos atléticos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">contiene oltre 55.000 immagini di vita urbana 
bloccate sulle negazioni della lastra di vetro fra 1902 e 1933 dai 
photographers impiegati dalle notizie quotidiane del Chicago, allora 
uno dei giornali principali del Chicago. Le fotografie 
illustrano la varietà enorme di soggetti e di eventi coperti nel 
giornale, anche se soltanto circa venti per cento delle immagini 
nell'accumulazione sono stati pubblicati nel giornale. La 
maggior parte delle fotografie sono state prese in Chicago, 
l'Illinois, o ain città vicine, in parchi, o nei campi atletici.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">περιλαμβάνει πάνω από 55.000 εικόνες της αστικής 
ζωής που συλλαμβάνονται στα αρνητικά πιάτων γυαλιού μεταξύ 
1902 και 1933 από τους φωτογράφους που απασχολούνται από τις
καθημερινές ειδήσεις του Σικάγου, έπειτα μια των κύριων 
εφημερίδων του Σικάγου. Οι φωτογραφίες επεξηγούν την 
τεράστια ποικιλία των θεμάτων και των γεγονότων που καλύπτονται 
στην εφημερίδα, αν και μόνο περίπου είκοσι τοις εκατό των 
εικόνων στη συλλογή δημοσιεύθηκαν στην εφημερίδα. Οι 
περισσότερες από τις φωτογραφίες λήφθηκαν στο Σικάγο, Ιλλινόις, 
ή στις κοντινές πόλεις, τα πάρκα, ή τα αθλητικά πεδία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">abarca sobre 55.000 imágenes de la vida urbana 
capturadas en negativas de la placa de cristal entre 1902 y 1933 por 
los fotógrafos empleados por las noticias diarias de Chicago, 
entonces uno de los periódicos principales de Chicago. Las 
fotografías ilustran la variedad enorme de asuntos y de 
acontecimientos cubiertos en el periódico, aunque solamente cerca de 
veinte por ciento de las imágenes en la colección fueron publicados 
en el periódico. La mayoría de las fotografías fueron tomadas
en Chicago, Illinois, o en ciudades próximas, parques, o campos 
atléticos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207049</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107662</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/photographs-from-the-chicago-daily-news-1902-1933</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
