<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106376</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106376</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206213</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Gravity Probe B</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Schwerkraft-Prüfspitze B</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sonde B de Pesanteur</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ponta de prova B Da Gravidade</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sonda B Di Gravità</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Έλεγχος β βαρύτητας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Punta de prueba B De la Gravedad</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a relativity gyroscope experiment designed to test two unverified predictions of Albert Einstein's general theory of relativity (1916): that the presence of a mass in space, such as the Earth, would warp local spacetime, creating a dip or curve in spacetime, and that the rotation of a mass in space would twist or drag the local spacetime frame around it. An educator's guide and space science activities are included.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist ein Relativität Gyroskopexperiment, das 
konzipiert ist, um zwei zu prüfen, unverified Vorhersagen Albert 
Einsteins der allgemeinen Theorie der Relativität (1916): daß 
das Vorhandensein einer Masse im Platz, wie der Masse, lokales 
spacetime verwerfen würde und ein Bad oder eine Kurve im spacetime 
herstellen würde und daß die Umdrehung einer Masse im Platz das 
lokale spacetime Feld um sie verdrehen oder schleppen würde. 
Anleitung- und Platzwissenschaft Aktivitäten eines Erziehers 
sind enthalten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est une expérience de gyroscope de relativité 
conçue pour tester deux prévisions invérifiées de théorie 
générale d'Albert Einstein de la relativité (1916) : que la 
présence d'une masse dans l'espace, tel que la terre, déformerait le
spacetime local, créant une immersion ou une courbe dans le 
spacetime, et que la rotation d'une masse dans l'espace tordrait ou 
traînerait la trame locale de spacetime autour d'elle. Les 
activités de la science du guide et de l'espace d'un éducateur sont 
incluses.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é uma experiência do gyroscope do relativity 
projetada testar dois unverified predições da teoria geral de Albert
Einstein do relativity (1916): que a presença de uma massa no 
espaço, tal como a terra, entortaria o spacetime local, criando um 
mergulho ou uma curva no spacetime, e que a rotação de uma massa no 
espaço torceria ou arrastaria o frame local do spacetime em torno 
dela. As atividades da ciência da guia e do espaço de um 
educador são incluídas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è un esperimento del giroscopio di relatività 
destinato per esaminare due unverified le previsioni della teoria 
generale del Albert Einstein della relatività (1916): che la 
presenza di una massa nello spazio, quale la terra, deformerebbe lo 
spacetime locale, creando un tuffo o una curva nello spacetime e che 
la rotazione di una massa nello spazio torcerebbe o trascinerebbe la 
struttura locale dello spacetime intorno esso. Le attività di 
scienza della guida e dello spazio dell'educatore sono incluse.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι ένα πείραμα γυροσκοπίων σχετικότητας με σκοπό 
να εξετάσει δύο ανεπιβεβαίωτες προβλέψεις της γενικής θεωρίας 
Αλβέρτου Einstein's της σχετικότητας (1916): ότι η 
παρουσία μιας μάζας στο διάστημα, όπως η γη, θα στρέβλωνε τοπικό
spacetime, που δημιουργεί μια εμβύθιση ή μια καμπύλη 
spacetime, και ότι η περιστροφή μιας μάζας στο διάστημα θα 
έστριβε ή θα έσερνε το τοπικό spacetime πλαίσιο γύρω από το.
Ο οδηγός ενός εκπαιδευτικού και οι διαστημικές 
δραστηριότητες επιστήμης συμπεριλαμβάνονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es un experimento del giroscopio de la relatividad 
diseñado para probar dos unverified predicciones de la teoría 
general de Albert Einstein de la relatividad (1916): que la 
presencia de una masa en espacio, tal como la tierra, combaría el 
spacetime local, creando una inmersión o una curva en spacetime, y 
que la rotación de una masa en espacio torcería o arrastraría el 
marco local del spacetime alrededor de ella. Las actividades de 
la ciencia de la guía y del espacio de un educador son incluidas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206213</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106376</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/gravity-probe-b</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
