<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107573</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107573</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086499</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"My Husband Was Seized With the Mania": Emigration from New York to Michigan, 1824</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"mein Ehemann wurde mit der Manie" ergriffen: 
Auswanderung von New York nach Michigan, 1824</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"mon mari a été saisi avec la manie" : 
Émigration de New York vers le Michigan, 1824</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"meu marido foi apreendido com o mania": 
Emigration de New York a Michigan, 1824</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"il mio marito è stato grippato con il mania": 
Emigrazione da New York nel Michigan, 1824</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ο σύζυγός μου αρπάχτηκε με τη μανία": Αποδημία
από τη Νέα Υόρκη στο Μίτσιγκαν, 1824</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">agarraron a "mi marido con el mania": 
Emigración de Nueva York a Michigan, 1824</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The end of the War of 1812 promoted a surge of migration to the territories west of the Appalachian Mountains. In 1790, 95 percent of the population lived in the states along the Atlantic Ocean; by 1812 one-quarter lived west of the Appalachians. Farmers looking for new lands found these vast areas attractive after the War for Independence had forced many Indian peoples into land cessation and removal in the Michigan territory and other northwestern areas. Low land prices also enticed families from overpopulated eastern regions. Harriet Noble and her family took the northernmost of the major migration routes west, crossing upstate New York and Lake Erie to reach Detroit. She found multiethnic Detroit "the most filthy, irregular place I had ever seen." While her husband faced sickness and other hazards on their isolated farm, Harriet voiced complaints familiar from many women's narratives of the frontier: the absence of society and social institutions.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Ende des Krieges von 1812 förderte einen 
Stromstoß der Migration zu den Gegenden westlich von den Appalachian 
Bergen. 1790 lebten 95 Prozent der Bevölkerung in den 
Zuständen entlang dem Atlantik; durch 1812 ein viertel lebte 
westlich von den Appalachians. Die Landwirte, die nach neuen 
Ländern suchen, fanden diese beträchtlichen Bereiche attraktiv nach 
dem Krieg für Unabhängigkeit hatten erzwungen viele indische Völker
in Landaufhören und -abbau in die Michigan Gegend und in andere 
nordwestliche Bereiche. Niedriges Land setzt für Preis auch 
verleitete Familien von overpopulated östlichen Regionen fest. 
Harriet, das vortrefflich sind und ihre Familie nahmen das 
nördlichste der Hauptmigration Wege nach Westen und kreuzten upstate 
New York und See Erie, um Detroit zu erreichen. Sie fand 
multiethnisches Detroit "der schmutzigste, unregelmäßigste Platz, 
den ich hatte überhaupt gesehen." Während ihre Ehemann 
gegenübergestellte Krankheit und andere Gefahren auf ihrem 
lokalisierten Bauernhof, Harriet die Beanstandungen äußerten, die 
von den Darstellungen vieler Frauen der Grenze vertraut sind: 
die Abwesenheit der Gesellschaft und der Sozialanstalten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La fin de la guerre de 1812 a favorisé une 
montée subite de transfert aux territoires à l'ouest des montagnes 
appalachiennes. En 1790, 95 pour cent de la population ont vécu
dans les états le long de l'Océan Atlantique ; à côté de 
1812 un quart a vécu à l'ouest des Appalaches. Les fermiers 
recherchant de nouvelles terres ont trouvé ces vastes zones 
attrayantes après la guerre pour l'indépendance avaient forcé 
beaucoup de peuples indiens dans le cessation et l'enlèvement de 
terre dans le territoire du Michigan et d'autres zones du nord-ouest. 
La basse terre évalue les familles également attirées des 
régions orientales surpeuplées. Harriet noble et sa famille 
ont pris le plus au nord des itinéraires principaux de transfert à 
l'ouest, croisant New York hors de la ville et lac Erie pour atteindre 
Detroit. Elle a trouvé Detroit multi-ethnique "l'endroit le 
plus dégoûtant et le plus irrégulier que j'avais jamais vu." 
Tandis que sa maladie faite face par mari et d'autres risques à
leur ferme d'isolement, Harriet exprimaient des plaintes familières 
des récits de beaucoup de femmes de la frontière : l'absence 
de la société et des institutions sociaux.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O fim da guerra de 1812 promoveu um surge da 
migração aos territórios ao oeste das montanhas appalachian. 
Em 1790, 95 por cento da população viveram nos estados ao 
longo do Oceano Atlântico; por 1812 um quarto viveu ao oeste 
dos appalachians. Os fazendeiros que procuram terras novas 
encontraram estas áreas vastas atrativas após a guerra para a 
independência tinham forçado muitos povos indian na cessação e na 
remoção da terra no território de Michigan e em outras áreas do 
noroeste. A terra baixa fixa o preço de famílias também 
seduzidas das regiões orientais overpopulated. Harriet nobre e 
sua família fizeram exame do mais northernmost das rotas principais 
da migração para o oeste, cruzando o upstate New York e o lago erie 
para alcançar Detroit. Encontrou Detroit multiethnic "o lugar 
que o mais filthy, o mais irregular eu tinha visto sempre." 
Quando sua doença enfrentada marido e outros perigos em sua 
fazenda isolada, Harriet exprimiram as queixas familiares das 
narrativas de muitas mulheres da fronteira: a ausência da 
sociedade e de instituições sociais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La conclusione della guerra di 1812 ha promosso un
impulso di espansione ai territori ad ovest delle montagne 
appalachian. In 1790, 95 per cento della popolazione hanno 
vissuto in dichiarano lungo l'Oceano Atlantico; da 1812 un 
quarto ha vissuto ad ovest dei appalachians. I coltivatori che 
cercano le nuove terre hanno trovato queste zone ampie attraenti dopo 
la guerra per indipendenza avevano forzato molta gente indiana in 
cessazione ed in rimozione della terra nel territorio del Michigan ed 
in altre zone nordoccidentali. La terra bassa valuta le famiglie
anche attratte dalle regioni orientali overpopulated. Harriet 
nobile e la sua famiglia hanno preso il più northernmost degli 
itinerari principali di espansione verso ovest, attraversando il 
upstate New York ed il lago Erie per raggiungere Detroit. Ha 
trovato Detroit multiethnic "il posto che più ripugnante e più 
irregolare avevo visto mai." Mentre la sua malattia affrontata 
marito ed altri rischi sul loro podere isolato, Harriet hanno espresso
i reclami esperti dalle descrizioni di molte donne della frontiera: 
l'assenza della società e delle istituzioni sociali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το τέλος του πολέμου 1812 προώθησε ένα κύμα της 
μετανάστευσης στα εδάφη δυτικά των της όξινης απορροής βουνών. 
Το 1790 ..95 τοις εκατό του πληθυσμού έζησαν στα κράτη
κατά μήκος του Ατλαντικού Ωκεανού  από 1812 τέταρτο 
έζησε δυτικά του Appalachians. Οι αγρότες που ψάχνουν τα 
νέα εδάφη βρήκαν αυτές τις απέραντες περιοχές ελκυστικές 
αφότου είχε αναγκάσει ο πόλεμος για την ανεξαρτησία πολλούς 
ινδικούς λαούς στη διακοπή και την αφαίρεση εδάφους στο έδαφος 
του Μίτσιγκαν και άλλες βορειοδυτικές περιοχές. Οι χαμηλές 
τιμές εδάφους προσέλκυσαν επίσης τις οικογένειες από τις 
overpopulated ανατολικές περιοχές. Ο Harriet Noble 
και η οικογένειά της πήραν τον πιό βορειότατο της σημαντικότερης
δύσης διαδρομών μετανάστευσης, που διασχίζει την εκτός κράτους 
Νέα Υόρκη και τη λίμνη Erie για να φθάσουν στο Ντητρόιτ. 
Βρήκε το multiethnic Ντητρόιτ "η πιό ακάθαρτη, ανώμαλη 
θέση που είχα δει πάντα." Ενώ ο σύζυγός της 
αντιμετώπισε την ασθένεια και άλλους κινδύνους στο απομονωμένο 
αγρόκτημά τους, ο Harriet εξέφρασε τις καταγγελίες γνωστές 
από τα αφηγήματα πολλών γυναικών των συνόρων: η απουσία 
κοινωνίας και κοινωνικών οργάνων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El final de la guerra de 1812 promovió una oleada
de la migración a los territorios al oeste de las montañas 
apalaches. En 1790, 95 por ciento de la población vivieron en 
los estados a lo largo del Océano Atlántico; por 1812 un 
cuarto vivió al oeste de los apalaches. Los granjeros que 
buscaban pistas nuevas encontraron estas áreas extensas atractivas 
después de la guerra para la independencia habían forzado a mucha 
gente india en la cesación y el retiro de la pista en el territorio 
de Michigan y otras áreas del noroeste. La pista baja tasa a 
familias también tentadas de regiones del este superpobladas. 
Harriet noble y su familia tomaron el más situado más al norte
de las rutas principales de la migración al oeste, cruzando el 
upstate Nueva York y el lago Erie para alcanzar Detroit. Ella 
encontró Detroit multiethnic "el lugar más asqueroso, más irregular
que había visto siempre." Mientras que su enfermedad hecha 
frente marido y otros peligros en su granja aislada, Harriet 
expresaron las quejas familiares de las narrativas de muchas mujeres 
de la frontera: la ausencia de la sociedad y de instituciones 
sociales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086499</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107573</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/my-husband-was-seized-with-the-mania-emigration-from-new-york-to-michigan-1824</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
