<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105620</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105620</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209875</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Hexagon </string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hexagon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Hexagone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Hexágono</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Esagono</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Hexagon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Hexágono</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A web page and interactive applet illustrating the properties of a hexagon (6 sided polygon). The applet shows a hexagon where the user can drag any vertex to reshape it. User can see that the interior and exterior angles are constant in a regular hexagon, but vary in an irregular version. Controls allow the display or hiding of the diagonals, and triangles within the hexagon. The web page lists the properties of a hexagon including interior angles, exterior angles, sum of exterior angles, area, number of diagonals and number of internal triangles. Links to pages with generalized properties of all polygons. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Webseite und ein interaktiver applet, welche 
die Eigenschaften eines Hexagons veranschaulichen (6 mit Seiten 
versehenes Polygon). Der applet zeigt einem Hexagon, wo der 
Benutzer jeden möglichen Gipfel schleppen kann, um ihn umzugestalten.
Benutzer kann sehen, daß die Innen- und Außenwinkel in einem 
regelmäßigen Hexagon, aber in eine unregelmäßige Version schwanken
konstant sind. Kontrollen erlauben die Bildschirmanzeige oder 
das Verstecken der Diagonalen und die Dreiecke innerhalb des Hexagons.
Die Webseite druckt die Eigenschaften eines Hexagons 
einschließlich Innenwinkel, Außenwinkel, Summe Außenwinkel, 
Bereich, Zahl der Diagonalen und Zahl der internen Dreiecke aus. 
Links zu den Seiten mit generalisierten Eigenschaften aller 
Polygone. Applet kann zum vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit 
einem Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. Nachgebrauch 
im Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von jedem möglichem web 
browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den benötigten LOGON 
wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Bestandteil des 
Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une page Web et un applet interactif illustrant 
les propriétés d'un hexagone (polygone dégrossi par 6). 
L'applet montre à un hexagone où l'utilisateur peut traîner 
n'importe quel sommet pour le restructurer. L'utilisateur peut 
voir que les angles intérieurs et extérieurs sont constants dans un 
hexagone régulier, mais changer dans une version irrégulière. 
Les commandes permettent l'affichage ou se cacher des 
diagonales, et les triangles dans l'hexagone. La page Web 
énumère les propriétés d'un hexagone comprenant des angles 
intérieurs, des angles extérieurs, la somme d'angles extérieurs, la
zone, le nombre de diagonales et le nombre de triangles internes. 
Liens aux pages avec les propriétés généralisées de tous 
les polygones. L'applet peut être agrandi à la taille de plein
écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de classe. Le 
après utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant peut lui 
accéder encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la maison ou 
dans la bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion exigée. 
Cette ressource est un composant du projet interactif de manuel 
de la géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um Web page e um applet interativo que ilustram as
propriedades de um hexágono (polygon tom o partido 6). O applet
mostra a um hexágono onde o usuário pode arrastar todo o vertex para
reshape o. O usuário pode ver que os ângulos interior e 
exteriores são constantes em um hexágono regular, mas variá-lo em 
uma versão irregular. Os controles permitem o indicador ou 
esconder das diagonais, e os triângulos dentro do hexágono. O 
Web page alista as propriedades de um hexágono including ângulos 
interior, ângulos exteriores, soma de ângulos exteriores, área, 
número das diagonais e número de triângulos internos. 
Ligações às páginas com propriedades generalizadas de todos 
os polygons. O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de tela cheia
para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. O depois de uso na 
sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo o web 
browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma sessão 
requerido. Este recurso é um componente do projeto interativo 
do textbook da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un Web page e un applet interattivo che illustrano
le proprietà di un esagono (poligono parteggiato 6). Il applet 
mostra ad un esagono dove l'utente può trascinare tutto il vertice 
per rimodellarlo. L'utente può vedere che gli angoli interni ed
esterni sono costanti in un esagono normale, ma variare in una 
versione irregolare. I comandi permettono la visualizzazione o 
nascondersi delle diagonali ed i triangoli all'interno dell'esagono. 
Il Web page elenca le proprietà di un esagono compreso gli 
angoli interni, gli angoli esterni, la somma degli angoli esterni, la 
zona, il numero di diagonali ed il numero di triangoli interni. 
Collegamenti alle pagine con le proprietà generalizzate di 
tutti i poligoni. Il applet può essere ingrandito al formato di
schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore dell'aula. La 
post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può accederle ancora da tutto 
il web browser nel paese o nella libreria senza l'inizio attività 
richiesto. Questa risorsa è un componente del progetto 
interattivo del manuale della geometria di riferimento aperto di per 
la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ιστοσελίδας και διαλογικό ένα applet που επεξηγούν 
τις ιδιότητες hexagon (6 πλαισιωμένο πολύγωνο). Το 
applet εμφανίζει hexagon όπου ο χρήστης μπορεί να σέρει 
οποιοδήποτε vertex για να το αναδιαμορφώσει. Ο χρήστης 
μπορεί να δει ότι οι εσωτερικές και εξωτερικές γωνίες
είναι σταθερές κανονικό hexagon, αλλά ποικίλλουν σε μια 
ανώμαλη έκδοση. Οι έλεγχοι επιτρέπουν την παρουσίαση ή το 
κρύψιμο των διαγώνιών, και τα τρίγωνα μέσα hexagon. 
Ιστοσελίδας εμφανίζει λίστα τις ιδιότητες hexagon 
συμπεριλαμβανομένων των εσωτερικών γωνιών, των εξωτερικών γωνιών,
του ποσού των εξωτερικών γωνιών, της περιοχής, του αριθμού 
διαγώνιών και του αριθμού εσωτερικών τριγώνων. Συνδέσεις 
με τις σελίδες με τις γενικευμένες ιδιότητες όλων των πολυγώνων. 
Το Applet μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης
για τη χρήση με έναν προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση 
στην τάξη, ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από
οποιοδήποτε ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς 
την άδεια εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο 
συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος 
εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un Web page y un applet interactivo que ilustran 
las características de un hexágono (polígono echado a un lado 6). 
El applet muestra a hexágono donde el utilizador puede 
arrastrar cualquier cima para restructurarla. El utilizador 
puede ver que los ángulos interiores y exteriores son constantes en 
un hexágono regular, sino variar en una versión irregular. Los
controles permiten la visualización u ocultar de las diagonales, y 
los triángulos dentro del hexágono. El Web page enumera las 
características de un hexágono incluyendo ángulos interiores, 
ángulos exteriores, la suma de ángulos exteriores, el área, el 
número de diagonales y el número de triángulos internos. 
Conexiones a las paginaciones con las características 
generalizadas de todos los polígonos. El applet se puede 
agrandar a la talla de la pantalla completa para el uso con un 
proyector de la sala de clase. El uso posterior en la sala de 
clase, estudiante puede tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier web 
browser en el país o en la biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. 
Este recurso es un componente del proyecto interactivo del libro
de textos de la geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas
en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209875</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105620</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/hexagon</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
