<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104373</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104373</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086121</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Enemies, A Drama of Modern Marriage: The Sexual Revolution Enacted</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Feinde, ein Drama der modernen Verbindung: 
Die Sexuelle Umdrehung Verordnet</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ennemis, un drame de mariage moderne : La 
Révolution Sexuelle Décrétée</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Inimigos, um drama da união moderna: A 
Volta Sexual Decretada</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nemici, un dramma dell'unione moderna: 
Rivoluzione Sessuale Promulgata</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εχθροί, ένα δράμα του σύγχρονου γάμου: Η 
επανάσταση που θεσπίζεται σεξουαλική</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Enemigos, un drama de la unión moderna: La 
Revolución Sexual Decretada</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the 1920s, new sexual ideologies reshaped prescriptions for marriage, incorporating moderate versions of feminism. Neith Boyce and Hutchins Hapgood shared the romantic radicalism of Floyd Dell and other Greenwich Village bohemians in the early 20th century. They practiced open marriage, though not without pain and confusion. Written in 1916 for the Provincetown Players, an innovative theater group that operated between 1915 and 1922,  Enemies  was an autobiographical meditation on the emotional struggles of a couple in a non-monogamous marriage. The characters expressed considerable bitterness, yet in the end affirmed their partnership. In the first draft of the play the characters bore the names of their authors, clearly suggesting its autobiographical inspiration.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In den zwanziger Jahren gestalteten neue sexuelle 
Ideologien die Verordnungen für Verbindung um und enthielten 
gemäßigte Versionen von Feminismus. Neith Boyce und Hutchins 
Hapgood teilten die romantische Radikalismus von Floyd Dell und 
andere Greenwich Villageböhmen im frühen 20. Jahrhundert. Sie 
übten geöffnete Verbindung, zwar nicht ohne die Schmerz und 
Durcheinander. Geschrieben 1916 für die Provincetown Spieler, 
war eine erfinderische Theatergruppe, die zwischen 1915 und 1922 
funktionierte, Feinde eine autobiographische Meditation auf den 
emotionalen Kämpfen eines Paares in einer non-monogam Verbindung. 
Die Zeichen drückten beträchtliche Bitterkeit aus, dennoch im 
Ende bestätigte ihre Teilhaberschaft. Im ersten Entwurf des 
Spiels bohren die Zeichen die Namen ihrer Autoren und offenbar 
schlagen seine autobiographische Inspiration vor.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans les années 20, les nouvelles idéologies 
sexuelles ont restructuré des prescriptions pour le mariage, 
incorporant des versions modérées du féminisme. Neith Boyce 
et Hutchins Hapgood ont partagé le radicalisme romantique de 
Floyd Dell et d'autres bohémiens de village de Greenwich en 
début du 20ème siècle. Ils ont pratiqué le mariage ouvert, 
cependant pas sans douleur et confusion. Écrit en 1916 pour 
les joueurs de Provincetown, un groupe innovateur de théâtre qui a 
fonctionné entre 1915 et 1922, des ennemis était une méditation 
autobiographique sur les luttes émotives d'un couple dans un mariage 
de non-monogame. Les caractères ont exprimé l'amertume 
considérable, pourtant à la fin a affirmé leur association. 
Dans la première ébauche du jeu les caractères alèsent les 
noms de leurs auteurs, suggérant clairement son inspiration 
autobiographique.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nos 1920s, os ideologies sexual novos reshaped as 
prescrições para a união, incorporando versões moderadas do 
feminismo. Neith Boyce e Hutchins Hapgood compartilharam do 
radicalism romântico de Floyd Dell e outros bohemians da vila de 
Greenwich no 20o século adiantado. Praticaram a união aberta, 
though não sem dor e confusão. Escrito em 1916 para os 
jogadores de Provincetown, um grupo inovativo do teatro que se 
operasse entre 1915 e 1922, inimigos era um meditation 
autobiographical nos esforços emocionais de um par em uma união 
non-monogamous. Os caráteres expressaram o bitterness 
considerável, contudo na extremidade afirmou sua parceria. No 
primeiro esboço do jogo os caráteres furam os nomes de seus autores,
sugerindo claramente sua inspiração autobiographical.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Negli anni 20, le nuove ideologie sessuali hanno 
rimodellato le prescrizioni per l'unione, comprendenti le versioni 
moderate di feminism. Neith Boyce e Hutchins Hapgood hanno 
ripartito il radicalism romantico di Floyd Dell ed altri bohemians del
villaggio di Greenwich nell'inizio del 20esimo secolo. Si sono 
esercitati nell'unione aperta, comunque non senza dolore e confusione.
Scritto in 1916 per i giocatori di Provincetown, un gruppo 
innovatore del teatro che ha funzionato fra 1915 e 1922, nemici era 
una meditazione autobiografica sulle lotte impressionabili di una 
coppia in un'unione non-monogamous. I caratteri hanno espresso 
l'amarezza considerevole, tuttavia alla fine ha affermato la loro 
associazione. Nella prima brutta copia del gioco i caratteri 
alesano i nomi dei loro autori, suggerenti chiaramente la relativa 
ispirazione autobiografica.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στη δεκαετία του '20, νέες σεξουαλικές 
αναδιαμορφωμένες ιδεολογίες συνταγές για το γάμο, που ενσωματώνει
τις μέτριες εκδόσεις του φεμινισμού. Το Neith Boyce και
Hutchins Hapgood μοιράστηκε τη ρομαντική ριζοσπαστισμό της 
κοιλάδας Floyd και άλλου χωριού του Γκρήνουιτς bohemians 
στις αρχές του 20ού αιώνα. Ασκησαν τον ανοικτό γάμο, εν 
τούτοις όχι χωρίς τον πόνο και σύγχυση. Γραπτοί το 1916
για τους Provincetown φορείς, μια καινοτόμος ομάδα θεάτρων που 
λειτούργησε μεταξύ 1915 και 1922, οι εχθροί ήταν μια 
αυτοβιογραφική περισυλλογή στις συναισθηματικές προσπάθειες ενός 
ζεύγους σε έναν μη-μονογαμικό γάμο. Οι χαρακτήρες 
εξέφρασαν την ιδιαίτερη πικρία, όμως στο τέλος βεβαίωσε τη 
συνεργασία τους. Στο πρώτο σχέδιο του παιχνιδιού οι 
χαρακτήρες έφεραν τις επωνυμίες των συντακτών τους, προτείνοντας 
σαφώς την αυτοβιογραφική έμπνευσή του.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En los años 20, las nuevas ideologías sexuales 
restructuraron las prescripciones para la unión, incorporando 
versiones moderadas del feminismo. Neith Boyce y Hutchins 
Hapgood compartieron el radicalismo romántico de Floyd Dell y otros 
bohemios de la aldea de Greenwich en el vigésimo siglo temprano. 
Practicaron la unión abierta, aunque no sin dolor y la 
confusión. Escrito en 1916 para los jugadores de Provincetown, 
un grupo innovador del teatro que funcionó entre 1915 y 1922, los 
enemigos era una meditación autobiográfica en las luchas emocionales
de un par en una unión non-monogamous. Los caracteres 
expresaron amargura considerable, con todo en el extremo afirmó su 
sociedad. En el primer bosquejo del juego los caracteres 
agujerean los nombres de sus autores, sugiriendo claramente su 
inspiración autobiográfica.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086121</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104373</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/enemies-a-drama-of-modern-marriage-the-sexual-revolution-enacted</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
