<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104813</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104813</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087374</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"All We Are Seeking Here Is Equal Opportunity": The American G.I. Forum Desegregates a Texas Community's Schools</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Alle, die Wir Hier Suchen, Ist Gleiche 
Gelegenheit": Schulen der amerikanisch G.I. Forum Desegregates 
Texas Gemeinschaft</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Tout Que Nous Recherchons Ici Est Égalité des 
chances" : Américain G.I. Forum Desegregates les écoles d'une 
Communauté du Texas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Tudo Que Nós Estamos procurando Aqui É 
Oportunidade Igual": Escolas americano G.I. Forum Desegregates 
da comunidade de Texas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Tutta Che Stiamo cercando Qui È Occasione 
Uguale": Scuole americano G.I. Forum Desegregates della 
Comunità del Texas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Το μόνο που επιδιώκουμε εδώ είναι ίση ευκαιρία": 
Το αμερικανικό G.I. φόρουμ Desegregates σχολεία μιας 
του Τέξας Κοινότητας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Toda Lo que Estamos buscando Aquí Es Oportunidad
Igual": Escuelas americano G.I. Forum Desegregates de la 
comunidad de Tejas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">With the annexation of Texas in 1848 at the end of the Mexican-American War, Tejanos--Texans of Mexican descent--lost property rights and political power in a society dominated by Anglos. Through discriminatory practices and violent force, Tejanos were kept at the bottom of the new political and socio-cultural order. From 1900-1930, as an influx of immigrants from Mexico came north to meet a growing demand for cheap labor in the developing commercial agriculture industries, Tejanos experienced continued discrimination in employment, housing, public facilities, the judicial system, and educational institutions. Many school districts segregated Tejano and Anglo children into separate facilities with the Mexican schools grossly underfunded and often offering only a grade school education. In 1930, when 90% of the schools in South Texas were segregated, the League of United Latin American Citizens (LULAC), a Tejano advocacy group organized the previous year, supported the first major court challenge in Texas to end school segregation. The Texas Court of Appeals, however, ruled that school districts could use such criteria as language and irregular attendance due to seasonal work to separate children in school. The struggle of Mexican Americans to end discriminatory practices accelerated following World War II. In 1948, LULAC and the newly formed American G.I. Forum, an advocacy group of Mexican American veterans, assisted in a lawsuit. The federal district court ruling in that case prohibited school segregation based on Mexican ancestry. Localities devised ways to evade the ruling, however, and de facto segregation continued. Student protests in the late 1960s achieved an end to some discriminatory practices. In subsequent years a new civil rights organization, the Mexican American Legal Defense and Educational Fund (MALDEF), continued the fight in the courts, eventually concentrating on the introduction of bilingual and bicultural programs into schools. In the following interview, Ed Idar, associated with both the Forum and MALDEF, related a successful grassroots effort in the early 1950s to desegregate a school without a court ruling.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mit der Annexion von Texas 1848 am Ende des 
Mexikanisch-Amerikanischen Krieges, des Tejanos -- des Texans des 
mexikanischen Abfalls -- verlorene Eigentumsrechte und politische 
Energie in einer Gesellschaft beherrscht von Anglos. Durch 
diskriminierende Praxis und heftige Kraft wurden Tejanos an der 
Unterseite der neuen politischen und soziologisch-kulturellen Ordnung 
gehalten. Von 1900-1930 während ein Zufluß der Immigranten von
Mexiko nördlich kam, eine steigende Nachfrage nach preiswerter Arbeit
in den sich entwickelnden kommerziellen Landwirtschaft Industrien zu 
treffen, erfuhr Tejanos anhaltende Unterscheidung in der 
Beschäftigung, im Gehäuse, in den allgemeinen Teildiensten, im 
Gerichtssystem und in den pädagogischen Anstalten. Viel 
underfunded Schule Bezirke getrenntes Tejano und Anglokinder in 
unterschiedliche Teildienste mit den mexikanischen Schulen grob und 
nur eine Gradschuleausbildung häufig, anbietend. 1930 als 90% 
der Schulen in Südtexas getrennt wurden, organisierte die Liga der 
vereinigten lateinamerikanischen Bürger (LULAC), eine Tejano 
Befürwortung Gruppe das vorhergehende Jahr, unterstützt der ersten 
Hauptgerichtherausforderung in Texas, um Schuleabtrennung zu beenden. 
Das Texas Gericht von Anklänge ordnete jedoch an, daß 
Schulebezirke solche Kriterien wie die Sprache und unregelmäßige 
Anwesenheit verwenden konnten wegen der Saisonarbeit, Kinder in der 
Schule zu trennen. Der Kampf der mexikanischen Amerikaner, zum 
der diskriminierenden Praxis zu beenden beschleunigte den folgenden 
Zweiten Weltkrieg. 1948, LULAC und eben gebildete amerikanische 
G.I. Forum, eine Befürwortung Gruppe mexikanische amerikanische 
Veterane, unterstützt in einem Prozeß. Das Bundesamtsgericht, 
das in diesem Fall anordnet, verbot die Schuleabtrennung, die auf 
mexikanischem Geschlecht basierte. Stellen planten Methoden, dem
Anordnen auszuweichen, jedoch und de Facto Abtrennung fuhr fort. 
Kursteilnehmerproteste in den späten sechziger Jahren 
erreichten einen Zweck zu etwas diskriminierender Praxis. In den
folgenden Jahren setzten eine neue Zivilrechtorganisation, die 
mexikanische amerikanische zugelassene Verteidigung und die 
pädagogische Kapital (MALDEF), den Kampf in den Gerichten fort und 
schließlich konzentrierten sich auf die Einleitung der zweisprachigen
und bikulturellen Programme in Schulen. Im folgenden Interview 
verband ED Idar, mit dem Forum und MALDEF, eine erfolgreiche 
Basisbemühung in den frühen fünfziger Jahren auf desegregate 
in Verbindung gestanden eine Schule ohne Gerichtanzuordnen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Avec l'annexation du Texas en 1848 à la fin de la
guerre, du Tejanos Mexicain-Américains -- Texan de descente 
mexicaine -- droites de propriété perdues et puissance politique 
dans une société dominée par Anglos. Par les pratiques 
discriminatoires et la force violente, Tejanos ont été maintenus au 
bas de la nouvelle commande politique et socio-culturelle. De 
1900-1930, pendant qu'un afflux des immigrés du Mexique venait au 
nord pour satisfaire une demande croissante en main d'oeuvre à prix 
réduit dans les industries commerciales se développantes 
d'agriculture, Tejanos a éprouvé la discrimination continue dans 
l'emploi, le logement, les équipements publics, le système 
juridique, et les établissements éducatifs. Beaucoup de 
l'école Tejano isolé par zones et les enfants anglo dans les 
équipements séparés avec les écoles mexicaines underfunded 
excessivement et souvent offrant seulement une éducation d'école de 
catégorie. En 1930, quand 90% des écoles dans le Texas 
Du sud ont été isolés, la ligue des citoyens 
latino-américains unis (LULAC), un groupe de recommandation de Tejano
a organisé l'année précédente, supportée le premier défi 
principal de cour dans le Texas pour terminer la ségrégation 
d'école. La cour du Texas des appels, cependant, a régné que 
les zones d'école pourraient utiliser des critères tels que le 
langage et le assistance irrégulier dus au travail saisonnier pour 
séparer des enfants à l'école. La lutte des Américains 
mexicains pour terminer des pratiques discriminatoires a accéléré 
la deuxième guerre mondiale suivante. En 1948, LULAC et G.I. 
Forum américain nouvellement formé, un groupe de recommandation de 
vétérans américains mexicains, aidé à un procès. La cour 
de zone fédérale régnant dans ce cas a interdit la ségrégation 
d'école basée sur l'ascendance mexicaine. Les localités ont 
trouvé des moyens d'éluder régner, cependant, et la ségrégation 
de fait a continué. Les protestations d'étudiant vers la fin 
des années 60 ont atteint un but à quelques pratiques 
discriminatoires. En années ultérieures une nouvelle 
organisation de droits civiques, la défense légale américaine 
mexicaine et les fonds éducatifs (MALDEF), ont continué le combat 
dans les cours, se concentrant par la suite sur l'introduction des 
programmes bilingues et biculturels dans des écoles. Dans 
l'entrevue suivante, ED Idar, s'est associé au forum et à MALDEF, 
liés un effort réussi de bases au début des années 50 au 
desegregate une école sans régner de cour.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Com o annexation de Texas em 1848 no fim da 
guerra, do Tejanos -- o Texans Mexicano-Americanos da descida mexicana
-- direitas de propriedade perdidas e potência política em uma 
sociedade dominada por Anglos. Através das práticas 
discriminatory e da força violenta, Tejanos foi mantido no fundo da 
ordem política e socio-socio-cultural nova. De 1900-1930, 
enquanto um influx dos immigrants de México veio para o norte se 
encontrar com uma demanda de crescimento para o trabalho barato nas 
indústrias comerciais se tornando da agricultura, Tejanos 
experimentou a discriminação continuada no emprego, na carcaça, em 
facilidades públicas, no sistema judicial, e em instituições 
educacionais. Muito a escola Tejano segregado distritos e as 
crianças anglo em facilidades separadas com as escolas mexicanas 
underfunded bruta e frequentemente oferecendo somente uma instrução 
da escola da classe. Em 1930, quando 90% das escolas em Texas 
sul foram segregadas, a liga dos cidadãos americanos latin unidos 
(LULAC), um grupo do advocacy de Tejano organizou o ano precedente, 
suportado o primeiro desafio principal da corte em Texas para terminar
o segregation da escola. A corte de Texas de apelações, 
entretanto, governou que os distritos da escola poderiam usar 
critérios como a língua e o comparecimento irregular  devido ao 
trabalho seasonal separar crianças na escola. O esforço dos 
americanos mexicanos para terminar práticas discriminatory acelerou 
seguinte segunda guerra mundial. Em 1948, em LULAC e no G.I. 
americano recentemente dado forma Forum, um grupo do advocacy de 
veterans americanos mexicanos, ajudado em um lawsuit. A corte de
distrito federal que governa nesse caso proibiu o segregation da 
escola baseado no ancestry mexicano. Os localities planejaram 
maneiras evade governar, entretanto, e o segregation de de facto 
continuou. Os protestos do estudante nos 1960s atrasados 
conseguiram uma extremidade a algumas práticas discriminatory. 
Em anos subseqüentes uma organização nova das direitas civis,
a defesa legal americana mexicana e o fundo educacional (MALDEF), 
continuaram a luta nas cortes, concentrando eventualmente na 
introdução de programas bilíngües e bicultural em escolas. 
Na seguinte entrevista, o Ed Idar, associou com  o forum e o 
MALDEF, relacionados um esforço bem sucedido dos grassroots nos 1950s
adiantados ao desegregate uma escola sem governar da corte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Con il annexation del Texas in 1848 alla 
conclusione della guerra di messicano-american, del Tejanos -- il 
Texans della discesa messicana -- diritti di proprietà persi e 
potenza politica in una società dominata da Anglos. Attraverso 
le pratiche discriminatorie e la forza violenta, Tejanos è stato 
mantenuto alla parte inferiore di nuovo ordine politico e 
socio-culturale. Da 1900-1930, mentre un afflusso degli 
immigranti dal Messico è venuto a nord venire a contatto di una 
domanda crescente del lavoro poco costoso nelle industrie 
commerciali di sviluppo di agricoltura, Tejanos ha avvertito la 
distinzione continuata nell'occupazione, in alloggiamento, nelle 
attrezzature pubbliche, nel sistema giudiziario e negli istituti 
scolastici. Molto la scuola Tejano segregato distretti ed i 
bambini anglo nelle attrezzature separate con le scuole messicane 
grossolanamente underfunded e spesso offrendo soltanto una formazione 
della scuola del grado. In 1930, quando 90% delle scuole nel 
Texas del sud sono stati segregati, la lega dei cittadini dell'America
latina uniti (LULAC), un gruppo di avvocatura di Tejano ha organizzato
l'anno precedente, sostenuto la prima sfida principale della corte nel
Texas per concludere la segregazione della scuola. La Corte 
d'Appello del Texas, tuttavia, ha regolato che i distretti della 
scuola potrebbero usare tali test di verifica come il linguaggio e la 
presenza irregolare dovuto lavoro stagionale separare i bambini a 
scuola. La lotta degli Americani messicani per concludere le 
pratiche discriminatorie ha accelerato la seguente seconda guerra 
mondiale. In 1948, in LULAC e nel G.I. Forum americano 
recentemente formato, un gruppo di avvocatura dei veterani americani 
messicani, aiutato in una causa. La corte di distretto 
federale che regola in quel caso ha proibito la segregazione della 
scuola basata sull'ascendenza messicana. Le località hanno 
inventato i modi eludere il regolamento, tuttavia e la segregazione de
facto è continuato. Le proteste dell'allievo verso la fine 
degli anni 60 hanno raggiunto uno scopo ad alcune pratiche 
discriminatorie. Durante gli anni successivi una nuova 
organizzazione di diritti civili, la difesa legale americana 
messicana ed il fondo monetario educativo (MALDEF), hanno continuato
la lotta nelle corti, finalmente concentrantesi sull'introduzione dei 
programmi bilingue e biculturali nelle scuole. Nella seguente 
intervista, il Ed Idar, si è associato con sia la tribuna che MALDEF,
relativi uno sforzo riuscito dei grassroots nell'inizio degli anni 
cinquanta a desegregate una scuola senza un regolamento della corte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Με την προσάρτηση του Τέξας το 1848 στο τέλος του 
Μεξικανοαμερικάνύ πολέμου, Tejanos -- Texans της μεξικάνικης
καταγωγής -- έχασαν τα δικαιώματα ιδιοκτησιών και την πολιτική 
δύναμη σε μια κοινωνία που εξουσιάστηκε από Anglos. Μέσω
των μεροληπτικών πρακτικών και της βίαιας δύναμης, Tejanos 
κρατήθηκε στο κατώτατο σημείο της νέας πολιτικής και 
κοινωνικοπολιτιστικής κατάταξης. Από το 1900-1930, καθώς 
μια εισροή των μεταναστών από το Μεξικό ήρθε βόρεια να 
ικανοποιήσει μια αυξανόμενη ζήτηση για τη φτηνή εργασία στις 
αναπτυσσόμενες εμπορικές βιομηχανίες γεωργίας, Tejanos 
δοκίμασε τη συνεχή διάκριση στην απασχόληση, την κατοικία, τις 
δημόσιες εγκαταστάσεις, το δικαστικό σύστημα, και τα εκπαιδευτικά
όργανα. Πολλές σχολικές περιοχές διαχώρισαν 
Tejano και τα παιδιά Anglo στις χωριστές εγκαταστάσεις με τα 
μεξικάνικα σχολεία συνολικά και προσφέροντας συχνά μόνο μια 
σχολική εκπαίδευση βαθμού. Το 1930, όταν διαχωρίστηκαν 
90% των σχολείων στο νότιο Τέξας, η ένωση των ενωμένων 
λατινοαμερικανικών πολιτών (LULAC), μια ομάδα υπεράσπισης 
Tejano που οργανώθηκε το προηγούμενο έτος, υποστήριξε την 
πρώτη σημαντική πρόκληση δικαστηρίων στο Τέξας στο σχολικό 
διαχωρισμό τελών. Το Εφετείο του Τέξας, εντούτοις, διέταξε
ότι οι σχολικές περιοχές θα μπορούσαν να χρησιμοποιήσουν τέτοια 
κριτήρια όπως τη γλώσσα και την ανώμαλη συμμετοχή λόγω στην 
εποχιακή εργασία στα χωριστά παιδιά στο σχολείο. Η 
προσπάθεια μεξικάνικων Αμερικανών να τελειώσουν τις μεροληπτικές 
πρακτικές επιτάχυνε μετά από τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο ΙΙ. Το 
1948, LULAC και το πρόσφατα διαμορφωμένο αμερικανικό G.I. 
φόρουμ, μια ομάδα υπεράσπισης μεξικάνικων αμερικανικών 
παλαιμάχων, βοήθησε σε μια δίκη. Το ομοσπονδιακό 
περιφερειακό δικαστήριο που διατάζει σε εκείνη την υπόθεση 
απαγόρευσε το σχολικό διαχωρισμό βασισμένο στη μεξικάνικη 
καταγωγή. Οι τοποθεσίες επινόησαν τους τρόπους να η 
απόφαση, εντούτοις, και ο de facto διαχωρισμός συνεχίστηκε. 
Οι διαμαρτυρίες σπουδαστών προς το τέλος της δεκαετίας του 
'60 επέτυχαν ένα τέλος σε μερικές μεροληπτικές πρακτικές. 
Στα επόμενα έτη μια νέα οργάνωση αστικών δικαιωμάτων, η 
μεξικάνικη αμερικανική νομική υπεράσπιση και το εκπαιδευτικό 
Ταμείο (MALDEF), συνέχισαν την πάλη στα δικαστήρια, 
επικεντρωμένος τελικά στην εισαγωγή των δίγλωσσων και 
διπολιτιστικών προγραμμάτων στα σχολεία. Στην ακόλουθη 
συνέντευξη, οι ΕΔ Idar, που συνδέεται και με το φόρουμ και με 
MALDEF, αφορούσαν μια επιτυχή προσπάθεια σε επίπεδο βάσης στις
αρχές της δεκαετίας του '50 το desegregate ένα σχολείο χωρίς 
μια απόφαση του δικαστηρίου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Con la anexión de Tejas en 1848 en el final de la
guerra, del Tejanos -- el Texans Mexicano-Americanos de la pendiente 
mexicana -- las derechas de característica perdidas y potencia 
política en una sociedad dominada por Anglos. A través de 
prácticas discriminatorias y de fuerza violenta, Tejanos fue guardado
en el fondo de la nueva orden política y socio-cultural. A 
partir de 1900-1930, como una afluencia de inmigrantes de México vino
al norte resolver una demanda creciente para el trabajo barato en las 
industrias comerciales de la agricultura que se convertían, Tejanos 
experimentó la discriminación continuada en el empleo, la cubierta, 
los recursos públicos, el sistema judicial, e instituciones 
educativas. Mucho la escuela Tejano segregado los districtos y 
los niños anglo en recursos separados con las escuelas mexicanas 
underfunded grueso y a menudo ofreciendo solamente una educación de 
la escuela del grado. En 1930, cuando los 90% de las escuelas en
Tejas del sur fueron segregados, la liga de los ciudadanos americanos 
latinos unidos (LULAC), un grupo de la defensa de Tejano ordenó el 
año anterior, utilizado el primer desafío principal de la corte en 
Tejas para terminar la segregación de la escuela. El tribunal 
de apelación de Tejas, sin embargo, gobernó que los districtos de la
escuela podrían utilizar los criterios tales como el lenguaje y la 
atención irregular  debido al trabajo estacional separar a niños en 
escuela. La lucha de los americanos mexicanos para terminar 
prácticas discriminatorias aceleró la Segunda Guerra Mundial 
siguiente. En 1948, LULAC y el G.I. americano nuevamente formado
Forum, un grupo de la defensa de veteranos americanos mexicanos, 
asistido a un pleito. La corte de districto federal que 
gobernaba en ese caso prohibió la segregación de la escuela basada 
en ascendencia mexicana. Los lugares idearon maneras de evadir 
la decisión, sin embargo, y la segregación de hecho continuó. 
Las protestas del estudiante en los últimos años 60 alcanzaron
un extremo a algunas prácticas discriminatorias. En años 
subsecuentes una nueva organización de las derechas civiles, la 
defensa legal americana mexicana y el fondo educativo (MALDEF), 
continuaron la lucha en las cortes, concentrándose eventual en la 
introducción de programas bilingües y biculturales en escuelas. 
En la entrevista siguiente, el Ed Idar, se asoció al foro y a 
MALDEF, relacionados un esfuerzo acertado de los pueblos en los 
comienzos de los años 50 con el desegregate una escuela sin una 
decisión de la corte.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087374</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104813</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/all-we-are-seeking-here-is-equal-opportunity-the-american-g-i-forum-desegregates-a-texas-communitys-schools</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
