<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106402</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106402</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209926</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Area of a circle segment</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bereich eines Kreissegments</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Zone d'un segment de cercle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Área de um segmento do círculo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Zona di un segmento del cerchio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τομέας ενός τμήματος μνήμης κύκλων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Área de un segmento del círculo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate the area of a segment of a circle - a part of a circle cut off by a chord. The applet shows a circle and a segment of that circle, the ends of which can be dragged to resize the segment. As you drag the endpoints, the area is continuously recalculated. The calculation can be turned off for class discussions. The web page has the formula for the area. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die den Bereich eines Segments eines Kreises - ein Teil 
eines Kreises zeigen, schnitten durch einen Akkord ab. Der 
applet zeigt einen Kreis und ein Segment dieses Kreises, deren Enden 
geschleppt werden können, um das Segment die Größe neu zu 
bestimmen. Da Sie die Endpunkte schleppen, wird der Bereich 
ununterbrochen nachgerechnet. Die Berechnung kann für Kategorie
Diskussionen abgestellt werden. Die Webseite hat die Formel für
den Bereich. Applet kann zum vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit
einem Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. Nachgebrauch 
im Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von jedem möglichem web 
browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den benötigten LOGON 
wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Bestandteil des 
Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent la zone d'un segment d'un cercle - une partie d'un 
cercle ont découpé par une corde. L'applet montre un cercle et
un segment de ce cercle, dont les fins peuvent être traînées pour 
remettre à la côte le segment. Car vous traînez les points 
finaux, la zone est sans interruption recalculée. Le calcul 
peut être arrêté pour des discussions de classe. La 
page Web a la formule pour la zone. L'applet peut être 
agrandi à la taille de plein écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur 
de salle de classe. Le après utilisation dans la salle de 
classe, étudiant peut lui accéder encore de n'importe quel 
navigateur de Web à la maison ou dans la bibliothèque sans la 
procédure de connexion exigée. Cette ressource est un 
composant du projet interactif de manuel de la géométrie de 
référence ouverte de maths à http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrassem a área de um segmento de um círculo - uma parte de um 
círculo cortaram fora por uma corda. O applet mostra um 
círculo e um segmento desse círculo, os fins de que podem ser 
arrastados para resize o segmento. Porque você arrasta os 
endpoints, a área recalculated continuamente. O cálculo pode 
ser desligado para discussões da classe. O Web page tem a 
fórmula para a área. O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de 
tela cheia para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. O depois 
de uso na sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo 
o web browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma 
sessão requerido. Este recurso é um componente do projeto 
interativo do textbook da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano la zona di un segmento di un cerchio - una parte di un 
cerchio hanno tagliato da una corda. Il applet mostra un cerchio
e un segmento di quel cerchio, le conclusioni di cui possono essere 
trascinate per ridimensionare il segmento. Poichè trascinate i 
punti finali, la zona è ricalcolata continuamente. Il calcolo 
può essere spento per le discussioni del codice categoria. Il 
Web page ha la formula per la zona. Il applet può essere 
ingrandito al formato di schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore 
dell'aula. La post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può 
accederle ancora da tutto il web browser nel paese o nella libreria 
senza l'inizio attività richiesto. Questa risorsa è un 
componente del progetto interattivo del manuale della geometria di 
riferimento aperto di per la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν τον τομέα ενός τμήματος μνήμης ενός κύκλου - ένα
μέρος ενός κύκλου που κόβεται από μια χορδή. Το applet 
εμφανίζει έναν κύκλο και ένα τμήμα μνήμης εκείνου του κύκλου, 
οι άκρες του οποίου μπορούν να σέρθούν για να επαναταξινομήσουν 
το τμήμα μνήμης. Δεδομένου ότι σέρνετε τα σημεία τέλους, 
η περιοχή υπολογίζεται εκ νέου συνεχώς. Ο υπολογισμός 
μπορεί να κλειθεί για τις συζητήσεις κλάσης. Ιστοσελίδας 
έχει τον τύπο για την περιοχή. Το Applet μπορεί να 
διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με έναν 
προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο 
σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε 
ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια 
εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς 
είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος εγχειριδίων 
γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran el área de un segmento de un círculo - una parte de un 
círculo cortaron por un acorde. El applet muestra un círculo y
un segmento de ese círculo, los finales de el cual se pueden 
arrastrar para volver a clasificar según el tamaño el segmento. 
Pues usted arrastra las puntos finales, el área se recalcula 
continuamente. El cálculo se puede dar vuelta apagado para las 
discusiones de la clase. El Web page tiene el fórmula para el 
área. El applet se puede agrandar a la talla de la pantalla 
completa para el uso con un proyector de la sala de clase. El 
uso posterior en la sala de clase, estudiante puede tenerle acceso 
otra vez de cualquier web browser en el país o en la biblioteca sin 
la conexión requerida. Este recurso es un componente del 
proyecto interactivo del libro de textos de la geometría de la 
referencia abierta de la matemáticas en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209926</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106402</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/area-of-a-circle-segment</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
