<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104719</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104719</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086328</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Inauguration.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Einweihung.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Inauguration.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Inauguration.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Inaugurazione.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εγκαινίαση.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Inauguración.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Huey Long, a senator and former governor of Louisiana, while initially a supporter of President Franklin D. Roosevelt, became one of the most important critics of the New Deal during the Great Depression. To curb the power of the rich, Long proposed the Share Our Wealth Plan" that would redistribute wealth from large fortunes to the needy and enable the government to provide every family with "enough for a home</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Huey sehnen sich, ein Senator und ehemaliger Regler von 
Louisiana, während zuerst ein Verfechter des Präsidenten Franklin D.
Roosevelt, wurde einer der wichtigsten Kritiker des neuen Abkommens 
während des großen Tiefstands. Die Energie vom reichen 
bändigen, den Anteil lang vorgeschlagen unser Fülle-Plan ", dem 
Fülle von den großen Vermögenn zum bedürftigen neuverteilen und 
die Regierung aktivieren würde, jeder Familie mit" genug für ein 
Haus zu versorgen</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Huey désirent ardemment, un sénateur et l'ancien 
gouverneur de la Louisiane, alors qu'au commencement un défenseur du 
Président Franklin D. Roosevelt, est devenu l'un des critiques les 
plus importants de la nouvelle affaire pendant la grande dépression. 
Pour limiter la puissance du riche, longtemps proposée la part 
notre plan de richesse "lequel redistribuerait la richesse de grandes 
fortunes à l'indigent et permettrait au gouvernement de fournir à 
chaque famille assez" pour une maison</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Huey long, um senator e o regulador anterior de Louisiana,
quando inicialmente um supporter do presidente Franklin D. Roosevelt, 
transformou-se um dos críticos os mais importantes do negócio novo 
durante o depression grande. Para curb a potência do rico, 
proposta por muito tempo a parte nossa planta da riqueza "que 
redistribute a riqueza das fortunas grandes ao needy e permitiria o 
governo de fornecer cada família com" bastante para uma HOME</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Huey desidera, un senatore ed il regolatore precedente 
della Luisiana, mentre inizialmente un sostenitore del presidente 
Franklin D. Roosevelt, si è transformato in in uno dei critici più 
importanti di nuovo affare durante la depressione grande. Per 
porre freno l'potenza del ricco, lungamente proposta la parte il 
nostro programma di ricchezza "che ridistribuirebbe la ricchezza dalle
grandi fortune al needy e permetterebbe al governo di fornire ad ogni 
famiglia con" abbastanza per una sede</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Huey μακρύ, ένας γερουσιαστής και ένας 
προηγούμενος κυβερνήτης της Λουιζιάνας, ενώ αρχικά ένας 
υποστηρικτής του Προέδρου Franklin D. Roosevelt, έγινε 
ένας από τους σημαντικότερους κριτικούς της νέας διαπραγμάτευσης
κατά τη διάρκεια της μεγάλης οικονομικής κρίσης. Για να 
συγκρατήσει τη δύναμη του πλούσιου, πρότεινε πολύ το μερίδιο το 
σχέδιο πλούτου μας "που θα ανακατένεμε τον πλούτο από τις 
μεγάλες τύχες στις ενδεείς και θα επέτρεπε στην κυβέρνηση για να 
παρέχει σε κάθε οικογένεια" αρκετά για ένα σπίτι</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Huey desea, un senador y el gobernador anterior de 
Luisiana, mientras que inicialmente un partidario de presidente 
Franklin D. Roosevelt, se convirtió en uno de los críticos más 
importantes del nuevo reparto durante la gran depresión. Para 
contener la potencia del rico, propuesta de largo la parte nuestro 
plan de la abundancia "con el cual redistribuiría abundancia de 
fortunas grandes al needy y permitiría al gobierno proporcionar a 
cada familia" bastante para un hogar</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086328</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104719</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/inauguration</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
