<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103352</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103352</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087110</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"This Is the Pressure That They Used": Genora Dollinger Recalls the Flint Sit-Down Strike</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"dieses ist der Druck, den sie" verwendeten: 
Genora Dollinger Rückrufe der Feuerstein Sitzen-Unten Schlag</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"c'est la pression qu'elles ont utilisée" : 
Les rappels de Genora Dollinger le silex Reposent-Vers le bas la
grève</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"esta é a pressão que usaram": As 
recordações de Genora Dollinger o flint Sentam-Para baixo a batida</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"questa è la pressione che hanno usato": I 
richiami di Genora Dollinger il silice Siedono -Giù il colpo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Αυτό είναι η πίεση που χρησιμοποίησαν": Το 
Genora Dollinger θυμάται ότι η τσακμακόπετρα 
κάθομαι-κατεβάζει την απεργία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"ésta es la presión que utilizaron": 
Memorias de Genora Dollinger el pedernal Sientan -Abajo huelga</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Strikes affect an entire community, and in the end they need that community's support to succeed. This is especially true in the case of a sit-down strike like the legendary sit-down strike at Flint, Michigan, in 1936, when the strikers occupied the GM plants. The strikers, isolated at first inside the Fisher Body Plant Number One, needed food; they also needed information and advance warning on what management might be up to. The Women's Emergency Brigade, formed during the Flint strike, proved indispensable to the union effort more than once. Genora Johnson Dollinger helped found the Women's Emergency Brigade and became one of the strike's key leaders. In this interview, conducted by historian Sherna Gluck in 1976, Genora Johnson Dollinger described first how the strike affected her family.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Schläge beeinflussen eine gesamte Gemeinschaft, 
und im Ende müssen sie daß Support der Gemeinschaft folgen. 
Dieses ist im Fall von einem sit-down Schlag wie dem legendären
sit-down Schlag am Feuerstein, Michigan, 1936 besonders zutreffend, 
als die Schlaggeräte die GR. Betriebe besetzten. Die 
Schlaggeräte, am ersten Innere den Fischer-Körper-Betrieb Nr. eine 
lokalisiert, benötigten Nahrung; bis zu sie auch benötigten 
Informationen und VorcWarning auf, was Management sein konnte. 
Die Brigade Dringlichkeit der Frauen, gebildet während des 
Feuersteinschlages, prüfte Indispensable zur Anschlußbemühung mehr 
als einmal. Genora Johnson geholfenes Dollinger fand die Brigade
Dringlichkeit der Frauen und wurde einer der Schlüsselführer des 
Schlages. In diesem Interview geleitet mit Historiker Sherna 
Gluck 1976, Genora Johnson Dollinger beschrieb zuerst, wie der Schlag 
ihre Familie beeinflußte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les grèves affectent une communauté entière, et
à la fin elles doivent que le soutien du de la Communauté réussir. 
C'est particulièrement vrai dans le cas d'une grève sur le tas
comme la grève sur le tas légendaire au silex, Michigan, en 1936, 
quand les butées ont occupé les usines de GM. Les butées, 
d'isolement au premier intérieur la usine le numéro un de corps de 
Fisher, ont eu besoin de nourriture ; elles ont également eu 
besoin de l'information et de l'avertissement anticipé sur jusqu'à 
ce que la gestion pourrait être. La brigade du secours des 
femmes, formée pendant la grève de silex, a prouvé le nécessaire 
à l'effort des syndicats plus de par le passé. Genora 
Johnson Dollinger aidé a trouvé la brigade du secours des femmes 
et est devenu l'une des amorces principales de la grève. Dans 
cette entrevue, conduite par l'historien Sherna Gluck en 1976, Genora 
Johnson Dollinger a décrit d'abord comment la grève a affecté sa
famille.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As batidas afetam uma comunidade inteira, e na 
extremidade necessitam que sustentação da comunidade suceder. 
Isto é especial verdadeiro no exemplo de uma batida sit-down 
como a batida sit-down legendária no flint, Michigan, em 1936, quando
os grevistas ocuparam as plantas do GM. Os grevistas, isolados 
no primeiro interior a planta número um do corpo do fisher, 
necessitaram o alimento; necessitaram também a informação e o
aviso avançado em o que a gerência pôde ser até. O brigade 
da emergência das mulheres, dado forma durante a batida do flint, 
provou o indispensable ao esforço da união mais de uma vez. 
Genora Johnson Dollinger ajudado encontrou o brigade da 
emergência das mulheres e transformou-se um dos líderes chaves da 
batida. Nesta entrevista, conduzida pelo historian Sherna Gluck 
em 1976, Genora Johnson Dollinger descreveu primeiramente como a 
batida afetou sua família.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I colpi interessano un'intera Comunità ed alla 
fine devono che supporto della Comunità riuscire. Ciò è 
particolarmente allineare nel caso di un colpo sit-down come il colpo 
sit-down leggendario a silice, Michigan, in 1936, quando i percussori 
hanno occupato le piante di GM. I percussori, isolati alla prima
parte interna la pianta il numero uno del corpo del pescatore, hanno 
avuto bisogno dell'alimento; egualmente hanno avuto bisogno 
delle informazioni e dell'avvertimento di avanzamento su che cosa la 
gestione potrebbe spettare. La brigata di emergenza delle donne,
formata durante il colpo del silice, ha dimostrato più di una volta 
il indispensable allo sforzo del sindacato. Genora Johnson 
Dollinger aiutato ha trovato la brigata di emergenza delle donne e si 
è transformato in in uno dei capi chiave del colpo. In 
questa intervista, condotta dallo storico Sherna Gluck in 1976, Genora
Johnson Dollinger ha descritto in primo luogo come il colpo ha 
interessato la sua famiglia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι απεργίες έχουν επιπτώσεις σε μια ολόκληρη 
κοινότητα, και στο τέλος χρειάζονται εκείνη την ενίσχυση της 
Κοινότητας για να πετύχουν. Αυτό ισχύει ιδιαίτερα στην 
περίπτωση μιας κάθομαι-κάτω απεργίας όπως τη θρυλική 
κάθομαι-κάτω απεργία στην τσακμακόπετρα, Μίτσιγκαν, το 1936, 
όταν κατέλαβαν οι απεργοί τις εγκαταστάσεις της GM. Οι 
απεργοί, που απομονώθηκαν πρώτα μέσα στις εγκαταστάσεις αριθμός 
ένα σώματος ψαράδων, χρειάστηκαν τα τρόφιμα  χρειάστηκαν 
επίσης την προειδοποίηση πληροφοριών και προόδου σε ποια 
διαχείριση να είναι μέχρι. Η ταξιαρχία έκτακτης ανάγκης 
των γυναικών, που διαμορφώθηκε κατά τη διάρκεια της απεργίας 
τσακμακόπετρας, αποδείχθηκε αναπόφευκτη στην προσπάθεια ένωσης 
περισσότερο από μία φορά. Το Genora Johnson 
Dollinger που ενισχύθηκε να βρεί την ταξιαρχία έκτακτης 
ανάγκης των γυναικών και έγινε ένας από τους βασικούς ηγέτες 
της απεργίας. Σε αυτήν την συνέντευξη, που πραγματοποιήθηκε 
από τον ιστορικό Sherna Gluck το 1976, Genora Johnson
Dollinger περιέγραψε πρώτα πώς η απεργία είχε επιπτώσεις στην
οικογένειά της.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las huelgas afectan a comunidad entera, y en el 
extremo necesitan que la ayuda de la comunidad tener éxito. 
Esto es especialmente verdad en el caso de una huelga sit-down 
como la huelga sit-down legendaria en el pedernal, Michigan, en 1936, 
cuando los huelguistas ocuparon las plantas del GM. Los 
huelguistas, aislados en el primer interior la planta número uno del 
cuerpo del pescador, necesitaron el alimento; también 
necesitaron la información y la alerta anticipada en hasta lo que 
pudo estar la gerencia. La brigada de la emergencia de las 
mujeres, formada durante la huelga del pedernal, probó la 
indispensable al esfuerzo de la unión más de una vez. Genora 
Johnson Dollinger ayudado encontró a brigada de la emergencia de las 
mujeres y se convirtió en uno de los arranques de cinta dominantes de
la huelga. En esta entrevista, conducida por el historiador 
Sherna Gluck en 1976, Genora Johnson Dollinger describió primero 
cómo la huelga afectó a su familia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087110</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103352</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/this-is-the-pressure-that-they-used-genora-dollinger-recalls-the-flint-sit-down-strike</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
