<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106347</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106347</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200944</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Collaboration via Slime Mold</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zusammenarbeit über Schlamm-Form</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Collaboration par l'intermédiaire de moule de 
boue</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Colaboração através do molde do slime</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Collaborazione via la muffa della melma</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Συνεργασία μέσω slime της φόρμας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Colaboración vía molde del limo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This hands-on activity gives students the opportunity to use skills and concepts developed in a unit on cells with an unknown organism. They are asked to design and complete a controlled experiment which attempts to answer a simple question about the slime mold Physarum. The activity includes background information, preparation time, abstract, materials, procedure, evaluation, and additional thoughts. The activity is part of The Access Excellence Fellows Collection, an archive of the favorite classroom activities submitted by high school biology and life sciences teachers participating in the Access Excellence program.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Blindeinschub Aktivität gibt 
Kursteilnehmern die Gelegenheit, die Fähigkeiten und Konzepte zu 
verwenden, die in einer Maßeinheit auf Zellen mit einem unbekannten 
Organismus entwickelt werden. Sie werden gebeten, ein 
kontrolliertes Experiment zu konzipieren und durchzuführen, welche 
Versuche, eine einfache Frage über die Schlammform Physarum zu 
beantworten. Die Aktivität schließt Hintergrundinformationen, 
Vorbereitung Zeit, Auszug, Materialien, Prozedur, Auswertung und 
zusätzliche Gedanken ein. Die Aktivität ist ein Teil der 
Zugriff hervorragende Leistung Mitansammlung, ein Archiv der 
Lieblingsklassenzimmeraktivitäten, die von den High School Biologie- 
und Lebenwissenschaftslehrern eingegeben werden, die am Zugriff 
hervorragende Leistung Programm teilnehmen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette activité à commande manuelle donne à des 
étudiants l'occasion d'utiliser des qualifications et des concepts 
développés dans une unité sur des cellules avec une organization 
inconnue. Ils sont invités à concevoir et terminer une 
expérience commandée quelles tentatives de répondre à une question
simple au sujet du moule Physarum de boue. L'activité inclut 
l'information de fond, le temps de préparation, l'abstrait, les 
matériaux, le procédé, l'évaluation, et les pensées 
supplémentaires. L'activité fait partie de la collection de 
camarades d'excellence d'accès, des archives des activités 
préférées de salle de classe soumises par des professeurs de 
biologie de lycée et de sciences de vie participant au programme 
d'excellence d'accès.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta atividade hands-on dá a estudantes a 
oportunidade de usar as habilidades e os conceitos desenvolvidos em 
uma unidade em pilhas com um organismo desconhecido. São 
pedidos para projetar e terminar uma experiência controlada que 
tentativas de responder a uma pergunta simples sobre o molde Physarum 
do slime. A atividade inclui a informação de fundo, o tempo da
preparação, o sumário, os materiais, o procedimento, a avaliação,
e pensamentos adicionais. A atividade é parte da coleção dos 
companheiros do excellence do acesso, um arquivo das atividades 
favoritas da sala de aula submetidas pelos professores da biologia da 
High School e das ciências de vida que participam no programa do 
excellence do acesso.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa attività hands-on dà ad allievi 
l'occasione usare le abilità ed i concetti sviluppati in un'unità 
sulle cellule con un organismo sconosciuto. Sono chiesti di 
progettare e completare un esperimento controllato quali tentativi di 
rispondere ad una domanda semplice circa la muffa Physarum della 
melma. L'attività include le informazioni di base, il tempo 
della preparazione, l'estratto, i materiali, la procedura, la 
valutazione ed i pensieri supplementari. L'attività fa parte 
dell'accumulazione dei colleghe di merito di accesso, un archivio 
delle attività favorite dell'aula presentate dagli insegnanti di 
biologia della High School e di scienze biologiche che partecipano al 
programma di merito di accesso.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η εμπράγματη δραστηριότητα δίνει στους 
σπουδαστές την ευκαιρία να χρησιμοποιήσει τις δεξιότητες και τις 
έννοιες που αναπτύσσονται σε μια μονάδα στα κύτταρα με έναν 
άγνωστο οργανισμό. Καλούνται να σχεδιάσουν και να 
ολοκληρώσουν ένα ελεγχόμενο πείραμα που προσπαθεί να απαντήσει 
σε μια απλή ερώτηση για τη slime φόρμα Physarum. Η 
δραστηριότητα περιλαμβάνει τις βασικές πληροφορίες, το χρόνο 
προετοιμασιών, την περίληψη, τα υλικά, τη διαδικασία, την 
αξιολόγηση, και τις πρόσθετες σκέψεις. Η δραστηριότητα 
είναι μέρος της συλλογής συνεργατών τελειότητας πρόσβασης, ένα 
αρχείο των αγαπημένων δραστηριοτήτων τάξεων που υποβάλλονται από
τους δασκάλους της βιολογίας γυμνασίου και βιολογικών επιστημών 
που συμμετέχουν στο πρόγραμμα τελειότητας πρόσβασης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta actividad con manos da a estudiantes la 
oportunidad de utilizar las habilidades y los conceptos desarrollados 
en una unidad en las células con un organismo desconocido. Les 
piden diseñar y terminar un experimento controlado qué tentativas de
contestar a una pregunta simple sobre el molde Physarum del limo. 
La actividad incluye la información de fondo, el tiempo de la 
preparación, el extracto, los materiales, procedimiento, la 
evaluación, y pensamientos adicionales. La actividad es parte 
de la colección de los compañeros de la excelencia del acceso, un 
archivo de las actividades preferidas de la sala de clase sometidas 
por los profesores de la biología de la High School secundaria y de 
las ciencias de vida que participan en el programa de la excelencia 
del acceso.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PEGGY SKINNER
FN:PEGGY SKINNER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ACCESS EXCELLENCE
FN:ACCESS EXCELLENCE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200944</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106347</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/collaboration-via-slime-mold</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
