<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107564</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107564</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209881</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Linear Pair of Angles</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lineares Paar Winkel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Paire linéaire d'angles</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Par linear dos ângulos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Accoppiamento lineare degli angoli</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γραμμικό ζευγάρι των γωνιών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Par linear de ángulos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate a linear pair of angles. A pair of angles are shown and the user can drag the common side. It demonstrates that they a supplementary (add to 180 degrees) and have a common side. The angle measures can be turned off for class discussion. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die ein lineares Paar Winkel zeigen. Ein Paar Winkel 
werden gezeigt und der Benutzer kann die geläufige Seite schleppen. 
Sie zeigt daß sie ein Ergänzungs (fügen Sie 180 Grad) hinzu 
und hat eine geläufige Seite. Die Winkelmasse können für 
Kategorie Diskussion abgestellt werden. Applet kann zum vollen 
Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert
werden. Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf 
es von jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek 
ohne den benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel 
ist ein Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven 
Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent une paire linéaire d'angles. Une paire d'angles
sont montrées et l'utilisateur peut traîner le côté commun. 
Il démontre qu'ils un supplémentaire (ajoutez à 180 degrés) 
et a un côté commun. Les mesures d'angle peuvent être 
arrêtées pour la discussion de classe. L'applet peut être 
agrandi à la taille de plein écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur 
de salle de classe. Le après utilisation dans la salle de 
classe, étudiant peut lui accéder encore de n'importe quel 
navigateur de Web à la maison ou dans la bibliothèque sans la 
procédure de connexion exigée. Cette ressource est un 
composant du projet interactif de manuel de la géométrie de 
référence ouverte de maths à http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem um par linear dos ângulos. Um par dos ângulos é 
mostrado e o usuário pode arrastar o lado comum. Demonstra que 
eles um suplementar (adicione a 180 graus) e tem um lado comum. 
As medidas do ângulo podem ser desligadas para a discussão da 
classe. O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de tela cheia para
o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. O depois de uso na sala 
de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo o web browser 
na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma sessão requerido. 
Este recurso é um componente do projeto interativo do textbook 
da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano un accoppiamento lineare degli angoli. Un 
accoppiamento degli angoli è indicato e l'utente può trascinare il 
lato comune. Dimostra che un supplementare (aggiunga a 180 
gradi) ed ha un lato comune. Le misure di angolo possono essere 
spente per la discussione del codice categoria. Il applet può 
essere ingrandito al formato di schermo pieno per uso con un 
proiettore dell'aula. La post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo 
può accederle ancora da tutto il web browser nel paese o nella 
libreria senza l'inizio attività richiesto. Questa risorsa è 
un componente del progetto interattivo del manuale della geometria di 
riferimento aperto di per la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν ένα γραμμικό ζευγάρι των γωνιών. Ένα 
ζευγάρι των γωνιών εμφανίζεται και ο χρήστης μπορεί να σέρει την
κοινή πλευρά. Καταδεικνύει ότι ένας συμπληρωματικός 
(προσθέστε σε 180 βαθμούς) και έχουν μια κοινή πλευρά. 
Τα μέτρα γωνίας μπορούν να κλειθούν για τη συζήτηση 
κλάσης. Το Applet μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες 
μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με έναν προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά
από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε
τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη 
βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το
στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού 
προγράμματος εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού 
σε http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran un par linear de ángulos. Un par de ángulos se 
muestra y el utilizador puede arrastrar la cara común. 
Demuestra que ellos un suplementario (agregue a 180 grados) y 
tiene una cara común. Las medidas del ángulo se pueden dar 
vuelta apagado para la discusión de la clase. El applet se 
puede agrandar a la talla de la pantalla completa para el uso con un 
proyector de la sala de clase. El uso posterior en la sala de 
clase, estudiante puede tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier web 
browser en el país o en la biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. 
Este recurso es un componente del proyecto interactivo del libro
de textos de la geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas
en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209881</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107564</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/linear-pair-of-angles</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
