<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105084</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105084</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087039</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The 'Right' To Sell" vs. "The Sanctuary of Christian Homes": Proposed Legislation to Limit Liquor Advertising</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"das ' rechte ', zum gegen zu verkaufen". 
"das Schongebiet der christlichen Häuser": Vorgeschlagene
Gesetzgebung zum Begrenzen das Alkohol-Bekanntmachen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"le 'droit 'à vendre" contre. "le sanctuaire
des maisons chrétiennes" : Législation proposée pour limiter 
la publicité de boisson alcoolisée</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"' o direito ' a vender" contra. "o sanctuary
de HOME christian": Legislação proposta para limitar anunciar 
do licor</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"'il di destra 'da vendere" contro. "il 
santuario delle sedi cristiane": Legislazione proposta per 
limitare pubblicità del liquore</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"" Ο σωστός "να πωλήσει" εναντίον. "Το άδυτο των
χριστιανικών"Οικιαών ": Προτεινόμενη νομοθεσία για να 
περιορίσει τη διαφήμιση ποτού</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"el ' derecho ' a vender" contra. "el 
santuario de hogares cristianos": Legislación propuesta para 
limitar la publicidad del licor</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Organized temperance movements have been part of the American political landscape since the early 19th century. Reform groups, dominated at various times by clergy, social elites, workingmen, and clubwomen, tried alternately to convince individuals to take a pledge against drinking alcohol, to promote drinking only in moderation, and to enact laws prohibiting the production and sale of liquor. Prior to the ratification in 1919 of the 18th Amendment banning liquor nationwide, two-thirds of the states had passed similar legislation. After rampant noncompliance with the Amendment led to its repeal in 1933, anti-liquor advocates focused protests against liquor advertising on the radio. While the Federal Communications Commission did not have the authority to ban liquor ads, their threats to hold license renewal hearings for offending stations induced broadcasters to self-impose a ban. Similarly, in 1948, the television industry voluntarily decided to restrict alcoholic beverage advertising to beer and wine commercials. Congress, nevertheless, proposed legislation in the 1950s to prohibit all liquor ads from radio, TV, and in interstate commerce. In the following testimony, an attorney for an advertising association argued that a proposed House bill would interfere with the "right to sell," while a police sergeant and member of the Woman's Christian Temperance Union contended in a Senate hearing that children should be protected from televised liquor ads in their homes. No legislation was enacted, and in November 1996 due to a sharp decrease in sales of hard liquor, the Distilled Spirits Council voted to allow advertising of its products on TV. In December 2001, NBC became the first network since 1948 to broadcast hard liquor ads.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Organisierte temperance Bewegungen sind ein Teil 
der amerikanischen politischen Landschaft seit dem frühen 19. 
Jahrhundert gewesen. Verbessern Sie die Gruppen, beherrscht zu 
den verschiedenen Zeiten vom Klerus, die Sozialauslesen, Workingmen, 
und clubwomen, wechselnd versucht, Einzelpersonen zu überzeugen, 
versprochene gegen trinkenden Spiritus zu nehmen, nur, in der Mäßigung
zu trinken zu fördern, und die Gesetze zu verordnen, welche die 
Produktion und den Verkauf des Alkohols verbieten. Vor der 
Bestätigung 1919 der 18. Änderung, die im ganzen Land Alkohol 
verbietet, hatten zweidrittel der Zustände ähnliche Gesetzgebung 
geführt. Nachdem zügellose Zuwiderhandlung mit der Änderung 
zu seinen Repeal 1933 führte, richteten Anti-Alkohol Fürsprecher 
Proteste gegen den Alkohol, der auf den Radio bekanntmacht. 
Während die Bundeskommunikationen Kommission nicht die 
Berechtigung hatte, zum des Alkohols ADS zu verbieten, verursachen 
ihre Drohungen, zum der Lizenzerneuerunghörfähigkeiten für 
beleidigende Stationen anzuhalten Rundfunksprecher, ein Verbot 
Selbst-aufzuerlegen. Ähnlich 1948, entschied die 
Fernsehenindustrie freiwillig, das alkoholische Getränk 
einzuschränken, das zu den Bier- und Weinwerbungen bekanntmacht. 
Kongreß schlug dennoch Gesetzgebung in den fünfziger Jahren 
vor, um allen Alkohol ADS vom Radio, Fernsehapparat zu verbieten und 
im landesweiten Handel. Im folgenden Zeugnis argumentierte ein 
Rechtsanwalt für eine bekanntmachende Verbindung, daß eine 
vorgeschlagene Hausrechnung das "rechte behinderen würde, zum zu 
verkaufen,", während ein PolizeiSergeant und Bauteil des 
christlichen Anschlußes Temperance der Frau in einer 
Senathörfähigkeit rang, daß Kinder vor im Fernsehen übertragenem 
Alkohol ADS in ihren Häusern geschützt werden sollten. Keine 
Gesetzgebung wurde verordnet, und im November 1996 wegen einer 
scharfen Abnahme an den Verkäufen des harten Alkohols, der 
destillierte Geist-Rat, der gewählt wurde, um das Bekanntmachen 
seiner Produkte auf Fernsehapparat zu erlauben. Im Dezember 
2001, wurde NBC das erste Netz seit 1948, zum des harten Alkohols ADS 
zu übertragen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les mouvements organisés de modération ont fait 
partie de l'horizontal politique américain depuis le 19ème siècle 
tôt. Reformez les groupes, dominés à de diverses heures par 
le clergé, les élites sociales, ouvriers, et clubwomen, essayé 
alternativement de convaincre des individus de prendre un engagement 
contre l'alcool potable, de le favoriser boire seulement dans la 
modération, et de décréter des lois interdisant la production et la
vente de la boisson alcoolisée. Avant la ratification dans 1919
du 18ème amendement interdisant la boisson alcoolisée dans tout le 
pays, deux-tiers des états avait passé la législation semblable. 
Après que l'insoumission effrénée avec la modification ait 
mené à son abrogation en 1933, les avocats d'anti-boisson 
alcoolisée ont concentré des protestations contre la boisson 
alcoolisée annonçant sur la radio. Tandis que la Commission 
fédérale de transmissions n'avait pas l'autorité pour interdire la 
boisson alcoolisée ADS, leurs menaces pour tenir des auditions de 
renouvellement de permis pour les stations offensantes induisent des 
radiodiffuseurs à art de l'auto-portrait-impose une interdiction. De même, 
en 1948, l'industrie de télévision a volontairement décidé de 
limiter la boisson alcoolique annonçant aux films publicitaires de 
bière et de vin. Le congrès, néanmoins, a proposé la 
législation dans les années 50 pour interdire toute la boisson 
alcoolisée ADS de la radio, TV, et dans le commerce entre Etats. 
Dans le témoignage suivant, un mandataire pour une association 
de publicité a argué du fait qu'une facture proposée de Chambre 
gênerait le "droit à vendre," tandis qu'un sergent de police et 
le membre de l'union chrétienne de la Modération de la femme 
contestait dans une audition de sénat que des enfants devraient être
protégés contre la boisson alcoolisée télévisée ADS dans leurs 
maisons. Aucune législation n'a été décrétée, et en 
novembre 1996 dû à une diminution marquée des ventes de la boisson 
alcoolisée dure, le Conseil distillé de spiritueux voté pour 
permettre la publicité de ses produits sur la TV. En décembre 
2001, le NBC est devenu le premier réseau depuis 1948 pour annoncer 
la boisson alcoolisée dure ADS.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os movimentos organizados do temperance foram parte
da paisagem política americana desde o 1ø século adiantado. 
Reforme os grupos, dominados em várias horas pelo clergy, 
elites sociais, workingmen, e clubwomen, tentado alternadamente 
convencer indivíduos fazer exame de um pledge de encontro ao álcool 
bebendo, promovê-lo beber somente no moderation, e decretar as leis 
que proíbem a produção e a venda do licor. Antes do 
ratification em 1919 da 1å emenda que proíbe o licor por todo o 
país, dois terços dos estados tinham passado a legislação similar.
Depois que o noncompliance rampant com a emenda conduziu a seu 
repeal em 1933, os advogados do anti-licor focalizaram protestos de 
encontro ao licor que anuncia no rádio. Quando o commission 
federal das comunicações não teve a autoridade para proibir o licor
ads, suas ameaças para prender hearings da renovação da licença 
para estações offending induzem radiodifusores self-impo uma 
proibição. Similarmente, em 1948, a indústria da televisão 
decidiu-se voluntàriamente restringir a bebida alcoólica que anuncia
aos comerciais da cerveja e do vinho. O congress, não obstante,
propôs a legislação nos 1950s proibir todo o licor ads do rádio, 
tevê, e no comércio interstate. No seguinte testimony, um 
advogado para uma associação anunciando discutiu que uma conta 
proposta da casa interferiria com o "direito a vender," quando 
polícias sergeant e o membro da união christian de Temperance da 
mulher contended em um hearing do senate que as crianças devem ser 
protegidas do licor televised ads em suas HOME. Nenhuma 
legislação foi decretada, e em novembro 1996  devido a uma 
diminuição afiada nas vendas do licor duro, conselho destilado dos 
espíritos votado para permitir anunciar de seus produtos na tevê. 
Em dezembro 2001, o NBC transformou-se a primeira rede desde 
1948 para transmitir o licor duro ads.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I movimenti organizzati di temperance hanno fatti 
parte del paesaggio politico americano dal diciannovesimo secolo in 
anticipo. Riformi i gruppi, dominati ai vari tempi da clergy, le
elite sociali, workingmen e clubwomen, provato alternatamente a 
convincere gli individui prendere un impegno contro alcool bevente, 
promuovere bere soltanto nella moderazione e promulgare le leggi che 
proibiscono la produzione e la vendita di liquore. Prima della 
ratifica in 1919 della diciottesima correzione che vieta il liquore in
tutta la nazione, due terzi del dichiara aveva passato la 
legislazione simile. Dopo che il noncompliance sfrenato con la 
correzione conduca alla relativa abrogazione in 1933, i fautori del 
anti-liquore hanno messo a fuoco le proteste contro liquore che fa 
pubblicità sulla radio. Mentre la Commissione federale di 
comunicazioni non ha avuta l'autorità per vietare il liquore ads, le 
loro minacce per tenere le udienze di rinnovamento dell'autorizzazione
per le stazioni offendenti inducono i distributori a spaglio 
auto-imporre un divieto. Similmente, in 1948, l'industria della 
televisione ha deciso volontariamente limitare la bevanda di alcoolico
che fa pubblicità agli annunci pubblicitari del vino e della birra. 
Il congresso, tuttavia, ha proposto la legislazione negli anni 
50 per proibire tutto il liquore ads dalla radio, TV e nel commercio 
da uno stato all'altro. Nella seguente testimonianza, un 
avvocato per un'associazione di pubblicità ha sostenuto che una 
fattura proposta della Camera interferirebbe con "il di destra da 
vendere," mentre polizia sergeant ed il membro dell'unione cristiana 
di Temperance della donna si è conteso in un'udienza del senato che i
bambini dovrebbero essere protetti da liquore teletrasmesso ads nelle 
loro sedi. Nessuna legislazione è stata promulgata ed in 
novembre 1996 dovuto una diminuzione marcata nelle vendite di liquore 
duro, il Consiglio distillato di alcoolici votato per permettere la 
pubblicità dei relativi prodotti sulla TV. Nel mese di dicembre
del 2001, il NBC si è transformato in nella prima rete dal 1948 per 
trasmettere per radio il liquore duro ads.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι οργανωμένες μετακινήσεις μετριοπάθειας είναι μέρος
του αμερικανικού πολιτικού τοπίου από τον πρόωρο 19$ο αιώνα. 
Οι ομάδες μεταρρύθμισης, που εξουσιάζονται στους διάφορους 
χρόνους από την ιεροσύνη, τα κοινωνικά elites, και, 
προσπάθησαν διαδοχικά να πείσουν τα άτομα για να πάρουν μια 
υποχρέωση ενάντια στην κατανάλωση του οινοπνεύματος, για να 
προωθήσουν την κατανάλωση μόνο στη μετριοπάθεια, και για να 
θεσπίσουν τους νόμους που απαγορεύουν την παραγωγή και την πώληση
του ποτού. Πριν από την επικύρωση το 1919 της 18$ης 
τροποποίησης που απαγορεύει το ποτό σε εθνικό επίπεδο, τα δύο 
τρίτα των κρατών είχαν περάσει την παρόμοια νομοθεσία. 
Αφότου οδήγησε η ασυγκράτητη μη συμμόρφωση με την 
τροποποίηση στην ανάκλησή της το 1933, το αντι-ποτό 
υποστηρίζει τις διαμαρτυρίες ενάντια στο ποτό διαφημιστικός στο 
ραδιόφωνο. Ενώ η ομοσπονδιακή Επιτροπή ανακοινώσεων δεν 
είχε την εξουσία για να απαγορεύσει τις αγγελίες ποτού, οι 
απειλές τους στη λαβή χορηγούν άδεια τις ακροάσεις ανανέωσης για
την προσβολή προκληθέντων των σταθμοί εκφωνητών για να 
μόνος-επιβάλουν μια απαγόρευση. Ομοίως, το 1948, η 
τηλεοπτική βιομηχανία αποφάσισε εθελοντικά να περιορίσει το 
οινοπνευματώδες ποτό διαφημιστικός στους αντιπροσώπους μπύρας και
κρασιού. Το συνέδριο, εντούτοις, πρότεινε τη νομοθεσία στη 
δεκαετία του '50 για να απαγορεύσει όλες τις αγγελίες ποτού από 
το ραδιόφωνο, TV, και στο διακρατικό εμπόριο. Στην 
ακόλουθη κατάθεση, ένας πληρεξούσιος για μια διαφημιστική ένωση 
υποστήριξε ότι ένας προτεινόμενος λογαριασμός σπιτιών θα 
παρεμπόδιζε "το σωστό να πωλήσει," ενώ ένας λοχίας αστυνομίας 
και ένα μέλος της χριστιανικής ένωσης μετριοπάθειας της γυναίκας
υποστήριξαν σε μια ακρόαση Συγκλήτου ότι τα παιδιά πρέπει να 
προστατευθούν από τις αγγελίες ποτού στα σπίτια τους. 
Καμία νομοθεσία δεν θεσπίστηκε, και τον Νοέμβριο του 1996
λόγω σε μια αιχμηρή μείωση στις πωλήσεις του σκληρού ποτού, το 
αποσταγμένο Συμβούλιο πνευμάτων ψήφισε να επιτρέψει τη διαφήμιση
των προϊόντων του στην TV. Τον Δεκέμβριο του 2001, 
NBC έγινε το πρώτο δίκτυο από το 1948 για να μεταδώσει 
ραδιοφωνικά τις σκληρές αγγελίες ποτού.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los movimientos ordenados del temperance han sido 
parte del paisaje político americano desde el diecinueveavo siglo 
temprano. Reforme los grupos, dominados en las varias horas por 
el clero, las élites sociales, workingmen, y clubwomen, intentado 
alternativamente convencer a individuos que tomen un compromiso contra
el alcohol que bebe, lo promuevan el beber solamente en la 
moderación, y decreten los leyes que prohíben la producción y la 
venta del licor. Antes de la ratificación en 1919 de la décimo
octava enmienda que prohibía el licor por toda la nación, dos 
tercios de los estados había aprobado la legislación similar. 
Después de que el noncompliance desenfrenado con la enmienda 
condujera a su abrogación en 1933, los abogados del contra-licor 
enfocaron protestas contra el licor que anunciaba en la radio. 
Mientras que la Comisión federal de las comunicaciones no 
tenía la autoridad para prohibir el licor ads, sus amenazas para 
llevar a cabo las audiencias de la renovación de la licencia para las
estaciones que se ofenden indujeron a locutores que uno mismo-impongan
una interdicción. Semejantemente, en 1948, la industria de la 
televisión decidía voluntariamente a restringir la bebida 
alcohólica que anunciaba a los anuncios de la cerveza y del vino. 
El congreso, sin embargo, propuso la legislación en los años 
50 para prohibir todo el licor ads de la radio, TV, y en comercio de 
un estado a otro. En el testimonio siguiente, un abogado para 
una asociación de publicidad discutió que una cuenta propuesta de la
casa interferiría con el "derecho a vender," mientras que policía 
sargento y el miembro de la unión cristiana de Temperance de la mujer
afirmó en una audiencia del senado que los niños deben ser 
protegidos contra el licor televisado ads en sus hogares. No se 
decretó ninguna legislación, y en noviembre 1996  debido a una 
disminución sostenida de ventas del licor duro, el consejo destilado 
de los alcoholes votado para permitir la publicidad de sus productos 
en la TV. En diciembre de 2001, el NBC se convirtió en la 
primera red desde 1948 para difundir el licor duro ads.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087039</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105084</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-right-to-sell-vs-the-sanctuary-of-christian-homes-proposed-legislation-to-limit-liquor-advertising</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
