<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106224</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106224</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206223</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Bridging the Watershed</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hohlraumbildung der Wasserscheide</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jeter un pont sur la ligne de partage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Construindo uma ponte sobre o watershed</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gettare un ponte sullo spartiacque</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γεφύρωμα του υδροκρίτη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Puentear la línea divisoria de las aguas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">presents online activities to assist teachers in helping students develop skills needed for field trips to Potomac Area National Parks. Activities include plant identification, macroinvertebrate identification, and Go Fish, a game that simulates the journey of fish to their spawning ground.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">die Online-Dienst der Geschenke, zum der Lehrer in
helfenden Kursteilnehmern zu unterstützen entwickeln die 
Fähigkeiten, die für benötigt werden, auffangen Reisen 
Potomac Bereich zu den Nationalparks. Aktivitäten schließen 
Betriebskennzeichen, macroinvertebrate Kennzeichen ein und gehen 
Fische, ein Spiel, das die Reise der Fische zu ihrem Entstehungsgebiet
simuliert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les activités en ligne de présents pour aider 
des professeurs dans les étudiants aidants développent des 
qualifications requises pour des voyages de zone aux parcs nationaux 
de région de Potomac. Les activités incluent l'identification 
d'usine, identification de macroinvertebrate, et vont des poissons, un
jeu qui simule le voyage des poissons à leur frayère.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">as atividades em linha dos presentes para ajudar a
professores em estudantes de ajuda desenvolvem as habilidades 
necessitadas para desengates de campo aos parques nacionais da área 
de Potomac. As atividades incluem a identificação da planta, 
identificação do macroinvertebrate, e vão peixes, um jogo que 
simule a viagem dos peixes a sua terra spawning.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">le attività in linea dei presenti per aiutare gli
insegnanti in allievi d'assistenza sviluppano le abilità state 
necessarie per i viaggi di campo ai parchi nazionali di zona di 
Potomac. Le attività includono l'identificazione della pianta, 
identificazione del macroinvertebrate e vanno pesci, un gioco che 
simula il viaggio dei pesci alla loro terra di deposizione delle uova.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρουσιάζει τις σε απευθείας σύνδεση δραστηριότητες 
για να βοηθήσει τους δασκάλους στη βοήθεια των σπουδαστών να 
αναπτυχθούν οι δεξιότητες που απαιτούνται για τα ταξίδια πεδίων 
potomac στα εθνικά πάρκα περιοχής. Οι δραστηριότητες 
περιλαμβάνουν τον προσδιορισμό εγκαταστάσεων, macroinvertebrate 
προσδιορισμός, και πηγαίνουν ψάρια, ένα παιχνίδι που μιμείται το
ταξίδι των ψαριών στο ωοτοκώντας έδαφός τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">las actividades en línea de los presentes para 
asistir a profesores en estudiantes que ayudan desarrollan las 
habilidades necesitadas para los disparos al campo a los parques 
nacionales del área de Potomac. Las actividades incluyen la 
identificación de la planta, identificación del macroinvertebrate, y
van los pescados, un juego que simule el viaje de pescados a su tierra
que spawn/genera.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206223</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106224</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/bridging-the-watershed</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
