<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103411</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103411</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086112</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Effie Bauer Turns Down Gabie Marks: Edna Ferber's "One of the Old Girls"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Effie Bauer Dreht Unten Gabie Markierungen: 
Edna Ferbers "eins der alten Mädchen"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Effie Bauer Tourne Vers le bas des Marques de 
Gabie : Une d'Edna Ferber "des vieilles filles"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Effie Bauer Gira Para baixo Marcas De Gabie: 
Uma de Edna Ferber "das meninas velhas"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Effie Bauer Gira Giù I Contrassegni Di Gabie: 
Una di Edna Ferber "delle ragazze anziane"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Effie Bauer γυρίζει κάτω τα σημάδια Gabie: 
Ένα Ferber Edna "από τα παλαιά κορίτσια"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Effie Bauer Da vuelta Abajo A las Marcas De Gabie:
Una de Edna Ferber "de las viejas muchachas"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Department stores not only became a major source of employment for young urban white women beginning in the late 19th century; they also offered a new focus for stories and novels about life in America's burgeoning cities. Writers as diverse as Theodore Dreiser, Edna Ferber, and O. Henry often used the world of department stores and the shop girls who worked there to create a modern fiction (including a brand new form--the short story) that allowed readers to feel the texture of urban life. Ferber's shop-girl heroines were strong-willed, and though they expressed vulnerability and desire for male companionship, they valued their careers. In this 1912 Ferber short story, titled "One of the Old Girls," the head of the corset department in Spiegel's department store is faced with a hard decision when her longtime swain "pops the question."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Abteilung Speicher wurden nicht nur eine 
Hauptquelle der Beschäftigung für die jungen städtischen weißen 
Frauen, die im des späten 19. jahrhunderts Jahrhundert anfangen; 
sie boten auch einen neuen Fokus für Geschichten und Romane 
über das Leben in Amerikas sprießenden Städte an. Verfasser 
so verschieden, wie Theodore Dreiser, Edna Ferber und O. Henry häufig
die Welt der Abteilung Speicher und der Systemmädchen benutzten, die 
dort arbeiteten, um eine moderne Erfindung zu erstellen 
(einschließlich nagelneues Formular -- die kurze Geschichte) die 
Lesern erlaubte, der Beschaffenheit der städtischen Lebensdauer zu 
glauben. Heldinnen Kaufenmädchen Ferbers wurden stark-gewillt, 
und obwohl sie Verwundbarkeit und Wunsch nach männlicher Begleitung 
ausdrückten, bewerteten sie ihre Karrieren. In dieser Ferber 
kurzen Geschichte 1912 betitelt "eins der alten Mädchen," wird der 
Kopf der Korsettabteilung im Speicher Abteilung Spiegels mit einer 
harten Entscheidung gegenübergestellt, wenn ihr langfristiges swain 
"knallt die Frage."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les grands magasins sont non seulement devenus une
source importante d'emploi pour de jeunes femmes blanches urbaines 
commençant vers la fin du 19ème siècle ; ils ont également 
offert un nouveau foyer pour des histoires et des romans au sujet de 
la vie dans les villes bourgeonnantes de l'Amérique. Auteurs 
aussi divers que Theodore Dreiser, Edna Ferber, et O. Henry ont 
souvent utilisé le monde des grands magasins et des filles de 
système qui ont travaillé là pour créer une fiction moderne (forme
nouvelle y compris -- l'histoire courte) qui a permis à des lecteurs 
de sentir la texture de la vie urbaine. Des héroïnes de la 
faire des emplettes-fille de Ferber fort-ont été voulues, et bien 
qu'ils aient exprimé la vulnérabilité et le désir pour la 
compagnie mâle, elles ont évalué leurs carrières. Dans cette
histoire 1912 courte de Ferber, intitulée "une des vieilles filles," 
le chef du service de corset dans le grand magasin de Spiegel est 
confronté à une décision dure quand son swain à long terme "saute 
la question."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As lojas de departamento transformaram-se não 
somente uma fonte principal do emprego para as mulheres brancas 
urbanas novas que começam no 1ø século atrasado; ofereceram 
também um foco novo para histórias e novelas sobre a vida em cidades
burgeoning de América. Escritores tão diversos como Theodore 
Dreiser, Edna Ferber, e O. Henry usaram frequentemente o mundo das 
lojas de departamento e das meninas da loja que trabalharam lá para 
criar um fiction moderno (formulário brandnew including -- a 
história curta) que permitisse que os leitores sentissem a textura da
vida urbana. Os heroines da compr-menina de Ferber forte-foram 
queridos, e embora expressaram o vulnerability e o desejo para o 
companionship masculino, avaliaram suas carreiras. Nesta 
história 1912 curta de Ferber, intitulada "uma das meninas velhas," a
cabeça do departamento do corset na loja de departamento de Spiegel 
está enfrentada com uma decisão dura quando seu swain longtime 
"estala a pergunta."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I grandi magazzini si sono transformati in non 
soltanto in una sorgente importante di occupazione per le donne 
bianche urbane giovani che cominciano verso la fine del diciannovesimo
secolo; egualmente hanno offerto un nuovo fuoco per le storia ed
i romanzi circa vita nelle città burgeoning dell'America. 
Produttori vari come Theodore Dreiser, Edna Ferber ed O. Henry 
hanno usato spesso il mondo dei grandi magazzini e delle ragazze del 
negozio che hanno lavorato là per creare un romanzo moderno (forma 
brandnew compresa -- la storia corta) che ha permesso che i lettori 
ritenessero la struttura di vita urbana. I heroines della 
acquist-ragazza del Ferber forte-sono stati voluti e benchè 
esprimessero la vulnerabilità ed il desiderio per companionship 
maschio, hanno stimato le loro carriere. In questa storia corta 
1912 di Ferber, nominata "una delle ragazze anziane," il capo del 
reparto del corsetto nel grande magazzino dello Spiegel è affrontato 
ad una decisione dura quando il suo swain da molto tempo "schiocca la 
domanda."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα καταστήματα τμήματος όχι μόνο έγιναν μια 
σημαντική πηγή απασχόλησης για τις νέες αστικές λευκές γυναίκες
που αρχίζουν προς το τέλος του 19$ου αιώνα  πρόσφεραν 
επίσης μια νέα εστίαση για τις ιστορίες και τα μυθιστορήματα για 
τη ζωή να φυτρώσουν της Αμερικής στις πόλεις. Οι συγγραφείς
τόσο διαφορετικοί όσο Theodore Dreiser, Edna Ferber, 
και Ο. Henry χρησιμοποίησαν συχνά τον κόσμο των καταστημάτων 
τμημάτων και των κοριτσιών καταστημάτων που ελειτούργησε εκεί για
να δημιουργήσει μια σύγχρονη μυθιστοριογραφία (συμπεριλαμβανομένης
μιας ολοκαίνουργιας μορφής -- η σύντομη ιστορία) που επέτρεψε 
στους αναγνώστες για να αισθανθεί τη σύσταση της αστικής ζωής. 
Οι ηρωϊ'δες κατάστημα-κοριτσιών του Ferber ήταν 
ισχυρογνώμουσες, και αν και εξέφρασαν την ευπάθεια και την 
επιθυμία για την αρσενική συντροφικότητα, εκτίμησαν τις 
σταδιοδρομίες τους. Σε αυτήν την σύντομη ιστορία Ferber, 
με τον τίτλο "ένα του 1912 από τα παλαιά κορίτσια," ο 
επικεφαλής του τμήματος κορσέδων στο κατάστημα τμημάτων 
Spiegel βρίσκεται αντιμέτωπος με μια σκληρή απόφαση όταν 
σκάει ο μακροπρόθεσμος βουκόλος της "την ερώτηση."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los almacenes grandes se convirtieron en no 
solamente una fuente importante del empleo para las mujeres blancas 
urbanas jóvenes que comenzaban en la a fines del siglo XIX; 
también ofrecieron un nuevo foco para las historias y las 
novelas sobre vida en las ciudades burgeoning de América. 
Programas de escritura tan diversos como Theodore Dreiser, Edna 
Ferber, y O. Henry utilizaron a menudo el mundo de los almacenes 
grandes y de las muchachas del departamento que trabajaron allí para 
crear una ficción moderna (forma brandnew incluyendo -- la historia 
corta) que permitió que los programas de lectura sintieran la textura
de la vida urbana. Fuerte-queri'an a las heroínas de la hacer
compras-muchacha de Ferber, y aunque expresaron vulnerabilidad y el 
deseo para el compañerismo masculino, valoraron sus carreras. 
En esta historia corta 1912 de Ferber, titulada "una de las 
viejas muchachas," el jefe del departamento del corsé en el almacén 
grande de Spiegel se hace frente con una decisión dura cuando su 
swain de largo plazo "hace estallar la pregunta."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086112</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103411</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/effie-bauer-turns-down-gabie-marks-edna-ferbers-one-of-the-old-girls</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
