<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105234</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105234</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085254</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Richmond Shipyards</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Richmond Werfte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Chantiers navals de Richmond</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Shipyards De Richmond</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Cantieri navali De Richmond</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ναυπηγεία του Ρίτσμοντ</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Astilleros De Richmond</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Industrialist Henry J. Kaiser ran seven shipyards and employed thousands of people. He used an assembly line to build ships, assembling some in less than five days. One image in this collection shows a ship's hull under construction. Another shows a diagram with goals for completing a ship. The workers at the Kaiser shipyards in Richmond, California, produced the most warships in the country during World War II. One photograph shows workers celebrating the launch of one of their ships. Kaiser was a forward thinker in terms of employee benefits. As the "Be a Healthy Shipbuilder" sign in one of the photographs shows, he was concerned about the welfare of his employees. Kaiser provided his employees with a health care plan by creating the first health maintenance organization, an HMO that exists to this day; and he set up on-site day care centers, where workers could leave their children while they worked their shift. Several photographs show the masses of workers who came to work each day, and many show women and minorities working at the Richmond Shipyards. A shortage of male workers and the pressing need for labor (as evidenced by the image of the recruiting billboard), created these new opportunities. This need for workers contributed to the migration to California of African Americans, who came in great numbers from the South in search of job opportunities. The many people who streamed into the shipyards in search of work turned Richmond into a boomtown, even attracting national attention. All of the workers needed a place to live, and makeshift living conditions were cramped and uncomfortable. One photograph shows the wife of worker standing in her home: a cramped bus that housed her family of six. Other photographs show families camping in tents and sleeping on the ground as they waited for housing to be built. Some shipyard workers resorted to living on boats, as you can see from the newspaper advertising "Boats for Sale."
A few of these photographs were taken by photographer Dorothea Lange, who collaborated with photographer Ansel Adams on a wartime photo assignment for Fortune magazine in 1944 focusing on the town of Richmond, California.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Industriell-Henry J. Kaiser ließ sieben Werfte 
laufen und beschäftigte Tausende von Leuten. Er benutzte ein 
Fließband, um die Schiffe aufzubauen und baute einiges in weniger als
fünf Tagen zusammen. Ein Bild in dieser Ansammlung zeigt den 
Rumpf eines Schiffs im Bau. Eine anderen Erscheinen ein Diagramm
mit Zielen für das Durchführen eines Schiffs. Die Arbeiter an 
den Kaiser Werften in Richmond, Kalifornien, produzierten die meisten 
Kriegsschiffe im Land während des Zweiten Weltkrieges. Eine 
Fotographie zeigt die Arbeiter, welche die Produkteinführung von 
einem ihrer Schiffe feiern. Kaiser war ein Vorwärtsdenker in 
Angestelltnutzen ausgedrückt. Da das "Zeichen eines gesunden 
Shipbuilder" in einem der Fotographien Erscheinen seien Sie, wurde er 
über die Wohlfahrt seiner Angestellten betroffen. Kaiser versah
seine Angestellten mit einem Gesundheitspflegeplan vom Erstellen der 
ersten Gesundheit Wartung Organisation, ein HMO, das zu diesem Tag 
existiert; und er stellte örtliche Tagesobachtmitten auf, wo 
Arbeiter ihre Kinder lassen konnten, während sie ihre Schicht 
bearbeiteten. Einige Fotographien zeigen die Massen der 
Arbeiter, die kamen, jeden Tag zu bearbeiten, und viele zeigen die 
Frauen und Minoritäten, die an den Richmond Werften arbeiten. 
Ein Mangel an männliche Arbeiter und das dringende Bedürfnis 
an der Arbeit (wie durch das Bild der einziehenden Anschlagtafel 
bewiesen), erstellt diesen neuen Gelegenheiten. Diese 
Notwendigkeit an den Arbeitern trug zur Migration zu Kalifornien der 
afrikanischen Amerikaner bei, die in große Zahlen vom Süden auf der 
Suche nach Jobgelegenheiten kamen. Die vielen Leute, die in die 
Werfte auf der Suche nach Arbeit strömten, machten Richmond zu ein 
boomtown und sogar erregten nationale Aufmerksamkeit. Alle 
Arbeiter benötigten einen Platz zu leben, und behelfsmäßige lebende
Bedingungen waren verkrampft und unbequem. Eine Fotographie 
zeigt die Frau des Arbeiters stehend in ihrem Haus: ein 
verkrampfter Bus, der ihre Familie von sechs unterbrachte. 
Andere Fotographien Erscheinenfamilien, die in den Zelten 
kampieren und aus den Grund schlafen, wie sie die aufgebaut zu werden 
warteten Unterbringung. Einige Werftarbeiter griffen auf das 
Leben auf Booten zurück, wie Sie von der Zeitung sehen können, die 
"Boote für Sale."A bekanntmacht, das wenige dieser Fotographien vom 
Photographen Dorothea Lange genommen wurden, der mit Photographen 
Ansel Adams auf einer Kriegfotoanweisung für Vermögen Zeitschrift 
1944 konzentrierend auf die Stadt von Richmond, Kalifornien 
zusammenarbeitete.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Henry J. Kaiser d'industriel a exécuté sept 
chantiers navals et a employé des milliers de personnes. Il 
avait l'habitude une chaîne de montage pour construire des bateaux, 
en assemblant en moins de cinq jours. Une image dans cette 
collection montre la coque d'un bateau en construction. Des 
autres expositions un diagramme avec des buts pour terminer un bateau.
Les ouvriers aux chantiers navals de Kaiser à Richmond, la 
Californie, ont produit les la plupart des vaisseaux de guerre dans le
pays pendant la deuxième guerre mondiale. Une photographie 
montre des ouvriers célébrant le lancement d'un de leurs bateaux. 
Kaiser était un penseur vers l'avant en termes d'avantages des 
employés. Car "soyez le signe d'un constructeur de navires en 
bonne santé" dans une des expositions de photographies, il a été 
préoccupé par le bien-être de ses employés. Kaiser a fourni 
à ses employés un plan de santé en créant la première 
organisation d'entretien de santé, un HMO qui existe à ce jour ; 
et il a installé les centres sur place de soin de jour, où les
ouvriers pourraient laisser leurs enfants tandis qu'ils travaillaient 
leur poste. Plusieurs photographies montrent les masses des 
ouvriers qui sont venus pour travailler chaque jour, et beaucoup 
montrent des femmes et des minorités travaillant aux chantiers navals
de Richmond. Un manque d'ouvriers de sexe masculin et la 
nécessité pressante du travail (comme démontré par l'image du 
panneau-réclame recruteur), créée ces nouvelles occasions. Ce
besoin d'ouvriers a contribué au transfert à la Californie des 
Américains africains, qui sont venus dans de grands nombres des 
Sud à la recherche des possibilités d'emploi. Le 
nombreux peuple qui a coulé dans les chantiers navals à la recherche
du travail a transformé Richmond en boomtown, attirant même une 
attention nationale. Tous les ouvriers ont eu besoin d'un 
endroit pour vivre, et les conditions vivantes expédient étaient à 
l'etroit et inconfortables. Une photographie montre l'épouse de
l'ouvrier se tenant dans sa maison : un bus à l'etroit qui a 
logé sa famille de six. D'autres familles d'exposition de 
photographies campant dans des tentes et dormant sur la terre comme 
ils ont attendu loger à construire. Quelques ouvriers de 
chantier naval ont recouru à la vie sur des bateaux, comme vous 
pouvez voir du journal annonçant des "bateaux pour Sale."A que peu de
ces photographies ont été pris par le photographe Dorothea Lange, 
qui a collaboré avec le photographe Ansel Adams sur une affectation 
de photo de temps de guerre pour le magazine de fortune en 1944 se 
concentrant sur la ville de Richmond, la Californie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Henry J. Kaiser do industrialista funcionou sete
shipyards e empregou milhares de povos. Usou uma linha de 
conjunto construir os navios, montando algum em menos de cinco dias. 
Uma imagem nesta coleção mostra o hull de um navio sob a 
construção. Umas outras mostras um diagrama com objetivos para
terminar um navio. Os trabalhadores nos shipyards de Kaiser em 
Richmond, Califórnia, produziram a maioria de navios de guerra no 
país durante a segunda guerra mundial. Uma fotografia mostra os
trabalhadores que comemoram o lançamento de um de seus navios. 
Kaiser era um thinker para diante nos termos de benefícios do 
empregado. Porque "seja o sinal de um shipbuilder saudável" em 
uma das mostras das fotografias, foi concernido sobre o bem-estar de 
seus empregados. Kaiser forneceu seus empregados com uma planta 
do cuidado de saúde criando a primeira organização da manutenção 
da saúde, um HMO que existisse a este dia; e ajustou acima 
centros no local do cuidado do dia, onde os trabalhadores poderiam 
deixar suas crianças quando trabalharam sua SHIFT. Diversas 
fotografias mostram as massas dos trabalhadores que vieram trabalhar 
cada dia, e muitos mostram as mulheres e os minorities que trabalham 
nos shipyards de Richmond. Uma falta dos trabalhadores 
masculinos e a necessidade pressionando para o trabalho (como 
evidenciado pela imagem do billboard recrutando), criada estas 
oportunidades novas. Esta necessidade para trabalhadores 
contribuiu à migração a Califórnia dos americanos africanos, que 
vieram em números grandes do sul na busca de oportunidades de 
trabalho. Muitos povos que fluíram nos shipyards na busca do 
trabalho giraram Richmond em um boomtown, atraindo mesmo a atenção 
nacional. Todos os trabalhadores necessitaram um lugar viver, e 
as circunstâncias vivas temporárias eram cramped e incômodas. 
Uma fotografia mostra a esposa do trabalhador que está em sua 
HOME: uma barra-ônibus cramped que abrigasse sua família de 
seis. Outras famílias da mostra das fotografias que acampam nas
barracas e que dormem na terra como esperaram abrigar a ser 
construído. Alguns trabalhadores do shipyard recorreram a viver
em barcos, como você pode ver do jornal que anuncia "barcos para 
Sale."A que poucas destas fotografias foram feitas exame pelo 
fotógrafo Dorothea Lange, que collaborated com o fotógrafo Ansel 
Adams em uma atribuição da foto do wartime para o compartimento da 
fortuna em 1944 que focalizam na cidade de Richmond, Califórnia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il henry J. Kaiser dell'industriale ha fatto 
funzionare sette cantieri navali ed ha impiegato i migliaia della 
gente. Ha usato una catena di montaggio per costruire le navi, 
montanti alcuno in più meno di cinque giorni. Un'immagine in 
questa accumulazione mostra lo scafo della nave in costruzione. 
Lle altre esposizioni uno schema con gli obiettivi per 
completare una nave. Gli operai ai cantieri navali di Kaiser a 
Richmond, la California, hanno prodotto la maggior parte delle navi da
guerra nel paese durante la seconda guerra mondiale. Una 
fotografia mostra gli operai che celebrano il lancio di una delle loro
navi. Kaiser era un thinker di andata in termini di benefici 
degli impiegati. Poichè "sia il segno del costruttore navale in
buona salute" in una delle esposizioni delle fotografie, è stato 
interessato circa il benessere dei suoi impiegati. Kaiser ha 
fornito ai suoi impiegati un programma di sanità creando la prima 
organizzazione di manutenzione di salute, un HMO che esiste a questo 
giorno; ed ha installato i centri sul posto di cura di giorno, 
in cui gli operai potrebbero lasciare i loro bambini mentre hanno 
lavorato il loro spostamento. Parecchie fotografie mostrano le 
masse di operai che sono venuto lavorare ogni giorno e molti mostrano 
le donne e le minoranze che lavorano ai cantieri navali de Richmond. 
Una scarsità degli operai maschii e la necessità urgente del 
lavoro (come provato dall'immagine del tabellone per le 
affissioni di reclutamento), creata queste nuove occasioni. 
Questa esigenza degli operai ha contribuito all'espansione alla 
California degli Americani africani, che sono venuto nei numeri grandi
dal sud alla ricerca delle occasioni di lavoro. La molta gente 
che è effluito nei cantieri navali alla ricerca di lavoro ha 
trasformato in Richmond un boomtown, persino attraente l'attenzione 
nazionale. Tutti gli operai hanno avuto bisogno di un posto di 
vivere e le circostanze di vita improvvisate erano cramped e scomode. 
Una fotografia mostra la moglie dell'operaio che si leva in 
piedi nella sua sede: un bus cramped che ha alloggiato la sua 
famiglia di sei. Altre famiglie di esposizione delle fotografie 
che si accampano in tende e che dormono sulla terra come hanno 
aspettato l'alloggio da costruire. Alcuni operai del cantiere 
navale hanno ricorso a vivere sulle barche, come potete vedere dal 
giornale che fa pubblicità "alle barche per Sale."A che poche di 
queste fotografie sono state prese dal photographer Dorothea Lange, 
che ha collaborato con il photographer Ansel Adams su un'assegnazione 
della foto di wartime per lo scomparto di fortuna in 1944 che mette a 
fuoco sulla città di Richmond, la California.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Industrialist Henry Θ*ι. Kaiser έτρεξε επτά 
ναυπηγεία και απασχόλησε χιλιάδες άτομα. Χρησιμοποίησε μια 
γραμμή συμβολικών γλωσσών για να ναυπηγήσει τα σκάφη, 
συγκεντρώνοντας μερικά σε λιγότερο από πέντε ημέρες. Μια 
εικόνα σε αυτήν την συλλογή εμφανίζει φλούδα ενός σκάφους κάτω
από την κατασκευή. Αλλος εμφανίζει ένα διάγραμμα με τους 
στόχους για ένα σκάφος. Οι εργαζόμενοι στα ναυπηγεία 
Kaiser στο Ρίτσμοντ, Καλιφόρνια, παρήγαγαν τα περισσότερα 
θωρηκτά στη χώρα κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ. 
Μια φωτογραφία εμφανίζει εργαζομένους που γιορτάζουν την 
έναρξη ένα από τα σκάφη τους. Το Kaiser ήταν μπροστινός
φιλόσοφος από την άποψη των οφελών υπαλλήλων. Δεδομένου 
ότι "να είστε υγιής ναυπηγόσ" το σημάδι σε μια από τις 
φωτογραφίες εμφανίζει, ανησύχησε για την ευημερία των υπαλλήλων 
του. Το Kaiser παρείχε στους υπαλλήλους του ένα σχέδιο 
υγειονομικής περίθαλψης με τη δημιουργία της πρώτης οργάνωσης 
συντήρησης υγείας, ένα HMO που υπάρχει σε αυτήν την ημέρα  
και οργάνωσε τα επιτόπια κέντρα ημερήσιας φροντίδας, όπου 
οι εργαζόμενοι μπόρεσαν να αφήσουν τα παιδιά τους ενώ 
ελειτούργησαν τη μετατόπισή τους. Διάφορες φωτογραφίες 
εμφανίζουν τις μάζες των εργαζομένων που ήρθαν να απασχοληθούν σε
κάθε ημέρα, και πολλές γυναίκες και μειονότητες επίδειξης 
εργαζόμενος στα ναυπηγεία του Ρίτσμοντ. Μια έλλειψη των 
αρσενικών εργαζόμενοι και η επείγουσα ανάγκη για την εργασία 
(όπως αποδεικνύεται από την εικόνα του πίνακα διαφημίσεων 
στρατολόγησης), δημιούργησε αυτές τις νέες ευκαιρίες. Αυτή
η ανάγκη για τους εργαζομένους συνέβαλε στη μετανάστευση σε 
Καλιφόρνια αφρικανικών Αμερικανών, οι οποίοι προήλθαν στους 
μεγάλους αριθμούς από το νότο σε αναζήτηση των ευκαιριών 
εργασίας. Οι πολλοί άνθρωποι που έρευσαν στα ναυπηγεία σε 
αναζήτηση της εργασίας μετέτρεψαν το Ρίτσμοντ σε boomtown, 
προσελκύοντας ακόμη και την εθνική προσοχή. Όλοι οι 
εργαζόμενοι χρειάστηκαν μια θέση για να ζήσουν, και οι προσωρινές
συνθήκες διαβίωσης ήταν περιορισμένες και ανήσυχες. Μια 
φωτογραφία εμφανίζει τη σύζυγο του εργαζομένου που στέκεται στο 
σπίτι της: ένας περιορισμένος διάδρομος που στέγασε την 
οικογένειά της έξι. Αλλες φωτογραφίες εμφανίζουν 
οικογένειες που στρατοπεδεύουν στις σκηνές και που κοιμούνται στο 
έδαφος όπως περίμεναν την κατοικία που χτίζεται. Μερικοί 
εργαζόμενοι ναυπηγείων προσέφυγαν στη διαβίωση στις βάρκες, 
δεδομένου ότι μπορείτε να δείτε βάρκες από της 
εφημερίδων διαφήμισης "για Sale."A που λίγες από αυτές τις 
φωτογραφίες λήφθηκαν από το φωτογράφο Dorothea Lange, που 
συνεργάστηκε με το φωτογράφο Ansel Adams σε μια εν καιρώ 
πολέμου ανάθεση φωτογραφιών για το περιοδικό τύχης το 1944 που
εστιάζει στην πόλη του Ρίτσμοντ, Καλιφόρνια.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Henrio J. Kaiser del industrial ejecutó siete 
astilleros y empleó a millares de gente. Él utilizó una 
planta de fabricación para construir las naves, ensamblando alguno en
menos de cinco días. Una imagen en esta colección muestra el 
casco de una nave bajo construcción. Otras demostraciones un 
diagrama con las metas para terminar una nave. Los trabajadores 
en los astilleros de Kaiser en Richmond, California, produjeron la 
mayoría de los buques de guerra en el país durante la Segunda Guerra
Mundial. Una fotografía muestra a trabajadores que celebran el 
lanzamiento de una de sus naves. Kaiser era un pensador 
delantero en términos de las ventajas del empleado. Pues "sea 
la muestra de un constructor naval sano" en una de las demostraciones 
de las fotografías, él fue referido sobre el bienestar de sus 
empleados. Kaiser proveió de sus empleados un plan del cuidado 
médico creando la primera organización del mantenimiento de la 
salud, un HMO que existe a este día; y él instaló centros en 
sitio del cuidado del día, donde los trabajadores podrían dejar a 
sus niños mientras que trabajaron su rotación. Varias 
fotografías muestran las masas de los trabajadores que vinieron 
trabajar cada día, y muchos muestran a las mujeres y a minorías que 
trabajan en los astilleros de Richmond. Una escasez de los 
trabajadores masculinos y la necesidad acuciante del trabajo (según 
lo evidenciado por la imagen de la cartelera de reclutamiento), creada
estas nuevas oportunidades. Esta necesidad de trabajadores 
contribuyó a la migración a California de los americanos africanos, 
que vinieron en grandes números del sur en la búsqueda de las 
oportunidades de trabajo. La mucha gente que fluyó en los 
astilleros en la búsqueda del trabajo dio vuelta a Richmond en un 
boomtown, incluso atrayendo la atención nacional. Todos los 
trabajadores necesitaron un lugar vivir, y las condiciones vivas de 
expediente eran obstaculizadas e incómodas. Una fotografía 
muestra a esposa del trabajador que está parada en su hogar: un
megabus encogido que contuvo su familia de seises. Otras 
familias de la demostración de las fotografías que acampan en 
tiendas y que duermen en la tierra como esperaron contener que se 
construirá. Algunos trabajadores del astillero recurrieron a 
vivir en los barcos, como usted puede ver del periódico que anuncia 
los "barcos para Sale."A que pocas de estas fotografías fueron 
tomadas por el fotógrafo Dorothea Lange, que colaboró con el 
fotógrafo Ansel Adams en una asignación de la foto del tiempo de 
guerra para el compartimiento de la fortuna en 1944 que se centraba en
la ciudad de Richmond, California.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085254</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105234</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/richmond-shipyards</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
