<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103924</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103924</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211292</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">NCBI More Information: Similarity</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">NCBI Mehr Informationen: Ähnlichkeit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">NCBI Plus d'Information : Similitude</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">NCBI Mais Informação: Similaridade</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">NCBI Le Più Informazioni: Somiglianza</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">NCBI περισσότερες πληροφορίες: Ομοιότητα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">NCBI Más Información: Semejanza</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This page summarizes the basic concept and vocabulary of sequence similarity searching. It is included for those new to the field who may not appreciate the importance of this technique in biology, who lack the vocabulary to understand the BLAST guide and tutorial or who require a basic rather than a sophisticated understanding of the methods involved. Sections include introduction, premise, terms, general approach, the BLAST algorithm, quantification, gaps, significance, and databases. Users can link to BLAST, BLAST tutorial, and additional BLAST information from this page.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Seite faßt das Grundmodell und den 
Wortschatz des Reihenfolge Ähnlichkeitsuchens zusammen. Sie ist
für die enthalten, die zu auffangene neu sind, das möglicherweise
nicht den Wert dieser Technik in der Biologie schätzen können, die 
den Wortschatz ermangeln, um die KNALL Anleitung und den Tutorial zu 
verstehen, oder das ein grundlegendes anstatt hoch entwickeltes 
Verständnis der betroffenen Methoden benötigen. Kapitel 
schließen Einleitung, Voraussetzung, Bezeichnungen, allgemeine 
Annäherung, den KNALL-Algorithmus, Quantifikation, Abstände, 
Stichhaltigkeit und Datenbanken ein. Benutzer können binden, um
ZU STARTEN, SPRENGEN Tutorial und zusätzliche KNALL-Informationen von
dieser Seite.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette page récapitule le concept de base et le 
vocabulaire de la recherche de similitude d'ordre. Elle est 
incluse pour ceux nouvelles à la zone qui peut ne pas apprécier 
l'importance de cette technique dans la biologie, qui manquent du 
vocabulaire pour comprendre le guide et le cours d'instruction de 
SOUFFLE ou qui exigent un arrangement de base plutôt que sophistiqué
des méthodes impliquées. Les sections incluent l'introduction,
les lieux, les limites, l'approche générale, l'algorithme de 
SOUFFLE, la quantification, les lacunes, la signification, et les 
bases de données. Les utilisateurs peuvent joindre POUR 
SOUFFLER, SOUFFLENT le cours d'instruction, et l'information 
supplémentaire de SOUFFLE de cette page.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta página sumaria o conceito básico e o 
vocabulário de procurarar da similaridade da seqüência. É 
incluída para aquelas novas ao campo que não podem apreciar a 
importância desta técnica na biologia, que faltam o vocabulário 
para compreender a guia e o tutorial da EXPLOSÃO ou que requer uma 
compreensão básica melhor que sofisticada dos métodos envolvidos. 
As seções incluem a introdução, a premissa, os termos, a 
aproximação geral, o algoritmo da EXPLOSÃO, a quantificação, as 
aberturas, o significado, e as bases de dados. Os usuários 
podem ligar PARA EXPLODIR, EXPLODEM o tutorial, e a informação 
adicional da EXPLOSÃO desta página.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa pagina ricapitola il concetto di base ed il
vocabolario di ricerca di somiglianza di sequenza. È inclusa 
per quelle nuove al campo che non può apprezzare l'importanza di 
questa tecnica nella biologia, che difettano del vocabolario per 
capire la guida e la lezione privata di SCOPPIO o che richiede una 
comprensione di base piuttosto che specializzata dei metodi 
coinvolgere. Le sezioni includono l'introduzione, i locali, i 
termini, il metodo generale, la procedura di SCOPPIO, la 
quantificazione, le lacune, l'importanza e le basi di dati. Gli 
utenti possono collegarsi PER FARE SALTARE, FANNO SALTARE la lezione 
privata e le informazioni supplementari di SCOPPIO da questa pagina.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η σελίδα συνοψίζει τη βασικά έννοια και το 
λεξιλόγιο της έρευνας ομοιότητας ακολουθίας. 
Συμπεριλαμβάνεται για εκείνους νέους στο πεδίο που δεν 
μπορεί να εκτιμήσει τη σημασία αυτής της τεχνικής στη βιολογία, 
οι οποίοι στερούνται το λεξιλόγιο για να καταλάβουν τον οδηγό και
το σεμινάριο ΦΥΣΗΜΑΤΟΣ ή που απαιτούν έναν βασικό παρά μια 
περίπλοκη κατανόηση των μεθόδων σχετικών. Τα τμήματα 
περιλαμβάνουν την εισαγωγή, την προϋπόθεση, τους όρους, τη 
γενική προσέγγιση, τον αλγόριθμο ΦΥΣΗΜΑΤΟΣ, τον προσδιορισμό της 
ποσότητας, τα χάσματα, τη σημασία, και τις βάσεις δεδομένων. 
Οι χρήστες μπορούν να συνδέσουν με το ΦΥΣΗΜΑ, το σεμινάριο 
ΦΥΣΗΜΑΤΟΣ, και τις πρόσθετες πληροφορίες ΦΥΣΗΜΑΤΟΣ από αυτήν την 
σελίδα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta paginación resume el concepto básico y el 
vocabulario de buscar de la semejanza de la secuencia. Es 
incluida para las nuevas al campo que pueden no apreciar la 
importancia de esta técnica en biología, que faltan el vocabulario 
para entender la guía y la guía de la RÁFAGA o que requiere una 
comprensión básica más bien que sofisticada de los métodos 
implicados. Las secciones incluyen la introducción, la premisa,
términos, acercamiento general, el algoritmo de la RÁFAGA, la 
cuantificación, boquetes, la significación, y bases de datos. 
Los utilizadores pueden conectar PARA ARRUINAR, ARRUINAN guía, 
y la información adicional de la RÁFAGA de esta paginación.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:NATIONAL CENTER FOR BIOTECHNOLOGY INFORMATION
FN:NATIONAL CENTER FOR BIOTECHNOLOGY INFORMATION
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211292</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103924</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/ncbi-more-information-similarity</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
