<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103905</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103905</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086172</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Four Minute Men: Volunteer Speeches During World War I</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Vier Minuziöse Männer: Freiwillige Reden 
Während Des Ersten Weltkrieges</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Quatre Hommes Minute : Discours Volontaires 
Pendant La Première Guerre Mondiale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quatro Homens Minuciosos: Discursos 
Voluntários Durante O World.war.i</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Quattro Uomini Minuti: Discorsi Volontari 
Durante Il World.war.i</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέσσερα μικρά άτομα: Εθελοντικές ομιλίες κατά 
τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου Ι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cuatro Hombres Minuciosos: Discursos 
Voluntarios Durante Primera Guerra Mundial</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">During World War I, the United States fought a war of ideas with unprecedented ingenuity and organization. President Woodrow Wilson established the Committee on Public Information (CPI) to manage news and solicit widespread support for the war at home and abroad. Under the energetic direction of Mississippi newspaper editor George Creel, the CPI churned out national propaganda through diverse media. Creel organized the "Four Minute Men," a virtual army of volunteers who gave brief speeches wherever they could get an audience--in movie theaters, churches, synagogues, and labor union, lodge, and grange halls. Creel claimed that his 75,000 amateur orators had delivered over 7.5 million speeches to more than 314 million people. CPI publications from the Four Minute Man crusade offered tips on developing and delivering a brief, effective speech--the predecessor to today's "sound bite." They also recognized diverse audiences, with reports of Yiddish speakers in theaters and workplaces, a Sioux Four Minute Man, and a speech called "The Meaning of America" delivered in seven languages.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während des Ersten Weltkrieges kämpften die 
Vereinigten Staaten einen Krieg von Ideen mit beispiellosem Scharfsinn
und Organisation. Präsident Woodrow Wilson stellte den 
Ausschuß für allgemeine Informationen (CPI) her um Nachrichten zu 
handhaben und weitverbreiteten Support für den Krieg im In- und 
Ausland zu erbitten. Unter der energischen Richtung von 
Mississippi Zeitungsverleger George Creel, schüttelte das CPI aus 
nationaler Propaganda durch verschiedene Media durch. Creel 
organisierte die "vier minuziösen Männer," eine virtuelle Armee der 
Freiwilliger, die kurze Reden gleichgültig wo, das sie ein Publikum 
-- in den Filmtheatern erhalten konnten, Kirchen, Synagogen und 
Arbeiterverband, Hütte und Gutshofhallen gaben. Creel 
behauptete, daß seine 75.000 laienhaften Redner über 7.5 Million 
Reden an mehr als 314 Million Leute geliefert hatten. CPI 
Publikationen vom minuziösen Kreuzzug des Mannes vier boten Spitzen 
auf dem Entwickeln und dem Liefern eines Schriftsatzes, wirkungsvolle 
Rede -- der Vorgänger zum heutigen "stichhaltigen Bissen." an 
Sie erkannten auch verschiedene Publikum, mit Reports der 
Yiddish Sprecher an Theatern und Arbeitsplätzen, des Sioux vier 
minuziösen Mannes und der Rede, die "die Bedeutung von Amerika 
genannt wurde", das in sieben Sprachen geliefert wurde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant la Première Guerre Mondiale, les 
Etats-Unis ont combattu une guerre des idées avec l'ingéniosité et 
l'organisation sans précédent. Le Président Woodrow Wilson a 
établi le comité de l'information publique (CPI) pour contrôler des
nouvelles et pour solliciter le support répandu pour la guerre ici et
ailleurs. Sous la direction énergique du panier de pêche de 
George d'éditeur de journal du Mississippi, la CPI a battu hors 
de la propagande nationale par des medias divers. Le panier de 
pêche a organisé les "quatre hommes minute," une armée virtuelle 
des volontaires qui ont donné de brefs discours là où qu'ils 
pourraient obtenir une assistance -- dans des théâtres de film, 
églises, synagogues, et syndicat, loge, et halls de grange. 
Le panier de pêche a réclamé que ses 75.000 orateurs 
d'amateur avaient livré plus de 7.5 millions de discours à plus de 
314 millions de personnes. Les publications de CPI de la 
croisade minute de l'homme quatre ont offert des extrémités sur 
développer et fournir un dossier, le discours pertinent -- le 
prédécesseur "à la morsure saine d'aujourd'hui." Elles ont 
également identifié les assistances diverses, avec des états des 
orateurs de Yiddish dans les théâtres et les lieux de travail, d'un 
homme minute de Sioux quatre, et d'un discours appelé "la 
signification de l'Amérique" livrée dans sept langages.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Durante o world.war.i, os estados unidos lutaram 
uma guerra das idéias com o ingenuity e a organização 
unprecedented. O presidente Woodrow Wilson estabeleceu o comitê
na informação pública (CPI) para controlar a notícia e solicit 
sustentação difundida para a guerra na HOME e no exterior. Sob
o sentido energético do creel de George do editor de jornal de 
Mississippi, o CPI churned para fora do propaganda nacional com os 
media diversos. O creel organizou os "quatro homens minuciosos,"
um exército virtual dos voluntários que deram discursos breves 
wherever que poderiam começar uma audiência -- em teatros do filme, 
igrejas, synagogues, e união labor, alojamento, e salões do grange. 
O creel reivindicou que seus 75.000 orators amadores tinham 
entregado sobre 7.5 milhão discursos a mais de 314 milhão povos. 
As publicações do CPI do crusade minucioso do homem quatro 
ofereceram pontas em desenvolver e em entregar um sumário, discurso 
eficaz -- predecessor "à mordida sadia de hoje." Reconheceram 
também audiências diversas, com relatórios de altofalantes de 
Yiddish nos teatros e nos workplaces, de um homem minucioso de Sioux 
quatro, e de um discurso chamado "o meaning de América" entregada em 
sete línguas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Durante il world.war.i, unito Dichiara ha 
combattuto una guerra delle idee con ingegnosità e l'organizzazione 
senza precedente. Il presidente Woodrow Wilson ha istituito il 
comitato delle informazioni pubbliche (caratteri per pollice) per 
gestire le notizie e sollecitare il supporto diffuso per la guerra nel
paese ed all'estero. Sotto il senso energico della rastrelliera 
di George dell'editore di giornale del Mississippi, i caratteri per 
pollice hanno sbattuto verso l'esterno la propaganda nazionale con i 
media vari. La rastrelliera ha organizzato "i quattro uomini 
minuti," un esercito virtuale dei volontari che hanno dato i brevi 
discorsi laddove che potrebbero ottenere un pubblico -- nei teatri di 
film, chiese, synagogues ed unione di lavoro, casetta e 
corridoi del grange. La rastrelliera ha sostenuto che i suoi 
75.000 orators dilettanti avevano trasportato oltre 7.5 milione 
discorsi a più di 314 milione di persone. Le pubblicazioni di 
caratteri per pollice dal crusade minuto dell'uomo quattro hanno 
offerto le punte sullo sviluppare e sul trasporto del riassunto, il 
discorso efficace -- il predecessore all'odierno "morso sano." 
Egualmente hanno riconosciuto i pubblici vari, con i rapporti 
degli altoparlanti di Yiddish nei teatri ed in posti di lavoro, di un 
uomo minuto del Sioux quattro e di un discorso chiamato "il 
significato dell'America" trasportata in sette linguaggi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατά τη διάρκεια παγκόσμιος πόλεμος Ι, οι Ηνωμένες 
Πολιτείες διεξήγαγαν έναν πόλεμο των ιδεών με την πρωτοφανείς 
ευστροφία και την οργάνωση. Ο Πρόεδρος Woodrow Wilson 
καθιέρωσε την Επιτροπή των δημόσιων πληροφοριών (ΔΤΚ) για να 
διαχειριστεί τις ειδήσεις και να ζητήσει τη διαδεδομένη 
υποστήριξη για τον πόλεμο στο σπίτι και στο εξωτερικό. Υπό 
την ενεργητική καθοδήγηση του επεξεργαστή George Creel, η 
αναδευμένη ΔΤΚ έξω εθνική προπαγάνδα εφημερίδων του Μισισιπή 
μέσω των διαφορετικών μέσων. Το ψαροκόφινο οργάνωσε τα 
"τέσσερα μικρά άτομα," ένας εικονικός στρατός των εθελοντών που
έδωσαν τις συνοπτικές ομιλίες οπουδήποτε θα μπορούσαν να πάρουν 
ένα ακροατήριο -- στους κινηματογράφους, τις εκκλησίες, τις 
συναγωγές, και το εργατικό συνδικάτο, να κατοικήσουν, και 
grange τις αίθουσες. Το ψαροκόφινο υποστήριξε ότι 
75.000 ερασιτεχνικοί ομιλητές του είχαν παραδώσει πάνω από 
7,5 εκατομμύριο ομιλίες σε περισσότερους από 314 
εκατομμύριο ανθρώπους. Οι δημοσιεύσεις ΔΤΚ από τη μικρή 
σταυροφορία ατόμων τέσσερα πρόσφεραν τις άκρες στην ανάπτυξη και
την παράδοση μιας συνοπτικής, αποτελεσματικής ομιλίας -- ο 
προκάτοχος στο σημερινό "υγιές δάγκωμα." Αναγνώρισαν 
επίσης τα διαφορετικά ακροατήρια, με τις εκθέσεις των γίντις 
ομιλητών στα θέατρα και τους εργασιακούς χώρους, ενός σιού 
μικρού ατόμου τέσσερα, και μιας ομιλίας αποκαλούμενης "έννοια 
της Αμερικήσ" που παραδόθηκε σε επτά γλώσσες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Durante Primera Guerra Mundial, los Estados Unidos
lucharon una guerra de ideas con ingeniosidad y la organización sin 
precedentes. Presidente Woodrow Wilson estableció a comité 
sobre la información pública (CPI) para manejar noticias y para 
solicitar la ayuda extensa para la guerra en el país y en el 
extranjero. Bajo dirección enérgia de la cesta de George del 
redactor de Mississippi, el CPI batió fuera de propaganda nacional 
con media diversos. La cesta ordenó a "cuatro hombres 
minuciosos," un ejército virtual de los voluntarios que dieron 
discursos abreviados que podrían conseguir dondequiera que a una 
audiencia -- en teatros de la película, las iglesias, las 
sinagogas, y sindicato, casa de campo, y los pasillos del grange. 
La cesta demandó que sus 75.000 oradores aficionados habían
entregado sobre 7.5 millones de discursos más de 314 millones de 
personas de. Las publicaciones del CPI de la cruzada 
minuciosa del hombre cuatro ofrecieron extremidades en desarrollar y 
entregar un escrito, discurso eficaz -- el precursor a la "mordedura 
de hoy de los sonidos." También reconocieron a audiencias 
diversas, con informes de los locutores de Yiddish en teatros y 
lugares de trabajo, de un hombre minucioso de Sioux cuatro, y de un 
discurso llamado "el significado de América" entregada en siete 
lenguajes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086172</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103905</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/four-minute-men-volunteer-speeches-during-world-war-i</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
