<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106129</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106129</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206515</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Campaign for Vicksburg, 1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Kampagne für Vicksburg, 1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La campagne pour Vicksburg, 1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A campanha para Vicksburg, 1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La campagna per Vicksburg, 1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η εκστρατεία για Vicksburg, 1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La campaña para Vicksburg, 1863</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">describes the effort of the Union Army of Tennessee to capture Vicksburg, Mississippi. Taking Vicksburg was the key to ending the Civil War. It was the key to regaining control of the lower Mississippi River, which had been lost when Confederate forces closed the river. Regaining control of this area and the river, the most important economic feature of the continent, would allow the rich agricultural produce of the Northwest to reach world markets. It would also split the South in two.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">beschreibt die Bemühung der Anschluß-Armee von 
Tennessee, Vicksburg, Mississippi zu erfassen. Vicksburg zu 
nehmen war die Taste zum Ende des Bürgerkrieges. Es war die 
Taste zur Wiedergewinnung von von Steuerung des untereren Mississippi 
Flusses, der verloren worden war, als verbündet, erzwingt schloß den
Fluß. Steuerung dieses Bereiches und des Flusses 
wiedergewinnend, würde das wichtigste ökonomische Merkmal des 
Kontinentes, das reiche landwirtschaftliche Erzeugnis des Nordwestens 
zu den Reichweiteweltmärkten erlauben. Es würde auch den 
Süden in zwei aufspalten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">décrit l'effort de l'armée des syndicats du 
Tennessee de capturer Vicksburg, Mississippi. La prise de 
Vicksburg était la clé à terminer la guerre civile. C'était 
la clé à regagner la commande du fleuve inférieur du Mississippi, 
qui avait été détruit si confédéré force a fermé le fleuve. 
Regagnant la commande de cette zone et du fleuve, le dispositif 
économique le plus important du continent, permettrait le produit 
agricole riche du nord-ouest aux marchés mondiaux d'extension. 
Il dédoublerait également les Sud dans deux.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">descreve o esforço do exército de união de 
Tennessee capturar Vicksburg, Mississippi. Fazer exame de 
Vicksburg era a chave a terminar a guerra civil. Era a chave a 
regaining o controle do rio mais baixo de Mississippi, que tinha sido 
perdido quando confederate força fechou o rio. Regaining o 
controle desta área e do rio, a característica econômica a mais 
importante do continente, permitiria o produto agricultural rico do 
noroeste aos mercados de mundo do alcance. Racharia também o 
sul em dois.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">descrive lo sforzo dell'esercito del sindacato del
Tennessee bloccare Vicksburg, Mississippi. La presa del 
Vicksburg era il tasto a concludere la guerra civile. Era il 
tasto a riguadagnare il controllo del fiume più basso del 
Mississippi, che era stato perso una volta confederato forza 
chiuso il fiume. Riguadagnando il controllo di questa zona e
del fiume, la caratteristica economica più importante del continente,
permetterebbe i prodotti agricoli ricchi del nord-ovest ai mercati 
mondiali di estensione. Egualmente spaccherebbe il sud in due.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">περιγράφει την προσπάθεια του στρατού ένωσης του 
Tennessee για να συλλάβει Vicksburg, Μισισιπής. Η λήψη 
Vicksburg ήταν το πλήκτρο στο τελείωμα του εμφύλιου πολέμου. 
Ήταν το πλήκτρο στην επανάκτηση του ελέγχου του χαμηλότερου
ποταμού του Μισισιπή, ο οποίος ήταν χαμένου όταν έκλεισαν οι 
ομόσπονδες δυνάμεις τον ποταμό. Επανακτώντας τον έλεγχο 
αυτής της περιοχής και του ποταμού, το σημαντικότερο οικονομικό 
χαρακτηριστικό γνώρισμα της ηπείρου, θα επέτρεπε στα πλούσια 
γεωργικά προϊόντα των βορειοδυτικών για να φθάσει στις 
παγκόσμιες αγορές. Θα χώριζε επίσης το νότο σε δύο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">describe el esfuerzo del ejército de unión de 
Tennessee de capturar Vicksburg, Mississippi. Tomar Vicksburg 
era el clave a terminar la guerra civil. Era el clave a 
recuperar el control del río más bajo de Mississippi, que había 
sido perdido cuando es confederado fuerza cerró el río. 
Recuperando control de esta área y del río, la característica
económica más importante del continente, permitiría el producto 
agrícola rico del noroeste a los mercados mundiales del alcance. 
También partiría el sur en dos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206515</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106129</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-campaign-for-vicksburg-1863</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
