<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103653</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103653</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212008</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Salmon Smolt Activity</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lachssmolt Aktivität</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Activité Saumonée de Smolt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Atividade Salmon De Smolt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Attività Di color salmone Di Smolt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δραστηριότητα Smolt σολομών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Actividad De color salmón De Smolt</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Stella Smolts Migration Model focuses on the spring migration of hatchery smolts to the ocean. It may be used to test the relative merits of barging fish or drawing down the reservoirs to help the smolts reach the ocean. This pre-made Stella Model demonstrates how model simulation might be used in fishery management. Students learn how previous simulation models have been used to help managers deal with the many factors contributing to the decline. The model includes an interactive exercise to place you in the role of fishery manager. This is an appropriate for an introductory geoscience course with an Earth System approach and a useful activity to show the connection between the physical environment (river system with dams) and the biosphere (salmon smolt). This site also includes teaching notes and tips, necessary teaching materials, assessment ideas and additional resources. This activity is part of the Starting Point Collection: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Stella Smolts Migration Modell konzentriert 
auf die Frühling Migration von Brutplatz smolts zum Ozean. Es 
kann verwendet werden, um die relativen Übertragungsgüte der barging
Fische oder des Zeichnens hinunter die Vorratsbehälter zu prüfen, 
den smolts zu helfen, den Ozean zu erreichen. Dieses 
vor-gebildete Stella Modell zeigt, wie vorbildliche Simulation im 
Fischereimanagement verwendet werden konnte. Kursteilnehmer 
erlernen, wie vorhergehende Simulation Modelle benutzt worden sind, um
Managern zu helfen, die vielen Faktoren zu beschäftigen, die zur 
Abnahme beitragen. Das Modell schließt eine interaktive Übung 
ein, um Sie in die Rolle des Fischereimanagers zu legen. Dieses 
ist für einen einleitenden geoscience Kurs mit einer Masse System 
Annäherung und einer nützlichen Aktivität ein angebrachtes, zum des
Anschlußes zwischen der körperlichen Umgebung (Flußsystem mit 
Verdammungen) und der Biosphäre (Lachssmolt) zu zeigen. Diese 
Site schließt auch unterrichtende Anmerkungen und Spitzen, notwendige
Lehrmittel, Einschätzung Ideen und zusätzliche Betriebsmittel ein. 
Diese Aktivität ist ein Teil der Ausgangspunkt-Ansammlung: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le modèle de transfert de Stella Smolts se 
concentre sur le transfert de ressort des smolts d'établissement 
d'incubation à l'océan. Il peut être employé pour tester les
mérites relatifs des poissons barging ou du baisse les réservoirs 
d'aider les smolts pour atteindre l'océan. Ce modèle pré-fait
de Stella démontre comment la simulation modèle pourrait être 
utilisée dans la gestion de pêche. Les étudiants apprennent 
comment des modèles précédents de simulation ont été employés 
pour aider des gestionnaires à traiter les nombreux facteurs 
contribuant au déclin. Le modèle inclut un exercice interactif
pour vous placer dans le rôle du gestionnaire de pêche. C'est 
un approprié pour un cours préliminaire de geoscience avec une 
approche systématisée de la terre et une activité utile pour 
montrer la connexion entre l'environnement physique (système de 
fleuve avec des barrages) et la biosphère (smolt saumoné). Ce 
site inclut également les notes et les extrémités d'enseignement, 
le matériel didactique nécessaire, les idées d'évaluation et les 
ressources supplémentaires. Cette activité fait partie de la 
collection de point de départ : 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O modelo da migração de Stella Smolts focaliza 
na migração da mola de smolts do hatchery ao oceano. Pode ser 
usado testar os méritos relativos de peixes barging ou de desenhar 
abaixo os reservatórios ajudar aos smolts alcançar o oceano. 
Este modelo pre-feito de Stella demonstra como a simulação 
modelo pôde ser usada na gerência do fishery. Os estudantes 
aprendem como os modelos precedentes da simulação foram usados 
ajudar a gerentes tratar de muitos fatores que contribuem ao 
declínio. O modelo inclui um exercício interativo para 
colocá-lo no papel do gerente do fishery. Este é um apropriado
para um curso introdutório do geoscience com uma aproximação de 
sistema da terra e uma atividade útil para mostrar a conexão entre o
ambiente físico (sistema do rio com represas) e o biosphere (smolt 
salmon). Este local inclui também notas e pontas ensinando, 
materiais de ensino necessários, idéias da avaliação e recursos 
adicionais. Esta atividade é parte da coleção do ponto 
começar: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il modello di espansione di Stella Smolts mette a 
fuoco sull'espansione della molla degli smolts dello stabilimento 
d'incubazione all'oceano. Può essere usato per verificare i 
meriti relativi dei pesci barging o di abbassare i serbatoi aiutare 
gli smolts per raggiungere l'oceano. Questo modello pre-fatto di
Stella dimostra come la simulazione di modello potrebbe essere usata 
nella gestione dell'industria della pesca. Gli allievi imparano 
come i modelli precedenti di simulazione sono stati usati per aiutare 
i gestori a occuparsi dei molti fattori che contribuiscono al declino.
Il modello include un'esercitazione interattiva per disporlo nel
ruolo del gestore dell'industria della pesca. Ciò è un adatto 
per un corso introduttivo di geoscience con un approccio sistematico 
della terra e un'attività utile per mostrare il collegamento fra 
l'ambiente fisico (sistema del fiume con le dighe) e la biosfera 
(smolt di color salmone). Questo luogo egualmente include le 
note e punte d'istruzione, materiali didattici necessari, idee di 
valutazione e risorse supplementari. Questa attività fa parte 
dell'accumulazione del punto di partenza: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η Στέλλα Smolts Migration Model εστιάζει στη 
μετανάστευση άνοιξη του εκκολαπτηρίου smolts στον ωκεανό. 
Μπορεί να χρησιμοποιηθεί για να εξετάσει τις σχετικές αξίες
τα ψάρια ή να σύρει κάτω τις δεξαμενές για να βοηθήσει τα 
smolts να φθάσουν στον ωκεανό. Αυτή η η προ-γίνοντη 
Στέλλα Model καταδεικνύει πώς η πρότυπη προσομοίωση να 
χρησιμοποιηθεί στη διαχείριση αλιείας. Οι σπουδαστές 
μαθαίνουν πώς τα προηγούμενα μοντέλα προσομοίωσης έχουν 
χρησιμοποιηθεί για να βοηθήσουν τους διευθυντές να εξετάσουν τους 
πολλούς παράγοντες που συμβάλλουν στην πτώση. Το μοντέλο 
περιλαμβάνει μια διαλογική άσκηση για να σας τοποθετήσει στο ρόλο
του διευθυντή αλιείας. Αυτό είναι ένα αρμόζον για μια 
εισαγωγική σειρά μαθημάτων geoscience με μια προσέγγιση γήινων
συστημάτων και μια χρήσιμη δραστηριότητα να εμφανίσει τη σύνδεση 
μεταξύ του φυσικού περιβάλλοντος (σύστημα ποταμών με τα 
φράγματα) και της βιόσφαιρας (σολομός smolt). Αυτή η 
περιοχή περιλαμβάνει επίσης τις σημειώσεις και τις άκρες 
διδασκαλίας, τα απαραίτητα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, τις ιδέες 
αξιολόγησης και τα πρόσθετα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς. Αυτή η 
δραστηριότητα είναι μέρος της συλλογής αφετηρίας: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El modelo de la migración de Stella Smolts se 
centra en la migración del resorte de los smolts del criadero al 
océano. Puede ser utilizado para probar los méritos relativos 
de pescados barging o de trazar abajo de los depósitos de ayudar a 
los smolts para alcanzar el océano. Este modelo pre-hecho de 
Stella demuestra cómo la simulación modelo se pudo utilizar en la 
gerencia de la industria pesquera. Los estudiantes aprenden 
cómo los modelos anteriores de la simulación se han utilizado para 
ayudar a encargados a ocuparse de los muchos factores que contribuían
a la declinación. El modelo incluye un ejercicio interactivo 
para colocarle en el papel del encargado de la industria pesquera. 
Esto es un apropiado para un curso introductorio del geoscience 
con un acercamiento de sistema de la tierra y una actividad útil para
mostrar la conexión entre el ambiente físico (sistema del río con 
las presas) y la biosfera (smolt de color salmón). Este sitio 
también incluye notas y las extremidades de enseñanza, los 
materiales didácticos necesarios, las ideas del gravamen y los 
recursos adicionales. Esta actividad es parte de la colección 
del punto de partida: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212008</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103653</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/salmon-smolt-activity</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
