<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108057</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108057</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087135</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Tramps' Terror."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Terror Der Tramps'."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La "Terreur des Bruits."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Das "Terror Caminhadas."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Terrore Dei Vagabondi."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Τρόμος των αγυρτών."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Terror De los Vagabundos."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The massive growth in unemployment during the depression of the 1870s forced many urban workers to wander from town to town, looking for work. These wanderers often used the railroads to travel, which gave rise to the popular image of the rail-riding "tramp." To some Americans, the unemployed who wandered the country in this manner posed a threat to order and safety. The "tramp menace," many argued, required a repressive response--and advertisements like this exploited the pervasive fear.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das massive Wachstum in der Arbeitslosigkeit während des 
Tiefstands des 1870s erzwang viele städtische Arbeiter wander von 
Stadt zu die Stadt und suchte nach Arbeit. Diese wanderers 
benutzten häufig die Eisenbahnen, um zu reisen, die verursachten das 
populäre Bild des Schiene-Reitens "Tramp." Zu einigen 
Amerikanern warfen die Arbeitslosen, die wandered, das Land in dieser 
Weise eine Drohung auf, um zu bestellen und Sicherheit. Die 
"Trampdrohung," argumentierten viele, benötigt einer repressiven 
Antwort -- und Reklameanzeigen so nutzten die durchdringende Furcht 
aus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La croissance massive du chômage pendant la dépression 
du 1870s a forcé beaucoup d'ouvriers urbains à errer de la ville à 
la ville, recherchant le travail. Ces vagabonds ont souvent 
utilisé les chemins de fer pour voyager, qui ont provoqué l'image 
populaire de la rail-équitation "bruit." À quelques 
Américains, les chômeurs qui ont erré le pays de cette manière ont
posé une menace pour passer commande et la sûreté. La "menace
de bruit," beaucoup ont discuté, requise une réponse répressive -- 
et les annonces comme ceci ont exploité la crainte dominante.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O crescimento maciço no desemprego durante o depression 
do 1870s forçou muitos trabalhadores urbanos a vaguear da cidade à 
cidade, procurando o trabalho. Estes wanderers usaram 
frequentemente as estradas de ferro viajar, que deram a ascensão à 
imagem popular da trilho-equitação "caminhada." A alguns 
americanos, os desempregados que vaguearam o país nesta maneira posed
uma ameaça para requisitar e a segurança. Da "a ameaça 
caminhada," muitos discutiram, requerida uma resposta repressive -- e 
as propagandas como esta exploraram o medo pervasive.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lo sviluppo voluminoso nella disoccupazione durante la 
depressione del 1870s ha forzato molti operai urbani vagare dalla 
città alla città, cercante il lavoro. Questi wanderers hanno 
utilizzato spesso le ferrovie per viaggiare, che hanno provocato 
l'immagine popolare del guida-rail-riding "vagabondo." Ad alcuni
Americani, i disoccupati che hanno vagato il paese in questo modo 
hanno proposto una minaccia per ordinare e la sicurezza. "la 
minaccia del vagabondo," molti hanno discusso, richiesta una risposta 
repressiva -- e le pubblicità come questa hanno sfruttato il timore 
dominante.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ογκώδης αύξηση της ανεργίας κατά τη διάρκεια της 
κατάθλιψης 1870s ανάγκασε πολλούς αστικούς εργαζομένους για να
περιπλανηθεί από την πόλη στην πόλη, ψάχνοντας την εργασία. 
Αυτά τα wanderers χρησιμοποίησαν συχνά τους σιδηροδρόμους
για να ταξιδεψουν, το οποίο προκάλεσε τη δημοφιλή εικόνα του 
ράγα-οδηγώντας "αγύρτη." Σε μερικούς Αμερικανούς, οι 
άνεργοι που περιπλανήθηκαν η χώρα με αυτόν τον τρόπο αποτέλησαν 
απειλή για την κατάταξη και την ασφάλεια. Η "απειλή 
αγυρτών," πολλοί που υποστηρίχτηκαν, απαίτησε μια κατασταλτική 
απάντηση -- και οι διαφημίσεις όπως αυτό εκμεταλλεύτηκαν τον 
κυρίαρχο φόβο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El crecimiento masivo en el desempleo durante la 
depresión del 1870s forzó a muchos trabajadores urbanos vagar de 
ciudad a la ciudad, buscando el trabajo. Estos wanderers 
utilizaron a menudo los ferrocarriles para viajar, que dieron lugar a 
la imagen popular del carril-montar a caballo "vagabundo." A 
algunos americanos, los parados que vagaron el país de este modo 
plantearon una amenaza para ordenar y seguridad. La "amenaza del
vagabundo," muchos discutieron, requerida una respuesta represiva -- y
los anuncios como esto explotaron el miedo penetrante.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087135</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108057</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/tramps-terror</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
