<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104140</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104140</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202652</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Understanding the Complexities of Setting</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Verstehen der Kompliziertheiten der Einstellung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arrangement les complexités du réglage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Compreendendo as complexidades do ajuste</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Capire le complessità di regolazione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατανόηση των περιπλοκών της τιμής τών παραμέτρων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Entender las complejidades de fijar</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In order to address a variety of learning styles with emphasis upon the tactile learner, students will participate in a class project to construct a wall-sized, three dimensional mural of the setting of the novel, "Where the Lillies Bloom". This project cannot be too large. (An outside corridor wall is suggested.) The massive size of the mural makes the project distinctly different from similar art projects attempted in the past; it and also allows students enough space for all of the details desired in the end result of the mural; and affords enough space for all students in the class to display their work.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Um eine Vielzahl der erlernenarten mit 
Hauptgewicht nach dem Tastanfänger zu adressieren, nehmen 
Kursteilnehmer an einem Kategorie Projekt teil um ein Wand-sortiertes,
dreidimensionales Wandbild aus der Einstellung des Romans zu 
konstruieren, "wo die Lillies Blüte". Dieses Projekt kann nicht
zu groß sein. (eine äußere Flurwand wird. vorgeschlagen) 
Die massive Größe des Wandbildes bildet das Projekt deutlich 
unterschiedlich zu den ähnlichen kunstprojekten, die in der 
Vergangenheit versucht werden; sie und gesteht Kursteilnehmern 
genügend Platz für alle Details auch zu, die im Ende Resultat des 
Wandbildes gewünscht werden; und leistet sich genügend Platz 
für alle Kursteilnehmer in der Kategorie, um ihre Arbeit anzuzeigen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Afin d'adresser une variété de modèles d'étude 
avec l'emphase sur l'étudiant tactile, les étudiants participeront 
à un projet de classe pour construire un mural mur-classé et 
tridimensionnel avec de la configuration du roman, "où la fleur de 
Lillies". Ce projet ne peut pas être trop grand. (un mur 
extérieur de couloir est suggéré.) La taille massive du mural
rend le projet distinctement différent des projets semblables d'art 
essayés dans le passé ; elle et permet également à des 
étudiants assez d'espace pour tous les détails désirés dans le 
résultat de fin du mural ; et a les moyens assez d'espace pour 
tous les étudiants dans la classe pour afficher leur travail.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A fim dirigir-se a uma variedade de estilos de 
aprendizagem com ênfase em cima do learner tátil, os estudantes 
participarão em um projeto da classe para construir um mural 
parede-feito sob medida, tridimensional do ajuste da novela, "onde a 
flor de Lillies". Este projeto não pode ser demasiado grande. 
(uma parede exterior do corredor é sugerida.) O tamanho 
maciço do mural faz o projeto distintamente diferente dos projetos 
similares da arte tentados no passado; e permite também a 
estudantes bastante espaço para todos os detalhes desejados no 
resultado de fim do mural; e tem recursos para bastante espaço 
para todos os estudantes na classe indicar seu trabalho.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Per richiamare una varietà di stili imparanti con 
enfasi sul principiante tattile, gli allievi parteciperanno ad un 
progetto del codice categoria per costruire un mural parete-graduato e
tridimensionale con regolazione del romanzo, "dove la fioritura di 
Lillies". Questo progetto non può essere troppo grande. 
(una parete esterna del corridoio è suggerita.) Il 
formato voluminoso del mural rende il progetto distintamente 
differente dai progetti simili di arte tentati nel passato; ed 
egualmente concede ad allievi abbastanza spazio per tutti i 
particolari voluti nel risultato finale del mural; e si permette
abbastanza spazio per tutti gli allievi nel codice categoria per 
visualizzare il loro lavoro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Προκειμένου να εξεταστούν ποικίλες μορφές εκμάθησης 
με την έμφαση επάνω στον αφής αρχάριο, οι σπουδαστές θα 
συμμετάσχουν σε ένα πρόγραμμα κλάσης για να κατασκευαστεί 
τοίχος-ταξινομημένη, διαστατική τοιχογραφία τρεις της τιμής τών 
παραμέτρων του μυθιστορήματος, "όπου η άνθιση Lillies". 
Αυτό το πρόγραμμα δεν μπορεί να είναι πάρα πολύ μεγάλο. 
(Ένας εξωτερικός τοίχος διαδρόμων προτείνεται.) Το 
ογκώδες μέγεθος της τοιχογραφίας καθιστά το πρόγραμμα ευδιάκριτα
διαφορετικό από τα παρόμοια προγράμματα τέχνης που έχουν 
προσπαθηθεί στο παρελθόν  και επιτρέπει επίσης στους 
σπουδαστές αρκετό διάστημα για όλες τις λεπτομέρειες που 
επιδιώκονται στο τελικό αποτέλεσμα της τοιχογραφίας  και 
αντέχει οικονομικά αρκετό διάστημα για όλους τους σπουδαστές 
στην κλάση για να παρουσιάσει την εργασία τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Para tratar una variedad de estilos que aprenden 
con énfasis sobre el principiante táctil, los estudiantes 
participarán en un proyecto de la clase para construir un mural 
pared-clasificado, tridimensional de la configuración de la novela, 
"donde la floración de Lillies". Este proyecto no puede ser 
demasiado grande. (se sugiere una pared exterior del pasillo.) 
La talla masiva del mural hace el proyecto distintamente 
diferente de los proyectos similares del arte procurados en el pasado;
y también no prohibe a estudiantes bastante espacio para todos 
los detalles deseados en el resultado final del mural; y produce
bastante espacio para todos los estudiantes en la clase para 
visualizar su trabajo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAM ALTOM
FN:PAM ALTOM
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202652</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104140</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/understanding-the-complexities-of-setting</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
