<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106464</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106464</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206251</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Energy Activities for Teachers and Students</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Energie-Aktivitäten für Lehrer und 
Kursteilnehmer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Activités d'énergie pour des professeurs et des 
étudiants</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Atividades da energia para professores e 
estudantes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Attività di energia per gli insegnanti e gli 
allievi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ενεργειακές δραστηριότητες για τους δασκάλους και τους 
σπουδαστές</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Actividades de la energía para los profesores y 
los estudiantes</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">offers activities for learning about electrolysis, electric-powered vehicles, ethanol-fueled cars, solar collectors, levers, energy in hurricanes, energy in light, how a thermometer works, liquefied natural gas, solar cooking a hot dog, natural refrigeration, measuring electricity, wind turbines, the blackout of 2003, and underwater oil recovery. Students can use energy surveys to examine energy use at school and at home.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">bietet Aktivitäten für das Lernen über 
Elektrolyse, elektrisch betriebene Träger, Äthanol-getankte Autos, 
Sonnenkollektoren, Hebel, Energie in den Hurrikanen, Energie im Licht,
wie ein Thermometer arbeitet, das verflüssigtes Erdgas an, Solar, 
einen heißen Hund, natürliche eine Abkühlung-, Messenelektrizität,
Windturbinen, die Verdunkelung von 2003 und Unterwasserölwiederanlauf
kochend. Kursteilnehmer können Energieübersichten verwenden, 
um Energiegebrauch an der Schule zu überprüfen und zu Hause.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">offre des activités pour se renseigner sur 
l'électrolyse, les véhicules électriques, les voitures 
éthanol-remplies de combustible, les capteurs solaires, les leviers, 
l'énergie dans les ouragans, l'énergie dans la lumière, comment un 
thermomètre fonctionne, le gaz naturel, solaires liquéfiés faisant 
cuire un hot-dog, une électricité normale de réfrigération, de 
mesure, des turbines de vent, l'arrêt total de 2003, et la reprise 
sous-marine d'huile. Les étudiants peuvent employer des 
enquêtes d'énergie pour examiner l'utilisation d'énergie à 
l'école et à la maison.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">oferece atividades para aprender sobre o 
electrolysis, veículos electric-powered, carros ethanol-abastecidos, 
coletores solares, alavancas, energia nos furacões, energia na luz, 
como um termômetro trabalha, o gás natural, solares liquefied 
cozinhando um cão quente, uma eletricidade natural do refrigeration, 
da medição, umas turbinas do vento, o escurecimento de 2003, e a 
recuperação subaquática do óleo. Os estudantes podem usar 
exames da energia examinar o uso da energia na escola e na HOME.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">offre le attività per imparare circa 
l'elettrolisi, i veicoli elettrici, gli automobili etanolo-riforniti, 
i collettori solari, le leve, l'energia negli uragani, l'energia alla 
luce, come un termometro funziona, il gas naturale, solari liquefatti 
cucinando un cane caldo, un'elettricità naturale di misurazione, di 
refrigerazione, lle turbine del vento, la mancanza di corrente 
elettrica di 2003 ed il recupero subacqueo dell'olio. Gli 
allievi possono usare le indagini di energia per esaminare l'uso di 
energia alla scuola e nel paese.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">προσφέρει τις δραστηριότητες για να μάθει για την 
ηλεκτρόλυση, electric-powered οχήματα, αιθανόλη-τροφοδοτημένα 
με καύσιμα αυτοκίνητα, ηλιακοί συσσωρευτές, μοχλοί, ενέργεια 
στους τυφώνες, ενέργεια στο φως, πώς μια εργασία θερμομέτρων, 
υγροποιημένοι φυσικός αέριο, ηλιακός μαγειρεύοντας ένα χοτ 
ντογκ, φυσική ψύξη, που μετρά την ηλεκτρική ενέργεια, τους 
ανεμοστροβίλους, τη συσκότιση του 2003, και την υποβρύχια 
αποκατάσταση πετρελαίου. Οι σπουδαστές μπορούν να 
χρησιμοποιήσουν τις ενεργειακές έρευνες για να εξετάσουν την 
ενεργειακή χρήση στο σχολείο και στο σπίτι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece las actividades para aprender sobre 
electrólisis, vehículos eléctricos, coches etanol-aprovisionados de
combustible, colectores solares, palancas, energía en huracanes, 
energía en luz, cómo un termómetro funciona, el gas natural, 
solares licuefechos cocinando un perro caliente, una electricidad 
natural de la refrigeración, el medir, turbinas del viento, el 
apagón de 2003, y la recuperación subacuática del aceite. Los
estudiantes pueden utilizar encuestas sobre la energía para examinar 
uso de la energía en la escuela y en el país.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206251</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106464</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/energy-activities-for-teachers-and-students</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
