<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106277</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106277</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086974</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Iroquois were much astonished that two men should have been killed so quickly": Samuel de Champlain Introduces Firearms to Native Warfare, 1609</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die Irokesen wurden viel erstaunt, daß zwei 
Männer so schnell beendet worden sein sollten": Samuel de 
Champlain Introduces Feuerwaffen zu gebürtiger Kriegsführung, 1609</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"les Iroquois ont été beaucoup étonnés que deux
hommes devraient avoir été détruits tellement rapidement" : 
Armes à feu de Samuel de Champlain Introduces à la guerre 
indigène, 1609</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"os iroquois astonished muito que dois homens devem
ter sido matados assim rapidamente": Firearms de Samuel de 
Champlain Introduzir à guerra nativa, 1609</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"i iroquois molto sono stati stupiti che due uomini
dovrebbero essere uccisi così rapidamente": Firearms del Samuel
de Champlain Introduces a guerra natale, 1609</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Iroquois πολύ έμειναν έκπληκτοι ότι δύο άτομα 
πρέπει να έχουν σκοτωθεί τόσο γρήγορα": Πυροβόλα του 
Samuel δε Champlain Introduces στην εγγενή εχθροπραξία, 
1609</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"los iroquois estuvieron asombrados mucho que dos 
hombres deben haber sido matados tan rápidamente": Armas de 
fuego de Samuel de Champlain Introduces a la guerra nativa, 1609</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Samuel de Champlain was a trader, soldier, explorer, diplomat, and author. The critical figure in French efforts to establish the colony of New France along the St. Lawrence river, he set up a small trading post at Quebec, the capital of the colony, in 1608. Given the small numbers of French colonists and their primary interest in the fur trade, Champlain recognized that success depended on alliances with the native peoples of the northern region. In June 1609, Champlain and nine French soldiers joined a war party of Montganais, Algonkaian, and Hurons to fight their enemies, the Iroquois. They met their foe, probably about 200 Mohawks, along the lake later named Lake Champlain. The French firearms caused death and consternation among the Indians and introduced such weapons to native conflicts. Over the next decades, Champlain chronicled his explorations and observations of New France in several volumes, providing important information on life and warfare in seventeenth-century North America.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Samuel de Champlain war ein Händler, ein Soldat, 
ein Forscher, ein Diplomat und ein Autor. Die kritische 
Abbildung in den französischen Bemühungen, die Kolonie von neuem 
Frankreich entlang dem Str. Lawrence Fluß herzustellen, stellte er 
einen kleinen handelnden Pfosten bei Quebec, das Kapital der Kolonie, 
1608 auf. Die eine geringe Anzahl französischen Kolonisten und 
ihr Primärinteresse am Pelzhandel gegeben, erkannte Champlain, daß 
Erfolg von den Bündnissen mit den gebürtigen Völkern der Nordregion
abhing. Im Juni 1609, verbanden Champlain und neun französische
Soldaten eine KriegPartei von Montganais, von Algonkaian und 
von Huronen, um ihre Feinde, den Irokesen zu kämpfen. Sie 
trafen ihren Feind, vermutlich ungefähr 200 Mohikaner, entlang dem 
See später benannter Lake Champlain. Die französischen 
Feuerwaffen verursachten Tod und Bestürzung unter den Indern und 
führten solche Waffen zu den gebürtigen $überschneidungen ein. 
Über den folgenden Dekaden zeichnete Champlain seine 
Erforschungen und Beobachtungen von neuem Frankreich in einigen 
Datenträgern auf und stellte wichtige Informationen auf dem Leben und
Kriegsführung im Seventeenthjahrhundert Nordamerika zur Verfügung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Samuel de Champlain était un commerçant, un 
soldat, un explorateur, un diplomate, et un auteur. La figure 
critique dans des efforts français d'établir la colonie de la 
nouvelle France le long du fleuve de rue Laurent, il a installé un 
petit comptoir commercial chez le Québec, le capital de la colonie, 
en 1608. Etant donné les petits nombres de colons français et 
de leur intérêt primaire pour le commerce de fourrure, Champlain a 
identifié que le succès a dépendu des alliances avec les indigènes
de la région nordique. En juin 1609, Champlain et neuf soldats 
français ont joint une partie de guerre de Montganais, d'Algonkaian, 
et d'Hurons pour combattre leurs ennemis, le Iroquois. Ils ont 
rencontré leur ennemi, probablement environ 200 Mohawk, le long du 
lac Lake Champlain plus tard nommé. Les armes à feu 
françaises ont causé la mort et la consternation parmi les Indiens 
et ont présenté de telles armes aux conflits indigènes. 
Pendant les décennies suivantes, Champlain a fait la chronique 
de ses explorations et observations de la nouvelle France en plusieurs
volumes, fournissant l'information importante la vie et la guerre dans
le nord Amérique de dix-septième-siècle.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Samuel de Champlain era um comerciante, um soldado,
um explorador, um diplomata, e um autor. A figura crítica em 
esforços franceses estabelecer a colônia de France novo ao longo do 
rio do St. Lawrence, ajustou acima um borne negociando pequeno em 
Quebeque, o capital da colônia, em 1608. Dado um pequeno 
número de colonos franceses e seu interesse preliminar no comércio 
da pele, Champlain reconheceu que o sucesso dependeu dos alliances com
os povos nativos da região do norte. Em junho 1609, Champlain e
nove soldados franceses juntaram um partido da guerra de Montganais, 
de Algonkaian, e de hurons para lutar seus inimigos, iroquois. 
Encontraram-se com seu foe, provavelmente aproximadamente 200 
mohawks, ao longo do lago Lago mais tarde nomeado Champlain. Os 
firearms franceses causaram a morte e o consternation entre os indians
e introduziram tais armas aos conflitos nativos. Sobre as 
décadas seguintes, Champlain chronicled suas explorações e 
observações de France novo em diversos volumes, fornecendo a 
informação importante na vida e a guerra no décimo-século America 
do Norte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Samuel de Champlain era un commerciante, un 
soldato, un esploratore, un diplomatico e un autore. La figura 
critica negli sforzi francesi stabilire la colonia di nuova Francia 
lungo il fiume della st Lawrence, ha installato un piccolo alberino di
commercio alla Quebec, il capitale della colonia, in 1608. Dato 
un piccolo numero di colonizzatori francesi ed il loro interesse 
primario nel commercio della pelliccia, Champlain ha riconosciuto che 
il successo dipendeva dalle alleanze con le popolazioni autoctone 
della regione nordica. Nel mese di giugno del 1609, Champlain e 
nove soldati francesi hanno unito un partito di guerra di Montganais, 
di Algonkaian e dei hurons per combattere i loro nemici, il iroquois. 
Hanno venuto a contatto del loro nemico, probabilmente 
circa 200 mohawks, lungo il lago Lake Champlain più successivamente 
chiamato. I firearms francesi hanno causato la morte ed il 
consternation fra gli indiani ed hanno introdotto tali armi ai 
conflitti natali. Durante le decadi prossime, Champlain 
chronicled le sue esplorazioni ed osservazioni di nuova Francia in 
parecchi volumi, fornendo le informazioni importanti sulla vita e la 
guerra nel diciassettesimo-secolo America del Nord.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο Samuel δε Champlain ήταν έμπορος, στρατιώτης, 
εξερευνητής, διπλωμάτης, και συντάκτης. Ο κρίσιμος αριθμός 
στις γαλλικές προσπάθειες να καθιερωθεί η αποικία της νέας 
Γαλλίας κατά μήκος του ποταμού του ST Lawrence, οργάνωσε 
μια μικρή θέση εμπορικών συναλλαγών στο Κεμπέκ, το κεφάλαιο της 
αποικίας, το 1608. Λαμβάνοντας υπόψη τους μικρούς 
αριθμούς γαλλικών αποίκων και αρχικού ενδιαφέροντός τους για το 
εμπόριο γουνών, Champlain αναγνώρισε ότι η επιτυχία 
εξαρτήθηκε από τις συμμαχίες με τους εγγενείς λαούς της βόρειας 
περιοχής. Τον Ιούνιο του 1609, Champlain και εννέα 
γαλλικοί στρατιώτες προσχώρησαν σε ένα πολεμικό συμβαλλόμενο 
μέρος Montganais, Algonkaian, και Hurons για να παλεψουν 
τους εχθρούς τους, iroquois. Συνάντησαν τον εχθρό τους, 
πιθανώς περίπου 200 Mohawks, κατά μήκος της ονομασμένη 
λιμνών αργότερα λίμνης Champlain. Τα γαλλικά πυροβόλα 
προκάλεσαν το θάνατο και την κατάπληξη μεταξύ των Ινδών και 
εισήγαγαν τέτοια όπλα στις εγγενείς συγκρούσεις. Κατά τη 
διάρκεια των επόμενων δεκαετιών, Champlain ηξιστόρησε κατά 
γράμμα τις εξερευνήσεις και τις παρατηρήσεις νέας Γαλλίας του σε 
διάφορες εντάσεις του ήχου, που παρέχουν τις σημαντικές 
πληροφορίες για τη ζωή και την εχθροπραξία στον δέκατος-αιώνα 
Βόρεια Αμερική.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Samuel de Champlain era comerciante, soldado, 
explorador, diplomata, y autor. La figura crítica en esfuerzos 
franceses de establecer a la colonia de Francia nueva a lo largo del 
río del St. Lorenzo, él instaló un poste que negociaba pequeño en 
Quebec, el capital de la colonia, en 1608. Dado los una pequeña
cantidad de colonos franceses y su interés primario en el comercio de
la piel, Champlain reconoció que el éxito dependió de alianzas con 
los indígenas de la región norteña. En junio de de 1609, 
Champlain y nueve soldados franceses ensamblaron un partido de la 
guerra de Montganais, de Algonkaian, y de hurons para luchar a sus 
enemigos, el iroquois. Satisficieron a su enemigo, probablemente
cerca de 200 mohawks, a lo largo del lago Lake más adelante nombrado 
Champlain. Los armas de fuego franceses causaron muerte y 
consternación entre los indios e introdujeron tales armas a los 
conflictos nativos. Durante las décadas próximas, Champlain 
chronicled sus exploraciones y observaciones de Francia nueva en 
varios volúmenes, proporcionando a la información importante el vida
y a la guerra en el decimose'ptimo-siglo Norteamérica.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086974</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106277</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-iroquois-were-much-astonished-that-two-men-should-have-been-killed-so-quickly-samuel-de-champlain-introduces-firearms-to-native-warfare-1609</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
