<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105066</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105066</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207150</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Statue of Liberty Teacher's Corner</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Freiheitsstatue Ecke des Lehrers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Statue du coin du professeur de liberté</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Estátua do canto do professor da liberdade</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Statua del angolo dell'insegnante di libertà</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αγαλμα της γωνίας του δασκάλου ελευθερίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Estatua de la esquina del profesor de la libertad</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features the 305-foot monument that stands in New York Harbor as a symbol of political freedom and democracy. The copper statue, a gift from the people of France, was built by Frederic-Bartholdi in Paris and was dedicated in the U.S. in 1886. This website identifies 11 symbolic elements in the monument and describes seven individuals responsible for its construction.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">kennzeichnet das Denkmal 305-foot, das im New York
Hafen als Symbol der politischen Freiheit und der Demokratie steht. 
Die kupferne Statue, ein Geschenk von den Leuten von Frankreich,
wurde von Frederic-Bartholdi in Paris aufgebaut und wurde in den 
VEREINIGTEN STAATEN 1886 eingesetzt. Diese Web site kennzeichnet
11 symbolische Elemente im Denkmal und beschreibt sieben 
Einzelpersonen, die für seinen Aufbau verantwortlich sind.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">comporte le monument 305-foot qui se tient dans le
port de New York comme symbole de la liberté et de la démocratie 
politiques. La statue de cuivre, un cadeau du peuple de la 
France, a été construite par Frederic-Bartholdi à Paris et a été 
consacrée aux ETATS-UNIS en 1886. Ce site Web identifie 11 
éléments symboliques dans le monument et décrit sept individus 
responsables de sa construction.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">caracteriza o monumento 305-foot que está no 
porto de New York como um símbolo da liberdade e da democracia 
políticas. A estátua de cobre, um presente dos povos de 
France, foi construída por Frederic-Bartholdi em Paris e dedicada nos
ESTADOS UNIDOS em 1886. Este Web site identifica 11 elementos 
simbólicos no monumento e descreve sete indivíduos responsáveis 
para sua construção.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">caratterizza il monumento 305-foot che si leva in 
piedi nel porto de New York come simbolo della libertà e della 
democrazia politiche. La statua di rame, un regalo dalla gente 
della Francia, è stata costruita da Frederic-Bartholdi a Parigi ed è
stata dedicata negli STATI UNITI in 1886. Questo Web site 
identifica 11 elemento simbolico nel monumento e descrive sette 
individui responsabili della relativa costruzione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χαρακτηρίζει το μνημείο 305-ποδιών που στάσεις στο 
λιμάνι της Νέας Υόρκης ως σύμβολο της πολιτικών ελευθερίας και 
της δημοκρατίας. Το άγαλμα χαλκού, ένα δώρο από τους 
πληθυσμούς της Γαλλίας, χτίστηκε από Frederic-Bartholdi στο 
Παρίσι και αφιερώθηκε στις ΗΠΑ το 1886. Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος
προσδιορίζει 11 συμβολικά στοιχεία στο μνημείο και περιγράφει 
επτά άτομα αρμόδια για την κατασκευή του.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece el monumento 305-foot que está parado en 
el puerto de Nueva York como símbolo de la libertad y de la 
democracia políticas. La estatua de cobre, un regalo de la 
gente de Francia, fue construida por Frederic-Bartholdi en París y 
dedicada en los ESTADOS UNIDOS en 1886. Este Web site identifica
11 elementos simbólicos en el monumento y describe a siete individuos
responsables de su construcción.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207150</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105066</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/statue-of-liberty-teachers-corner</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
