<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106456</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106456</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087420</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Bandits or Patriots?: Documents from Charlemagne Pralte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Banditen oder Patrioten?: Dokumente von Karl
der Große Pralte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bandits ou patriotes ? : Documents de 
Charlemagne Pralte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Bandidos ou patriots?: Originais de 
Charlemagne Pralte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Banditi o patriots?: Documenti da 
Charlemagne Pralte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ληστές ή πατριώτες;: Έγγραφα από Charlemagne
Pralte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Bandidos o patriotas?: Documentos de 
Charlemagne Pralte</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1910, an international consortium of banks refinanced Haiti's international debt and took control of the country's treasury. In 1914, the bank refused to issue gold payments to the Haitian government and asked the U.S. military to protect the gold reserves. On December 17, 1914, U.S. marines landed in Haiti and moved the gold to the bank's New York vaults. Eight months later, the marines again landed in Port au Prince, Haiti's capital, this time claiming the need to protect foreign lives and property. They placed Port au Prince under martial law, ruthlessly subdued armed resistance in rural areas, and began training a new Haitian militia. Charlemagne Pralte led a resistance movement. In this "call to arms" and letter to the French minister, Pralte attacked President Wilson as a hypocrite for claiming to respect the sovereignty of small nations of Europe while occupying Haiti and urged Haitians to resist the Americans. (An English translation of the letter follows the French version.)</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1910 nahm eine internationale Vereinigung von 
Bänke neu finanzierten Haitis internationaler Schuld und Steuerung 
des Fiskus des Landes. 1914, die Bank abgelehnt, um 
Goldzahlungen zur haitianischen Regierung herauszugeben und gefragt 
das VEREINIGTE STAATEN Militär, um die Goldbestände zu schützen. 
An Dezember 17, 1914, VEREINIGTE STAATEN Marinen gelandet in 
Haiti und dem Gold auf die Wölbungen New York der Bank verschoben. 
Acht Monate später, landeten die Marinen wieder im Portau 
Prinzen, Kapital Haitis, dieses mal, welches die Notwendigkeit 
behauptet, fremde Lebensdauern und Eigenschaft zu schützen. Sie
plazierten Portau Prinzen unter kriegerisches Gesetz, überwanden 
unbarmherzig bewaffneten Widerstand in den ländlichen Gebieten und 
fingen an, eine neue haitianische Miliz auszubilden. Karl der 
Große Pralte führte eine Widerstandsbewegung. In diesem 
"Aufruf zu den Armen" und im Zeichen zum französischen Minister, 
griff Pralte Präsidenten Wilson als Heuchler an, damit das Behaupten 
respektiert die Hoheit der kleinen Nationen von Europa beim Besetzen 
von von Haiti und von von gedrängten Haitianern, um den Amerikanern 
zu widerstehen. (eine englische Übersetzung des Zeichens folgt 
der französischen Version.)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1910, un consortium international de la dette 
internationale du Haïti refinancé par banques et a pris la commande 
du trésor du pays. À 1914, à la banque refusée pour émettre
des paiements d'or au gouvernement haïtien et demandée les 
militaires des ETATS-UNIS pour protéger les réserves d'or. 
17 décembre 1914, marines des ETATS-UNIS débarquées au 
Haïti et déplacées l'or aux chambres fortes de New York de la 
banque. Pendant huit mois plus tard, les marines ont encore 
débarqué dans le prince gauche d'Au, le capital du Haïti, cette 
fois réclamant la nécessité de protéger les vies et la propriété
étrangères. Ils ont placé le prince gauche d'Au en vertu de 
la loi martiale, ont impitoyablement soumis la résistance armée dans
des zones rurales, et ont commencé à former une nouvelle milice 
haïtienne. Charlemagne Pralte a mené un mouvement de 
résistance. Dans cet "appel aux bras" et lettre au ministre 
français, Pralte a attaqué le Président Wilson en tant qu'hypocrite
pour que prétendre respecte la souveraineté de petites nations de 
l'Europe tout en occupant le Haïti et les haïtiens recommandés pour
résister aux Américains. (une traduction en anglais de la 
lettre suit la version française.)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1910, um consortium internacional do débito 
internacional de Haiti refinanced bancos e fêz exame do controle do 
Tesouraria do país. Em 1914, no banco recusado emitir 
pagamentos do ouro ao governo haitian e perguntado as forças armadas 
de ESTADOS UNIDOS para proteger as reservas de ouro. Em dezembro
17, 1914, fuzileiros navais de ESTADOS UNIDOS aterrados em Haiti e 
movidos o ouro para os vaults de New York do banco. Oito meses 
mais tarde, os fuzileiros navais aterraram outra vez no príncipe 
portuário do au, capital de Haiti, esta vez que reivindica a 
necessidade proteger vidas e a propriedade extrangeiras. 
Colocaram o príncipe portuário do au sob a lei martial, 
subdued ruthlessly resistência armada em áreas rurais, e começaram 
a treinar uma milícia haitian nova. Charlemagne Pralte conduziu
a um movimento de resistência. Neste "atendimento aos braços" 
e em letra ao ministro francês, Pralte atacou o presidente Wilson 
como um hypocrite para que reivindicar respeite o sovereignty de 
nações pequenas de Europa ao ocupar Haiti e haitians incitados para 
resistir os americanos. (uma tradução inglesa da letra segue a
versão francesa.)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1910, un consorzio internazionale del debito 
internazionale dell'Haiti rifinanziata banca ed ha preso il 
controllo del Ministero del Tesoro del paese. In 1914, nella 
banca rifiutata per pubblicare i pagamenti dell'oro al governo 
haitian e chiesta ai militari degli STATI UNITI per proteggere le 
riserve di oro. Dicembre 17, 1914, su fanti di marina degli 
STATI UNITI atterrati in Haiti e spostati l'oro verso le volte de New 
York della banca. Otto mesi più successivamente, i fanti 
di marina hanno atterrato ancora nel principe port dell'Au, il 
capitale dell'Haiti, questo volta che esige la necessità di 
proteggere le vite e la proprietà straniere. Hanno disposto il 
principe port dell'Au secondo legge martial, ruthlessly hanno 
sottomesso la resistenza munita nelle zone rurali ed hanno cominciato 
ad addestrare una nuova milizia haitian. Charlemagne Pralte ha 
condotto un movimento di resistenza. In questa "chiamata 
all'armi" e nella lettera al ministro francese, Pralte ha 
attacato il presidente Wilson come hypocrite affinchè sostenere 
rispetti la sovranità di piccole nazioni di Europa mentre occupava 
l'Haiti ed i haitians sollecitati per resistere agli Americani. 
(una traduzione in inglese della lettera segue la versione 
francese.)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1910, μια διεθνής κοινοπραξία των τραπεζών 
αναχρηματοδότησε το διεθνές χρέος της Αϊτής και πήρε τον έλεγχο
του Υπουργείου Οικονομικών της χώρας. Το 1914, η τράπεζα 
αρνήθηκε να διανείμει τις χρυσές πληρωμές στην αϊτινή κυβέρνηση
και ζήτησε από τις ΗΠΑ στρατιωτικές για να προστατεύσει τις 
χρυσές επιφυλάξεις. Στις 17 Δεκεμβρίου ..1914, τα 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΑ ναυτικά προσγειώθηκαν στην Αϊτή και κίνησαν το χρυσό
προς τους υπόγειους θαλάμους της Νέας Υόρκης της τράπεζας. 
Οκτώ μήνες αργότερα, τα ναυτικά προσγειώθηκαν πάλι στον 
πρίγκηπα Au λιμένων, κεφάλαιο της Αϊτής, απαιτώντας αυτή τη 
φορά την ανάγκη να προστατεύσουν τις ξένες ζωές και την 
ιδιοκτησία. Τοποθέτησαν τον πρίγκηπα Au λιμένων βάσει 
του στρατιωτικού νόμου, κατάκτησε άσπλαχνα την οπλισμένη 
αντίσταση στις αγροτικές περιοχές, και άρχισε μια νέα αϊτινή 
πολιτοφυλακή. Το Charlemagne Pralte οδήγησε μια 
μετακίνηση αντίστασης. Σε αυτήν την "κλήση στα όπλα" και 
την επιστολή στο γαλλικό υπουργό, Pralte επιτέθηκε στον 
Πρόεδρο Wilson ως υποκριτή για να υποστηρίξει ότι σέβεται η 
κυριαρχία των μικρών εθνών της Ευρώπης καταλαμβάνοντας την Αϊτή
και ώθησε Αϊτινούς για να αντισταθεί στους Αμερικανούς. 
(Μια αγγλική μετάφραση της επιστολής ακολουθεί τη γαλλική 
εκδοχή.)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1910, un consorcio internacional de la deuda 
internacional de Haití financiado de nuevo las baterías y tomó el 
control del Hacienda del país. En 1914, la batería rechazada 
para publicar pagos del oro al gobierno haitiano y preguntada los 
militares de ESTADOS UNIDOS para proteger las reservas de oro. 
De diciembre el 17, 1914, infantes de marina de ESTADOS UNIDOS 
aterrizados en Haití y movidos el oro a las cámaras acorazadas de 
Nueva York de la batería. Ocho meses más adelante, los 
infantes de marina aterrizaron otra vez en el príncipe portuario del 
au, capital de Haití, este vez que demandaba la necesidad de proteger
vidas y la característica no nativas. Colocaron a príncipe 
portuario del au bajo ley marcial, sometieron despiadadamente 
resistencia armada en áreas rurales, y comenzaron a entrenar a una 
nueva milicia haitiana. Charlemagne Pralte condujo un 
movimiento de resistencia. En esta "llamada a los brazos" y 
carta al ministro francés, Pralte atacó a presidente Wilson como 
hipócrita para que el demandar respete la soberanía de naciones 
pequeñas de Europa mientras que ocupaba Haití y a haitianos 
impulsados para resistir a los americanos. (una traducción 
inglesa de la carta sigue la versión francesa.)</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087420</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106456</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/bandits-or-patriots-documents-from-charlemagne-pralte</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
