<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103978</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103978</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206668</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Presidency</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Vorsitz</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Présidence</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Presidency</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Presidenza</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η προεδρία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Presidencia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features 40 documents from 23 Presidents -- Washington's first inaugural address, Adams' description of his reception by King George III as America's first minister to Great Britain, Adams' letter ordering the relocation of government offices from Philadelphia to D.C., Lincoln's instructions to the commander at Fort Sumter, Roosevelt's letter thanking Oppenheimer and his colleagues for their ongoing secret atomic research, and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Merkmale 40 Dokumente von 23 Präsidenten -- 
Washingtons erste Eröffnungsadresse, Beschreibung Adams' seiner 
Aufnahme durch König George III als Amerikas erster Minister nach 
Großbritannien, Zeichen Adams', welches die Verschiebung der 
Regierungsstellen von Philadelphia zu Gleichstrom, Anweisungen 
Lincolns zum Kommandanten am Zeichen des Forts Sumter, Roosevelts 
Oppenheimer und seinen Kollegen für ihre fortwährende geheime 
Atomforschung dankend und an mehr bestellt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dispositifs 40 documents de 23 présidents -- la 
première adresse inaugurale de Washington, la description d'Adams de 
sa réception par roi George III comme premier ministre de 
l'Amérique vers la Grande-Bretagne, la lettre d'Adams commandant le 
réadressage des bureaux de gouvernement de Philadelphie à C.C, les 
instructions de Lincoln au commandant à la lettre de fort Sumter, de 
Roosevelt remerciant Oppenheimer et ses collègues de leur recherche 
atomique secrète continue, et à plus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">características 40 originais de 23 presidentes --
primeiro endereço inaugural de Washington, descrição de Adams' de 
sua recepção pelo rei George III como o primeiro ministro de 
América a Grâ Bretanha, letra de Adams' que requisita o relocation 
de escritórios de governo de Filadélfia a C.C., instruções de 
Lincoln ao comandante na letra do fort Sumter, do Roosevelt 
agradecendo Oppenheimer e seus colegas para sua pesquisa atômica 
secreta ongoing, e em mais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">caratteristiche 40 documenti da 23 presidenti -- 
il primo indirizzo inaugurale de Washington, descrizione del Adams 
della sua ricezione dal re George III come America in primo luogo 
assiste in Gran Bretagna, lettera del Adams che ordina la 
rilocazione dei servizi governativi da Filadelfia alla CC, istruzioni 
de Lincoln al comandante alla lettera Forte del Roosevelt, di 
Sumter ringraziante Oppenheimer ed i suoi colleghe per la loro ricerca
atomica segreta continua ed a più.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χαρακτηρίζει 40 έγγραφα από 23 Προέδρους -- 
πρώτη εναρκτήρια διεύθυνση της Ουάσιγκτον, περιγραφή των Adams
της λήψης του από το βασιλιά George ΙΙΙ ως πρώτο υπουργό της 
Αμερικής στη Μεγάλη Βρετανία, επιστολή των Adams που διατάζει 
την επαναμετάθεση των κυβερνητικών γραφείων από τη Φιλαδέλφεια 
στο ΣΥΝΕΧΈΣ ΡΕΎΜΑ, οδηγίες του Λίνκολν στο διοικητή στο οχυρό 
Sumter, την επιστολή Roosevelt που ευχαριστούν Oppenheimer 
και τους συναδέλφους του για την τρέχουσα μυστική ατομική έρευνά
τους, και περισσότεροι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">características 40 documentos a partir de 23 
presidentes -- primer direccionamiento inaugural de Washington, 
descripción de Adams de su recepción de rey George III como primer 
ministro de América a Gran Bretaña, carta de Adams que pide la 
realocación de las oficinas gubernamentales de Philadelphia a C.C., 
instrucciones de Lincoln al comandante en la carta de la fortaleza 
Sumter, de Roosevelt agradeciendo a Oppenheimer y a sus colegas por su
investigación atómica secreta en curso, y más.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206668</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103978</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-presidency</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
