<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103058</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103058</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085241</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Changing Workplace</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Ändernde Arbeitsplatz</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Lieu de travail Changeant</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Workplace Em mudança</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Posto di lavoro Cambiante</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο μεταβαλλόμενος εργασιακός χώρος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Lugar de trabajo Que cambia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The 20th century ushered in a change from handcrafting to machine tooling. Henry Ford introduced one of the first moving assembly lines as a way to turn out more cars more quickly, and the emerging auto industry popularized this mode. A photo of the Doble Steam Motors Corporation factory shows a line of workers and car chassis in production. This new technology, and the spread of industrialization, changed forever the way that work was completed. A wide variety of industries all across the country converted to mechanization, and California was no exception. One 1929 image shows young women working in a towel factory in Orange. Photographs taken in San Francisco illustrate that workers used machines to make products as different as Ghirardelli Chocolate and music rolls for automated player pianos. Images also show women working on an assembly line in a soap factory, and men sewing clothes in a shop (at a time when a good suit, cut on machines instead of by hand, retailed for $40 to $50). Automation and mechanization also changed agricultural practices. The combined traction steam harvester built by Stockton J. Barry on his California ranch was one of the machines that changed the way produce was harvested. Mechanized canning changed the way fruit and vegetables were processed and preserved, and made out-of-season produce available year round. Photographs in this group show cannery workers at tables, and cans going through a labeling machine. The introduction of mechanized food processing eventually brought a new awareness of the importance of standards for foods production. The Pure Food and Drug Act and the Meat Inspection Act were both passed in 1906. As workers nationwide adjusted to an increasingly mechanized workplace, good working conditions took on new importance. Workers in several industries formed unions (such as the Berryessa Fruit Growers formed in 1920, shown here) to promote safer working conditions and limit maximum working hours.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das 20. Jahrhundert hineingeführt in einer 
Änderung vom Handcrafting an der Maschine Werkzeugausstattung. 
Henry Ford führte eins der ersten beweglichen Fließbänder als
Methode, sich aus mehr Autos schneller zu drehen ein, und die 
auftauchende Selbstindustrie popularisierte diesen Modus. Ein 
Foto der Doble Steam Motors Corporation Fabrik zeigt eine Zeile der 
Arbeiter und des Autochassis in der Produktion. Diese neue 
Technologie und die Verbreitung der Industrialisierung, für immer 
geändert der Methode, die Arbeit durchgeführt wurde. Eine 
breite Vielzahl von Industrien alle über dem Land, das in 
Mechanisierung umgewandelt wurde, und Kalifornien waren keine 
Ausnahme. Ein 1929 Bild zeigt die jungen Frauen, die in einer 
Tuchfabrik in der Orange arbeiten. Die Fotographien, die in San 
Francisco genommen werden, veranschaulichen daß Arbeiter benutzte 
Maschinen, um Produkte so unterschiedlich zu bilden wie Ghirardelli 
Schokolade und Musikrollen für automatisierte Spielerklaviere. 
Bilder zeigen auch die Frauen, die auf einem Fließband in einer
Seifenfabrik arbeiten, und die Männer, die Kleidung in einem System 
nähen (zu einer Zeit als eine gute Klage, Schnitt auf Maschinen 
anstelle von eigenhändig, retailed für $40 bis $50). 
Automatisierung und der Mechanisierung auch geänderte 
landwirtschaftliche Praxis. Die kombinierte 
Zugkraftdampferntemaschine, die durch Stockton J. Barry auf seiner 
Kalifornien Ranch aufgebaut wurde, war eine der Maschinen, die die 
Methode änderten, die, Erzeugnis geerntet wurde. Das 
mechanisierte Einmachen änderte das Methode Obst und Gemüse wurden 
und das konservierte verarbeitet, und gebildete vorhandene Jahr des 
Heraus-vonjahreszeit Erzeugnisses rund. Fotographien in dieser 
Gruppe zeigen Konservenfabrikarbeiter an den Tischen und an den Dosen,
die eine Etikettiermaschine durchlaufen. Die Einleitung von 
mechanisiertem Nahrungsmittelschließlich verarbeiten holte ein neues 
Bewußtsein des Wertes der Standards für Nahrungsmittelproduktion. 
Die reine Nahrungsmittel-und Droge-Tat und die Fleisch-Kontrolle
Tat wurden beide 1906 geführt. Als Arbeiter, die im ganzen Land
auf einen in zunehmendem Maße mechanisierten Arbeitsplatz justiert 
wurden, nahmen gute Arbeitsbedingungen auf neuem Wert. Arbeiter 
in einigen Industrien gebildeten Anschlüßen (wie den Berryessa 
Frucht-Züchtern gebildet 1920, hier dargestellt) zum der sichereren 
Arbeitsbedingungen und Begrenzung der maximalen Arbeitsstunden zu 
fördern.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le 20ème siècle déclenché un changement de 
handcrafting à l'outillage de machine. Henry Ford a présenté 
une des premières chaînes de montage mobiles comme voie de s'avérer
plus de voitures plus rapidement, et l'industrie automatique naissante
a popularisé ce mode. Une photo de l'usine de Doble Steam 
Motors Corporation montre une ligne des ouvriers et du châssis de 
voiture dans la production. Cette nouvelle technologie, et la 
diffusion de l'industrialisation, changée pour toujours la manière 
dont le travail a été terminé. Une grande variété des 
industries toutes à travers le pays converti en mécanisation, et la 
Californie n'étaient aucune exception. Une 1929 images montrent
de jeunes femmes travaillant dans une usine de serviette dans 
l'orange. Les photographies prises dans San Francisco 
illustrent que les machines utilisées par ouvriers pour rendre des 
produits aussi différents que des roulements de chocolat et de 
musique de Ghirardelli pour les pianos automatisés de joueur. 
Les images montrent également des femmes travaillant sur une 
chaîne de montage dans une savonnerie, et des hommes cousant des 
vêtements dans un système (à un moment où un bon costume, coupe 
sur des machines au lieu d'à la main, vendu au détail pour $40 à 
$50). Pratiques en matière agricoles également changées 
d'automatisation et de mécanisation. La moissonneuse combinée 
de vapeur de traction établie par Stockton J. Barry sur son ranch de 
la Californie était l'une des machines qui ont changé la voie que le
produit a été moissonné. La mise en boîte mécanisée a 
changé le fruit de voie et des légumes ont été traités et année 
disponible préservée et et faite de produit de dehors-de-saison 
ronde. Les photographies dans ce groupe montrent des ouvriers de
fabrique de conserves aux tables, et aux bidons passant par une 
machine à étiquettes. L'introduction de la transformation des 
produits alimentaires mécanisée par la suite a apporté une nouvelle
conscience d'importance des normes pour la production de nourritures. 
La Loi pure et l'acte toutes les deux de nourriture et de drogue
d'inspection de viande ont été passés en 1906. Comme ouvriers
dans tout le pays ajustés sur un lieu de travail de plus en plus 
mécanisé, les bonnes conditions de travail ont pris la nouvelle 
importance. Ouvriers dans plusieurs syndicats formés par 
industries (tels que les cultivateurs de fruit de Berryessa formés en
1920, montré ici) pour favoriser des conditions de travail plus 
sûres et des heures de travail maximum de limite.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O 20o século ushered em uma mudança de 
handcrafting ao trabalho feito com ferramentas da máquina. O 
Henry Ford introduziu uma das primeiras linhas de conjunto moventes 
como uma maneira girar mais rapidamente para fora de mais carros, e a 
auto indústria emergente popularized esta modalidade. Uma foto 
da fábrica de Doble Vapor Motores Corporation mostra uma linha dos 
trabalhadores e do chassi do carro na produção. Esta 
tecnologia nova, e a propagação do industrialization, mudada para 
sempre a maneira que o trabalho foi terminado. Uma variedade 
larga das indústrias todas através do país convertido ao 
mechanization, e Califórnia não eram nenhuma exceção. Uma 
1929 imagens mostram as mulheres novas que trabalham em uma fábrica 
de toalha na laranja. As fotografias feitas exame em San 
Francisco ilustram que máquinas usadas trabalhadores para fazer 
produtos tão diferentes quanto rolos do chocolate e da música de 
Ghirardelli para pianos automatizados do jogador. As imagens 
mostram também as mulheres que trabalham em uma linha de conjunto em 
uma fábrica de sabão, e os homens que sewing a roupa em uma loja (em
uma hora em que um terno bom, corte em máquinas em vez pela mão, 
vendida a varejo para $40 a $50). Práticas agriculturais 
também mudadas da automatização e do mechanization. O 
harvester combinado do vapor da tração construído por Stockton J. 
Barry em seu rancho de Califórnia era uma das máquinas que mudaram a
maneira que o produto foi colhido. Enlatar mechanized mudou a 
fruta da maneira e os vegetais foram processados e ano disponível 
preservado, e feito do produto da para fora-$$$-ESTAÇÃO redondo. 
As fotografias neste grupo mostram trabalhadores da fábrica de 
conservas em tabelas, e em latas que atravessam uma máquina 
etiquetando. A introdução de processar de alimento mechanized 
eventualmente trouxe uma consciência nova da importância dos 
padrões para a produção dos alimentos. O ato puro do alimento
e da droga e o ato ambos da inspeção da carne foram passados em 
1906. Como os trabalhadores ajustados por todo o país a um 
workplace cada vez mais mechanized, as condições de funcionamento 
boas fizeram exame na importância nova. Trabalhadores em 
diversas uniões dadas forma indústrias (tais como os growers da 
fruta de Berryessa dados forma em 1920, mostrado aqui) para promover 
condições de funcionamento mais seguras e horas de funcionamento 
máximas do limite.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il ventesimo secolo introdotto un cambiamento dal 
handcrafting alla lavorazione con utensili della macchina. Il 
henry Ford ha introdotto una delle prime catene di montaggio 
commoventi come modo risultare più rapidamente più automobili e 
l'industria automatica d'emersione ha diffuso questo modo. Una 
foto della fabbrica di Doble Steam Motors Corporation mostra una riga 
degli operai e del telaio dell'automobile nella produzione. 
Questa nuova tecnologia e la diffusione 
dell'industrializzazione, cambiata per sempre il modo che il lavoro è
stato completato. Un'ampia varietà di industrie tutta 
attraverso il paese si è convertita in meccanizzazione e la 
California faceva eccezione. Un'1929 immagini mostrano le donne 
giovani che lavorano in una fabbrica del tovagliolo in arancio. 
Le fotografie prese a San Francisco illustrano che gli operai 
hanno utilizzato le macchine per rendere i prodotti differenti come 
rulli del cioccolato e di musica di Ghirardelli per i piani 
automatizzati del giocatore. Le immagini egualmente mostrano le 
donne che lavorano ad una catena di montaggio in una fabbrica di 
sapone e gli uomini che cucono i vestiti in un negozio (in un momento 
in cui un buon vestito, taglio sulle macchine anziché a mano, venduto
al dettaglio per $40 - $50). Pratiche agricole anche cambiate di
meccanizzazione e di automazione. La mietitrice unita del vapore
della trazione sviluppata da Stockton J. Barry sul suo ranch della 
California era una delle macchine che hanno cambiato il modo che i 
prodotti sono stati raccolti. L'inscatolamento meccanizzato ha 
cambiato la frutta di modo e le verdure sono state elaborate ed anno 
disponibile conservato e e fatto dei prodotti di fuori-de-stagione 
rotondo. Le fotografie in questo gruppo mostrano gli operai del 
conservificio alle tabelle ed alle latte che passano tramite 
un'etichettatrice. L'introduzione di trasformazione dei prodotti
alimentari meccanizzata finalmente ha portato una nuova consapevolezza
dell'importanza degli standard per produzione degli alimenti. La
Legge pura della droga e dell'alimento e la Legge entrambe di 
controllo della carne sono state passate in 1906. Come operai in
tutta la nazione registrati ad un posto di lavoro sempre più 
meccanizzato, le buone condizioni di lavoro hanno intrapreso la nuova 
importanza. Gli operai in parecchie industrie hanno formato i 
sindacati (quali i coltivatori della frutta di Berryessa formati in 
1920, indicato qui) per promuovere le condizioni di lavoro più sicuri
e le ore lavorative massime di limite.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο 20ός αιώνας ανήγγειλε μέσα μια αλλαγή από στην 
εργαλειομηχανή. Θ*Χενρυ Ford εισήγαγε μιας από τις πρώτες
κινούμενες γραμμές συμβολικών γλωσσών ως τρόπος να βγαλθούν 
περισσότερα αυτοκίνητα γρηγορότερα, και η αναδυόμενη αυτόματη 
βιομηχανία διέδωσε αυτόν τον τρόπο. Μια φωτογραφία του 
εργοστασίου εταιριών μηχανών ατμού Doble εμφανίζει μια γραμμή
εργαζομένων και πλαισίων αυτοκινήτων στην παραγωγή. Αυτή η 
νέα τεχνολογία, και η διάδοση της εκβιομηχάνισης, άλλαξαν για 
πάντα τον τρόπο ότι η εργασία ολοκληρώθηκε. Μια ευρεία 
ποικιλία των βιομηχανιών όλες σε ολόκληρη τη χώρα που 
μετατράπηκε στη μηχανοποίηση, και Καλιφόρνια δεν ήταν καμία 
εξαίρεση. Μια εικόνα του 1929 εμφανίζει νέες γυναίκες 
που εργάζονται σε ένα εργοστάσιο πετσετών στο πορτοκάλι. Οι
φωτογραφίες που λαμβάνονται στο Σαν Φρανσίσκο διευκρινίζουν ότι 
οι εργαζόμενοι χρησιμοποίησαν τις μηχανές για να καταστήσουν τα 
προϊόντα τόσο διαφορετικά όσο τους ρόλους σοκολάτας 
Ghirardelli και μουσικής για τα αυτοματοποιημένα πιάνα φορέων. 
Οι εικόνες εμφανίζουν επίσης τις γυναίκες που εργάζονται σε
μια γραμμή συμβολικών γλωσσών σε ένα εργοστάσιο σαπουνιών, και 
άνδρες που ράβουν τα ενδύματα σε ένα κατάστημα (σε μία εποχή 
που ένα καλό κοστούμι, αποκοπή στις μηχανές αντί με το χέρι, 
που πουλιέται λιανικώς για $40 έως $50). Η 
αυτοματοποίηση και η μηχανοποίηση άλλαξαν επίσης τις γεωργικές 
πρακτικές. Η συνδυασμένη θεριστική μηχανή ατμού έλξης που 
στηρίχτηκε από Stockton Θ*ι. Barry στο αγρόκτημα Καλιφόρνιας
του ήταν μια από τις μηχανές που άλλαξαν τον τρόπο που τα 
προϊόντα συγκομίστηκαν. Η μηχανοποιημένη κονσερβοποίηση 
άλλαξε τα φρούτα τρόπων και τα λαχανικά υποβλήθηκαν σε 
επεξεργασία και συντηρήθηκαν, και έγιναν τα προϊόντα 
έξω-$$$-ΕΠΟΧΉΣ διαθέσιμα το χρόνο. Οι φωτογραφίες σε αυτήν
την ομάδα εμφανίζουν τους εργαζομένους κονσερβοποιείων στους 
πίνακες, και δοχεία που περνούν από μια μηχανή μαρκαρίσματος. 
Η εισαγωγή της μηχανοποιημένης επεξεργασίας τροφίμων έφερε 
τελικά μια νέα συνειδητοποίηση της σημασίας των προτύπων για την 
παραγωγή τροφίμων. Τον καθαρό νόμο και ο νόμος και οι δύο 
τροφίμων και φαρμάκων επιθεώρησης κρέατος πέρασαν το 1906. 
Σαν εργαζομένους σε εθνικό επίπεδο που προσαρμόστηκε σε 
έναν όλο και περισσότερο μηχανοποιημένο εργασιακό χώρο, οι 
καλές συνθήκες εργασίας πήραν τη νέα σημασία. Οι 
εργαζόμενοι σε διάφορες βιομηχανίες συγκρότησαν τις 
συνδικαλιστικές οργανώσεις (όπως οι καλλιεργητές φρούτων 
Berryessa που διαμορφώνονται το 1920, εμφανισμένος εδώ) για 
να προωθήσουν τις ασφαλέστερες συνθήκες εργασίας και να 
περιορίσουν τις μέγιστες ώρες απασχόλησης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El vigésimo siglo llevado en un cambio de 
handcrafting a los útiles de la máquina. El Henrio Ford 
introdujo una de las primeras plantas de fabricación móviles como 
manera de resultar más coches más rápidamente, y la industria auto 
que emergía popularizó este modo. Una foto de la fábrica de 
Doble Steam Motors Corporation muestra una línea de trabajadores y 
del chasis del coche en la producción. Esta nueva tecnología, 
y la extensión de la industrialización, cambiante por siempre la 
manera que el trabajo fue terminado. Una variedad amplia de las 
industrias toda a través del país convertido a la mecanización, y 
California no eran ninguna anomalía. Una 1929 imágenes 
muestran a mujeres jóvenes que trabajan en una fábrica de la toalla 
en naranja. Las fotografías tomadas en San Francisco ilustran 
que las máquinas usadas los trabajadores para hacer productos tan 
diferentes como los rodillos del chocolate y de la música de 
Ghirardelli para los pianos automatizados del jugador. Las 
imágenes también muestran a las mujeres que trabajan en una planta 
de fabricación en una fábrica de jabón, y a hombres que cosen las 
ropas en un departamento (en un momento en que un buen juego, corte en
las máquinas en vez de a mano, vendido al por menor para $40 a $50). 
Prácticas agrícolas también cambiantes de la automatización 
y de la mecanización. La máquina segador combinada del vapor 
de la tracción construida por Stockton J. Barry en su rancho de 
California era una de las máquinas que cambiaron la manera que el 
producto fue cosechado. El conservar mecanizado cambió la fruta
de la manera y los vehículos fueron procesados y año disponible 
preservado, y hecho del producto de la hacia fuera-de-estacio'n 
redondo. Las fotografías en este grupo muestran a trabajadores 
del cannery en los vectores, y las latas que pasan a través de una 
máquina de etiquetado. La introducción de la transformación 
de los alimentos mecanizada eventual trajo un nuevo conocimiento de la
importancia de los estándares para la producción de los alimentos. 
El acto puro y el acto ambos del alimento y de la droga del 
examen de la carne fueron pasados en 1906. Como trabajadores por
toda la nación ajustados a un lugar de trabajo cada vez más 
mecanizado, las buenas condiciones de trabajo adquirieron nueva 
importancia. Trabajadores en varias uniones formadas industrias 
(tales como los cultivadores de la fruta de Berryessa formados en 
1920, mostrado aquí) para promover condiciones de trabajo más 
seguras y horas de funcionamiento máximas del límite.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085241</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103058</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-changing-workplace</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
