<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103460</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103460</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206680</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">At a Crossroads: The King of Prussia Inn</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">An einer Querstraße: Der König des 
Preußen-Gasthauses</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">À un carrefour : Le roi de l'auberge de la 
Prusse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em um crossroads: O rei do inn do prussia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ad una strada trasversale: Il re della 
locanda del prussia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σταυροδρόμια: Ο βασιλιάς του πανδοχείου της 
Πρωσίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En una encrucijada: El rey del mesón del 
prussia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">recounts the history of this inn, built originally as a farmhouse in 1719 at an intersection of two roads northwest of Philadelphia, not far from Valley Forge. The inn provided hospitality to travelers when the colony was just a scattering of farms. In part because of its location, it became a prosperous tavern, inn, and social center for the evolving community of the same name.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">zählt die Geschichte dieses Gasthauses nach, 
ursprünglich aufgebaut als Bauernhaus 1719 an einem Durchschnitt des 
zwei Straßen Nordwestens von Philadelphia, nicht weit von 
Senke-Schmiede. Das Gasthaus stellte Gastfreundschaft zu den 
Reisenden zur Verfügung, als die Kolonie ein Zerstreuen der 
Bauernhöfe gerecht war. Im Teil wegen seines Standorts, wurde 
es ein wohlhabender Tavern, ein Gasthaus und eine Sozialmitte für die
entwickelnde Gemeinschaft des gleichen Namens.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">raconte l'histoire de cette auberge, établie 
initialement comme ferme en 1719 à une intersection de nord-ouest de 
deux routes de Philadelphie, pas loin de forge de vallée. 
L'auberge a fourni l'hospitalité aux voyageurs quand la colonie
était juste une dispersion des fermes. En partie en raison de 
son emplacement, c'est devenu une taverne prospère, une auberge, et 
un centre social pour la communauté d'évolution du même nom.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">recounts o history deste inn, construído 
originalmente como um farmhouse em 1719 em uma interseção de um 
noroeste de duas estradas de Filadélfia, não longe da forja do vale.
O inn forneceu o hospitality aos viajantes quando a colônia era
justa dispersar das fazendas. Na parte por causa de sua 
posição, transformou-se um tavern próspero, um inn, e um centro 
social para a comunidade em desenvolvimento do mesmo nome.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">racconta la storia di questa locanda, sviluppata 
originalmente come fattoria in 1719 ad un'intersezione di un 
nord-ovest delle due strade di Filadelfia, non lontano dalla forgia 
della valle. La locanda ha fornito l'ospitalità ai viaggiatori 
quando la colonia era giusta una dispersione dei poderi. In 
parte a causa della relativa posizione, si è transformato in in una 
locanda prosperosa, in una locanda ed in un centro sociale per la 
Comunità d'evoluzione dello stesso nome.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξιστορεί την ιστορία αυτού του πανδοχείου, που 
χτίζεται αρχικά καθώς farmhouse το 1719 σε μια διατομή των 
βορειοδυτικών δύο δρόμων της Φιλαδέλφειας, όχι μακριά από την 
κοιλάδα σφυρηλατεί. Το πανδοχείο παρείχε τη φιλοξενία στους
ταξιδιώτες όταν η αποικία ήταν ακριβώς μια διασπορά των 
αγροκτημάτων. Εν μέρει λόγω της θέσης του, έγινε μια 
ακμάζουσα ταβέρνα, ένα πανδοχείο, και κοινωνικό κέντρο για την 
εξελισσόμενη κοινότητα του ίδιου ονόματος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">contó de nuevo la historia de este mesón, 
construida originalmente como cortijo en 1719 en una intersección del
noroeste de dos caminos de Philadelphia, no lejos de la fragua del 
valle. El mesón proporcionó a hospitalidad a las hojas de ruta
(traveler) cuando la colonia era justa una dispersión de granjas. 
En parte debido a su localización, se convirtió en una taberna
próspera, un mesón, y un centro social para la comunidad de 
desarrollo del mismo nombre.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206680</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103460</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/at-a-crossroads-the-king-of-prussia-inn</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
