<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106917</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106917</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086218</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Having Tasted the Sweets of  Freedom ": Cato Petitions the Pennsylvania Legislature to Remain Free</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">", die Bonbons der Freiheit schmeckend": 
Cato ersucht die Pennsylvania Gesetzgebung, frei zu bleiben</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"après avoir goûté les bonbons de la liberté" 
: Cato pétitionne la législature de la Pennsylvanie rester 
librement</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"provando os doces da liberdade": Cato 
peticiona a legislatura de Pensilvânia remanescer livre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"assagiando i dolci di libertà": Cato fa 
una petizione la legislatura della Pensilvania rimanere liberamente</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Δοκιμάζοντας τα γλυκά της ελευθερίασ": Το 
Cato υποβάλλει αίτηση στο νομοθετικό σώμα της Πενσυλβανίας για
να παραμείνει ελεύθερο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"probando los dulces de la libertad": Cato 
solicita a legislatura de Pennsylvania permanecer libremente</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Pressures for abolition of slavery increased in the Revolutionary era; five northern states abolished slavery between 1780 and 1804. Pennsylvania was the first in 1780 when its legislature passed a gradual abolition bill. However, no one was actually freed; all those enslaved when the law went into effect remained enslaved, and all those born after that date were required to provide their mothers' masters with twenty-eight years of servitude before they could obtain their freedom. Despite the law's extreme gradualism, the following year a more conservative legislature attempted to repeal it. Newly freed African Americans petitioned the Assembly to reject such a move. Cato, newly freed with his children, wrote to  Philadelphia's Freeman's Journal , an African-American newspaper, in 1781, making his case by using the legislature's own words about the promise of universal civilization while adding his own views of the meaning of the Revolution. The legislature voted against repealing the gradual abolition act.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Druck für Aufhebung der Sklaverei erhöhte sich 
der revolutionären Ära; fünf Nordzustände schufen Sklaverei 
zwischen 1780 und 1804 ab. Pennsylvania war das erste 1780, als 
seine Gesetzgebung einen stufenweisen Aufhebung Gesetz verabschiedete.
Jedoch wurde niemand wirklich freigegeben; alles 
versklavten die, als das Gesetz in Effekt blieb versklavt einstieg und
alles die, die nach diesem Datum getragen wurden, benoetigt wurden, um
Meister ihre Mutter mit achtundzwanzig Jahren der Versklavung zu 
versehen, bevor sie ihre Freiheit erreichen konnten. Trotz des 
extremen gradualism des Gesetzes das folgende Jahr versuchte eine 
konservativere Gesetzgebung, es zu widerrufen. Eben freigegebene
afrikanische Amerikaner ersuchten die Versammlung, solch eine Bewegung
zurückzuweisen. Cato, eben freigegeben mit seinen Kindern, 
schrieb zum Journal des Ehrenbürgers Philadelphias, eine 
Afrikanisch-Amerikanische Zeitung, 1781 und bildete seinen Fall, indem
er verwendete eigene Wörter der Gesetzgebung über die Versprechung 
der Universalzivilisation beim Hinzufügen seiner eigenen Ansichten 
der Bedeutung von der Umdrehung. Die Gesetzgebung wählte gegen 
das Widerrufen der stufenweisen Aufhebung Tat.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les pressions pour l'abolition de l'esclavage ont 
augmenté dans l'ère révolutionnaire ; cinq états nordiques 
ont supprimé l'esclavage entre 1780 et 1804. La Pennsylvanie 
était la première en 1780 où sa législature a passé une facture 
progressive d'abolition. Cependant, personne n'a été libéré 
réellement ; tout ceux ont asservi quand la loi est entrée 
dans l'effet est restée asservie, et tout ceux soutenues après cette
date ont été exigées pour fournir aux maîtres de leurs mères 
vingt-huit ans de servitude avant qu'elles pourraient obtenir leur 
liberté. En dépit de la gradation extrême de la loi, 
l'année suivante une législature plus conservatrice a essayé de 
l'abroger. Les Américains africains nouvellement libres ont 
pétitionné l'Assemblée rejeter un tel mouvement. Cato, 
nouvellement libéré avec ses enfants, a écrit au journal du citoyen
d'honneur de Philadelphie, un journal afro-américain, en 1781, faisant 
son cas en utilisant les propres mots de la législature au sujet de 
la promesse de la civilisation universelle tout en ajoutant ses 
propres vues de la signification de la révolution. La 
législature a voté contre abroger l'acte progressif d'abolition.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As pressões para o abolition do slavery 
aumentaram na era revolucionária; cinco estados do norte 
abolished um slavery entre 1780 e 1804. Pensilvânia era a 
primeira em 1780 em que sua legislatura passou uma conta gradual do 
abolition. Entretanto, ninguém foi livrado realmente; 
todo o aqueles enslaved quando a lei entrou no efeito remanesceu
enslaved, e todo o aquelas carregadas após essa data foram requeridas
para fornecer mestres das suas matrizes com os twenty-eight anos do 
servitude antes que poderiam obter sua liberdade. Apesar do 
gradualism extremo da lei, o seguinte ano uma legislatura mais 
conservadora tentou repeal o. Os americanos africanos 
recentemente livrados peticionaram o conjunto rejeitar tal movimento. 
Cato, livrado recentemente com suas crianças, escreveu ao 
jornal do freeman de Filadélfia, um jornal Africano-Americano, em 
1781, fazendo seu caso usando próprias palavras da legislatura sobre 
a promessa da civilização universal ao adicionar suas próprias 
vistas do meaning da volta. A legislatura votou de encontro a 
repealing o ato gradual do abolition.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le pressioni per l'abolizione di slavery sono 
aumentato di era rivoluzionaria; cinque nordici dichiarano 
lo slavery abolito fra 1780 e 1804. La Pensilvania era la prima 
in 1780 in cui la relativa legislatura ha passato una fattura graduale
di abolizione. Tuttavia, nessuno realmente è stato liberato; 
tutto quelli hanno asservito quando la legge ha entrato in 
effetto è rimasto asservita e tutto quelle sopportate dopo quella 
data sono state richieste per fornire ai supervisori delle loro madri 
ventotto anni del servitude prima che potrebbero ottenere la loro 
libertà. Malgrado il gradualism estremo della legge, il 
seguente anno una legislatura più conservatrice ha tentato di 
abrogarla. Gli Americani africani recentemente liberati hanno 
fatto una petizione l'Assemblea rifiutare un tal movimento. 
Cato, recentemente liberato con i suoi bambini, ha scritto al 
giornale del freeman de Filadelfia, un giornale Africano-Americano, in
1781, facente il suo caso usando le proprie parole della legislatura 
circa la promessa di civilizzazione universale mentre aggiungeva i 
suoi propri punti di vista del significato della rivoluzione. La
legislatura ha votato contro l'abrogazione dell'atto graduale di 
abolizione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι πιέσεις για την κατάργηση της σκλαβιάς αυξήθηκαν 
στην επαναστατική εποχή  πέντε βόρεια κράτη κατάργησαν τη 
σκλαβιά μεταξύ 1780 και 1804, Πενσυλβανία ήταν το πρώτο το 
1780 πότε το νομοθετικό σώμα του ψήφισε ένα βαθμιαίο 
νομοσχέδιο κατάργησης. Εντούτοις, κανένας ελευθερώθηκε 
πραγματικά  όλοι εκείνοι υποδούλωσαν πότε ο νόμος τέθηκε 
σε ισχύ παρέμεινε υποδουλωμένος, και όλοι εκείνοι γεννημένοι 
αφότου απαιτήθηκε εκείνη η ημερομηνία για να παρέχει στους 
κυρίους των μητέρων τους είκοσι οχτώ έτη δουλείας προτού να 
μπορέσουν να λάβουν την ελευθερία τους. Παρά την ακραία 
βαθμιαία εξέλιξη του νόμου, το επόμενο έτος ένα πιό 
συντηρητικό νομοθετικό σώμα προσπάθησε να τον ακυρώσει. 
Πρόσφατα ελευθερωμένοι αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί υπέβαλαν 
αίτηση στη συμβολική γλώσσα για να απορρίψουν μια τέτοια κίνηση.
Το Cato, που ελευθερώθηκε πρόσφατα με τα παιδιά του, 
έγραψε στο περιοδικό του ελεύθερου πολίτη της Φιλαδέλφειας, μια 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανική εφημερίδα, το 1781, δίνοντας τα 
επιχειρήματά του με τη χρησιμοποίηση των λέξεων του νομοθετικού 
σώματος για την υπόσχεση του καθολικού πολιτισμού προσθέτοντας 
τις όψεις του της έννοιας της επανάστασης. Το νομοθετικό 
σώμα που ψηφίζεται ενάντια στην ακύρωση της βαθμιαίας πράξης 
κατάργησης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las presiones para la abolición de la esclavitud 
aumentaron de la era revolucionaria; cinco estados norteños 
suprimieron esclavitud entre 1780 y 1804. Pennsylvania era la 
primera en 1780 en que su legislatura aprobó una cuenta gradual de la
abolición. Sin embargo, nadie fue liberada realmente; 
todo el ésos esclavizaron cuando la ley entró efecto seguía 
esclavizada, y todo el ésas llevadas después de esa fecha fueron 
requeridas para proveer de los amos de sus madres veintiocho años de 
la servidumbre antes de que podrían obtener su libertad. A 
pesar de el gradualism extremo de la ley, el año siguiente una 
legislatura más conservadora procuró abrogarlo. Los americanos
africanos nuevamente liberados solicitaron a asamblea rechazar tal 
movimiento. Cato, liberado nuevamente con sus niños, escribió 
al diario del freeman de Philadelphia, un periódico 
Africano-Americano, en 1781, haciendo su caso usando propias palabras 
de la legislatura sobre la promesa de la civilización universal 
mientras que agregaba sus propias opiniones del significado de la 
revolución. La legislatura votó contra la abrogación del acto
gradual de la abolición.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086218</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106917</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/having-tasted-the-sweets-of-freedom-cato-petitions-the-pennsylvania-legislature-to-remain-free</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
