<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105221</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105221</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087471</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Cartooning for Victory: World War I Instructions to Artists</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Cartooning für Sieg: Weltkrieg-Anweisungen 
zu den Künstlern</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cartooning pour la victoire : Instructions 
de Première Guerre Mondiale aux artistes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Cartooning para a vitória: Instruções do 
world.war.i aos artistas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Cartooning per la vittoria: Istruzioni di 
world.war.i agli artisti</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Cartooning για τη νίκη: Παγκόσμιος πόλεμος Ι 
οδηγίες στους καλλιτέχνες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cartooning para la victoria: Instrucciones 
de la Primera Guerra Mundial a los artistas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">During World War I, the United States fought a war of ideas with unprecedented ingenuity and organization. President Woodrow Wilson established the Committee on Public Information (CPI) to manage news and solicit widespread support for the war at home and abroad. Under the energetic direction of Mississippi newspaper editor George Creel, the CPI churned out national propaganda through diverse media including films, cartoons, and speeches. The CPI's home-front propaganda cartoons were no laughing matter. The Bureau of Cartoons, headed by George Hecht, exhorted cartoonists to use their popular medium to support the war effort. Like other CPI pamphlets that urged Americans to integrate the war effort into their home and work lives, this excerpt from the CPI's  Bulletin for Cartoonists  provided a mixture of suggestions, practical advice, and inspirational prose.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während des Ersten Weltkrieges kämpften die 
Vereinigten Staaten einen Krieg von Ideen mit beispiellosem Scharfsinn
und Organisation. Präsident Woodrow Wilson stellte den 
Ausschuß für allgemeine Informationen (CPI) her um Nachrichten zu 
handhaben und weitverbreiteten Support für den Krieg im In- und 
Ausland zu erbitten. Unter der energischen Richtung von 
Mississippi Zeitungsverleger George Creel, schüttelte das CPI aus 
nationaler Propaganda durch verschiedene Media einschließlich Filme, 
Karikaturen und Reden durch. Die CPI's Haus-vorderen 
Propagandakarikaturen waren kein lachender Stoff. Das Büro der 
Karikaturen, vorangegangen von George Hecht, exhorted 
Karikaturenzeichner, ihren populären Medium zu verwenden, um die 
Kriegbemühung zu unterstützen. Wie andere CPI Flugschriften, 
die Amerikaner drängten, die Kriegbemühung in ihr Haus zu 
integrieren und die Leben zu bearbeiten, stellte dieses Excerpt von 
der CPI's Nachricht für Karikaturenzeichner eine Mischung von 
Vorschlägen, von praktischem Rat und von inspirational Prosa zur 
Verfügung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant la Première Guerre Mondiale, les 
Etats-Unis ont combattu une guerre des idées avec l'ingéniosité et 
l'organisation sans précédent. Le Président Woodrow Wilson a 
établi le comité de l'information publique (CPI) pour contrôler des
nouvelles et pour solliciter le support répandu pour la guerre ici et
ailleurs. Sous la direction énergique du panier de pêche de 
George d'éditeur de journal du Mississippi, la CPI a battu hors 
de la propagande nationale par des medias divers comprenant des films,
des dessins animés, et des discours. Les dessins animés 
maison-avant de propagande de CPI's n'étaient aucune matière riante.
Le bureau des dessins animés, dirigé par George Hecht, a 
recommandé instamment des réalisateurs de dessins animés d'employer
leur support populaire pour supporter l'effort de guerre. Comme 
d'autres brochures de CPI qui ont invité des Américains à intégrer
l'effort de guerre dans leur maison et à travailler les vies, cet 
extrait du bulletin de CPI's pour des réalisateurs de dessins animés
a fourni un mélange des suggestions, du conseil pratique, et de la
prose inspirée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Durante o world.war.i, os estados unidos lutaram 
uma guerra das idéias com o ingenuity e a organização 
unprecedented. O presidente Woodrow Wilson estabeleceu o comitê
na informação pública (CPI) para controlar a notícia e solicit 
sustentação difundida para a guerra na HOME e no exterior. Sob
o sentido energético do creel de George do editor de jornal de 
Mississippi, o CPI churned para fora do propaganda nacional com os 
media diversos including películas, cartoons, e discursos. Os 
cartoons HOME-DIANTEIROS do propaganda de CPI's não eram nenhuma 
matéria rindo. O departamento dos cartoons, dirigido por George
Hecht, exhorted cartoonists usar seu media popular suportar o esforço
da guerra. Como outros panfletos do CPI que incitaram americanos
integrar o esforço da guerra em sua HOME e trabalhar vidas, este 
excerpt do boletim de CPI's para cartoonists forneceu uma mistura das 
sugestões, do conselho prático, e da prosa do inspirational.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Durante il world.war.i, unito Dichiara ha 
combattuto una guerra delle idee con ingegnosità e l'organizzazione 
senza precedente. Il presidente Woodrow Wilson ha istituito il 
comitato delle informazioni pubbliche (caratteri per pollice) per 
gestire le notizie e sollecitare il supporto diffuso per la guerra nel
paese ed all'estero. Sotto il senso energico della rastrelliera 
di George dell'editore di giornale del Mississippi, i caratteri per 
pollice hanno sbattuto verso l'esterno la propaganda nazionale con i 
media vari compreso le pellicole, i fumetti ed i discorsi. I 
fumetti sede-anteriori di propaganda di CPI's erano materia ridente. 
L'ufficio dei fumetti, diretto da George Hecht, exhorted i 
cartoonists usare il loro media popolare per sostenere lo sforzo di 
guerra. Come altri opuscoli di caratteri per pollice che hanno 
invitato gli Americani ad integrare lo sforzo di guerra nella loro 
sede ed a lavorare le vite, questo brano dal bollettino di CPI's per i
cartoonists ha fornito una miscela dei suggerimenti, del consiglio 
pratico e della prosa di inspirational.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατά τη διάρκεια παγκόσμιος πόλεμος Ι, οι Ηνωμένες 
Πολιτείες διεξήγαγαν έναν πόλεμο των ιδεών με την πρωτοφανείς 
ευστροφία και την οργάνωση. Ο Πρόεδρος Woodrow Wilson 
καθιέρωσε την Επιτροπή των δημόσιων πληροφοριών (ΔΤΚ) για να 
διαχειριστεί τις ειδήσεις και να ζητήσει τη διαδεδομένη 
υποστήριξη για τον πόλεμο στο σπίτι και στο εξωτερικό. Υπό 
την ενεργητική καθοδήγηση του επεξεργαστή George Creel, η 
αναδευμένη ΔΤΚ έξω εθνική προπαγάνδα εφημερίδων του Μισισιπή 
μέσω των διαφορετικών μέσων συμπεριλαμβανομένων των ταινιών, των 
κινούμενων σχεδίων, και των ομιλιών. Τα σπίτι-μπροστινά 
κινούμενα σχέδια προπαγάνδας του ΔΤΚ δεν ήταν κανένα θέμα 
γέλιου. Το γραφείο των κινούμενων σχεδίων, που διευθύνθηκε 
από George Hecht, προέτρεψε τους σκιτσογράφους για να 
χρησιμοποιήσει το δημοφιλές μέσο τους για να υποστηρίξει την 
πολεμική προσπάθεια. Όπως άλλα τεύχη ΔΤΚ που ώθησαν 
Αμερικανούς για να ενσωματώσουν την πολεμική προσπάθεια στο σπίτι
τους και η εργασία ζει, αυτό το απόσπασμα από το δελτίο του ΔΤΚ 
για τους σκιτσογράφους παρείχε ένα μίγμα προτάσεων, πρακτικών 
συμβουλών, και εμπνευσμένης πεζογραφίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Durante Primera Guerra Mundial, los Estados Unidos
lucharon una guerra de ideas con ingeniosidad y la organización sin 
precedentes. Presidente Woodrow Wilson estableció a comité 
sobre la información pública (CPI) para manejar noticias y para 
solicitar la ayuda extensa para la guerra en el país y en el 
extranjero. Bajo dirección enérgia de la cesta de George del 
redactor de Mississippi, el CPI batió fuera de propaganda nacional 
con media diversos incluyendo las películas, las historietas, y los 
discursos. Las historietas hogar-delanteras de la propaganda de 
CPI's no eran ninguna materia que reía. La oficina de 
historietas, dirigida por George Hecht, suplicó a dibujantes que 
utilizaran su media popular para utilizar el esfuerzo de la guerra. 
Como otros folletos del CPI que impulsaron a americanos integrar
el esfuerzo de la guerra en su hogar y trabajar vidas, este extracto 
del boletín de CPI's para los dibujantes proporcionó a una mezcla de
sugerencias, del consejo práctico, y de la prosa del inspirational.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087471</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105221</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/cartooning-for-victory-world-war-i-instructions-to-artists</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
