<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105347</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105347</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205707</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A Visual Sourcebook of Chinese Civilization</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Sichtsourcebook der chinesischen Zivilisation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un Sourcebook visuel de civilisation chinoise</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um Sourcebook visual da civilização chinesa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un Sourcebook visivo di civilizzazione 
cinese</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα οπτικό Sourcebook του κινεζικού πολιτισμού</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un Sourcebook visual de la civilización china</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site features units on Chinese history, culture, and society. Each unit organizes photos, maps, and art around a theme: China's geography, archaeology, religion, calligraphy, military technology, painting, homes, gardens, clothing, and the graphic arts. Questions highlight key facets of Chinese culture: Why is calligraphy highly ranked as an art form in China? Over what kinds of terrain did Chinese civilization spread?</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Situationsmerkmalmaßeinheiten auf 
chinesischer Geschichte, Kultur und Gesellschaft. Jede 
Maßeinheit organisiert Fotos, Karten und kunst um ein Thema: 
Geographie Chinas, Archäologie, Religion, Kalligraphie, 
militärische Technologie, Anstrich, Häuser, Gärten, Kleidung und 
die graphischen künste. Fragen Höhepunkt-Tastefacetten der 
chinesischen Kultur: Warum wird Kalligraphie in hohem Grade 
als Kunstform in China geordnet? Über welchen Arten des 
Geländes verbritt chinesische Zivilisation?</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Unités de dispositifs de ce site sur l'histoire, 
la culture, et la société chinoises. Chaque unité organise 
des photos, des cartes, et l'art autour d'un thème : La 
géographie de la Chine, l'archéologie, la religion, la calligraphie, 
la technologie militaire, la peinture, les maisons, les jardins, 
l'habillement, et les industries graphiques. Facettes de clé de
point culminant de questions de culture chinoise : Pourquoi la 
calligraphie est-elle fortement rangée comme forme d'art en Chine ? 
Au-dessus de quels genres de terrain la civilisation chinoise 
a-t-elle écarté ?</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Unidades das características deste local no 
history, na cultura, e na sociedade chineses. Cada unidade 
organiza fotos, mapas, e arte em torno de um tema: Geografia de 
China, archaeology, religião, calligraphy, tecnologia militar, 
pintura, HOME, jardins, roupa, e as artes gráficas. Facets da 
chave do destaque das perguntas da cultura chinesa: Por que o 
calligraphy espesso altamente como um formulário de arte em China? 
Sobre que tipos do terreno a civilização chinesa espalhou?</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Unità delle caratteristiche di questo luogo su 
storia cinese, su coltura e sulla società. Ogni unità 
organizza le foto, i programmi e l'arte intorno ad un tema: 
Geografia della Cina, archaeology, religione, calligraphy, 
tecnologia militare, pittura, case, giardini, vestiti ed arti 
grafiche. Sfaccettature di tasto di punto culminante di domande 
di coltura cinese: Perchè il calligraphy altamente è 
allineato come forma di arte in Cina? In che generi di terreno 
la civilizzazione cinese ha distribuito?</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει τις μονάδες στην 
κινεζικούς ιστορία, τον πολιτισμό, και την κοινωνία. Κάθε 
μονάδα οργανώνει τις φωτογραφίες, τους χάρτες, και την τέχνη 
γύρω από ένα θέμα: Γεωγραφία της Κίνας, αρχαιολογία, 
θρησκεία, καλλιγραφία, στρατιωτική τεχνολογία, ζωγραφική, 
σπίτια, κήποι, ιματισμός, και οι γραφικές τέχνες. Οι 
ερωτήσεις δίνουν έμφαση στις βασικές απόψεις του κινεζικού 
πολιτισμού: Γιατί η καλλιγραφία ταξινομείται ιδιαίτερα ως 
μορφή τέχνης στην Κίνα; Σε ποια είδη έκτασης ο κινεζικός 
πολιτισμός ήταν εξαπλωμένος;</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Unidades de las características de este sitio en 
historia, cultura, y sociedad chinas. Cada unidad ordena las 
fotos, las correspondencias, y arte alrededor de un tema: 
Geografía de China, archaeology, religión, calligraphy, 
tecnología militar, pintura, hogares, jardines, ropa, y los artes 
gráficos. Facetas del clave del toque de luz de las preguntas 
de la cultura china: ¿Por qué el calligraphy se alinea 
altamente como forma de arte en China? ¿Sobre qué clases de 
terreno la civilización china se separó?</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205707</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105347</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/a-visual-sourcebook-of-chinese-civilization</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
