<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103600</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103600</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211399</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Ocean World</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ozean-Welt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Monde d'Océan</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Mundo Do Oceano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Mondo Dell'Oceano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ωκεάνιος κόσμος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mundo Del Océano</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Ocean World site has a wide variety of information regarding the ocean. Established by Texas A and M University's Jason Project, Ocean World provides a wealth of information on weather, forams, icebergs, fisheries, coral reefs, waves, El Nino, currents and more. The site contains information for both students and teachers. The teacher section of the site contains background information on all subjects, helpful hints for using the web in the classroom and classroom activities. Student users can access the latest news in oceanography and an abundance of oceanography topics information. There are also additional resources for both teachers or students including book lists, a glossary, a guide to four star sites and helpful links. This is a very useful site for any user looking for information about our oceans</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Ozean-Weltsite hat eine breite Vielzahl der 
Informationen betreffend sind den Ozean. Hergestellt durch Texas
A und Projekt Jason der M Universität, stellt Ozean-Welt eine Fülle 
der Informationen auf Wetter, forams, Eisbergen, Fischereien, 
Korallenriffen, Wellen, EL Nino, Strömen und mehr zur Verfügung. 
Die Site enthält Informationen für Kursteilnehmer und Lehrer. 
Das Lehrerkapitel der Sites enthält Hintergrundinformationen 
über alle Themen, nützliche Tips für das Verwenden des Webs im 
Klassenzimmer und in den Klassenzimmeraktivitäten. 
Kursteilnehmerbenutzer können die neuesten Nachrichten in der 
Ozeanographie und einen Überfluß an auf den 
Ozeanographiethemainformationen zugreifen. Es gibt auch 
zusätzliche Betriebsmittel für Lehrer oder Kursteilnehmer 
einschließlich Buchlisten, ein Glossar, eine Anleitung zu vier 
Sternsites und nützliche Links. Dieses ist eine sehr nützliche
Site für jeden möglichen Benutzer, welche nach Informationen über 
unsere Ozeane sucht</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le site du monde d'océan a une grande variété 
d'information concernant l'océan. Établi par le Texas A et le 
projet de Jason de l'université de M, le monde d'océan fournit une 
richesse d'information survivent à en fonction, des forams, des 
icebergs, pêche, des récifs de corail, des vagues, EL Nino, des 
courants et plus. Le site contient l'information pour des 
étudiants et des professeurs. La section de professeur du site 
contient l'information de fond sur tous les sujets, conseils utiles 
pour l'usage du Web dans la salle de classe et les activités de salle
de classe. Les utilisateurs d'étudiant peuvent accéder aux 
dernières nouvelles en océanographie et à une abondance 
d'information de sujets d'océanographie. Il y a également les 
ressources supplémentaires pour des professeurs ou les étudiants 
comprenant des listes de livre, un glossaire, un guide de quatre 
tiennent le premier rôle des sites et des liens utiles. C'est un site 
très utile pour n'importe quel utilisateur recherchant des 
informations sur nos océans</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O local do mundo do oceano tem uma variedade larga
da informação a respeito do oceano. Estabelecido por Texas A e
por projeto de Jason da universidade de M, o mundo do oceano fornece 
uma riqueza da informação no tempo, nos forams, nos icebergs, nos 
fisheries, nos recifes corais, nas ondas, no EL Nino, nas correntes e 
em mais. O local contem a informação para  estudantes e 
professores. A seção do professor do local contem a 
informação de fundo em todos os assuntos, sugestões úteis para 
usar o Web na sala de aula e nas atividades da sala de aula. Os 
usuários do estudante podem alcançar a notícia a mais atrasada no 
oceanography e uma abundância de informação dos tópicos do 
oceanography. Há também uns recursos adicionais para  
professores ou estudantes including listas do livro, um glossário, 
uma guia a quatro locais da estrela e as ligações úteis. Este
é um local muito útil para todo o usuário que procura a 
informação sobre nossos oceanos</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il luogo del mondo dell'oceano ha un'ampia 
varietà di informazioni per quanto riguarda l'oceano. Stabilito
dal Texas A e dal progetto Jason dell'università di m., il mondo 
dell'oceano fornisce una ricchezza delle informazioni su tempo, su 
forams, sugli iceberg, sulle industrie della pesca, sui reefs di 
corallo, sulle onde, sul EL Nino, sulle correnti e su più. Il 
luogo contiene le informazioni per sia gli allievi che gli insegnanti.
La sezione dell'insegnante del luogo contiene le informazioni di
base su tutti gli oggetti, suggerimenti utili per usando il Web 
nell'aula e nelle attività dell'aula. Gli utenti dell'allievo 
possono accedere alle ultime notizie in oceanografia e ad 
un'abbondanza delle informazioni di soggetti di oceanografia. Ci
sono egualmente risorse supplementari per sia gli insegnanti o gli 
allievi compreso le liste del libro, un glossario, una guida a quattro
luoghi della stella che i collegamenti utili. Ciò è un luogo 
molto utile per tutto l'utente che cerca le informazioni sui nostri 
oceani</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ωκεάνια παγκόσμια περιοχή έχει μια ευρεία ποικιλία
των πληροφοριών σχετικά με τον ωκεανό. Καθιερωμένος από το 
Τέξας Α και το πρόγραμμα Jason του πανεπιστημίου μ, ο ωκεάνιος 
κόσμος παρέχει έναν πλούτο των πληροφοριών για τον καιρό, 
forams, τα παγόβουνα, την αλιεία, τις κοραλλιογενείς υφάλους, 
τα κύματα, Ελ Νίνιο, τα ρεύματα και περισσότερους. Η 
περιοχή περιέχει τις πληροφορίες και για τους σπουδαστές και για 
τους δασκάλους. Το τμήμα δασκάλων της περιοχής περιέχει τις
βασικές πληροφορίες για όλα τα θέματα, χρήσιμοι υπαινιγμοί για 
τη χρησιμοποίηση του Ιστού στην τάξη και τις δραστηριότητες 
τάξεων. Οι χρήστες σπουδαστών μπορούν να έχουν πρόσβαση 
στις πιό πρόσφατες ειδήσεις στην ωκεανογραφία και μια αφθονία 
πληροφοριών θεμάτων ωκεανογραφίας. Υπάρχουν επίσης 
πρόσθετα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς και για τους δασκάλους ή τους 
σπουδαστές συμπεριλαμβανομένων των καταλόγων βιβλίων, ένα 
γλωσσάρι, ένας οδηγός σε τέσσερις περιοχές αστεριών και τις 
χρήσιμες συνδέσεις. Αυτό είναι μια πολύ χρήσιμη περιοχή 
για οποιοδήποτε χρήστη που ψάχνει τις πληροφορίες για τους 
ωκεανούς μας</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El sitio del mundo del océano tiene una variedad 
amplia de información con respecto al océano. Establecido por 
Tejas A y el proyecto de Jason de la universidad de M, el mundo del 
océano proporciona a una abundancia de la información en el tiempo, 
los forams, los icebergs, las industrias pesqueras, los filones 
coralinos, las ondas, el EL Nino, corrientes y más. El sitio 
contiene la información para los estudiantes y los profesores. 
La sección del profesor del sitio contiene la información de 
fondo sobre todos los temas, consejos de utilización provechosos el 
Web en la sala de clase y las actividades de la sala de clase. 
Los utilizadores del estudiante pueden tener acceso a las 
noticias más últimas en oceanografía y a una abundancia de 
información de los asuntos de la oceanografía. Hay también 
recursos adicionales para los profesores o los estudiantes incluyendo 
listas del libro, un glosario, una guía a cuatro sitios de la 
estrella y conexiones provechosas. Esto es un sitio muy útil 
para cualquier utilizador que busca la información sobre nuestros 
océanos</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211399</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103600</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/ocean-world</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
