<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108236</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108236</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086803</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Says Lax Conditions Caused Race Riots":  Chicago Daily News  and Carl Sandburg Report the Chicago Race Riot of 1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Sagt, Daß die Lockeren Bedingungen, die 
Rennen Verursacht Werden," Randaliert: Chicago tägliche 
Nachrichten und Karl Sandburg berichten über den Chicago 
Rennen-Aufstand von 1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Dit Que Les Conditions Relâchées Causées La 
Course S'ameute" : Les nouvelles quotidiennes et le Karl 
Sandburg de Chicago enregistrent l'émeute de course de Chicago de 
1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Diz Que As Circunstâncias Lax Causadas A Raça 
Se amotinam": As notícias diárias de Chicago e Carl Sandburg 
relatam o motim da raça de Chicago de 1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Dice Che Stati Di Lassismo Causati La Corsa 
Si solleva": Le notizie quotidiane del Chicago e Carl Sandburg 
segnalano il tumulto della corsa del Chicago di 1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Λέει τους αμελείς όρους προκαλούμενους τις φυλετικές
ταραχέσ": Καθημερινές ειδήσεις και Carl Sandburg 
Report του Σικάγου η φυλετική ταραχή του Σικάγου του 1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Dice Que Las Condiciones Flojas Causadas La Raza 
Se desenfrenan": Las noticias diarias y Carl Sandburg de Chicago
señalan el alboroto de la raza de Chicago de 1919</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">As U.S. soldiers returned from Europe in the aftermath of World War I, scarce housing and jobs heightened racial and class antagonisms across urban America. African-American soldiers, in particular, came home from the war expecting to enjoy the full rights of citizenship that they had fought to defend overseas. In the spring and summer of 1919, murderous race riots erupted in 22 American cities and towns. Chicago experienced the most severe of these riots. On Sunday, July 27, white bathers attacked several black youths swimming near one of Lake Michigan's white beaches, resulting in the death of an African-American boy. Five days of intense racial violence followed, claiming the lives of 23 black and 15 white Chicagoans, with more than 500 others wounded and thousands of black and white citizens burned out of their homes. A plethora of news reports and editorials offered instant analysis and helped shape local and national attitudes. On July 28, 1919, the  Chicago Daily News  printed this article by noted poet Carl Sandburg on its front page. Unlike most white reporters, Sandburg relied on black sources in researching his articles. The  Chicago Daily News 's reporting on the riot was generally considered the most evenhanded of the city's daily newspapers, yet even it inflamed tensions by printing unsubstantiated stories. For example, the same front page included a "bulletin" that recounted supposed African-American plans to retaliate against white rioters.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während VEREINIGTE STAATEN Soldaten von Europa in
der Nachmahd des Ersten Weltkrieges zurückkamen, erhöhten knappes 
Gehäuse und Jobs die rassische und Kategorie Antagonismen über 
städtischem Amerika. Die Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Soldaten 
kamen insbesondere nach Hause vom Krieg erwartend, die vollen Rechte 
der Staatsbürgerschaft zu genießen, die sie gekämpft hatten, um 
übersee zu verteidigen. Im Frühling und im Sommer von 1919, 
brachen mörderische Rennenaufstände in 22 amerikanischen Städte und
in Städten aus. Chicago erfuhr das strengste dieser Aufstände.
Am Sonntag Juli 27, nahmen die weißen Badegäste einige 
schwarze Jugend schwimmend nahe einem von See-Michigans weißen 
Stränden in Angriff, und das resultiert im Tod eines 
Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Jungen. Fünf Tage der intensiven 
rassischen Gewalttätigkeit folgten und behaupteten die Lebensdauern 
von 23 schwarz und 15 Weiß Chicagoans, wenn mehr als 500 andere 
verwundet sind und Tausenden der schwarzen und weißen Bürger brennt 
von ihren Häusern aus. Eine Fülle Nachrichtenreporte und 
Leitartikel bot sofortige Analyse an und half der lokalen Form und 
nationaler Haltung. An Juli 28, 1919, druckten die Chicago 
täglichen Nachrichten diesen Artikel durch beachteten Dichter Karl 
Sandburg auf seiner Vorderseite. Anders als die meisten weißen 
Reporter beruhte Sandburg auf schwarzen Quellen, wenn er seine Artikel
erforschte. Die Chicago täglichen Nachrichten ' s berichtend 
über den Aufstand galten im Allgemeinen als das unparteilichste der 
täglichen Zeitungen der Stadt, dennoch gleichmäßig entflammte 
sie Spannkräfte, indem sie druckten, unsubstantiated Geschichten. 
Z.B. schloß die gleiche Vorderseite eine "Nachricht" ein, die 
angenommene Afrikanisch-Amerikanische Pläne nachzählte, um sich 
gegen weiße rioters zu revanchieren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant que les soldats des ETATS-UNIS 
retournaient de l'Europe dans le lendemain de la Première Guerre 
Mondiale, le logement rare et les travaux ont intensifié des 
antagonismes raciaux et de classe à travers l'Amérique urbaine. 
Les soldats afro-américains, en particulier, sont venus à la 
maison de la guerre comptant apprécier les pleines droites de la 
citoyenneté qu'ils avaient combattu pour défendre outre-mer. 
Au printemps et l'été de 1919, les émeutes meurtrières de 
course ont éclaté dans 22 villes et villes américaines. 
Chicago a éprouvé le plus grave de ces émeutes. 
Dimanche, juillet 27, les baigneurs blancs ont attaqué 
plusieurs jeunesses noires nageant près d'une des plages blanches de 
Michigan de lac, ayant pour résultat la mort d'un garçon 
afro-américain. Une violence raciale intense de cinq jours a 
suivi, réclamant les vies de 23 noirs et 15 le blanc Chicagoans, avec
plus de 500 autres enroulés et des milliers de citoyens noirs et 
blancs grillent de leurs maisons. Une pléthore d'états de 
nouvelles et d'éditoriaux a offert l'analyse instantanée et a aidé 
la forme locale et les attitudes nationales. 28 juillet 1919, 
les nouvelles quotidiennes de Chicago ont imprimé cet article par le 
poèt remarquable Karl Sandburg sur son page avant. À la 
différence de la plupart des journalistes blancs, Sandburg s'est 
fondé sur des sources noires en recherchant ses articles. Les 
nouvelles quotidiennes 's de Chicago rendant compte de l'émeute ont 
été généralement considérées le plus impartial des journaux 
quotidiens de la ville, pourtant égal elles ont enflamé des tensions
par des histoires non fondées d'impression. Par exemple, la 
même page avant a inclus un "bulletin" qui a raconté des plans 
afro-américains supposés pour exercer des représailles contre les 
rioters blancs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Enquanto os soldados de ESTADOS UNIDOS retornaram 
de Europa no aftermath do world.war.i, a carcaça escassa e os 
trabalhos heightened antagonisms raciais e da classe através de 
América urbana. Os soldados Africano-Americanos, no detalhe, 
vieram para casa da guerra esperando apreciar as direitas cheias do 
citizenship que tinham lutado para defender no ultramar. Na mola
e no verão de 1919, os motins murderous da raça erupted em 22 
cidades e cidades americanas. Chicago experimentou o mais severo
destes motins. Em domingo, julho 27, os bathers brancos atacaram
diversas juventudes pretas que nadam perto de uma das praias brancas 
de michigan de lago, tendo por resultado a morte de um menino 
Africano-Americano. Cinco dias da violência racial intensa 
seguiram, reivindicando as vidas 23 pretos e 15 do branco Chicagoans, 
com os mais de 500 outros feridos e os milhares dos cidadãos pretos e
brancos queimados fora de suas HOME. Um plethora de relatórios 
de notícia e de editorials ofereceu a análise imediata e ajudou à 
forma local e a atitudes nacionais. Julho em 28, 1919, a 
notícia diária de Chicago imprimiu este artigo pelo poeta notável 
Carl Sandburg em sua página dianteira. Ao contrário de a 
maioria de repórteres brancos, Sandburg confiou em fontes pretas em 
pesquisar seus artigos. A notícia diária ' s de Chicago que 
relata no motim foi considerada geralmente o mais evenhanded dos 
jornais diários da cidade, contudo uniforme inflamed tensões 
imprimindo unsubstantiated histórias. Para o exemplo, a mesma 
página dianteira incluiu um "boletim" que recounted plantas 
Africano-Americanas supostas para retaliate de encontro aos rioters 
brancos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Mentre i soldati degli STATI UNITI hanno ritornato
da Europa nel guaime del world.war.i, l'alloggiamento limitato ed i 
lavori hanno intensificato gli antagonismi del codice categoria e 
razziali attraverso l'America urbana. I soldati 
Africano-Americani, in particolare, sono venuto a casa dalla guerra 
pensanti godere i diritti completi della cittadinanza che avevano 
combattuto per difendere oltremare. Nella molla e nell'estate di
1919, i tumulti murderous della corsa hanno scoppiato in 22 
città e città americane. Chicago ha sperimentato il più 
severo di questi tumulti. La domenica, il 27 luglio, i bathers 
bianchi hanno attacato parecchie gioventù nere che nuotano vicino ad 
una delle spiagge bianche di Michigan di lago, con conseguente morte 
di un ragazzo Africano-Americano. Cinque giorni della violenza 
razziale intensa sono seguito, esigendo le durate di 23 neri e 15 il 
bianco Chicagoans, con più di 500 altri feriti e le migliaia dei 
cittadini neri e bianchi brucia delle loro sedi. Una pletora di 
rapporti di notizie e di editoriali ha offerto l'analisi istante ed ha
aiutato la figura locale e gli atteggiamenti nazionali. Il 28 
luglio 1919, le notizie quotidiane del Chicago hanno stampato questo 
articolo dal poet celebre Carl Sandburg alla relativa pagina 
anteriore. Diverso della maggior parte dei reporter bianchi,
Sandburg ha contato sulle sorgenti nere nella ricerca dei suoi 
articoli. Le notizie quotidiane 's del Chicago che segnalano sul
tumulto generalmente sono state considerate il più evenhanded dei 
giornali quotidiani della città, tuttavia uniforme hanno 
infiammato i tensionamenti stampando unsubstantiated le storia.
Per esempio, la stessa pagina anteriore ha incluso "un 
bollettino" che ha raccontato i programmi Africano-Americani presunti 
per retaliate contro i rioters bianchi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δεδομένου ότι οι ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΙ στρατιώτες επέστρεψαν 
από την Ευρώπη στη συνέπεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου Ι, η λιγοστή 
κατοικία και οι εργασίες ύψωσαν τους φυλετικούς και ανταγωνισμούς
κλάσης σε ολόκληρη την αστική Αμερική. 
Αφρικανικός-αμερικανικά οι στρατιώτες, ειδικότερα, προήλθαν
κατ' οίκον από τον πόλεμο αναμένοντας να απολαύσουν των πλήρων 
δικαιωμάτων της υπηκοότητας που είχαν παλεψει για να υπερασπίσουν 
στο εξωτερικό. Την άνοιξη και το καλοκαίρι του 1919, οι 
δολοφονικές φυλετικές ταραχές ξέσπασαν σε 22 αμερικανικές 
πόλεις και κωμοπόλεις. Το Σικάγο δοκίμασε τον αυστηρότερο 
αυτών των ταραχών. Την Κυριακή, 27 Ιουλίου, οι λευκοί 
λουόμενοι επιτέθηκαν σε διάφορες μαύρες νεολαίες κολυμπώντας 
κοντά σε μια από τις άσπρες παραλίες του Μίτσιγκαν λιμνών, με 
συνέπεια το θάνατο ενός αφρικανικός-αμερικανικού αγοριού. 
Πέντε ημέρες της έντονης φυλετικής βίας ακολούθησαν, 
απαιτώντας τις ζωές 23 μαύρων και 15 άσπρο Chicagoans, με
περισσότερες από 500 άλλες που πληγώθηκαν και χιλιάδες μαύροι
και λευκοί πολίτες που καηκαν από τα σπίτια τους. Ένας 
μεγάλος αριθμός εκθέσεων και κύριων άρθρων ειδήσεων πρόσφερε τη
στιγμιαία ανάλυση και βοήθησε να διαμορφώσει τις τοπικές και 
εθνικές τοποθετήσεις. Στις 28 Ιουλίου ..1919, οι 
καθημερινές ειδήσεις του Σικάγου τύπωσαν αυτό το άρθρο από το 
σημειωμένο ποιητή Carl Sandburg της πρώτη σελίδα. 
Αντίθετα από τους περισσότερους λευκούς δημοσιογράφους, 
Sandburg στηρίχθηκε στις μαύρες πηγές στην έρευνα των άρθρων 
του. Οι καθημερινές ειδήσεις "s του Σικάγου που 
υποβάλλουν έκθεση σχετικά με την ταραχή θεωρήθηκαν γενικά πιό 
αμερόληπτος των καθημερινών εφημερίδων της πόλης, όμως ακόμη και
αυτό άκαυστες εντάσεις με την εκτύπωση των αβάσιμων ιστοριών. 
Παραδείγματος χάριν, το ίδιο πράγμα περιέλαβε πρώτη σελίδα 
ένα "δελτίο" που εξιστόρησε τα υποτιθέμενα 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικά σχέδια για να εκδικηθεί τους λευκούς 
στασιαστές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mientras que los soldados de ESTADOS UNIDOS 
volvieron de Europa en las consecuencias de la Primera Guerra Mundial,
la cubierta escasa y los trabajos aumentaron antagonismos raciales y 
de la clase a través de América urbana. Los soldados 
Africano-Americanos, en detalle, vinieron a casa de la guerra 
esperando gozar de las derechas completas de la ciudadanía que 
habían luchado para defender en ultramar. En el resorte y el 
verano de 1919, los alborotos murderous de la raza entraron en 
erupción en 22 ciudades y ciudades americanas. Chicago 
experimentó el más severo de estos alborotos. El domingo, de 
julio el 27, los bañistas blancos atacaron varias juventudes negras 
que nadaban cerca de una de las playas blancas de Michigan de lago, 
dando por resultado la muerte de un muchacho Africano-Americano. 
De cinco días una violencia racial intensa siguió, demandando 
las vidas de 23 negros y 15 el blanco Chicagoans, con más de 500 
otros heridos y millares de ciudadanos negros y blancos quema de sus 
hogares. Una plétora de informes de noticias y de editoriales 
ofreció análisis inmediato y ayudó a la dimensión de una variable 
local y a actitudes nacionales. 28 de julio de 1919, las 
noticias diarias de Chicago imprimieron este artículo del poeta 
conocido Carl Sandburg en su paginación delantera. Desemejante 
de la mayoría de los reporteros blancos, Sandburg confió en fuentes 
negras en investigar sus artículos. Las noticias diarias ' s de
Chicago que señalaban sobre el alboroto generalmente eran 
consideradas el más evenhanded de los periódicos diarios de la 
ciudad, con todo uniforme inflamaron tensiones imprimiendo 
unsubstantiated historias. Por ejemplo, la misma paginación 
delantera incluyó un "boletín" que contó de nuevo planes 
Africano-Americanos supuestos para tomar represalias contra los 
rioters blancos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086803</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108236</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/says-lax-conditions-caused-race-riots-chicago-daily-news-and-carl-sandburg-report-the-chicago-race-riot-of-1919</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
