<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106703</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106703</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086346</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"It Had a Lot of Advantages"Alfred DuBray Praises the Indian Reorganization Act</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"es hatte eine Menge Advantages"Alfred DuBray Lobe
die indische Reorganisierung-Tat</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"il a eu beaucoup d'éloges d'Advantages"Alfred 
DuBray la Loi indienne de réorganisation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"teve muitos de elogios de Advantages"Alfred 
DuBray o ato indian do reorganization</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"ha avuto elogi molto di Advantages"Alfred 
DuBray la Legge indiana della riorganizzazione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Είχε πολλούς επαίνους Advantages"Alfred DuBray ο
ινδικός νόμος αναδιοργάνωσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"tenía muchos de las alabanzas de 
Advantages"Alfred DuBray el acto indio de la reorganización</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Indian Reorganization Act of 1934, which became known as the Indian New Deal, dramatically changed the federal government's Indian policy. Although John Collier, the commissioner of Indian affairs who was responsible for the new policy, may have viewed Indians with great sympathy, not all Native Americans viewed the Indian New Deal in equally positive terms. But in this 1970 interview, Sioux tribal leader Alfred DuBray argued that the Indian New Deal, on balance, brought positive changes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die indische Reorganisierung-Tat von 1934, die als
das indische neue Abkommen bekannt wurde, indische Politik der 
drastisch geänderten die Bundesregierung. Obgleich John 
Collier, der Beauftragte der indischen Angelegenheiten, der für die 
neue Politik verantwortlich war, Inder mit großer Sympathie angesehen
haben kann, sahen nicht alle gebürtigen Amerikaner das indische neue 
Abkommen in den gleichmäßig positiven Bezeichnungen an. Aber 
in diesen 1970 Interview, Sioux argumentierte Stammes- Führer Alfred 
DuBray, daß das indische neue Abkommen, auf Balance, positive 
Änderungen holte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Loi indienne de réorganisation de 1934, qui 
est devenue notoire comme nouvelle affaire indienne, la politique 
indienne de gouvernement fédéral excessivement changé. Bien 
que John Collier, commissaire des affaires indiennes qui était 
responsable de la nouvelle politique, ait pu avoir visualisé des 
Indiens avec la grande sympathie, non tous les Américains indigènes 
ont visualisé la nouvelle affaire indienne en termes également 
positifs. Mais dans ces 1970 entrevue, le Chef tribal Alfred 
DuBray de Sioux a argué du fait que la nouvelle affaire indienne, 
tout bien pesé, a apporté les changements positifs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O ato indian do reorganization de 1934, que se 
tornou sabido como o negócio novo indian, a política indian de 
governo federal dramàtica mudado. Embora o collier de John, 
comissário de casos indian que era responsável para a política 
nova, pudesse ter visto indians com sympathy grande, não todos os 
americanos nativos viram o negócio novo indian em termos ingualmente 
positivos. Mas nestes 1970 entrevista, o líder tribal Alfred 
DuBray de Sioux discutiu que o negócio novo indian, no contrapeso, 
trouxe mudanças positivas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Legge indiana della riorganizzazione di 1934, 
che è stato conosciuta come il nuovo affare indiano, politica indiana
del governo federale drammaticamente cambiato. Anche se il 
collier del John, il commissario degli affari indiani che era 
responsabile di nuova politica, può osservare gli indiani con 
compassione grande, non tutti gli Americani natali hanno osservato il 
nuovo affare indiano nei termini ugualmente positivi. Ma in 
questi 1970 intervista, il capo tribale Alfred DuBray del 
Sioux ha sostenuto che il nuovo affare indiano, tutto soppesato, ha 
portato i cambiamenti positivi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο ινδικός νόμος αναδιοργάνωσης του 1934, που έγινε 
γνωστός ως ινδική νέα διαπραγμάτευση, άλλαξε εντυπωσιακά την 
ινδική πολιτική της ομοσπονδιακής κυβέρνησης. Αν και John
Collier, ο Επίτροπος των ινδικών υποθέσεων που ήταν αρμόδιος 
για τη νέα πολιτική, μπορεί να είχε εμφανίσει Ινδούς με τη 
μεγάλη συμπόνοια, δεν εμφάνισαν όλοι οι εγγενείς Αμερικανοί την 
ινδική νέα διαπραγμάτευση στους εξίσου θετικούς όρους. 
Αλλά σε αυτήν την συνέντευξη του 1970, ο σιού φυλετικός 
ηγέτης Alfred DuBray υποστήριξε ότι η ινδική νέα 
διαπραγμάτευση, στην ισορροπία, έφερε τις θετικές αλλαγές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El acto indio de la reorganización de 1934, que 
se conocía como el nuevo reparto indio, la política india del 
gobierno federal dramáticamente cambiante. Aunque el collier de
Juan, la comisión de asuntos indios que era responsable de la nueva 
política, pudo haber visto a indios con gran condolencia, no todos 
los americanos nativos vieron el nuevo reparto indio en términos 
igualmente positivos. Pero en estos 1970 entrevista, el arranque
de cinta tribal Alfred DuBray de Sioux discutió que el nuevo reparto 
indio, en balance, trajera cambios positivos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086346</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106703</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/it-had-a-lot-of-advantages-alfred-dubray-praises-the-indian-reorganization-act</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
