<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108542</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108542</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087107</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"This Is No Time for You to Take a Rest": Hollywood Goes to War</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"dieses ist keine Zeit für Sie, einen Rest zu 
nehmen": Hollywood geht War</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"ce n'est aucune heure pour vous de prendre un 
repos" : Hollywood va faire la guerre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"este não é nenhum tempo para você para fazer 
exame de um descanso": Hollywood vai guerrear</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"questo è tempo per voi di prendere un resto": 
Hollywood va fare la guerra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Αυτό δεν είναι κανένας χρόνος για σας να πάρετε ένα
υπόλοιπο": Το Hollywood πηγαίνει στον πόλεμο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"éste no es ningún tiempo para usted para tomar 
un resto": Hollywood va a guerrear</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the battle for the hearts and minds of the American people during World War II, the U.S. government viewed its popular performers--singers, dancers, and actors--as a crucial weapon. Even before Pearl Harbor, Treasury Department officials began making plans to raise money to finance the war by selling bonds to the public, which would be repaid with interest after the war was over. During the war, private citizens and organizations bought $190 billion worth of war bonds at the low interest rate of 1.8 percent. Hollywood stars became central to war bond drives. The glamorous actress Dorothy Lamour alone was credited with selling $350 million in war bonds. A September 1942 "bond blitz" enlisted more than three hundred actors who worked eighteen-hour days and sold more than $800 million in bonds. As the war dragged on, the Hollywood bond salespeople continued to motivate purchases even when allied victory seemed secure. This 1945 recording by Bing Crosby exhorted people to participate in the seventh war loan.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In der Schlacht für die Inneren und den Verstand 
der amerikanischen Leute während des Zweiten Weltkrieges, sah die 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Regierung seine populären Ausführenden -- 
Sänger, Tänzer und Schauspieler -- als entscheidende Waffe an. 
Sogar vor Pearl Harbor, fingen Fiskus-Abteilung Beamte an, 
Pläne Geld anheben zu lassen, um den Krieg zu finanzieren, indem sie 
Bindungen zur Öffentlichkeit verkauften, die mit Interesse 
zurückerstattet würde, nachdem der Krieg rüber sein. Während
des Krieges kauften private Bürger und Organisationen $190 Milliarde 
Wert der Kriegbindungen mit dem niedrigen Zinssatz von 1.8 Prozent. 
Hollywood Sterne wurden zu den Kriegbindungslaufwerken zentral. 
Der bezaubernde Schauspielerin Dorothy Lamour alleine wurde das 
Verkaufen $350 Million in den Kriegbindungen gutgeschrieben. Ein
September 1942 "trug Bondüberraschungsangriff" mehr als drei hundert 
Schauspieler ein, die Achtzehnstunde Tage bearbeiteten und mehr als 
$800 Million in den Bindungen verkauften. Als der Krieg 
schleppte an, die Hollywood Bondverkäufer, die fortgesetzt wurden, um
Erwerbe zu motivieren, selbst wenn verbündeter Sieg sicher schien. 
Diese Aufnahme 1945 durch Bing Crosby exhorted Leute, am 7. 
Kriegdarlehen teilzunehmen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans la bataille pour les coeurs et les esprits 
des  américains pendant la deuxième guerre mondiale, le gouvernement
des ETATS-UNIS a visualisé ses interprètes populaires -- chanteurs, 
danseurs, et acteurs -- comme arme cruciale. Même avant port de
perle, les fonctionnaires de service de trésor ont commencé à faire
des plans pour soulever l'argent pour financer la guerre en vendant 
des obligations au public, qui serait remboursé d'intérêt après 
que la guerre plus de. Pendant la guerre, les citoyens privés 
et les organismes ont acheté $190 milliards de valeur des 
obligations de guerre au bas taux d'intérêt d'intérêt de 1.8 pour
cent. Hollywood tient le premier rôle est devenu central pour faire 
la guerre des lecteurs d'obligation. L'actrice fascinante 
Dorothy seul Lamour a été créditée de vendre $350 millions dans 
des obligations de guerre. Septembre 1942 "l'attaque éclaire 
d'obligation" a enrôlé plus de trois cents acteurs qui ont 
travaillé des jours de dix-huit-heure et ont vendu plus de $800 
millions dans les obligations. Comme guerre a traîné, les 
vendeurs d'obligation de Hollywood continués pour motiver des 
achats même lorsque la victoire alliée a semblé bloquée. Cet
enregistrement 1945 par Bing Crosby a recommandé instamment des 
personnes de participer au septième prêt de guerre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Na batalha para os corações e as mentes dos 
povos americanos durante a segunda guerra mundial, o governo de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS viu seus performers populares -- singers, dancers, e 
atores -- como uma arma crucial. Mesmo antes do porto de 
pérola, os oficiais do departamento do Tesouraria começaram a fazer 
plantas para levantar o dinheiro para financiar a guerra vendendo 
ligações ao público, que seria reembolsado com interesse depois que
a guerra sobre. Durante a guerra, os cidadãos confidenciais e 
as organizações compraram $190 bilhões do valor de ligações de 
guerra na taxa de interesse baixa de 1.8 por cento. As estrelas 
de Hollywood tornaram-se centrais às movimentações da ligação de 
guerra. A actriz glamorous Dorothy Lamour sozinho foi creditada 
com vender $350 milhões em ligações de guerra. Um setembro 
1942 "o blitz bond" alistou mais de três cem atores que trabalharam 
dias de dezoito-hora e venderam mais de $800 milhões nas ligações. 
Como a guerra arrastou sobre, os salespeople bond de Hollywood 
continuados a motivate compras mesmo quando a vitória aliada pareceu 
segura. Esta gravação 1945 por Bing Crosby exhorted povos 
participar no sétimo empréstimo da guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nella battaglia per i cuori e le menti della gente
americana durante la seconda guerra mondiale, il governo degli STATI 
UNITI ha osservato i relativi esecutori popolari -- cantanti, 
ballerini ed attori -- come arma cruciale. Anche prima del 
porto di perla, i funzionari di reparto di Ministero del Tesoro hanno 
cominciato a fare i programmi per alzare i soldi per finanziare la 
guerra vendendo i legami al pubblico, che sarebbe rimborsato con 
interesse dopo che la guerra finito. Durante la guerra, i 
cittadini riservati e le organizzazioni hanno comprato $190 miliardo 
di valore dei legami di guerra al tasso di interesse basso di 1.8 per 
cento. Le stelle di Hollywood sono diventato centrali agli 
azionamenti del legame di guerra. Il actress glamorous Dorothy 
Lamour da solo è stato accreditato vendere $350 milioni nei legami di
guerra. Settembre del 1942 "il blitz schiavo" ha arruolato più 
di trecento attori che hanno lavorato i giorni di diciotto-ora ed 
hanno venduto più di $800 milioni nei legami. Come la guerra si
è trascinato sopra, i commessi schiavi di Hollywood continuati per 
motivare gli acquisti anche quando la vittoria alleata ha sembrato 
sicura. Questa registrazione 1945 da Bing Crosby exhorted la 
gente partecipare al settimo prestito di guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στη μάχη για τις καρδιές και τα μυαλά των αμερικανικών
ανθρώπων κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ, η 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ κυβέρνηση εμφάνισε τους δημοφιλείς εκτελεστές της -- 
τραγουδιστές, χορευτές, και δράστες -- ως κρίσιμο όπλο. 
Ακόμη και πριν από το λιμάνι μαργαριταριών, οι ανώτεροι 
υπάλληλοι τμήματος Υπουργείου Οικονομικών άρχισαν τα σχέδια για 
να συγκεντρώσουν τα χρήματα για να χρηματοδοτήσουν τον πόλεμο με 
την πώληση των δεσμών στο κοινό, το οποίο θα ξεπληρωνόταν με το 
ενδιαφέρον αφότου τελείωσε ο πόλεμος. Κατά τη διάρκεια του
πολέμου, οι απλοί πολίτες και οι οργανώσεις αγόρασαν την αξία 
$190 δισεκατομμυρίων των πολεμικών δεσμών στο χαμηλό επιτόκιο 
1,8 τοις εκατό. Τα αστέρια Hollywood έγιναν κεντρικά 
στις κινήσεις πολεμικών δεσμών. Η γοητευτική ηθοποιός 
Dorothy Lamour μόνο πιστώθηκε με την πώληση $350 
εκατομμυρίων στους πολεμικούς δεσμούς. Ένας Σεπτέμβριος 
1942 "blitz δεσμών" στρατολόγησε περισσότερους από 
τριακόσιους δράστες που απασχολήθηκαν στις ημέρες δεκαοχτώ-ώρας 
και πώλησαν περισσότερα από $800 εκατομμύρια στους δεσμούς. 
Σαν πόλεμο που σέρθηκε επάνω, salespeople δεσμών 
Hollywood συνέχισαν να παρακινούν τις αγορές ακόμα και όταν η 
συνδεμένη νίκη φάνηκε ασφαλής. Αυτή η καταγραφή του 
1945 από Bing Crosby προέτρεψε τους ανθρώπους για να 
συμμετέχει στο έβδομο πολεμικό δάνειο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En la batalla para los corazones y las mentes de 
la gente americana durante la Segunda Guerra Mundial, el gobierno de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS vio a sus ejecutantes populares -- cantantes, 
bailarines, y agentes -- como arma crucial. Incluso antes de 
puerto de perla, los funcionarios del departamento del Hacienda 
comenzaron a hacer planes para levantar el dinero para financiar la 
guerra vendiendo enlaces al público, que sería compensado con 
interés después de que la guerra encima. Durante la guerra, 
los ciudadanos privados y las organizaciones compraron $190 mil 
millones del valor de los enlaces de guerra en el tipo de interés 
bajo de 1.8 por ciento. Las estrellas de Hollywood llegaron a 
ser centrales a los mecanismos impulsores del enlace de guerra. 
Acreditaron la actriz encantadora Dorothy Lamour solamente con 
la venta de $350 millones en enlaces de guerra. Un septiembre de
1942 "los bombardeos en enlace" alistaron a más de trescientos 
agentes que trabajaron días de la dieciocho-hora y vendieron más de 
$800 millones en enlaces. Como la guerra arrastró encendido, 
los vendedores en enlace de Hollywood continuados para motivar compras
incluso cuando la victoria aliada se parecía segura. Esta 
grabación 1945 de Bing Crosby suplicó a gente que participara en el 
séptimo préstamo de la guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087107</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108542</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/this-is-no-time-for-you-to-take-a-rest-hollywood-goes-to-war</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
