<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106391</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106391</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206459</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Penniman House: A Whaling Story</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Penniman Haus: Eine Whaling-Geschichte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Chambre de Penniman : Une Histoire de 
Pêche à la baleine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A Casa De Penniman: Uma História Da 
Baleação</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Camera Di Penniman: Una Storia Di Caccia 
alla balena</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το σπίτι Penniman: Μια ιστορία κυνηγιού 
φάλαινας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Casa De Penniman: Una Historia De la 
Pesca de ballenas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">focuses on one of the most successful whaling captains in New England. Edward Penniman was 11 in 1842 when he signed on as cook on a schooner. Years later, as a captain, he set sail from New Bedford seven times to hunt whales. The trips generally took several years each. Letters indicate he did not like life at sea, but the money allowed him to afford a large ornate house, which is featured at this site, along with a brief a history of whaling in America.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Foki auf einem der erfolgreichsten 
Whalingkapitäne in Neu-England. Edward Penniman war 11 1842, 
als er an als Koch auf einem schooner unterzeichnete. Jahre 
später, als Kapitän, stellte er Segel von New-Bedford siebenmal, 
Wale zu jagen ein. Die Reisen dauerten im Allgemeinen einige 
Jahre jedes. Zeichen zeigen an, daß er das Leben nicht am Meer 
mochte, aber das Geld ihm erlaubte, sich ein großes aufwendiges Haus,
das an dieser Site gekennzeichnet wird, zusammen mit einem Schriftsatz
zu leisten eine Geschichte von Whaling in Amerika.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">foyers sur un des capitaines de pêche à la 
baleine les plus réussis en Nouvelle Angleterre. Edouard 
Penniman était 11 de 1842 où il s'est connecté en tant que 
cuisinier sur un schooner. Des ans après, en tant que 
capitaine, il a placé la voile de New Bedford sept fois de chasser 
des baleines. Les voyages ont généralement pris plusieurs 
années chacune. Les lettres indiquent qu'il n'a pas aimé la 
vie en mer, mais l'argent lui a permis d'avoir les moyens une grande 
maison fleurie, qui est décrite à ce site, avec un dossier une 
histoire de la pêche à la baleine en Amérique.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">focos em um dos capitães os mais bem sucedidos da
baleação em Nova Inglaterra. Edward Penniman era 11 em 1842 em
que assinou sobre como o cozinheiro em um schooner. Anos mais 
tarde, como um capitão, ajustou o sail de New Bedford sete vezes 
caçar baleias. Os desengates fizeram exame geralmente de 
diversos anos cada um. As letras indicam não gostou da vida no 
mar, mas o dinheiro permitiu que tivesse recursos para uma casa ornate
grande, que seja caracterizada neste local, junto com um sumário um 
history da baleação em América.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fuochi su uno dei capitani di caccia alla balena 
più riusciti in Nuova Inghilterra. Edward Penniman era 11 di 
1842 in cui ha firmato sopra come cuoco su uno schooner. Anni 
più successivamente, come capitano, ha regolato la vela da New 
Bedford sette volte cercare le balene. I viaggi hanno 
occorr generalmente parecchi anni ciascuno. Le lettere indicano 
non ha gradito la vita in mare, ma i soldi hanno permesso che lui si 
permettesse una grande casa ornate, che è descritta a questo luogo, 
con un riassunto una storia della caccia alla balena in America.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εστίαση σε έναν από τους επιτυχέστερους καπετάνιους 
κυνηγιού φάλαινας στη Νέα Αγγλία. Ο Edward Penniman 
ήταν 11 το 1842 πότε υπέγραψε επάνω ως μάγειρας σε ένα 
schooner. Έτη αργότερα, ως καπετάνιο, έθεσε το πανί από
το Νιού Μπέντφορτ επτά φορές για να κυνηγήσει τις φάλαινες. 
Τα ταξίδια διάρκεσαν γενικά αρκετά έτη κάθε ένα. Οι
επιστολές δείχνουν ότι δεν συμπάθησε τη ζωή εν πλω, αλλά τα 
χρήματα επέτρεψαν σε τον για να αντέξουν οικονομικά ένα μεγάλο 
περίκομψο σπίτι, που χαρακτηρίζεται επί αυτού του τόπου, μαζί 
με μια σύνοψη μια ιστορία του κυνηγιού φάλαινας στην Αμερική.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">focos en uno de los capitanes más acertados de la
pesca de ballenas de Nueva Inglaterra. Edward Penniman era 11 de
1842 en que él firmó encendido como cocinero en un schooner. 
Los años más adelante, como capitán, él fijó la vela de New
Bedford siete veces de buscar ballenas. Los viajes tomaron 
generalmente varios años cada uno. Las cartas indican él no 
tuvo gusto de vida en el mar, pero el dinero permitió que él 
produjera una casa adornada grande, que se ofrece en este sitio, junto
con un escrito una historia de la pesca de ballenas en América.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206459</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106391</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-penniman-house-a-whaling-story</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
