<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107459</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107459</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086329</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Indian Trader John Lawson's Journal of Carolina, 1709</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Indischen Händler-John Lawsons Journal von 
Carolina, 1709</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Journal de John Lawson indien de commerçant de la
Caroline, 1709</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jornal de John Lawson indian do comerciante de 
Carolina, 1709</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giornale del John Lawson indiano del commerciante 
della Carolina, 1709</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ινδικό περιοδικό John Lawson's εμπόρων της 
Καρολίνας, 1709</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Diario de Juan Lawson indio del comerciante de 
Carolina, 1709</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Tragically, contact between Indians and the Europeans extended beyond just trade goods; the invasion of foreign microbes devastated Indian communities well beyond the coastal region. When John Lawson visited the Carolina interior in the 1690s, he encountered the Congaree people, whose numbers and villages had been dramatically reduced by smallpox and other diseases. In 1660, Lawson, born into a London gentry family and aspiring to a career as a natural scientist, had set sail for the Carolina colony that was founded after the restoration of the British monarchy. He traveled more than a thousand miles as an employee of the colony's proprietors, who were eager to attract additional colonists and foster economic development. Lawson's keen eye for the native and non-native people, flora, and fauna of the region was evidenced in his journal  A New Voyage to Carolina , published in 1709.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Tragisch dehnte sich Kontakt zwischen Indern und 
den Europäern über gerechten Geschäftswaren hinaus aus; die 
Invasion der fremden Mikroben verwüstete indische Gemeinschaften gut 
über dem Küstengebiet hinaus. Als John Lawson das Carolina 
Inneren im 1690s besuchte, traf er die Congaree Leute an, deren Zahlen
und Dörfer drastisch durch Pocken und andere Krankheiten verringert 
worden waren. 1660 hatte Lawson, getragen in eine London 
Adelfamilie und in das Streben zu einer Karriere als natürlicher 
Wissenschaftler, Segel für die Carolina Kolonie eingestellt, die nach
der Wiederherstellung der britischen Monarchie gegründet wurde. 
Er reiste mehr als tausend Meilen als Angestellter der 
Eigentümer der Kolonie, die eifrig waren, zusätzliche Kolonisten 
anzuziehen und ökonomische Entwicklung zu fördern. Lawsons 
scharfes Auge für die gebürtigen und non-native Leute, die Flora und
die Fauna der Region wurde in seinem Journal eine neue Reise nach 
Carolina bewiesen, veröffentlicht 1709.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Tragiquement, le contact entre les Indiens et les 
Européens a étendu au delà des marchandises commerciales justes ; 
l'invasion des microbes étrangers a bien dévasté les 
communautés indiennes au delà de la région côtière. Quand 
John Lawson a visité l'intérieur de la Caroline dans le 1690s, il a 
rencontré les personnes de Congaree, dont des nombres et les villages
avaient été excessivement réduits par la variole et d'autres 
maladies. En 1660, Lawson, soutenu dans une famille de gens de 
la haute société de Londres et aspirer à une carrière en tant que 
scientifique normal, avait placé la voile pour la colonie de la 
Caroline qui a été fondée après la restauration de la monarchie 
britannique. Il a voyagé davantage que mille milles en tant 
qu'employé des propriétaires de la colonie, qui étaient désireux 
d'attirer les colons supplémentaires et de stimuler le développement
économique. L'oeil vif de Lawson pour les personnes, la flore, 
et la faune indigènes et d'origine étrangère de la région a été 
démontré en son journal un nouveau voyage vers la Caroline, éditée
en 1709.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Tràgica, o contato entre indians e os Europeus 
estendeu além dos bens de comércio justos; a invasão de 
micróbios extrangeiros devastated comunidades indian bem além da 
região litoral. Quando John Lawson visitou o interior de 
Carolina no 1690s, encontrou os povos de Congaree, cujos números e as
vilas tinham sido reduzidas dramàtica pelo smallpox e pelas outras 
doenças. Em 1660, Lawson, carregado em uma família do gentry 
de Londres e em aspiring a uma carreira como um cientista natural, 
tinha ajustado o sail para a colônia de Carolina que foi fundada 
após a restauração do monarchy britânico. Viajou mais do que
mil milhas como um empregado dos proprietors da colônia, que estavam 
ansiosos para atrair colonos adicionais e para promover o 
desenvolvimento econômico. O olho afiado de Lawson para os 
povos, o flora, e o fauna nativos e non-native da região foi 
evidenciado em seu jornal uma viagem nova a Carolina, publicado em 
1709.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Tragicamente, il contatto fra gli indiani e gli 
Europei si è esteso oltre le merci commerciali giuste; 
l'invasione dei microbi stranieri ha devastato bene le Comunità
indiane oltre la regione litoranea. Quando John Lawson ha 
visitato l'interiore della Carolina nel 1690s, ha incontrato la gente 
di Congaree, di cui numeri ed i villaggi erano stati ridotti 
drammaticamente dalla vaiolo e da altre malattie. In 1660, 
Lawson, sopportato in una famiglia del gentry de Londra e 
nell'aspirazione ad una carriera come scienziato naturale, aveva 
regolato la vela per la colonia della Carolina che è stata fondata 
dopo il ripristino del monarchy britannico. Ha viaggiato più di
mille miglia come impiegato dei proprietari della colonia, che erano 
desiderosi di attrarre i colonizzatori supplementari e di promuovere 
lo sviluppo economico. L'occhio acuto del Lawson per la gente, 
la flora e la fauna natali e non-native della regione è stato provato
in suo giornale un nuovo viaggio in Carolina, pubblicata in 1709.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τραγικά, η επαφή μεταξύ Ινδών και των Ευρωπαίων 
επεκτάθηκε πέρα από ακριβώς τα εμπορικά αγαθά  η εισβολή 
των ξένων μικροβίων κατάστρεψε τις ινδικές κοινότητες καλά πέρα
από την παράκτια περιοχή. Όταν John Lawson 
επισκέφτηκε το εσωτερικό της Καρολίνας στο 1690s, αντιμετώπισε 
τους ανθρώπους Congaree, οι των οποίων αριθμοί και τα χωριά 
ήταν μειωμένων εντυπωσιακά από την ευλογιά και άλλες ασθένειες.
Το 1660, Lawson, γεννημένο σε μια ανώτερη οικογένεια 
του Λονδίνου και επιδίωξη σε μια σταδιοδρομία ως φυσικό 
επιστήμονα, είχε θέσει το πανί για την αποικία της Καρολίνας που
ιδρύθηκε μετά από την αποκατάσταση της βρετανικής μοναρχίας. 
Ταξίδεψε περισσότερα από χίλια μίλια ως υπάλληλο των 
ιδιοκτητών της αποικίας, οι οποίοι ήταν πρόθυμοι να προσελκύσουν
τους πρόσθετους αποίκους και να ενθαρρύνουν την οικονομική 
ανάπτυξη. Το έντονο μάτι του Lawson για τους εγγενείς και
μη ιθαγενείς ανθρώπους, τη χλωρίδα, και την πανίδα της περιοχής 
αποδείχθηκε στο περιοδικό του ένα νέο ταξίδι στην Καρολίνα, που 
δημοσιεύθηκε το 1709.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Trágico, el contacto entre los indios y los 
europeos extendió más allá de mercancías comerciales justas; 
la invasión de microbios no nativos devastó a comunidades 
indias bien más allá de la región costera. Cuando Juan Lawson
visitó el interior de Carolina en el 1690s, él encontró a gente de 
Congaree, que números y aldeas habían sido reducidas dramáticamente
por la viruela y otras enfermedades. En 1660, Lawson, llevado en
una familia del gentry de Londres y la aspiración a una carrera como 
científico natural, había fijado la vela para la colonia de Carolina
que fue fundada después de la restauración de la monarquía 
británica. Él viajó más que mil millas como empleado de los 
propietarios de la colonia, que eran impacientes atraer a colonos 
adicionales y fomentar el desarrollo económico. El ojo afilado 
de Lawson para la gente, la flora, y la fauna nativas y extranjeras de
la región fue evidenciado en su diario un nuevo viaje a Carolina, 
publicada en 1709.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086329</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107459</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/indian-trader-john-lawsons-journal-of-carolina-1709</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
