<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106580</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106580</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974025</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Kevlar: The Wonder Material Activity</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kevlar: Die Wunder-Material-Aktivität</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Kevlar : l'Activité De Matériel de 
Merveille</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Kevlar: A Atividade Do Material Da 
Maravilha</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Kevlar: L'Attività Del Materiale Di Wonder</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Kevlar: Η υλική δραστηριότητα κατάπληξης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Kevlar: La Actividad Del Material De la 
Maravilla</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A material so strong it stops bullets! Find out why Kevlar is so strong. And learn how research facilities like the Advanced Light Source can reveal the details of Kevlar's structure. Bring the scientific research done at the the Advanced Light Source into your classroom using this complete teaching module.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein starkes Material so stoppt sie Gewehrkugeln! 
Finden Sie heraus, warum Kevlar so stark ist. Und erlernen
Sie, wie Forschung Teildienste wie die hochentwickelte Lichtquelle die
Details von Struktur Kevlar aufdecken können. Holen Sie die 
wissenschaftliche Forschung, die an der hochentwickelten Lichtquelle 
in Ihr Klassenzimmer mit diesem kompletten unterrichtenden Modul 
erfolgt ist.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un matériel si fort elle arrête des balles ! 
Découvrez pourquoi Kevlar est si fort. Et apprenez 
comment les équipements de recherches comme la source lumineuse 
avançée peuvent indiquer les détails de la structure de Kevlar. 
Apportez la recherche scientifique faite l'à la source 
lumineuse avançée dans votre salle de classe à l'aide de ce module 
d'enseignement complet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um material assim forte para balas! Encontre
para fora porque Kevlar é assim forte. E aprenda como as 
facilidades da pesquisa como a fonte clara avançada podem revelar os 
detalhes da estrutura de Kevlar. Traga a pesquisa científica 
feita o na fonte clara avançada em sua sala de aula usando este 
módulo ensinando completo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un materiale così forte arresta le pallottole! 
Scopra perchè Kevlar è così forte. Ed impari come le 
attrezzature di ricerca come la fonte di luce avanzata possono 
rivelare i particolari della struttura del Kevlar. Porti la 
ricerca scientifica fatta alla fonte di luce avanzata nella vostra 
aula per mezzo di questo modulo d'istruzione completo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα υλικό τόσο ισχυρό αυτό σταματά τις σφαίρες! 
Ανακαλύψτε γιατί Kevlar είναι τόσο ισχυρό. Και 
μάθετε πώς οι ερευνητικές εγκαταστάσεις όπως την προηγμένη πηγή
φωτός μπορούν να αποκαλύψουν τις λεπτομέρειες της δομής 
Kevlar. Φέρτε την επιστημονική έρευνα που γίνεται στην 
προηγμένη πηγή φωτός στην τάξη σας χρησιμοποιώντας αυτήν την 
πλήρη ενότητα διδασκαλίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Un material tan fuerte para puntos negros! 
Descubra porqué Kevlar es tan fuerte. Y aprenda cómo los
recursos de la investigación como la fuente de luz avanzada pueden 
revelar los detalles de la estructura de Kevlar. Traiga la 
investigación científica hecha en el fuente de luz avanzada en su 
sala de clase usando este módulo de enseñanza completo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974025</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106580</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/kevlar-the-wonder-material-activity</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
