<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108449</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108449</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087396</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">An Undocumented Worker Describes the Impact of the World Trade Center Attack</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein undokumentierter Arbeiter beschreibt die 
Auswirkung des Welthandel-Mitte-Angriffs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un ouvrier non documenté décrit l'impact de 
l'attaque de centre commercial mondial</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um trabalhador undocumented descreve o impacto do 
ataque do centro de comércio de mundo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un operaio non documentato descrive l'effetto 
dell'attacco del centro di commercio mondiale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένας ατεκμηρίωτος εργαζόμενος περιγράφει τον 
αντίκτυπο της κεντρικής επίθεσης παγκόσμιου εμπορίου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un trabajador indocumentado describe el impacto del
ataque del centro de comercio mundial</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This undocumented worker was left without work when the World Trade Center was attacked on September 11, 2001. The hundreds of thousands of undocumented immigrants who staff low paying jobs in the service industries are often invisible, despite their important contributions to the nation's economy. Largely unprotected by labor laws and ineligible for social security and unemployment insurance, these immigrants struggle to support themselves as well as, in many cases, family and relatives in their countries of origin. Their suffering in the wake of the World Trade Center attack was similarly invisible, although the tragedy hit the undocumented workers who worked in the center particularly hard. Undocumented workers could not gain government-sponsored economic assistance or other forms of relief available to citizens who lost work.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser undokumentierte Arbeiter wurde ohne Arbeit 
gelassen, als die Welthandel-Mitte an September 11, 2001 in Angriff 
genommen wurde. Die Hunderte von Tausenden der undokumentierten 
Immigranten, die das Tief mit Personal versorgen, das Jobs in der 
Dienstleistungsindustrie zahlt, sind häufig, trotz ihrer wichtigen 
Beiträge zur Wirtschaft der Nation unsichtbar. Groß 
ungeschützt durch Arbeitsrechte und untauglich für 
Sozialversicherung und Arbeitslosenversicherung, kämpfen diese 
Immigranten, um sich sowie, in vielen Fällen, Familie und Verwandte 
in ihren Ursprungsländern zu unterstützen. Ihr Suffering 
unmittelbar nach dem Welthandel-Mitteangriff war ähnlich unsichtbar, 
obgleich die Tragödie die undokumentierten Arbeiter schlug, die in 
der Mitte besonders stark arbeiteten. Undokumentierte Arbeiter 
konnten nicht die staatlich geförderte ökonomische Unterstützung 
oder andere Formulare der Entlastung gewinnen vorhanden für Bürger, 
die Arbeit verloren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cet ouvrier non documenté a été laissé sans 
travail quand le centre commercial mondial a été attaqué septembre 
11, 2001. Les centaines de milliers d'immigrés non documentés 
qui fournissent le bas de personnel payant les travaux dans le secteur
tertiaire sont souvent invisibles, en dépit de leurs contributions 
importantes à l'économie de la nation. En grande partie non 
protégé par des lois du travail et inéligible pour la sécurité 
sociale et l'assurance chômage, ces immigrés luttent pour se 
supporter aussi bien que, dans beaucoup de cas, la famille et les 
parents dans leurs pays d'origine. Leur douleur à la suite de 
l'attaque de centre commercial mondial était pareillement invisible, 
bien que la tragédie ait frappé les ouvriers non documentés qui ont
travaillé au centre particulièrement dur. Les ouvriers non 
documentés ne pourraient pas gagner l'aide économique commanditée 
par le gouvernement ou d'autres formes de soulagement disponibles aux 
citoyens qui ont détruit le travail.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este trabalhador undocumented foi deixado sem o 
trabalho quando o centro de comércio de mundo foi atacado setembro em
11, 2001. As centenas dos milhares dos immigrants undocumented 
que staff o ponto baixo que paga trabalhos nas indústrias de serviço
são frequentemente invisíveis, apesar de suas contribuições 
importantes à economia da nação. Pela maior parte 
desprotegido por leis labor e inelegível para a segurança social e o
seguro de desemprego, estes immigrants esforçam-se para suportar-se 
as.well.as, em muitos casos, em família e em parentes em seus países
de origem. Seu sofrimento na vigília do ataque do centro de 
comércio de mundo era similarmente invisível, embora a tragédia 
batesse os trabalhadores undocumented que trabalharam no centro 
particularmente duramente. Os trabalhadores undocumented não 
poderiam ganhar o auxílio econômico government-sponsored ou os 
outros formulários do relevo disponível aos cidadãos que perderam o
trabalho.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo operaio non documentato è stato lasciato 
senza lavoro quando il centro di commercio mondiale è stato attacato 
il 11 settembre 2001. Le centinaia dei migliaia degli immigranti
non documentati che forniscono il livello basso di personale che paga 
i lavori nel terziario sono spesso invisibili, malgrado i loro 
contributi importanti all'economia della nazione. In gran parte 
non protetto dalle leggi di lavoro ed ineleggibile per la previdenza 
sociale e l'assicurazione contro la disoccupazione, questi immigranti 
lottano per sostenersi così come, in molti casi, la famiglia ed i 
parenti nei loro pæsi d'origine. Il loro suffering come 
conseguenza dell'attacco del centro di commercio mondiale era 
similmente invisibile, anche se la tragedia ha colpito gli operai non 
documentati che hanno lavorato particolarmente duro nel centro. 
Gli operai non documentati non potrebbero guadagnare 
l'assistenza economica government-sponsored o altre forme di rilievo 
disponibili ai cittadini che hanno perso il lavoro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο ατεκμηρίωτος εργαζόμενος αφέθηκε χωρίς 
εργασία όταν επιτέθηκε το κέντρο παγκόσμιου εμπορίου στις 11 
Σεπτεμβρίου, το 2001. Οι εκατοντάδες χιλιάδες των 
ατεκμηρίωτων μεταναστών που επανδρώνουν τις χαμηλές εργασίες 
πληρωμής στις βιομηχανίες υπηρεσιών είναι συχνά αόρατες, παρά 
τις σημαντικές συνεισφορές τους στην οικονομία του έθνους. 
Κατά ένα μεγάλο μέρος μη προστατευμένί από τα εργατικά 
δίκαια και μη εκλέξιμοι για την κοινωνική ασφάλιση και την 
ασφάλεια ανεργίας, αυτοί οι μετανάστες αγωνίζονται να 
υποστηριχθούν καθώς επίσης και, σε πολλές περιπτώσεις, την 
οικογένεια και τους συγγενείς στις χώρες προέλευσής τους. 
Το βάσανό τους αμέσως μετά την κεντρική επίθεση 
παγκόσμιου εμπορίου ήταν ομοίως αόρατο, αν και η τραγωδία 
χτύπησε τους ατεκμηρίωτους εργαζομένους που εργάστηκαν στο κέντρο
ιδιαίτερα σκληρό. Οι ατεκμηρίωτοι εργαζόμενοι δεν θα 
μπορούσαν να κερδίσουν τη χρηματοδοτούμενη από την κυβέρνηση 
οικονομική βοήθεια ή άλλες μορφές της ανακούφισης διαθέσιμη 
στους πολίτες που έχασαν την εργασία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Dejaron este trabajador indocumentado sin trabajo 
cuando el centro de comercio mundial fue atacado 11 de septiembre 
de 2001. Los centenares de millares de inmigrantes 
indocumentados que provean de personal el punto bajo que paga trabajos
en las industrias de servicio son a menudo invisibles, a pesar de sus 
contribuciones importantes a la economía de la nación. En gran
parte desprotegido por leyes de trabajo e inelegible para la Seguridad
Social y el subsidio de paro, estos inmigrantes luchan para apoyarse 
así como, en muchos casos, la familia y a parientes en sus países de
origen. Su sufrimiento en la estela del ataque del centro de 
comercio mundial era semejantemente invisible, aunque la tragedia 
golpeó a trabajadores indocumentados que trabajaron en el centro 
determinado difícilmente. Los trabajadores indocumentados no 
podrían ganar la ayuda económica government-sponsored u otras formas
de relevación disponibles para los ciudadanos que perdieron el 
trabajo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087396</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108449</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/an-undocumented-worker-describes-the-impact-of-the-world-trade-center-attack</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
