<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108294</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108294</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087144</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Trust in Poverty": Lampooning the Trusts</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Vertrauen in der Armut": Verspotten der 
Vertrauen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"confiance dans la pauvreté" : Lancer des 
satires les confiances</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"confiança na pobreza": Lampooning as 
confianças</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"fiducia nella povertà": Lampooning i fondi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Εμπιστοσύνη στην ένδεια": Σάτυρα των 
εμπιστοσυνών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"confianza en pobreza": Lampooning las 
confianzas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">At the turn of the 20th century, the number of business mergers skyrocketed. Among manufacturing companies, mergers jumped from three in 1896 to sixty-three only three years later. Just as quickly the wave of mergers subsided--by 1904, there were only three mergers. This unprecedented wave of mergers was marked by horizontal consolidation--the simultaneous merger of many or all competitors in an industry into a single, giant enterprise. Many of the consolidated firms created in this period--DuPont, U.S. Steel, and International Harvester--remained major corporations throughout the 20th century. Contemporaries reacted to the great merger movement with alarm. Some used satire to express their concern. In this poem published in the New York  Journal , George V. Hobart lampooned the wide range of trusts created by merger mania.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">An der Jahrhundertwende 20., schnellte die Zahl 
Geschäft Fusionen empor. Unter Produktionsgesellschaften 
sprangen Fusionen von drei 1896 bis dreiundsechzig nur drei Jahre 
später. Gerade da schnell die Welle von Fusionen nachließ -- 
bis zum 1904, gab es nur drei Fusionen. Diese beispiellose Welle
von Fusionen wurde durch horizontale Verdichtung -- die simultane 
Fusion von vielen oder von allen Konkurrenten in einer Industrie in 
ein einzelnes, riesiges Unternehmen gekennzeichnet. Viele der 
vereinigten Unternehmen hergestellt in dieser Periode -- DuPont, 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Stahl und internationale Erntemaschine -- 
gebliebene Hauptkorporationen während des 20. Jahrhunderts. 
Zeitgenossen reagierten zur großen Fusionbewegung mit Warnung. 
Einige verwendeten Satire, um ihr Interesse 
auszudrücken. In diesem Gedicht veröffentlichte im New York 
Journal, George V. Hobart verspottete die breite Strecke der 
Vertrauen, die durch Fusionmanie erstellt wurden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">À la fin du 20ème siècle, le nombre de fusions 
d'affaires a monté en flèche. Parmi des compagnies de 
fabrication, les fusions ont branché de trois en 1896 à 
soixante-trois seulement trois ans après. Juste comme 
rapidement la vague des fusions s'abaissait -- d'ici 1904, il y avait 
seulement trois fusions. Cette vague sans précédent des 
fusions a été marquée par la fusion horizontale -- la fusion 
simultanée de beaucoup ou de tous les concurrents dans une industrie 
dans une entreprise simple et géante. Plusieurs des sociétés 
consolidées créées dans cette période -- DuPont, acier des 
ETATS-UNIS, et moissonneuse internationale -- sociétés principales 
restées tout au long du 20ème siècle. Les contemporains ont 
réagi au grand mouvement de fusion avec l'alarme. Certains ont 
employé la satire pour exprimer leurs inquiétudes. En 
cette poésie a publié au journal de New York, George V. Hobart a
lancé des satires l'éventail de confiances créées par manie de 
fusion.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Na volta do 20o século, o número de mergers do 
negócio skyrocketed. Entre companhias de manufacturing, os 
mergers saltaram de três 1896 a sessenta e três somente três anos 
em mais tarde. Apenas porque rapidamente a onda dos mergers 
subsided -- por 1904, havia somente três mergers. Esta onda 
unprecedented dos mergers foi marcada pela consolidação horizontal 
-- o merger simultâneo de muitos ou de todos os concorrentes em uma 
indústria em uma única, empresa gigante. Muitas das firmas 
consolidadas criadas neste período -- DuPont, aço de ESTADOS UNIDOS,
e harvester internacional -- corporation principais remanescidos 
durante todo o 20o século. Os comtemporâneos reagiram ao 
movimento grande do merger com o alarme. Alguns usaram o satire 
expressar seu interesse. Neste poema publicou no jornal de New 
York, George V. Hobart lampooned a escala larga das confianças 
criadas pelo mania do merger.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Alla fine del ventesimo secolo, il numero di 
fusioni di affari skyrocketed. Fra le aziende di manufacturing, 
le fusioni hanno saltato da tre 1896 - sessantatre soltanto tre anni 
in più successivamente. Appena poichè l'onda delle fusioni si 
è abbassata rapidamente -- entro 1904, ci erano soltanto tre fusioni.
Questa onda senza precedente delle fusioni è stata 
contrassegnata da consolidamento orizzontale -- la fusione simultanea 
molti o di tutti i competitori in un'industria in una singola, impresa
gigante. Molte delle ditte consolidate create in questo periodo 
-- DuPont, acciaio degli STATI UNITI e mietitrice internazionale -- 
società importanti rimaste durante il ventesimo secolo. I 
contemporanei hanno reagito al movimento grande di fusione con 
l'allarme. Alcuni hanno usato il satire per esprimere la loro 
preoccupazione. In questo poem ha pubblicato nel giornale de New
York, George V. Hobart lampooned la vasta gamma dei fondi creati da 
mania di fusione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στο γύρισμα του 20ού αιώνα, ο αριθμός επιχειρησιακών 
συγχωνεύσεων που ανέρχονται στα ύψη. Μεταξύ των 
κατασκευαστικών επιχειρήσεων, οι συγχωνεύσεις πήδησαν από τρεις 
το 1896 εξήντα τρία μόνο τρία έτη αργότερα. Ακριβώς 
όπως γρήγορα το κύμα των συγχωνεύσεων υποχώρησε -- μέχρι το 
1904, υπήρξαν μόνο τρεις συγχωνεύσεις. Αυτό το 
πρωτοφανές κύμα των συγχωνεύσεων χαρακτηρίστηκε από την 
οριζόντια σταθεροποίηση -- η ταυτόχρονη συγχώνευση πολλοί ή 
όλων των ανταγωνιστών σε μια βιομηχανία σε μια ενιαία, γιγαντιαία
επιχείρηση. Πολλές από τις παγιωμένες εταιρίες που 
δημιουργήθηκαν σε αυτήν την περίοδο -- DuPont, ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΌΣ 
χάλυβας, και διεθνής θεριστική μηχανή -- παρέμειναν σημαντικές 
εταιρίες καθ' όλη τη διάρκεια του 20ού αιώνα. Οι σύγχρονοι
αντέδρασαν στη μεγάλη μετακίνηση συγχώνευσης με το συναγερμό. 
Μερικοί χρησιμοποίησαν τη σάτυρα για να εκφράσουν την 
ανησυχία τους. Σε αυτό το ποίημα που δημοσιεύθηκε στο 
περιοδικό της Νέας Υόρκης, George V. Χόμπαρτ σατύρισε το 
ευρύ φάσμα των εμπιστοσυνών που δημιουργήθηκαν από τη μανία 
συγχώνευσης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Al final del vigésimo siglo, el número de las 
fusiones del negocio se elevó súbitamente. Entre las 
compañías de fabricación, las fusiones saltaron a partir del tres 
en 1896 a sesenta y tres solamente tres años más tarde. Apenas
pues se desplomó rápidamente la onda de fusiones -- antes de 1904, 
había solamente tres fusiones. Esta onda sin precedente de 
fusiones fue marcada por la consolidación horizontal -- la fusión 
simultánea de muchos o de todos los competidores en una industria en 
una empresa sola, gigante. Muchas de las firmas consolidadas 
creadas en este período -- DuPont, acero de ESTADOS UNIDOS, y 
máquina segador internacional -- corporaciones importantes 
permanecidas a través del vigésimo siglo. Los contemporáneos 
reaccionaron al gran movimiento de la fusión con el alarmar. 
Algunos utilizaron sátira para expresar su preocupación. 
En este poema publicó en el diario de Nueva York, George V. 
Hobart lampooned la amplia gama de las confianzas creadas por mania de
la fusión.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087144</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108294</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/trust-in-poverty-lampooning-the-trusts</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
