<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108813</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108813</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086988</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Men Seem To Be Pretty Well Satisfied": John Anderson on the 1919 Steel Strike</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Die Männer Scheinen, Die Hübsche Erfüllte 
Vertiefung Zu sein": John Anderson auf dem Stahlschlag 1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Les Hommes Semblent Être Joli Puits Satisfait" :
John Anderson sur la grève 1919 en acier</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Os Homens Parecem Ser Poço Bonito Satisfeito": 
John Anderson na batida 1919 de aço</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Gli Uomini Sembrano Essere Pozzo Grazioso 
Soddisfatto": John Anderson sul colpo d'acciaio 1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Τα άτομα φαίνονται αρκετά καλά να ικανοποιούνται": 
Θ*Ιοχν Αντερσον στην απεργία χάλυβα του 1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Los Hombres Se parecen Ser Receptor de papel 
Bonito Satisfecho": Juan Anderson en la huelga de acero 1919</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the dramatic 1919 steel strike, 350,000 workers walked off their jobs and crippled the industry. The U.S. Senate Committee on Education and Labor set out to investigate the strike while it was still in progress. In his testimony before the committee, John Anderson, a helper in the open-hearth furnace at the Homestead steelworks in Pennsylvania, maintains that the steelworkers were satisfied with conditions. Although born in Scotland, Anderson identified himself as an"American" in distinction from the (also) foreign-born laborers who are out on strike.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im drastischen 1919 Stahlschlag gingen 350.000 
Arbeiter weg von ihren Jobs und verkrüppelten die Industrie. 
Der VEREINIGTE STAATEN Senat-Ausschuß für Ausbildung und 
Arbeit legte dar, um den Schlag nachzuforschen, während er noch in 
Bewegung war. In seinem Zeugnis vor dem Ausschuß, behält John 
Anderson, ein Helfer im open-hearth Ofen am Gehöftstahlwerk in 
Pennsylvania bei, daß die Steelworkers mit Bedingungen 
zufriedenWAREN. Obgleich geboren in Schottland, Anderson, 
kennzeichnete sich, wie an"American" in der Unterscheidung von den 
(auch) foreign-born Arbeitern, die heraus an Schlag sind.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans les 1919 grèves en acier excessive, 350.000 
ouvriers ont marché outre de leurs travaux et ont estropié 
l'industrie. Le comité de sénat des ETATS-UNIS de l'éducation
et du travail s'est mis à étudier la grève tandis qu'elle était 
encore en marche. Dans son témoignage devant le comité, John 
Anderson, une aide dans le four Martin à l'aciérie de ferme en 
Pennsylvanie, met à jour que les travailleurs dans l'industrie 
sidérurgique ont été satisfaits dans des conditions. Bien que
né en Ecosse, Anderson s'est identifié comme an"American" dans la 
distinction (aussi) des travailleurs nés à l'étranger qui sont 
dehors en grève.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nas 1919 batidas de aço dramática, 350.000 
trabalhadores andaram fora de seus trabalhos e aleijaram a indústria.
O comitê do senate de ESTADOS UNIDOS na instrução e no 
trabalho ajustou-se para fora para investigar a batida quando era 
ainda em andamento. Em seu testimony antes do comitê, John 
Anderson, um ajudante na fornalha open-hearth no steelworks do 
homestead em Pensilvânia, mantem que os steelworkers estiveram 
satisfeitos com as circunstâncias. Embora nascido em Scotland, 
Anderson identificou-se como an"American" na distinção (também) dos
laborers foreign-born que estão para fora sobre batida.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nei 1919 colpi d'acciaio drammatico, 350.000 
operai hanno camminato fuori dei loro lavori ed hanno paralizzato 
l'industria. Il comitato del senato degli STATI UNITI di 
formazione e del Lavoro ha precisato per studiare il colpo mentre
era ancora in progresso. Nella sua testimonianza prima del 
comitato, John Anderson, un assistente nella fornace Martin-Siemens 
all'acciaieria della fattoria in Pensilvania, effettua che gli addetti
alla lavorazione dell'acciaio sono stati soddisfatti con le 
circostanze. Anche se nato in Scozia, Anderson si è 
identificato come an"American" nella distinzione (anche) dai 
lavoratori foreign-born che sono fuori sopra colpo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στη δραματική απεργία χάλυβα του 1919, 350.000 
εργαζόμενοι περπάτησαν από τις εργασίες τους και ακρωτηρίασαν τη 
βιομηχανία. Η Επιτροπή ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ Συγκλήτου της 
εκπαίδευσης και η εργασία καθόρισαν να ερευνήσουν την απεργία 
ενώ ήταν ακόμα υπό εξέλιξη. Στην κατάθεσή του ενώπιον 
της επιτροπής, John Αντερσον, ένας αρωγός στο open-hearth 
φούρνο στα χαλυβουργεία αγροτικών σπιτιών στην Πενσυλβανία, 
υποστηρίζει ότι οι σιδηρουργοί ικανοποιήθηκαν με τους όρους. 
Αν και γεννημένο στη Σκωτία, το Αντερσον προσδιορίστηκε ως 
an"American" στη διάκριση από τα (επίσης) ξένος-γεννημένα 
laborers που είναι έξω στην απεργία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En las 1919 huelgas de acero dramática, 350.000 
trabajadores recorrieron de sus trabajos y lisiaron la industria. 
El comité del senado de ESTADOS UNIDOS sobre la educación y el
trabajo precisó para investigar la huelga mientras que todavía 
estaba en marcha. En su testimonio ante el comité, Juan 
Anderson, un ayudante en el horno de hogar abierto en la acería de la
granja en Pennsylvania, mantiene que los trabajadores siderúrgicos 
fueron satisfechos con condiciones. Aunque es nato en Escocia, 
Anderson se identificó como an"American" en la distinción (también)
de los trabajadores foreign-born que están hacia fuera encendido 
huelga.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086988</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108813</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-men-seem-to-be-pretty-well-satisfied-john-anderson-on-the-1919-steel-strike</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
