<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106770</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106770</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211967</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">River Systems: Process and Form</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Fluss-Systeme: Prozeß und Formular</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Systèmes de Fleuve : Processus et forme</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Sistemas Do Rio: Processo e formulário</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sistemi Del Fiume: Processo e forma</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Συστήματα ποταμών: Διαδικασία και μορφή</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sistemas Del Río: Proceso y forma</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site provides access to a number of visual resources and supporting material about physical processes acting in rivers and floodplains. Visualizations include simple animations, visual output from numerical models, sediment transfer movies, and numerous static illustrations and photos. Resources can be integrated into lectures, labs, classes, or other activities about fluvial processes and landscape evolution over time.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site liefert Zugriff zu einer Zahl der 
Sichtbetriebsmittel und des Hilfsmaterials über die körperlichen 
Prozesse, die in den Flüssen und in den floodplains fungieren. 
Sichtbarmachungen schließen einfache Animationen, Sichtausgabe 
von den numerischen Modellen, Sedimentübergangsfilme und zahlreiche 
statische Abbildungen und Fotos ein. Betriebsmittel können in 
Vorträge, in Labors, in Kategorien oder in andere Aktivitäten über 
fluviale Prozesse und Landschaftsentwicklung Überzeit integriert 
werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site fournit l'accès à un certain nombre de 
ressources visuelles et le matériel de support au sujet des processus
physiques agissant dans les fleuves et les floodplains. Les 
visualisations incluent les animations simples, la sortie visuelle des
modèles numériques, les films de transfert de sédiment, et les 
nombreuses illustrations et photos statiques. Des ressources 
peuvent être intégrées dans des conférences, des laboratoires, des
classes, ou d'autres activités au sujet des processus fluviaux et de 
temps fini d'évolution d'horizontal.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local fornece o acesso a um número de 
recursos visuais e o material suportando sobre os processos físicos 
que agem nos rios e nos floodplains. Os visualizations incluem 
animations simples, saída visual dos modelos numéricos, filmes de 
transferência do sedimento, e ilustrações e fotos de estática 
numerosas. Os recursos podem ser integrados em lectures, em 
laboratórios, em classes, ou em outras atividades sobre processos 
fluvial e o tempo excedente da evolução da paisagem.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo fornisce l'accesso ad un certo numero
di risorse visive ed il materiale di sostegno circa i processi fisici 
che si comportano nei fiumi e nei floodplains. Le 
visualizzazioni includono le animazioni semplici, uscita visiva dai 
modelli numerici, film di trasferimento del sedimento ed 
illustrazioni e foto statiche numerose. Le risorse possono 
essere integrate nelle conferenze, nei laboratori, nei codici 
categoria, o in altre attività circa i processi fluviali e col tempo 
di sviluppo di paesaggio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή παρέχει την πρόσβαση σε διάφορα 
οπτικά στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς και ενισχυτικό υλικό για τις 
φυσικές διαδικασίες ενεργώντας στους ποταμούς και τις κοίτες 
πλημμυρών. Οι απεικονίσεις περιλαμβάνουν τις απλές 
ζωτικότητες, οπτική έξοδος από τα αριθμητικά μοντέλα, τους 
κινηματογράφους μεταφοράς ιζημάτων, και τις πολυάριθμες στατικές 
απεικονίσεις και τις φωτογραφίες. Τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς 
μπορούν να ενσωματωθούν στις διαλέξεις, τα εργαστήρια, τις 
κλάσεις, ή άλλες δραστηριότητες για τις ποτάμιες διαδικασίες και
την εξέλιξη τοπίων κατά τη διάρκεια του χρόνου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio proporciona al acceso a un número de 
recursos visuales y al material que utiliza sobre los procesos 
físicos que actúan en los ríos y los floodplains. Las 
visualizaciones incluyen animaciones simples, salida visual de modelos
numéricos, las películas de la transferencia del sedimento, y las 
ilustraciones y las fotos estáticas numerosas. Los recursos se 
pueden integrar en conferencias, laboratorios, clases, u otras 
actividades sobre procesos fluviales y en un cierto plazo la 
evolución del paisaje.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211967</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106770</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/river-systems-process-and-form</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
