<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106127</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106127</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086235</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Henry Grady Sells the "New South"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Henry Grady verkauft den "neuen Süden"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Henry Grady vend les "nouveaux Sud"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Henry Grady vende "o sul novo"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il henry Grady vende "il nuovo sud"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θ*Χενρυ Grady Sells ο "νέος νότοσ"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Henrio Grady vende el "nuevo sur"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The vision of a "New South" was heralded by southern landowners, entrepreneurs, and newspaper editors in the decades following the Confederacy's defeat in 1865 and the abolition of racial slavery across the South. These "New South" boosters argued that, with its plantation economy destroyed by the Civil War and Reconstruction, the South would develop a new economy more attuned to the industrial capitalism that defined the rest of the American economy. Atlanta  Constitution  editor Henry Grady was the leading exponent of a "New South" based on industrial development, giving speeches throughout the country and writing articles and editorials in his newspaper. Both of the following speeches by Grady--one given in Boston in 1889, the other in New York in 1886--conveyed not only the message of industrialization as a panacea, but also Grady's fierce regional pride and his general moderation on racial issues, which were becoming increasingly contentious in these years.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Anblick eines "neuen Südens" wurde von den 
südlichen Grundbesitzern, von den Unternehmern und von den 
Zeitungsverlegern in den Dekaden angekündigt, die der Niederlage der 
Konföderation 1865 und der Aufhebung der rassischen Sklaverei über 
dem Süden folgen. Diese "neuen Süd" Verstärker 
argumentierten, daß, wenn seine Plantagewirtschaft durch den 
Bürgerkrieg und die Rekonstruktion zerstört ist, der Süden eine 
neue Wirtschaft entwickeln würde, die mehr zum industriellen 
Kapitalismus abgestimmt wurde, der den Rest der amerikanischen 
Wirtschaft definierte. Atlanta Beschaffenheit-Herausgeber Henry 
Grady war der führende Exponent eines "neuen Südens", der auf 
industrieller Entwicklung, dem Geben von von Reden in dem Land und dem
Schreiben der Artikel und der Leitartikel in seine Zeitung basierte. 
Beide der folgenden Reden durch Grady -- einer gegeben in Boston
1889, der andere in New York 1886 -- übermittelt nicht nur der 
Meldung der Industrialisierung als Panazee, aber auch Gradys heftiger 
regionaler Stolz und seine allgemeine Mäßigung auf rassischen 
Ausgaben, die in diesen Jahren in zunehmendem Maße streitsüchtig 
wurden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La vision d'un "nouveau Sud" a été 
annoncée par les propriétaires fonciers, les entrepreneurs, et les 
éditeurs de journal méridionaux dans les décennies suivant la 
défaite de la confédération en 1865 et l'abolition de l'esclavage 
racial à travers les Sud. Ces "nouveaux" propulseurs 
Du sud ont argué du fait que, avec sa économie de plantation 
détruite par la guerre civile et la reconstruction, les Sud 
développeraient une nouvelle économie davantage adaptée au 
capitalisme industriel qui a défini le reste de l'économie 
américaine. Henry Grady d'éditeur de constitution d'Atlanta 
était le principal exposant d'un "nouveau Sud" basé sur le 
développement industriel, donner des discours dans tout le pays et 
écrire des articles et des éditoriaux en son journal. Tous les
deux discours suivants par Grady -- un donné à Boston en 1889, 
l'autre à New York en 1886 -- transporté non seulement le message de
l'industrialisation comme panacée, mais également la fierté 
régionale féroce et sa modération générale de Grady sur les 
questions raciales, qui devenaient de plus en plus controversables en 
ces années.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A visão "de um sul novo" heralded por 
latifundiários, por empreendedores, e por editores de jornal do sul 
nas décadas que seguem a derrota do confederacy em 1865 e o abolition
do slavery racial através do sul. Estes impulsionadores "sul" 
novos discutiram que, com sua economia da plantação destruída pela 
guerra civil e pelo reconstruction, o sul desenvolveria uma economia 
nova attuned mais ao capitalismo industrial que definiu o descanso da 
economia americana. O Henry Grady do editor do constitution de 
Atlanta era o exponente principal "de um sul novo" baseado no 
desenvolvimento industrial, em dar discursos durante todo o país e em
escrever artigos e editorials em seu jornal. Ambos os seguintes 
discursos por Grady -- um dado em Boston em 1889, o outro em New York 
em 1886 -- feito saber não somente a mensagem do industrialization 
como um panacea, mas também orgulho regional feroz e seu moderation 
geral de Grady nas edições raciais, que se estavam tornando cada vez
mais contentious nestes anos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La visione "di nuovo sud" è stata annunziata dai 
latifondisti, dagli imprenditori e dagli editori di giornale del sud 
nelle decadi che seguono la sconfitta del confederacy in 1865 e 
l'abolizione di slavery razziale attraverso il sud. Questi 
"nuovi" ripetitori del sud hanno sostenuto che, con la relativa 
economia della piantagione distrutta dalla guerra civile e 
dalla ricostruzione, il sud svilupperebbe una nuova economia di più 
adattata al capitalismo industriale che ha definito il resto 
dell'economia americana. Il henry Grady dell'editore di 
costituzione de Atlanta era l'esponente principale "di nuovo sud" 
basato su sviluppo industriale, sul dare i discorsi durante il paese e
sulla scrittura gli articoli e degli editoriali in suo giornale. 
Entrambi i seguenti discorsi da Grady -- uno dato a Boston in 
1889, l'altro a New York in 1886 -- trasportato non soltanto il 
messaggio dell'industrializzazione come panacea, ma anche orgoglio 
regionale feroce e la sua moderazione generale del Grady sulle 
edizioni razziali, che stavano diventando sempre più polemiche 
durante questi anni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το όραμα ενός "νέου νότου" ανακοινώθηκε από τα 
νότιους landowners, τους επιχειρηματίες, και τους επεξεργαστές 
εφημερίδων στις δεκαετίες μετά από την ήττα της συνομοσπονδίας 
το 1865 και την κατάργηση της φυλετικής σκλαβιάς πέρα από το 
νότο. Αυτοί οι ενισχυτές "νέου νότου" υποστήριξαν ότι, με
την οικονομία φυτειών του που καταστρέφεται από τον εμφύλιο 
πόλεμο και την αναδημιουργία, ο νότος θα ανέπτυσσε μια νέα 
οικονομία που προσαρμόζεται περισσότερο στη βιομηχανική 
κεφαλαιοκρατία που καθόρισε το υπόλοιπο της αμερικανικής 
οικονομίας. Ο επεξεργαστής Henry Grady συνταγμάτων της 
Ατλάντας ήταν ο κύριος εκθέτης ενός "νέου νότου" βασισμένου 
στη βιομηχανική ανάπτυξη, που δίνει τις ομιλίες σε όλη τη χώρα 
και που γράφει τα άρθρα και τα κύρια άρθρα στην εφημερίδα του. 
Και των ακόλουθων ομιλιών Grady -- ένα που δίνεται στη 
Βοστώνη το 1889, άλλη στη Νέα Υόρκη το 1886 -- μεταβίβασε 
όχι μόνο το μήνυμα της εκβιομηχάνισης ως πανάκεια, αλλά και την 
άγρια περιφερειακή υπερηφάνεια Grady και τη γενική 
μετριοπάθειά του στα φυλετικά ζητήματα, τα οποία γίνονταν όλο 
και περισσότερο εριστικά σε αυτά τα έτη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La visión de un "nuevo sur" fue anunciada por los
terratenientes, los empresarios, y los redactores meridionales en las 
décadas que seguían la derrota del confederacy en 1865 y la 
abolición de la esclavitud racial a través del sur. Estos 
aumentadores de presión "del sur" nuevos discutieron que, con su 
economía de la plantación destruida por la guerra civil y la 
reconstrucción, el sur desarrollara una nueva economía adaptada más
al capitalismo industrial que definió el resto de la economía 
americana. El Henrio Grady del editor de la constitución de 
Atlanta era el exponente principal de un "nuevo sur" basado en el 
desarrollo industrial, dar discursos a través del país y escribir 
los artículos y los editoriales en su periódico. Ambos 
discursos siguientes de Grady -- uno dado en Boston en 1889, el otro 
en Nueva York en 1886 -- transportado no solamente el mensaje de la 
industrialización como panacea, pero también orgullo regional feroz 
y su moderación general de Grady en las ediciones raciales, que 
llegaban a ser cada vez más discutibles en estos años.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086235</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106127</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/henry-grady-sells-the-new-south</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
