<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105930</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105930</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086056</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Dancing after Dark: A Rural Woman Recalls Farm Life in the Early 20th century</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Tanzen nach Dunkelheit: Eine 
landwirtschaftliche Frau erinnert an das Bauernhof-Leben im frühen 
20. Jahrhundert</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Danser après l'obscurité : Une femme rurale
rappelle la vie de ferme en début du 20ème siècle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Dançar após a obscuridade: Uma mulher rural
recorda a vida da fazenda no 20o século adiantado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ballando dopo l'oscurità: Una donna rurale 
ricorda la vita dell'azienda agricola nell'inizio del 20esimo secolo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Χορός μετά από το σκοτάδι: Μια αγρότισσα 
υπενθυμίζει την αγροτική ζωή στις αρχές του 20ού αιώνα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El bailar después de obscuridad: Una mujer 
rural recuerda vida de la granja en el vigésimo siglo temprano</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Although we sometimes think of farm and factory as antithetical, many people moved easily between the two. Icy Norman grew up in North Carolina, the daughter of a miner. As a young woman she worked long hours in a textile mill, but she also helped with the farm chores, especially seasonal chores like the corn shucking described here. In this excerpt from a 1979 interview conducted by the Southern Oral History Program at the University of North Carolina, she recalled family and friends rolling up the rug for dances and parties when the day's work was done.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Obgleich wir manchmal an Bauernhof und Fabrik 
denken, wie antithetical, zogen viele Leute leicht zwischen die zwei 
um. Eisiger Normanne wuchs in Nord-Carolina, die Tochter eines 
Bergmannes auf. Da eine junge Frau sie lange Stunden in einem 
Textiltausendstel bearbeitete, aber sie auch bei den Bauernhof Chores 
half, besonders Saisonchores wie das Maisschälen hier beschrieben. 
In diesem Excerpt von einem Interview 1979, das mit dem 
südlichen Mundgeschichte Programm an der Universität von 
Nord-Carolina geleitet wurde, rief sie die Familie und Freunde wieder 
auf, die herauf die Wolldecke für Tänze und Parteien, als die 
Arbeit des Tages, rollen erledigt wurde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bien que nous pensions parfois à la ferme et à 
l'usine comme antithétique, beaucoup de gens se sont déplacées 
facilement entre les deux. Le Normand glacial a grandi en 
Caroline du nord, la fille d'un mineur. Car une jeune femme 
elle a travaillé de longues heures dans un moulin de textile, mais 
elle aidait également avec les corvées de ferme, particulièrement 
des corvées saisonnières comme l'écossage de maïs décrit ici. 
Dans cet extrait d'une entrevue 1979 conduite par le programme 
oral méridional d'histoire à l'université de la Caroline 
du nord, elle a rappelé la famille et les amis roulant vers le 
haut de la couverture pour des danses et des parties quand le travail 
du jour a été effectué.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Embora nós pensássemos às vezes da fazenda e da 
fábrica como antithetical, muitos povos moveram-se fàcilmente entre 
os dois. O normando gelado cresceu acima em North.carolina, 
filha de um mineiro. Porque uma mulher nova ela trabalhou horas 
longas em um moinho de textile, mas ajudou também com os chores da 
fazenda, especial chores seasonal como shucking do milho descrito 
aqui. Neste excerpt de uma entrevista 1979 conduzida pelo 
programa oral do sul do history na universidade de North.carolina, 
recordou a família e os amigos que rolam acima do tapete para danças
e partidos quando o trabalho do dia foi feito.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Anche se a volte pensiamo al podere ed alla 
fabbrica come antitetico, molta gente si è mossa facilmente fra i 
due. Il normanno ghiacciato si è sviluppato in su in 
North.carolina, la figlia di un minatore. Poichè una donna 
giovane lei ha lavorato le ore lunghe in un laminatoio della tessile, 
ma egualmente ha aiutato con i chores dell'azienda agricola, 
particolarmente chores stagionali come la sgusciatura del cereale 
descritta qui. In questo brano da un'intervista 1979 condotta 
dal programma orale del sud di storia all'università di 
North.carolina, ha ricordato la famiglia e gli amici che rotolano 
sulla coperta per i balli ed i partiti quando il lavoro del giorno è 
stato fatto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αν και σκεφτόμαστε μερικές φορές το αγρόκτημα και το 
εργοστάσιο όπως αντιθετικός, πολλοί άνθρωποι κινήθηκαν εύκολα 
μεταξύ των δύο. Ο παγωμένος Norman μεγάλωσε στη βόρεια 
Καρολίνα, η κόρη ενός ανθρακωρύχου. Σαν νέα γυναίκα 
απασχολήθηκε στις πολλές ώρες σε έναν υφαντικό μύλο, αλλά 
βοήθησε επίσης με τις αγροτικές μικροδουλειές, ειδικά εποχιακές 
μικροδουλειές όπως το ξεφλούδισμα καλαμποκιού που περιγράφηκε 
εδώ. Σε αυτό το απόσπασμα από μια συνέντευξη του 1979 
που πραγματοποιήθηκε από το νότιο προφορικό πρόγραμμα ιστορίας 
στο πανεπιστήμιο της βόρειας Καρολίνας, υπενθύμισε την οικογένεια
και τους φίλους που κυλούν επάνω την κουβέρτα για τους χορούς και
τα συμβαλλόμενα μέρη όταν έγινε η εργασία της ημέρας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Aunque pensamos a veces en granja y fábrica como 
antitético, mucha gente se movió fácilmente entre los dos. El
normando helado creció para arriba en Carolina del Norte, la hija de 
un minero. Pues una mujer joven ella trabajó largases horas en 
un molino del textil, pero ella también ayudó con las tareas de la 
granja, especialmente las tareas estacionales como desvainar del maíz
descrito aquí. En este extracto de una entrevista 1979 
conducida por el programa oral meridional de la historia en la 
universidad de Carolina del Norte, ella recordó a la familia y a 
amigos que rodaban encima de la manta para las danzas y los partidos 
cuando el trabajo del día fue hecho.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086056</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105930</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/dancing-after-dark-a-rural-woman-recalls-farm-life-in-the-early-20th-century</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
