<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103372</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103372</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087048</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Shadow of Incipient Censorship": The Creation of the Television Code of 1952</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"der Schatten der anfänglichen Zensur": Die 
Kreation des Fernsehen-Codes von 1952</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"l'ombre de la censure naissante" : La 
création du code de télévision de 1952</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"a sombra da censura incipient": A criação 
do código da televisão de 1952</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"l'ombra di censura incipiente": La creazione
del codice della televisione di 1952</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η σκιά της αρχικής λογοκρισίασ": Η δημιουργία 
του τηλεοπτικού κώδικα του 1952</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"la sombra de la censura incipiente": La 
creación del código de la televisión de 1952</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">While experimental television broadcasts were first transmitted in the 1920s, mass production of television sets did not occur until after World War II. By 1960 the number of sets in the U.S. had surpassed the number of homes. With this relatively swift introduction of television into domestic American life, concern was voiced over the harmful influence that watching television might have on the nation's children. Although Congress held its first hearing on the subject in 1952, they chose not to take any action to interfere with the industry, in part because that year the National Association of Radio and Television Broadcasters adopted a code to regulate broadcast content. The Senate report held hearings in 1954 and 1955 on the possible influence of television on juvenile delinquency. The resulting report summarized standards included in the Television Code pertaining to the portrayal of crime, horror, sex, and law enforcement, and to the industry's responsibility to provide "wholesome entertainment" for children. The report also presented testimony from a television executive who cited the motion picture industry's history of successful self-regulation to ward off government censorship. The Senate report--excerpts of which are included below--also presented the preamble to the Code and detailed the Code's review mechanism.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während experimentelle Fernsehensendungen zuerst 
in die zwanziger Jahre übertragen wurden, trat Großserienfertigung 
der Fernseher nicht bis nach den Zweiten Weltkrieg auf. Durch 
1960 hatte die Zahl Sets in den VEREINIGTEN STAATEN die Zahl Häusern 
übertroffen. Mit dieser verhältnismäßig schnellen Einleitung
des Fernsehens in inländische amerikanische Lebensdauer, wurde 
Interesse über dem schädlichen Einfluß geäußert, den 
überwachendes Fernsehen auf den Kindern der Nation haben konnte. 
Obgleich Kongreß seine erste Hörfähigkeit auf dem Thema 1952 
anhielt, beschlossen sie, keine Maßnahmen zu ergreifen, um die 
Industrie, im Teil zu behinderen, weil dieses Jahr die nationale 
Verbindung der Radio-und Fernsehen-Rundfunkstationen einen Code 
annahm, um Sendung Inhalt zu regeln. Der Senatreport hielt 
Hörfähigkeiten 1954 und 1955 auf dem möglichen Einfluß des 
Fernsehens auf jugendliche Gesetzesverletzung an. Der 
resultierende Report faßte die Standards zusammen, die im 
Fernsehen-Code eingeschlossen waren, der die Schilderung des 
Verbrechens, der Grausigkeit, des Geschlechtes und der 
Gesetzdurchführung und die Verantwortlichkeit der Industrie, "gesunde
Unterhaltung" für Kinder zur Verfügung zu stellen betrifft. 
Der Report stellte auch Zeugnis von einem Fernsehenleitprogramm 
dar, das die Geschichte der Bewegung Abbildung Industrie des 
erfolgreichen Self-regulation zitierte, um weg von der Regierung 
Zensur einzuweisen. Der Senatreport -- Excerpts, von denen unten
enthalten seien Sie -- auch stellte die Präambel dem Code dar und 
schilderte die Schreibtischtest für ein Programmeinheit genau.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Tandis que des émissions expérimentales de 
télévision étaient transmises la première fois dans les années 
20, la production en série des téléviseurs ne s'est pas produite 
jusque 2'après la deuxième guerre mondiale. Par 1960 le nombre
de positionnements aux ETATS-UNIS avait surpassé le nombre de 
maisons. Avec cette introduction relativement rapide de 
télévision dans la vie américaine domestique, le souci a été 
exprimé au-dessus de l'influence nocive que la télévision 
d'observation pourrait avoir sur les enfants de la nation. Bien 
que le congrès ait tenu sa première audition sur le sujet en 1952, 
ils ont choisi de ne pas prendre n'importe quelle mesure pour gêner 
l'industrie, en partie parce que cette année l'association nationale 
des radiodiffuseurs de radio et de télévision a adopté un code pour
régler le contenu d'émission. L'état de sénat a tenu des 
auditions en 1954 et 1955 sur l'influence possible de la télévision 
sur la délinquance juvénile. L'état résultant a récapitulé
des normes incluses dans le code de télévision concernant la 
représentation du crime, de l'horreur, du sexe, et de l'application 
de loi, et la responsabilité de l'industrie de fournir "le 
divertissement sain" pour des enfants. L'état a également 
présenté le témoignage d'un directeur de télévision qui a cité 
l'histoire d'industrie de film cinématographique de 
art de l'auto-portrait-regulation réussi pour écarter la censure de gouvernement. 
L'état de sénat -- les extraits dont soyez inclus ci-dessous 
-- a également présenté le préambule au code et a détaillé le 
mécanisme de la revue de code.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quando as transmissões experimentais da 
televisão foram transmitidas primeiramente nos 1920s, a produção 
maciça de jogos de televisão não ocorreu até após a segunda 
guerra mundial. Por 1960 o número dos jogos nos ESTADOS UNIDOS 
surpassed o número das HOME. Com esta introdução 
relativamente rápida da televisão na vida americana doméstica, o 
interesse foi exprimido sobre a influência prejudicial que a 
televisão prestando atenção pôde ter nas crianças da nação. 
Embora o congress prendesse seu primeiro hearing no assunto em 
1952, escolheram não fazer exame de nenhuma ação para interferir 
com a indústria, na parte porque esse ano a associação nacional de 
radiodifusores do rádio e da televisão adotou um código para 
regular o índice da transmissão. O relatório do senate 
prendeu hearings em 1954 e em 1955 na influência possível da 
televisão no delinquency juvenile. O relatório resultante 
sumariou os padrões incluídos no código da televisão que pertence 
ao portrayal do crime, do horror, do sexo, e do enforcement de lei, e 
à responsabilidade da indústria fornecer "o entertainment wholesome"
para crianças. O relatório apresentou também o testimony de 
um executivo da televisão que cited o history de indústria de 
retrato de movimento do self-regulation bem sucedido para ward fora da
censura do governo. O relatório do senate -- os excerpts de que
seja incluído abaixo -- também apresentou o preamble ao código e 
detalhou o mecanismo da revisão de código.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Mentre le radiodiffusioni sperimentali della 
televisione in primo luogo sono state trasmesse negli anni 20, la 
fabbricazione in serie dei televisori non si è presentata fino dopo 
alla seconda guerra mondiale. Da 1960 il numero di insiemi negli
STATI UNITI aveva sorpassato il numero di sedi. Con questa 
introduzione relativamente rapida della televisione in vita americana 
domestica, la preoccupazione è stata espressa sopra l'influenza 
nociva che la televisione guardante potrebbe avere sui bambini della 
nazione. Anche se il congresso ha tenuto la relativa prima 
udienza sull'oggetto in 1952, hanno scelto non intraprendere 
alcun'azione per interferire con l'industria, in parte perché 
quell'anno l'associazione nazionale dei distributori a spaglio della 
televisione e della radio ha adottato un codice per regolare il 
soddisfare di radiodiffusione. Il rapporto del senato ha tenuto 
le udienze in 1954 ed in 1955 sull'influenza possibile della 
televisione sulla delinquenza giovanile. Il rapporto risultante 
ha ricapitolato gli standard inclusi nel codice della televisione che 
appartiene la rappresentazione del crimine, dell'orrore, del sesso e 
dell'applicazione di legge e la responsabilità dell'industria di 
fornire "l'intrattenimento sano" per i bambini. Il rapporto 
egualmente ha presentato la testimonianza da un esecutivo della 
televisione che ha citato la storia dell'industria cinematografica di 
autoregolazione riuscita per evitare censura di governo. Il 
rapporto del senato -- brani di cui sia incluso sotto -- egualmente ha
presentato la premessa al codice ed ha dettagliato il meccanismo di 
revisione del codice.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ενώ οι πειραματικές τηλεοπτικές ραδιοφωνικές 
μεταδόσεις μεταδόθηκαν αρχικά στη δεκαετία του '20, η μαζική 
παραγωγή των τηλεοπτικών συνόλων δεν εμφανίστηκε μέχρι τον 
παγκόσμιο πόλεμο ΙΙ. Μέχρι το 1960 ο αριθμός συνόλων 
στις ΗΠΑ είχε ξεπεράσει τον αριθμό σπιτιών. Με αυτήν την 
σχετικά γρήγορη εισαγωγή της τηλεόρασης στην εσωτερική 
αμερικανική ζωή, η ανησυχία εκφράστηκε πέρα από την επιβλαβή 
επιρροή που η τηλεόραση προσοχής να έχει στα παιδιά του έθνους. 
Αν και το συνέδριο πραγματοποίησε την πρώτη ακρόασή του για
το θέμα το 1952, επέλεξαν να μην λάβουν οποιαδήποτε μέτρα να 
παρεμποδίσουν τη βιομηχανία, εν μέρει επειδή εκείνο το έτος η 
εθνική ένωση των εκφωνητών ραδιοφώνων και τηλεόρασης υιοθέτησε 
έναν κώδικα για να ρυθμίσει το περιεχόμενο ραδιοφωνικής 
μετάδοσης. Η έκθεση Συγκλήτου πραγματοποίησε τις ακροάσεις 
το 1954 και το 1955 για την πιθανή επιρροή της τηλεόρασης στη
νεανική εγκληματικότητα. Η προκύπτουσα έκθεση συνόψισε τα 
πρότυπα που περιλήφθηκαν στον τηλεοπτικό κώδικα σχετικά με την 
απεικόνιση του εγκλήματος, της φρίκης, του φύλου, και της 
επιβολής νόμου, και στην ευθύνη της βιομηχανίας να παρέχει τη 
"θρεπτική ψυχαγωγία" για τα παιδιά. Η έκθεση παρουσίασε 
επίσης την κατάθεση από έναν τηλεοπτικό ανώτερο υπάλληλο που 
ανέφερε την ιστορία της βιομηχανίας ταινιών της επιτυχούς 
αυτορύθμισης για να αποκρούσει την κυβερνητική λογοκρισία. Η
έκθεση Συγκλήτου -- αποσπάσματα των οποίων συμπεριλαμβάνεται 
κατωτέρω -- επίσης παρουσίασε τον πρόλογο στον κώδικα και 
απαρίθμησε το μηχανισμό αναθεώρησης του κώδικα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mientras que las difusiones experimentales de la 
televisión primero fueron transmitidas en los años 20, la 
producción en masa de las televisiones no ocurrió hasta después de 
la Segunda Guerra Mundial. Por 1960 el número de conjuntos en 
los ESTADOS UNIDOS había sobrepasado el número de hogares. Con
esta introducción relativamente rápida de la televisión en vida 
americana doméstica, la preocupación fue expresada sobre la 
influencia dañosa que la televisión que miraba pudo tener en los 
niños de la nación. Aunque el congreso llevó a cabo su 
primera audiencia en el tema en 1952, eligieron no tomar ninguna 
acción para interferir con la industria, en parte porque ese año la 
asociación nacional de los locutores de la radio y de la televisión 
adoptó un código para regular el contenido de la difusión. El
informe del senado llevó a cabo audiencias en 1954 y 1955 en la 
influencia posible de la televisión en delincuencia juvenil. El
informe que resultaba resumió los estándares incluidos en el código
de la televisión que pertenecía a la representación del crimen, del
horror, del sexo, y de la aplicación de ley, y a la responsabilidad 
de la industria de proporcionar a la "hospitalidad sana" para los 
niños. El informe también presentó testimonio de un ejecutivo
de la televisión que citó la historia de la industria de película 
de la autoregulación acertada para guardar de censura del gobierno. 
El informe del senado -- los extractos de los cuales sea 
incluido abajo -- también presentó el preámbulo al código y 
detalló el mecanismo de la revisión de código.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087048</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103372</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-shadow-of-incipient-censorship-the-creation-of-the-television-code-of-1952</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
