<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103364</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103364</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206567</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Minuteman Missile National Historic Site: Protecting a Legacy of the Cold War</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Minuteman-Flugnationale Historische Site: 
Schützen einer Legacy des kalten Krieges</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Site Historique National de Missile de Minuteman :
Protection d'un legs de la guerre froide</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Local Historic Nacional Do Míssil Do Minuteman: 
Protegendo um legacy da guerra fria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Luogo Storico Nazionale Del Missile Del Minuteman:
Protezione dell'eredità della guerra fredda</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εθνική ιστορική περιοχή βλημάτων Minuteman: 
Προστασία μιας κληρονομιάς του ψυχρού πολέμου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sitio Histórico Nacional Del Misil Del Minuteman:
Protección de una herencia de la guerra fría</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">tells the story of one of the most significant strategic weapons in U.S. history: the Minuteman ICBM (Intercontinental Ballistic Missile). By 1965 there were 1,000 Minuteman ICBMs hidden across the Great Plains in six missile fields, transforming the prairie into a military-technological frontier and providing a key component in the U.S. Cold War policy of deterrence.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erklärt die Geschichte von einer der 
bedeutendsten strategischen Waffen in der VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Geschichte: der Minuteman ICBM (ballistischer 
interkontinentalflugkörper). Bis zum 1965 gab es 1.000 den 
Minuteman ICBMs, der über den Prairien in sechs versteckt wurde, die,
Flugkörper auffängt, wandelte das Grasland in eine 
militärisch-technologische Grenze um und stellt einen 
Schlüsselbestandteil in der VEREINIGTE STAATEN Politik des kalten 
Krieges von Abschreckung zur Verfügung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dit l'histoire d'une les plus significatives 
d'armes stratégiques dans l'histoire des ETATS-UNIS : le 
minuteman ICBM (missile ballistique intercontinental). D'ici 
1965 il y avait 1.000 le minuteman ICBMs caché à travers les grandes
plaines dans six domaines de missile, transformant la prairie en 
frontière militaire-technologique et fournissant une composante clé 
dans la politique de guerre froide des ETATS-UNIS de la dissuasion.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">diz a história de uma das armas estratégicas as 
mais significativas no history de ESTADOS UNIDOS: o minuteman 
ICBM (míssil balístico intercontinental). Por 1965 havia 1.000
o minuteman ICBMs escondido através das planícies grandes em seis 
campos do míssil, transformando a pradaria em uma fronteira 
militar-military-technological e fornecendo um componente chave na 
política da guerra fria de ESTADOS UNIDOS do deterrence.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">dice alla storia di una delle armi strategiche 
più significative nella storia degli STATI UNITI: il minuteman 
ICBM (missile balistico intercontinentale). Entro 1965 ci era 
1.000 minuteman ICBMs nascosto attraverso le pianure grandi in sei 
giacimenti del missile, trasformanti il prairie in una frontiera 
militare-tecnologica e fornenti un componente chiave nella politica di
guerra fredda degli STATI UNITI di deterrenza.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">λέει την ιστορία ένα από τα σημαντικότερα στρατηγικά
όπλα στην ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ ιστορία: το Minuteman ICBM 
(διηπειρωτικό βαλλιστικό βλήμα). Μέχρι το 1965 υπήρξαν 
1.000 Minuteman ICBMs που κρύφτηκε στις μεγάλες πεδιάδες 
σε έξι πεδία βλημάτων, που μετασχηματίζουν το λιβάδι σε 
στρατιωτικός-τεχνολογικά σύνορα και που παρέχουν ένα βασικό 
συστατικό στην πολιτική ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΎ ψυχρού πολέμου της 
αποτροπής πολέμου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">cuenta la historia de una de las armas 
estratégicas más significativas de la historia de ESTADOS UNIDOS: 
el minuteman ICBM (misil balístico intercontinental). 
Antes de 1965 había 1.000 el minuteman ICBMs ocultado a través
de los grandes llanos en seis campos del misil, transformando la 
pradera en una frontera militar-tecnolo'gica y proporcionando a un 
componente dominante en la política de la guerra fría de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS de la disuasión.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206567</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103364</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/minuteman-missile-national-historic-site-protecting-a-legacy-of-the-cold-war</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
