<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104059</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104059</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204615</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"What Do YOU See?" (Visit)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Was SIE Sehen?" (Besuch)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Ce qui VOUS Voyez?" (visite)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"O que VOCÊ Vê?" (visita)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Che cosa Vedete?" (chiamata)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Τι ΕΣΕΙΣ Βλέπει;" (Επίσκεψη)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Qué USTED Ve?" (visita)</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This lesson outlines activities for students to complete while visiting the Ackland Art Museum in Chapel Hill, NC. Students will observe and reflect upon a variety of artwork. In doing so, they will develop observation and communication skills, and learn to understand and appreciate others' interpretations and opinions of works of art. This lesson applies skills learned in the previous lesson, "What Do You See" (Pre-Visit).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Lektion umreißt Aktivitäten, damit 
Kursteilnehmer durchführen beim Besichtigen des Ackland kunst-Museums
im Kapelle-Hügel, NC. Kursteilnehmer beobachten und 
reflektieren sich nach einer Vielzahl der Gestaltungsarbeit. 
Wenn sie so tun, entwickeln sie Beobachtung und Kommunikation 
Fähigkeiten und erlernen, anderer zu verstehen und zu schätzen 
Deutungen und Meinungen der Kunstwerke. Diese Lektion wendet die
Fähigkeiten an, die in der vorhergehenden Lektion, "erlernt werden, 
was Sie" sehen (Vor-Besuchen Sie).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette leçon trace les grandes lignes des 
activités pour que les étudiants se terminent tout en visitant le 
musée d'art d'Ackland en colline de chapelle, OR. Les 
étudiants observeront et se refléteront sur une variété de 
dessin-modèle. De cette manière, ils développeront des 
qualifications d'observation et de transmission, et apprennent à 
comprendre et apprécier d'autres des traductions et des avis des 
oeuvres d'art. Cette leçon applique des qualifications apprises
dans la leçon précédente, "ce qui vous voient" (Pré-Visitez).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta lição esboça atividades para que os 
estudantes terminem ao visitar o museu da arte de Ackland no monte do 
chapel, NC. Os estudantes observarão e refletirão em cima de 
uma variedade da arte -final. Em fazer assim, desenvolverão 
habilidades da observação e da comunicação, e aprendem-nas 
compreender e apreciar outros interpretações e opiniões dos 
trabalhos de arte. Esta lição aplica as habilidades aprendidas
na lição precedente, "o que você vêem" (Pre-Visite).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa lezione descrive le attività affinchè gli
allievi completi mentre visita il museo di arte di Ackland in collina 
del chapel, NC. Gli allievi osserveranno e rifletteranno su una 
varietà di illustrazione. In tal modo, svilupperanno le 
abilità di comunicazione e di osservazione ed imparano capire ed 
apprezzare altri le interpretazioni ed opinioni delle opere d'arte. 
Questa lezione applica le abilità imparate nella lezione 
precedente, "che cosa voi vedono" (Pre-Visiti).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το μάθημα περιγράφει τις δραστηριότητες για τους 
σπουδαστές για να ολοκληρώσει επισκεμμένος το μουσείο τέχνης 
Ackland στο Hill παρεκκλησιών, NC. Οι σπουδαστές θα 
παρατηρήσουν και θα σκεφθούν σχετικά με ποικίλο έργο τέχνης. 
Με αυτό τον τρόπο, θα αναπτύξουν τις δεξιότητες παρατήρησης
και επικοινωνίας, και θα μάθουν να καταλαβαίνουν και θα εκτιμήσουν
άλλες τις ερμηνείες και τις απόψεις σχετικά με τα έργα της 
τέχνης. Αυτό το μάθημα εφαρμόζει τις δεξιότητες που 
μαθαίνονται στο προηγούμενο μάθημα, "τι εσείς Βλέπει" 
(προ-επίσκεψη).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta lección contornea las actividades para que 
los estudiantes terminen mientras que visita el museo del arte de 
Ackland en la colina de la capilla, NC. Los estudiantes 
observarán y reflejarán sobre una variedad de ilustraciones. 
En hacer así pues, desarrollarán habilidades de la 
observación y de la comunicación, y aprenden entender y apreciar 
otros las interpretaciones y las opiniones de obras de arte. 
Esta lección aplica las habilidades aprendidas en la lección 
anterior, "qué usted ven" (Pre-Visite).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:REAGAN WEST
FN:REAGAN WEST
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204615</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104059</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/what-do-you-see-visit</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
