<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103582</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103582</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206513</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Robinson House: A Portrait of African American Heritage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Robinson Haus: Ein Portrait des 
afrikanischen amerikanischen Erbes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Chambre de Robinson : Une verticale 
d'héritage américain africain</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A Casa De Robinson: Um retrato do heritage 
americano africano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Camera Di Robinson: Un Ritratto 
dell'eredità americana africana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το σπίτι Robinson: Ένα πορτρέτο της 
αφρικανικής αμερικανικής κληρονομιάς</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Casa De Robinson: Un retrato de la 
herencia americana africana</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Pieces together the story of the James Robinson family from artifacts found in archaeological excavations around the house where they lived for nearly a century. An African American born free in 1799, Robinson worked in a Virginia tavern earning nearly $500 to purchase 170 acres of land near Bull Run. There he built a log cabin, and his family turned the land into a prosperous farm, making him one of the wealthiest African Americans in the Manassas area in the mid-19th century.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Stücke zusammen die Geschichte der James Robinson
Familie von den Kunstprodukten fanden in den archäologischen 
Aushöhlungen um das Haus, wo sie für fast ein Jahrhundert lebten. 
Ein afrikanischer Amerikaner, der frei 1799 geboren war, 
Robinson arbeitete in einem Virginia Tavern, der fast $500 erwirbt, um
170 Morgen Land nahe Bull Durchlauf zu kaufen. Dort baute er 
eine Protokollkabine auf, und seine Familie machte das Land zu einen 
wohlhabenden Bauernhof und bildete ihn ein von den wohlhabendsten 
afrikanischen Amerikanern im Manassas Bereich im mid-19th Jahrhundert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Morceaux ensemble l'histoire de la famille de 
James Robinson des objets façonnés trouvés dans les 
excavations archéologiques autour de la maison où elles ont vécu 
pendant presque un siècle. Un Américain africain né librement
en 1799, Robinson a travaillé dans une taverne de la Virginie gagnant
presque $500 pour acheter 170 acres de terre près du passage de Bull.
Là il a construit une carlingue de logarithme naturel, et sa 
famille a transformé la terre en ferme prospère, lui faisant un des 
Américains africains les plus riches dans la région de Manassas en 
siècle de mid-19th.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As partes junto a história da família de James 
Robinson dos artifacts encontraram em escavações archaeological em 
torno da casa onde viveram por quase um século. Um americano 
africano carregado livre em 1799, Robinson trabalhou em um tavern de 
Virgínia que ganha quase $500 para comprar 170 acres da terra perto 
do funcionamento de Bull. Lá construiu uma cabine do registro, 
e sua família girou a terra em uma fazenda próspera, fazendo lhe um 
dos americanos africanos os mais ricos na área de Manassas no século
de mid-19th.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le parti la storia della famiglia di James 
Robinson dai manufatti hanno trovato insieme negli scavi 
archaeological intorno alla casa dove hanno vissuto per quasi un 
secolo. Un americano africano sopportato liberamente in 1799, 
Robinson ha lavorato in una locanda della Virginia che guadagna quasi 
$500 per comprare 170 acri di terra vicino al funzionamento di Bull. 
Là ha costruito una baracca del libro macchina e la sua 
famiglia ha trasformato nella terra un podere prosperoso, rendentegli 
uno degli Americani africani più ricchi nella zona di Manassas nel 
secolo di mid-19th.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Συναρμολογεί την ιστορία της james Robinson 
οικογένειας από τα χειροποίητα αντικείμενα που βρίσκονται στις 
αρχαιολογικές ανασκαφές γύρω από το σπίτι όπου έζησαν για 
σχεδόν έναν αιώνα. Αφρικανικός αμερικανικός γεννημένος 
ένας ελεύθερος το 1799, Robinson ελειτούργησε σε μια ταβέρνα
της Βιρτζίνια κερδίζοντας σχεδόν $500 για να αγοράσει 170 
στρέμματα του εδάφους κοντά στο τρέξιμο του Bull. Εκεί 
έχτισε μια καμπίνα κούτσουρων, και η οικογένειά του μετέτρεψε το
έδαφος σε ακμάζον αγρόκτημα, κάνοντας του ενός από τους 
πλουσιότερους αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς στην περιοχή Manassas 
στο μέσος-19$ο αιώνα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los pedazos juntos la historia de la familia de 
James Robinson de los artefactos encontraron en excavaciones 
arqueológicas alrededor de la casa dónde vivieron por casi un siglo.
Un americano africano nacido libremente en 1799, Robinson 
trabajó en una taberna de Virginia que ganaba casi $500 para comprar 
170 acres de pista cerca del funcionamiento de Bull. Allí él 
construyó una cabina del registro, y su familia dio vuelta a la pista
en una granja próspera, haciéndole uno de los americanos africanos 
más ricos del área de Manassas en el siglo de mid-19th.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206513</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103582</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-robinson-house-a-portrait-of-african-american-heritage</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
