<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107130</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107130</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207243</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">An American Time Capsule: Three Centuries of Broadsides and Other Printed Ephemera</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Amerikanische Zeit-Kapsel: Drei 
Jahrhunderte Broadsides und andere gedruckte Eintagsfliegen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une Capsule Américaine de Temps : Trois 
siècles de Flancs et d'autres éphémères imprimés</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uma Cápsula Americana Do Tempo: Três 
séculos de Broadsides e de outros ephemera impressos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Una Capsula Americana Di Tempo: Tre secoli 
degli Attacchi e di altre cose effimere stampate</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια αμερικανική χρονική κάψα: Τρεις αιώνες 
broadsides και άλλα τυπωμένα ephemera</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una Cápsula Americana Del Tiempo: Tres 
siglos de Costados y de otros ephemera impresos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">comprises 28,000 primary source items dating from the seventeenth century to the present and encompasses key events and eras in American history. Items include a variety of posters, notices, advertisements, proclamations, leaflets, propaganda, manifestos, and business cards. They capture the experience of the American Revolution, slavery, the western land rush, the Civil War, woman suffrage, and the Industrial Revolution from the viewpoint of those who lived through those events.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">enthält 28.000 Primärquelleinzelteile, die vom 
seventeenth Jahrhundert zum Geschenk datieren und gibt 
Schlüsselfälle und Ären in der amerikanischen Geschichte um. 
Einzelteile schließen eine Vielzahl der Plakate, der Begriffe, 
der Reklameanzeigen, der Proklamationen, der Blättchen, der 
Propaganda, der Manifeste und der Geschäft Karten ein. Sie
erfassen die Erfahrung der amerikanischen Revolution, der Sklaverei, 
der westlichen Landanstürme, des Bürgerkrieges, des Fraustimmrechts 
und der industriellen Revolution von der Veranschaulichung von denen, 
die durch jene Fälle lebten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">comporte 28.000 éléments primaires de source 
datant du dix-septième siècle au présent et couvre les événements
et les ères principaux dans l'histoire américaine. Les 
éléments incluent une variété d'affiches, de notices, d'annonces, 
de proclamations, de feuillets, de propagande, de manifestes, et de 
cartes de visite professionnelle de visite. Ils capturent 
l'expérience de la révolution américaine, de l'esclavage, des 
précipitations occidentales de terre, de la guerre civile, du 
suffrage de femme, et de la révolution industrielle du point de vue 
de ceux qui ont vécu par ces événements.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">compreende 28.000 artigos preliminares da fonte 
que datam do décimo séptimo século ao presente e abrange os eventos
e as eras chaves no history americano. Os artigos incluem uma 
variedade dos posteres, das observações, das propagandas, dos 
proclamations, dos leaflets, do propaganda, dos manifestos, e dos 
cartões de negócio. Capturam a experiência da volta 
americana, do slavery, das arremetidas ocidentais da terra, da guerra 
civil, do suffrage da mulher, e da volta industrial do viewpoint 
daquelas que viveram com aqueles eventos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">contiene 28.000 articoli primari di sorgente che 
datano dal diciassettesimo secolo al presente e comprende gli eventi e
le ere chiave nella storia americana. Gli articoli includono una
varietà di manifesti, di avvisi, di pubblicità, di proclamazioni, di
opuscoli, di propaganda, di manifesti e di schedi di affari. 
Bloccano l'esperienza nella rivoluzione americana, nello 
slavery, negli sbalzi occidentali della terra, nella guerra civile, 
nel suffrage della donna e nella rivoluzione industriale dal punto di 
vista di coloro che ha vissuto con quegli eventi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">περιλαμβάνει 28.000 αρχικά αντικείμενα πηγής που 
χρονολογούν από το δέκατο έβδομο αιώνα στο παρόν και καλύπτει 
τα βασικές γεγονότα και τις εποχές στην αμερικανική ιστορία. 
Τα αντικείμενα περιλαμβάνουν ποικίλα αφίσες, ειδοποιήσεις, 
διαφημίσεις, προκηρύξεις, φυλλάδια, προπαγάνδα, μανιφέστα, και 
τις επιχειρησιακές κάρτες. Συλλαμβάνουν την εμπειρία της 
αμερικανικής επανάστασης, της σκλαβιάς, της δυτικής βιασύνης 
εδάφους, του εμφύλιου πολέμου, της ψήφου γυναικών, και της 
βιομηχανικής επανάστασης από την άποψη εκείνοι που έζησαν μέσω 
εκείνων των γεγονότων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">abarca 28.000 items primarios de la fuente que 
fechan a partir del decimoséptimo siglo al presente y abarca los 
acontecimientos y las eras dominantes en historia americana. Los
items incluyen una variedad de carteles, de avisos, de anuncios, de 
proclamaciones, de prospectos, de propaganda, de manifiestos, y de 
tarjetas de visita. Capturan la experiencia de la revolución 
americana, de la esclavitud, de las acometidas occidentales de la 
pista, de la guerra civil, del sufragio de la mujer, y de la 
revolución industrial del punto de vista de los que vivieron con esos
acontecimientos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207243</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107130</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/an-american-time-capsule-three-centuries-of-broadsides-and-other-printed-ephemera</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
