<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106732</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106732</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085248</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Help and a New Deal</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hilfe und ein neues Abkommen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Aide et une nouvelle affaire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ajuda e um negócio novo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Aiuto e un nuovo affare</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οδηγίες και μια νέα διαπραγμάτευση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ayuda y un nuevo reparto</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">President Franklin Delano Roosevelt (photographed in 1935 with his wife, Eleanor) created the New Deal as a solution for bringing the United States out of the Great Depression. The New Deal created a new role for the federal government, one that involved infusing money into the economy largely through the creation of new jobs and social programs. One photograph shows Roosevelt signing the Social Security Act of 1935, which was designed to keep citizens from becoming destitute. The New Deal also created the Works Progress Administration (WPA), which funded artists to create public art projects and others to complete a wide variety of work projects, such as the construction of roads, trails, theaters, and public buildings. Several images show the wide variety of work that the WPA helped fund: an artist painting a mural, a man tending a butterfly collection in the Natural History Museum, and people clipping articles. Not everyone supported the government's new, expanded role. The image of men holding a banner that reads "Against Roosevelt's New Deal" was taken at a Communist demonstration in San Diego in 1933. Still others created their own solution to the Depression's hard times by forming cooperative organizations. The aim of the co-op movement was for people to work together and share the proceeds of their labors. In the early years of the Depression in California, many sorts of self-help cooperatives were formed by individuals (often called "cooperators"). The images in this group show cooperative pie-making, sewing and quilting ventures, and a cooperative barber shop, art studio, construction enterprises, and cannery.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Präsident Franklin Delano Roosevelt (fotografiert
1935 mit seiner Frau, Eleanor) erstellte das neue Abkommen als Lösung
für das Holen der Vereinigten Staaten aus dem großen Tiefstand 
heraus. Das neue Abkommen erstellte eine neue Rolle für die 
Bundesregierung, eine, die miteinbezog, Geld in die Wirtschaft durch 
die Arbeitsplatzbeschaffung und Sozialprogramme groß hineinzugießen.
Eine Fotographie Erscheinen Roosevelt, welches die 
Sozialversicherung Tat von 1935 unterzeichnet, das konzipiert war, um 
Bürger vom Werden zu halten hilflos. Das neue Abkommen 
erstellte auch die Arbeiten Fortschritt-Leitung (WPA), die Künstler 
finanzierte, um allgemeine kunstprojekte und -andere zu erstellen, um 
eine breite Vielzahl der Arbeit Projekte, wie des Aufbaus der 
Straßen, der Spuren, der Theater und der allgemeinen Gebäude 
durchzuführen. Einige Bilder zeigen die breite Vielzahl der 
Arbeit, der das WPA Kapital half: ein Künstler, der ein 
Wandbild malen, ein Mann, der eine Basisrecheneinheit Ansammlung im 
Naturgeschichte-Museum neigen, und Leuteausschnitt Artikel. 
Nicht jeder unterstützte der neuen Regierung, erweiterter 
Rolle. Das Bild der Männer, die eine Fahne anhalten, die "gegen
Roosevelts neues Abkommen" liest, wurde an einer kommunistischen 
Demonstration in San Diego 1933 genommen. Noch erstellten andere
ihre eigene Lösung zu den harten Zeiten des Tiefstands, indem sie 
kooperative Organisationen bildeten. Das Ziel der Korbbewegung 
war, damit Leute zusammen und die Erträge ihrer Arbeiten zu teilen 
arbeiten. In den frühen Jahren des Tiefstands in Kalifornien, 
wurden viele Sortierungen der Self-helpmitwirkender von den 
Einzelpersonen gebildet (häufig angerufen "cooperators"). Die 
Bilder in dieser Gruppe zeigen das kooperative Torte-Bilden, das 
Nähen und die quilting Wagnisse und ein kooperatives 
Herrenfriseursystem, ein kunststudio, Aufbauunternehmen und eine 
Konservenfabrik.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Président Franklin Delano Roosevelt 
(photographié en 1935 avec son épouse, Eleanor) a créé la nouvelle
affaire comme solution pour apporter les Etats-Unis hors de la grande 
dépression. La nouvelle affaire a créé un nouveau rôle pour 
le gouvernement fédéral, un qui a impliqué d'infuser l'argent dans 
l'économie en grande partie par la création des nouveaux travaux et 
des programmes sociaux. Expositions Roosevelt d'une photographie
signant l'acte de sécurité sociale de 1935, qui a été conçu pour 
garder des citoyens de devenir indigent. La nouvelle affaire a 
également créé la gestion d'avancement de travaux (WPA), qui a 
placé des artistes pour créer des projets publics et d'autres d'art 
pour terminer une grande variété de projets de travail, tels que la 
construction des routes, de traînées, de théâtres, et de 
bâtiments publics. Plusieurs images montrent la grande 
variété de travail que le WPA a aidé des fonds : un artiste 
peignant un mural, un homme tendant une collection de papillon dans le
musée d'histoire naturelle, et articles de découpage de personnes. 
Pas chacun a supporté le gouvernement nouveau, rôle augmenté.
L'image des hommes tenant un drapeau qui lit "contre la nouvelle
affaire de Roosevelt" a été prise à une démonstration communiste 
à San Diego en 1933. Encore d'autres ont créé leur propre 
solution aux périodes difficiles de la dépression en formant des 
organismes coopératifs. Le but du mouvement de cage était pour
que les personnes travaillent ensemble et partager le montant de leurs
travaux. En premières années de la dépression en Californie, 
beaucoup de tris des coopératives de art de l'auto-portrait-help ont été 
constitués par des individus (souvent appelés les "cooperators"). 
Les images dans ce groupe montrent la pâté en 
croûte-fabrication coopérative, la couture et les entreprises 
piquantes, et un système de coiffeur, un studio d'art, des 
entreprises de construction, et une fabrique de conserves 
coopératifs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O presidente Franklin Delano Roosevelt 
(fotografado em 1935 com sua esposa, Eleanor) criou o negócio novo 
como uma solução para trazer os estados unidos fora do depression 
grande. O negócio novo criou um papel novo para o governo 
federal, um que envolveu infusing o dinheiro na economia pela maior 
parte através da criação de trabalhos novos e de programas sociais.
Mostras Roosevelt de uma fotografia que assina o ato da 
segurança social de 1935, que foi projetado manter cidadãos de se 
tornar destitute. O negócio novo criou também a 
administração do progresso de trabalhos (WPA), que financiou 
artistas para criar projetos públicos e outros da arte para terminar 
uma variedade larga de projetos de trabalho, tais como a construção 
das estradas, de fugas, de teatros, e de edifícios públicos. 
Diversas imagens mostram a variedade larga do trabalho que o WPA
ajudou ao fundo: um artista que pintam um mural, um homem que 
tendem uma coleção da borboleta no museu do history natural, e 
artigos do clipping dos povos. Não todos suportou o governo 
novo, papel expandido. A imagem dos homens que prendem uma 
bandeira que lesse "de encontro ao negócio novo de Roosevelt" foi 
feita exame em uma demonstração comunista em San Diego em 1933. 
Ainda outros criaram sua própria solução aos tempos duros do 
depression dando forma a organizações cooperativas. O alvo do 
movimento da gaiola era para que os povos trabalhem junto e para 
compartilhar dos rendimentos de seus trabalhos. Nos anos 
adiantados do depression em Califórnia, muitas sortes de cooperatives
do self-help foram dadas forma pelos indivíduos (chamados 
frequentemente "cooperators"). As imagens neste grupo mostram 
torta-fazer cooperativo, sewing e riscos quilting, e uma loja do 
barbeiro, um estúdio da arte, umas empresas da construção, e uma 
fábrica de conservas cooperativos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il presidente Franklin Delano Roosevelt 
(fotografato in 1935 con la sua moglie, Eleanor) ha creato il nuovo 
affare come una soluzione per portare unito Dichiara dalla 
depressione grande. Il nuovo affare ha creato un nuovo ruolo per
il governo federale, uno che ha coinvolto infondere i soldi 
nell'economia in gran parte attraverso la creazione di nuovi lavori e 
dei programmi sociali. Lle esposizioni Roosevelt dell'una 
fotografia che firma la Legge di previdenza sociale di 1935, che è 
stato destinato per mantenere i cittadini dal diventare indigente. 
Il nuovo affare egualmente ha creato la gestione di progresso 
degli impianti (WPA), che ha costituito un fondo per gli artisti per 
creare i progetti pubblici ed altri di arte per completare un'ampia 
varietà di progetti di lavoro, quale la costruzione delle strade, di 
tracce, di teatri e di costruzioni pubbliche. Parecchie immagini
mostrano l'ampia varietà di lavoro che il WPA ha aiutato il fondo 
monetario: un artista che verniciano un mural, un uomo che 
tendono una collezione della farfalla nel museo di storia naturale ed 
articoli di clipping della gente. Non tutto ha sostenuto il 
governo nuovo, ruolo espanso. L'immagine della tenuta degli
uomini una bandiera che legge "contro il nuovo affare del Roosevelt" 
è stata presa ad una dimostrazione comunista a San Diego in 1933. 
Ancora altri hanno creato la loro propria soluzione ai tempi 
duri della depressione formando le organizzazioni cooperative. 
Lo scopo del movimento della gabbia era affinchè la gente 
funzioni insieme e ripartire i ricavati dei loro lavori. 
Durante i primi anni della depressione nella California, molti 
ordinamenti delle cooperative di self-help sono stati costituiti dagli
individui (spesso chiamati "cooperators"). Le immagini in questo
gruppo mostrano torta-fare cooperativo, il cucito e le imprese 
quilting e un negozio del barbiere, un studio di arte, lle imprese 
della costruzione e un conservificio cooperativi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο Πρόεδρος Franklin Delano Roosevelt (που 
φωτογραφίζεται το 1935 με τη σύζυγό του, Eleanor) 
δημιούργησε τη νέα διαπραγμάτευση ως λύση για να φέρει τις 
Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες από τη μεγάλη οικονομική κρίση. Η νέα 
διαπραγμάτευση δημιούργησε έναν νέο ρόλο για την ομοσπονδιακή 
κυβέρνηση, μια που περιέλαβε τα εμποτίζοντας χρήματα στην 
οικονομία κατά ένα μεγάλο μέρος μέσω της δημιουργίας των νέων 
θέσεων και των κοινωνικών προγραμμάτων. Μια φωτογραφία 
εμφανίζει Roosevelt υπογράφοντας το νόμο κοινωνικής ασφάλισης 
του 1935, ο οποίος σχεδιάστηκε για να κρατήσει τους πολίτες 
από να γίνει άπορος. Η νέα διαπραγμάτευση δημιούργησε 
επίσης τη διοίκηση προόδου εργασιών (WPA), η οποία 
χρηματοδότησε τους καλλιτέχνες για να δημιουργήσει τα δημόσια 
προγράμματα τέχνης και άλλα για να ολοκληρώσει μια ευρεία 
ποικιλία των προγραμμάτων εργασίας, όπως η οικοδόμηση των 
δρόμων, των ιχνών, των θεάτρων, και των δημόσιων κτηρίων. 
Διάφορες εικόνες εμφανίζουν ευρεία ποικιλία της εργασίας 
που το WPA βοήθησε να χρηματοδοτήσει: ένας καλλιτέχνης 
που χρωματίζουν μια τοιχογραφία, ένα άτομο που τείνουν μια 
συλλογή πεταλούδων στο μουσείο φυσικής ιστορίας, και άνθρωποι 
που ψαλιδίζουν τα άρθρα. Όχι ο καθένας υποστήριξε τον 
κυβερνητικό νέο, επεκταθέντα ρόλο. Η εικόνα των ατόμων που
κρατούν ένα έμβλημα που διαβάζει "ενάντια στη νέα 
διαπραγμάτευση Roosevelt" λήφθηκε σε μια κομμουνιστική επίδειξη
στο Σαν Ντιέγκο σε 1933, Ακόμα άλλοι δημιούργησαν τη 
λύση τους στους σκληρούς χρόνους της κατάθλιψης με τη διαμόρφωση 
των συνεταιριστικών οργανώσεων. Ο στόχος της μετακίνησης 
συνεταιρισμών ήταν για τους ανθρώπους να απασχοληθούν μαζί και να
μοιραστούν οι εισπράξεις του τους εργάζεται. Τα πρώτα έτη 
της κατάθλιψης σε Καλιφόρνια, πολλά είδη των συνεταιρισμών 
αυτοβοήθειας διαμορφώθηκαν από τα άτομα (συχνά αποκαλούμενα 
"συνεργάτεσ"). Οι εικόνες σε αυτήν την ομάδα εμφανίζουν 
συνεταιρισμό πίτα-που κάνει, επιχειρήσεις ραψίματος και να 
γεμίσουν, και ένα συνεταιριστικό κατάστημα κουρέων, ένα 
στούντιο τέχνης, επιχειρήσεις κατασκευής, και κονσερβοποιείο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Presidente Franklin Delano Roosevelt (fotografiado
en 1935 con su esposa, Eleanor) creó el nuevo reparto como solución 
para traer los Estados Unidos de la gran depresión. El nuevo 
reparto creó un nuevo papel del gobierno federal, uno que implicó el
infundir del dinero en la economía en gran parte a través de la 
creación de nuevos trabajos y de programas sociales. 
Demostraciones Roosevelt de una fotografía que firma el acto de
la Seguridad Social de 1935, que fue diseñado para guardar a 
ciudadanos de llegar a ser indigente. El nuevo reparto también 
creó la administración del progreso de trabajos (WPA), que financió
a artistas para crear proyectos públicos y otros del arte para 
terminar una variedad amplia de proyectos de trabajo, tales como la 
construcción de caminos, de rastros, de teatros, y de edificios 
públicos. Varias imágenes muestran la variedad amplia de 
trabajo que el WPA ayudó al fondo: un artista que pinta un 
mural, un hombre que tiende a una colección de la mariposa en el 
museo de la historia natural, y artículos del truncamiento de la 
gente. No cada uno utilizó el gobierno nuevo, papel ampliado. 
La imagen de los hombres que sostenían una bandera que lee 
"contra el nuevo reparto de Roosevelt" fue tomada en una demostración
comunista en San Diego en 1933. Todavía otros crearon su propia
solución a los tiempos duros de la depresión formando organizaciones
cooperativas. La puntería del movimiento del tonel estaba para 
que la gente trabaje junta y compartir los ingresos de sus trabajos. 
En los años de la depresión en California, muchas clases de 
cooperativas del esfuerzo personal fueron formadas por los individuos 
(a menudo llamados los "cooperators"). Las imágenes en este 
grupo muestran la empanada-fabricacio'n cooperativa, la costura y 
empresas que acolchan, y un departamento del peluquero, un estudio del
arte, empresas de la construcción, y un cannery cooperativos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085248</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106732</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/help-and-a-new-deal</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
