<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107324</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107324</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200786</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Calibrated Peer Review: Petroleum Geology of the Persian Gulf Region</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kalibrierte Gleiche Zusammenfassung: 
Erdöl-Geologie der persischer Golf-Region</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Examen par les pairs Calibré : Géologie de 
pétrole de la région de golfe Persique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Revisão De Par Calibrada: Geologia do 
petróleo da região do golfo persa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Rassegna Di Pari Calibrata: Geologia del 
petrolio della regione del golfo persiano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βαθμολογημένη όμοια αναθεώρηση: Γεωλογία 
πετρελαίου της περιοχής Περσικών Κόλπων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Revisión De Par Calibrada: Geología del 
petróleo de la región del golfo persa</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this assignment, students explore the origin and distribution of oil and gas in a region of global significance. Also included are the geologic history and the socio-political and environmental issues associated with hydrocarbon exploration and production. Students then walk through an online case study and write an essay addressing important points that they have learned. The Calibrated Peer Review interface is then used to give feedback on the essays. On this Starting Point page, users can access information about the exercise's learning goals, context for use, teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment ideas, references and topics covered.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In dieser Anweisung erforschen Kursteilnehmer den 
Ursprung und die Verteilung des Öls und des Gases in einer Region der
globalen Stichhaltigkeit. Auch geschlossen die geologische 
Geschichte und die socio-political und Klimaausgaben ein, die mit 
Kohlenwasserstofferforschung verbunden sind und die Produktion. 
Kursteilnehmer dann gehen durch eine Onlinefallstudie und 
schreiben einen Versuch, der wichtige Punkte adressiert, die sie 
erlernt haben. Die kalibrierte Schnittstelle der Gleichen 
Zusammenfassung wird dann benutzt, um Feedback auf den Versuchen zu 
geben. Auf dieser Ausgangspunktseite können Benutzer auf 
Informationen über die erlernenziele der Übung, Kontext für 
Gebrauch-, die Unterrichtenumfaßten anmerkungen und Spitzen, 
Lehrmittel, Einschätzung Ideen, Referenzen und Themen zugreifen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cette affectation, les étudiants explorent 
l'origine et la distribution de pétrole et de gaz dans une région 
d'importance globale. En outre incluses sont l'histoire 
géologique et les issues liées à l'exploration d'hydrocarbure et la
production sociopolitiques et environnementales. Les étudiants 
alors marchent par une étude de cas en ligne et écrivent un essai 
adressant les points importants qu'ils ont appris. L'interface 
calibrée d'examen par les pairs est alors employée pour donner le 
feedback sur les essais. À cette page de point de départ, les 
utilisateurs peuvent accéder aux informations sur les buts d'étude 
de l'exercice, contexte pour les extrémités d'utilisation, 
d'enseignement les notes et, le matériel didactique, les idées 
d'évaluation, les références et les sujets couverts.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta atribuição, os estudantes exploram a origem
e a distribuição do óleo e do gás em uma região do significado 
global. São incluídos também o history geologic e as 
edições associados com a exploração do hidrocarboneto e a 
produção socio-political e ambientais. Os estudantes então 
andam com um estudo de caso em linha e escrevem um essay que dirige-se
aos pontos importantes que aprenderam. A relação calibrada da 
revisão de par é usada então dar o feedback nos essays. Nesta
página do ponto começar, os usuários podem alcançar a informação
sobre os objetivos de aprendizagem do exercício, contexto para as 
pontas do uso, ensinar as notas e, os materiais de ensino, as idéias 
da avaliação, as referências e os tópicos cobertos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questa assegnazione, gli allievi esplorano 
l'origine e la distribuzione di petrolio e di gas in una regione di 
importanza globale. Egualmente sono incluse la storia geologica 
e le edizioni connesse con esplorazione dell'idrocarburo e la 
produzione sociopolitiche ed ambientali. Gli allievi allora 
camminano con un'inchiesta in linea e scrivono un saggio che richiama 
i punti importanti che hanno imparato. L'interfaccia calibrata 
di revisione di pari allora è usata per dare le risposte sui saggi. 
A questa pagina del punto di partenza, gli utenti possono 
accedere alle informazioni sugli obiettivi imparanti 
dell'esercitazione, contesto per le punte di istruzione, di uso note 
e, i materiali didattici, le idee di valutazione, i riferimenti ed i 
soggetti coperti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτήν την ανάθεση, οι σπουδαστές ερευνούν την 
προέλευση και τη διανομή του πετρελαίου και αέριο σε μια 
περιοχή της σφαιρικής σημασίας. Επίσης περιλαμβάνονται η 
γεωλογική ιστορία και τα κοινωνικοπολιτικά και περιβαλλοντικά 
ζητήματα που συνδέονται με την εξερεύνηση και την παραγωγή 
υδρογονανθράκων. Οι σπουδαστές περπατούν έπειτα μέσω μιας 
σε απευθείας σύνδεση περιπτωσιολογικής μελέτης και γράφουν ένα 
δοκίμιο εξετάζοντας τα σημαντικά σημεία που έχουν μάθει. Η
βαθμολογημένη όμοια διαπροσωπεία αναθεώρησης χρησιμοποιείται 
έπειτα για να δώσει την ανατροφοδότηση στα δοκίμια. Σε 
αυτήν την σελίδα αφετηρίας, οι χρήστες μπορούν να έχουν 
πρόσβαση στις πληροφορίες για τους στόχους εκμάθησης της άσκησης,
πλαίσιο για τη χρήση, τις σημειώσεις και τις άκρες διδασκαλίας, 
τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, τις ιδέες αξιολόγησης, τις αναφορές και τα
θέματα που καλύπτονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta asignación, los estudiantes exploran el 
origen y la distribución del aceite y del gas en una región de la 
significación global. También se incluyen la historia 
geológica y las ediciones asociadas a la exploración del 
hidrocarburo y la producción sociopolíticas y ambientales. Los
estudiantes después recorren con un estudio de caso en línea y 
escriben un ensayo que trata las puntas importantes que han aprendido.
El interfaz calibrado de la revisión de par entonces se utiliza
para dar feedback en los ensayos. En esta paginación del punto 
de partida, los utilizadores pueden tener acceso a la información 
sobre las metas que aprenden del ejercicio, contexto para las 
extremidades del uso, de la enseñanza las notas y, los materiales 
didácticos, las ideas del gravamen, las referencias y los asuntos 
cubiertos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ELIZABETH HEISE
FN:ELIZABETH HEISE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200786</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107324</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/calibrated-peer-review-petroleum-geology-of-the-persian-gulf-region</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
