<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106648</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106648</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206155</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Doing Science and Technology: The Process of Scientific Inquiry</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Tun von von Wissenschaft und von von Technologie: 
Der Prozeß der wissenschaftlichen Anfrage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Faire la Science et la technologie : Le 
processus de l'enquête scientifique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fazendo a ciência e a tecnologia: O processo
do inquérito científico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fare scienza e tecnologia: Il processo 
dell'inchiesta scientifica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Να κάνει την επιστήμη και την τεχνολογία: Η 
διαδικασία της επιστημονικής έρευνας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Hacer ciencia y tecnología: El proceso de la
pregunta científica</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">helps students understand the basics of scientific inquiry. Lessons progress from what students already know about scientific inquiry, or think they know, toward a more complete and accurate perspective. Activities include distinguishing questions that can be tested by a scientific investigation from those that cannot and participating in a computer-based scientific investigation as members of a fictitious community health department.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hilfen Kursteilnehmer verstehen die Grundlagen der
wissenschaftlichen Anfrage. Lektionfortschritt von was 
Kursteilnehmer bereits über wissenschaftliche Anfrage kennen oder 
denken, daß sie, in Richtung zu einer kompletteren und genaueren 
Perspektive wissen. Aktivitäten schließen unterscheidene 
Fragen ein, die durch eine wissenschaftliche Untersuchung von denen 
geprüft werden können, die nicht können und teilnehmend an einer 
rechnergestützten wissenschaftlichen Untersuchung als Bauteile einer 
erfundenen Gemeinschaftsgesundheit Abteilung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les étudiants d'aides comprennent les fondations 
de l'enquête scientifique. Le progrès de leçons de ce que les
étudiants connaissent déjà l'enquête scientifique, ou pensent 
qu'ils savent, vers une perspective plus complète et plus précise. 
Les activités incluent les questions de distinction qui peuvent
être testées par une recherche scientifique de ceux qui ne peuvent 
pas et participant à une recherche scientifique sur ordinateur comme 
membres d'un service factice de santé de la communauté.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">os estudantes das ajudas compreendem os 
princípios do inquérito científico. O progresso das lições 
de o que os estudantes sabem já sobre o inquérito científico, ou 
pensa que sabem, para um perspective mais completo e mais exato. 
As atividades incluem as perguntas distinguindo que podem ser 
testadas por uma investigação científica daquelas que não podem e 
participando em uma investigação científica por computador como 
membros de um departamento fictitious da saúde da comunidade.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">gli allievi di aiuti capiscono i principi 
fondamentali dell'inchiesta scientifica. Il progresso di lezioni
da che cosa gli allievi già conoscono circa l'inchiesta scientifica, 
o pensa che sappiano, verso una prospettiva più completa e più 
esatta. Le attività includono le domande di distinzione che 
possono essere esaminate tramite una ricerca scientifica da quelle che
non possono e partecipando ad una ricerca scientifica computerizzata 
come membri di un reparto fittizio di salute della Comunità.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">βοηθά τους σπουδαστές να καταλάβουν τα βασικά της 
επιστημονικής έρευνας. Η πρόοδος μαθημάτων από ποιους 
σπουδαστές ξέρτε ήδη για την επιστημονική έρευνα, ή σκέφτεται 
ότι ξέρουν, προς μια πληρέστερη και ακριβή προοπτική. Οι 
δραστηριότητες περιλαμβάνουν τις ιδιαίτερες ερωτήσεις που μπορούν
να εξεταστούν από μια επιστημονική έρευνα από εκείνους που δεν 
μπορούν και συμμετέχων σε μια βασισμένη σε υπολογιστή 
επιστημονική έρευνα ως μέλη ενός φανταστικού κοινοτικού 
τμήματος υγείας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">los estudiantes de las ayudas entienden los 
fundamentos de la pregunta científica. El progreso de las 
lecciones de lo que saben los estudiantes ya sobre pregunta 
científica, o piensa que saben, hacia una perspectiva más completa y
más exacta. Las actividades incluyen las preguntas que 
distinguen que se pueden probar por una investigación científica de 
los que no puedan y participando en una investigación científica 
computarizada como miembros de un departamento ficticio de la salud de
la comunidad.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206155</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106648</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/doing-science-and-technology-the-process-of-scientific-inquiry</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
