<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105417</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105417</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086282</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Glanced Up--The Statue of Liberty!": Emma Goldman Describes Her Deportation in the Era of the Red Scare</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ich blickte oben -- das Freiheitsstatue!" 
flüchtig: Emma Goldman beschreibt ihre Zwangsverschickung in 
der Ära des roten Schreckens</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"j'ai jeté un coup d'oeil vers le haut -- la 
statue de la liberté!" : Emma Goldman décrit sa déportation 
dans l'ère de l'alarme rouge</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"eu olhei de relance acima -- a estátua de 
liberdade!": Emma Goldman descreve sua deporta16cao na era do 
scare vermelho</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"ho gettato uno sguardo in su -- la statua della 
libertà!": Emma Goldman descrive la sua deportazione nell'era 
dello spavento rosso</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"κοίταξα επάνω -- το άγαλμα της ελευθερίας!": 
Θ*Εμμα Goldman Describes Her Deportation στην εποχή
του κόκκινου τρόμου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"eché un vistazo para arriba -- la estatua de la 
libertad!": Emma Goldman describe su deportación en la era del 
susto rojo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">After World War I, a "red scare" gripped the United States. One reflection of this climate of hysteria was in the "Palmer raids" on radicals. Striking without warning and without warrants, Attorney General A. Mitchell Palmer's men smashed union offices and the headquarters of Communist and Socialist organizations. They concentrated whenever possible on aliens rather than citizens, because aliens had fewer rights. In December 1919, in their most famous act, Palmer's agents seized 249 resident aliens. Those seized were placed on board a ship, the  Buford , bound for the Soviet Union. Deportees included the feminist, anarchist, and writer Emma Goldman, who later recalled the deportation in her autobiography,  Living My Life .</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nach dem Ersten Weltkrieg griff ein "roter 
Schrecken" die Vereinigten Staaten. Eine Reflexion dieses Klimas
der Hysterie war im "Palmer überfällt" auf Radikalen. 
Anschlagend ohne WARNING und ohne Ermächtigungen, 
Generalstaatsanwalt A. Mitchell Palmers zertrümmerten Männer 
Anschlußbüros und die Hauptsitze der kommunistischen und 
sozialistischen Organisationen. Sie konzentrierten, wann immer 
möglich auf Ausländer anstatt Bürger, weil Ausländer wenige Rechte
hatten. Im Dezember 1919, in ihrer berühmtesten Tat, ergriffen 
Mittel Palmers 249 Residentausländer. Ergriffene die wurden an 
Bord eines Schiffs, das Buford, Grenze für den Sowjet-Anschluß 
plaziert. Deportierten enthielten den Feminist, den 
Anarchisten und den Verfasser Emma Goldman, der später die 
Zwangsverschickung in ihrer Autobiographie erinnerte an und lebten 
meine Lebensdauer.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Après la Première Guerre Mondiale, "une alarme 
rouge" a saisi les Etats-Unis. Une réflexion de ce climat 
d'hystérie était dans le "Palmer pille" sur des radicaux. 
Frappant sans avertissement et sans garanties, les hommes de A. 
Mitchell Palmer's Général de mandataire ont cassé des bureaux des 
syndicats et les sièges sociaux des organismes communistes et 
socialistes. Ils se sont concentrés autant que possible sur des
étrangers plutôt que des citoyens, parce que les étrangers ont eu 
peu de droits. En décembre 1919, dans leur acte plus célèbre,
les agents de Palmer ont saisi 249 étrangers résidents. Ceux 
saisis ont été placés à bord d'un bateau, le Buford, limite pour 
Union Soviétique. Les déportés ont inclus le féministe, 
l'anarchiste, et l'auteur Emma Goldman, qui plus tard a rappelé la 
déportation en son autobiographie, vivant ma vie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Após o world.war.i, "um scare vermelho" prendeu 
os estados unidos. Uma reflexão deste clima do hysteria estava 
no "Palmer invade" em radicais. Golpeando sem aviso e sem 
autorizações, de advogado os homens de A. Mitchell Palmer geral 
despedaçaram escritórios da união e as matrizes de organizações 
comunistas e socialist. Concentraram sempre que possível em 
estrangeiros melhor que em cidadãos, porque os estrangeiros tiveram 
poucas direitas. Em dezembro 1919, em seu ato mais famoso, os 
agentes de Palmer apreenderam 249 estrangeiros residentes. 
Aqueles apreendidos foram colocados na placa um navio, o Buford,
limite para a Soviete-união. Deportees incluiu a feminista, o 
anarquista, e o escritor Emma Goldman, que recordou mais tarde a 
deporta16cao em seu autobiography, vivendo minha vida.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dopo il world.war.i, "uno spavento rosso" ha 
afferrato unito Dichiara. Una riflessione di questo 
clima di hysteria era "nel Palmer raids" sui radicali. Colpendo 
senza avvertimento e senza garanzie, di avvocato gli uomini del A. 
Mitchell Palmer generale hanno fracassato gli uffici del sindacato e 
le sedi delle organizzazioni comuniste e socialiste. Si sono 
concentrati per quanto possibile sugli stranieri piuttosto che sui 
cittadini, perché gli stranieri hanno avuti pochi diritti. Nel 
mese di dicembre del 1919, nel loro atto più famoso, gli agenti del 
Palmer hanno grippato 249 stranieri residenti. Quelli grippati 
sono stati disposti a bordo una nave, il Buford, limite per 
l'Soviet-unione. I deportati hanno incluso la femminista, 
l'anarchico ed il produttore Emma Goldman, che più successivamente ha
ricordato la deportazione in suo autobiography, vivente la mia vita.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μετά από παγκόσμιος πόλεμος Ι, ένας "κόκκινος 
τρόμοσ" επίασε τις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες. Μια αντανάκλαση 
αυτού του κλίματος της υστερίας ήταν στις "επιδρομές Palmer" 
στους ριζοσπάστες. Εντυπωσιακά χωρίς προειδοποίηση και 
χωρίς εντάλματα, τα άτομα Α. Mitchell Palmer's γενικών 
εισαγγελέων συνέθλιψαν τα γραφεία ένωσης και την έδρα των 
κομμουνιστικών και σοσιαλιστικών οργανώσεων. Συγκέντρωσαν 
όποτε είναι δυνατόν στους αλλοδαπούς παρά τους πολίτες, επειδή 
οι αλλοδαποί είχαν λιγότερα δικαιώματα. Τον Δεκέμβριο του 
1919, στη διασημότερη πράξη τους, οι πράκτορες Palmer 
ήρπαξαν 249 εδρεύοντες αλλοδαπούς. Εκείνοι που 
καταλήφθηκαν τοποθετήθηκαν σε ένα σκάφος, το Buford, που 
δεσμεύθηκε για τη Σοβιετική Ένωση. Τα απελαυμένος 
περιέλαβαν τη φεμινίστρια, τον αναρχικό, και το συγγραφέα Emma 
Goldman, οι οποίοι υπενθύμισαν αργότερα την εκτόπιση στην 
αυτοβιογραφία της, ζωντανός η ζωή μου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Después de Primera Guerra Mundial, un "susto 
rojo" apretó los Estados Unidos. Una reflexión de este clima 
de la histeria estaba en el "Palmer ataca" en radicales. Pulso 
sin la alerta y sin autorizaciones, de abogado los hombres de A. 
Mitchell Palmer general rompieron oficinas de la unión y las 
jefaturas de organizaciones comunistas y socialistas. Se 
concentraron siempre que sea posible en extranjeros más bien que 
ciudadanos, porque los extranjeros tenían pocas derechas. En 
diciembre de 1919, en su acto más famoso, los agentes de Palmer 
agarraron a 249 extranjeros residentes. Ésos agarrados fueron 
colocados a bordo de una nave, el Buford, límite para la 
Soviet-unio'n. Los deportados incluyeron a la feminista, al 
anarquista, y a programa de escritura Emma Goldman, que recordó más 
adelante la deportación en su autobiografía, viviendo mi vida.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086282</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105417</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-glanced-up-the-statue-of-liberty-emma-goldman-describes-her-deportation-in-the-era-of-the-red-scare</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
