<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/977204962</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>977204962</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206534</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Portals to the World</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Portale zur Welt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Portails au monde</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Portals ao mundo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Portals al mondo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πύλες στον κόσμο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Portals al mundo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a starting point for studying other countries and parts of the world. Learn about the culture, economy, geography, government, history, languages, politics, religions, and other aspects of more than 150 countries, from Afghanistan to Zimbabwe. Along with general information, the site provides links to authoritative, in-depth information selected by area specialists and other staff at the Library of Congress.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ein ist Ausgangspunkt für das Studieren anderer 
Länder und Teile der Welt. Erlernen Sie über die Kultur, 
Wirtschaft, Geographie, Regierung, Geschichte, Sprachen, Politik, 
Religionen und andere Aspekte von mehr als 150 Ländern, von 
Afghanistan nach Zimbabwe. Zusammen mit allgemeinen 
Informationen stellt die Site Links zu den maßgebenden, eingehenden 
Informationen zur Verfügung, die von den Bereich Fachleuten 
ausgewählt werden und anderen Personal an der Bibliothek des 
Kongresses.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est un point de départ pour étudier d'autres 
pays et régions du monde. Renseignez-vous sur la culture, 
l'économie, la géographie, le gouvernement, l'histoire, les 
langages, la politique, les religions, et d'autres aspects de plus de 
150 pays, d'Afghanistan au Zimbabwe. Avec des informations 
générales, le site fournit les liens à l'information bien fondée 
et détaillée choisie par des spécialistes en zone et tout autre 
personnel à la bibliothèque du congrès.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é um ponto começar para estudar outros países e
partes do mundo. Aprenda sobre a cultura, a economia, a 
geografia, o governo, o history, as línguas, a política, as 
religiões, e os outros aspectos de mais de 150 países, de 
Afeganistão a Zimbabwe. Junto com a informação geral, o local
fornece as ligações à informação authoritative, in-depth 
selecionada por specialists da área e a outra equipe de funcionários
na biblioteca do congress.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è un punto di partenza per studiare altri paesi e
parti del mondo. Impari circa la coltura, l'economia, la 
geografia, il governo, la storia, i linguaggi, la politica, le 
religioni ed altre funzioni di più di 150 paesi, dall'Afghanistan 
nello Zimbabwe. Con generalità, il luogo fornisce ai 
collegamenti alle informazioni autorevoli e approfondite selezionate 
dagli esperti di zona ed all'altro personale alla libreria del 
congresso.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι μια αφετηρία για τη μελέτη άλλων χωρών και 
μερών του κόσμου. Μάθετε για τον πολιτισμό, την οικονομία, 
τη γεωγραφία, την κυβέρνηση, την ιστορία, τις γλώσσες, την 
πολιτική, τις θρησκείες, και άλλες πτυχές περισσότερων από 
150 χωρών, από το Αφγανιστάν στη Ζιμπάπουε. Μαζί με τις 
γενικές πληροφορίες, η περιοχή παρέχει τις συνδέσεις με τις 
επιτακτικές, σε βάθος πληροφορίες που επιλέγονται από τους 
ειδικούς περιοχής και άλλο προσωπικό στη βιβλιοθήκη του 
συνεδρίου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es un punto de partida para estudiar otros países
y partes del mundo. Aprenda sobre la cultura, la economía, la 
geografía, el gobierno, la historia, lenguajes, política, 
religiones, y otros aspectos de más de 150 países, de Afganistán a 
Zimbabwe. Junto con la información de carácter general, el 
sitio proporciona a las conexiones a la información autoritaria, 
profundizada seleccionada por los especialistas del área y al otro 
personal en la biblioteca del congreso.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206534</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>977204962</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/portals-to-the-world</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
