<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108268</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108268</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087252</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Working Her Fingers to the Bone: Agnes Nestor's Story</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bearbeiten ihrer Finger zum Knochen: Agnes 
Nestors Geschichte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Travailler ses doigts à l'os : Histoire 
d'Agnes Nestor's</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Trabalhando seus dedos ao osso: História De
Agnes Nestor</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Funzionamento delle sue barrette all'osso: 
Storia Di Agnes Nestor</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Να απασχοληθεί στα δάχτυλά της στο κόκκαλο: 
Ιστορία Agnes Nestor's</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Trabajo de sus dedos al hueso: Historia De 
Agnes Nestor</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Agnes Nestor's mother was a textile mill worker. Her father was a machinist and a one-time member of the Knights of Labor who became a city alderman in Grand Rapids, Michigan. The family migrated to Chicago during the depression of the 1890s, and the teenage Agnes went to work in a glove factory. The sixty-hour work weeks exhausted her. "I have been so tired all day I could hardly work," she regularly noted in her diary. This reminiscence by Nestor described how the oppressive conditions of the glove factory pushed her to take a leading role in a successful strike of female glove workers in 1898. Soon she became president of her glove workers local and later a leader of the International Glove Workers Union. She also took a leading role in the Women's Trade Union League, serving as president of the Chicago branch from 1913 to 1948.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Agnes Nestors Mutter war ein 
Textiltausendstelarbeiter. Ihr Vater war ein Maschinist und ein 
einmaliges Bauteil der Ritter der Arbeit, die ein Stadtstadtrat in 
großartigem Rapids, Michigan wurden. Die Familie zog zu Chicago
während des Tiefstands des 1890s fort, und das Jugendagnes ging, in 
einer Handschuhfabrik zu arbeiten. Die Sechzigstunde Arbeit 
Wochen erschöpften sie. "ich bin gewesen, also ermüdet aller 
Tag, den ich kaum bearbeiten könnte," sie, beachtete regelmäßig in 
ihrem Tagebuch. Diese Erinnerung durch Nestor beschrieben, wie 
die bedrückenden Zustände der Handschuhfabrik sie drückten, um eine
führende Rolle in einem erfolgreichen Schlag der weiblichen 
Handschuharbeiter 1898 zu nehmen. Bald wurde sie Präsident 
ihrer lokalen Handschuharbeiter und später des Führers des 
internationalen Handschuh-Arbeiter-Anschlußes. Sie nahm auch 
eine führende Rolle in der Gewerkschaft-Liga der Frauen und diente 
als Präsident des Chicago Zweigs von 1913 bis 1948.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La mère d'Agnes Nestor's était une ouvrière de 
moulin de textile. Son père était un machiniste et un membre 
jetable des chevaliers du travail qui sont devenus un conseiller 
municipal de ville dans Rapids grand, Michigan. La famille a 
passé à Chicago pendant la dépression du 1890s, et l'Agnes 
d'adolescent est allé fonctionner dans une usine de gant. Les 
semaines de travail de soixante-heure l'ont épuisée. "j'ai 
été ainsi fatigué toute la journée je pourrais à peine 
travailler," elle ai régulièrement noté en son agenda. Cette 
réminiscence par Nestor a décrit comment les conditions accablants 
de l'usine de gant l'ont poussée pour prendre un principal rôle dans
une grève réussie des ouvriers féminins de gant en 1898. 
Bientôt elle est devenue président de ses ouvriers de gant 
locaux et plus tard d'une amorce du syndicat international de gant. 
Elle a également pris un principal rôle dans la ligue du 
syndicat des femmes, servant de président du branchement de Chicago 
de 1913 à 1948.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A matriz de Agnes Nestor era um trabalhador do 
moinho de textile. Seu pai era um machinist e um membro one-time
dos knights do trabalho que se transformaram um vereador em Rapids 
grande, Michigan da cidade. A família migrou a Chicago durante 
o depression do 1890s, e o Agnes teenage foi trabalhar em uma fábrica
da luva. As semanas do trabalho de sessenta-hora esgotaram-na. 
"eu fui assim que cansado o dia inteiro eu poderia mal 
trabalhar," ela anotei regularmente em seu diário. Este 
reminiscence por Nestor descrito como as condições oppressive da 
fábrica da luva a empurraram para fazer exame de um papel principal 
em uma batida bem sucedida de trabalhadores fêmeas da luva em 1898. 
Logo transformou-se presidente de seus trabalhadores da luva 
locais e mais tarde de um líder da união de trabalhadores 
internacional da luva. Fêz exame também de um papel principal 
na liga da união de comércio das mulheres, servindo como o 
presidente da filial de Chicago de 1913 a 1948.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La madre di Agnes Nestor era un operaio del 
laminatoio della tessile. Il suo padre era un macchinista e un 
membro di una volta dei cavalieri del Lavoro che sono diventato 
un alderman in grande Rapids, Michigan della città. La famiglia
ha migrato a Chicago durante la depressione del 1890s ed il Agnes 
teenage è andato funzionare in una fabbrica del guanto. Le 
settimane del lavoro di sessanta-ora la hanno esaurita. "sono 
stato io potrei appena funzionare così stanco tutto il giorno," 
lei regolarmente ho notato in suo diario. Questa reminiscenza da
Nestor ha descritto come gli stati oppressive della fabbrica del 
guanto la hanno spinta per prendere un ruolo principale in un colpo 
riuscito degli operai femminili del guanto in 1898. Presto è 
diventato presidente dei suoi operai del guanto locali e più 
successivamente di un capo dell'unione di operai 
internazionale del guanto. Egualmente ha preso un ruolo 
principale nella lega del sindacato delle donne, servente da 
presidente del ramo del Chicago da 1913 a 1948.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η μητέρα Agnes Nestor's ήταν εργαζόμενος 
υφαντικών μύλων. Ο πατέρας της ήταν μηχανικός και 
one-time μέλος των ιπποτών της εργασίας που έγιναν δημοτικός 
σύμβουλος πόλεων σε μεγάλο Rapids, Μίτσιγκαν. Η 
οικογένεια μετανάστευσε στο Σικάγο κατά τη διάρκεια της 
κατάθλιψης του 1890s, και η εφηβική Agnes πήγε να εργαστεί 
σε ένα εργοστάσιο γαντιών. Οι εβδομάδες εργασίας 
εξήντα-ώρας την εξάντλησαν. "έχω κουραστεί έτσι όλη την 
ημέρα εγώ θα μπορούσα μετά βίας να εργαστώ," σημείωσε τακτικά 
στο ημερολόγιό της. Αυτό το reminiscence από το Nestor
περιέγραψε πώς οι καταπιεστικοί όροι του εργοστασίου γαντιών την
ώθησαν για να πάρουν έναν κύριο ρόλο σε μια επιτυχή απεργία των
εργαζομένων γαντιών θηλυκών σε 1898, Σύντομα έγινε 
Πρόεδρος των εργαζομένων γαντιών της τοπικών και αργότερα ενός 
ηγέτη της διεθνούς ένωσης εργαζομένων γαντιών. Πήρε 
επίσης έναν κύριο ρόλο στην ένωση συνδικάτου των γυναικών, που 
χρησιμεύει ως ο Πρόεδρος του κλάδου του Σικάγου από το 1913 ως
το 1948.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La madre de Agnes Nestor era trabajador del molino
del textil. Su padre era maquinista y un miembro de una sola vez
de los caballeros del trabajo que hicieron concejal en Rapids 
magnífico, Michigan de la ciudad. La familia emigró a Chicago 
durante la depresión del 1890s, y el Agnes adolescente fue a trabajar
en una fábrica del guante. Las semanas del trabajo de la 
sesenta-hora la agotaron. "he sido así que cansado todo el dia 
podría trabajar apenas," ella observé regularmente en su diario. 
Esta reminiscencia de Nestor describió cómo las condiciones 
opresivas de la fábrica del guante la empujaron para tomar un papel 
principal en una huelga acertada de los trabajadores femeninos del 
guante en 1898. Pronto ella hizo presidente de sus trabajadores 
del guante locales y más adelante de un arranque de cinta de la 
unión de trabajadores internacional del guante. Ella también 
llevó un papel principal en la liga del sindicato de las mujeres, 
sirviendo como presidente de la ramificación de Chicago a partir de 
1913 1948.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087252</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108268</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/working-her-fingers-to-the-bone-agnes-nestors-story</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
