<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106849</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106849</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087349</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A Woman Recounts Her Twelve Abortions in Turn-of-the-Century New York</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Frau zählt ihre zwölf Abtreibungen in der 
Jahrhundertwende New York nach</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une femme raconte ses douze suspensions en 
Tourner-de-le-Siècle New York</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uma mulher recounts seus doze abortions no 
Gir-$$$-$$$-Século New York</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Una donna racconta i suoi dodici aborti nel 
Gir-de-$$$-Secolo New York</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια γυναίκα εξιστορεί δώδεκα αμβλώσεις της στον 
στροφή-$$$-Ο-ΑΙΏΝΑ Νέα Υόρκη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una mujer contó de nuevo sus doce abortos en el 
Dar vuelta-de-$$$-Siglo Nueva York</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In an interview, conducted by oral historian Allyson Knoth for the Feminist History Research Project, Elizabeth Anderson, born in Germany in the late 1880s, described the twelve abortions she endured as a young married woman living in New York City with a husband who refused to use birth control devices such as condoms. Anderson detailed a series of painful and dangerous procedures, including the use of ergot pills, and pricking the cervix with a hat pin. Anderson also suggested that abortion was used by working-class women as well as those better off; the typical abortionist charged $25 (a decent week's wage) to perform the illegal procedure.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In einem Interview geleitet mit Mundhistoriker 
Allyson Knoth für das feministische Geschichte Forschung Projekt, 
Elizabeth Anderson, getragen in Deutschland im späten 1880s, 
beschrieb die zwölf Abtreibungen, die sie als junge verheiratete Frau
aushielt, die in New York City mit einem Ehemann wohnt, der ablehnte, 
Geburtenkontrolleeinheiten wie Kondome zu benutzen. Anderson 
schilderte eine Reihe schmerzliche und gefährliche Prozeduren, 
einschließlich den Gebrauch der Mutterkornpillen und des Stechens des
Cervix mit einem Hutstift genau. Anderson schlug auch vor, daß 
Abtreibung von den Arbeiterklassefrauen sowie jene besseren weg 
verwendet wurde; das typische abortionist lud $25 (der Lohn 
einer annehmbaren Woche) auf um die ungültige Prozedur 
durchzuführen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans une entrevue, conduite par l'historien oral 
Allyson Knoth pour le projet de recherche féministe d'histoire, 
Elizabeth Anderson, soutenu en Allemagne vers la fin de 1880s, a 
décrit les douze suspensions qu'elle a supportées en tant que jeune 
femme mariée habitant à New York City avec un mari qui a refusé 
d'utiliser des dispositifs de contrôle des naissances tels que des 
condoms. Anderson a détaillé une série de procédures 
douloureuses et dangereuses, y compris l'utilisation des pillules 
d'ergot de seigle, et de piquer le cervix avec une broche de chapeau. 
Anderson a également suggéré que la suspension ait été 
employée par des femmes de classe ouvrier aussi bien que ces 
meilleurs hors fonction ; l'avorteur typique a chargé $25 
(le salaire d'une semaine décente) pour exécuter le procédé 
illégal.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em uma entrevista, conduzida pelo historian oral 
Allyson Knoth para o projeto de pesquisa feminista do history, 
Elizabeth Anderson, carregado em Germany no 1880s atrasado, descreveu 
os doze abortions que resistiu como uma mulher casada nova que vive em
New York City com um marido que recusasse usar dispositivos do 
controle de nascimento tais como condoms. Anderson detalhou uma 
série de procedimentos dolorosos e perigosos, including o uso de 
pills do ergot, e de pricking o cervix com um pino do chapéu. 
Anderson sugeriu também que o abortion estêve usado por 
mulheres do working-class as.well.as aqueles melhores fora; o 
abortionist típico carregou $25 (salário de uma semana decent) para 
executar o procedimento ilegal.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In un'intervista, condotta dallo storico orale 
Allyson Knoth per il progetto di ricerca femminista di storia, 
Elizabeth Anderson, sopportato in Germania verso la fine di 1880s, ha 
descritto i dodici aborti che ha resistito a come donna sposata 
giovane che vive a New York City con un marito che ha rifiutato di 
utilizzare i dispositivi di controllo di nascita quali i condoms. 
Anderson ha dettagliato una serie di procedure dolorose e 
pericolose, compreso l'uso delle pillole della segale cornuta e di 
puntura della cervice con un perno del cappello. Anderson 
egualmente ha suggerito che l'aborto è stato usato dalle donne della 
classe operaia così come quei migliori fuori; il abortionist 
tipico ha caricato $25 (stipendio della settimana decent) per 
effettuare la procedura illegale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε μια συνέντευξη, που πραγματοποιήθηκε από τον 
προφορικό ιστορικό Allyson Knoth για το φεμινιστικό 
ερευνητικό πρόγραμμα ιστορίας, Elizabeth Αντερσον, γεννημένο 
στη Γερμανία προς το τέλος 1880s, περιέγραψε τις δώδεκα 
αμβλώσεις που υπόμεινε ως νέα παντρεμένη γυναίκα που ζει στην 
πόλη της Νέας Υόρκης με έναν σύζυγο που αρνήθηκε να 
χρησιμοποιήσει τις συσκευές ελέγχου γέννησης όπως τα 
προφυλακτικά. Το Αντερσον απαρίθμησε μια σειρά επίπονων και
επικίνδυνων διαδικασιών, συμπεριλαμβανομένης της χρήσης ergot 
των χαπιών, και να τσιμπήσει τον τράχηλο με μια καρφίτσα καπέλου.
Το Αντερσον επίσης πρότεινε ότι η άμβλωση χρησιμοποιήθηκε 
από τις γυναίκες εργατικών τάξεων καθώς επίσης και εκείνους 
καλύτερους  τα χαρακτηριστικά υπέρ της έκτρωσης χρεωμένα 
$25 (η αμοιβή μιας κόσμιης εβδομάδας) για να εκτελέσει την 
παράνομη διαδικασία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En una entrevista, conducida por el historiador 
oral Allyson Knoth para el proyecto de investigación feminista de la 
historia, Elizabeth Anderson, llevada en Alemania en el último 1880s,
describió los doce abortos que ella aguantó como mujer casada joven 
que vivía en New York City con un marido que rechazó utilizar los 
dispositivos del control de la natalidad tales como condones. 
Anderson detalló una serie de procedimientos dolorosos y 
peligrosos, incluyendo el uso de las píldoras del cornezuelo de 
centeno, y de pinchar la cerviz con un contacto del sombrero. 
Anderson también sugirió que el aborto fuera utilizado por las
mujeres de la clase obrera así como esos mejores apagado; el 
abortionist típico cargó a $25 (el salario de una semana decente) 
que realizaran el procedimiento ilegal.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087349</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106849</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-woman-recounts-her-twelve-abortions-in-turn-of-the-century-new-york</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
