<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105135</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105135</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087399</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"And This Happened in Los Angeles:" Malcolm X Describes Police Brutality Against Members of the Nation of Islam</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"und dieses geschah in Los Angeles:" Malcolm
X beschreibt Polizei-Brutalitäten gegen Bauteile der Nation des 
Islams</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"et ceci s'est produit à Los Angeles :" 
Malcolm X décrit la brutalité de police contre des membres de 
la nation de l'Islam</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"e isto aconteceu em Los Angeles:" Malcolm X
descreve o brutality das polícias de encontro aos membros da nação 
do islam</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"e questo è accaduto a Los Angeles:" 
Malcolm X descrive il brutality della polizia contro i membri 
della nazione di Islam</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Και αυτό συνέβη στο Λος Αντζελες:" Θ*Μαλθολμ 
X Describes Police Brutality ενάντια στα μέλη του 
έθνους του Ισλάμ</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"y esto sucedió en Los Ángeles:" Malcolm X
describe brutalidad del policía contra los miembros de la nación del
Islam</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Malcolm X was a civil rights leader, a spokesperson for the Nation of Islam, and a leading black nationalist during the early 1960's. Viewing integration as an illusory solution to the problems of black Americans, Malcolm X advocated self-reliance, black pride, and unity. Malcolm's message became popular among Northern blacks as the Civil Rights movement failed to alleviate problems such as poverty, joblessness, police brutality, and de facto segregation. Although many Northern whites felt uncomfortable confronting racial inequities close to home, conditions for African Americans living in Northern and Western cities rivaled those of the South. In 1962 the Los Angeles Police Department, notorious in the Watts section of L.A. for harassing and brutalizing black youth, targeted the Nation of Islam in an act of violence. Malcolm X spoke out about the incident on WBAI radio.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Malcolm X war ein Zivilrechtführer, ein Sprecher 
für die Nation des Islams und ein führender schwarzer Nationalist 
während der frühen sechziger Jahre, die Integration da eine 
illusorische Lösung zu den Problemen schwarzem Amerikaner, Malcolm X 
befürwortetem Self-reliance, schwarzem Stolz und Einheit ansehen. 
Meldung Malcolms wurde unter Nordschwarzen populär, während 
die Zivilrechtbewegung Probleme wie Armut, Joblessness, 
PolizeiBrutalitäten und de Facto Abtrennung vermindern nicht konnte.
Obgleich viel Nordweiß unbequem fühlte, rassische 
Ungerechtigkeiten nah an Haus konfrontierend, rivalisierten 
Bedingungen für die afrikanischen Amerikaner, die in den Nord- und 
westlichen Städte leben, mit denen des Südens. In 1962 zielte 
die Los Angeles Polizei-Abteilung, die im Wattkapitel von L.A. für 
das Bedrängen und das Brutal behandeln der schwarzen Jugend notorisch
ist, die Nation des Islams in einem Gewaltakt. Malcolm X sprach 
aus über dem Ereignis auf WBAI Radio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Malcolm X était une amorce de droits civiques, un
porte-parole pour la nation de l'Islam, et un principal nationaliste 
noir pendant le début des années soixante visualisant l'intégration
car une solution illusoire aux problèmes des Américains noirs, du 
Malcolm art de l'auto-portrait-reliance préconisé par X, de la fierté noire, et 
de l'unité. Le message de Malcolm est devenu populaire parmi 
des noirs nordiques pendant que le mouvement de droits civiques 
n'allégeait pas des problèmes tels que la pauvreté, le chômage, la
brutalité de police, et la ségrégation de fait. Bien que 
beaucoup de blancs nordiques se soient sentis inconfortables 
confrontant des injustices raciales près de maison, les conditions 
pour les Américains africains vivant dans les villes nordiques et 
occidentales ont rivalisé ceux des Sud. Dans 1962 le 
service de police de Los Angeles, notoire dans la section de watts de 
L.A. pour harceler et brutalizer la jeunesse noire, a visé la nation 
de l'Islam dans un acte de violence. Malcolm X a parlé hors de 
environ l'incident sur la radio de WBAI.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Malcolm X era chefes dos direitos civis, um 
spokesperson para a nação do islam, e um nacionalista preto 
principal durante os 1960's. adiantados que vêem a integração 
porque uma solução illusory aos problemas do self-reliance advogado 
X preto dos americanos, do Malcolm, do orgulho preto, e da unidade. 
A mensagem de Malcolm tornou-se popular entre pretos do norte 
enquanto o movimento das direitas civis não aliviou problemas tais 
como a pobreza, o joblessness, o brutality das polícias, e o 
segregation de de facto. Embora muitos brancos do norte 
sentissem incômodos confrontando inequities raciais perto da HOME, as
condições para os americanos africanos que vivem em cidades do norte
e ocidentais rivalizaram aquelas do sul. Em 1962 o departamento 
das polícias de Los Angeles, notorious na seção dos watts de L.A. 
para harassing e brutalizing a juventude preta, alvejou a nação do 
islam em um ato de violência. Malcolm X falou para fora sobre 
do incident no rádio de WBAI.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Malcolm X era un capo di diritti civili, 
uno spokesperson per la nazione di Islam e un nazionalista nero 
principale durante l'inizio degli anni 60 che osserva l'integrazione 
poichè una soluzione illusoria ai problemi della fiducia in se stesso
sostenuta X nera di Malcolm, degli Americani, dell'orgoglio nero e 
dell'unità. Il messaggio del Malcolm è diventato popolare fra 
i neri nordici poichè il movimento di diritti civili non è riuscito 
ad attenuare i problemi quali povertà, joblessness, il brutality 
della polizia e la segregazione de facto. Anche se molti bianchi
nordici hanno ritenuto scomodi confrontando le ingiustizie razziali 
vicino alla sede, i termini per gli Americani africani che vivono 
nelle città nordiche ed occidentali hanno rivaleggiato con quelli del
sud. In 1962 il reparto della polizia de Los Angeles, rinomato 
nella sezione di watt di L.A. per harassing e brutalizing la gioventù
nera, ha designato la nazione come bersaglio di Islam in un 
atto della violenza. Malcolm X ha parlato verso l'esterno 
dell'avvenimento sulla radio di WBAI.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο Malcolm X ήταν ηγέτης αστικών δικαιωμάτων, 
ένας εκπρόσωπος για το έθνος του Ισλάμ, και ένας κύριος μαύρος 
εθνικιστής κατά τη διάρκεια της πρόωρης δεκαετίας του '60 που 
εμφανίζει την ολοκλήρωση ως ψευδαισθητική λύση στα προβλήματα 
μαύρων Αμερικανών, Malcolm X υποστήριξε την αυτάρκεια, τη 
μαύρη υπερηφάνεια, και την ενότητα. Το μήνυμα του Malcolm
έγινε δημοφιλές μεταξύ των βόρειων Μαύρων δεδομένου ότι η 
μετακίνηση αστικών δικαιωμάτων απέτυχε να ανακουφίσει τα 
προβλήματα όπως η ένδεια, το joblessness, η βιαιότητα 
αστυνομίας, και ο de facto διαχωρισμός. Αν και πολλά 
βόρεια λευκά αισθάνθηκαν τις ανήσυχες αντιμετωπίζοντας φυλετικές
αδικίες κοντά στο σπίτι, οι όροι για αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς 
που ζουν στις βόρειες και δυτικές πόλεις συναγωνίστηκαν εκείνων 
του νότου. Το 1962 το τμήμα αστυνομίας του Λος Αντζελες, 
πασίγνωστο στο τμήμα Watt L.A. για την παρενόχληση και της 
μαύρης νεολαίας, στόχευσε στο έθνος του Ισλάμ σε μια πράξη της 
βίας. Ο Malcolm X μίλησε έξω για το γεγονός στο 
ραδιόφωνο WBAI.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Malcolm X era un arranque de cinta de las derechas
civiles, portavoz para la nación del Islam, y un nacionalista negro 
principal durante los años 60 tempranos que veían la integración 
pues una solución ilusoria a los problemas de la independencia 
abogada X negra de los americanos, de Malcolm, del orgullo negro, y de
la unidad. El mensaje de Malcolm llegó a ser popular entre 
negros norteños mientras que el movimiento de las derechas civiles no
pudo aliviar problemas tales como pobreza, desempleo, brutalidad del 
policía, y segregación de hecho. Aunque muchos blancos 
norteños se sentían incómodos enfrentando injusticias raciales 
cerca del hogar, las condiciones para los americanos africanos que 
vivían en ciudades norteñas y occidentales rivalizaron los del sur. 
En 1962 el departamento del policía de Los Ángeles, notorio en
la sección de los vatios de L.A. para acosar y brutalizing la 
juventud negra, apuntó la nación del Islam en un acto de la 
violencia. Malcolm X habló fuera sobre del incidente en radio 
de WBAI.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087399</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105135</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/and-this-happened-in-los-angeles-malcolm-x-describes-police-brutality-against-members-of-the-nation-of-islam</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
