<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108232</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108232</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206361</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Drop Me Off in Harlem</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lassen Sie mich weg in Harlem fallen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Relâchez-moi hors fonction dans Harlem</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Deixe-me cair fora em Harlem</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Cadalo fuori in Harlem</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Με κατεβάστε σε Harlem</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cáigame apagado en Harlem</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a multimedia exploration of the Harlem Renaissance (1920s-1930s). Students can hear Langston Hughes read his poems, listen to Duke Ellington direct his orchestra, or watch Shorty George Snowden dance the Lindy Hop. An interactive map displays important cultural, social, and political establishments. Lesson ideas and learning activities facilitate an arts-integrated approach to the study of key works and themes that emerged.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist eine Multimediaerforschung der Harlem 
Renaissance (1920s-1930s). Kursteilnehmer können Langston 
Hughes hören, seine Gedichte zu lesen, auf Herzog Ellington zu hören
verweisen Sie sein Orchester oder Uhr Shorty George Snowden Tanz das 
Lindy Hopfen. Eine interaktive Karte zeigt wichtige kulturelle, 
Sozial- und politische Einrichtungen an. Lektionideen und 
Lernenaktivitäten erleichtern eine kunst-integrierte Annäherung zur 
Studie der Schlüsselarbeiten und der Themen, die auftauchten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est une exploration de multimédia de la 
Renaissance de Harlem (1920s-1930s). Les étudiants peuvent
entendre Langston Hughes lire ses poésies, écouter duc Ellington 
dirigez son orchestre, ou danse de Shorty George Snowden de 
montre l'houblon de Lindy. Une carte interactive affiche les 
établissements culturels, sociaux, et politiques importants. 
Les idées de leçon et l'étude facilitent une approche 
art-intégrée à l'étude des travaux et des thèmes principaux qui 
ont émergé.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é uma exploração dos multimedia do renascimento
de Harlem (1920s-1930s). Os estudantes podem ouvir Langston 
Hughes ler seus poemas, para escutar o duque Ellington dirija seu 
orchestra, ou dança de Shorty George Snowden do relógio o hop de 
Lindy. Um mapa interativo indica estabelecimentos cultural, 
sociais, e políticos importantes. As idéias da lição e as 
atividades de aprendizagem facilitam uma aproximação arte-integrada 
ao estudo dos trabalhos e dos temas chaves que emergiram.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è un'esplorazione di multimedia della rinascita 
di Harlem (1920s-1930s). Gli allievi possono sentire Langston 
Hughes leggere i suoi poems, ascoltare il duca Ellington diriga la sua
orchestra, o il ballo di Shorty George Snowden della vigilanza il 
luppolo di Lindy. Un programma interattivo visualizza le imprese
culturali, sociali e politiche importanti. Le idee di lezione e 
le attività imparanti facilitano un metodo arte-integrato allo studio
sugli impianti e sui temi chiave che sono emerso.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι μια εξερεύνηση πολυμέσων της αναγέννησης 
Harlem (η δεκαετία του '20-δεκαετία του '30). Οι 
σπουδαστές μπορούν να ακούσουν ότι Langston Hughes διάβασε 
τα ποιήματά του, ακούει το δούκα Ellington κατευθύνει την 
ορχήστρα του, ή το χορό Shorty George Snowden ρολογιών ο 
λυκίσκος Lindy. Ένας διαλογικός χάρτης παρουσιάζει τα 
σημαντικά πολιτιστικά, κοινωνικά, και πολιτικά ιδρύματα. Οι
ιδέες μαθήματος και οι δραστηριότητες εκμάθησης διευκολύνουν μια 
τέχνη-ενσωματωμένη προσέγγιση στη μελέτη των βασικών εργασιών 
και των θεμάτων που προέκυψαν.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es una exploración de las multimedias del 
renacimiento de Harlem (1920s-1930s). Los estudiantes pueden 
oír Langston Hughes leer sus poemas, escuchar duque Ellington dirija 
su orquesta, o la danza de Shorty George Snowden del reloj el salto de
Lindy. Una correspondencia interactiva visualiza los 
establecimientos culturales, sociales, y políticos importantes. 
Las ideas de la lección y las actividades que aprenden 
facilitan un acercamiento arte-integrado al estudio de los trabajos y 
de los temas dominantes que emergieron.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206361</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108232</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/drop-me-off-in-harlem</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
