<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107735</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107735</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087000</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Natural Tie Between Master and Apprentice has been Rent Asunder": An Old Apprentice Laments Changes in the Workplace, 1826</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die natürliche Gleichheit zwischen Meister und 
Lehrling ist Miete Asunder" gewesen: Ein alter Lehrling 
bejammert Änderungen an dem Arbeitsplatz, 1826</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"la cravate normale entre le maître et l'apprenti
a été loyer Asunder" : Un vieil apprenti déplore des 
changements du lieu de travail, 1826</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"o laço natural entre o mestre e o aprendiz foi 
aluguel Asunder": Um aprendiz velho laments mudanças no 
workplace, 1826</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"il legame naturale fra il supervisore e 
l'apprendista è stato affitto Asunder": Un apprendista anziano 
deplora i cambiamenti nel posto di lavoro, 1826</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ο φυσικός δεσμός μεταξύ του κυρίου και του 
μαθητευόμενου είναι μίσθωμα χωριστά": Ένας παλαιός 
μαθητευόμενος θρηνεί τις αλλαγές στον εργασιακό χώρο, 1826</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"el lazo natural entre el amo y el aprendiz ha 
sido alquiler Asunder": Un viejo aprendiz lamenta de cambios en 
el lugar de trabajo, 1826</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The urban workplace changed dramatically in the early decades of the nineteenth century. The American Revolution, with its rampant egalitarianism, dissolved much of the paternalistic control once wielded by fathers, masters and other authority figures, as the anonymous author "Old Apprentice" made clear in his set of three letters to the  New York Observer  in 1826. But significant blame for this erosion rested with the manufacturers themselves. Eager to seize upon new markets with expanded production, they divided up tasks to produce cheaper clothing or shoes. Semiskilled and unskilled women and children performed this labor rather than apprentices or other workingmen of the traditional artisanal system. These changes also dissolved the traditional residential patterns, pushing working men out into the housing market. A loss of reciprocity and responsibility occurred on both sides.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der städtische Arbeitsplatz änderte drastisch in
den frühen Dekaden des 19.jahrhunderts. Die amerikanische 
Umdrehung, mit seinem zügellosen Egalitarismus, löste viel der 
paternalistischen Steuerung auf, die einmal durch Väter, Meister und 
andere Berechtigung Abbildungen ausgeübt wurde, da der anonyme Autor 
"alter Lehrling" dem New York Beobachter 1826 klar in seinem Set von 
drei Zeichen bildete. Aber bedeutende Schuld für diese 
Abnutzung stand mit den Herstellern selbst still. Eifrig, nach 
neuen Absatzmärkten mit erweiterter Produktion zu ergreifen, teilten 
sich sie herauf Aufgaben, preiswertere Kleidung oder Schuhe zu 
produzieren. Hilfs- und unerfahrene Frauen und Kinder führten 
diese Arbeit anstatt Lehrlinge oder andere Workingmen des 
traditionellen artisanal Systems durch. Diese Änderungen 
lösten auch die traditionellen Wohnmuster auf und drückten Funktion 
Männer heraus in den Gehäusemarkt. Ein Verlust der 
Reziprozität und der Verantwortlichkeit trat auf beiden Seiten auf.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le lieu de travail urbain a changé excessivement 
dans les décennies tôt du dix-neuvième siècle. La 
révolution américaine, avec son égalitarisme effréné, a dissous 
une grande partie de la commande paternaliste une fois utilisée par 
des pères, des maîtres et d'autres chiffres d'autorité, car 
l'auteur anonyme "vieil apprenti" a fait clairement dans son ensemble 
de trois lettres à l'observateur de New York en 1826. Mais le 
blâme significatif pour cette érosion s'est reposé avec les 
constructeurs eux-mêmes. Désireux de saisir sur les marchés 
avec la production augmentée, ils ont divisé charge de 
produire l'habillement ou les chaussures meilleur marché. Les 
femmes et les enfants semi-qualifiés et non qualifiés ont exécuté 
ce travail plutôt qu'apprentis ou d'autres ouvriers du système 
traditionnel d'artisanal. Ces changements ont également dissous
les configurations résidentielles traditionnelles, poussant des 
ouvriers dehors dans le marché du logement. Une perte de 
réciprocité et de responsabilité s'est produite des deux côtés.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O workplace urbano mudou dramàtica nas décadas 
adiantadas do décimo nono século. A volta americana, com seu 
egalitarianism rampant, dissolveu muito do controle paternalistic 
wielded uma vez por pais, por mestres e por outras figuras da 
autoridade, porque o autor anonymous "aprendiz velho" fêz claramente 
em seu jogo de três letras ao observador de New York em 1826. 
Mas a culpa significativa para esta erosão descansou com os 
fabricantes eles mesmos. Ansioso para apreender em cima dos 
mercados novos com produção expandida, dividiram-se acima das 
tarefas produzir uma roupa ou umas sapatas mais baratas. As 
mulheres e as crianças semiskilled e inábeis executaram este 
trabalho melhor que aprendizes ou outros workingmen do sistema 
tradicional do artisanal. Estas mudanças dissolveram também os
testes padrões residential tradicionais, introduzindo homens de 
funcionamento para fora no mercado de carcaça. Uma perda do 
reciprocity e da responsabilidade ocorreu em ambos os lados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il posto di lavoro urbano è cambiato 
drammaticamente nelle decadi in anticipo del diciannovesimo secolo. 
La rivoluzione americana, con il relativo egalitarianism 
sfrenato, ha dissolto gran parte del controllo paternalistic 
maneggiato una volta dai padri, dai supervisori e da altre figure di 
autorità, poichè l'autore anonimo "apprendista anziano" ha fatto 
chiaramente nel suo insieme di tre lettere all'osservatore de New York
in 1826. Ma la colpa significativa per questa erosione si 
riposava con i fornitori essi stessi. Desideroso di grippare sui
nuovi mercati con produzione espansa, hanno diviso le mansioni 
produrre i vestiti o i pattini più poco costosi. Le donne ed i 
bambini parzialmente qualificati e non qualificati hanno effettuato 
questo lavoro piuttosto che gli apprendisti o altri workingmen 
del sistema tradizionale di artisanal. Questi cambiamenti 
egualmente hanno dissolto i modelli residenziali tradizionali, 
spingenti gli uomini di funzionamento fuori nel mercato degli alloggi.
Una perdita di reciprocità e della responsabilità si è 
presentata da entrambi i lati.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο αστικός εργασιακός χώρος άλλαξε εντυπωσιακά στις 
αρχές των δεκαετιών του δέκατου έννατου αιώνα. Η 
αμερικανική επανάσταση, με την ασυγκράτητη ισότητά της, διάλυσε 
ένα μεγάλο μέρος του paternalistic ελέγχου που χειρίστηκε μιά
φορά από τους πατέρες, κύριοι και άλλοι αριθμοί αρχής, ως 
ανώνυμος συντάκτης "παλαιός μαθητευόμενοσ" σαφές στο σύνολο 
τριών επιστολών του στον παρατηρητή της Νέας Υόρκης το 1826. 
Αλλά η σημαντική επίπληξη για αυτήν την διάβρωση 
στηρίχτηκε με τους κατασκευαστές οι ίδιοι. Πρόθυμοι να 
εκμεταλλευτούν τις νέες αγορές με την επεκταθείσα παραγωγή, 
κατένειμαν τις στοιχειώδεις εργασίες να παραχθεί ο φτηνότερα 
ιματισμός ή τα παπούτσια. Οι ημιειδικευμένα και ανειδίκευτα
γυναίκες και τα παιδιά εκτέλεσαν αυτήν την εργασία παρά τους 
μαθητευόμενους ή άλλος του παραδοσιακού χειρωνακτικού 
συστήματος. Αυτές οι αλλαγές διάλυσαν επίσης τα 
παραδοσιακά κατοικημένα πρότυπα, που ωθούν τα εργαζόμενα άτομα 
έξω στην αγορά κατοικίας. Μια απώλεια αμοιβαιότητας και 
ευθύνης εμφανίστηκε και στις δύο πλευρές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El lugar de trabajo urbano cambió dramáticamente
en las décadas tempranas del diecinueveavo siglo. La 
revolución americana, con su egalitarianism desenfrenado, disolvió 
mucho del control paternalistic manejado una vez por los padres, los 
amos y otras figuras de la autoridad, pues el autor anónimo "viejo 
aprendiz" hizo claramente en su conjunto de tres cartas al observador 
de Nueva York en 1826. Pero la culpa significativa para esta 
erosión se reclinó con los fabricantes ellos mismos. 
Impaciente agarrar sobre nuevos mercados con la producción 
ampliada, se dividieron encima de tareas de producir una ropa o 
zapatos más baratos. Las mujeres y los niños semicualificados 
e inexpertos realizaron este trabajo más bien que aprendices u otros 
workingmen del sistema tradicional del artisanal. Estos cambios 
también disolvieron los modelos residenciales tradicionales, 
empujando a hombres de funcionamiento hacia fuera en el mercado de 
cubierta. Una pérdida de reciprocidad y de responsabilidad 
ocurrió en ambas caras.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087000</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107735</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-natural-tie-between-master-and-apprentice-has-been-rent-asunder-an-old-apprentice-laments-changes-in-the-workplace-1826</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
