<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108759</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108759</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086267</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Am a Democrat and not a Revolutionist": Senator David Bennett Hill Defends the Gold Standard</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ich bin ein Demokrat und nicht ein 
Revolutionist": Senator David Bennett Hill Defends die 
Goldaktie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"je suis un démocrate et pas un Revolutionist" : 
Le sénateur David Bennett Hill Defends le étalon or or</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"eu sou uma democrata e não um Revolutionist": 
Senator David Bennett Monte Defender o padrão de ouro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"sono una carbossimetilazione e non un 
Revolutionist": Il senatore David Bennett Hill Defends la 
parità aurea</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"είμαι δημοκράτης και όχι ένα Revolutionist": 
Γερουσιαστής Δαβίδ Bennett Hill Defends τα χρυσά 
πρότυπα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"soy un demócrata y no un Revolutionist": 
Senador David Bennett Hill Defends el patrón oro</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The most famous speech in American political history was delivered by William Jennings Bryan on July 9, 1896, at the Democratic National Convention in Chicago, but it was preceded by two other significant speeches. The subject under debate was the currency plank in the Democratic platform. The majority of members of the resolutions committee had endorsed the free coinage of silver at a ratio of silver to gold of 16 to 1. (This inflationary measure would have increased the amount of money in circulation and aided cash-poor and debt-burdened farmers.) In the ensuing debate, Senator Benjamin Tillman of South Carolina spoke for the majority, framing the silver issue as a sectional one. His disastrous performance dashed his hopes to be the silverite candidate for the U.S. presidency. The speakers for the minority position, including Senator David Bennett Hill of New York--whose speech is excerpted here--defended President Cleveland and the gold standard.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die berühmteste Rede in der amerikanischen 
politischen Geschichte wurde von William Jennings Bryan an Juli 9, 
1896, an demokratischen Nationalkonventin Chicago geliefert, aber sie 
wurde von zwei anderen bedeutenden Reden vorangegangen. Das 
Thema unter Debatte war die Währungplanke in der demokratischen 
Plattform. Die Mehrheit einen Bauteilen des Zerlegungausschusses
hatte die freie Prägung des Silbers an einem Verhältnis des Silbers 
zum Gold von 16 bis 1 indossiert. (dieses inflationistische Maß
würde die Menge des Geldumlaufs erhöht haben und den 
Bargeld-schlechten und Schuld-belasteten Landwirten. geholfen) 
In der folgenden Debatte sprach Senator Benjamin Tillman von 
Südcarolina für die Majorität und gestaltete die silberne Ausgabe 
als Schnitt. Seine verhängnisvolle Leistung gestrichelt seine 
Hoffnungen, der silverite Anwärter für den VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Vorsitz zu sein. Die Lautsprecher für die Minoritätposition, 
einschließlich Senator David Bennett Hill von New York -- dessen Rede
hier excerptiert wird -- verteidigter Präsident Cleveland und die 
Goldaktie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le discours le plus célèbre dans l'histoire 
politique américaine a été fourni par William Jennings Bryan 
9 juillet 1896, à la convention nationale démocratique Chicago, 
mais il a été précédé par deux autres discours significatifs. 
Le sujet sous la discussion était la planche de devise dans la 
plateforme démocratique. La majorité de membres du comité de 
résolutions avait approuvé l'invention libre de l'argent à un 
rapport d'argent à l'or de 16 à 1. (cette mesure 
inflationniste aurait augmenté le montant d'argent dans la 
circulation et avait aidé les fermiers argent-pauvres et 
dette-chargés.) Au cours de la discussion suivante, le 
sénateur Benjamin Tillman de la Caroline du sud a parlé pour 
la majorité, encadrant l'issue argentée en tant que sectionnelle. 
Sa exécution désastreuse à tiret ses espoirs d'être le 
candidat de silverite pour la présidence des ETATS-UNIS. Les 
haut-parleurs pour la position de minorité, y compris le sénateur 
David Bennett Hill de New York -- dont le discours est extrait ici -- 
le Président défendu Cleveland et le étalon or or.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O discurso o mais famoso no history político 
americano foi entregado por William Jennings Bryan julho em 9, 1896, 
na convenção nacional democrática em Chicago, mas foi precedido 
outros por dois discursos significativos. O assunto sob o debate
era a prancha da moeda corrente na plataforma democrática. A 
maioria dos membros do comitê das definições tinha endossado o 
coinage livre da prata em uma relação da prata a um ouro de 16 a 1. 
(esta medida inflationary aumentaria a quantidade de dinheiro na
circulação e ajudaria a fazendeiros dinheiro-deficientes e 
débito-debt-burdened.) No debate seguindo, o senator Benjamin 
Tillman de carolina sul falou para a maioria, moldando a edição de 
prata como secional. Seu desempenho desastroso tracejado suas 
esperanças ser o candidato do silverite para o presidency de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS. Os altofalantes para a posição do minority, including 
o senator David Bennett Monte de New York -- cujo o discurso excerpted
aqui -- presidente defendido Cleveland e o padrão de ouro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il discorso più famoso nella storia politica 
americana è stato trasportato da William Jennings Bryan il 9 luglio 
1896, alla convenzione nazionale democratica in Chicago, ma è stato 
preceduto altri da due discorsi significativi. L'oggetto sotto 
il dibattito era la plancia di valuta nella piattaforma democratica. 
La maggior parte dei membri del comitato di risoluzioni aveva 
firmato l'invenzione libera di argento ad un rapporto di argento ad un
oro di 16 - 1. (questa misura inflazionistica avrebbe aumentato 
l'importo di soldi nella circolazione ed aiutato cash-povero e 
debito-caricato i coltivatori.) Nel dibattito seguente, il 
senatore Benjamin Tillman di Carolina del Sud ha parlato per la 
maggioranza, incorniciando l'edizione d'argento come sezionale. 
Le sue prestazioni disastrose tratteggiate le sue speranze 
essere il candidato del silverite per la presidenza degli STATI UNITI.
Gli altoparlanti per la posizione di minoranza, compreso il 
senatore David Bennett Hill di New York -- di cui il discorso è 
stralciato qui -- presidente difeso Cleveland e la parità aurea.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η διασημότερη ομιλία στην αμερικανική πολιτική 
ιστορία παραδόθηκε από William Jennings Bryan στις 9 
Ιουλίου ..1896, στη δημοκρατική εθνική Συνθήκη στο Σικάγο, 
αλλά προηγήθηκε από δύο άλλες σημαντικές ομιλίες. Το 
θέμα κάτω από τη συζήτηση ήταν η σανίδα νομίσματος στη 
δημοκρατική πλατφόρμα. Η πλειοψηφία των μελών της επιτροπής
ψηφισμάτων είχε επικυρώσει την ελεύθερη δημιουργία του ασημιού 
σε μια αναλογία του ασημιού στο χρυσό 16 έως 1. (Αυτό το
πληθωριστικό μέτρο θα είχε αυξήσει το χρηματικό ποσό στην 
κυκλοφορία και τους βοηθημένους μετρητό-φτωχούς και τους 
χρέος-φορτωμένους αγρότες.) Στην επόμενη συζήτηση, ο 
γερουσιαστής Benjamin Tillman της νότιας Καρολίνας μίλησε 
για την πλειοψηφία, πλαισιώνοντας το ασημένιο ζήτημα ως ένα 
τμηματικό. Η καταστρεπτική απόδοσή του όρμησε τις ελπίδες 
του να είναι ο υποψήφιος silverite για την ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ προεδρία.
Οι ομιλητές για τη μειονότητα τοποθετούν, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένου του γερουσιαστή Δαβίδ Bennett Hill της 
Νέας Υόρκης -- η της οποίας ομιλία είναι εδώ -- υπεράσπισε τον 
Πρόεδρο Cleveland και τα χρυσά πρότυπα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El discurso más famoso de la historia política 
americana fue entregado por Guillermo Jennings Bryan 9 de julio de 
1896, en la convención nacional democrática en Chicago, pero fue 
precedido por dos otros discursos significativos. El tema bajo 
discusión era el tablón de la modernidad en la plataforma 
democrática. La mayoría de los miembros del comité de las 
resoluciones había endosado la invención libre de la plata en una 
relación de transformación de la plata al oro de 16 a 1. (esta
medida inflacionista habría aumentado la cantidad de dinero en la 
circulación y había ayudado a granjeros efectivo-pobres y 
deuda-cargados.) En el discusión que sobrevenía, senador 
Benjamin Tillman de Carolina del Sur habló para la mayoría, 
enmarcando la edición de plata como seccional. Su 
funcionamiento desastroso rayado sus esperanzas de ser el candidato 
del silverite a la presidencia de ESTADOS UNIDOS. Los altavoces 
para la posición de la minoría, incluyendo senador David Bennett 
Hill de Nueva York -- que discurso se extracta aquí -- presidente 
defendido Cleveland y el patrón oro.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086267</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108759</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-am-a-democrat-and-not-a-revolutionist-senator-david-bennett-hill-defends-the-gold-standard</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
