<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102911</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102911</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212366</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Sun Path Activity</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sonne-Pfad-Aktivität</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Activité De Voie d'accès du Soleil</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Atividade Do Trajeto Do Sol</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Attività Del Percorso Del Sole</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δραστηριότητα μονοπατιών ήλιων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Actividad Del Camino Del Sol</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Sun Path exercise helps students gain an understanding of the movement of the sun throught the day, month and year. The Sun Path JAVA applet uses equations for a spherical Earth to calculate the sunrise and sunset times, the solar azimuth and solar altitude for any time of year and any latitude. The program can be run in yearly, monthly, daily, or hourly modes to create animations of the sun's path across the sky for different conditions and with different time resolutions. The example activity provided has students use Sun Path in the yearly mode to investigate seasonal changes in sunrise, sunset, length of day and sun altitude at their own latitude. Students learn to graph data, estimate their shadow length for their height and the sun's altitude and use trigonometry to check their shadow length results. This Starting Point page includes teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment idea and additional resources and references.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Sonne-Pfadübung Hilfen Kursteilnehmer 
gewinnen ein Verständnis der Bewegung des Sonne throught der Tag, der
Monat und das Jahr. Der Sonne-Pfad JAVA applet verwendet 
Gleichungen für eine kugelförmige Masse, um die Sonnenaufgang- und 
Sonnenuntergangzeiten, den Solarazimut und Solarhöhe für jederzeit 
des Jahres und jeder möglicher Breite zu errechnen. Das 
Programm kann innen jährlich, monatlich, täglich laufen gelassen 
werden oder stündliche Modi, um Animationen des Pfades des Sonnen 
über dem Himmel für unterschiedliche Bedingungen und mit 
unterschiedlichen Zeitzerlegungen zu erstellen. Die 
bereitgestellte Beispielaktivität hat Kursteilnehmergebrauch 
Sonne-Pfad im jährlichen Modus, zum der Saisonänderungen im 
Sonnenaufgang, im Sonnenuntergang, in der Länge des Tages und in der 
Sonnehöhe an ihrer eigenen Breite nachzuforschen. 
Kursteilnehmer erlernen, Daten graphisch darzustellen, schätzen
ihre Schattenlänge für ihre Höhe und die Höhe des Sonnen und 
verwenden Trigonometrie, um ihre Schattenlänge Resultate zu 
überprüfen. Diese Ausgangspunktseite schließt unterrichtende 
Anmerkungen und Spitzen, Lehrmittel, Einschätzung Idee und 
zusätzliche Betriebsmittel und Referenzen ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les étudiants d'aides d'exercice de voie d'accès
du soleil gagnent un arrangement du mouvement du throught du soleil 
le jour, le mois et l'année. Le Java applet de voie d'accès du
soleil emploie des équations pour une terre sphérique pour calculer 
les temps de lever de soleil et de coucher du soleil, l'azimut solaire
et l'altitude solaire pour n'importe quand de l'année et de n'importe
quelle latitude. Le programme peut être exécuté dedans 
annuellement, mensuellement, quotidiennement, ou des modes horaires 
pour créer des animations de la voie d'accès du soleil à travers le
ciel pour différentes conditions et avec différentes résolutions de
temps. L'activité d'exemple fournie a la voie d'accès du 
soleil d'utilisation d'étudiants dans le mode annuel pour étudier 
les changements saisonniers du lever de soleil, du coucher du soleil, 
de la durée le jour et de l'altitude du soleil à leur propre 
latitude. Les étudiants apprennent à représenter 
graphiquement des données, estiment leur longueur d'ombre pour leur 
taille et l'altitude du soleil et emploient la trigonométrie pour 
contrôler leurs résultats de longueur d'ombre. Cette page de 
point de départ inclut les notes et les extrémités d'enseignement, 
le matériel didactique, l'idée d'évaluation et les ressources et 
les références supplémentaires.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os estudantes das ajudas do exercício do trajeto 
do sol ganham uma compreensão do movimento do throught do sol o dia, 
o mês e o ano. O Java applet Do trajeto do sol usa equações 
para uma terra esférica calcular os tempos do sunrise e do por do 
sol, o azimuth solar e a altura solar para em qualquer altura que do 
ano e da toda a latitude. O programa pode ser funcionado dentro 
anualmente, mensalmente, diariamente, ou modalidades de hora em hora 
para criar animations do trajeto do sun através do céu para 
circunstâncias diferentes e com definições diferentes do tempo. 
A atividade do exemplo fornecida tem o trajeto do sol do uso dos
estudantes na modalidade anual para investigar mudanças seasonal no 
sunrise, no por do sol, no comprimento do dia e na altura do sol em 
sua própria latitude. Os estudantes aprendem representar 
graficamente dados, estimam seu comprimento da sombra para sua altura 
e a altura do sun e usam o trigonometry verificar seus resultados do 
comprimento da sombra. Esta página do ponto começar inclui 
notas e pontas ensinando, materiais de ensino, idéia da avaliação e
recursos e referências adicionais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli allievi di aiuti di esercitazione del percorso
del sole guadagnano una comprensione del movimento del throught del 
sole il giorno, il mese e l'anno. Il Java applet Del percorso 
del sole usa le equazioni per una terra sferica per calcolare i tempi 
di tramonto e di alba, l'azimut solare e l'altezza solare per in 
qualunque momento dell'anno e di tutta la latitudine. Il 
programma può essere funzionato annualmente, mensilmente, 
giornalmente dentro, o modi orari per creare le animazioni del 
percorso del sun attraverso il cielo per le circostanze differenti e 
con differenti risoluzioni di tempo. L'attività di esempio 
fornita ha percorso del sole di uso degli allievi nel modo annuale per
studiare i cambiamenti stagionali nell'alba, nel tramonto, nella 
lunghezza del giorno e nell'altezza del sole alla loro propria 
latitudine. Gli allievi imparano rappresentare graficamente i 
dati, valutano la loro lunghezza dell'ombra per la loro altezza e 
l'altezza del sun ed usano la trigonometria per controllare i loro 
risultati di lunghezza dell'ombra. Questa pagina del punto di 
partenza include le note e punte d'istruzione, materiali didattici, 
idea di valutazione e risorse e riferimenti supplementari.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η άσκηση μονοπατιών ήλιων βοηθά τους σπουδαστές να 
κερδίσουν μια κατανόηση της μετακίνησης του ήλιου throught η 
ημέρα, ο μήνας και το έτος. Το applet της ΙΑΒΑΣ 
μονοπατιών ήλιων χρησιμοποιεί τις εξισώσεις για μια σφαιρική γη 
για να υπολογίσει τους χρόνους ανατολής και ηλιοβασιλέματος, το 
ηλιακό αζιμούθιο και το ηλιακό ύψος για οποτεδήποτε του έτους 
και οποιουδήποτε γεωγραφικού πλάτους. Το πρόγραμμα μπορεί 
να οργανωθεί μέσα ετήσια, μηνιαία, καθημερινά, ή ωριαίοι 
τρόποι για να δημιουργήσει τις ζωτικότητες του μονοπατιού του 
ήλιου πέρα από τον ουρανό για τους διαφορετικούς όρους και με τα
διαφορετικά χρονικά ψηφίσματα. Η δραστηριότητα 
παραδείγματος παρεχόμενη έχει το μονοπάτι ήλιων χρήσης 
σπουδαστών στον ετήσιο τρόπο για να ερευνήσει τις εποχιακές 
αλλαγές στην ανατολή, το ηλιοβασίλεμα, το μήκος της ημέρας και το
ύψος ήλιων στο γεωγραφικό πλάτος τους. Οι σπουδαστές 
μαθαίνουν στα στοιχεία γραφικών παραστάσεων, υπολογίζουν το 
μήκος σκιών τους για το ύψος τους και trigonometry ύψους και 
χρήσης του ήλιου για να ελέγξουν τα αποτελέσματα μήκους σκιών 
τους. Αυτή η σελίδα αφετηρίας περιλαμβάνει τις σημειώσεις 
και τις άκρες διδασκαλίας, τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, την ιδέα 
αξιολόγησης και τα πρόσθετα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς και τις 
αναφορές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los estudiantes de las ayudas del ejercicio del 
camino del sol ganan una comprensión del movimiento del throught del 
sol el día, el mes y el año. El Java applet Del camino del sol
utiliza las ecuaciones para una tierra esférica para calcular los 
tiempos de la salida del sol y de la puesta del sol, el acimut solar y
la altitud solar para en caulquier momento del año y de cualquier 
latitud. El programa se puede ejecutar adentro anualmente, 
mensualmente, diariamente, o los modos cada hora para crear las 
animaciones del camino del sun a través del cielo para diversas 
condiciones y con diversas resoluciones del tiempo. La actividad
del ejemplo proporcionada tiene camino del sol del uso de los 
estudiantes en el modo anual para investigar cambios estacionales en 
salida del sol, puesta del sol, la longitud del día y la altitud del 
sol en su propia latitud. Los estudiantes aprenden representar 
datos gra'ficamente, estiman su longitud de la sombra para su altura y
la altitud del sun y utilizan la trigonometría para controlar sus 
resultados de la longitud de la sombra. Esta paginación del 
punto de partida incluye notas y las extremidades de enseñanza, los 
materiales didácticos, idea del gravamen y los recursos y las 
referencias adicionales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212366</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102911</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/sun-path-activity</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
