<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105423</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105423</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087131</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"To the colored soldiers of the U.S. Army."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"zu den farbigen Soldaten der VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Armee."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"aux soldats colorés de l'armée des ETATS-UNIS."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"aos soldados coloridos do exército de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"ai soldati colorati dell'esercito degli STATI 
UNITI."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Στους έγχρωμους στρατιώτες του ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΥ στρατού."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"a los soldados coloreados del ejército de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This propaganda leaflet was dropped by German airplanes behind American lines during World War I. Nearly 370,000 African Americans were drafted into the U.S. Army starting in the fall of 1917 (they were not allowed to join the Marines, and the Navy took African Americans only as cooks and kitchen help). Although more than half of the black troops were in combat units, they remained segregated from white troops. Subjected to racist harassment (including demeaning insults from white officers), black troops were continually reminded of their second-class citizenship. By stressing racist conditions in the United States, leaflets such as this attempted to destroy morale and encourage desertion among African-American troops.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Propagandablättchen wurde mit den German 
Flugzeugen hinter amerikanische Zeilen während des Weltkrieges I. 
Nearly fallengelassen, 370.000, die afrikanische Amerikaner in die 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Armee gezeichnet wurden, die im Fall von 1917 
beginnt (sie durften nicht, die Marinen zu verbinden, und die Marine 
nahm afrikanische Amerikaner nur als Köche und Küchehilfe). 
Obgleich mehr als Hälfte der schwarzen Truppen in den 
Kampfmaßeinheiten waren, blieben sie von den weißen Truppen 
getrennt. Unterworfen rassistischer Belästigung 
(einschließlich erniedrigende Beleidigungen von den weißen 
Offizieren), wurden schwarze Truppen fortwährend an ihre 
Zweitkategorie Staatsbürgerschaft erinnert. Durch das Betonen 
der rassistischen Bedingungen in den Vereinigten Staaten, in 
Blättchen wie diesem versucht, um Moral zu zerstören und Verlassen 
unter Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Truppen anzuregen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce feuillet de propagande a été lâché en avions 
d'German derrière les lignes américaines pendant la Première Guerre
Mondiale. Presque 370.000 Américains africains ont été 
dessinés dans l'armée des ETATS-UNIS commençant en automne de 1917 
(on ne leur a pas permis de joindre les soldats de marine, et la 
marine a pris les Américains africains seulement en tant que des 
cuisiniers et aide de cuisine). Bien que plus que la moitié des
troupes noires aient été dans des unités de combat, elles sont 
restées isolées des troupes blanches. Soumis au harcèlement 
raciste (insultes se humiliantes y compris des officiers blancs), des 
troupes noires ont été continuellement rappelées leur citoyenneté 
de deuxième-classe. En soumettant à une contrainte des 
conditions racistes aux Etats-Unis, aux feuillets comme ceci essayé 
pour détruire le moral et pour encourager l'abandon parmi les troupes
afro-américaines.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este leaflet do propaganda foi deixado cair por aviões de
Alemão atrás das linhas americanas durante a guerra de mundo I. 
Quase 370.000 que os americanos africanos foram esboçados no 
exército de ESTADOS UNIDOS que começa na queda de 1917 (não foram 
permitidos juntar os fuzileiros navais, e a marinha fêz exame de 
americanos africanos somente como cozinheiros e ajuda da cozinha). 
Embora mais do que a metade das tropas pretas estivessem em 
unidades do combate, remanesceram segregados das tropas brancas. 
Sujeitado ao harassment racist (insultos se humilhando including
dos oficiais brancos), as tropas pretas foram lembradas continuamente 
de seu citizenship da segundo-classe. Forçando condições 
racist nos estados unidos, em leaflets tais como este tentado destruir
o morale e incentivar o desertion entre tropas Africano-Americanas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo opuscolo di propaganda è stato caduto in aeroplani
del German dietro le righe americane durante la guerra mondiale I. 
Nearly 370.000 che gli Americani africani sono stati disegnati 
nell'esercito degli STATI UNITI che comincia nell'autunno di 1917 (non
sono stati permessi unire i fanti di marina ed il blu marino ha preso 
gli Americani africani soltanto come i cuochi ed aiuto della cucina). 
Anche se più della metà delle truppe nere erano nelle unità 
di combattimento, sono rimasto segregate dalle truppe bianche. 
Sottoposto al harassment razzista (insulti abbassantesi compresi
dagli ufficiali bianchi), le truppe nere sono state ricordate a 
continuamente della loro cittadinanza del secondo-codice categoria. 
Sollecitando i termini razzisti in unito Dichiara, 
opuscoli come questo tentato per distruggere il morale e 
consigliare al desertion fra le truppe Africano-Americane.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το φυλλάδιο προπαγάνδας τα γερμανικά αεροπλάνα 
έπεσε πίσω από τις αμερικανικές γραμμές κατά τη διάρκεια του 
παγκόσμιου πολέμου Ι. Σχεδόν 370.000 αφρικανικοί 
Αμερικανοί συντάχθηκαν στον ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ στρατό που αρχίζει το 
φθινόπωρο του 1917 (δεν επιτράπηκαν για να ενώσουν τα ναυτικά, 
και το ναυτικό πήρε αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς μόνο όπως τους 
μάγειρες και οδηγίες κουζινών). Αν και περισσότερο από τα 
μισά από τα μαύρα στρατεύματα ήταν στις μονάδες αγώνα, 
παρέμειναν διαχωρισμένα από τα λευκά στρατεύματα. Στη 
ρατσιστική παρενόχληση (συμπεριλαμβανομένων των εξευτελιστικών 
προσβολών από τους λευκούς ανώτερους υπαλλήλους), τα μαύρα 
στρατεύματα υπενθυμίστηκαν συνεχώς τη δεύτερης θέσης υπηκοότητά
τους. Με να τονίσουν ρατσιστικοί όρος στις Ηνωμένες 
Πολιτείες, τα φυλλάδια όπως αυτό προσπάθησαν να καταστρέψουν το 
ηθικό και να ενθαρρύνουν τη λιποταξία μεταξύ των 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικών στρατευμάτων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este prospecto de la propaganda fue caído por los 
aeroplanos german detrás de líneas americanas durante la guerra 
mundial I. Nearly 370.000 que bosquejaron a los americanos africanos 
en el ejército de ESTADOS UNIDOS que comenzaba en la caída de 1917 
(a les no se permitió ensamblar a los infantes de marina, y la 
Marina de guerra tomó a americanos africanos solamente como cocineros y 
ayuda de la cocina). Aunque más que la mitad de las tropas 
negras estaban en unidades del combate, seguían segregada de las 
tropas blancas. Sujetado al hostigamiento racist (insultos que 
se degradan incluyendo de los oficiales blancos), recordaron a las 
tropas negras continuamente su ciudadanía de la segundo-clase. 
Tensionando condiciones racist en los Estados Unidos, los 
prospectos tales como esto procurada para destruir moral y para animar
la deserción entre las tropas Africano-Americanas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087131</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105423</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/to-the-colored-soldiers-of-the-u-s-army</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
