<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104642</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104642</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201358</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Earth Exploration Toolbook</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Masse Erforschung Toolbook</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Exploration Toolbook de la Terre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Exploração Toolbook Da Terra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Esplorazione Toolbook Della Terra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γήινη εξερεύνηση Toolbook</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Exploración Toolbook De la Tierra</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The purpose of the Earth Exploration Toolbook is to support the use of scientific datasets, tools, and other products by the broader educational community. The Toolbook provides a collection of earth science datasets and scientific tools along with educational applications of the datasets. Each chapter in the Toolbook presents the specific datasets needed for the exercise, the analysis or visualization tools, clear instructions to the educator who would be using the dataset, and step-by-step instructions that could be given to students. The chapters list the learning goals, inquiry standards and content standards for each activity. Suggestions for further exploration of the data and other ways to use the tool are also provided. The chapters are designed for K-12 and undergraduate college level.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Zweck der Masse Erforschung Toolbook ist, den 
Gebrauch der wissenschaftlichen Datensätze, der Hilfsmittel und 
anderer Produkte durch die ausgedehntere pädagogische Gemeinschaft zu
unterstützen. Das Toolbook stellt eine Ansammlung 
Geowissenschaftdatensätze und wissenschaftliche Hilfsmittel zusammen 
mit pädagogischen Anwendungen der Datensätze zur Verfügung. 
Jedes Kapitel im Toolbook stellt die spezifischen Datensätze 
dar, die für die Übung, die Analyse oder die 
Sichtbarmachunghilfsmittel, freie Anweisungen dem Erzieher benötigt 
werden, der den Datensatz verwenden würde, und schrittweisee 
Anweisungen, die erteilt werden konnten den Kursteilnehmern. Die
Kapitel drucken die erlernenziele, die Anfragestandards und die 
zufriedenen Standards für jede Aktivität aus. Vorschläge für
weitere Erforschung der Daten und anderer Methoden, das Hilfsmittel zu
benutzen werden auch zur Verfügung gestellt. Die Kapitel sind 
für K-12 und Nichtgraduierthochschulstufe bestimmt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le but de l'exploration Toolbook de la terre est de
supporter l'utilisation des ensembles de données scientifiques, des 
outils, et d'autres produits par la communauté éducative plus large.
Le Toolbook fournit une collection d'ensembles de données de 
science de la terre et d'outils scientifiques avec des applications 
éducatives des ensembles de données. Chaque chapitre dans le 
Toolbook présente les ensembles de données spécifiques requis pour 
l'exercice, l'analyse ou les outils de visualisation, des instructions
claires à l'éducateur qui utiliserait l'ensemble de données, et des
instructions pas à pas qui pourraient être données aux étudiants. 
Les chapitres énumèrent les buts d'étude, les normes 
d'enquête et les normes contentes pour chaque activité. Des 
suggestions pour davantage d'exploration des données et d'autres 
voies d'utiliser l'outil sont également fournies. Les chapitres
sont conçus pour K-12 et niveau d'université d'étudiant préparant 
une licence.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A finalidade da exploração Toolbook da terra é 
suportar o uso de séries de dados científicas, de ferramentas, e de 
outros produtos pela comunidade educacional mais larga. O 
Toolbook fornece uma coleção de séries de dados da ciência de 
terra e de ferramentas científicas junto com aplicações 
educacionais das séries de dados. Cada capítulo no Toolbook 
apresenta as séries de dados específicas necessitadas para o 
exercício, a análise ou as ferramentas do visualization, 
instruções desobstruídas ao educador que estaria usando a série de
dados, e as instruções passo a passo que poderiam ser dadas aos 
estudantes. Os capítulos alistam os objetivos de aprendizagem, 
os padrões do inquérito e os padrões satisfeitos para cada 
atividade. As sugestões para uma exploração mais adicional 
dos dados e de outras maneiras usar a ferramenta são fornecidas 
também. Os capítulos são projetados para K-12 e nível de 
faculdade do undergraduate.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lo scopo dell'esplorazione Toolbook della terra è 
sostenere l'uso dei gruppi di dati scientifici, degli strumenti e di 
altri prodotti dalla più vasta Comunità educativa. Il Toolbook
fornisce una collezione di gruppi di dati di scienze della terra e di 
strumenti scientifici con le applicazioni educative dei gruppi di 
dati. Ogni capitolo nel Toolbook presenta i gruppi di dati 
specifici stati necessari per l'esercitazione, l'analisi o gli 
strumenti di visualizzazione, istruzioni libere all'educatore che 
stava usando il gruppo di dati ed istruzioni graduali che potrebbero 
essere date agli allievi. I capitoli elencano gli obiettivi 
imparanti, gli standard di inchiesta e gli standard soddisfatti per 
ogni attività. I suggerimenti per ulteriore esplorazione dei 
dati e di altri modi utilizzare lo strumento egualmente sono forniti. 
I capitoli sono progettati per K-12 ed il livello di università
dello studente non laureato.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο σκοπός της γήινης εξερεύνησης Toolbook είναι να 
υποστηριχθεί η χρήση των επιστημονικών συνόλων δεδομένων, των 
εργαλείων, και άλλων προϊόντων από την ευρύτερη εκπαιδευτική 
κοινότητα. Το Toolbook παρέχει μια συλλογή των συνόλων 
δεδομένων γήινης επιστήμης και των επιστημονικών εργαλείων μαζί 
με τις εκπαιδευτικές εφαρμογές των συνόλων δεδομένων. Κάθε 
κεφάλαιο στο Toolbook παρουσιάζει τα συγκεκριμένα σύνολα 
δεδομένων που απαιτούνται για την άσκηση, την ανάλυση ή τα 
εργαλεία απεικόνισης, τις σαφείς οδηγίες στον εκπαιδευτικό που θα
χρησιμοποιούσε το σύνολο δεδομένων, και τις βαθμιαίες οδηγίες που
θα μπορούσαν να δοθούν στους σπουδαστές. Τα κεφάλαια 
εμφανίζουν λίστα τους στόχους εκμάθησης, τα πρότυπα έρευνας και 
τα ικανοποιημένα πρότυπα για κάθε δραστηριότητα. Οι 
προτάσεις για την περαιτέρω εξερεύνηση των στοιχείων και άλλων 
τρόπων να χρησιμοποιηθεί το εργαλείο παρέχονται επίσης. Τα 
κεφάλαια σχεδιάζω για Κ- 12 και το επίπεδο προπτυχιακών 
κολλεγίων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El propósito de la exploración Toolbook de la 
tierra es utilizar el uso de datasets científicos, de herramientas, y
de otros productos de la comunidad educativa más amplia. El 
Toolbook proporciona a una colección de datasets de la geología y de
herramientas científicas junto con las aplicaciones educativas de los
datasets. Cada capítulo en el Toolbook presenta los datasets 
específicos necesitados para el ejercicio, el análisis o las 
herramientas de la visualización, las instrucciones claras al 
educador que estaría utilizando el dataset, y las instrucciones paso 
a paso que se podrían dar a los estudiantes. Los capítulos 
enumeran las metas que aprenden, los estándares de la pregunta y los 
estándares contentos para cada actividad. Las sugerencias para 
la exploración adicional de los datos y de otras maneras de utilizar 
la herramienta también se proporcionan. Los capítulos se 
diseñan para K-12 y el nivel de universidad del estudiante.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201358</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104642</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/earth-exploration-toolbook</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
