<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103194</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103194</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207233</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Frederick Douglass Papers at the Library of Congress</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Frederick Douglass Papiere an der Bibliothek 
des Kongresses</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les papiers de Frederick Douglass à la 
bibliothèque du congrès</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os papéis de Frederick Douglass na biblioteca do 
congress</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le carte da Frederick Douglass alla libreria del 
congresso</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα έγγραφα Frederick Douglass στη βιβλιοθήκη του 
συνεδρίου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los papeles de Frederick Douglass en la biblioteca
del congreso</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">presents the papers of the 19th-century African-American abolitionist who escaped from slavery and then risked his own freedom by becoming an outspoken antislavery lecturer, writer, and publisher. The first release of the Douglass Papers contains 2,000 items (16,000 images) that span the years 1841 to 1964 and relate to Douglass's life as an escaped slave, abolitionist, editor, orator, and public servant.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt die Papiere des Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen 
abolitionist 19th-century dar, das von der Sklaverei entging und dann 
seine eigene Freiheit riskierte, indem es ein freimütiger antislavery
Lektor, ein Verfasser und ein Verleger wurde. Die erste 
Freisetzung von den Douglass Papieren enthält 2.000 Einzelteile 
(16.000 Bilder) diese Überspannung die Jahre 1841 bis 1964 und steht 
auf dem Leben Douglasss wie ein entgangener Sklave, ein abolitionist, 
ein Herausgeber, ein Redner und ein allgemeiner Bediensteter in 
Verbindung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">présente les papiers de l'abolitionniste 
19th-century afro-américain qui s'est échappé de l'esclavage et a puis 
risqué sa propre liberté en devenant un conférencier, un auteur, et
un éditeur francs d'antiesclavagiste. La première version des 
papiers de Douglass contient 2.000 éléments (16.000 images) cette 
envergure les années 1841 à 1964 et associe à la vie de Douglass en
tant qu'un slave échappé, un abolitionniste, un éditeur, un 
orateur, et fonctionnaire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">apresenta os papéis do abolitionist 19th-century 
Africano-Americano que se escapou do slavery e se arriscou então sua 
própria liberdade assentando bem em um lecturer, em um escritor, e em
um publisher outspoken do antislavery. A primeira liberação 
dos papéis de Douglass contem 2.000 artigos (16.000 imagens) essa 
extensão os anos 1841 a 1964 e relaciona-se à vida de Douglass como 
um escravo escapado, um abolitionist, um editor, um orator, e um 
empregado público.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">presenta i documenti del abolitionist 
Africano-Americano 19th-century che ha fuoriuscito da slavery ed 
allora ha rischiato la sua propria libertà stando bene ad un 
conferenziere, ad un produttore e ad un editore franchi di 
antislavery. La prima versione delle carte da Douglass contiene 
2.000 articoli (16.000 immagini) quella portata gli anni 1841 - 1964 e
si riferisce a vita del Douglass come uno schiavo fuoriuscito, un 
abolitionist, un editore, un orator e un funzionario.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρουσιάζει τις εργασίες του αφρικανικός-αμερικανικού 
ρεφορμιστή 19$ος-αιώνα που δραπέτευσε από τη σκλαβιά και 
διακινδύνευσε έπειτα την ελευθερία του με να γίνει ειλικρινείς 
ενάντιοι στη δουλεία ομιλητής, συγγραφέας, και εκδότης. Η 
πρώτη έκδοση των εγγράφων Douglass περιέχει 2.000 
αντικείμενα (16.000 εικόνες) που εκτείνονται τα έτη 1841 
έως 1964 και αφορούν τη ζωή Douglass ως δραπετευμένος 
σκλάβος, ρεφορμιστής, επεξεργαστής, ομιλητής, και δημόσιος 
υπάλληλος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">presenta los papeles del abolitionist 
Africano-Americano 19th-century que se escapó de esclavitud y 
después arriesgó su propia libertad sintiendo bien a un 
conferenciante, a un programa de escritura, y a un editor abiertos del
antislavery. El primer desbloquear de los papeles de Douglass 
contiene 2.000 items (16.000 imágenes) ese palmo los años 1841 a 
1964 y se relaciona con la vida de Douglass como un esclavo escapado, 
un abolitionist, un editor, un orador, y un criado público.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207233</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103194</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-frederick-douglass-papers-at-the-library-of-congress</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
