<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105299</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105299</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086115</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Eight Hours in the Forenoon, Eight Hours in the Afternoon": An IWW Organizer Describes the Horrors of Rural Work</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"acht Stunden im Vormittag, acht Stunden am 
Nachmittag": Ein IWW Organisator beschreibt die Grausigkeiten 
der landwirtschaftlichen Arbeit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"huit heures dans le matin, huit heures 
l'après-midi" : Un organisateur d'IWW décrit les horreurs du 
travail rural</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"oito horas no forenoon, oito horas na tarde": 
Um organizer de IWW descreve os horrors do trabalho rural</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"otto ore nella mattina, otto ore nel pomeriggio": 
Un organizzatore di IWW descrive gli orrori di lavoro rurale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Οκτώ ώρες forenoon, οκτώ ώρες το απόγευμα": 
Ένας διοργανωτής IWW περιγράφει τις φρίκες της αγροτικής
εργασίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"ocho horas en la mañana, ocho horas por la 
tarde": Un organizador de IWW describe los horrores del trabajo 
rural</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Farmers in the years before World War I faced thoroughly modern economic stresses and labor conflicts as the scale of their enterprises increased. By World War I, Midwestern and Great Plains farmers had come to rely on large pools of seasonal migrant labor, mostly unemployed urban workers from Chicago and other Midwestern cities, to harvest wheat or corn. Workers faced long hours and low wages, isolated in temporary camps without permanent homes or meeting places. The Industrial Workers of the World (IWW) union attempted to organize these "harvest stiffs." The radical "Wobblies" argued that wheat farmers were businessmen in a protected industry who, thanks to wartime government price supports, reaped large profits and returned none of that wealth to those who actually harvested their crop. E. F. Doree, an IWW organizer, described in detail the difficult conditions migrants faced and mocked the idea of rural work as wholesome and benevolent with the famous joke that in the wheat states, the "eight-hour work day" prevailed--"eight hours in the forenoon, eight hours in the afternoon."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Landwirte in den Jahren bevor Erster Weltkrieg 
gegenübergestellte gänzlich moderne ökonomische Drücke und Arbeit 
$überschneidungen, wie die Skala ihrer Unternehmen sich erhöhte. 
Durch den Ersten Weltkrieg waren Landwirte der des mittleren 
Westens und Prairien gekommen, auf große Pools der Wander- 
saisonalarbeit, meistens der arbeitslosen städtischen Arbeiter von 
Chicago und anderer des mittleren Westensstädte zu bauen, Weizen oder
Mais zu ernten. Arbeiter stellten lange Stunden und niedrigen 
die Löhne gegenüber, lokalisiert in den temporären Lagern ohne 
permanente Häuser oder Treffpunkte. Die industriellen Arbeiter 
des Anschlußes der Welt (IWW) versuchten, diese zu organisieren 
"Ernte stiffs." Das Radikal "Wobblies" argumentierte, daß 
Weizenlandwirte Geschäftsmänner in einer geschützten Industrie 
waren, die, dank Support des Kriegregierung Preises, große Profite 
erntete und keine dieser Fülle zu denen zurückbrachten, die wirklich
ihr Getreide ernteten. E. F. Doree, ein IWW Organisator, im 
Detail beschrieben den schwierigen Bedingungwanderern stellte 
gegenüber und verspottete die Idee der landwirtschaftlichen Arbeit, 
wie gesund und wohltätig mit dem berühmten Witz, den in den 
Weizenzuständen, der "Achtstundenarbeit Tag" vorherschte -- "acht 
Stunden im Vormittag, acht Stunden am Nachmittag."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Fermiers en années avant qu'efforts et conflits 
économiques complètement modernes de travail faits face par 
Première Guerre Mondiale à mesure que l'échelle de leurs 
entreprises augmentait. Par la Première Guerre Mondiale, les 
fermiers de plaines du milieu du middle-ouest et grandes étaient 
venus pour compter sur de grands regroupements de main-d'oeuvre 
saisonnière saisonnière, la plupart du temps ouvriers urbains sans 
emploi de Chicago et d'autres villes du milieu du middle-ouest, pour 
moissonner le blé ou le maïs. Les ouvriers ont fait face à de
longues heures et bas à salaires, d'isolement dans les camps 
provisoires sans maisons ou endroits de réunion permanents. Les
ouvriers industriels de l'union du monde (IWW) ont essayé d'organiser
ces derniers les "stiffs de moisson." Le radical "Wobblies" a 
argué du fait que les fermiers de blé étaient des hommes d'affaires
dans une industrie protégée qui, grâce aux soutiens des prix de 
prix de gouvernement de temps de guerre, a récolté de grands 
bénéfices et n'en ont renvoyé aucune de cette richesse à ceux qui 
a moissonné réellement leur collecte. E. F. Doree, un 
organisateur d'IWW, décrit en détail les migrants difficiles de 
conditions a fait face et a raillé à l'idée du travail rural comme 
saine et bienveillante avec la plaisanterie célèbre que dans les 
états de blé, "le jour de huit heures de travail" a régnée -- 
"huit heures dans le matin, huit heures l'après-midi."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fazendeiros nos anos antes que stresses e conflitos
econômicos completamente modernos enfrentados world.war.i do trabalho
como a escala de suas empresas aumentou. Pelo world.war.i, os 
fazendeiros das planícies midwestern e grandes tinham vindo confiar 
em pools grandes do trabalho emigrante seasonal, na maior parte de 
trabalhadores urbanos unemployed de Chicago e de outras cidades 
midwestern, para colher o trigo ou o milho. Os trabalhadores 
enfrentaram horas longas e os salários baixos, isolados em 
acampamentos provisórios sem HOME ou lugares de reunião permanentes.
Os trabalhadores industriais da união do mundo (IWW) tentaram 
organizar estes da "os stiffs colheita." O radical "Wobblies" 
discutiu que os fazendeiros do trigo eram homens de negócios em uma 
indústria protegida que, agradecimentos às sustentações de preço 
do governo do wartime, reaped lucros grandes e não retornavam 
nenhumas dessa riqueza àquelas que colheram realmente sua colheita. 
E. F. Doree, um organizer de IWW, descrito em detalhe os 
emigrantes difíceis das circunstâncias enfrentou e mocked a idéia 
do trabalho rural como wholesome e benevolent com o gracejo famoso que
nos estados do trigo, "o dia eight-hour do trabalho" prevaleceu -- 
"oito horas no forenoon, oito horas na tarde."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Coltivatori durante gli anni prima che sforzi e 
conflitti economici completamente moderni di lavoro affrontati 
world.war.i come la scala delle loro imprese è aumentato. Dal 
world.war.i, i coltivatori delle pianure midwestern e grandi erano 
venuto contare sui grandi stagni del lavoro migratore stagionale,
principalmente sugli operai urbani disoccupati da Chicago e su altre 
città midwestern, raccogliere il frumento o il cereale. Gli 
operai hanno affrontato le ore lunghe e gli stipendi bassi, isolati 
negli accampamenti provvisori senza sedi o punti d'incontro 
permanente. I lavoratori dell'industria dell'unione del mondo 
(IWW) hanno tentato di organizzare questi "gli stiffs della raccolta."
Il radicale "Wobblies" ha sostenuto che i coltivatori del 
frumento erano uomini d'affari in un'industria protetta che, grazie ai
sostegni dei prezzi di governo di wartime, ha raccolto i grandi 
profitti e non ne hanno restituito di quella ricchezza a coloro che 
realmente ha raccolto il loro raccolto. E. F. Doree, un 
organizzatore di IWW, descritto dettagliatamente i migranti difficili 
di circostanze ha affrontato e deriso l'idea di lavoro rurale come 
sano e benevolo con lo scherzo famoso che nel frumento 
dichiara, "il giorno di otto ore del lavoro" è prevalso -- 
"otto ore nella mattina, otto ore nel pomeriggio."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αγρότες στα έτη πριν από τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο 
αντιμετώπισα τις λεπτομερώς σύγχρονες οικονομικές πιέσεις και τις
συγκρούσεις εργασίας καθώς η κλίμακα των επιχειρήσεών τους 
αυξήθηκε. Από τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι, οι midwestern και 
μεγάλοι αγρότες πεδιάδων είχαν έρθει να στηριχθούν στις μεγάλες
ομάδες της εποχιακής αποδημητικής εργασίας, συνήθως άνεργοι 
αστικοί εργαζόμενοι από το Σικάγο και άλλες midwestern 
πόλεις, για να συγκομίσουν το σίτο ή το καλαμπόκι. Οι 
εργαζόμενοι αντιμετώπισαν τις πολλές ώρες και τις χαμηλές 
αμοιβές, που απομονώθηκαν στα προσωρινά στρατόπεδα χωρίς τα 
μόνιμους σπίτια ή χώρους συνάντησης. Οι βιομηχανικοί 
εργάτες της παγκόσμιας (IWW) ένωσης προσπάθησαν να οργανώσουν 
αυτών "συγκομιδή stiffs." Ριζικοί "wobblies" 
υποστήριξαν ότι οι αγρότες σίτου ήταν επιχειρηματίες σε μια 
προστατευμένη βιομηχανία που, χάρι στις εν καιρώ πολέμου 
υποστηρίξεις κυβερνητικών τιμών, συγκέντρωσε τα μεγάλα κέρδη και
δεν επέστρεψε κανενός από εκείνο τον πλούτο σε εκείνοι που 
συγκόμισαν πραγματικά τη συγκομιδή τους. Ε. Φ. Doree, 
ένας διοργανωτής IWW, περιέγραψε λεπτομερώς τους δύσκολους 
μετανάστες όρων που αντιμετωπίστηκαν και που χλευάστηκαν την ιδέα
της αγροτικής εργασίας ως θρεπτικός και γενναιόδωρος με το 
διάσημο αστείο ότι στα κράτη σίτου, η "οκτώ ωρών ημέρα 
εργασίασ" επικράτησε -- "οκτώ ώρες forenoon, οκτώ ώρες το 
απόγευμα."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Granjeros en los años antes de que tensiones y 
conflictos económicos a conciencia modernos hechos frente Primera 
Guerra Mundial del trabajo como la escala de sus empresas aumentó. 
Por Primera Guerra Mundial, los granjeros de los llanos 
midwestern y grandes habían venido confiar en piscinas grandes del 
trabajo migratorio estacional, sobre todo de los trabajadores urbanos 
parados de Chicago y de otras ciudades midwestern, cosechar trigo o 
maíz. Los trabajadores hicieron frente a largases horas y a los
salarios bajos, aislados en campos temporales sin hogares o lugares de
reunión permanentes. Los trabajadores industriales de la unión
del mundo (IWW) procuraron ordenar éstos los "stiffs de la cosecha." 
El radical "Wobblies" discutió que los granjeros del trigo 
fueran hombres de negocios en una industria protegida que, gracias a 
los mantenimientos de precios del gobierno del tiempo de guerra, 
cosechó beneficios grandes y no volvieran ninguna de esa abundancia a
las que cosecharon realmente su cosecha. E. F. Doree, 
organizador de IWW, descrito detalladamente los nómadas difíciles de
las condiciones hizo frente y de imitación a la idea del trabajo 
rural como sana y benévola con la broma famosa que en los estados del
trigo, el "día de ocho horas del trabajo" prevaleció -- "ocho horas 
en la mañana, ocho horas por la tarde."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086115</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105299</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/eight-hours-in-the-forenoon-eight-hours-in-the-afternoon-an-iww-organizer-describes-the-horrors-of-rural-work</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
