<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103674</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103674</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087223</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"What He Has Done Is Sickening to Contemplate": Catholic Liberal John Ryan Denounces Father Charles Coughlin</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"was er getan hat, erwägen" widerlich ist: 
Katholischer Liberaler John Ryan Denunziert Vater Charles 
Coughlin</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"ce qui il a fait est écoeurant contemplent" : 
John Libéral Catholique Ryan Dénonce Le Père Charles 
Coughlin</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"o que fêz é sickening contemplam": John 
Liberal Catholic Ryan Denounces O Pai Charles Coughlin</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"che cosa ha fatto è sickening contemplano": 
John Liberale Cattolico Ryan Denuncia Il Padre Charles Coughlin</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Τι έχει κάνει είναι sickening για να συλλογιστεί":
Καθολικός φιλελεύθερος John Ryan Denounces Father 
Charles Coughlin</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"qué él ha hecho es repugnante comtemplaban": 
Juan Liberal Católico Ryan Denunci A Padre Charles Coughlin</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Father Charles Coughlin attracted an enormous audience for his radio sermons in the 1930s. Although he initially supported President Franklin Roosevelt and the New Deal, his speeches turned increasingly strident, conspiratorial, and anti-Semitic over the course of the decade. After 1936, his talks combined harsh attacks on Roosevelt as the tool of international Jewish bankers with praise for the fascist leaders Mussolini and Hitler. The now bitter and delusional tone of his sermons alienated his larger audience and made many of his fellow Catholics nervous. John Ryan, a Catholic priest himself, had long been active as a social reformer and university educator, and became a vocal critic of Coughlin. Ryan published the following missive in the Catholic journal  Commonweal  in October, 1936.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Vater Charles Coughlin zog ein enormes Publikum 
für seine Radiopredigten in den dreißiger Jahren an. Obgleich 
er zuerst Präsidenten Franklin Roosevelt und das neue Abkommen 
unterstützte, drehten sich seine Reden in zunehmendem Maße 
scharf, conspiratorial, und anti-Semitic über dem Kurs der 
Dekade. Nach 1936 kombinierten seine Gespräche rauhe Angriffe 
auf Roosevelt als das Hilfsmittel der internationalen jüdischen 
Banker mit Lob für die faschistischen Führer Mussolini und Hitler. 
Der jetzt bittere und wahnhafte Ton seiner Predigten entfremdete
seine größeren Publikum und bildete viele von seinen 
Gefährtekatholischen nervös. John Ryan, ein katholischer 
Priester selbst, war lang als SozialReformer und 
Universitätserzieher aktiv gewesen und wurde ein vocal Kritiker von 
Coughlin. Ryan veröffentlichte das folgende Sendschreiben im 
katholischen Journal Commonweal im Oktober, 1936.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le père Charles Coughlin a attiré une énorme 
assistance pour ses sermons par radio dans les années 30. Bien 
qu'il ait au commencement supporté le Président Franklin Roosevelt 
et la nouvelle affaire, ses discours ont tourné de plus en plus 
strident, mystérieux, et anti-sémitique en décennie. Après 
1936, ses entretiens ont combiné des attaques dures sur Roosevelt 
comme outil des banquiers juifs internationaux avec l'éloge pour les 
Chefs fascistes Mussolini et Hitler. La tonalité maintenant 
amère et illusoire de ses sermons a aliéné ses plus grandes 
assistances et a rendu beaucoup de ses catholiques de camarade 
nerveux. John Ryan, un prêtre catholique lui-même, avait 
longtemps été en activité en tant qu'un réformateur et éducateur 
sociaux d'université, et est devenu un critique vocal de Coughlin. 
Ryan a édité le missive suivant dans le bien de tous 
catholique de journal en octobre, 1936.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O pai Charles Coughlin atraiu uma audiência 
enorme para seus sermons de rádio nos 1930s. Embora suportasse 
inicialmente o presidente Franklin Roosevelt e o negócio novo, seus 
discursos giraram cada vez mais strident, conspiratorial, e 
anti-Semitic sobre o curso da década. Após 1936, suas 
conversas combinaram ataques ásperos em Roosevelt como a ferramenta 
de banqueiros jewish internacionais com o elogio para os líderes 
fascist Mussolini e Hitler. O tom agora amargo e delusional de 
seus sermons alienated suas audiências maiores e fêz muitos de seus 
catholics do companheiro nervosos. John Ryan, um priest catholic
ele mesmo, tinha sido por muito tempo ativo como um educador social do
reformer e da universidade, e transformou-se um crítico vocal de 
Coughlin. Ryan publicou o seguinte missive no commonweal 
catholic do jornal em outubro, 1936.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il padre Charles Coughlin ha attratto un pubblico 
enorme per i suoi sermons radiofonici nei 1930s. Anche se 
inizialmente ha sostenuto il presidente Franklin Roosevelt ed il nuovo
affare, i suoi discorsi hanno girato sempre più strident, 
conspiratorial ed anti-Semitic durante la decade. Dopo 1936, i 
suoi colloqui hanno unito gli attacchi duri a Roosevelt come lo 
strumento dei banchieri ebrei internazionali con elogio per i 
capi fascisti Mussolini e Hitler. Il tono ora amaro e 
delusional dei suoi sermons ha allontanato suoi di vasto pubblico ed 
ha reso molti dei suoi cattolici del collega nervosi. John Ryan,
un priest cattolico egli stesso, lungamente era stato attivo come 
educatore sociale dell'università e del reformer ed è diventato un 
critico vocale di Coughlin. Ryan ha pubblicato il seguente 
missive nel commonweal cattolico del giornale in ottobre, del 1936.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο πατέρας Charles Coughlin προσέλκυσε ένα 
τεράστιο ακροατήριο για τα ραδιο κηρύγματά του στη δεκαετία του 
'30. Αν και υποστήριξε αρχικά τον Πρόεδρο Franklin 
Roosevelt και τη νέα διαπραγμάτευση, οι ομιλίες του έγιναν όλο
και περισσότερο τραχιές, συνωμοτικές, και αντισημιτικές 
κατά τη διάρκεια της δεκαετίας. Μετά από το 1936, οι 
συζητήσεις του συνδύασαν τις σκληρές επιθέσεις σε Roosevelt ως 
εργαλείο των διεθνών εβραϊκών τραπεζιτών με τον έπαινο για τους 
φασιστικούς ηγέτες mussolini και hitler. Ο τώρα πικρός
και απατηλός τόνος των κηρυγμάτων του αλλοτρίωσε το μεγαλύτερο 
ακροατήριό του και κατέστησε πολλών από τους συντροφικούς 
Καθολικούς του νευρικών. Θ*Ιοχν Ryan, ένας καθολικός 
ιερέας ο ίδιος, ήταν από καιρό ενεργός ως κοινωνικό 
μεταρρυθμιστή και πανεπιστημιακό εκπαιδευτικό, και έγινε 
φωνητικός κριτικός Coughlin. Το Ryan δημοσίευσε 
ακόλουθο τον missive στο καθολικό περιοδικό Commonweal τον 
Οκτώβριο, του 1936.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El padre Charles Coughlin atrajo a audiencia 
enorme para sus sermones de radio en los años 30. Aunque él 
apoyó inicialmente a presidente Franklin Roosevelt y el nuevo 
reparto, sus discursos dieron vuelta cada vez más estridente, 
conspiratorial, y anti-Semitic sobre el curso de la década. 
Después de 1936, sus negociaciones combinaron ataques ásperos 
contra Roosevelt como la herramienta de banqueros judíos 
internacionales con la alabanza para los arranques de cinta fascistas 
Mussolini e Hitler. El tono ahora amargo y delusional de sus 
sermones enajenó a su público más mucho e hizo a muchos de sus 
católicos del compañero nerviosos. Juan Ryan, sacerdote 
católico mismo, había sido de largo activo como un reformador y 
educador sociales de la universidad, e hizo crítico vocal de 
Coughlin. Ryan publicó el missive siguiente en el commonweal 
católico del diario en octubre de 1936.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087223</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103674</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/what-he-has-done-is-sickening-to-contemplate-catholic-liberal-john-ryan-denounces-father-charles-coughlin</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
