<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105003</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105003</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087337</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A Shoemaker and the Tea Party</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Schuster und die Tee-Partei</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un cordonnier et la partie de thé</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um shoemaker e o partido do chá</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un calzolaio ed il partito del tè</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένας υποδηματοποιός και το συμβαλλόμενο μέρος τσαγιού</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un zapatero y el partido del té</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">George Robert Twelve Hewes, a Boston shoemaker, participated in many of the key events of the Revolutionary crisis. Over half a century later, Hewes described his experiences to James Hawkes. When Parliament passed the Tea Act in 1773, colonists refused to allow cargoes of tea to be unloaded. In the evening of December 16, with Hewes leading one group, the colonists dressed in "the costume of a Indian." They boarded the ships in Boston harbor and dropped the tea overboard. Hewes' account shed light on how resistance became revolution. The"Boston Tea Party," as it became known in the 19th century, became a powerful symbol of the Revolution. And Hewes, artisan and ordinary citizen, was celebrated as a venerable veteran of the struggle for Independence.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">George Robert zwölf Hewes, ein Boston Schuster, 
teilgenommen an vielen der Schlüsselfälle der revolutionären Krise.
Über Hälfte ein Jahrhundert später, beschrieb Hewes seine 
Erfahrungen zu James Hawkes. Als Parlament die Tee-Tat 1773 
führte, lehnten Kolonisten ab zu erlauben, daß Ladungen des Tees aus
dem Programm genommen werden. Am Abend von Dezember 16, wenn 
Hewes eine Gruppe führt, kleideten die Kolonisten "im Kostüm eines 
Inders." an Sie verschalten die Schiffe im Boston Hafen und 
ließen den Tee über Bord fallen. Konto-Hallelicht Hewes' auf, 
wie Widerstand Umdrehung wurde. The"Boston Tee-Partei,",
während sie im 19. Jahrhundert bekannt wurde, wurde ein 
leistungsfähiges Symbol der Umdrehung. Und Hewes, Handwerker 
und gewöhnlicher Bürger, wurden als venerable Veteran des Kampfes 
für Unabhängigkeit gefeiert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">George Robert douze Hewes, un cordonnier de 
Boston, participé à plusieurs des événements principaux de la 
crise révolutionnaire. Plus de la moitié par siècle plus 
tard, Hewes a décrit ses expériences à James Hawkes. 
Quand le Parlement a passé la Loi de thé en 1773, des colons 
ont refusé de permettre à des cargaisons de thé d'être 
déchargés. En soirée décembre de 16, avec Hewes menant un 
groupe, les colons se sont habillés dans "le costume d'un Indien." 
Ils ont monté à bord des bateaux dans le port de Boston et ont
relâché le thé par dessus bord. Lumière de hangar du compte 
de Hewes sur la façon dont la résistance est devenue révolution. 
La partie de thé de The"Boston," pendant qu'elle devenait 
notoire au 19ème siècle, est devenue un symbole puissant de la 
révolution. Et Hewes, artisan et citoyen ordinaire, ont été 
célébrés en tant que vétéran vénérable de la lutte pour 
l'indépendance.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">George Robert doze Hewes, um shoemaker de Boston, 
participado em muitos dos eventos chaves da crise revolucionária. 
Sobre a metade um do século mais tarde, Hewes descreveu suas 
experiências a James Hawkes. Quando o parliament passou o ato 
do chá em 1773, os colonos recusaram permitir que as cargas do chá 
sejam descarregadas. Na noite dezembro de 16, com o Hewes que 
conduz a um grupo, os colonos vestiram-se "no traje de um indian." 
Boarded os navios no porto de Boston e deixaram cair o chá ao 
mar. Luz da vertente do cliente de Hewes' em como a resistência
se transformou volta. O partido do chá de The"Boston," enquanto
se tornou sabido no 1ø século, transformou-se um símbolo poderoso 
da volta. E Hewes, o artisan e o cidadão ordinário, foram 
comemorados como um veteran venerable do esforço para a 
independência.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">George Robert dodici Hewes, un calzolaio de 
Boston, partecipato a molti degli eventi chiave della crisi 
rivoluzionaria. Più della metà un di secolo più 
successivamente, Hewes ha descritto le sue esperienze a James Hawkes. 
Quando il Parlamento ha passato la Legge del tè in 1773, i 
colonizzatori hanno rifiutato di permettere che i carichi di tè siano
scaricati. Nella sera del 16 dicembre, con Hewes che conduce un 
gruppo, i colonizzatori si sono vestiti "nel costume di un indiano." 
Si sono imbarcati sulle navi nel porto de Boston ed hanno caduto
il tè fuori bordo. Luce della tettoia di cliente del Hewes su 
come la resistenza si è transformata in in giro. Il partito del
tè di The"Boston," mentre è stato conosciuto nel diciannovesimo 
secolo, si è transformato in in un simbolo potente della rivoluzione.
E Hewes, l'artigianale ed il cittadino ordinario, sono stati 
celebrati come veterano venerable della lotta per indipendenza.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θ*Γεοργε Robert δώδεκα Hewes, ένας υποδηματοποιός
της Βοστώνης, συμμετείχε σε πολλά από τα βασικά γεγονότα της 
επαναστατικής κρίσης. Κατά τη διάρκεια μισού αιώνα 
αργότερα, Hewes περιέγραψε την εμπειρία του james Hawkes. 
Όταν το Κοινοβούλιο πέρασε το νόμο τσαγιού το 1773, οι 
άποικοι αρνήθηκαν να επιτρέψουν στα φορτία του τσαγιού για να 
ξεφορτωθούν. το βράδυ της 16ης Δεκεμβρίου, με Hewes που 
οδηγεί μια ομάδα, οι άποικοι έντυσαν "στο κοστούμι ενός Ινδού."
Επιβιβάστηκαν στα σκάφη στο λιμάνι της Βοστώνης και έριξαν 
το τσάι overboard. Ο απολογισμός των Hewes έριξε το φως
στον τρόπο με τον οποίο η αντίσταση έγινε επανάσταση. The"Boston το συμβαλλόμενο μέρος τσαγιού," καθώς έγινε γνωστό
στο 19$ο αιώνα, έγινε ένα ισχυρό σύμβολο της επανάστασης. 
Και Hewes, χειροτεχνικός και απλός πολίτης, γιορτάστηκε 
ως σεβάσμιος παλαίμαχος της προσπάθειας για την ανεξαρτησία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">George Roberto doce Hewes, zapatero de Boston, 
participado en muchos de los acontecimientos dominantes de la crisis 
revolucionaria. Sobre mitad del siglo más adelante, Hewes 
describió sus experiencias a James Hawkes. Cuando el parlamento
pasó el acto del té en 1773, los colonos rechazaron permitir que los
cargos del té sean descargados. Por la tarde del de diciembre 
16, con Hewes conduciendo a un grupo, los colonos vistieron en "el 
traje de un indio." Subieron a las naves en el puerto de Boston 
y cayeron el té al agua. Luz de la vertiente de la cuenta de 
Hewes en cómo la resistencia se convirtió en revolución. El 
partido del té de The"Boston," como se sabía en el diecinueveavo 
siglo, se convirtió en un símbolo de gran alcance de la revolución.
Y celebraron Hewes, al artesano y al ciudadano ordinario, como 
veterano venerable de la lucha para la independencia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087337</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105003</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-shoemaker-and-the-tea-party</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
