<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104487</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104487</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201644</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Extreme 2002: Mission to the Abyss</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Übermaß 2002: Mission zum Abgrund</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Extrémité 2002 : Mission à l'abîme</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Extremo 2002: Missão ao abyss</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Estremo 2002: Missione al abyss</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ακρο 2002: Αποστολή στην άβυσσο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Extremo 2002: Misión en el abismo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This is the expedition page of the 2002 Mission to the Abyss. Developed by the University of Delaware Graduate College of Marine Studies, the site highlights the mission and crew, seafloor geology, creature features, and high-tech tools used in the study. This interactive website allows students to explore the submersible Alvin, find out how hydrothermal vents form, define the deep ocean, study plate tectonics, and meet hydrothermal vent organisms. The site includes extreme experiments, including: compression of a fluid vs. a gas, rising under pressure, my cup shrinks, soda squeeze, and plant pressure.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses ist die Expeditionseite der Mission 2002 
zum Abgrund. Sich entwickelt durch die Universität Delaware der
graduierten Hochschule der Marine-Studien, markiert die Site die 
Mission und die Mannschaft, seafloor Geologie, Geschöpfmerkmale und 
die high-tech Hilfsmittel, die in der Studie benutzt werden. 
Diese interaktive Web site erlaubt Kursteilnehmern, den 
Submersible Alvin zu erforschen, finden heraus, wie hydrothermale 
Entlüftungsöffnungen sich bilden, definieren den tiefen Ozean, 
studieren Plattentektonik und treffen hydrothermale 
Entlüftungsöffnung organismen. Die Site schließt die extremen
Experimente ein und schließt ein: die Komprimierung einer 
Flüssigkeit gegen ein Gas, steigend unter Druck, mein Cup schrumpft, 
Sodapressung und Betriebsdruck.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">C'est la page d'expédition de la mission 2002 à 
l'abîme. Développé par l'université de l'université 
graduée du Delaware des études de soldat de marine, le site met en 
valeur la mission et sert d'équipier, géologie de seafloor, 
dispositifs de créature, et outils de pointe utilisés dans l'étude.
Ce site Web interactif permet à des étudiants d'explorer le 
sous-marin Alvin, trouvent dehors comment les évents hydrothermiques 
forment, définissent l'océan profond, étudient la tectonique de 
plat, et rencontrent les organizations hydrothermiques d'évent. 
Le site inclut des expériences extrêmes, incluant : le 
compactage d'un fluide contre un gaz, montant sous pression, ma tasse 
se rétrécit, compression de soude, et pression d'usine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta é a página da expedição da missão 2002 
ao abyss. Tornado pela universidade da faculdade graduada de 
Delaware de estudos do fuzileiro naval, o local destaca a missão e o 
grupo, geologia do seafloor, características da criatura, e as 
ferramentas high-tech usadas no estudo. Este Web site interativo
permite que os estudantes explorem o submarino Alvin, encontra para 
fora como os respiradouros hydrothermal dão forma, define o oceano 
profundo, estuda o tectonics de placa, e encontra-se com organismos 
hydrothermal do respiradouro. O local inclui as experiências 
extremas, incluindo: a compressão de um líquido contra um 
gás, levantando-se sob a pressão, meu copo encolhe, aperto da soda, 
e pressão da planta.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ciò è la pagina di spedizione della missione 
2002 al abyss. Sviluppato dall'università di università 
laureata del Delaware degli studi del fante di marina, il luogo 
evidenzia la missione e la squadra, la geologia di seafloor, 
caratteristiche della creatura e strumenti high-tech utilizzati nello 
studio. Questo Web site interattivo permette che gli allievi 
esplorino il sommergibile Alvin, trova fuori come gli sfiati 
idrotermali formano, definisce l'oceano profondo, studia la tettonica 
di piastra e viene a contatto degli organismi idrotermali dello 
sfiato. Il luogo include gli esperimenti estremi, includenti: 
la compressione di un liquido contro un gas, aumentante sotto 
pressione, la mia tazza ristringe, compressione della soda e pressione
della pianta.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό είναι η σελίδα αποστολής της αποστολής του 
2002 στην άβυσσο. Αναπτυγμένη από το πανεπιστήμιο του 
διαβαθμισμένου κολλεγίου του Delaware των θαλασσίων μελετών, η 
περιοχή δίνει έμφαση στην αποστολή και το πλήρωμα, τη γεωλογία 
θαλάσσιου πυθμένα, τα χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα πλασμάτων, και τα
εργαλεία υψηλής τεχνολογίας που χρησιμοποιούνται στη μελέτη. 
Αυτός ο διαλογικός ιστοχώρος επιτρέπει στους σπουδαστές για
να εξερευνήσει το υποβρύχιο Alvin, να ανακαλύψει πώς η μορφή 
υδροθερμικών διεξόδων, καθορίζει το βαθύ ωκεανό, τεκτονική 
πιάτων μελέτης, και συναντά τους οργανισμούς υδροθερμικών 
διεξόδων. Η περιοχή περιλαμβάνει τα ακραία πειράματα, που 
περιλαμβάνουν: η συμπίεση ενός ρευστού εναντίον αέριο,
που αυξάνεται διά πίεση, το φλυτζάνι μου στενεύει, συμπίεση 
σόδας, και πίεση εγκαταστάσεων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ésta es la paginación de la expedición de la 
misión 2002 al abismo. Convertido por la universidad de la 
universidad graduada de Delaware de los estudios del infante de 
marina, el sitio destaca la misión y el equipo, geología del 
seafloor, las características de la criatura, y las herramientas de 
alta tecnología usadas en el estudio. Este Web site interactivo
permite que los estudiantes exploren el sumergible Alvin, encuentra 
hacia fuera cómo los respiraderos hidrotérmicos forman, define el 
océano profundo, estudia la tectónica de placa, y resuelve 
organismos hidrotérmicos del respiradero. El sitio incluye los 
experimentos extremos, incluyendo: la compresión de un líquido
contra un gas, levantándose bajo presión, mi taza se contrae, 
apretón de la soda, y presión de la planta.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:UNIVERSITY OF DELAWARE GRADUATE COLLEGE OF MARINE STUDIES
FN:UNIVERSITY OF DELAWARE GRADUATE COLLEGE OF MARINE STUDIES
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201644</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104487</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/extreme-2002-mission-to-the-abyss</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
