<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106461</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106461</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209862</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Diameter of a circle </string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Durchmesser eines Kreises</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Diamètre d'un cercle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Diâmetro de um círculo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Diametro di un cerchio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διάμετρος ενός κύκλου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Diámetro de un círculo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate the diameter of a circle. The applet shows a circle and a diameter line, the ends of which can be dragged to show that the diameter passes through the center and has a constant length regardless of where on the circle it is drawn. The web page has the circle-related formulae. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die den Durchmesser eines Kreises zeigen. Der applet 
zeigt einen Kreis und eine Durchmesserzeile, dessen Enden geschleppt 
werden können, um zu zeigen, daß der Durchmesser durch die Mitte 
überschreitet und eine konstante Länge hat unabhängig davon, der 
auf dem Kreis er gezeichnet wird. Die Webseite hat die Kreis-in 
Verbindung stehenden Formeln. Applet kann zum vollen Bildumfang 
für Gebrauch mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. 
Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von 
jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den 
benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein 
Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven 
Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent le diamètre d'un cercle. L'applet montre un 
cercle et une ligne de diamètre, dont les extrémités peuvent être 
traînées pour prouver que le diamètre traverse le centre et a une 
longueur constante indépendamment d'où sur le cercle il est 
dessiné. La page Web a les formules cercle-connexes. 
L'applet peut être agrandi à la taille de plein écran pour 
l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de classe. Le après 
utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant peut lui accéder 
encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la maison ou dans la 
bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion exigée. Cette 
ressource est un composant du projet interactif de manuel de la 
géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem o diâmetro de um círculo. O applet mostra um 
círculo e uma linha do diâmetro, as extremidades de que podem ser 
arrastadas para mostrar que o diâmetro passa através do centro e tem
um comprimento constante não obstante onde no círculo seja 
desenhado. O Web page tem as fórmulas círculo-relacionadas. 
O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de tela cheia para o uso 
com um projetor da sala de aula. O depois de uso na sala de 
aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo o web browser na 
HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma sessão requerido. 
Este recurso é um componente do projeto interativo do textbook 
da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano il diametro di un cerchio. Il applet mostra un 
cerchio e una riga del diametro, le estremità di cui possono essere 
trascinate per indicare che il diametro attraversa il centro ed ha una
lunghezza costante senza riguardo a dove sul cerchio è dissipato. 
Il Web page ha le formule cerchio-relative. Il applet può
essere ingrandito al formato di schermo pieno per uso con un 
proiettore dell'aula. La post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo 
può accederle ancora da tutto il web browser nel paese o nella 
libreria senza l'inizio attività richiesto. Questa risorsa è 
un componente del progetto interattivo del manuale della geometria di 
riferimento aperto di per la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν τη διάμετρο ενός κύκλου. Το applet 
εμφανίζει έναν κύκλο και γραμμή διαμέτρων, οι άκρες των οποίων 
μπορούν να σέρθούν για να δείξουν ότι η διάμετρος περνά μέσω 
του κέντρου και έχει ένα σταθερό μήκος ανεξάρτητα από όπου 
στον κύκλο σύρεται. Ιστοσελίδας έχει τους κύκλος-σχετικούς
με τον τύπους. Το Applet μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες 
μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με έναν προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά
από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε
τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη 
βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το
στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού 
προγράμματος εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού 
σε http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran el diámetro de un círculo. El applet muestra un 
círculo y una línea del diámetro, los extremos de los cuales se 
pueden arrastrar para mostrar que el diámetro pasa a través del 
centro y tiene una longitud constante sin importar donde en el 
círculo se traza. El Web page tiene los fórmulas 
ci'rculo-relacionados. El applet se puede agrandar a la talla de
la pantalla completa para el uso con un proyector de la sala de clase.
El uso posterior en la sala de clase, estudiante puede tenerle 
acceso otra vez de cualquier web browser en el país o en la 
biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. Este recurso es un 
componente del proyecto interactivo del libro de textos de la 
geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas en 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209862</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106461</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/diameter-of-a-circle</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
