<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108068</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108068</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087281</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A Clear and Present Danger: The Chinese Exclusion Act</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine freie und anwesende Gefahr: Die 
Chinesische Ausschluss-Tat</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un danger clair et actuel : La Loi Chinoise 
d'Exclusion</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um perigo desobstruído e atual: O Ato 
Chinês Da Exclusão</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un pericolo libero ed attuale: La Legge 
Cinese Di Esclusione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένας σαφής και παρών κίνδυνος: Ο κινεζικός 
νόμος αποκλεισμού</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un peligro claro y actual: El Acto Chino De 
la Exclusión</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The San Francisco Building Trades Council (BTC), organized in 1898, actively participated in the anti-Asian agitation that characterized California politics, particularly labor politics, in the late-19th century. The BTC, like the national American Federation of Labor (AFL), argued that the very presence of Chinese (and, after 1900, Japanese and Korean immigrants as well) dragged down the living standards of white workers. The following excerpt is from a 1902 AFL pamphlet entitled  Some Reasons for Chinese Exclusion: Meat vs. Rice , which called for a second extension of the 1882 Chinese Exclusion Act. Despite the pamphlet's disclaimer that it was not prejudiced, arguments were riddled with racist statements about the employment history and "Social Habits" of "John Chinaman." The selections from the pamphlet reprinted here reflected the abiding beliefs of many white workers, especially skilled workers who belonged to the San Francisco BTC.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der San Francisco Baugewerbe-Rat (BTC), 
organisiert 1898, aktiv teilgenommen an der Anti-Asiatischen Bewegung,
die Kalifornien Politik kennzeichnete, besonders Arbeitspolitik, im 
des späten 19. jahrhunderts Jahrhundert. Das BTC, wie die 
nationale amerikanische Vereinigung der Arbeit (AFL), argumentierte, 
daß die Anwesenheit des Chinesen (und, nach 1900, japanischer und 
koreanischer Immigranten außerdem) hinunter die lebenden Standards 
der weißen Arbeiter schleppte. Das folgende Excerpt ist von 
einer 1902 AFL Flugschrift, die etwas Gründe für chinesischen 
Ausschluß erlaubt wird: Fleisch gegen Reis, den eine zweite 
Extension der der 1882 Chinese-Ausschluss-Tat trotz des Verzichts der 
Flugschrift verlangte, daß er nicht benachteiligt wurde, Argumente 
wurde enträtselt mit rassistischen Anweisungen über die 
Beschäftigunggeschichte und "die Sozialgewohnheiten" von "John 
Chinaman." Die Anwählungen von der Flugschrift, die hier 
neugedruckt wurde, reflektierten den bleibenden Glauben vieler weißer
Arbeiter, besonders erfahrene Arbeiter, die nach das San Francisco BTC
gehörten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Conseil de industries du bâtiment de San 
Francisco (BTC), organisé en 1898, activement participé à 
l'agitation anti-Asiatique qui a caractérisé la politique de la 
Californie, en particulier la politique de travail, en fin du 19me 
siècle. Le BTC, comme la fédération américaine nationale du 
travail (AFL), a argué du fait que la présence même du Chinois (et,
après de 1900, japonais et coréens immigrés aussi bien) a traîné 
en bas des normes vivantes des ouvriers blancs. L'extrait 
suivant est d'une brochure de 1902 AFL autorisée quelques raisons 
d'exclusion chinoise : Viande contre le riz, qui a nécessité 
une deuxième extension de la Loi d'exclusion de 1882 Chinois. 
En dépit du déni de la brochure qu'il n'a pas été compromis,
des arguments ont été résolus avec des rapports racistes au sujet 
de l'histoire d'emploi et "des habitudes sociales" du "Chinois de 
John." Les sélections à partir de la brochure réimprimée ici
ont reflété la croyance demeurante de beaucoup d'ouvriers blancs, 
particulièrement les ouvriers habiles qui ont appartenu au San 
Francisco BTC.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O conselho dos comércios de edifício do San 
Francisco (BTC), organizado em 1898, participado ativamente no 
agitation anti-anti-Asian que caracterizou a política de Califórnia,
particularmente política labor, no século late-19th. O BTC, 
como o federation americano nacional do trabalho (AFL), discutiu que a
presença very do chinês (e, após de 1900, immigrants japoneses e 
korean também) arrastou abaixo os padrões vivos dos trabalhadores 
brancos. O seguinte excerpt é de um panfleto de 1902 AFL 
intitulado algumas razões para a exclusão chinesa: A carne 
contra o arroz, que se chamou para uma segunda extensão do ato da 
exclusão de 1882 chineses apesar do disclaimer do panfleto que não 
estêve prejudicado, argumentos riddled com indicações racist sobre 
o history de emprego e "os hábitos sociais" de "do chinaman John." 
As seleções do panfleto reprinted aqui refletiram a opinião 
abiding de muitos trabalhadores brancos, especial os trabalhadores 
hábeis que pertenceram ao San Francisco BTC.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Consiglio di commerci edificio de San Francisco 
(BTC), organizzato in 1898, attivamente partecipato all'agitazione 
anti-Asiatica che ha caratterizzato la politica della California, 
specialmente politica di lavoro, nel fine del 19esimo secolo. 
Il BTC, come la federazione americana nazionale del Lavoro
(AFL), ha sostenuto che la presenza stessa del cinese (e, dopo 
di 1900, immigranti giapponesi e coreani pure) si è trascinata giù 
gli standard viventi degli operai bianchi. Il seguente brano 
proviene da un opuscolo di 1902 AFL intitolato alcuni motivi per 
l'esclusione cinese: La carne contro riso, che ha richiesto
una seconda estensione delle 1882 Leggi cinesi di esclusione 
malgrado il diniego dell'opuscolo che non è stato pregiudicato, 
argomenti riddled con le istruzione razziste circa il curriculum 
professionale e "le abitudini sociali" "del chinaman del John." 
Le selezioni dall'opuscolo ristampato qui hanno riflesso la 
credenza rimanente di molti operai bianchi, particolarmente in operai 
esperti che hanno appartenuto a San Francisco BTC.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το εμπορικό Συμβούλιο κτηρίου του Σαν Φρανσίσκο 
(BTC), που οργανώθηκε το 1898, συμμετείχε ενεργά στην 
αντι-ασιατική αναταραχή που χαρακτήρισε την πολιτική Καλιφόρνιας,
ιδιαίτερα πολιτική εργασίας, στο late-19th αιώνα. Το 
BTC, όπως την εθνική αμερικανική ομοσπονδία της εργασίας 
(AFL), υποστήριξε ότι η ίδια η παρουσία των κινέζικων (και, 
μετά από το 1900, ιαπωνικών και κορεατικών μεταναστών επίσης)
που σέρθηκαν κάτω από το βιοτικό επίπεδο των λευκών 
εργαζομένων. Το ακόλουθο απόσπασμα είναι από ένα τεύχος 
AFL του 1902 που τιτλοφορείται μερικοί λόγοι για τον 
κινεζικό αποκλεισμό: Κρέας εναντίον του ρυζιού, το οποίο 
απαίτησε μια δεύτερη επέκταση του κινεζικού νόμου αποκλεισμού 
1882. Παρά την αποκήρυξη του τεύχους ότι δεν ήταν 
προκατειλημμένο, τα ορίσματα διατρυπήθηκαν με τις ρατσιστικές 
δηλώσεις για την ιστορία απασχόλησης και τις "κοινωνικές 
συνήθειεσ" "John Chinaman." Οι επιλογές από το τεύχος 
που ανατυπώθηκε εδώ απεικόνισαν τις τηρώντας πεποιθήσεις πολλών 
λευκών εργαζομένων, ειδικά ειδικευμένοι εργαζόμενοι που άνηκαν 
στο Σαν Φρανσίσκο BTC.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El consejo de los comercios de edificio de San 
Francisco (BTC), ordenado en 1898, participado activamente en la 
agitación contra-Asia'tica que caracterizó la política de 
California, determinado política de trabajo, en el siglo de fines del
siglo diecinueve. El BTC, como la federación americana nacional
del trabajo (AFL), discutió que la misma presencia del chino (y, 
después de 1900, japoneses y coreanos inmigrantes también) 
arrastrara abajo de los estándares vivos de los trabajadores blancos.
El extracto siguiente es de un folleto de 1902 AFL titulado 
algunas razones de la exclusión china: La carne contra el 
arroz, que llamó para una segunda extensión del acto de la 
exclusión de 1882 chinos a pesar de la negación del folleto que no 
fue perjudicado, los argumentos fue acribillada con declaraciones 
racist sobre la historia de empleo y los "hábitos sociales" del 
"chinaman de Juan." Las selecciones del folleto reimpreso aquí 
reflejaron la creencia que habitaba de muchos trabajadores blancos, 
especialmente los trabajadores expertos que pertenecieron al San 
Francisco BTC.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087281</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108068</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-clear-and-present-danger-the-chinese-exclusion-act</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
