<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105571</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105571</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085256</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The 442nd Regimental Combat Team</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das 442. Regimentskampf-Team</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La 442nd Équipe Régimentaire de Combat</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A 442nd Equipe Regimental Do Combate</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La 442nd Squadra Regimental Di Combattimento</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η 442nd συνταγματική ομάδα αγώνα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El 44ò Equipo Regimental Del Combate</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Several special fighting forces from the United States, made up of single ethnic groups, made significant contributions during World War II, including the African American Tuskegee Airmen and the Navajo Code Talkers. The 442nd Regimental Combat Team was made up solely of Japanese Americans, some of whom were recruited directly from internment camps. (Some Japanese American men who would later become leaders, such as Senator Daniel Inouye, were members of the 442nd.) The images in this group provide a look at the lives and sacrifices of the men of the 442nd, the most highly decorated American unit in WWII. The photographs in this group were all taken for the government-run War Relocation Authority (WRA) and are meant to portray the proud patriotism of the men and their families. One photo shows three women holding their babies, with photographs of their enlisted husbands. Another is a portrait of an older couple who had five sons in the 442nd. Other photographs reflect the training the soldiers of the 442nd received, their life in the battlefield, and their triumphant homecoming. Other documents in this group show a more personal side of the men of the 442nd. One soldier's photo album depicts his personal experiences as a member of the combat team. A 50-page booklet, The Story of the 442nd Combat Team, compiled by members of the team, has this quote from Franklin D. Roosevelt on the dedication page: "Americanism is a matter of the mind and heart; Americanism is not and never was a matter of race and ancestry." On a more poignant note, oil paintings by Japanese American artist Henry Sugimoto reflect the emotions, pain, and suffering these individuals and their families experienced as a result of the war. In Senninbari (Thousand Stiches), a woman holds a scarf of remembrance as a ghostly Nisei soldier looks down from the sky. And in Send Off Husband at Jerome Camp, an internee family stays behind the camp gates as their soldier father/husband goes off to fight for the United States.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Einige spezielle kämpfende Kräfte von den 
Vereinigten Staaten, gebildet von den einzelnen ethnischen Gruppen, 
bildeten bedeutende Beiträge während des Zweiten Weltkrieges, 
einschließlich die afrikanischen amerikanischen Tuskegee Flieger und 
die Navajo-Codetalkers. Das 442. Regimentskampf-Team wurde nur 
von den japanischen Amerikanern, einiger von gebildet, wurden wem 
direkt von den Internierunglagern eingezogen. (einige japanische
amerikanische Männer, die später Führer, wie Senator Daniel Inouye 
werden würden, waren Bauteile vom 442..) Die Bilder in dieser 
Gruppe stellen einen Blick an den Leben und an den Opfern der Männer 
vom 442., die in hohem Grade verzierte amerikanische Maßeinheit in 
WWII zur Verfügung. Alle Fotographien in dieser Gruppe wurden 
für die Regierung Durchlauf Krieg-Verschiebung Berechtigung (WRA) 
genommen und werden bedeutet, um den stolzen Patriotismus der Männer 
und ihrer Familien zu schildern. Ein Foto zeigt drei Frauen, die
ihre Babys, mit Fotographien ihrer eingetragenen Ehemänner anhalten. 
Anders ist ein Portrait eines älteren Paares, das fünf Söhne 
im 442nd. andere Fotographien das Training reflektieren ließ die 
Soldaten von 442. empfangen, ihrer Lebensdauer im Schlachtfeld und 
ihres triumphierenden Homecomings. Andere Dokumente in dieser 
Gruppe zeigen eine persönlichere Seite der Männer vom 442.. 
Ein Fotoalbum des Soldaten stellt seine persönlichen 
Erfahrungen als Bauteil des Kampfteams bildlich dar. Eine 
50-page Broschüre, die Geschichte des 442. Kampf-Teams, kompiliert 
von den Bauteilen des Teams, hat diesen Anführungsstrich von Franklin
D. Roosevelt auf der Widmung Seite: "Amerikanismus ist ein Stoff
des Verstandes und des Inneren; Amerikanismus ist nicht und war 
nie ein Stoff des Rennens und des Geschlechtes." Auf einer 
poignant Anmerkung reflektieren Ölanstriche durch Japanese American 
Künstler Henry Sugimoto die Gefühle, die Schmerz und das Erleiden 
dieser Einzelpersonen und ihrer Familien, die resultierend aus dem 
Krieg erfahren werden. In Senninbari (tausend Stiches), hält 
eine Frau einen Schal der Erinnerung, während ein gespenstischer 
Nisei Soldat unten vom Himmel schaut und innen weg vom Ehemann am 
Jerome Lager sendet, einen Internee an, den Familie hinter den 
Lagergattern bleibt, während ihr Soldat father/husband ausgeht, für 
die Vereinigten Staaten zu kämpfen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Plusieurs forces de combat spéciales des 
Etats-Unis, composés de seuls groupes ethniques, ont apporté des 
contributions significatives pendant la deuxième guerre mondiale, y 
compris les aviateurs américains africains de Tuskegee et les 
causeurs de code de Navajo. La 442nd équipe régimentaire de 
combat s'est composée seulement des Américains japonais, une partie 
de qui ont été recrutés directement des camps d'internement. 
(quelques hommes américains japonais qui deviendraient plus 
tard des amorces, telles que le sénateur Daniel Inouye, étaient des 
membres du 442nd.) Les images dans ce groupe fournissent un 
regard aux vies et aux sacrifices des hommes du 442nd, l'unité 
américaine le plus fortement décorée dans WWII. Toutes les 
photographies dans ce groupe ont été prises pour l'autorité de 
réadressage de guerre de passage de gouvernement (WRA) et sont 
censées pour dépeindre le patriotisme fier des hommes et de leurs 
familles. Une photo montre trois femmes tenant leurs bébés, 
avec des photographies de leurs maris enrôlés. Une autre est 
une verticale d'un couple plus ancien qui a eu cinq fils dans le 
442nd. D'autres photographies reflètent la formation les 
soldats de la 442nd reçue, leur vie dans le champ de bataille, et 
leur homecoming triomphant. D'autres documents dans ce groupe 
montrent un côté plus personnel des hommes du 442nd. Un album 
photos du soldat dépeint ses expériences personnelles en tant que 
membre de l'équipe de combat. 50-page un livret, l'histoire de 
la 442nd équipe de combat, compilée par des membres de l'équipe, a 
ces guillemet de Franklin D. Roosevelt à la page d'attachement : 
l'"Américanisme est une question de l'esprit et du coeur ; 
l'Américanisme n'est pas et n'était jamais une question de 
course et d'ascendance." Sur une note plus intense, les 
peintures à l'huile par Henry Sugimoto d'artiste de Japanese American
réfléchissent les émotions, la douleur, et souffrir ces individus 
et leurs familles éprouvés en raison de la guerre. Dans 
Senninbari (mille Stiches), une femme tient une écharpe de souvenir
pendant qu'un soldat fantomatique de Nisei regarde vers le bas du 
ciel. Et envoyez dedans outre du mari au camp de Jerome, 
séjours d'une famille d'interné derrière les portes de camp comme 
leur soldat father/husband va hors fonction combattre pour les 
Etats-Unis.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Diversas forças de combate especiais dos estados 
unidos, compostos de únicos grupos étnicos, fizeram contribuições 
significativas durante a segunda guerra mundial, including os 
aviadores americanos africanos de Tuskegee e os talkers do código do 
navajo. A 442nd equipe regimental do combate foi composta 
unicamente dos americanos japoneses, algum de quem foram recrutadas 
diretamente dos acampamentos do internamento. (alguns homens 
americanos japoneses que se transformariam mais tarde líderes, tais 
como o senator Daniel Inouye, eram membros do 442nd.) As imagens
neste grupo fornecem um olhar nas vidas e nos sacrifícios dos homens 
do 442nd, a unidade americana o mais altamente decorada em WWII. 
Todas as fotografias neste grupo foram feitas exame para a 
autoridade do relocation da guerra do funcionamento do governo (WRA) e
são significadas portray o patriotism orgulhoso dos homens e de suas 
famílias. Uma foto mostra três mulheres que prendem seus 
bebês, com as fotografias de seus maridos alistados. Outro é 
um retrato de um par mais velho que mande cinco filhos no 442nd. 
outras fotografias refletir o treinamento os soldados da 442nd 
recebida, de sua vida no campo de batalha, e do seu homecoming 
triunfante. Outros originais neste grupo mostram um lado mais 
pessoal dos homens do 442nd. Um album de foto do soldado 
descreve suas experiências pessoais como um membro da equipe do 
combate. 50-page um livreto, a história da 442nd equipe do 
combate, compilada por membros da equipe, tem estas citações de 
Franklin D. Roosevelt na página do dedication: o "americanism 
é uma matéria da mente e do coração; O americanism não é e
nunca não era uma matéria da raça e do ancestry." Em uma nota
mais poignant, as pinturas de óleo pelo Henry Sugimoto do artista de 
Japonês Americano refletem as emoções, a dor, e sofrer estes 
indivíduos e suas famílias experimentados em conseqüência da 
guerra. Em Senninbari (mil Stiches), uma mulher prende um scarf 
do remembrance enquanto um soldado ghostly de Nisei olha para baixo do
céu e emite dentro fora do marido no acampamento de Jerome, um 
internee que a família permanece atrás das portas do acampamento 
enquanto seu soldado father/husband se apaga lutar pelos estados 
unidos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Parecchie forze speciali di combattimento dal unito 
Dichiara, composto di singoli gruppi etnici, reso a contributi 
significativi durante la seconda guerra mondiale, compreso gli 
aviatori americani africani di Tuskegee ed i talkers di codice del 
navajo. La 442nd squadra regimental di combattimento si è 
composta solamente degli Americani giapponesi, alcuno di chi sono 
stati reclutati direttamente dagli accampamenti di internamento. 
(alcuni uomini americani giapponesi che più successivamente 
diventerebbero capi, quale il senatore Daniel Inouye, erano 
membri del 442nd.) Le immagini in questo gruppo forniscono uno 
sguardo alle vite ed ai sacrifici degli uomini del 442nd, l'unità 
americana il più altamente decorata in WWII. Le fotografie in 
questo gruppo tutte sono state prese per l'autorità di rilocazione di
guerra di funzionamento di governo (WRA) e sono significate per 
ritrarre il patriotism fiero degli uomini e delle loro famiglie. 
Una foto mostra a tre donne la tenuta i loro bambini, con 
le fotografie dei loro mariti arruolati. Un altro è un 
ritratto di più vecchia coppia che ha fatta a cinque riflettere 
figli nel 442nd. altre fotografie l'addestramento i soldati della 
442nd ricevuta di, della loro vita nel campo di battaglia e del loro 
homecoming trionfante. Altri documenti in questo gruppo mostrano
un lato più personale degli uomini del 442nd. Un album di foto 
del soldato descrive le sue esperienze personali come membro della 
squadra di combattimento. 50-page un libretto, la storia della 
442nd squadra di combattimento, compilata dai membri della squadra, ha
questa virgoletta da Franklin D. Roosevelt alla pagina di dedica: 
"il americanism è un aspetto della mente e del cuore; Il 
americanism non è e mai non era un aspetto della razza e delle 
origini." Su una nota più poignant, le pitture di olio dal 
henry Sugimoto dell'artista del Japanese American riflettono le 
emozioni, il dolore e la sofferenza questi individui e delle loro 
famiglie sperimentati come conseguenza della guerra. In 
Senninbari (mille Stiches), una donna tiene una sciarpa del 
remembrance mentre un soldato ghostly di Nisei osserva giù dal cielo 
e dentro trasmette fuori del marito all'accampamento di Jerome, un 
internee che la famiglia rimane dietro i cancelli dell'accampamento 
mentre il loro soldato father/husband si spegne combattere per unito 
Dichiara.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διάφορες ειδικές δύναμη πάλης από τις Ηνωμένες 
Πολιτείες, φιαγμένες επάνω από ενιαίες εθνικές ομάδες, είχαν 
τις σημαντικές συνεισφορές κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου 
πολέμου ΙΙ, συμπεριλαμβανομένων των αφρικανικών αμερικανικών 
αεροπόρων Tuskegee και του κώδικα Talkers Ναβάχο. Η 
442nd συνταγματική ομάδα αγώνα αποτελούταν απλώς από 
ιαπωνικούς Αμερικανούς, μερικοί από τους οποίους στρατολογήθηκαν
άμεσα από τα στρατόπεδα περιορισμού. (Μερικά ιαπωνικά 
αμερικανικά άτομα που θα γίνονταν αργότερα ηγέτες, όπως ο 
γερουσιαστής Ντάνιελ Inouye, ήταν μέλη του 442nd.) Οι 
εικόνες σε αυτήν την ομάδα παρέχουν ένα βλέμμα στις ζωές και 
τις θυσίες των ατόμων του 442nd, η ο πιό ιδιαίτερα 
διακοσμημένη αμερικανική μονάδα σε WWII. Οι φωτογραφίες 
σε αυτήν την ομάδα όλες λήφθηκαν για την αρχή πολεμικής 
επαναμετάθεσης κυβέρνηση-τρεξίματος (WRA) και προορίζονται να 
απεικονίσουν τον υπερήφανο πατριωτισμό των ατόμων και των 
οικογενειών τους. Μια φωτογραφία εμφανίζει τρεις γυναίκες 
που κρατούν τα μωρά τους, με τις φωτογραφίες των στρατολογημένων 
συζύγων τους. Αλλο είναι ένα πορτρέτο ενός παλαιότερου 
ζεύγους που είχε πέντε γιους στα 442nd. Αλλες 
φωτογραφίες απεικονίζουν την κατάρτιση οι στρατιώτες 442nd 
λαμβανόμενης, της ζωής τους στο πεδίο μάχη, και θριαμβευτικά 
τους. Αλλα έγγραφα σε αυτήν την ομάδα εμφανίζουν πιό 
προσωπική πλευρά των ατόμων του 442nd. Ένα λεύκωμα 
φωτογραφιών του στρατιώτη απεικονίζει την προσωπική εμπειρία του 
ως μέλος της ομάδας αγώνα. Ένα βιβλιάριο 50-σελίδων, η 
ιστορία της 442nd ομάδας αγώνα, που μεταγλωττίζεται από τα 
μέλη της ομάδας, έχει αυτό το απόσπασμα Franklin Δ. 
Roosevelt στη σελίδα αφιέρωσης: "Americanism είναι ένα
θέμα του μυαλού και της καρδιάς  Το Americanism και δεν 
είναι ποτέ ένα θέμα φυλής και καταγωγής." Σε μια πιό 
οδυνηρή σημείωση, τα έργα ζωγραφικής πετρελαίου από τον 
ιαπωνικό αμερικανικό καλλιτέχνη Henry Sugimoto απεικονίζουν 
τις συγκινήσεις, τον πόνο, και να υποστούν αυτά τα άτομα και τις 
οικογένειές τους που βιώνονται ως αποτέλεσμα του πολέμου. 
Σε Senninbari (χίλιο Stiches), μια γυναίκα κρατά ένα 
μαντίλι της ενθύμησης όπως ένας πνευματικός στρατιώτης Nisei 
εξετάζει κάτω από τον ουρανό και Send μακριά στο σύζυγο το 
Jerome Camp, παραμονή internee οικογενειών πίσω από τις 
πύλες στρατόπεδων καθώς ο πατέρας/ο σύζυγος στρατιωτών τους 
πηγαίνει μακριά να παλεψει για τις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Varias fuerzas que luchaban especiales de los 
Estados Unidos, compuestos de solos grupos étnicos, hicieron 
contribuciones significativas durante la Segunda Guerra Mundial, 
incluyendo los aviadores americanos africanos de Tuskegee y los 
transmisores del código de Navajo. Compusieron al 44ò equipo 
regimental del combate solamente de los americanos japoneses, algunos 
de quién fueron reclutadas directamente de campos de la internación.
(algunos hombres americanos japoneses que hicieron más adelante
arranques de cinta, tales como senador Daniel Inouye, eran miembros 
del 44òs.) Las imágenes en este grupo proporcionan a una 
mirada en las vidas y los sacrificios de los hombres del 44òs, la 
unidad americana lo más altamente posible adornada de WWII. Las
fotografías en este grupo todas fueron tomadas para la autoridad de 
la realocación de la guerra del funcionamiento del gobierno (WRA) y 
se significan para retratar el patriotismo orgulloso de los hombres y 
de sus familias. Una foto muestra a tres mujeres que sostienen a
sus bebés, con las fotografías de sus maridos alistados. Otro 
es un retrato de un más viejo par que hizo que cinco hijos en el 
442nd. otras fotografías reflejaran el entrenamiento los soldados de 
la 44à haber recibido, de su vida en el campo de batalla, y de su 
homecoming triunfante. Otros documentos en este grupo muestran a
cara más personal de los hombres del 44òs. Un álbum de foto 
del soldado representa sus experiencias personales como miembro del 
equipo del combate. 50-page un librete, la historia del 44ò 
equipo del combate, compilada por los miembros del equipo, tiene esta 
cotización de Franklin D. Roosevelt en la paginación del esmero: 
el "americanism es una cuestión de la mente y del corazón; 
El americanism no es y nunca no era una cuestión de raza y de 
ascendencia." En una nota más conmovedora, las pinturas de 
aceite por el Henrio Sugimoto del artista japanese american reflejan 
las emociones, dolor, y el sufrimiento de estos individuos y de sus 
familias experimentados como resultado de la guerra. En 
Senninbari (mil Stiches), una mujer sostiene una bufanda del 
remembrance como un soldado fantasmal de Nisei mira abajo del cielo y 
adentro envía de marido en el campo de Jerome, internado que la 
familia permanece detrás de las puertas del campo mientras que su 
soldado father/husband se apaga luchar para los Estados Unidos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085256</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105571</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-442nd-regimental-combat-team</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
