<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103442</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103442</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200915</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Climate reconstruction using Foraminifera in Deep Sea Sediments</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Klimarekonstruktion mit Foraminifera in den tiefen
Sesedimenten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Reconstruction de climat en utilisant Foraminifera
en sédiments profonds de mer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Reconstruction do clima usando Foraminifera em 
sedimentos profundos do mar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ricostruzione di clima usando Foraminifera in 
sedimenti profondi del mare</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αναδημιουργία κλίματος που χρησιμοποιεί Foraminifera
στα ιζήματα μεγάλων θαλασσίων βαθών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Reconstrucción del clima usando Foraminifera en 
sedimentos profundos del mar</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Wright Center for Science Education lesson plan (PDF) uses pasta as an analog to teach students how deep sea sediments are collected and analyzed to identify different foraminifera species in order to interpret global paleo temperature change. It includes National Science Education Standards as well as background information and images, a list of materials needed, a step-by-step photo-guided walk-through of the activity, evaluation questions, and reference list.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Wright Mitte für Wissenschaft Ausbildung 
Lektionplan (pdf) benutzt Teigwaren als Entsprechung, um 
Kursteilnehmern beizubringen, wie tief Sesedimente gesammelt und 
analysiert werden, um unterschiedliche foraminifera Sorte zu 
kennzeichnen, um globalen paleo Temperaturwechsel zu deuten. Sie
schließt nationale Wissenschaft Ausbildung Standards sowie 
Hintergrundinformationen und Bilder, eine Liste der Materialien ein, 
die benötigt werden, die Schritt für Schritt gehen-durch die 
Aktivität Foto-geführt werden, Auswertung Fragen und Bezugsliste.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce centre de Wright pour le plan de leçon 
d'éducation de la Science (pdf) emploie des pâtes comme analogue 
pour enseigner à des étudiants comment des sédiments de mer sont 
rassemblés et profondément analysés pour identifier différentes 
espèces de foraminifera afin d'interpréter le changement de 
température global de paleo. Il inclut des normes nationales 
d'éducation de la Science aussi bien que l'information de fond et les
images, une liste de matériaux requis, point par point photo-guidés 
marcher-à travers de l'activité, les questions d'évaluation, et la 
liste de référence.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este centro de Wright para a planta da lição da 
instrução da ciência (pdf) usa o pasta como um analog ensinar a 
estudantes como profundamente os sedimentos do mar são coletados e 
analisados para identificar a espécie diferente do foraminifera a fim
interpretar a mudança de temperatura global do paleo. Inclui 
padrões nacionais da instrução da ciência as.well.as a 
informação e as imagens de fundo, uma lista dos materiais 
necessitados, foto-guiados step-by-step and-através da atividade, 
perguntas da avaliação, e lista de referência.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo centro di Wright per il programma di 
lezione di formazione di scienza (pdf) usa la pasta come analogo per 
insegnare ad allievi quanto in profondità i sedimenti del mare sono 
raccolti ed analizzati per identificare la specie differente di 
foraminifera per interpretare il mutamento di temperatura globale di 
paleo. Include gli standard nazionali di formazione di scienza 
così come informazioni di base ed immagini, una lista dei materiali 
stati necessari, per gradi foto-guidati cammin-attraverso 
dell'attività, domande di valutazione e l'indice bibliografico.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το κέντρο Wright για το σχέδιο μαθήματος 
εκπαίδευσης επιστήμης (PDF) χρησιμοποιεί τα ζυμαρικά ως 
ανάλογο για να διδάξει στους σπουδαστές πώς τα ιζήματα μεγάλων 
θαλασσίων βαθών συλλέγονται και αναλύονται για να προσδιορίσουν 
τα διαφορετικά είδη foraminifera προκειμένου να ερμηνευθεί η 
σφαιρική αλλαγή θερμοκρασίας paleo. Περιλαμβάνει τα 
εθνικά πρότυπα εκπαίδευσης επιστήμης καθώς επίσης και τις 
βασικές πληροφορίες και τις εικόνες, έναν κατάλογο υλικών που 
απαιτούνται, ένα βαθμιαίο φωτογραφία-καθοδηγημένο πέρασμα της 
δραστηριότητας, τις ερωτήσεις αξιολόγησης, και τον κατάλογο 
αναφοράς.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este centro de Wright para el plan de la lección 
de la educación de la ciencia (pdf) utiliza las pastas como análogo 
para enseñar a estudiantes cómo profundamente los sedimentos del mar
se recogen y se analizan para identificar diversa especie del 
foraminifera para interpretar el cambio de temperatura global del 
paleo. Incluye estándares nacionales de la educación de la 
ciencia así como la información e imágenes de fondo, una lista de 
los materiales necesitados, gradualmente foto-dirigidos recorrer-por 
de la actividad, las preguntas de la evaluación, y lista de 
referencia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ZACH SMITH
FN:ZACH SMITH
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:WRIGHT CENTER FOR SCIENCE EDUCATION- TUFTS UNIVERSITY
FN:WRIGHT CENTER FOR SCIENCE EDUCATION- TUFTS UNIVERSITY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200915</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103442</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/climate-reconstruction-using-foraminifera-in-deep-sea-sediments</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
