<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102943</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102943</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086681</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Now Tulsa Does Care": A White Tulsan's Perspective on the Tulsa Race Riot of 1921</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Jetzt Interessiert Sich Tulsa": Perspektive 
eines weißen Tulsans auf dem Tulsa Rennen-Aufstand von 1921</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Maintenant Tulsa S'inquiète" : La 
perspective d'un Tulsan blanc sur l'émeute de course de Tulsa de 
1921</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Agora Tulsa Importa-se": Perspective de um 
Tulsan branco no motim da raça de Tulsa de 1921</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Ora Tulsa Si preoccupa": Prospettiva del 
Tulsan bianco sul tumulto della corsa de Tulsa di 1921</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Τώρα Tulsa φροντίζει": Η προοπτική ενός 
άσπρου Tulsan στη φυλετική ταραχή Tulsa του 1921</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Ahora Tulsa Cuida": Perspectiva de un Tulsan
blanco en el alboroto de la raza de Tulsa de 1921</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The years following World War I in the United States saw devastating race riots around the nation, in cities small and large. But the 1921 Tulsa race riot, a 24-hour rampage by white Tulsans, was one of the most vicious and intense race riots in American history before or since, resulting in the death of anywhere from 75 to 250 people and the burning of more than 1,000 black homes and businesses. Although the city's white leaders assured the nation's press that restitution and reconciliation would be forthcoming, other whites denied any responsibility for the carnage. In an article in the magazine  Survey , Amy Comstock, personal secretary to the editor of the  Tulsa Tribune , attempted to deflect attention from Tulsa's white citizenry by fixing blame for the 1921 riot on an ostensibly impoverished and licentious black community. Comstock argued that the responsibility for improving conditions, and for enforcing law and order, in this bustling community rested with white officials.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Jahre, die dem Ersten Weltkrieg in den 
verheerenden Rennenaufständen der Vereinigte Staaten Säge um die 
Nation, in den Städte klein und groß folgen. Aber der Tulsa 
Rennenaufstand 1921, ein 24stündiges randalieren durch weißes 
Tulsans, waren einer der schändlichsten und intensivsten 
Rennenaufstände in der amerikanischen Geschichte vor oder, da, und 
das überall resultiert im Tod von von 75 bis 250 Leuten und das 
Brennen von mehr als 1.000 schwarzen Häusern und von Geschäften. 
Obgleich die weißen Führer der Stadt der Presse der Nation 
versicherten, daß Zurückerstattung und Versöhnung bevorstehend sein
würden, verweigerte anderes Weiß jede mögliche Verantwortlichkeit 
für das Massaker. In einem Artikel in der Zeitschrift 
Übersicht, im Amy Comstock, in der persönlichen Sekretärin zum 
Herausgeber der Tulsa Tribüne, versucht, um Aufmerksamkeit 
Tulsas von der weißen Bürgerschaft abzulenken durch das Reparieren 
der Schuld für den Aufstand 1921 auf einer anscheinend verarmten und 
ausschweifenden schwarzen Gemeinschaft. Comstock argumentierte 
daß die Verantwortlichkeit für das Verbessern von von Bedingungen 
und für das Erzwingen des Gesetzes und der Ordnung, in dieser 
hastenden Gemeinschaft, die mit weißen Beamten stillgestanden wurde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les années suivant la Première Guerre Mondiale 
dans les émeutes dévastatrices de course de scie des Etats-Unis dans
la nation, dans les villes petites et grandes. Mais 1921 
l'émeute de course de Tulsa, un saccage de 2$4$ heures par Tulsans 
blanc, était l'une des émeutes de course les plus méchantes et les 
plus intenses dans l'histoire américaine avant ou puisque, ayant pour
résultat la mort n'importe où de de 75 à 250 personnes et la 
brûlure de plus de 1.000 maisons et entreprises noires. Bien 
que les amorces blanches de la ville aient assuré la presse de la 
nation que la restitution et la réconciliation seraient reçues, 
d'autres blancs ont nié n'importe quelle responsabilité du carnage. 
Dans un article dans l'enquête de magasin, l'ami Comstock, le 
secrétaire personnel à l'éditeur de Tulsa Tribune, essayé pour 
braquer l'attention de l'ensemble des habitants blanc de Tulsa en 
fixant le blâme pour l'émeute 1921 sur une communauté noire en 
apparence appauvrie et licencieuse. Comstock a argué du fait 
que la responsabilité d'améliorer des conditions, et d'imposer la 
loi et la commande, dans cette communauté se activante reposée avec 
les fonctionnaires blancs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os anos que seguem o world.war.i nos motins 
devastating unidos da raça da serra dos estados em torno da nação, 
nas cidades pequenas e grandes. Mas 1921 o motim da raça de 
Tulsa, um rampage de 24 horas por Tulsans branco, era um dos motins os
mais vicious e os mais intensos da raça no history americano antes ou
desde que, tendo por resultado a morte em qualquer lugar  de 75 a 250 
povos e da queimadura de mais de 1.000 HOME e negócios pretos. 
Embora os líderes brancos da cidade assegurassem a imprensa da 
nação que a restituição e o reconciliation seriam forthcoming, 
outros brancos negaram toda a responsabilidade para o massacre. 
Em um artigo no exame do compartimento, no amy Comstock, na 
secretária pessoal ao editor do Tulsa Tribune, tentado deflexionar a 
atenção do citizenry branco de Tulsa reparando a culpa para o motim 
1921 em uma comunidade preta ostensibly impoverished e licentious. 
Comstock discutiu que a responsabilidade para melhorar 
circunstâncias, e para reforçar a lei e a ordem, nesta comunidade 
apressando-se descansada com os oficiais brancos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli anni che seguono il world.war.i in unito 
Dichiara i tumulti devastating della corsa della sega intorno 
alla nazione, in città piccole e grandi. Ma 1921 il tumulto 
della corsa de Tulsa, un rampage di 24 ore da Tulsans bianco, era uno 
dei tumulti della corsa più viziosi e più intensi nella storia 
americana prima o poiché, con conseguente morte dovunque di 75 - 250 
genti e bruciarsi di più di 1.000 sedi e commercio neri. Anche 
se i capi bianchi della città hanno assicurato la pressa della
nazione che la restituzione e la riconciliazione sarebbero prossime, 
altri bianchi hanno negato tutta la responsabilità della carneficina.
In un articolo nell'indagine dello scomparto, nel amy Comstock, 
nella segretaria personale all'editore di Tulsa Tribune, tentato per 
deviare attenzione dal citizenry bianco de Tulsa riparando colpa per 
il tumulto 1921 su una Comunità nera apparentemente impoverita e 
licentious. Comstock ha sostenuto che la responsabilità del 
migliorare le circostanze e del fare rispettare la legge e l'ordine, 
in questa Comunità agitantesi riposata con i funzionari bianchi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα έτη μετά από παγκόσμιος πόλεμος Ι στις Ηνωμένες 
Πολιτείες εβλέίδαν τις καταστρεπτικές φυλετικές ταραχές 
γύρω από το έθνος, στις πόλεις μικρές και μεγάλες. Αλλά η
φυλετική ταραχή Tulsa, μια εικοσιτετράωρη έξαλλη συμπεριφορά 
του 1921 από άσπρο Tulsans, ήταν μια από τις πιό κακοήθεις
και έντονες φυλετικές ταραχές στην αμερικανική ιστορία πριν από 
ή από τότε, να προκύψει στο θάνατο οπουδήποτε από 75 έως 
250 ανθρώπους και το κάψιμο περισσότεροι από 1.000 μαύρες 
σπίτια και επιχειρήσεις. Αν και οι λευκοί ηγέτες της πόλης 
βεβαίωσαν τον Τύπο του έθνους ότι η αποκατάσταση και η 
συμφιλίωση θα ήταν προσεχείς, άλλα λευκά αρνήθηκαν οποιαδήποτε 
ευθύνη για τη σφαγή. Σε ένα άρθρο στην έρευνα περιοδικών, 
η Amy Comstock, προσωπικός γραμματέας στον επεξεργαστή του 
βήματος Tulsa, προσπάθησε να εκτρέψει την προσοχή από το 
άσπρο σύνολο των πολιτών Tulsa με τον καθορισμό της επίπληξης 
για την ταραχή του 1921 σε μια φαινομενικά και ελευθέρια μαύρη 
κοινότητα. Το Comstock υποστήριξε ότι η ευθύνη για τους 
όρους, και για την επιβολή του νόμου και της τάξης, σε αυτήν την 
δραστήρια κοινότητα που στηρίζεται με τους λευκούς ανώτερους 
υπαλλήλους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los años que siguen Primera Guerra Mundial en los
alborotos devastadores de la raza de la sierra de Estados Unidos 
alrededor de la nación, en las ciudades pequeñas y grandes. 
Pero 1921 el alboroto de la raza de Tulsa, un alboroto de 24 
horas por Tulsans blanco, era uno de los alborotos más viciosos y 
más intensos de la raza de la historia americana antes o puesto que, 
dando por resultado la muerte dondequiera a partir de 75 a 250 
personas y quemarse de más de 1.000 hogares y negocios negros. 
Aunque los arranques de cinta blancos de la ciudad aseguraron la
prensa de la nación que la restitución y la reconciliación serían 
próximas, otros blancos negaron cualquier responsabilidad de la 
carnicería. En un artículo en la encuesta sobre el 
compartimiento, el amy Comstock, la secretaria personal al editor del 
Tulsa Tribune, procurado para desviar la atención de los ciudadanos 
blancos de Tulsa fijando la culpa para el alboroto 1921 en una 
comunidad negra aparentemente de empobrecida y de licenciosa. 
Comstock discutió que la responsabilidad de mejorar 
condiciones, y de hacer cumplir ley y orden, en esta comunidad que 
apresuraba reclinada con los funcionarios blancos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086681</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102943</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/now-tulsa-does-care-a-white-tulsans-perspective-on-the-tulsa-race-riot-of-1921</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
