<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103003</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103003</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087072</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The War and the Intellectuals: Randolph Bourne Vents His Animus Against War</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Krieg und die Intellektuellen: Randolph 
Bourne Lüftet Seinen Animus Gegen Krieg</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La guerre et les intellectuels : Randolph 
Bourne Exhale Son Animosité Contre La Guerre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A guerra e os intelectuais: Randolph Bourne 
Exala Seu Animus De encontro À Guerra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La guerra e gli intellettuali: Randolph 
Bourne Scarica Il Suo Animus Contro La Guerra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο πόλεμος και οι διανοούμενοι: Το Randolph 
Bourne αερίζει το σκοπό του ενάντια στον πόλεμο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La guerra y los intelectuales: Randolph 
Bourne Expresa Su Animus Contra Guerra</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Pro-war statements and speeches--as well as more coercive measures--gradually captured American public discourse in 1917. Fairly quickly, those who rejected the rationales for United States participation in the war found themselves increasingly isolated. Liberals, intellectuals, and even many socialists soon supported American intervention. A youthful critic in his twenties, Randolph Bourne wrote a bitter essay in the intellectual magazine  Seven Arts , lambasting his fellow intellectuals for lining up so readily behind the war effort.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Pro-Krieg Anweisungen und Reden -- sowie 
zwingendere Masse -- stufenweise erfaßte amerikanische allgemeine 
Darlegung 1917. Ziemlich schnell, fanden sich die, die die 
rationales für Vereinigte Staaten Teilnahme am Krieg zurückwiesen, 
in zunehmendem Maße lokalisiert. Liberale, Intellektuelle und 
sogar viele Sozialisten unterstützten bald amerikanische 
Intervention. Ein jugendlicher Kritiker in seinen Zwanziger 
Jahren, Randolph Bourne schrieb einen bitteren Versuch in die 
intellektuellen Zeitschrift sieben künste und machte seine 
Mitintellektuellen für so betriebsbereit ausrichten hinter der 
Kriegbemühung fertig.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">rapports et discours de Pro-guerre -- aussi bien 
que des mesures plus coercitives -- discours public américain 
graduellement capturé en 1917. Assez rapidement, ceux qui ont 
rejeté les rationales pour la participation des Etats-Unis à la 
guerre se sont trouvés de plus en plus d'isolement. Les 
libéraux, les intellectuels, et même beaucoup de socialistes ont 
bientôt supporté l'intervention américaine. Un critique jeune 
en quelques ses années '20, Randolph Bourne a écrit un essai amer 
dans les arts intellectuels du magasin sept, fustigeant ses 
intellectuels de camarade pour aligner tellement aisément derrière 
l'effort de guerre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">indicações e discursos da Pro-guerra -- 
as.well.as medidas mais coercive -- discurso público americano 
gradualmente capturado em 1917. Razoavelmente rapidamente, 
aqueles que rejeitaram os rationales para a participação unida dos 
estados na guerra encontraram-se isolados cada vez mais. Os 
liberais, os intelectuais, e mesmo muitos socialists suportaram logo a
intervenção americana. Um crítico jovem em seus twenties, 
Randolph Bourne escreveu um essay amargo nas artes intelectuais do 
compartimento sete, lambasting seus intelectuais do companheiro 
alinhando acima assim prontamente atrás do esforço da guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">istruzione e discorsi di Pro-guerra -- così come 
le misure più coercive -- discorso pubblico americano gradualmente 
bloccato in 1917. Ragionevolmente rapidamente, coloro che ha 
rifiutato i rationales per unito Dichiarano la partecipazione 
alla guerra si sono trovati sempre più isolati. I liberali, gli
intellettuali e perfino molti socialisti presto hanno sostenuto 
l'intervento americano. Un critico youthful nei suoi anni '20, 
Randolph Bourne ha scritto un saggio amaro nelle arti intellettuali 
dello scomparto sette, lambasting i suoi intellettuali del collega per
allineare così prontamente dietro lo sforzo di guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι υπέρ-πολεμικές δηλώσεις και οι ομιλίες -- καθώς 
επίσης και περισσότερα καταναγκαστικά μέτρα -- βαθμιαία 
συνέλαβαν την αμερικανική δημόσια ομιλία σε 1917, Αρκετά
γρήγορα, εκείνοι που απέρριψαν τις λογικές για Ηνωμένη συμμετοχή
στον πόλεμο βρέθηκαν όλο και περισσότερο απομονωμένου. Οι 
φιλελεύθεροι, οι διανοούμενοι, και ακόμη και πολλοί σοσιαλιστές 
υποστήριξαν σύντομα την αμερικανική επέμβαση. Ένας 
νεανικός κριτικός στις δεκαετίες του '20 του, Randolph Bourne
έγραψε σε ένα πικρό δοκίμιο στο διανοητικό περιοδικό επτά τις 
τέχνες, poy οι συντροφικοί διανοούμενοί του για να παρατάξει 
τόσο εύκολα πίσω από την πολεμική προσπάθεια.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">declaraciones y discursos de la Favorable-guerra 
-- así como medidas más coactivas -- discurso público americano 
gradualmente capturado en 1917. Bastante rápidamente, los que 
rechazaron los rationales para la participación de Estados Unidos en 
la guerra se encontraron aislados cada vez más. Los liberales, 
los intelectuales, e incluso muchos socialistas pronto utilizaron la 
intervención americana. Un crítico joven en sus años 20, 
Randolph Bourne escribió un ensayo amargo en los artes intelectuales 
del compartimiento siete, lambasting a sus intelectuales del 
compañero para alinearse tan fácilmente detrás del esfuerzo de la 
guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087072</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103003</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-war-and-the-intellectuals-randolph-bourne-vents-his-animus-against-war</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
