<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108644</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108644</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087446</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Born Yet We Are Debarred Englishmen's Liberty": A Massachusetts Soldier Confronts British Society, 1759</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Getragen Dennoch Sind Wir Freiheit Der 
Ausgeschlossenen Engländer": Ein Massachusetts Soldat 
Konfrontiert Britische Gesellschaft, 1759</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Soutenu Pourtant Nous Sommes La Liberté Des 
Anglais Excluant" : Un Soldat du Massachusetts Confronte La 
Société Britannique, 1759</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Carregado Contudo Nós Somos Liberdade Dos 
Ingleses Excluídos": Um Soldado De Massachusetts Confronta A 
Sociedade Britânica, 1759</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Sopportato Tuttavia Siamo La Libertà Degli 
Inglesi Esclusi": Un Soldato Del Massachusetts Confronta La 
Società Britannica, 1759</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Γεννημένος ακόμα είμαστε αποκλεισμένη ελευθερία 
Αγγλων": Ένας στρατιώτης της Μασαχουσέτης αντιμετωπίζει τη 
βρετανική κοινωνία, 1759</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Llevado Con todo Somos Libertad De los Ingleses 
Excluidos": Un Soldado De Massachusetts Enfrenta A Sociedad 
Británica, 1759</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">During the 18th century, American colonists found themselves increasingly involved in wars, often imperial ones, spiraling out of European battlefields onto the North American continent. The Seven Years War between France and Great Britain began along the western frontier and spread in 1754. New Englanders eagerly volunteered for expeditions leading to the invasion of French Canada. British and colonial forces succeeded together in capturing the great French fortress of Louisbourg in Nova Scotia in 1758. But as Massachusetts soldier Gibson Clough discovered, the British regular army looked down on the colonial militia. British concepts of discipline and social hierarchy varied significantly from colonial ones, and the war experience began to encourage colonists' conception of themselves as Americans.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während des 18. Jahrhunderts fanden sich 
amerikanische Kolonisten in zunehmendem Maße beteiligt in den 
Kriegen, die häufig imperiale und wanden sich aus europäischen 
Schlachtfeldern auf den nordamerikanischen Kontinent heraus. Die
sieben Jahre War zwischen Frankreich und Großbritannien fing entlang 
der westlichen Grenze und der Verbreitung 1754 an. Neue 
Engländer erboten begeistert sich für die Expeditionen freiwillig, 
die zu die Invasion von französischem Kanada führen. Britische
und Kolonialkräfte folgten zusammen, mit, die große französische 
Festung von Louisbourg in Neuschottland 1758 zu erfassen. Aber 
wie Massachusetts Soldat Gibson entdecktes Clough, die britische 
regelmäßige Armee unten auf der Kolonialmiliz schaute. 
Britische Konzepte der Disziplin und der Sozialhierarchie 
schwankten erheblich von den Kolonial, und die Kriegerfahrung fing an,
Auffassung der Kolonisten von selbst als Amerikaner anzuregen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant le 18ème siècle, les colons américains 
se sont trouvés de plus en plus impliqués dans les guerres, souvent 
les impériales, se développant en spirales hors des champs de 
bataille européens sur le continent américain du nord. Les 
sept années font la guerre entre la France et la Grande-Bretagne a 
commencé le long de la frontière et de l'étendre occidentaux en 
1754. Les nouveaux Anglais ont ardemment offert pour des 
expéditions menant à l'invasion du Canada français. Les 
forces britanniques et coloniales ont réussi ensemble à capturer la 
grande forteresse française de Louisbourg en Nouvelle-Écosse en 
1758. Mais comme le soldat Gibson Clough du Massachusetts 
découvert, l'armée régulière britannique a regardé vers le bas 
sur la milice coloniale. Les concepts britanniques de la 
discipline et de la hiérarchie sociale ont changé de manière 
significative de la coloniale, et l'expérience de guerre a commencé 
à encourager la conception des colons d'eux-mêmes comme Américains.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Durante o 18o século, os colonos americanos 
encontraram-se cada vez mais involvidos nas guerras, as frequentemente
imperiais, espiralando fora dos campos de batalha europeus no 
continente norte-americano. Os sete anos guerreiam entre France 
e Grâ Bretanha começou ao longo da fronteira e da propagação 
ocidentais em 1754. Os englanders novos ofereceram-se 
ansiosamente para as expedições que conduzem à invasão de Canadá 
francês. As forças britânicas e coloniais sucederam junto em 
capturar o fortress francês grande de Louisbourg em Nova Escócia em 
1758. Mas como o soldado Gibson Clough de Massachusetts 
descoberto, o exército regular britânico olhou para baixo na 
milícia colonial. Os conceitos britânicos da disciplina e da 
hierarquia social variaram significativamente das coloniais, e a 
experiência da guerra começou a incentivar o conception dos colonos 
dse como americanos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Durante il diciottesimo secolo, i colonizzatori 
americani si sono trovati sempre più implicati nelle guerre, quelle 
spesso imperiali, sviluppantesi a spirale dai campi di battaglia 
europei sul continente nordamericano. I sette anni fanno la 
guerra fra la Francia e la Gran Bretagna ha cominciato lungo la 
frontiera e la diffusione occidentali in 1754. I nuovi 
englanders si sono offerti volontariamente ardentemente per le 
spedizioni che conducono all'invasione del Canada francese. Le 
forze britanniche e coloniali sono riuscito insieme a bloccare il 
fortress francese grande di Louisbourg in Nuova Scozia in 1758. 
Ma come il soldato Gibson Clough del Massachusetts scoperto, 
l'esercito normale britannico ha osservato giù sulla milizia 
coloniale. I concetti britannici di disciplina e della gerarchia
sociale hanno variato significativamente da quelle coloniali e 
l'esperienza di guerra ha cominciato a consigliare alla concezione dei
colonizzatori di se stesso come Americani.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατά τη διάρκεια του 18$ου αιώνα, οι αμερικανικοί 
άποικοι βρέθηκαν όλο και περισσότερο περιλήφθείτυ στους 
πολέμους, συχνά αυτοκρατορικοί, που κινούνται σπειροειδώς από τα
ευρωπαϊκά πεδία μάχες επάνω στη βορειοαμερικανική ήπειρο. 
Τα επτά έτη πολεμικά μεταξύ της Γαλλίας και της Μεγάλης 
Βρετανίας άρχισαν κατά μήκος των δυτικών συνόρων και διέδωσαν 
σε 1754, νέο Englanders που προσφέρθηκε εθελοντικά ανυπόμονα
για τις αποστολές που οδηγούν στην εισβολή του γαλλικού Καναδά. 
Οι βρετανικές και αποικιακές δυνάμεις πέτυχαν μαζί στη 
σύλληψη του μεγάλου γαλλικού φρουρίου Louisbourg στη Νέα 
Σκοτία το 1758. Αλλά ως χαράδρα Gibson στρατιωτών της 
Μασαχουσέτης που ανακαλύφθηκε, ο βρετανικός κανονικός στρατός 
κοίταξε κάτω στην αποικιακή πολιτοφυλακή. Οι βρετανικές 
έννοιες της πειθαρχίας και της κοινωνικής ιεραρχίας ποίκιλαν 
σημαντικά από αποικιακές, και η πολεμική εμπειρία άρχισε να 
ενθαρρύνει τη σύλληψη των αποίκων τους ως Αμερικανούς.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Durante el décimo octavo siglo, los colonos 
americanos se encontraron cada vez más implicados en las guerras, las
a menudo imperiales, torciendo en espiral de campos de batalla 
europeos sobre el continente norteamericano. Los siete años 
guerrean entre Francia y Gran Bretaña comenzó a lo largo de la 
frontera y de la extensión occidentales en 1754. Los nuevos 
ingleses se ofrecieron voluntariamente con impaciencia para las 
expediciones que conducían a la invasión de Canadá francés. 
Las fuerzas británicas y coloniales tuvieron éxito juntas en 
capturar la gran fortaleza francesa de Louisbourg en Nueva Escocia en 
1758. Pero como el soldado Gibson Clough de Massachusetts 
descubierto, el ejército regular británico miraba abajo en la 
milicia colonial. Los conceptos británicos de la disciplina y 
de la jerarquía social variaron perceptiblemente las coloniales, y la
experiencia de la guerra comenzó a animar el concepto de los colonos 
de sí mismos como americanos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087446</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108644</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/born-yet-we-are-debarred-englishmens-liberty-a-massachusetts-soldier-confronts-british-society-1759</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
