<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104166</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104166</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086142</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Eyewitness to Murder: Recounting the Ludlow Massacre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zu ermorden Augenzeuge: Nachzählen des 
Ludlow Blutbads</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Témoin oculaire à assassiner : Racontage 
du Massacre de Ludlow</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Testemunha ocular a assassinar: Recounting o
massacre de Ludlow</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Testimone oculare da assassinare: Racconto 
del massacre di Ludlow</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτόπτης μάρτυρας που δολοφονεί: Εξιστόρηση της 
σφαγής Ludlow</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Testigo presencial a asesinar: Contar de 
nuevo la Masacre de Ludlow</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The labor struggles of the early 20th century, many of which ended in violence and death, engendered deep concern at all levels of society and led to a series of governmental investigations. The most important--the Commission on Industrial Relations--was appointed by newly elected Democratic president Woodrow Wilson early in 1913. The commission was in the midst of taking testimony from owners, workers, and reformers in dozens of industrial communities around the country when a coal strike erupted in southern Colorado. On Easter night, 1914, three women and eleven children were killed at a mining encampment in Ludlow, Colorado. One of the most famous accounts of what came to be called the "Ludlow massacre" was the statement of a young electrical engineer, Godfrey Irwin, who was traveling through southern Colorado and provided an eyewitness account to a New York  World  reporter, reproduced here.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Arbeitskämpfe des frühen 20. Jahrhunderts, 
von dem viele in der Gewalttätigkeit und im Tod beendeten, erzeugtes 
tiefes Interesse auf allen Stufen der Gesellschaft und zu eine Reihe 
Regierungsuntersuchungen geführt. Das wichtigste -- die 
Kommission auf industriellen Beziehungen zwischen den Sozialpartnern 
-- wurde von eben gewähltem demokratischem Präsidenten Woodrow 
Wilson früh 1913 ernannt. Die Kommission war in der Mitte des 
Nehmens des Zeugnisses von den Inhabern, von den Arbeitern und von den
Reformern in den Dutzenden der industriellen Gemeinschaften um 
das Land, als ein Kohleschlag in Südkolorado ausbrach. Auf 
Ostern Nacht wurden 1914, drei Frauen und elf Kinder an einem 
gewinnenlager in Ludlow, Kolorado beendet. Eine die 
berühmtesten Rechnungsprüfungen von was kamen, genannt zu werden das
"Ludlow Blutbad" waren die Anweisung über einen jungen 
Elektroingenieur, Godfrey Irwin, das durch Südkolorado reiste und 
vorausgesetzt ein Augenzeugekonto zu einem New York Weltreporter, hier
reproduziert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les luttes de travail du début du 20ème siècle,
dont beaucoup ont terminé dans la violence et la mort, souci profond 
engendré de tous les niveaux de la société et menés à une série 
d'investigations gouvernementales. Le plus important -- la 
Commission sur des relations industrielles -- a été nommé par le 
Président démocratique nouvellement élu Woodrow Wilson au début de
1913. La commission était au milieu de prendre le témoignage 
des propriétaires, des ouvriers, et des réformateurs dans les 
douzaines des communautés industrielles dans le pays quand une grève
de charbon a éclaté dans le Colorado méridional. La nuit de 
Pâques, les 1914, trois femmes et les onze enfants ont été 
détruits à un campement d'extraction dans Ludlow, le Colorado. 
Un des comptes les plus célèbres de ce qui sont venus pour 
s'appeler le "massacre de Ludlow" étaient le rapport d'un jeune 
ingénieur électrique, Godfrey Irwin, qui voyageait par le Colorado 
méridional et si un compte de témoin oculaire à un journaliste du 
monde de New York, reproduit ici.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os esforços labor do 20o século adiantado, 
muitos de que terminaram na violência e na morte, interesse profundo 
engendered em todos os níveis da sociedade e conduzidos a uma série 
de investigações governamentais. O mais importante -- o 
commission em relações industriais -- foi apontado pelo presidente 
democrático recentemente eleito Woodrow Wilson cedo em 1913. O 
commission estava no meio de fazer exame do testimony dos 
proprietários, dos trabalhadores, e dos reformers nas dúzias de 
comunidades industriais em torno do país quando uma batida de carvão
erupted em Colorado do sul. Na noite de Easter, 1914, três 
mulheres e onze crianças foram matadas em um encampment minando em 
Ludlow, Colorado. Um dos clientes os mais famosos de o que 
vieram ser chamados de "o massacre Ludlow" eram a indicação de um 
coordenador elétrico novo, Godfrey Irwin, que estava viajando 
através de Colorado do sul e desde que um cliente da testemunha 
ocular a um repórter do mundo de New York, reproduzido aqui.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le lotte di lavoro di inizio del 20esimo secolo, 
molte di où si sono concluse nella violenza e nella morte, 
preoccupazione profonda generata a tutti i livelli della società e 
condotti ad una serie di indagini governative. L'più importante
-- la Commissione sulle relazione industriali -- è stato nominato dal
presidente democratico recentemente scelto Woodrow Wilson all'inizio 
di 1913. La commissione in mezzo a stava prendendo la 
testimonianza dai proprietari, dagli operai e dai reformers nelle 
dozzine delle Comunità industriali intorno al paese quando un colpo 
del carbone ha scoppiato in Colorado del sud. Sulla 
notte di Pasqua, 1914, tre donne ed undici bambini sono stati uccisi 
ad un encampment estraente in Ludlow, Colorado. Uno dei clienti 
più famosi di che cosa sono venuto essere chiamati "il massacre di 
Ludlow" erano l'istruzione di un assistente tecnico elettrotecnico 
giovane, Godfrey Irwin, che stava attraversando through Colorado del 
sud e se un cliente del testimone oculare ad un reporter del mondo
de New York, riprodotto qui.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι προσπάθειες εργασίας του πρόωρου 20ού αιώνα, 
πολλές από τις οποίες τελείωσαν στη βία και το θάνατο, 
προκάλεσαν τη βαθιά ανησυχία σε όλα τα επίπεδα της κοινωνίας και
οδήγησαν σε μια σειρά κυβερνητικών ερευνών. Ο 
σημαντικότερος -- η Επιτροπή στις εργασιακές σχέσεις -- 
διορίστηκε από πρόσφατα εκλεγμένος το δημοκρατικό Πρόεδρο 
Woodrow Wilson νωρίς το 1913. Η επιτροπή ήταν στη 
μέση της λήψης της κατάθεσης από τους ιδιοκτήτες, τους 
εργαζομένους, και τους μεταρρυθμιστές στις δωδεκάδες των 
βιομηχανικών κοινοτήτων γύρω από τη χώρα όταν εξερράγη μια 
απεργία άνθρακα στο νότιο Κολοράντο. Στη νύχτα Πάσχας, 
1914, τρεις γυναίκες και ένδεκα παιδιά σκοτώθηκαν σε μια 
στρατοπέδευση μεταλλείας σε Ludlow, Κολοράντο. Ένας από 
τους διασημότερους απολογισμούς αυτό που ήρθε να κληθεί "σφαγή 
Ludlow" ήταν η δήλωση ενός νέου ηλεκτρολόγου μηχανικού, 
Godfrey Irwin, που ταξίδευε μέσω του νότιου Κολοράντο και 
παρείχε μια περιγραφή αυτοπτών μαρτύρων σε έναν παγκόσμιο 
δημοσιογράφο της Νέας Υόρκης, αναπαρήγαγε εδώ.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las luchas de trabajo del vigésimo siglo 
temprano, muchas de el cual terminaron en violencia y muerte, 
preocupación profunda engendrada en todos los niveles de la sociedad 
y conducidos a una serie de investigaciones gubernamentales. El 
más importante -- la Comisión en relaciones laborales -- fue 
designado por presidente democrático nuevamente elegido Woodrow 
Wilson temprano en 1913. La comisión estaba en el medio de 
tomar testimonio de propietarios, de trabajadores, y de reformadores en
docenas de comunidades industriales alrededor del país cuando una 
huelga del carbón entró en erupción en Colorado meridional. 
El la noche de Pascua, mataron a 1914, tres mujeres y a once 
niños en un campamento que minaba en Ludlow, Colorado. Una de 
las cuentas más famosas de qué vinieron ser llamadas la "masacre 
de Ludlow" eran la declaración de un ingeniero eléctrico joven, 
Godfrey Irwin, que viajaba a través de Colorado meridional y con tal 
que una cuenta del testigo presencial a un reportero del mundo de 
Nueva York, reproducido aquí.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086142</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104166</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/eyewitness-to-murder-recounting-the-ludlow-massacre</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
