<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105970</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105970</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086787</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Robert Bagnall on "The Madness of Marcus Garvey"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Robert Bagnall auf "der Verrücktheit von Marcus 
Garvey"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Robert Bagnall sur "la folie de Marcus Garvey"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Robert Bagnall "na loucura de Marcus Garvey"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Robert Bagnall "sulla Follia di Marcus 
Garvey"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θ*Ροψερτ Bagnall "στην τρέλα του Marcus Garvey"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Roberto Bagnall en "la locura de Marcus Garvey"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">After fighting World War I, ostensibly to defend democracy and the right of self-determination, thousands of African-American soldiers returned home to face intensified discrimination, segregation, and racial violence. Drawing on this frustration, Marcus Garvey attracted thousands of disillusioned black working-class and lower middle-class followers to his Universal Negro Improvement Association (UNIA). The UNIA, committed to notions of racial purity and separatism, insisted that salvation for African Americans meant building an autonomous, black-led nation in Africa. As Garvey's influence in the black community grew, so too did the voices of his many critics. Integrationists such as W. E. B. Du Bois and Robert Bagnall, both of the NAACP, worried that the UNIA leader was exploiting black disillusionment for personal gain. Moreover, they objected to the UNIA's call for racial separatism, and in this 1923 article Bagnall accused Garvey of "madness."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nachdem sie den Ersten Weltkrieg, um gekämpft 
hatten Demokratie und das Recht von Self-determination anscheinend zu 
verteidigen, kamen Tausenden der Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Soldaten 
nach Hause zu Gesicht verstärkter Unterscheidung, zur Abtrennung und 
zur rassischen Gewalttätigkeit zurück. Zeichnend auf diese 
Frustration, zog Marcus Garvey Tausenden der ernüchterten schwarzen 
Arbeiterklasse und der untereren Mittelklassenachfolger zu seiner 
Universalschwarze-Verbesserung Verbindung an (UNIA). Das UNIA, 
festgelegt an den Begriffen der rassischen Reinheit und des 
Separatismus, beharrte, daß Rettung für afrikanische Amerikaner 
das Aufbauen einer autonomen bedeutete, schwarz-führenden Nation in 
Afrika. Während Einfluß Garveys in der schwarzen Gemeinschaft 
wuchs, tat so auch die Stimmen seiner vielen Kritiker. 
Integrationists wie W. E. B. Du Bois und Robert Bagnall, beide 
des NAACP, sorgte sich, daß der UNIA Führer schwarze Desillusionierung 
für persönlichen Gewinn ausnutzte. Außerdem wendeten sie 
gegen den Aufruf des UNIAs für rassischen Separatismus ein, und in 
diesem Artikel 1923 beschuldigte Bagnall Garvey "von der 
Verrücktheit."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Après le combat de la Première Guerre Mondiale, 
pour défendre en apparence la démocratie et la droite de 
art de l'auto-portrait-determination, les milliers de soldats afro-américains sont 
revenus à la maison à la discrimination intensifiée par visage, à 
la ségrégation, et à la violence raciale. Dessinant sur cet 
anéantissement, Marcus Garvey a attiré des milliers de classe 
ouvrière noire désillusionnée et de sectateurs inférieurs de 
classe moyenne à son association universelle d'amélioration de 
nègre (UNIA). L'UNIA, commis aux notions de la pureté et du 
séparatisme raciaux, a insisté sur le fait que le salut pour les 
Américains africains a signifié établir une nation autonome et 
noir-menée en Afrique. Pendant que l'influence de Garvey dans 
la communauté noire se développait, a tellement aussi fait les voix 
de ses beaucoup de critiques. Integrationists tel que W. E. B. 
Du Bois et Robert Bagnall, tous les deux NAACP, s'est inquiété que 
l'amorce d'UNIA ait exploité la désillusion noire pour le gain 
personnel. D'ailleurs, ils se sont opposés à l'appel de l'UNIA
pour le séparatisme racial, et en cet article 1923 Bagnall accuse 
Garvey de la "folie."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Após ter lutado o world.war.i, para defender 
ostensibly a democracia e a direita do self-determination, os milhares
de soldados Africano-Americanos retornaram para casa à 
discriminação intensified cara, ao segregation, e à violência 
racial. Desenhando nesta frustração, Marcus Garvey atraiu 
milhares do working-class preto disillusioned e de uns seguidores mais
baixos do middle-class a sua associação universal da melhoria do 
negro (UNIA). O UNIA, cometido às noções do purity e do 
separatism raciais, insistiu que o salvation para americanos africanos
significou construir uma nação autônoma, preto-conduzida em 
África. Enquanto a influência de Garvey na comunidade preta 
cresceu, fêz assim demasiado as vozes de seus muitos críticos. 
Integrationists tal como W. E. B. Du Bois e Robert Bagnall, 
ambos o NAACP, preocupou-se que o líder de UNIA explorava o 
disillusionment preto para o ganho pessoal. Além disso, 
objetaram ao atendimento do UNIA para o separatism racial, e neste 
artigo 1923 Bagnall acusa Garvey da "loucura."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dopo il world.war.i di combattimento, difendere 
apparentemente la democrazia e la destra di self-determination, i 
migliaia dei soldati Africano-Americani hanno ritornato a casa a 
distinzione intensificata faccia, alla segregazione ed alla violenza 
razziale. Dissipando su questa frustrazione, Marcus Garvey ha 
attratto i migliaia della classe operaia nera disillusa e dei 
seguicamme più bassi della classe media alla sua associazione 
universale di miglioramento del negro (UNIA). Il UNIA, impegnato
nelle nozioni della purezza e del separatism razziali, ha insistito 
che la salvezza per gli Americani africani ha significato lo 
sviluppo della nazione autonoma e nero-condotta in Africa. 
Mentre l'influenza del Garvey nella Comunità nera si è 
sviluppata, così anche ha fatto le voci dei suoi molti critici. 
Integrationists quali W. E. B. Du Bois e Robert Bagnall, 
entrambi il NAACP, si è preoccupato che il capo di UNIA stava
sfruttando il disillusionment nero per guadagno personale. 
Inoltre, hanno obiettato alla richiesta del UNIA per il 
separatism razziale ed in questo articolo 1923 Bagnall accusa Garvey 
"della follia."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μετά από να διεξαγάγουν τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι, για 
να υπερασπίσουν φαινομενικά τη δημοκρατία και το δικαίωμα της 
αυτοδιάθεσης, χιλιάδες αφρικανικός-αμερικανικοί στρατιώτες 
επέστρεψαν το σπίτι ενταμένη στην πρόσωπο διάκριση, το 
διαχωρισμό, και τη φυλετική βία. Επισύροντας την προσοχή σε
αυτήν την απογοήτευση, ο Marcus Garvey προσέλκυσε χιλιάδες 
απογοητευμένη μαύρη εργατική τάξη και χαμηλότεροι οπαδοί 
μεσαίων τάξεων στην καθολική ένωση βελτίωσης νέγρων του 
(UNIA). Το UNIA, δεσμευμένο στις έννοιες της φυλετικών 
αγνότητας και του αυτονομισμού, επέμεινε ότι η σωτηρία για 
αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς σήμανε ένα αυτόνομο, μαύρος-οδηγημένο 
έθνος στην Αφρική. Δεδομένου ότι η επιρροή Garvey στη 
μαύρη κοινότητα αυξήθηκε, τόσο επίσης έκανε τις φωνές των 
πολλών κριτικών του. Το Integrationists όπως Θ*Ω. Ε. Β. 
du Bois και Robert Bagnall, και τα δύο από το NAACP, 
ανησύχησε ότι ο ηγέτης UNIA εκμεταλλευόταν τη μαύρη 
απομυθοποίηση για το προσωπικό κέρδος. Επιπλέον, 
αντιτέθηκαν στην κλήση του UNIA για το φυλετικό αυτονομισμό, 
και σε αυτό το άρθρο του 1923 Bagnall κατηγόρησε Garvey 
για "την τρέλα."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Después de luchar Primera Guerra Mundial, 
aparentemente para defender democracia y la derecha de la 
autodeterminación, los millares de soldados Africano-Americanos 
volvieron a casa a la discriminación intensificada cara, a la 
segregación, y a la violencia racial. Trazando en esta 
frustración, Marcus Garvey atrajo a millares de clase obrera negra 
desilusionada y de seguidores más bajos de la clase media a su 
asociación universal de la mejora del negro (UNIA). El UNIA, 
confiado a las nociones de la pureza y del separatism raciales, 
insistió que la salvación para los americanos africanos significó 
la construcción de una nación autónoma, negro-conducida en África.
Mientras que la influencia de Garvey en la comunidad negra 
creció, hizo tan también las voces de sus muchos críticos. 
Integrationists tal como W. E. B. Du Bois y Roberto Bagnall, 
ambos NAACP, se preocupó que el arranque de cinta de UNIA explotaba 
la desilusión negra para el aumento personal. Por otra parte, se
opusieron a la llamada del UNIA para el separatism racial, y en este 
artículo 1923 Bagnall acusa Garvey de "locura."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086787</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105970</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/robert-bagnall-on-the-madness-of-marcus-garvey</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
