<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106158</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106158</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201935</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Famous Composers I</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Berühmte Komponisten I</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Compositeurs Célèbres I</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Compositores Famosos I</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Compositori Famosi I</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διάσημοι συνθέτες Ι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Compositores Famosos I</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Throughout the centuries there have been hundreds of composers that excelled during their style periods. This is an introduction to 11 of them starting in the Baroque style period and ending in the 20th Century. In the presentations there are many facts about each composer. Please feel free to surf between the different composer and styles. As students participating in class, please note which composers we are studying at the present and only go to their slides. Some of the objectives of this module are to teach you the country of origin, musical style period, picture recognition, major works and life time achievements. There are quizzes, games, listening excerpts and much more. You must complete the first 11 quizzes to be able to go on. REMEMBER - Through learning about the past you will understand a little more about the present.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während der Jahrhunderte hat es Hunderte 
Komponisten gegeben, die während ihrer Artperioden übertrafen. 
Dieses ist eine Einleitung bis 11 von ihnen beginnend in der 
barocken Artperiode und im 20. Jahrhundert beendend. In den 
Darstellungen gibt es viele Tatsachen über jeden Komponisten. 
Fühlen Sie bitte frei, zwischen den unterschiedlichen 
Komponisten und die Arten zu surfen. Als Kursteilnehmer, die an 
der Kategorie teilnehmen, beachten Sie bitte welche Komponisten wir am
Geschenk studieren und nur zu ihren Plättchen gehen. Einige der
Lernziele dieses Moduls sind, Ihnen das Ursprungsland, musikalische 
Artperiode, Abbildung Anerkennung, Major Arbeiten und 
Lebenzeitausführungen beizubringen. Es gibt Quizen, Spiele, 
hörende Excerpts und viel mehr. Sie müssen die ersten 11 
Quizen durchführen, um zu können, weiterzugehen. ERINNERN Sie 
sich - durch das Lernen über die Vergangenheit verstehen Sie wenig 
mehr über das Geschenk.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Tout au long des siècles il y a eu des centaines 
de compositeurs qui ont excelé pendant leurs périodes de modèle. 
C'est une introduction à 11 d'entre eux commençant dans la 
période baroque de modèle et terminant au 20ème siècle. Dans
les présentations il y a beaucoup de faits sur chaque compositeur. 
Sentez-vous s'il vous plaît libre pour surfer entre le 
différents compositeur et modèles. Comme étudiants 
participant à la classe, notez s'il vous plaît quels compositeurs 
nous étudions au présent et allons seulement à leurs glissières. 
Certains des objectifs de ce module sont de vous enseigner le 
pays d'origine, la période musicale de modèle, l'identification 
d'image, les travaux de commandant et les accomplissements de temps de
la vie. Il y a des jeux, jeux, extraits d'écoute et beaucoup 
davantage. Vous devez terminer les 11 premiers jeux pour pouvoir
continuer. RAPPELEZ-VOUS - en se renseignant sur le passé vous 
comprendrez peu un plus au sujet du présent.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Durante todo os séculos houve umas centenas dos 
compositores que excelled durante seus períodos do estilo. Esta
é uma introdução a 11 deles que começam no período baroque do 
estilo e que terminam no 20o século. Nas apresentações há 
muitos fatos sobre cada compositor. Sinta por favor livre surf 
entre o compositor e os estilos diferentes. Como os estudantes 
que participam na classe, anote por favor que compositores nós 
estamos estudando no presente e vão somente a suas corrediças. 
Alguns dos objetivos deste módulo são ensinar-lhe o país de 
origem, do período musical do estilo, do recognition do retrato, dos 
trabalhos do major e das realizações do tempo da vida. Há uns
quizzes, jogos, excerpts escutando e muito mais. Você deve 
terminar os primeiros 11 quizzes para poder  ir sobre. RECORDE -
com da aprendizagem sobre o passado você compreenderá um pouco mais 
sobre o presente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Durante i secoli ci sono stati centinaia dei 
compositori che hanno eccelso durante i loro periodi di stile. 
Ciò è un'introduzione a 11 di loro che cominciano nel periodo 
baroque di stile e che si concludono nel ventesimo secolo. Nelle
presentazioni ci sono molti fatti circa ogni compositore. 
Ritenga prego libero surf fra il compositore e gli stili 
differenti. Come allievi che partecipano al codice categoria, 
noti prego quale compositori stiamo studiando al presente e soltanto 
vanno ai loro scorrevoli. Alcuni degli obiettivi di questo 
modulo sono di insegnarvi il pæse d'origine, il periodo musicale di 
stile, il riconoscimento dell'immagine, gli impianti del maggiore ed i
successi di tempo di vita. Ci sono quiz, giochi, brani 
ascoltanti e molto più. Dovete completare il primi 11 quiz per 
potere accendere. RICORDISI DI - con imparare circa l'esperienza
capirete poco un più circa il presente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Καθ' όλη τη διάρκεια των αιώνων έχουν υπάρξει 
εκατοντάδες των συνθετών που υπερείχαν κατά τη διάρκεια των 
περιόδων ύφους τους. Αυτό είναι μια εισαγωγή σε 11 τους 
που αρχίζουν στην μπαρόκ περίοδο ύφους και που τελειώνουν στο 
20ό αιώνα. Στις παρουσιάσεις υπάρχουν πολλά γεγονότα για 
κάθε συνθέτη. Παρακαλώ αισθανθείτε ελεύθερος να κάνει σερφ
μεταξύ του διαφορετικών συνθέτη και των μορφών. Σαν 
σπουδαστές που συμμετέχουν στην κλάση, παρακαλώ σημειώστε ποιους 
συνθέτες μελετάμε στο παρόν και πηγαίνουμε μόνο στις 
φωτογραφικές διαφάνειές τους. Μερικοί από τους στόχους 
αυτής της ενότητας είναι να διδαχθεί σας η χώρα προέλευσης, 
μουσικής περιόδου ύφους, αναγνώρισης εικόνων, σημαντικών 
εργασιών και χρονικών επιτευγμάτων ζωής. Υπάρχουν 
διαγωνισμοοι γνώσεων, παιχνίδια, αποσπάσματα ακούσματος και πολύ 
περισσότερο. Πρέπει να ολοκληρώσετε τους πρώτους 11 
διαγωνισμοους γνώσεων για να είστε σε θέση να συνεχιστείτε. 
ΘΥΜΗΘΕΙΤΕ - μέσω της εκμάθησης για από μπροστά θα 
καταλάβετε λίγο περισσότεροι για το παρόν.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">A través de los siglos ha habido centenares de 
los compositores que sobresalieron durante sus períodos del estilo. 
Esto es una introducción a 11 de ellos que comienzan en el 
período barroco del estilo y que terminan en el vigésimo siglo. 
En las presentaciones hay muchos hechos sobre cada compositor. 
Siéntase por favor libre practicar surf entre el diversos 
compositor y estilos. Como estudiantes que participan en la 
clase, observe por favor qué compositores estamos estudiando en el 
presente y van solamente a sus diapositivas. Algunos de los 
objetivos de este módulo son enseñarle el país de origen, período 
musical del estilo, reconocimiento del cuadro, trabajos del comandante
y logros del tiempo de la vida. Hay concursos, juegos, extractos
que escuchan y mucho más. Usted debe terminar los primeros 11 
concursos para poder continuar. RECUERDE - con aprender sobre el
pasado usted entenderá poco más sobre el presente.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:KEVIN SEARS
FN:KEVIN SEARS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201935</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106158</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/famous-composers-i</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
