<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105850</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105850</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207192</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Alexander Graham Bell Family Papers, 1862-1939</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Alexander Graham Bell Familie Papiere, 
1862-1939</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Papiers de Famille d'Alexandre Graham Bell, 
1862-1939</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os Papéis Da Família De Alexander Graham Bell, 
1862-1939</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le Carte Dalla Famiglia Del Alexander Graham Bell,
1862-1939</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο Αλέξανδρος Graham Bell Family Papers, 
1862-1939</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los Papeles De la Familia De Alexander Graham 
Bell, 1862-1939</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">contains correspondence, scientific notebooks, journals, blueprints, articles, and photographs documenting the invention of the telephone, his involvement in the first telephone company, family life, interest in the education of the deaf, and aeronautical and other scientific research. Included is his notebook containing the entry from March 10, 1876, describing the first successful experiment with the telephone, during which he spoke the famous words, Mr. Watson, Come here, I want to see you.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">enthält Korrespondenz, wissenschaftliche 
Notizbücher, Journale, Lichtpausen, Artikel und die Fotographien, 
welche die Erfindung des Telefons, seine Miteinbeziehung in der ersten
Telefonfirma, Familienleben, Interesse an der Ausbildung der tauben 
und aeronautischen und anderen wissenschaftlichen Forschung 
dokumentieren. Ist beschreibt sein Notizbuch enthalten, das den 
Eintrag von einem März 10, 1876 enthält und das erste erfolgreiche 
Experiment mit dem Telefon, während dessen er die berühmten Wörter,
Herrn Watson sprach, hergekommen, ich, möchten Sie sehen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">contient la correspondance, les cahiers 
scientifiques, les journaux, les modèles, les articles, et les 
photographies documentant l'invention du téléphone, sa participation
à la première compagnie de téléphone, la vie de famille, intérêt
pour l'éducation de la recherche sourde, et aéronautique et autre 
scientifique. Inclus est son cahier contenant l'entrée à 
partir mars de 10, 1876, décrivant la première expérience réussie 
avec le téléphone, pendant lequel il a parlé les mots célèbres, 
M. Watson, venu ici, je veulent vous voir.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">contem a correspondência, cadernos científicos, 
jornais, blueprints, artigos, e fotografias que documentam a 
invenção do telefone, sua participação na primeira companhia do 
telefone, vida de família, interesse na instrução da pesquisa 
surda, e aeronáutica e outra científica. Incluído é seu 
caderno que contem a entrada março de 10, 1876, descrevendo a 
primeira experiência bem sucedida com o telefone, durante que falou 
as palavras famosas, Sr. Watson, vindo aqui, mim quer vê-lo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">contiene la corrispondenza, i taccuini 
scientifici, le pubblicazioni, i modelli, gli articoli e le fotografie
che documentano l'invenzione del telefono, la sua partecipazione alla 
prima azienda del telefono, la vita di famiglia, interesse nella 
formazione della ricerca sorda ed aeronautica ed altra scientifica. 
Incluso è il suo taccuino che contiene l'entrata da 10 marzo 
1876, descrivente il primo esperimento riuscito con il telefono, 
durante cui ha parlato le parole famose, il sig. Watson, venuto qui, 
io desidera vederlo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">περιέχει την αλληλογραφία, τα επιστημονικά 
σημειωματάρια, τα περιοδικά, τα σχεδιαγράμματα, τα άρθρα, και τις 
φωτογραφίες τεκμηριώνοντας την εφεύρεση του τηλεφώνου, η 
συμμετοχή του στην πρώτη τηλεφωνική επιχείρηση, οικογενειακή 
ζωή, ενδιαφέρον για την εκπαίδευση της κωφής, και αεροναυτικής 
και άλλης επιστημονικής έρευνας. Περιλαμβάνεται το 
σημειωματάριό του που περιέχει την είσοδο από τις 10 Μαρτίου 
..1876, περιγράφοντας το πρώτο επιτυχές πείραμα με το 
τηλέφωνο, κατά τη διάρκεια του οποίου μίλησε τις διάσημες 
λέξεις, ο κ. Watson, έρχεται εδώ, θέλω να σας δω.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">contiene correspondencia, los cuadernos 
científicos, los diarios, los modelos, los artículos, y las 
fotografías que documentan la invención del teléfono, su 
implicación en la primera compañía del teléfono, vida de familia, 
interés en la educación investigación sorda, y aeronáutica y de la
otra científica. Incluido es su cuaderno que contiene la 
entrada del de marcha 10 de 1876, describiendo el primer experimento 
acertado con el teléfono, durante el cual él habló las palabras 
famosas, Sr. Watson, venido aquí, yo desea verle.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207192</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105850</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-alexander-graham-bell-family-papers-1862-1939</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
