<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107826</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107826</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201109</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Creatures that "glow" in the night</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geschöpfe, die in die Nacht "glühen Sie"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Créatures qui "rougeoyez" la nuit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Criaturas que "incandesça" na noite</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Creature che "emetta luce" nella notte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πλάσματα που "καείτε" στη νύχτα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Criaturas que "brille intensamente" en la noche</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Wisconsin Center for Environmental Education activity (PDF) encourages students to practice experimental design and scientific writing through the study of bioluminescence. Students observe and experiment with bioluminescent dinoflagellates (Pyrocystis fusiformis), learning how and why they produce light. The activity includes information for teacher preparation, an introduction to bioluminescence, defined vocabulary terms, a list of necessary materials, procedure, assessment questions, and references.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Wisconsin Mitte für Klimaausbildung 
Aktivität (pdf) regt Kursteilnehmer an, experimentelles Design und 
wissenschaftliches Schreiben durch die Studie von bioluminescence zu 
üben. Kursteilnehmer beobachten und experimentieren mit 
bioluminescent dinoflagellates (Pyrocystis fusiformis) und erlernen 
wie und warum sie Licht produzieren. Die Aktivität schließt 
Informationen als Lehrervorbereitung, eine Einleitung zum 
bioluminescence, definierte Wortschatzbezeichnungen, eine Liste der 
notwendigen Materialien, Prozedur, Einschätzung Fragen und Referenzen
ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce centre du Wisconsin pour l'activité 
environnementale d'éducation (pdf) encourage des étudiants à 
pratiquer la conception expérimentale et l'écriture scientifique par
l'étude du bioluminescence. Les étudiants observent et 
expérimentent avec les dinoflagellates bioluminescent (fusiformis de 
Pyrocystis), apprenant comment et pourquoi ils produisent la lumière.
L'activité inclut l'information pour la préparation de 
professeur, une introduction au bioluminescence, des limites définies
de vocabulaire, une liste de matériaux nécessaires, le procédé, 
les questions d'évaluation, et les références.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este centro de Wisconsin para a atividade 
ambiental da instrução (pdf) incentiva estudantes praticar o projeto
experimental e a escrita científica com o estudo do bioluminescence. 
Os estudantes observam e experimentam com os dinoflagellates 
bioluminescent (fusiformis de Pyrocystis), aprendendo como e porque 
produzem a luz. A atividade inclui a informação para a 
preparação do professor, uma introdução ao bioluminescence, termos
definidos do vocabulário, uma lista de materiais necessários, o 
procedimento, as perguntas da avaliação, e as referências.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo centro del Wisconsin per attività 
ambientale di formazione (pdf) consiglia agli allievi esercitarsi nel 
disegno sperimentale e nella scrittura scientifica con lo studio del 
bioluminescence. Gli allievi osservano e sperimentano con i 
dinoflagellates bioluminescent (fusiformis di Pyrocystis), imparando 
come e perchè producono la luce. L'attività include le 
informazioni per la preparazione dell'insegnante, un'introduzione al 
bioluminescence, i concetti definiti di vocabolario, una lista dei 
materiali necessari, la procedura, le domande di valutazione ed i 
riferimenti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το κέντρο του Wisconsin για τη δραστηριότητα 
περιβαλλοντικής εκπαίδευσης (PDF) ενθαρρύνει τους σπουδαστές 
για να ασκήσει το πειραματικό σχέδιο και το επιστημονικό γράψιμο 
μέσω της μελέτης της βιολογικής ακτινοβολίας. Οι σπουδαστές
παρατηρούν και πειραματίζονται με τα βιοφωτοβόλα dinoflagellates
(fusiformis Pyrocystis), μαθαίνοντας πώς και γιατί παράγουν 
το φως. Η δραστηριότητα περιλαμβάνει τις πληροφορίες για την 
προετοιμασία δασκάλων, μια εισαγωγή στη βιολογική ακτινοβολία, 
τους καθορισμένους όρους λεξιλογίου, έναν κατάλογο απαραίτητων 
υλικών, τη διαδικασία, τις ερωτήσεις αξιολόγησης, και τις 
αναφορές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este centro de Wisconsin para la actividad 
ambiental de la educación (pdf) anima a estudiantes que practiquen 
diseño experimental y la escritura científica con el estudio del 
bioluminescence. Los estudiantes observan y experimentan con los
dinoflagellates bioluminescent (fusiformis de Pyrocystis), aprendiendo
cómo y porqué producen la luz. La actividad incluye la 
información para la preparación del profesor, una introducción al 
bioluminescence, los términos definidos del vocabulario, una lista de
materiales necesarios, el procedimiento, las preguntas del gravamen, y
las referencias.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:WISCONSIN CENTER FOR ENVIRONMENTAL EDUCATION
FN:WISCONSIN CENTER FOR ENVIRONMENTAL EDUCATION
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201109</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107826</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/creatures-that-glow-in-the-night</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
