<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104881</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104881</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212937</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">US Global Change Research Program</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">US Globales Änderung Forschung Programm</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Programme de recherche Global de Changement des 
USA</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Programa De Pesquisa Global Da Mudança dos E. U.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Programma di ricerca Globale Del Cambiamento degli
Stati Uniti</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ερευνητικό πρόγραμμα αμερικανικής σφαιρικό αλλαγής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Programa De Investigación Global Del Cambio de 
los E.E.U.U.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site contains a variety of information related to global change research and specifically the research efforts of the US Global Change Research Program (USGCRP). Some of the sections on this site include global change data from a variety of government agencies as well as reports from national and international research projects. Frequently updated lists of new research findings and calls for proposals are frequently accessed services of this website. Some of the topics covered on this site are: atmospheric composition, climate variability and change, global carbon and water cycles, and land use / land cover change. This resource is part of the Biocomplexity collection. http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site enthält eine Vielzahl der 
Informationen in Verbindung gestanden auf globaler Änderung Forschung
und spezifisch der Forschung Bemühungen des US globalen Änderung 
Forschung Programms (USGCRP). Einige der Kapitel auf dieser Site
schließen globale Änderung Daten von einer Vielzahl der 
Regierungsagenturen sowie Reports von den nationalen und 
internationalen Forschung Projekten ein. Häufig aktualisierte 
Listen der neuen Forschung Entdeckungen und der Aufrufe für Anträge 
sind häufig erreichte Services dieser Web site. Einige der 
Themen, die auf dieser Site umfaßt werden, sind: 
atmosphärischer Aufbau, Klimaveränderlichkeit und -änderung, 
globale Carbon- und Wasserschleifen und 
Flächennutzung-/Landabdeckungänderung. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist 
ein Teil der Biocomplexity Ansammlung 
http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site contient une variété d'information liée
à la recherche globale de changement et spécifiquement d'efforts de 
recherches du programme de recherche global de changement des USA 
(USGCRP). Certaines des sections sur ce site incluent des 
données globales de changement d'une variété d'organismes 
gouvernementaux aussi bien que des états des projets de recherche 
nationaux et internationaux. Les listes fréquemment à jour de 
nouveaux résultats et appels de recherches pour des propositions sont
fréquemment des services consultés de ce site Web. Certains 
des sujets couverts sur ce site sont : composition 
atmosphérique, variabilité et changement de climat, cycles globaux 
de carbone et d'eau, et changement d'utilisation de la 
terre/couverture de terre. Cette ressource fait partie de la 
collection http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/ de Biocomplexity</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local contem uma variedade da informação 
relacionada à pesquisa global da mudança e especificamente dos 
esforços da pesquisa do programa de pesquisa global da mudança dos 
E. U. (USGCRP). Algumas das seções neste local incluem dados 
globais da mudança de uma variedade de agências de governo 
as.well.as relatórios dos projetos de pesquisa nacionais e 
internacionais. As listas freqüentemente atualizadas de 
findings e de atendimentos novos da pesquisa para propostas são 
freqüentemente serviços alcançados deste Web site. Alguns dos
tópicos cobertos neste local são: composição atmosférica, 
variability e mudança do clima, ciclos globais do carbono e da água,
e mudança do uso de terra/tampa de terra. Este recurso é parte
da coleção http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/ de Biocomplexity</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo contiene una varietà di informazioni
relativa a ricerca globale del cambiamento e specificamente degli 
sforzi di ricerca del programma di ricerca globale del cambiamento 
degli Stati Uniti (USGCRP). Alcune delle sezioni su questo luogo
includono i dati globali del cambiamento da una varietà di enti 
governativi così come i rapporti dai progetti di ricerca nazionali ed
internazionali. Le liste frequentemente aggiornate di nuovi 
risultati ed inviti alla presentazione di proposte di ricerca sono 
frequentemente servizi raggiunti di questo Web site. Alcuni dei 
soggetti coperti su questo luogo sono: composizione atmosferica,
variabilità e cambiamento di clima, cicli globali dell'acqua e del 
carbonio e cambiamento di utilizzazione delle terre/tipi di terreno. 
Questa risorsa fa parte dell'accumulazione 
http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/ di Biocomplexity</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή περιέχει ποικίλες πληροφορίες 
σχετικές με τη σφαιρική έρευνα αλλαγής και συγκεκριμένα τις 
ερευνητικές προσπάθειες του ερευνητικού προγράμματος αμερικανικής
σφαιρικού αλλαγής (USGCRP). Μερικά από τα τμήματα αυτής
της περιοχής περιλαμβάνουν τα σφαιρικά στοιχεία αλλαγής από 
ποικίλες κυβερνητικές αντιπροσωπείες καθώς επίσης και τις 
εκθέσεις από τα εθνικά και διεθνή ερευνητικά προγράμματα. 
Οι συχνά ενημερωμένοι κατάλογοι νέων ερευνητικών 
συμπερασμάτων και προσκλήσεων υποβολής προτάσεων είναι συχνά 
προσεγγισμένες υπηρεσίες αυτού του ιστοχώρου. Μερικά από 
τα θέματα που καλύπτονται σε αυτήν την περιοχή είναι: 
ατμοσφαιρική σύνθεση, μεταβλητότητα και αλλαγή κλίματος, 
σφαιρικοί κύκλοι άνθρακα και ύδατος, και χρήση εδάφους/αλλαγή 
κάλυψης εδάφους. Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς είναι 
μέρος της Biocomplexity συλλογής 
http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio contiene una variedad de información 
relacionada con la investigación global del cambio y específicamente
de los esfuerzos de la investigación del programa de investigación 
global del cambio de los E.E.U.U. (USGCRP). Algunas de las 
secciones en este sitio incluyen datos globales del cambio de una 
variedad de agencias de estatal así como informes de proyectos de 
investigación nacionales e internacionales. Las listas con 
frecuencia puestas al día de los nuevos resultados y llamados para 
presentar propuestas de la investigación son con frecuencia servicios
alcanzados de este Web site. Algunos de los asuntos cubiertos en
este sitio son: composición atmosférica, variabilidad y cambio
del clima, ciclos globales del carbón y del agua, y cambio de la 
utilización del suelo/de la cubierta de pista. Este recurso es 
parte de la colección http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/ de 
Biocomplexity</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212937</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104881</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/us-global-change-research-program</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
