<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108464</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108464</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086342</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Is It Not Enough that We Are Torn From Our Country and Friends?": Olaudah Equiano Describes the Horrors of the Middle Passage, 1780s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ist es nicht genug, daß wir von unserem Land und
von Freunden?" heftig gezerrissen werden: Olaudah Equiano 
beschreibt die Grausigkeiten des mittleren Durchganges, 1780s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"est il pas assez que nous sommes déchirés de 
notre pays et amis?" : Olaudah Equiano décrit les horreurs du 
passage moyen, 1780s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"é não bastantes que nós estamos rasgados de 
nossos país e amigos?": Olaudah Equiano descreve os horrors da 
passagem média, 1780s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"è non abbastanza che siamo strappati dal nostri 
paese ed amici?": Olaudah Equiano descrive gli orrori del 
passaggio centrale, 1780s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Είναι όχι αρκετοί ότι είμαστε σχισμένοι από τη 
χώρα και τους φίλους μας;": Το Olaudah Equiano 
περιγράφει τις φρίκες της μέσης μετάβασης, 1780s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"está no bastantes que nos rasgan de nuestro 
país y amigos?": Olaudah Equiano describe los horrores del paso
medio, 1780s</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In one of the largest forced migrations in human history, up to 12 million Africans were sold as slaves to Europeans and shipped to the Americas. Most slaves were seized inland and marched to coastal forts, where they were chained below deck in ships for the journey across the Atlantic or "Middle Passage," under conditions designed to ship the largest number of people in the smallest space possible. Olaudah Equiano had been kidnapped from his family when he was 11 years old, carried off first to Barbados and then Virginia. After serving in the British navy, he was sold to a Quaker merchant from whom he purchased his freedom in 1766. His pioneering narrative of the journey from slavery to freedom, a bestseller first published in London in 1789, builds upon the traditions of spiritual narratives and travel literature to help create the slave narrative genre.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In einer der größten vorverlegten Migrationen in
der menschlichen Geschichte, wurden bis 12 Million Afrikaner als 
Sklaven zu Europäern verkauft und versendet in das Amerika. Die
meisten Sklaven waren ergriffenes inländisches und gegrenzt zu den 
Küstenforts, in denen sie unter Plattform in den Schiffen für die 
Reise über dem Atlantik oder "dem mittleren Durchgang angekettet 
wurden," unter Bedingungen konzipierte, die größte Zahl Leuten im 
kleinsten möglichen Platz zu versenden. Olaudah Equiano war von
seiner Familie, als er 11 Jahre alt war, trug weg zuerst zu Barbados 
und dann zu Virginia entführt worden. Nachdem man in der 
britischen Marine gedient hatte, wurde er an einen Quäkerkaufmann 
verkauft, von dem er seine Freiheit 1766 kaufte. Seine 
bahnbrechende Darstellung der Reise von Sklaverei zu Freiheit, des 
Bestsellers zuerst veröffentlicht in London 1789, der Bauten nach den
Traditionen der geistigen Darstellungen und der Spielraumliteratur, um
zu helfen, das erzählende Sklavengenren zu erstellen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans un des plus grands transferts obligatoires 
dans l'histoire humaine, jusqu'à 12 millions d'Africains ont été 
vendus sous le nom d'esclaves à Européens et expédiés en 
Amériques. La plupart des esclaves étaient intérieurs saisi 
et marché aux forts côtiers, où ils ont été enchaînés 
au-dessous du paquet dans des bateaux pour le voyage à travers 
l'Océan atlantique ou "le passage moyen," dans des conditions a 
conçu pour expédier le plus grand nombre de personnes dans le plus 
petit espace possible. Olaudah Equiano avait été enlevé de sa
famille quand il avait 11 ans, a porté hors fonction d'abord en 
Barbades et puis Virginie. Après avoir servi dans la marine 
britannique, il a été vendu à un négociant de quaker duquel il a 
acheté sa liberté en 1766. Son récit pilote du voyage de 
l'esclavage à la liberté, d'un best-seller d'abord édité à 
Londres en 1789, des constructions sur les traditions des récits 
spirituels et de la littérature de voyage pour aider à créer le 
genre narratif slave.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em uma das migrações forçadas as maiores no 
history humano, até 12 milhão africanos foram vendidos como escravos
a Europeus e enviados aos Americas. A maioria de escravos eram 
inland apreendido e marchado aos forts litorais, onde foram 
acorrentados abaixo da plataforma nos navios para a viagem através do
Atlântico ou "da passagem média," sob circunstâncias projetou 
enviar o número o maior dos povos no espaço o menor possível. 
Olaudah Equiano tinha sido sequestrado de sua família quando 
tinha 11 anos velho, carregou fora primeiramente a Barbados e então a
Virgínia. Após servir na marinha britânica, foi vendido a um 
comerciante do quaker de quem comprou sua liberdade em 1766. Sua
narrativa abrindo caminho da viagem do slavery à liberdade, de um 
bestseller publicado primeiramente em Londres em 1789, de 
configurações em cima das tradições de narrativas espirituais e de
literatura do curso para ajudar criar o genre narrativo slave.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In una di più grandi espansioni forzate nella 
storia umana, fino a 12 milione Africani sono stati venduti sotto il 
nome di schiavi ad Europei e sono stati spediti nei Americas. La
maggior parte dei schiavi erano interno grippato e marciato ai forts 
litoranei, in cui sono stati concatenati sotto la piattaforma in navi 
per il viaggio attraverso l'Atlantico o "il passaggio centrale," nelle
circostanze ha progettato spedire il più grande numero di gente nel 
più piccolo spazio possibile. Olaudah Equiano era stato 
rapinato dalla sua famiglia quando aveva 11 anno, ha trasportato fuori
in primo luogo in Barbados ed allora la Virginia. Dopo avere 
servito nel blu marino britannico, è stato venduto ad un commerciante
del quaker da quale ha comprato la sua libertà in 1766. La sua 
descrizione aprente la strada del viaggio da slavery a libertà, di un
bestseller in primo luogo pubblicato a Londra in 1789, delle 
configurazioni sulle tradizioni delle descrizioni spiritose e della 
letteratura di corsa per contribuire a creare il genere narrativo
slave.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε μια από τις μεγαλύτερες αναγκασμένες μεταναστεύσεις
στην ανθρώπινη ιστορία, μέχρι 12 εκατομμύριο Αφρικανοί 
πωλήθηκαν ως σκλάβοι στους Ευρωπαίους και στάλησαν στην Αμερική. 
Οι περισσότεροι σκλάβοι ήταν καταλήφθείτι εσωτερικοί και 
βαδισμένος στα παράκτια οχυρά, όπου αλυσοδέθηκαν κάτω από το 
κατάστρωμα στα πλοία για το ταξίδι πέρα από την ατλαντική ή 
"μέση μετάβαση," υπό τους όρους με σκοπό να στείλουν το 
μεγαλύτερο αριθμό ανθρώπων μικρότερο διαστημικό στον πιθανό. 
Το Olaudah Equiano ήταν απαγμένο από την οικογένειά 
του όταν ήταν 11 ετών, έφερε μακριά πρώτα στα Μπαρμπάντος 
και έπειτα τη Βιρτζίνια. Μετά από να εξυπηρετήσει στο 
βρετανικό ναυτικό, πωλήθηκε σε έναν κουάκερο έμπορο από τον 
οποίο αγόρασε την ελευθερία του 1766. Το πρωτοποριακό 
αφήγημά του του ταξιδιού από τη σκλαβιά στην ελευθερία, ένα 
best-$l*seller που δημοσιεύεται πρώτα στο Λονδίνο το 1789, 
χτίζει επάνω στις παραδόσεις των πνευματικών αφηγημάτων και της 
λογοτεχνίας ταξιδιού για να βοηθήσει να δημιουργήσει το 
αφηγηματικό ύφος σκλάβων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En una de las migraciones forzadas más grandes de
la historia humana, vendieron como esclavos a europeos y fueron 
enviados a hasta 12 millones de africanos a las Américas. La 
mayoría de los esclavos eran interiores agarrado y marchado a las 
fortalezas costeras, donde fueron encadenados debajo de cubierta en 
las naves para el viaje a través del Atlántico o del "paso medio," 
bajo condiciones diseñó enviar el número más grande de la gente en
el espacio más pequeño posible. Olaudah Equiano había sido 
secuestrado de su familia cuando él era 11 años de viejo, 
llevó apagado primero a Barbados y entonces a Virginia. 
Después de servir en la marina de guerra británica, lo vendieron a 
un comerciante del quaker de quien él compró su libertad en 1766. 
Su narrativa pionera del viaje de la esclavitud a la libertad, 
de un bestseller primero publicado en Londres en 1789, de estructuras 
sobre las tradiciones de narrativas espirituales y de la literatura 
del recorrido para ayudar a crear el género narrativo auxiliar.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086342</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108464</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/is-it-not-enough-that-we-are-torn-from-our-country-and-friends-olaudah-equiano-describes-the-horrors-of-the-middle-passage-1780s</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
