<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103823</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103823</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206324</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Experiencing War (Voices of War): Stories from the Veterans History Project</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erfahren des Krieges (Stimmen des Krieges): 
Geschichten vom Veteran-Geschichte Projekt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Expérience de la guerre (voix de guerre) : 
Histoires du projet d'histoire de vétérans</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Experimentando a guerra (vozes da guerra): 
Histórias do projeto do history dos veterans</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Avvertire guerra (voci della guerra): Storia
dal progetto di storia dei veterani</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βίωση του πολέμου (φωνές του πολέμου): Ιστορίες
από το πρόγραμμα ιστορίας παλαιμάχων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Experimentar la guerra (voces de la guerra): 
Historias del proyecto de la historia de los veteranos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is the companion website for a book from the Veterans History Project. Video interviews, photos, and letters relate war through the eyes of 60 veterans and civilians. Stories are organized by book sections -- answering the call, a day in the life, combat, coming home -- and by themes: courage, life-altering moments, hurry up and wait, D-Day, POWs.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist die Begleiterweb site für ein Buch vom 
Veteran-Geschichte Projekt. Bildschirminterviews, -fotos und 
-zeichen stehen Krieg durch die Augen von 60 Veteranen und von 
Zivilisten in Verbindung. Geschichten werden durch Buchkapitel 
-- den Aufruf beantwortend, ein Tag in der Lebensdauer, Kampf, nach 
Hause kommen -- und durch Themen organisiert: Mut, Momente, Hast
und Wartezeit, D-Tag, POWs oben Lebensdauer-ändernd.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est le site Web de compagnon pour un livre du 
projet d'histoire de vétérans. Les entrevues, les photos, et 
les lettres de vidéo associent la guerre par les yeux de 60 
vétérans et civils. Des histoires sont organisées par des 
sections de livre -- répondant à l'appel, un jour dans la vie, 
combat, venir à la maison -- et par des thèmes : courage, 
vie-modifiant des moments, la hâte vers le haut et l'attente, 
jour J, prisonniers de guerre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é o Web site do companheiro para um livro do 
projeto do history dos veterans. As entrevistas, as fotos, e as 
letras do vídeo relacionam a guerra através dos olhos de 60 veterans
e civis. As histórias são organizadas por seções do livro --
respondendo ao atendimento, um dia na vida, combate, vinda para casa 
-- e por temas: coragem, vida-alterando momentos, pressa acima e
espera, D-Dia, POWs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è il Web site del compagno per un libro dal 
progetto di storia dei veterani. Le interviste, le foto e le 
lettere del video collegano la guerra attraverso gli occhi di 60 
veterani e civili. Le storia sono organizzate dalle sezioni del 
libro -- rispondendo alla chiamata, un giorno nella vita, 
combattimento, venire a casa -- e dai temi: coraggio, 
vita-alterante i momenti, fretta in su ed attesa, D-Giorno, POWs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι ο ιστοχώρος συντρόφων για ένα βιβλίο από το 
πρόγραμμα ιστορίας παλαιμάχων. Οι τηλεοπτικές συνεντεύξεις,
οι φωτογραφίες, και οι επιστολές αφορούν τον πόλεμο μέσω των 
ματιών 60 παλαιμάχων και πολιτών. Οι ιστορίες 
οργανώνονται από τα τμήματα βιβλίων -- που απαντούν στην κλήση, 
μια ημέρα στη ζωή, αγώνας, που έρχεται κατ' οίκον -- και από τα 
θέματα: το θάρρος, ζωή-αλλάζοντας στιγμές, βιασύνη επάνω 
και περιμένει, μέρα-μ, POWs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es el Web site del compañero para un libro del 
proyecto de la historia de los veteranos. Las entrevistas, las 
fotos, y las cartas del vídeo relacionan guerra a través de los ojos
de 60 veteranos y civiles. Las historias son ordenadas por las 
secciones del libro -- contestando a la llamada, un día en la vida, 
combate, el venir a casa -- y por temas: valor, vida-alterando 
momentos, prisa para arriba y la espera, D-Di'a, POWs.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206324</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103823</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/experiencing-war-voices-of-war-stories-from-the-veterans-history-project</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
