<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108423</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108423</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973984</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Child Soldiers: A Webquest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kind-Soldaten: Ein Webquest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Soldats d'Enfant : Un Webquest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Soldados Da Criança: Um Webquest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Soldati Del Bambino: Un Webquest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στρατιώτες παιδιών: Ένα Webquest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Soldados Del Niño: Un Webquest</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The goal of this WebQuest is to answer one big question: What should be done about child soldiers? While students grapple with this question, they will be asked to make the connection between their own lives and the lives of child soldiers. In addition, they will approach this issue from different perspectives within a given society and to make recommendations on what should be done to resolve it. A WebQuest is an inquiry-based activity in which most of the information that students use to complete a task comes from resources on the Internet. Students analyze information, transform it in some way, and then demonstrate knowledge of the material by creating something to which others can respond.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <language>ru</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Ziel von diesem WebQuest ist, eine grosse 
Frage zu beantworten: Was sollte über Kindsoldaten getan 
werden? Während Kursteilnehmer mit dieser Frage sich 
festhalten, werden sie gebeten, die Beziehung zwischen ihren eigenen 
Leben und den Leben der Kindsoldaten herzustellen. Zusätzlich 
nähern sich sie dieser Ausgabe von den unterschiedlichen Perspektiven
innerhalb einer gegebenen Gesellschaft und bilden Empfehlungen auf, 
was getan werden sollte, um sie zu beheben. Ein WebQuest ist 
eine Anfrage-gegründete Aktivität, in der die meisten der 
Informationen, die Kursteilnehmergebrauch, eine Aufgabe durchzuführen
von den Betriebsmitteln auf dem Internet kommt. Kursteilnehmer 
analysieren Informationen, wandeln sie auf gewisse Weise um und 
demonstrieren dann Wissen des Materials, indem sie etwas erstellen, 
auf das andere reagieren können.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le but de ce WebQuest est de répondre à une 
grande question : Que devrait être fait au sujet des soldats 
d'enfant ? Tandis que les étudiants s'attaquent à cette 
question, ils seront invités à établir le rapport entre leurs 
propres vies et les vies des soldats d'enfant. En outre, ils 
approcheront cette issue de différentes perspectives chez une 
société donnée et feront des recommandations concernant ce qui 
devrait être fait pour la résoudre. Un WebQuest est une 
activité enquête-basée dans laquelle la majeure partie 
d'information que l'utilisation d'étudiants de terminer un charger
vient des ressources sur l'Internet. Les étudiants analysent 
l'information, la transforment d'une manière quelconque, et 
démontrent alors la connaissance du matériel en créant quelque 
chose à laquelle d'autres peuvent répondre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O objetivo deste WebQuest é responder a uma 
pergunta grande: Que deve ser feito sobre soldados da criança? 
Quando os estudantes grapple com esta pergunta, estarão pedidos
para fazer a conexão entre suas próprias vidas e as vidas de 
soldados da criança. Além, aproximarão esta edição dos 
perspectives diferentes dentro de uma sociedade dada e farão 
recomendações em o que deve ser feito para a resolver. Um 
WebQuest é uma atividade inquérito-baseada em que a maioria da 
informação que o uso dos estudantes terminar uma tarefa vem dos 
recursos no Internet. Os estudantes analisam a informação, 
transformam-na em alguma maneira, e demonstram-nos então o 
conhecimento do material criando algo a que outros podem responder.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'obiettivo di questo WebQuest è di rispondere ad
una domanda grande: Che cosa dovrebbe essere fatto circa i 
soldati del bambino? Mentre gli allievi affrontano with questo 
problema, saranno chiesti di fare il collegamento fra le loro proprie 
vite e le vite dei soldati del bambino. In più, si 
avvicineranno a questa edizione dalle prospettive differenti presso 
una data società e faranno le raccomandazioni su che cosa dovrebbe 
essere fatto per risolverla. Un WebQuest è un'attività 
inchiesta-basata in cui la maggior parte delle informazioni che l'uso 
degli allievi completare un'operazione viene dalle risorse sul 
Internet. Gli allievi analizzano le informazioni, le trasformano
in qualche modo ed allora dimostrano la conoscenza del materiale 
creando qualcosa a cui altri possano rispondere.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο στόχος αυτού του WebQuest είναι να απαντηθεί μια 
μεγάλη ερώτηση: Τι θα έπρεπε να γίνει για τους στρατιώτες 
παιδιών; Ενώ οι σπουδαστές καταπιάνονται με αυτήν την 
ερώτηση, θα κληθούν να κάνουν τη σύνδεση μεταξύ των ζωών τους 
και των ζωών των στρατιωτών παιδιών. Επιπλέον, θα 
πλησιάσουν αυτό το ζήτημα από τις διαφορετικές προοπτικές μέσα 
σε μια δεδομένη κοινωνία και θα υποβάλουν συστάσεις σχετικά με 
αυτό που πρέπει να γίνει για να το επιλύσει. Ένα 
WebQuest είναι μια έρευνα-βασισμένη στον δραστηριότητα στην 
οποία η μεγαλύτερη μέρος των πληροφοριών που οι σπουδαστές 
χρησιμοποιούν για να ολοκληρώσουν μια υποχρέωση προέρχεται από τα
στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς στο διαδίκτυο. Οι σπουδαστές αναλύουν
τις πληροφορίες, τις μετασχηματίζουν με κάποιο τρόπο, και 
καταδεικνύουν έπειτα τη γνώση του υλικού με τη δημιουργία κάτι 
στο οποίο άλλα μπορούν να αποκριθούν.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La meta de este WebQuest es contestar a una 
pregunta grande: ¿Qué se debe hacer sobre soldados del niño? 
Mientras que los estudiantes atacan con esta pregunta, les 
pedirán hacer la conexión entre sus propias vidas y las vidas de los
soldados del niño. Además, acercarán a esta edición de 
diversas perspectivas dentro de una sociedad dada y harán 
recomendaciones en qué se debe hacer para resolverla. Un 
WebQuest es una actividad pregunta-basada en la cual la mayoría de la
información que el uso de los estudiantes de terminar una tarea viene
de recursos en el Internet. Los estudiantes analizan la 
información, la transforman de una cierta manera, y después 
demuestran el conocimiento del material creando algo a el cual otros 
pueden responder.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973984</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108423</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/child-soldiers-a-webquest</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
