<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104410</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104410</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206992</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Liberty, Equality, Fraternity: Exploring the French Revolution</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Freiheit, Gleichheit, Vereinigung: 
Erforschen der Französischen Revolution</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Liberté, Égalité, Fraternité : Explorer 
la révolution française</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Liberdade, Igualdade, Fraternity: Explorando
a volta francesa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Libertà, Uguaglianza, Classe: Esplorazione 
della rivoluzione francese</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ελευθερία, ισότητα, αδελφότητα: Εξερεύνηση της 
γαλλικής επανάστασης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Libertad, Igualdad, Fraternidad: Explorar la
revolución francesa</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is an introduction to the French Revolution and an archive of important documentary evidence from the Revolution, including more than 300 texts, nearly 250 images, and a number of maps and songs. Ten essays explore the major topics in the history of the revolution, including its social causes, the fall of the monarchy, women and the revolution, the story of Napoleon, and the legacies of the Revolution.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist eine Einleitung zur Französischen Revolution 
und zu einem Archiv der wichtigen Beweisurkunde von der Umdrehung, 
einschließlich mehr als 300 Texte, fast 250 Bilder und eine Anzahl 
von Karten und Lieden. 10 Versuche erforschen die Hauptthemen in
der Geschichte der Umdrehung, einschließlich seine Sozialursachen, 
der Fall der Monarchie, Frauen und die Umdrehung, die Geschichte 
von Napoleon und die Legacy der Umdrehung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est une introduction à la révolution française 
et des archives de titre justificatif important de la révolution, y 
compris plus de 300 textes, presque 250 images, et un certain nombre 
de cartes et de chansons. Dix essais explorent les sujets 
principaux dans l'histoire de la révolution, y compris ses causes 
sociales, la chute de la monarchie, des femmes et la révolution, 
l'histoire de Napoleon, et les legs de la révolution.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é uma introdução à volta francesa e um arquivo
da evidência documentary importante da volta, including mais de 300 
textos, quase 250 imagens, e um número mapas e de canções. 
Dez essays exploram os tópicos principais no history da volta, 
including suas causas sociais, a queda do monarchy, mulheres e a 
volta, a história de Napoleon, e os legacies da volta.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è un'introduzione alla rivoluzione francese e un 
archivio di prova documentata importante dalla rivoluzione, compresi 
più di 300 testi, quasi 250 immagini ed un certo numero di programmi 
e di canzoni. Dieci saggi esplorano i soggetti principali nella 
storia della rivoluzione, compreso le relative cause sociali, la 
caduta del monarchy, donne e la rivoluzione, la storia di Napoleon e 
le eredità della rivoluzione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι μια εισαγωγή στη γαλλική επανάσταση και ένα 
αρχείο των σημαντικών αποδεικτικών στοιχείων από την επανάσταση,
που περιλαμβάνει περισσότερα από 300 κείμενα, σχεδόν 250 
εικόνες, και διάφορους χάρτες και τραγούδια. Δέκα δοκίμια 
ερευνούν τα σημαντικότερα θέματα την ιστορία της επανάστασης, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένων των κοινωνικών αιτιών του, το φθινόπωρο της 
μοναρχίας, τις γυναίκες και την επανάσταση, την ιστορία 
Napoleon, και τις κληρονομιές της επανάστασης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">está una introducción a la revolución francesa 
y un archivo del certificado justificativo importante de la 
revolución, incluyendo más de 300 textos, casi 250 imágenes, y un 
número de correspondencias y de canciones. Diez ensayos 
exploran los asuntos principales en la historia de la revolución, 
incluyendo sus causas sociales, la caída de la monarquía, las 
mujeres y la revolución, la historia de Napoleon, y las herencias de 
la revolución.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206992</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104410</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/liberty-equality-fraternity-exploring-the-french-revolution</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
