<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107715</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107715</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206599</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Holocaust Memorial Museum: For Students</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Holocaust Erinnerungsmuseum: Für 
Kursteilnehmer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Musée Holocauste Commémoratif : Pour des 
Étudiants</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Museu Memorial De Holocaust: Para 
Estudantes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Museo Commemorativo Di Holocaust: Per Gli 
Allievi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αναμνηστικό μουσείο ολοκαυτώματος: Για τους 
σπουδαστές</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Museo Conmemorativo De Holocaust: Para Los 
Estudiantes</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">offers multimedia exhibits filled with artifacts and photos that help students learn about the Holocaust. Topics include Kristallnacht, the St. Louis ocean liner, the rescue of the Jews of Denmark, Oskar Schindler, the Social Sciencesaw ghetto uprising, Father Jacques, the dress of Lola Rein, Nazi book burnings, Dietrich Bonhoeffer, America's responses, Arthur Szyk, maps, and children.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Angebotmultimediaausstellungen füllten mit 
Kunstprodukten und Fotos, die Kursteilnehmern helfen, über das 
Holocaust zu erlernen. Themen enthalten Kristallnacht, den St. 
Louis Ozeandampfer, die Rettung der Juden von Dänemark, Oskar 
Schindler, der Sozialsciencesaw Gettoaufstieg, Vater Jacques, das 
Kleid des Lola Zügels, der Nazi Buch burnings, des Dietrich 
Bonhoeffer, Antworten Amerikas, des Arthurs Szyk, der Karten und der 
Kinder.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les objets exposés de multimédia d'offres ont 
rempli d'objets façonnés et de photos qui aident des étudiants à 
se renseigner sur Holocauste. Les sujets incluent 
Kristallnacht, le recouvrement d'océan de St Louis, la délivrance 
des juifs du Danemark, Oskar Schindler, le soulèvement social de 
ghetto de Sciencesaw, père Jacques, la robe de la rêne de Lola, 
des burnings Nazis de livre, du Dietrich Bonhoeffer, les 
réponses de l'Amérique, du Arthur Szyk, des cartes, et des enfants.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">as exibições dos multimedia das ofertas 
encheram-se com os artifacts e as fotos que ajudam a estudantes 
aprender sobre o Holocaust. Os tópicos incluem Kristallnacht, o
forro de oceano do St. Louis, o salvamento dos jews de Dinamarca, 
Oskar Schindler, o uprising social do ghetto de Sciencesaw, pai 
Jacques, o vestido da rédea de Lola, de burnings nazi do livro, de 
Dietrich Bonhoeffer, respostas de América, de Arthur Szyk, de mapas, 
e de crianças.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">le esposizioni di multimedia di offerte si sono 
riempite di manufatti e di foto che aiutano gli allievi ad imparare 
circa il Holocaust. I soggetti includono Kristallnacht, il 
rivestimento di oceano de St. Louis, il salvataggio degli ebrei della 
Danimarca, Oskar Schindler, la rivolta sociale del ghetto di 
Sciencesaw, padre Jacques, il vestito della redine di Lola, dei 
burnings Nazisti del libro, di Dietrich Bonhoeffer, risposte 
dell'America, di Arthur Szyk, dei programmi e dei bambini.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">προσφέρει τα εκθέματα πολυμέσων που γεμίζουν με τα 
χειροποίητα αντικείμενα και τις φωτογραφίες που βοηθούν τους 
σπουδαστές να μάθουν για το ολοκαύτωμα. Τα θέματα 
περιλαμβάνουν Kristallnacht, το υπερωκεάνειο του ST Louis, 
τη διάσωση των Εβραίων της Δανίας, Oskar Schindler, την 
κοινωνική έγερση γκέτο Sciencesaw, τον πατέρα Ζακ, το φόρεμα 
του ηνίου Lola, το ναζιστικό κάψιμο βιβλίων, Dietrich 
Bonhoeffer, απαντήσεις της Αμερικής, αρθούρο Szyk, τους 
χάρτες, και τα παιδιά.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">los objetos expuestos de las multimedias de las 
ofertas llenaron de los artefactos y de las fotos que ayudan a 
estudiantes a aprender sobre el Holocaust. Los asuntos incluyen 
Kristallnacht, el revestimiento marino de St. Louis, el rescate de los
judíos de Dinamarca, Oskar Schindler, la sublevación social del 
ghetto de Sciencesaw, padre Jacques, la alineada de la rienda de Lola,
de los burnings nazis del libro, de Dietrich Bonhoeffer, respuestas de
América, de Arturo Szyk, de correspondencias, y de niños.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206599</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107715</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/holocaust-memorial-museum-for-students</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
