<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104528</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104528</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086913</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Canal Boat: Nathaniel Hawthorne Travels the Erie Canal</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Kanal-Boot: Nathaniel Hawthorne 
Spielräume der Erie Kanal</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Bateau de Canal : Voyages de Nathaniel 
Hawthorne le canal d'Erie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Barco Do Canal: Cursos de Nathaniel 
Hawthorne o canal de erie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Crogiolo Di Canale: Corse di Nathaniel 
Hawthorne il canale di Erie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η βάρκα καναλιών: Το Nathaniel Hawthorne 
ταξιδεύει το κανάλι του Erie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Barco Del Canal: Recorridos de Nathaniel 
Hawthorne el canal de Erie</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the decades after the American Revolution, improvements in transportation facilitated the growth of internal commerce in the United States. State and local governments planned turnpikes, roads, and canals, and New York State built the grandest one of the era: the Erie Canal. The Erie Canal was constructed at public expense by thousands of laborers between 1817 and 1825. The canal stretched 364 miles from Albany to Buffalo and linked the new nation's heartlands in the Great Lakes and Ohio Valley with New York City and the Atlantic coastal trade. Nathaniel Hawthorne recorded his travels along the waterway in this 1835 sketch, noting the traffic in goods and people along with the rise in commercial activity along its path. The canal and other improvements, however, also threatened farmers 'abilities to withstand the market's fluctuations and maintain local sufficiency.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In den Dekaden nach der amerikanischen Umdrehung, 
erleichterten Verbesserungen im Transport das Wachstum des 
Binnenhandels in den Vereinigten Staaten. Zustand und lokale 
Regierungen geplante turnpikes, Straßen und Kanäle und Staat 
New-York bauten das großartigste der Ära auf: der Erie Kanal. 
Der Erie Kanal wurde an den Staatsausgaben von den Tausenden 
Arbeitern zwischen 1817 und 1825 konstruiert. Der Kanal dehnte 
364 Meilen von Albanien zum Büffel aus und band die neuen Heartlands 
der Nation in den Great Lakes und Ohio Senke mit New York City und dem
atlantischen Küstenhandel. Nathaniel Hawthorne speicherte seine
Spielräume entlang der Wasser-Strasse in dieser Skizze 1835 und 
beachtete den Verkehr in den Waren und in den Leuten zusammen mit dem 
Anstieg in der kommerziellen Aktivität entlang seinem Pfad. Der
Kanal und andere Verbesserungen jedoch Fähigkeiten der auch bedrohten
Landwirte ', den Preisschwankungen zu widerstehen und lokale 
Hinlänglichkeit beizubehalten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans les décennies après la révolution 
américaine, les améliorations dans le transport ont facilité la 
croissance du commerce interne aux Etats-Unis. Les péages 
d'état et de gouvernements locaux, les routes, et les canaux, et 
l'état de New-York prévus ont construit le plus grand de l'ère : 
le canal d'Erie. Le canal d'Erie a été construit à un 
coût public par des milliers de travailleurs entre 1817 et 1825. 
Le canal a étiré 364 milles d'Albany à Buffalo et a joint de 
la nouvelle les centres nation dans les Great Lakes et la vallée de 
l'Ohio avec New York City et le commerce côtier atlantique. 
Nathaniel Hawthorne a enregistré ses voyages le long de la voie
d'eau dans ce croquis 1835, notant le trafic dans les marchandises et 
les personnes avec l'élévation de l'activité commerciale le long de
sa voie d'accès. Le canal et d'autres améliorations, 
cependant, capacités de fermiers également menacés 'de résister 
aux fluctuations du marché et de mettre à jour la suffisance locale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nas décadas após a volta americana, as melhorias 
no transporte facilitaram o crescimento do comércio interno nos 
estados unidos. Os turnpikes do estado e dos governos locais, as
estradas, e os canais, e o estado de New York de planeamento 
construíram o mais grande da era: o canal de erie. O 
canal de erie foi construído na despesa pública por milhares dos 
laborers entre 1817 e 1825. O canal esticou 364 milhas de Albany
ao búfalo e ligou os heartlands da nação nova nos Great Lakes e o 
vale de Ohio com o New York City e o comércio litoral atlantic. 
Nathaniel Hawthorne gravou seus cursos ao longo do canal neste 
esboço 1835, anotando o tráfego nos bens e nos povos junto com a 
ascensão na atividade comercial ao longo de seu trajeto. O 
canal e outras melhorias, entretanto, abilidades dos fazendeiros 
também ameaçados ' de suportar as flutuações de mercado e de 
manter o sufficiency local.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nelle decadi dopo la rivoluzione americana, i 
miglioramenti in trasporto hanno facilitato lo sviluppo del commercio 
interno in unito Dichiara. Dichiari e turnpikes 
di enti pubblici territoriali, strade e canali previsti e New York 
Dichiara ha costruito quello più grande dell'era: il 
canale di Erie. Il canale di Erie è stato costruito a spesa 
pubblica dai migliaia dei lavoratori fra 1817 e 1825. Il canale 
ha allungato 364 miglia da Albany alla Buffalo ed ha collegato i 
heartlands della nuova nazione nei Great Lakes e la valle dell'Ohio 
con New York City ed il commercio litoraneo atlantico. Nathaniel
Hawthorne ha registrato le sue corse lungo il canale navigabile in 
questo abbozzo 1835, notando il traffico in merci e nella gente con 
l'aumento nell'attività commerciale lungo il relativo percorso. 
Il canale ed altri miglioramenti, tuttavia, capacità dei 
coltivatori anche minacciati 'di sostenere le fluttuazioni del mercato
e di effettuare sufficienza locale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στις δεκαετίες μετά από την αμερικανική επανάσταση, 
οι βελτιώσεις στη μεταφορά διευκόλυναν την αύξηση εσωτερικό 
εμπόριο στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες. Το κράτος και οι τοπικές 
κυβερνήσεις προγραμμάτισαν τους φραγμούς, τους δρόμους, και τα 
κανάλια, και το κράτος της Νέας Υόρκης έχτισε την μεγαλύτερη μια
από την εποχή: το κανάλι του Erie. Το κανάλι του 
Erie κατασκευάστηκε με δημόσια έξοδα από χιλιάδες laborers 
μεταξύ 1817 και 1825. Το κανάλι τέντωσε 364 μίλια 
από το Αλμπανυ στους βούβαλους και σύνδεσε τις ενδοχώρες του
νέου έθνους στις μεγάλες λίμνες και την κοιλάδα του Οχάιου με 
την πόλη της Νέας Υόρκης και το ατλαντικό παράκτιο εμπόριο. 
Το Nathaniel Hawthorne κατέγραψε τα ταξίδια του κατά 
μήκος της υδάτινης οδού σε αυτά τα 1835 σκιαγραφεί, 
σημειώνοντας την κυκλοφορία στα αγαθά και τους ανθρώπους μαζί με 
την άνοδο στην εμπορική δραστηριότητα κατά μήκος του μονοπατιού 
του. Το κανάλι και άλλες βελτιώσεις, εντούτοις, επίσης 
δυνατότητες απείλησαν των αγροτών "να αντισταθούν τις 
διακυμάνσεις της αγοράς και να διατηρήσουν την τοπική επάρκεια.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En las décadas después de la revolución 
americana, las mejoras en el transporte facilitaron el crecimiento del
comercio interno en los Estados Unidos. Los turnpikes del estado
y de los gobiernos locales, los caminos, y los canales, y el estado de
Nueva York previstos construyeron el más magnífico de la era: 
el canal de Erie. El canal de Erie fue construido en el 
costo público por millares de trabajadores entre 1817 y 1825. 
El canal estiró 364 millas de Albany al búfalo y conectó los 
heartlands de la nueva nación en los Great Lakes y el valle de Ohio a
New York City y al comercio costero atlántico. Nathaniel 
Hawthorne registró sus recorridos a lo largo del canal en este 
bosquejo 1835, observando el tráfico en mercancías y la gente junto 
con la subida de la actividad comercial a lo largo de su camino. 
El canal y otras mejoras, sin embargo, capacidades de los 
granjeros también amenazados ' de soportar las fluctuaciones de 
mercado y de mantener desahogo local.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086913</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104528</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-canal-boat-nathaniel-hawthorne-travels-the-erie-canal</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
