<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106408</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106408</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206377</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Petition Signed by Thomas A. Edison for Sunday Openings at the World's Columbian Exposition</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Petition unterzeichnete durch Thomas A. Edison 
für Sonntag Öffnungen an der kolumbianischen Ausstellung der Welt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La pétition a signé par Thomas A. Edison pour 
des ouvertures de dimanche à l'exposition colombienne du monde</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A petição assinou por Thomas A. Edison para 
aberturas de domingo na exposição columbian do mundo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La petizione ha firmato da Thomas A. Edison per le
aperture di domenica all'esposizione colombiana del mondo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αίτηση που υπογράφεται από τον Thomas A. 
Edison για τις ενάρξεις της Κυριακής στην παγκόσμια κολομβιανή 
έκθεση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La petición firmó por Thomas A. Edison para las 
aperturas de domingo en la exposición colombina del mundo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">focuses on petitioning the federal government, peaceably assembling, and exercising freedom of speech and religion, all of which are protected by the First Amendment to the Constitution. This lesson correlates to the National History Standards and the National Standards for Civics and Social Sciences.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Foki auf dem Ersuchen der Bundesregierung, 
friedlich zusammenbauen und der Ausübung von von Freiheit der Rede 
und der Religion, die durch die erste Änderung zur Beschaffenheit 
geschützt werden. Diese Lektion bezieht mit den nationalen 
Geschichte Standards und den nationalen Standards für 
Gemeinschaftskunde und Sozialwissenschaften aufeinander.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">foyers sur pétitionner le gouvernement fédéral,
se réunir pacifiquement, et exercer la liberté de la parole et de 
religion, qui sont protégés par le premier amendement à la 
constitution. Cette leçon se corrèle avec les normes 
nationales d'histoire et les normes nationales pour l'éducation 
civique et les sciences sociales.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">focos em peticionar o governo federal, na montagem
peaceably, e em exercitar a liberdade do discurso e da religião, que 
são protegidos pela primeira emenda ao constitution. Esta 
lição correlaciona aos padrões nacionais do history e aos padrões 
nacionais para o civics e ciências sociais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fuochi sul fare una petizione il governo federale,
peaceably sul montaggio e sull'esercitare libertà di discorso e della
religione, che sono protetti tramite la prima correzione alla 
costituzione. Questa lezione correla agli standard nazionali di 
storia ed agli standard nazionali per civics e le scienze sociali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εστίαση στην υποβολή αίτησης της ομοσπονδιακής 
κυβέρνησης, συγκεντρώνοντας peaceably, και ασκώντας την 
ελευθερία της ομιλίας και της θρησκείας, οι οποίες προστατεύονται
από την πρώτη τροποποίηση στο σύνταγμα. Αυτό το μάθημα 
συσχετίζει στα εθνικά πρότυπα ιστορίας και τα εθνικά πρότυπα για
Civics και τις κοινωνικές επιστήμες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">focos en solicitar el gobierno federal, peaceably 
ensamblar, y ejercitar la libertad del discurso y de la religión, que
son protegidos por la primera enmienda a la constitución. Esta 
lección correlaciona a los estándares nacionales de la historia y a 
los estándares nacionales para el civics y las ciencias sociales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206377</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106408</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/petition-signed-by-thomas-a-edison-for-sunday-openings-at-the-worlds-columbian-exposition</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
