<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104156</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104156</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211871</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Red Tide</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Rote Gezeiten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Marée Rouge</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Maré Vermelha</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Marea Rossa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κόκκινη παλίρροια</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Marea Roja</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Nova Scotia museum informational web page represents the Red Tide section of an online collection about poisonous plants. The page reviews several microscopic marine algae that are notoriously poisonous to humans, featuring links to images and descriptions of each. The page also discusses a typical poisoning scenario and briefly reviews the pathology and toxicology of these toxins.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Neuschottland Museum informatorische 
Webseite stellt das rote Gezeitenkapitel einer Onlineansammlung 
über giftige Betriebe dar. Die Seite wiederholt einige 
mikroskopische Marinealgen, die notorisch zu den Menschen giftig sind 
und kennzeichnet bindet mit Bildern und Beschreibungen von jedem. 
Die Seite behandelt auch ein typisches Vergiftung Drehbuch und 
wiederholt kurz die Pathologie und die Toxikologie dieser Giftstoffe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette page Web informationnelle de musée de la
Nouvelle-Écosse représente la section rouge de marée d'une 
collection en ligne au sujet des usines toxiques. La page passe 
en revue plusieurs algues marines microscopiques qui sont notoirement 
toxiques aux humains, comportant joint aux images et aux descriptions 
de chacun. La page discute également un scénario typique 
d'empoisonnement et passe en revue brièvement la pathologie et la 
toxicologie de ces toxines.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Web page informativo do museu de Nova 
Escócia representa a seção vermelha da maré de uma coleção em 
linha sobre plantas venenosas. A página revê diversas algas 
marinhas microscópicas que são notoriously venenosas aos seres 
humanos, caracterizando liga às imagens e às descrições de cada 
um. A página discute também um scenario típico do 
envenenamento e revê momentaneamente o pathology e o toxicology 
destes toxins.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Web page informativo del museo della Nuova 
Scozia rappresenta la sezione rossa di marea di una collezione in 
linea circa le piante tossiche. La pagina rivede parecchie alghe
marine microscopiche che sono notoriamente tossiche agli esseri umani,
caratterizzando si collega alle immagini ed alle descrizioni di 
ciascuno. La pagina egualmente discute un piano d'azione tipico 
di avvelenamento e brevemente rivede la patologia e la tossicologia di
queste tossine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η ενημερωτική ιστοσελίδας μουσείων της Νέας 
Σκοτίας αντιπροσωπεύει το κόκκινο τμήμα παλίρροιας μιας σε 
απευθείας σύνδεση συλλογής για τις δηλητηριώδεις εγκαταστάσεις. 
Η σελίδα αναθεωρεί διάφορα μικροσκοπικά θαλάσσια άλγη που 
είναι εμφανώς δηλητηριώδη στους ανθρώπους, που χαρακτηρίζουν τις 
συνδέσεις με τις εικόνες και τις περιγραφές κάθε μια. Η 
σελίδα συζητά επίσης ένα χαρακτηριστικό σενάριο δηλητηρίασης 
και αναθεωρεί εν συντομία την παθολογία και την τοξικολογία αυτών
των τοξινών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este Web page informativo del museo de Nueva 
Escocia representa la sección roja de la marea de una colección en 
línea sobre las plantas venenosas. La paginación repasa varias
algas marinas microscópicas que sean notorio venenosas a los seres 
humanos, ofreciendo conecta a las imágenes y a las descripciones de 
cada uno. La paginación también discute un decorado típico 
del envenenamiento y repasa abreviadamente la patología y la 
toxicología de estas toxinas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:RAY WHITLEY
FN:RAY WHITLEY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MARIAN ZINCK
FN:MARIAN ZINCK
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:NOVA SCOTIA MUSEUM
FN:NOVA SCOTIA MUSEUM
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211871</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104156</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/red-tide</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
