<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108336</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108336</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086910</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Burlend Family Encounters America's System for Populating the West, Pike Country, Illinois, 1830s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Burlend Familie trifft System Amerikas für das
Bevölkern des Westens, Spiess-Land, Illinois, 1830s an</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La famille de Burlend rencontre le système de 
l'Amérique pour peupler l'ouest, pays de brochet, l'Illinois, 1830s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A família de Burlend encontra o sistema de 
América para povoar o oeste, país do pique, Illinois, 1830s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La famiglia di Burlend incontra il sistema 
dell'America per il popolamento dell'ovest, il paese del luccio, 
l'Illinois, 1830s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η οικογένεια Burlend αντιμετωπίζει το σύστημα της 
Αμερικής για τη δύση, χώρα λούτσων, Ιλλινόις, 1830s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La familia de Burlend encuentra el sistema de 
América para poblar el oeste, país del lucio, Illinois, 1830s</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1831 Rebecca Burlend, her husband John, and their five youngest surviving children left England for Pike County, Illinois. Resentful of the high rent they paid for their Yorkshire farm, the Burlends looked forward to owning their own farm in the United States. Once arrived, however, they learned that land ownership on the American frontier presented its own difficulties and dangers. In Illinois, government land offices either sold sections of land to settlers or provided them with certificates of preemption. "Preemption" was a process through which a settler could stake a claim to a piece of land for up to four years without paying for it as long as he (or she) cultivated it, built on it, or otherwise "improved" it. The government's goal was to encourage settlement of the wilderness. Settlers, however, sometimes illegally exploited the process, as Burlend describes here.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1831 Rebecca Burlend, ihr Ehemann John und ihre 
fünf jüngsten überlebenden Kinder verließ England für 
Spiess-Grafschaft, Illinois. Aufgebracht von der hohen Miete, 
die sie für ihren Yorkshire Bauernhof zahlten, das Burlends vorwärts
geschauen zum Besitzen ihres eigenen Bauernhofes in den Vereinigten 
Staaten. Sobald angekommen jedoch erfuhren sie, daß Landbesitz 
auf der amerikanischen Grenze seine eigenen Schwierigkeiten und 
Gefahren darstellte. In Illinois verkaufte Grundstücksparzellen
der Regierung Immobilienbüros entweder zu den Siedleren oder 
vorausgesetzt sie mit Bescheinigungen des Vorkaufs. "Vorkauf" 
war ein Prozeß, durch den ein Siedler einen Anspruch zu einem Stück 
Land für bis vier Jahre anbinden könnte, ohne für ihn so lang zu 
zahlen, wie er (oder sie) ihn kultivierten, aufgebaut auf ihm oder 
anders ihn "verbesserte". Das Ziel der Regierung war, Regelung 
der Wildnis anzuregen. Siedleren jedoch nutzten manchmal illegal
den Prozeß aus, wie Burlend hier beschreibt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1831 Rebecca Burlend, son mari John, et leurs 
cinq plus jeunes enfants survivants a quitté l'Angleterre pour le 
comté de brochet, l'Illinois. Irrité du loyer élevé qu'ils 
ont payé leur ferme de Yorkshire, le Burlends attendu avec intérêt 
posséder leur propre ferme aux Etats-Unis. Une fois 
qu'arrivés, cependant, ils ont appris que la propriété terrienne 
sur la frontière américaine a présenté ses propres difficultés et
dangers. En Illinois, sections de bureaux de terre de 
gouvernement ou de terre vendues aux colons ou s'ils avec des 
certificats de la préemption. la "préemption" était un 
processus par lequel un colon pourrait revendiquer un droit à un 
morceau de terre pendant jusqu'à quatre années sans payer elle aussi
longtemps que lui (ou elle) l'a cultivée, établi là-dessus, ou 
autrement "l'a amélioré". Le but du gouvernement était 
d'encourager le règlement du désert. Les colons, cependant, 
ont parfois illégalement exploité le processus, comme Burlend 
décrit ici.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">1831 em Rebecca Burlend, seu marido John, e suas 
cinco crianças sobrevivendo mais novas saiu de Inglaterra para o 
condado do pique, Illinois. Resentful do aluguel que elevado 
pagaram por sua fazenda de Yorkshire, o Burlends olhado para a frente 
a possuir sua própria fazenda nos estados unidos. Uma vez que 
chegados, entretanto, aprenderam que a posse de terra na fronteira 
americana apresentou seus próprios dificuldades e perigos. Em 
Illinois, seções de escritórios de terra do governo ou de terra 
vendidas aos settlers ou desde que eles com os certificados do 
preemption. o "preemption" era um processo com que um settler 
poderia estacar uma reivindicação a uma parte de terra por até 
quatro anos sem pagar por ele tão por muito tempo como (ou) o 
cultivaram, construído nele, ou de outra maneira "o melhorou". 
O objetivo do governo era incentivar o estabelecimento da 
região selvagem. Os settlers, entretanto, exploraram às vezes 
ilegal o processo, como Burlend descreve aqui.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">1831 in Rebecca Burlend, il suo marito John ed i 
loro cinque bambini sopravviventi più giovani ha lasciato 
l'Inghilterra per la contea del luccio, l'Illinois. Irritato di 
alto affitto che hanno pagato il loro podere del Yorkshire, il 
Burlends osservato in avanti a possedere il loro proprio podere in 
unito Dichiara. Una volta che arrivati, tuttavia, hanno 
imparato che la proprietà terriera sulla frontiera americana ha 
presentato le relativi propri difficoltà e pericoli. 
Nell'Illinois, gli uffici del catasto di governo o hanno venduto
le sezioni di terra ai settlers o se loro con i certificati della 
prelazione. "la prelazione" era un processo con cui un settler 
potrebbe picchettare un reclamo ad una parte di terra per fino a 
quattro anni senza pagare esso finchè lui (o lei) la ha coltivata, 
sviluppato su esso, o "la ha migliorata al contrario". 
L'obiettivo del governo era di consigliare allo stabilimento 
della selva. I settlers, tuttavia, hanno sfruttato a volte 
illegalmente il processo, come Burlend descrive qui.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1831 Rebecca Burlend, σύζυγό της John, 
και πέντε νεώτερα επιζόντα παιδιά τους άφησε την Αγγλία για το 
νομό λούτσων, Ιλλινόις. Αγανακτισμένοι του υψηλού 
μισθώματος πλήρωσαν για το αγρόκτημα του Γιορκσάιρ τους, το 
Burlends ανυπομόνησε να είναι κύριο αγρόκτημά τους στις 
Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες. Μόλις προσεγγιστούν, εντούτοις, έμαθαν
ότι η ιδιοκτησία εδάφους στα αμερικανικά σύνορα παρουσίασε τις 
δυσκολίες και τους κινδύνους της. Στο Ιλλινόις, τα γραφεία 
κυβερνητικού εδάφους είτε πώλησαν τα τμήματα του εδάφους στους 
αποίκους είτε παρείχαν σε τα τα πιστοποιητικά του δικαιώματος 
προτίμησης. "Το δικαίωμα προτίμησησ" ήταν μια διαδικασία 
μέσω της οποίας ένας άποικος θα μπορούσε να πασσαλώσει μια 
αξίωση σε ένα κομμάτι του εδάφους μέχρι και τέσσερα έτη χωρίς 
πληρωμή για το εφ' όσον το καλλιέργησε (ή αυτή), στηρίχτηκε σε 
το, ή ειδάλλως "το βελτίωσε". Ο κυβερνητικός στόχος ήταν 
να ενθαρρυνθεί η τακτοποίηση της αγριότητας. Οι άποικοι, 
εντούτοις, μερικές φορές παράνομα εκμεταλλεύτηκαν τη διαδικασία,
καθώς Burlend περιγράφει εδώ.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1831 Rebecca Burlend, su marido Juan, y sus 
cinco niños que sobrevivían más jóvenes salió de Inglaterra para 
el condado del lucio, Illinois. Resentido del alto alquiler que 
pagaron su granja de Yorkshire, el Burlends mirado adelante a poseer 
su propia granja en los Estados Unidos. Una vez que estuvieron 
llegados, sin embargo, aprendieran que la propiedad de terreno en la 
frontera americana presentó sus propias dificultades y peligros. 
En Illinois, secciones vendidas de las oficinas de pista del 
gobierno o de la pista a los colonos o con tal que ellos con los 
certificados del derecho preferente de compra. el "derecho 
preferente de compra" era un proceso con el cual un colono podría 
estacar una demanda a un pedazo de pista por hasta cuatro años sin 
pagar él mientras él (o ella) lo cultivó, construido en él, o "lo 
mejoró de otra manera". La meta del gobierno era animar el 
establecimiento del yermo. Los colonos, sin embargo, explotaron 
a veces ilegal el proceso, como Burlend describe aquí.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086910</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108336</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-burlend-family-encounters-americas-system-for-populating-the-west-pike-country-illinois-1830s</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
