<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108025</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108025</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>20101479</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Simultaneity Video</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Simultaneity-Bildschirm</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Vidéo de Simultanéité</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Vídeo Da Simultaneidade</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Video Di Simultaneità</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βίντεο ταυτοχρόνου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Vídeo De la Simultaneidad</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Video Transcript: Imagine two observers, one seated in the center of a speeding train car, and another standing on the platform as the train races by. As the center of the car passes the observer on the platform, he sees two bolts of lightning strike the car - one on the front, and one on the rear. The flashes of light from each strike reach him at the same time, so he concludes that the bolts were simultaneous, since he knows that the light from both strikes traveled the same distance at the same speed, the speed of light. He also predicts that his friend on the train will notice the front strike before the rear strike, because from her perspective on the platform the train is moving to meet the flash from the front, and moving away from the flash from the rear.

But what does the passenger see? As her friend on the platform predicted, the passenger does notice the flash from the front before the flash from the rear. But her conclusion is very different. As Einstein showed, the speed of the flashes as measured in the reference frame of the train must also be the speed of light. So, because each light pulse travels the same distance from each end of the train to the passenger, and because both pulses must move at the same speed, he can only conclude one thing: if he sees the front strike first, it actually happened first.

Whose interpretation is correct - the observer on the platform, who claims that the strikes happened simultaneously, or the observer on the train, who claims that the front strike happened before the rear strike? Einstein tells us that both are correct, within their own frame of reference. This is a fundamental result of special relativity: From different reference frames, there can never be agreement on the simultaneity of events.

General Restrictions:
Images credited to the National Science Foundation, a federal agency, are in the public domain. The images were created by employees of the United States Government as part of their official duties or prepared by contractors as "works for hire" for NSF. You may freely use NSF-credited images and, at your discretion, credit NSF with a "Courtesy: National Science Foundation" notation. Additional information about general usage can be found in Conditions.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Videoabschrift: Stellen Sie sich zwei 
Beobachter vor, einer gesetzt in der Mitte eines beschleunigenserie 
Autos und andere, die vorbei auf der Plattform als die Serie Rennen 
stehen. Da die Mitte des Autos den Beobachter auf der Plattform 
führt, sieht er zwei Schraubbolzen Blitzschlag das Auto - eins auf 
der Frontseite und einen auf der Rückseite. Die Blitze des 
Lichtes von jedem Schlag erreichen ihn gleichzeitig, also stellt er 
fest, daß die Schraubbolzen, da er weiß, daß das Licht von beiden 
Schlägen der gleiche Abstand mit der gleichen Geschwindigkeit reiste,
die Lichtgeschwindigkeit simultan waren. Er sagt auch voraus, 
daß sein Freund auf der Serie den vorderen Schlag vor dem hinteren 
Schlag beachtet, weil von ihrer Perspektive auf der Plattform die 
Serie bewegt, um den Blitz von der Frontseite zu treffen, und bewegend
weg vom Blitz vom rear.But was den Passagier tut, sehen Sie? Als
ihr Freund auf der Plattform sagte, der Passagier beachtet den Blitz 
von der Frontseite vor dem Blitz von der Rückseite voraus. Aber
ihre Zusammenfassung ist sehr unterschiedlich. Wie Einstein, 
das, die Geschwindigkeit der Blitze gezeigt wird, wie gemessen im 
Bezugsfeld der Serie die Lichtgeschwindigkeit auch sein muß. So
weil jeder Lichtimpuls der gleiche Abstand von jedem Ende der Serie 
zum Passagier reist und weil beide Impulse mit der gleichen 
Geschwindigkeit bewegen müssen, kann er eine Sache nur folgern: 
wenn er den vorderen Schlag zuerst sieht, geschah er wirklich 
first.Whose Deutung ist korrekt - der Beobachter auf der Plattform, 
die behauptet, daß die Schläge gleichzeitig geschahen, oder der 
Beobachter auf der Serie, die behauptet, daß der vordere Schlag vor 
dem hinteren Schlag geschah? Einstein erklärt uns, daß beide 
korrekt sind, innerhalb ihres eigenen Feldes der Referenz. 
Dieses ist ein grundlegendes Resultat der speziellen 
Relativität: Von den unterschiedlichen Bezugsfeldern kann es 
Vereinbarung über den Simultaneity von events.General 
Restrictions:Images nie geben, das zum National Science Foundation, 
ein Bundesamt gutgeschrieben wird, sind im public domain. Die 
Bilder wurden von den Angestellten der Vereinigte Staaten Regierung 
als Teil ihrer Dienstpflichten erstellt oder vorbereitet durch 
Fremdfirmen, wie "für Miete" für NSF arbeitet. Sie können an 
NSF-GUTGESCHRIEBENEN Bildern und, an Ihrer Rücksicht, Gutschrift NSF 
frei üben mit einer "Höflichkeit: National Science 
Foundation"Darstellung. Zusätzliche Informationen über 
allgemeinen Verbrauch können in den Bedingungen gefunden werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Transcription Visuelle : Imaginez deux 
observateurs, un assiss au centre d'une voiture expédiante de train, 
et des autres qui se tiennent près sur la plateforme comme courses de
train. Car le centre de la voiture passe l'observateur sur la 
plateforme, il voit deux boulons de grève surprise la voiture - une 
sur l'avant, et un sur l'arrière. Les flashes de la lumière de
chaque grève l'atteignent en même temps, ainsi il conclut que les 
boulons étaient simultanés, puisqu'il sait que la lumière des deux 
grèves a voyagé la même distance à la même vitesse, la vitesse de
la lumière. Il prévoit également que son ami sur le train 
notera la grève avant avant la grève arrière, parce que de sa 
perspective sur la plateforme le train se déplace pour rencontrer le 
flash de l'avant, et en éloignant du flash du rear.But ce qui fait le
passager voyez ? En tant que son ami sur la plateforme a prévu,
le passager note le flash de l'avant avant le flash de l'arrière. 
Mais sa conclusion est très différente. Comme Einstein 
montré, la vitesse des flashes comme mesurée dans la trame de 
référence du train doit également être la vitesse de la lumière. 
Ainsi, parce que chaque pulsation lumineuse voyage la même 
distance de chaque extrémité du train au passager, et parce que les 
deux impulsions doivent se déplacer à la même vitesse, il peut 
seulement conclure une chose : s'il voit la grève avant 
d'abord, réellement s'est-elle produite traduction de first.Whose 
est-elle correcte - l'observateur sur la plateforme, qui réclame que 
les grèves se sont produites simultanément, ou l'observateur sur le 
train, qui réclame que la grève avant s'est produite avant la grève
arrière ? Einstein nous indique que tous les deux sont 
corrects, dans leur propre trame de la référence. C'est un 
résultat fondamental de relativité spéciale : De différentes
trames de référence, il peut jamais y avoir accord sur la 
simultanéité d'events.General Restrictions:Images crédité au 
National Science Foundation, une agence fédérale, sont dans le 
public domain. Les images ont été créées par des employés 
du gouvernement des Etats-Unis en tant qu'élément de leurs fonctions
officielles ou préparées par des entrepreneurs comme "travaille pour
la location" pour le NSF. Vous pouvez librement utiliser les 
images NSF-CRÉDITÉES et, à votre discrétion, NSF de degré de solvabilité 
avec une "courtoisie : Notation de National Science Foundation 
". Des informations supplémentaires sur l'utilisation 
générale peuvent être trouvées en conditions.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Transcript Video: Imagine dois observadores,
um assentados no centro de um carro apressando-se do trem, e outro que
está na plataforma como as raças do trem perto. Porque o 
centro do carro passa o observador na plataforma, vê dois parafusos 
da batida de relâmpago o carro - um na parte dianteira, e um na parte
traseira. Os flashes da luz de cada batida alcançam-no ao mesmo
tempo, assim que concli que os parafusos eram simultâneos, desde que 
sabe que a luz de ambas as batidas viajou à mesma distância na mesma
velocidade, a velocidade de luz. Prediz também que seu amigo no
trem observará a batida dianteira antes da batida traseira, porque de
seu perspective na plataforma o trem se está movendo para se 
encontrar com o flash da parte dianteira, e movendo-se afastado do 
flash do rear.But o que faz o passageiro veja? Como seu amigo na
plataforma predisse, o passageiro observa o flash da parte dianteira 
antes do flash da parte traseira. Mas sua conclusão é muito 
diferente. Como Einstein mostrado, a velocidade dos flashes como
medida no frame da referência do trem deve também estar a uma 
velocidade de luz. Assim, porque cada pulso claro viaja à mesma
distância de cada extremidade do trem ao passageiro, e porque ambos 
os pulsos devem se mover na mesma velocidade, pode somente conclir uma
coisa: se visse a batida dianteira primeiramente, aconteceu 
realmente interpretação de first.Whose está correta - o observador 
na plataforma, que reivindica que as batidas aconteceram 
simultaneamente, ou o observador no trem, que reivindica que a batida 
dianteira aconteceu antes da batida traseira? Einstein diz-nos 
que ambos estão corretos, dentro de seu próprio frame da 
referência. Este é um resultado fundamental do relativity 
especial: Dos frames diferentes da referência, pode nunca haver
um acordo na simultaneidade de events.General Restrictions:Images 
creditado ao National Science Foundation, uma agência federal, está 
no public domain. As imagens foram criadas por empregados do 
governo unido dos estados como a parte de seus deveres oficiais ou 
preparadas por contratantes como "trabalha para o hire" para o NSF. 
Você pode livremente usar as imagens NSF-CREDITADAS e, na sua 
discreção, NSF do crédito com uma "cortesia: Notação do 
National Science Foundation ". A informação adicional sobre o 
uso geral pode ser encontrada nas circunstâncias.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Video Trascrizione: Immagini due 
osservatori, uno messi nel centro di un automobile d'accelerazione del
treno ed un altro che si levano in piedi sulla piattaforma come le 
corse del treno vicino. Poichè il centro dell'automobile passa 
l'osservatore sulla piattaforma, vede due bulloni del colpo di lampo 
l'automobile - uno sulla parte anteriore ed uno sulla parte 
posteriore. I flash di luce da ogni colpo lo raggiungono allo 
stesso tempo, in modo da conclude che i bulloni erano simultanei, 
poiché sa che la luce da entrambi i colpi ha viaggiato la stessa 
distanza alla stessa velocità, la velocità di luce. Egualmente
predice che il suo amico sul treno noterà il colpo anteriore prima 
del colpo posteriore, perché dalla sua prospettiva sulla piattaforma 
il treno sta muovendosi per venire a contatto del flash dalla parte 
anteriore e muovendosi via dal flash dal rear.But che cosa fa il 
passeggero veda? Come suo amico sulla piattaforma ha predetto, 
il passeggero nota il flash dalla parte anteriore prima del flash 
dalla parte posteriore. Ma la sua conclusione è molto 
differente. Come Einstein indicato, la velocità dei flash come 
misurata nel telaio di riferimento del treno deve anche essere la 
velocità di luce. Così, perché ogni impulso luminoso viaggia 
la stessa distanza da ogni estremità del treno al passeggero e 
perché entrambi gli impulsi devono muoversi alla stessa velocità, 
può concludere soltanto una cosa: se vede il colpo anteriore in
primo luogo, realmente è accaduto l'interpretazione di first.Whose è
corretto - l'osservatore sulla piattaforma, che sostiene che i colpi 
sono accaduto simultaneamente, o l'osservatore sul treno, che sostiene
che il colpo anteriore è accaduto prima del colpo posteriore? 
Einstein ci dice che entrambi siano corretti, all'interno della 
loro propria struttura di riferimento. Ciò è un risultato 
fondamentale della relatività speciale: Dalle strutture 
differenti di riferimento, ci può mai provenire accordo sulla 
simultaneità di events.General Restrictions:Images accreditato al 
National Science Foundation, un ente federale, è nel public domain. 
Le immagini sono state create dagli impiegati del unito 
Dichiara il governo come componente delle loro funzioni 
ufficiali o preparato dagli appaltatori come "funziona per noleggio" 
per il NSF. Potete usare liberamente le immagini NSF-ACCREDITATE
e, alla vostra discrezione, NSF di accreditamento con "una cortesia: 
Notazione di National Science Foundation ". Le 
informazioni supplementari su uso generale possono essere trovate 
nelle circostanze.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τηλεοπτικό αντίγραφο: Φανταστείτε δύο 
παρατηρητές, ένας που κάθονται στο κέντρο ενός επιταχυνόμενου 
αυτοκινήτου τραίνων, και μια άλλη στάση στην πλατφόρμα καθώς το 
τραίνο συναγωνίζεται κοντά. Καθώς το κέντρο του 
αυτοκινήτου περνά τον παρατηρητή στην πλατφόρμα, βλέπει 
δύο μπουλόνια της αστραπής χτυπά το αυτοκίνητο - ένα στο 
μέτωπο, και ένα στο οπίσθιο τμήμα. Οι λάμψεις του φωτός 
από κάθε απεργία φθάνουν σε τον στον ίδιο χρόνο, έτσι 
καταλήγει στο συμπέρασμα ότι τα μπουλόνια ήταν ταυτόχρονα, 
δεδομένου ότι ξέρει ότι το φως και από τις δύο απεργίες 
ταξίδεψε την ίδια απόσταση με την ίδια ταχύτητα, η ταχύτητα του 
φωτός. Επίσης προβλέπει ότι ο φίλος του στο τραίνο θα 
παρατηρήσει την μπροστινή απεργία πριν από την οπίσθια απεργία, 
επειδή από την προοπτική της στην πλατφόρμα το τραίνο κινείται 
για να συναντήσει τη λάμψη από το μέτωπο, και την απομάκρυνση 
από τη λάμψη από το οπίσθιο τμήμα αλλά τι κάνει τον επιβάτη 
βλέπει; Όπως ο φίλος της στην πλατφόρμα πρόβλεψε, ο
επιβάτης παρατηρεί τη λάμψη από το μέτωπο πριν από τη λάμψη 
από το οπίσθιο τμήμα. Αλλά το συμπέρασμά της είναι πολύ 
διαφορετικό. Σαν Einstein που εμφανίζεται, η ταχύτητα των 
λάμψεων όπως μετριέται στο πλαίσιο αναφοράς του τραίνου πρέπει 
επίσης να είναι η ταχύτητα του φωτός. Έτσι, επειδή κάθε 
ελαφρύς σφυγμός ταξιδεύει την ίδια απόσταση από κάθε τέλος του
τραίνου στον επιβάτη, και επειδή και οι δύο σφυγμοί πρέπει να 
κινηθούν με την ίδια ταχύτητα, μπορεί μόνο να ολοκληρώσει ένα 
πράγμα: εάν βλέπει την μπροστινή απεργία πρώτα, 
συνέβη πραγματικά πρώτα η του οποίου ερμηνεία είναι σωστή - ο 
παρατηρητής στην πλατφόρμα, που υποστηρίζει ότι οι απεργίες 
συνέβησαν ταυτόχρονα, ή ο παρατηρητής στο τραίνο, το οποίο 
υποστηρίζει ότι η μπροστινή απεργία συνέβη πριν από την οπίσθια
απεργία; Το Einstein μας λέει ότι και οι δύο είναι 
σωστοί, μέσα στο πλαίσιο αναφοράς τους. Αυτό είναι ένα 
θεμελιώδες αποτέλεσμα της ειδικής σχετικότητας: Από τα 
διαφορετικά πλαίσια αναφοράς, δεν μπορεί ποτέ να υπάρξει 
συμφωνία για το ταυτόχρονο των γεγονότων που γενικά 
Restrictions:Images που πιστώνονται στο εθνικό ίδρυμα 
επιστήμης, μια ομοσπονδιακή αντιπροσωπεία, είναι στο δημόσιο 
τομέα. Οι εικόνες δημιουργήθηκαν από τους υπαλλήλους της 
Ηνωμένης κυβέρνησης ως τμήμα των επίσημων καθηκόντων τους ή 
προετοιμάστηκαν από τους αναδόχους ως "εργασίες για μίσθωση" για 
NSF. Μπορείτε ελεύθερα να χρησιμοποιήσετε τις 
νσφ-πιστωμένες εικόνες και, κατά την κρίση σας, την πίστωση 
NSF με μια "ευγένεια: Σημείωση εθνικού ιδρύματος 
επιστήμης ". Οι πρόσθετες πληροφορίες για τη γενική χρήση 
μπορούν να βρεθούν στους όρους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Transcripción Video: Imagine a dos 
observadores, uno asentados en el centro de un coche del tren que 
apresura, y otro que está parado en la plataforma como las razas del 
tren cerca. Pues el centro del coche pasa a observador en la 
plataforma, él ve dos pernos de huelga de relámpago el coche - uno 
en el frente, y uno en la parte posterior. Los flashes de la luz
de cada huelga lo alcanzan en el mismo tiempo, así que él concluye 
que los pernos eran simultáneos, puesto que él sabe que la luz de 
ambas huelgas viajó la misma distancia a la misma velocidad, la 
velocidad de la luz. ¿Él también predice que su amigo en el 
tren notará la huelga delantera antes de la huelga posterior, porque 
de su perspectiva en la plataforma el tren se está moviendo para 
resolver el flash del frente, y moviéndose lejos desde el flash del 
rear.But qué hace a pasajero vea? Como su amigo en la 
plataforma predijo, el pasajero nota el flash del frente antes del 
flash de la parte posterior. Pero su conclusión es muy 
diferente. Como Einstein mostrado, la velocidad de los flashes 
según lo medido en el marco de la referencia del tren debe también 
ser la velocidad de la luz. Así pues, porque cada pulso ligero 
viaja la misma distancia de cada extremo del tren al pasajero, y 
porque ambos pulsos deben moverse a la misma velocidad, él puede 
concluir solamente una cosa: ¿si él ve la huelga delantera 
primero, sucedió realmente interpretación de first.Whose está 
correcta - el observador en la plataforma, que demanda que sucedieron 
las huelgas simultáneamente, o el observador en el tren, que demanda 
que la huelga delantera sucedió antes de la huelga posterior? 
Einstein nos dice que ambos estén correctos, dentro de su 
propio marco de la referencia. Éste es un resultado fundamental
de la relatividad especial: De diversos marcos de la referencia,
puede nunca haber acuerdo en la simultaneidad de events.General 
Restrictions:Images acreditado al National Science Foundation, una 
agencia federal, está en el public domain. Las imágenes fueron
creadas por los empleados del gobierno de Estados Unidos como parte de
sus deberes oficiales o preparadas por los contratistas como "trabaja 
para el hire" para el NSF. Usted puede utilizar libremente las 
imágenes NSF-ACREDITADAS y, en su discreción, NSF del crédito con 
una "cortesía: Notación del National Science Foundation ". 
La información adicional sobre uso general se puede encontrar 
en condiciones.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:NSF
FN:NSF
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>20101479</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108025</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/simultaneity-video</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
