<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103289</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103289</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206627</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Congress, Law, and Politics</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kongreß, Gesetz und Politik</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le congrès, loi, et politique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Congress, lei, e política</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Congresso, legge e politica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Συνέδριο, νόμος, και πολιτική</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Congreso, ley, y política</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">presents papers of members of Congress, Supreme Court justices, and key federal law cases. Learn about the Revolution and the creation of the U.S. by investigating the papers of our earliest lawmakers -- Jefferson, Madison, Monroe, and others. See Calhoun's speech against the Compromise of 1850 and Webster's notes for his speech in favor of it, General MacArthur's Old Soldiers Never Die address to Congress (April 1951), and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geschenkpapiere der Bauteile von Gerechtigkeit des
Kongresses, des Höchsten Gerichts und von 
Schlüsselbundesrechtssachen. Erlernen Sie über die Umdrehung 
und die Kreation der VEREINIGTEN STAATEN, indem Sie die Papiere 
unserer frühesten Gesetzgeber -- Jefferson, Madison, Monroe und 
andere nachforschen. Sehen Sie Rede Calhouns gegen die 
Kompromiss- von 1850 und Webstersanmerkungen für seine Rede zugunsten
sie, General MacArthurs Old Soldiers Never Würfeladresse zum Kongreß
(April 1951) und mehr.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">papiers de présents des membres des justices du 
congrès, de cour suprême, et des cas de loi fédéraux principaux. 
Renseignez-vous sur la révolution et la création des 
ETATS-UNIS en étudiant les papiers de nos premiers législateurs -- 
Jefferson, Madison, Monroe, et d'autres. Voir la parole de 
Calhoun contre le compromis de 1850 et les notes de Webster pour 
son discours en faveur de lui, adresse de matrice de Old Soldiers 
Never du Général MacArthur's au congrès (avril 1951), et plus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">papéis de presentes dos membros de justiças do 
congress, da corte suprema, e dos casos de lei federais chaves. 
Aprenda sobre a volta e a criação dos ESTADOS UNIDOS 
investigando os papéis de nossos lawmakers mais adiantados -- 
Jefferson, Madison, Monroe, e outro. Veja o discurso de Calhoun 
de encontro às notas do acordo de 1850 e do Webster para seu discurso
no favor dele, endereço do dado de Velho Soldado Nunca do general 
MacArthur ao congress (abril 1951), e mais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">carte da presenti dei membri delle giustizie della
Corte suprema, del congresso e dei casi di legge federali chiave. 
Impari circa la rivoluzione e la creazione degli STATI UNITI 
studiando le carte dei nostri legislatori più in anticipo -- 
Jefferson, Madison, Monroe ed altre. Veda il discorso del 
Calhoun contro le note del Webster e di 1850 di compromesso per il suo
discorso per esso, l'indirizzo del dado del Old Soldiers Never del 
General MacArthur al congresso (aprile del 1951) e più.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρουσιάζει τις εργασίες των μελών του συνεδρίου, 
justices ανώτατου δικαστηρίου, και κλειδώνει τις ομοσπονδιακές 
υποθέσεις νόμου. Μάθετε για την επανάσταση και τη 
δημιουργία των ΗΠΑ με την έρευνα των εγγράφων των πιό πρώτων 
νομοθετών μας -- Jefferson, Μάντισον, Μονρόε, και άλλα. 
Δείτε την ομιλία Calhoun ενάντια στο συμβιβασμό
1850 και οι σημειώσεις Webster για την ομιλία του υπέρ της, 
γενικοί παλαιοί στρατιώτες MacArthur's δεν πεθαίνουν ποτέ 
διεύθυνση στο συνέδριο (Απρίλιος 1951), και περισσότερο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">documentos de miembros de las justicias del 
congreso, del Tribunal Supremo, y de los casos de ley federales 
dominantes. Aprenda sobre la revolución y la creación de los 
ESTADOS UNIDOS investigando los papeles de nuestros legisladores más 
tempranos -- Jefferson, Madison, Monroe, y otras. Vea el 
discurso de Calhoun contra las notas del compromiso de 1850 y de 
Webster para su discurso en el favor de él, el direccionamiento del 
dado Old Soldiers Never de general MacArthur al congreso (abril de 
1951), y más.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206627</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103289</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/congress-law-and-politics</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
