<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104168</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104168</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086805</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Secessionist spectators.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Secessionist Zuschauer.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Spectateurs de sécessionniste.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Espectadores de Secessionist.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Spectators di Secessionist.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σχησματικοί θεατές.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Espectadores de Secessionist.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">By the time Abraham Lincoln took office as president, seven southern states had seceded. Although Lincoln promised not to attack slavery where it existed, he did promise to halt its expansion. For southerners who viewed expansion necessary for the survival of slavery, this was unacceptable. The crisis came to a head at Fort Sumter, a U.S. post in Charleston Harbor. When Lincoln chose to reinforce the garrison in April 1861, Confederate forces demanded the fort's surrender, and opened fire when their demand was refused. Residents of Charleston watched the bombardment of Fort Sumter from the city's rooftops on April 12, 1861, knowing the attack meant war.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bis Abraham Lincoln Amt als Präsident übernahm, hatten 
sieben südliche Zustände seceded. Obgleich Lincoln, versprach 
Sklaverei nicht in Angriff zu nehmen, in der es existierte, versprach 
er, seine Expansion anzuhalten. Für southerners, die die 
Expansion ansahen, die für das Überleben der Sklaverei notwendig 
ist, war dieses nicht annehmbar. Die Krise kam zu einem Kopf am 
Fort Sumter, VEREINIGTE STAATEN bekanntgeben im Charleston Hafen. 
Als Lincoln beschloß, die Garnison im April 1861 zu 
verstärken, verlangten verbündete Kräfte die Auslieferung des Forts
und öffneten Feuer, als ihre Nachfrage abgelehnt wurde. 
Bewohner von Charleston überwachten die Bombardierung des Forts
Sumter von den Dachspitzen der Stadt an April 12, 1861 und kannten den
Angriff bedeuteten Krieg.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Avant qu'abraham Lincoln ait pris le bureau comme 
président, sept états méridionaux les avaient fait
 cécession. Bien que Lincoln ait promis de ne pas attaquer 
l'esclavage où il a existé, il a promis de stopper son expansion. 
Pour les habitants du sud qui ont visualisé l'expansion nécessaire 
pour la survie de l'esclavage, c'était inacceptable. La crise 
est venue à une tête au fort Sumter, les ETATS-UNIS signalent dans 
le port de Charleston. Quand Lincoln a choisi de renforcer la 
garnison en avril 1861, les forces confédérées ont exigé la 
reddition du fort, et ont ouvert le feu quand leur demande a été 
refusée. Les résidants de Charleston ont observé le 
bombardement du fort Sumter des dessus de toit de la ville avril 12, 
1861, sachant la guerre signifiée par attaque.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Pelo tempo Abraham Lincoln fêz exame do escritório como 
o presidente, sete estados do sul teve seceded. Embora Lincoln 
prometesse não atacar o slavery onde existiu, prometeu parar sua 
expansão. Para os southerners que viram a expansão necessária
para a sobrevivência do slavery, isto era inaceitável. A crise
veio a uma cabeça no fort Sumter, uns ESTADOS UNIDOS afixa no porto 
de Charleston. Quando Lincoln escolheu reforçar o garrison em 
abril 1861, as forças confederate exijiram a rendição do fort, e 
abriram o fogo quando sua demanda foi recusada. Os residentes de
Charleston prestaram atenção ao bombardeio do fort Sumter dos 
rooftops da cidade abril em 12, 1861, sabendo a guerra significada 
ataque.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Per il momento in cui Abraham Lincoln prenda l'ufficio 
come presidente, sette del sud dichiarano hanno avuti seceded. 
Anche se Lincoln ha promesso di non attacare lo slavery dove 
esista, ha promesso di fermare la relativa espansione. Per i 
southerners che hanno osservato l'espansione necessaria per la 
sopravvivenza di slavery, questo era inaccettabile. La crisi è 
venuto ad una testa a Sumter Forte, gli STATI UNITI invia nel 
porto de Charleston. Quando Lincoln ha scelto rinforzare il 
garrison nel mese di aprile del 1861, le forze confederate hanno 
richiesto la resa forte ed hanno aperto il fuoco quando la loro 
richiesta è stata rifiutata. I residenti di Charleston hanno 
guardato il bombardamento di Sumter Forte dai tetti della città 
il 12 aprile 1861, conoscenti la guerra significata attacco.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ώσπου να πήρε ο Abraham Λίνκολν το γραφείο καθώς ο
Πρόεδρος, επτά νότια κράτη είχε. Αν και το Λίνκολν 
υποσχέθηκε να μην επιτεθεί στη σκλαβιά όπου υπήρξε, υποσχέθηκε 
να σταματήσει την επέκτασή του. Για τους νοτίους που 
εμφάνισαν την επέκταση απαραίτητη για την επιβίωση της σκλαβιάς, 
αυτό ήταν απαράδεκτο. Η κρίση ήρθε σε ένα κεφάλι στο 
οχυρό Sumter, μια ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ θέση στο λιμάνι του Τσάρλεστον. 
Όταν το Λίνκολν επέλεξε να ενισχύσει τη φρουρά τον Απρίλιο
του 1861, οι ομόσπονδες δυνάμεις απαίτησαν την παράδοση του 
οχυρού, και άνοιξαν την πυρκαγιά όταν απορρίφτηκε η απαίτησή 
τους. Οι κάτοικοι του Τσάρλεστον πρόσεξαν το βομβαρδισμό του
οχυρού Sumter από τις στέγες της πόλης στις 12 Απριλίου 
..1861, ξέροντας το σημαμένο επίθεση πόλεμο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Para el momento en que Abraham Lincoln tomara la oficina 
como presidente, siete estados meridionales tenían seceded. 
Aunque Lincoln prometió no atacar la esclavitud donde existió,
él prometió parar su extensión. Para los southerners que 
vieron la extensión necesaria para la supervivencia de la esclavitud,
esto era inaceptable. La crisis vino a una pista en la fortaleza
Sumter, ESTADOS UNIDOS fija en el puerto de Charleston. Cuando 
Lincoln eligió reforzar la guarnición en abril de 1861, las fuerzas 
confederadas exigieron la entrega de la fortaleza, y abrieron el fuego
cuando su demanda fue rechazada. Los residentes de Charleston 
miraron el bombardeo de la fortaleza Sumter de los tejados de la 
ciudad 12 de abril de 1861, sabiendo la guerra significada ataque.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086805</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104168</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/secessionist-spectators</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
