<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106882</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106882</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086379</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Keep Off the Grass!: Coxey's Army Invades the Nation's Capital</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Unterhalt weg vom Gras!: Armee Coxeys dringt
das Kapital der Nation ein</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Retenez l'herbe ! : L'armée de Coxey 
envahit le capital de la nation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Evite a grama!: O exército de Coxey invade 
o capital da nação</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lasci stare l'erba!: L'esercito del Coxey 
invade il capitale della nazione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αποφύγετε τη χλόη!: Ο στρατός του Coxey 
εισβάλλει στο κεφάλαιο του έθνους</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Evite la hierba!: El ejército de Coxey 
invade el capital de la nación</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Although Coxey's Army was only one of more than forty different armies of the unemployed that headed for Washington, D.C., in 1894 to seek relief from their plight, it was by far the best known. Its leader was the colorful Jacob S. Coxey, a wealthy Populist who owned a sand quarry, bred horses, and wore hand-tailored suits. The publicity that preceded the arrival of the "armies" apparently frightened authorities. Fifteen hundred soldiers were stationed in Washington to meet the army; thousands more were available in Baltimore, Annapolis, and Philadelphia in anticipation of further trouble. But the army that arrived on May 1, 1894, numbered only 500. When Coxey tried to speak at the U.S. Capitol, police arrested him for walking on the grass. Fifty years to the day later, in 1944, Coxey finally delivered this speech from the steps of the U.S. Congress.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Obgleich Armee Coxeys nur eine von mehr war, als 
vierzig unterschiedliche Armeen der Arbeitslosen, die für Washington,
Gleichstrom, 1894 vorangehen, um Entlastung von ihrer Lage zu suchen, 
war sie bei weitem gut bekannt. Sein Führer war das bunte Jacob
S. Coxey, ein wohlhabender Populist, der einen Sandsteinbruch, 
gezüchtete Pferde besaß und Hand-hergestellte Klagen trug. Die
Werbung, die die Ankunft der "Armeen" voranging, erschrak anscheinend 
Behörden. Fünfzehn hundert Soldaten wurden in Washington 
stationiert, um die Armee zu treffen; Tausenden waren mehr in 
Baltimore, in Annapolis und in Philadelphia in Erwartung der weiteren 
Mühe vorhanden. Aber die Armee, die an Mai 1 ankam, 1894, 
numeriert nur 500. Als Coxey versuchte, am VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Kapitol zu sprechen, überwachen Sie festgehalten ihm für das Gehen 
auf das Gras polizeilich. Fünfzig Jahre zum Tag später, 1944, 
lieferte Coxey schließlich diese Rede von den Jobsteps des VEREINIGTE
STAATEN Kongresses.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bien que l'armée de Coxey ait été seulement une
de plus de quarante armées différentes des chômeurs qui se dirigent
pour Washington, C.C, en 1894 pour rechercher le soulagement de leur 
situation difficile, elle était de loin mieux connu. Son amorce
était le Jacob coloré S. Coxey, un populiste riche qui a possédé 
une carrière de sable, chevaux multipliés, et a porté les costumes 
main-travaillés. La publicité qui a précédé l'arrivée des 
"armées" a apparemment effrayé des autorités. Quinze cent 
soldats ont été postés à Washington pour rencontrer l'armée ; 
les milliers étaient de plus disponibles à Baltimore, 
Annapolis, et à Philadelphie en prévision davantage d'd'ennui. 
Mais l'armée qui est arrivée 1 mai 1894, numéroté seulement
500. Quand Coxey a essayé de parler au capitol des ETATS-UNIS, 
maintenez l'ordre arrêté lui pour marcher sur l'herbe. 
Cinquante ans au jour plus tard, en 1944, Coxey a finalement 
fourni ce discours des étapes du congrès des ETATS-UNIS.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Embora o exército de Coxey fosse somente um de 
mais de quarenta exércitos diferentes dos desempregados que dirigem 
para Washington, C.C., em 1894 para procurar o relevo de seu plight, 
estava distante pelo sabido melhor. Seu líder era o Jacob 
colorido S. Coxey, um populist rico que possuísse um quarry da areia,
cavalos produzidos, e desgastasse ternos mão-costurados. O 
publicity que precedeu a chegada dos "exércitos" frightened 
aparentemente autoridades. Quinze cem soldados foram postados em
Washington para encontrar-se com o exército; os milhares 
estavam mais disponíveis em Baltimore, em Annapolis, e em Filadélfia
em antecipação a um problema mais adicional. Mas o exército 
que chegou maio em 1, 1894, numerado somente 500. Quando Coxey 
tentou falar no capitol de ESTADOS UNIDOS, policie prendido lhe para 
andar na grama. Cinqüênta anos ao dia mais tarde, em 1944, 
Coxey entregou finalmente este discurso das etapas do congress de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Anche se l'esercito del Coxey era soltanto uno di 
più di quaranta eserciti differenti dei disoccupati che dirigono per 
Washington, DC, in 1894 per cercare il rilievo dalla loro situazione 
difficile, era conosciuto di gran lunga il più bene. Il 
relativo capo era il Jacob colorful S. Coxey, un populist ricco
che ha posseduto una cava della sabbia, cavalli allevati ed ha portato
i vestiti mano-adattati. La pubblicità che ha preceduto 
l'arrivo "degli eserciti" frightened apparentemente le autorità. 
Quindici cento soldati sono stati disposti a Washington per 
venire a contatto dell'esercito; le migliaia più erano 
disponibili a Baltimora, Annapolis e Filadelfia in previsione di 
ulteriore difficoltà. Ma l'esercito che è arrivato maggio su 
1, 1894, numerato soltanto 500. Quando Coxey ha provato a 
parlare al capitol degli STATI UNITI, sorvegli arrestato lui per 
camminare sull'erba. Cinquanta anni al giorno più 
successivamente, in 1944, Coxey infine ha trasportato questo discorso 
dai punti del congresso degli STATI UNITI.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αν και ο στρατός Coxey ήταν μόνο ένας από 
περισσότερους από σαράντα διαφορετικούς στρατούς των ανέργων που
διεύθυναν για την Ουάσιγκτον, το ΣΥΝΕΧΈΣ ΡΕΎΜΑ, το 1894 για να 
επιδιώξει την ανακούφιση από τη δύσκολη θέση τους, αυτό ήταν 
κατά πολύ το καλύτερο γνωστό. Ο ηγέτης του ήταν 
ζωηρόχρωμο Jacob Θ*ς. Coxey, πλούσιος ένας λαϊκιστικός 
ποιος ήταν κύριος ενός λατομείου άμμου, αναπαρήγαγε τα άλογα, 
και φόρεσε τα χέρι-προσαρμοσμένα κοστούμια. Η δημοσιότητα 
που προηγήθηκε της άφιξης των "στρατών" προφανώς εκφόβισε τις 
αρχές. Δεκαπέντε εκατό στρατιώτες τοποθετήθηκαν στην 
Ουάσιγκτον για να συναντήσουν το στρατό  οι χιλιάδες 
περισσότερο ήταν διαθέσιμες στη Βαλτιμόρη, Annapolis, και τη 
Φιλαδέλφεια σε αναμονή για το περαιτέρω πρόβλημα. Αλλά ο 
στρατός που έφθασε σε Μάιος 1 ..1894, αριθμημένος μόνο 
500. Όταν Coxey προσπάθησε να μιλήσει στις ΗΠΑ 
Capitol, αστυνομεύστε συλλήφθείτε τον για το περπάτημα στη 
χλόη. Πενήντα έτη στην ημέρα αργότερα, το 1944, Coxey
παρέδωσαν τελικά αυτήν την ομιλία από τα βήματα του ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΥ
συνεδρίου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Aunque el ejército de Coxey era solamente uno de 
más de cuarenta diversos ejércitos de los parados que dirigieron 
hacia Washington, C.C., en 1894 para buscar la relevación de su 
apuro, era sabido en gran medida lo más mejor posible. Su 
arranque de cinta era el Jacob colorido S. Coxey, populist rico que 
poseyó una mina de la arena, caballos criados, y desgastó juegos 
mano-adaptados. La publicidad que precedió la llegada de los 
"ejércitos" asustó al parecer autoridades. Colocaron a quince 
cientos soldados en Washington para satisfacer al ejército; los
millares estaban más disponibles en Baltimore, Annapolis, y 
Philadelphia en anticipación de apuro adicional. Pero el 
ejército que llegó 1 de mayo de 1894, numerado solamente 500. 
Cuando Coxey intentó hablar en el capitol de ESTADOS UNIDOS, 
limpie arrestado le para recorrer en la hierba. Cincuenta años 
al día más adelante, en 1944, Coxey finalmente entregó este 
discurso de los pasos de progresión del congreso de ESTADOS UNIDOS.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086379</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106882</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/keep-off-the-grass-coxeys-army-invades-the-nations-capital</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
