<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103554</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103554</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973927</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Literature Games: Find the Authors</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Literatur-Spiele: Finden Sie die Autoren</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jeux de Littérature : Trouvez les auteurs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogos Da Literatura: Encontre os autores</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giochi Della Letteratura: Trovi gli autori</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παιχνίδια λογοτεχνίας: Βρείτε τους συντάκτες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Juegos De la Literatura: Encuentre a 
autores</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Play a game and find out about a Nobel Prize awarded discovery or work! Among hundreds of letters, the names of Literature Laureates are hidden. Pick a period and search for the authors mentioned on the list beside the puzzle. The names may be written in all directions. When you've found a name, mark it with the mouse button down.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spielen Sie ein Spiel und finden Sie über eine 
zugesprochene Entdeckung oder eine Arbeit des Nobelpreises heraus! 
Unter Hunderten Zeichen, werden die Namen der 
Literatur-Laureaten versteckt. Wählen Sie eine Periode aus und 
suchen Sie nach den Autoren, die auf der Liste neben dem Puzzlespiel 
erwähnt werden. Die Namen können in alle Richtungen 
geschrieben werden. Wenn Sie einen Namen gefunden haben, 
kennzeichnen Sie ihn mit der Maustaste unten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jouez un jeu et découvrez au sujet d'une 
découverte ou d'un travail attribuée de prix Nobel ! Parmi des
centaines de lettres, les noms des lauréats de littérature sont 
cachés. Sélectionnez une période et recherchez les auteurs 
mentionnés sur la liste près du puzzle. Les noms peuvent être
écrits dans toutes les directions. Quand vous avez trouvé un 
nom, marquez-l'avec le bouton de souris vers le bas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogue um jogo e encontre-o para fora sobre uma 
descoberta ou um trabalho concedido do prêmio de nobel! Entre 
centenas das letras, os nomes de laureates da literatura são 
escondidos. Escolha um período e procurare pelos autores 
mencionados na lista ao lado do enigma. Os nomes podem ser 
escritos em todos os sentidos. Quando você encontrou um nome, 
marque-o com a tecla de rato para baixo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gioc un gioco e scopra circa una scoperta o un 
lavoro ricevuta del premio Nobel! Fra le centinaia delle 
lettere, i nomi dei laureates della letteratura sono nascosti. 
Selezioni un periodo e cerchi gli autori accennati sulla lista 
al lato del puzzle. I nomi possono essere scritti in tutti i 
sensi. Quando avete trovato un nome, contrassegnilo con il tasto
di mouse giù.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παίξτε ένα παιχνίδι και ανακαλύψτε για μια 
απονεμημένη βραβείο ανακάλυψη ή μια εργασία Νόμπελ! 
Μεταξύ των εκατοντάδων των επιστολών, τα ονόματα των 
δαφνοστεφών λογοτεχνίας είναι κρυμμένα. Επιλέξτε μια 
περίοδο και μια αναζήτηση των συντακτών που αναφέρονται στον 
κατάλογο εκτός από το γρίφο. Τα ονόματα μπορούν να 
γραφτούν σε όλες τις κατευθύνσεις. Όταν βρείτε ένα όνομα,
το με το κουμπί του ποντικιού κάτω.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Juegue un juego y descubra sobre un 
descubrimiento o un trabajo concedido del premio Nobel! Entre 
centenares de cartas, los nombres de los laureados de la literatura se
ocultan. Escoja un período y busque para a autores mencionados 
en la lista al lado del rompecabezas. Los nombres se pueden 
escribir en todas las direcciones. Cuando usted ha encontrado un
nombre, marqúelo con el botón de ratón abajo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973927</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103554</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/literature-games-find-the-authors</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
