<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108589</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108589</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205803</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Nineteenth-Century America in Art and Literature</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">19.-Jahrhundert Amerika in der kunst und in der 
Literatur</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dix-neuvième-Siècle Amérique en art et 
littérature</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Décimo-Século América na arte e na literatura</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Diciannovesimo-Secolo America in arte e 
letteratura</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δέκατος-αιώνας Αμερική στην τέχνη και τη λογοτεχνία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Diecinueveavo-Siglo América en arte y literatura</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">presents documents paired with 7 paintings, including Mahantango Valley Farm, Jolly Flatboatmen, and White Cloud, Head Chief of the Iowas. These paintings and writings help students see the impact of geography, technology, economics, and politics as America moved west, shifted from farming to industry, and fought a civil war.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geschenkdokumente paßten mit 7 Anstrichen, 
einschließlich Mahantango Senke-Bauernhof, lustigem Flatboatmen und 
weißer Wolke, Hauptleiter des Iowas zusammen. Diese Anstrich- 
und Schreibenshilfe Kursteilnehmer sehen die Auswirkung von 
Geographie, von Technologie, von Volkswirtschaft und von Politik als 
Amerika, das nach Westen verschoben wird, vom Bewirtschaften auf 
Industrie verschoben ist und einem Bürgerkrieg gekämpft ist.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les documents de présents ont appareillé avec 7 
peintures, y compris la ferme de vallée de Mahantango, Flatboatmen 
gai, et nuage blanc, chef principal de l'Iowas. Ces étudiants 
d'aide de peintures et d'écritures voient l'impact de la géographie,
de la technologie, des sciences économiques, et de la politique comme
l'Amérique déplacée à l'ouest, décalée de l'affermage à 
l'industrie, et combattue une guerre civile.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">os originais de presentes emparelharam-se com as 7
pinturas, including a fazenda do vale de Mahantango, o Flatboatmen 
alegre, e a nuvem branca, chefe principal do Iowas. Estes 
estudantes da ajuda das pinturas e das escritas vêem o impacto da 
geografia, da tecnologia, da economia, e da política como América 
movida para o oeste, deslocada de cultivar à indústria, e lutada uma
guerra civil.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">i presenti documenti hanno accoppiato con 7 
pitture, compreso il podere della valle di Mahantango, Flatboatmen 
allegro e la nube bianca, capo capo dello Iowas. Questi allievi 
di aiuto di scritture e delle pitture vedono l'effetto di geografia, 
di tecnologia, di economia e di politica come America spostata verso 
ovest, spostata dall'agricoltura ad industria e combattuta una guerra 
civile.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρουσιάζει τα έγγραφα που ζευγαρώνονται με 7 έργα 
ζωγραφικής, συμπεριλαμβανομένου του αγροκτήματος κοιλάδων 
Mahantango, ευχάριστα Flatboatmen, και του άσπρου σύννεφου, 
επικεφαλής Προϊστάμενος του Iowas. Αυτοί οι σπουδαστές 
οδηγιών έργων ζωγραφικής και γραφών βλέπουνε τον αντίκτυπο
της γεωγραφίας, τεχνολογία, οικονομικά, και η πολιτική ως Αμερική
κίνησε τη δύση, που μετατοπίστηκε από την καλλιέργεια στη 
βιομηχανία, και διεξήγαγε έναν εμφύλιο πόλεμο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">los documentos de presentes emparejaron con 7 
pinturas, incluyendo granja del valle de Mahantango, Flatboatmen 
alegre, y la nube blanca, jefe principal del Iowas. Estos 
estudiantes de la ayuda de las pinturas y de las escrituras ven el 
impacto de la geografía, de la tecnología, de la economía, y de la 
política como América movida al oeste, cambiada de puesto de 
cultivar a la industria, y de combate una guerra civil.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205803</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108589</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/nineteenth-century-america-in-art-and-literature</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
