<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103054</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103054</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207159</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Ohio &amp; Erie Canal: Catalyst of Economic Development for Ohio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Ohio U. Erie Kanal: Katalysator der 
ökonomischen Entwicklung für Ohio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Canal de l'Ohio et d'Erie : Catalyseur de
développement économique pour l'Ohio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Canal De Ohio &amp; De Erie: Catalizador do 
desenvolvimento econômico para Ohio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Canale Di Erie &amp; Dell'Ohio: Catalizzatore
di sviluppo economico per l'Ohio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το κανάλι του Οχάιου &amp; του Erie: Καταλύτης της
οικονομικής ανάπτυξης για το Οχάιο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Canal De Ohio Y De Erie: Catalizador del 
desarrollo económico para Ohio</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">tells how the construction of this canal transformed one of the poorest states in the Union in the 1820s into the third most prosperous by 1840. The 308-mile canal helped open New York and New Orleans markets for central Ohio farmers and traders. Stores and taverns sprang up along the canal. People in the vast wilderness were able to get goods from eastern ports?cloth, glass, nails, salt, coffee, and tea. The state's population nearly quadrupled from 1820 to 1850.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erklärt, wie der Aufbau dieses Kanals einen der 
schlechtesten Zustände im Anschluß im 1820s in den Third umwandelte,
der bis zum 1840 am wohlhabendsten ist. Das 308-mile Kanal 
geholfene geöffnete New York und New-Orleans Märkte für zentrale 
Ohio Landwirte und Händler. Speicher und Taverns entstanden 
entlang den Kanal. Leute in der beträchtlichen Wildnis konnten,
Waren vom östlichen ports?cloth, vom Glas, von den Nägeln, vom Salz,
vom Kaffee und vom Tee zu erhalten. Die Bevölkerung des 
Zustandes vervierfachte fast von 1820 bis 1850.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dit que la construction de ce canal a transformé 
un des états les plus faibles dans l'union dans le 1820s en tiers le 
plus prospère d'ici 1840. Le 308-mile marchés ouverts de New 
York aidés par canal et de Nouvelle-Orléans pour les fermiers et les
commerçants centraux de l'Ohio. Les mémoires et les tavernes 
ont pris naissance le long du canal. Les personnes dans le vaste
désert pouvaient obtenir des marchandises du ports?cloth, du verre, 
des ongles, du sel, du café, et du thé orientaux. La 
population de l'état a presque quadruplé de 1820 à 1850.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">diz como a construção deste canal transformou um
dos estados os mais deficientes na união no 1820s no third o mais 
próspero por 1840. O 308-mile mercados abertos ajudados canal 
de New York e de Nova Orleães para fazendeiros e comerciantes 
centrais de Ohio. As lojas e os taverns saltaram acima ao longo 
do canal. Os povos na região selvagem vasta podiam  começar 
bens do ports?cloth, do vidro, dos pregos, do sal, do café, e do chá
orientais. A população do estado quadrupled quase  1820 a 
1850.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">dice a come la costruzione di questo canale ha 
trasformato uno del più povero dichiara nell'unione nel 
1820s nel terzo più prosperoso entro 1840. Il canale 308-mile 
ha aiutato i mercati aperti de New Orleans e de New York per i 
coltivatori ed i commercianti centrali dell'Ohio. I depositi e 
le locande si sono generati lungo il canale. La gente nella 
selva ampia poteva ottenere le merci da ports?cloth, da vetro, dai 
chiodi, dal sale, dal caffè e dal tè orientali. La popolazione
di dichiarare quasi ha quadruplicato 1820 - 1850.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">λέει πώς η κατασκευή αυτού του καναλιού 
μετασχημάτισε μια από τις πιό κακές καταστάσεις στην ένωση στο 
1820s στο τρίτο το πιό ακμάζωτο από 1840. Το κανάλι 
308-μιλίου βοήθησε τις ανοικτές αγορές της Νέας Υόρκης και της 
Νέας Ορλεάνης για τους κεντρικούς αγρότες και τους εμπόρους του 
Οχάιου. Τα καταστήματα και οι ταβέρνες αναπήδησαν επάνω 
κατά μήκος του καναλιού. Οι άνθρωποι στην απέραντη 
αγριότητα ήταν σε θέση να πάρουν τα αγαθά από το ανατολικούς 
ports?cloth, το γυαλί, τα καρφιά, το άλας, τον καφέ, και το 
τσάι. Ο κρατικός πληθυσμός τετραπλασίασε σχεδόν από 
1820 έως 1850.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">dice cómo la construcción de este canal 
transformó uno de los estados más pobres de la unión en el 1820s en
el tercero más próspero antes de 1840. El 308-mile mercados 
abiertos ayudados canal de Nueva York y de New Orleans para los 
granjeros y los comerciantes centrales de Ohio. Los almacenes y 
las tabernas se originaron a lo largo del canal. La gente en el 
yermo extenso podía conseguir mercancías de ports?cloth, de cristal,
de clavos, de sal, de café, y de té del este. La población 
del estado cuadruplicó casi a partir la 1820 a 1850.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207159</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103054</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/ohio-erie-canal</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
