<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106973</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106973</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206582</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Latin America and the Caribbean: Peace Corps</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lateinisches Amerika und die Karibischen Meere: 
Friedenskorps</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">l'Amérique latine et les Caraïbes : Corps 
De Paix</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">América latin e as Caraíbas: Corpo De Paz</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'america latina ed i Caraibi: Corpo 
di pace</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Λατινική Αμερική και οι Καραϊβικές Θάλασσες: 
Ειρήνη Σώμα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">América latina y el Caribe: Cuerpo De Paz</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">provides lessons around stories, letters, poems, and folk tales from experiences of Peace Corps volunteers. Topics include the geography and cultures of the Dominican Republic, hurricanes, hero worship, conducting interviews, Paraguay, the risks of a one-crop economy (coffee), how best to use one's time in different cultures, why service to others matters, and the common good.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt Lektionen um Geschichten, Zeichen, Gedichte
und Volksgeschichten von den Erfahrungen der Friedenskorpsfreiwilliger
zur Verfügung. Themen schließen die Geographie und die 
Kulturen der Dominikanischen Republik, Hurrikane, Heldanbetung, 
Leitinterviews, Paraguay, die Gefahren einer Eingetreide Wirtschaft 
(Kaffee) ein, wie man gut irgendjemandes Zeit in den unterschiedlichen
Kulturen, warum Service zu anderen ausmacht und das geläufige gute 
verwendet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fournit des leçons autour des histoires, des 
lettres, des poésies, et des contes folkloriques des expériences des
volontaires de corps de paix. Les sujets incluent la géographie
et les cultures de la République Dominicaine dominicaine, ouragans, 
culte de héros, entrevues de conduite, Paraguay, les risques d'une 
économie d'un-collecte (café), comment mieux utiliser son temps dans
différentes cultures, pourquoi le service à d'autres importe, et le 
bien commun.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fornece lições em torno das histórias, das 
letras, dos poemas, e dos tales populares das experiências de 
voluntários do corpo de paz. Os tópicos incluem a geografia e 
as culturas da república dominican, furacões, adoração do herói, 
entrevistas conduzindo, Paraguai, os riscos de uma economia da 
um-colheita (café), como melhor usar one's tempo em culturas 
diferentes, porque o serviço a outro importa, e o bom comum.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fornisce le lezioni intorno alle storia, alle 
lettere, ai poems ed ai racconti pieghi per esperienza nei volontari 
di Corpo di pace. I soggetti includono il più bene la 
geografia e le colture della Repubblica Domenicana, uragani, culto del
hero, interviste di condotta, Paraguay, i rischi di economia del 
un-raccolto (caffè), quanto usare il suo tempo nelle colture 
differenti, perchè il servizio ad altri importa ed il buon comune.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρέχει τα μαθήματα γύρω από τις ιστορίες, τις 
επιστολές, τα ποιήματα, και τις λαϊκές ιστορίες από την 
εμπειρία των εθελοντών ειρήνης Σώμα. Τα θέματα 
περιλαμβάνουν τη γεωγραφία και τους πολιτισμούς της δομινικανής 
Δημοκρατίας, τυφώνες, λατρεία ηρώων, που πραγματοποιεί τις 
συνεντεύξεις, Παραγουάη, οι κίνδυνοι οικονομίας ένας-συγκομιδών 
(καφές), πόσο καλύτερα να χρησιμοποιήσει το χρόνο κάποιου στους 
διαφορετικούς πολιτισμούς, γιατί η υπηρεσία σε άλλοι πειράζει, 
και το κοινό αγαθό.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">proporciona a lecciones alrededor de historias, de
cartas, de poemas, y de cuentos populares por experiencia de los 
voluntarios del cuerpo de paz. Los asuntos incluyen la 
geografía y las culturas de la República Dominicana, huracanes, 
adoración del héroe, entrevistas que conducen, Paraguay, los riesgos
de una economía de la uno-cosecha (café), cómo lo más mejor 
posible utilizar su tiempo en diversas culturas, porqué importa el 
servicio a otros, y el bueno común.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206582</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106973</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/latin-america-and-the-caribbean-peace-corps</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
