<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104737</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104737</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206236</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Hands-On Universe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hand-Auf Universum</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Main-Sur l'Univers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Mão- No Universo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Mano- Sull'Universo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εμπράγματος κόσμος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mano-En El Universo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is an educational program that enables students to investigate the universe while applying tools and concepts from science, math, and technology. Using the Internet, HOU participants around the world request observations from an automated telescope, download images from a large image archive, and analyze them with the aid of user-friendly image processing software.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist ein pädagogisches Programm, das 
Kursteilnehmer aktiviert, das Universum beim Anwenden der Hilfsmittel 
und der Konzepte nachzuforschen von der Wissenschaft, von Mathe und 
von der Technologie. Mit dem Internet downloaden HOU Teilnehmer 
um die Weltantragbeobachtungen von einem automatisierten Teleskop, 
Bilder von einem großen Bildarchiv und analysieren sie mit dem 
Hilfsmittel der benutzerfreundlichen Bildübersetzungsoftware.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est un programme éducatif qui permet à des 
étudiants d'étudier l'univers tout en appliquant des outils et des 
concepts à partir de la science, des maths, et de la technologie. 
En utilisant l'Internet, les participants de HOU autour des 
observations de demande du monde d'un télescope automatisé, 
téléchargent des images de grandes archives d'image, et les 
analysent à l'aide du logiciel convivial de traitement d'image.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é um programa educacional que permita estudantes 
de investigar o universo ao aplicar ferramentas e conceitos da 
ciência, do math, e da tecnologia. Usando o Internet, os 
participants de HOU em torno das observações do pedido do mundo de 
um telescópio automatizado, download imagens de um arquivo grande da 
imagem, e analisam-nas com o dae (dispositivo automático de entrada) 
do software user-friendly processar de imagem.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è un programma educativo che permette agli 
allievi di studiare l'universo mentre applica gli strumenti ed i 
concetti dalla scienza, dal per la matematica e dalla tecnologia. 
Usando il Internet, i partecipanti di HOU intorno alle 
osservazioni di richiesta del mondo da un telescopio automatizzato, 
trasferiscono le immagini dal sistema centrale verso i satelliti da un
grande archivio di immagine e le analizzano con l'aiuto del software 
facile da usare di elaborazione di immagini.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι ένα εκπαιδευτικό πρόγραμμα που επιτρέπει στους 
σπουδαστές για να ερευνήσει τον κόσμο εφαρμόζοντας τα εργαλεία 
και τις έννοιες από την επιστήμη, math, και την τεχνολογία. 
Χρησιμοποιώντας το Διαδίκτυο, οι συμμετέχοντες HOU γύρω 
από τις παρατηρήσεις παγκόσμιου αιτήματος από ένα 
αυτοματοποιημένο τηλεσκόπιο, μεταφορτώνουν τις εικόνες από ένα 
μεγάλο αρχείο εικόνας, και τις αναλύουν με την ενίσχυση του 
φιλικού προς το χρήστη λογισμικού επεξεργασίας εικόνας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es un programa educativo que permite a estudiantes
investigar el universo mientras que aplica las herramientas y los 
conceptos de ciencia, de matemáticas, y de tecnología. Usando 
el Internet, los participantes de HOU alrededor de las observaciones 
de la petición del mundo de un telescopio automatizado, descargan 
imágenes de un archivo grande de la imagen, y las analizan con la 
ayuda del software convivial del proceso de imagen.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206236</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104737</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/hands-on-universe</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
