<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106241</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106241</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206399</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Letters, Telegrams, and Photographs Illustrating Factors That Affected the Civil War</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zeichen, Telegramme und Fotographien, die Faktoren 
veranschaulichen, die den Bürgerkrieg beeinflußten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Lettres, télégrammes, et photographies illustrant
les facteurs qui ont affecté la guerre civile</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Letras, telegramas, e fotografias que ilustram os 
fatores que afetaram a guerra civil</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lettere, telegrammi e fotografie che illustrano i 
fattori che hanno interessato la guerra civile</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστολές, τηλεγραφήματα, και φωτογραφίες που 
επεξηγούν τους παράγοντες που είχαν επιπτώσεις στον εμφύλιο 
πόλεμο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cartas, telegramas, y fotografías que ilustran los
factores que afectaron la guerra civil</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Allows students to analyze a variety of documents to identify events, actions, and individuals who contributed to the Civil War's outcome. This lesson correlates to the National History Standards and the National Standards for Civics and Social Sciences. It also has cross-curricular connections with your history, government, and American literature.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erlaubt Kursteilnehmern, eine Vielzahl der 
Dokumente zu analysieren, um Fälle, Tätigkeiten und Einzelpersonen 
zu kennzeichnen, die zum Resultat des Bürgerkrieges beitrugen. 
Diese Lektion bezieht mit den nationalen Geschichte Standards 
und den nationalen Standards für Gemeinschaftskunde und 
Sozialwissenschaften aufeinander. Sie hat auch 
Kreuzlehrplananschlüsse mit Ihrer Geschichte, Regierung und 
amerikanischen Literatur.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Permet à des étudiants d'analyser une variété 
de documents pour identifier des événements, des actions, et des 
individus qui ont contribué aux résultats de guerre civile. 
Cette leçon se corrèle avec les normes nationales d'histoire 
et les normes nationales pour l'éducation civique et les sciences 
sociales. Elle a également les connexions croix-curriculaires 
avec votre histoire, gouvernement, et littérature américaine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Permite que os estudantes analisem uma variedade 
dos originais para identificar eventos, ações, e indivíduos que 
contribuíram ao resultado de guerra civil. Esta lição 
correlaciona aos padrões nacionais do history e aos padrões 
nacionais para o civics e ciências sociais. Tem também 
conexões cruz-cross-curricular com seus history, governo, e 
literatura americana.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Permette che gli allievi analizzino una varietà 
di documenti per identificare gli eventi, le azioni e gli individui 
che hanno contribuito al risultato della guerra civile. Questa 
lezione correla agli standard nazionali di storia ed agli standard 
nazionali per civics e le scienze sociali. Egualmente ha 
collegamenti traversa-d'insegnamento con la vostri storia, governo e 
letteratura americana.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιτρέπει στους σπουδαστές για να αναλύσει ποικίλα 
έγγραφα για να προσδιορίσει τα γεγονότα, τις ενέργειες, και τα 
άτομα που συνέβαλαν στην έκβαση του εμφύλιου πολέμου. Αυτό
το μάθημα συσχετίζει στα εθνικά πρότυπα ιστορίας και τα εθνικά 
πρότυπα για Civics και τις κοινωνικές επιστήμες. Έχει 
επίσης τις διαγώνιος-διδακτικές συνδέσεις με την ιστορία, την 
κυβέρνηση, και την αμερικανική λογοτεχνία σας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Permite que los estudiantes analicen una variedad 
de documentos para identificar a acontecimientos, a acciones, y a los 
individuos que contribuyeron al resultado de la guerra civil. 
Esta lección correlaciona a los estándares nacionales de la 
historia y a los estándares nacionales para el civics y las ciencias 
sociales. También tiene conexiones cruz-del plan de estudios 
con su historia, gobierno, y literatura americana.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206399</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106241</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/letters-telegrams-and-photographs-illustrating-factors-that-affected-the-civil-war</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
