<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107085</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107085</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212641</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Microbial Biorealm</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Mikrobenbiorealm</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Biorealm Microbien</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Biorealm Microbial</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Biorealm Microbico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το μικροβιακό Biorealm</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Biorealm Microbiano</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Microbial Biorealm is an informational site about microbes written by students for students. Hosted by Kenyon College, the site includes molecular and taxonomic information about microbes from all three domains of life. A comprehensive table lists the properties and characteristics of each domain of life while taxonomy pages list classification, description, significance, genome structure, cell structure, metabolism, ecology, isolation, cultivation, and references specific to individual taxa. The home page features a menu of links to navigate through the Microbial Biorealm as well as links to several related organizations and resources.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Mikrobenbiorealm ist eine informatorische Site
über die Mikroben, die von den Kursteilnehmern für Kursteilnehmer 
geschrieben werden. Bewirtet durch Kenyon College, schließt die
Site die molekularen und taxonomischen Informationen über Mikroben 
von allen drei Gebieten des Lebens ein. Eine komplette Tabelle 
druckt die Eigenschaften und die Eigenschaften jedes Gebietes des 
Lebens aus, während Taxonomie Liste Klassifikation, Beschreibung, 
Stichhaltigkeit, Genomstruktur, Zelle Struktur, Metabolismus, 
Ökologie, Lokalisierung, Bearbeitung und die Referenzen, die auf 
einzelnen Taxa spezifisch sind paginiert. Das Home Page 
kennzeichnet ein Menü der Links, um durch das Mikrobenbiorealm sowie 
Links zu einigen in Verbindung stehenden Organisationen und zu 
Betriebsmitteln zu steuern.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Biorealm microbien est un site informationnel 
au sujet des microbes écrits par des étudiants pour des étudiants. 
Accueilli par Kenyon College, le site inclut des informations 
moléculaires et taxonomiques sur des microbes de chacun des trois 
domaines de la vie. Un tableau complet présente les 
propriétés et les caractéristiques de chaque domaine de la vie 
tandis que la taxonomie pagine la classification de liste, la 
description, la signification, la structure de génome, la structure 
de cellules, le métabolisme, l'écologie, l'isolement, la culture, et
les références spécifiques à différents taxa. Le Home Page 
comporte un menu des liens pour diriger par le Biorealm microbien 
aussi bien que des liens à plusieurs organismes et ressources 
relatifs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Biorealm microbial é um local informativo sobre
os micróbios escritos por estudantes para estudantes. Hospedado
por Kenyon Faculdade, o local inclui a informação molecular e 
taxonomic sobre micróbios de todos os três domínios da vida. 
Uma tabela detalhada alista as propriedades e as 
características de cada domínio da vida quando o taxonomy paginar a 
classificação da lista, a descrição, o significado, a estrutura do
genome, a estrutura da pilha, o metabolism, o ecology, a isolação, o
cultivation, e as referências específicas aos taxa individuais. 
O Home Page caracteriza um menu das ligações para navigate com
o Biorealm microbial as.well.as as ligações a diversos 
organizações e recursos relacionados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Biorealm microbico è un luogo informativo 
circa i microbi scritti dagli allievi per gli allievi. Ospitato 
da Kenyon College, il luogo include le informazioni molecolari e 
tassonomiche sui microbi da tutti e tre i settori di vita. Un 
piano completo presenta le proprietà e le caratteristiche di ogni 
settore di vita mentre la tassonomia pagina la classificazione della 
lista, la descrizione, l'importanza, la struttura del genome, la 
struttura delle cellule, il metabolismo, l'ecologia, l'isolamento, la 
coltura ed i riferimenti specifici ai diversi tassi. Il Home 
Page caratterizza un menu dei collegamenti per traversare con il 
Biorealm microbico così come i collegamenti a parecchie 
organizzazioni e risorse relative.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το μικροβιακό Biorealm είναι μια ενημερωτική 
περιοχή για τα μικρόβια που γράφονται από τους σπουδαστές για 
τους σπουδαστές. Φιλοξενημένη από Kenyon κολλέγιο, η 
περιοχή περιλαμβάνει τις μοριακές και ταξονομικές πληροφορίες για
τα μικρόβια και από τις τρεις δικτυακές γειτονιές της ζωής. 
Ένας περιεκτικός πίνακας εμφανίζει λίστα τις ιδιότητες και
τα χαρακτηριστικά κάθε δικτυακής γειτονιάς της ζωής ενώ οι 
σελίδες ταξονομίας εμφανίζουν λίστα την ταξινόμηση, την 
περιγραφή, τη σημασία, τη δομή γονιδιώματος, τη δομή κυττάρων, 
το μεταβολισμό, την οικολογία, την απομόνωση, την καλλιέργεια, και
τις αναφορές συγκεκριμένες για μεμονωμένα taxa. Η αρχική 
σελίδα χαρακτηρίζει έναν κατάλογο επιλογής των συνδέσεων για να 
πλοηγήσει μέσω του μικροβιακού Biorealm καθώς επίσης και των 
συνδέσεων με διάφορα σχετικά οργανώσεις και στοιχεία 
συμπεριφοράς.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Biorealm microbiano es un sitio informativo 
sobre los microbios escritos por los estudiantes para los estudiantes.
Recibido por Kenyon College, el sitio incluye la información 
molecular y taxonómica sobre microbios de los tres dominios de la 
vida. Un vector comprensivo enumera las características y las 
características de cada dominio de la vida mientras que la taxonomía
pagina la clasificación de la lista, la descripción, la 
significación, la estructura del genoma, la estructura de la 
célula, el metabolismo, la ecología, el aislamiento, la 
cultivación, y las referencias específicas a los taxa individuales. 
El Home Page ofrece un menú de conexiones para navegar con el 
Biorealm microbiano así como conexiones a varias organizaciones y 
recursos relacionados.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ALLISON WHIPPLE
FN:ALLISON WHIPPLE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ZEVA LEVINE
FN:ZEVA LEVINE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:LAURA DAMON-MOORE
FN:LAURA DAMON-MOORE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ARIEL KAHR
FN:ARIEL KAHR
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:HANNAH SACKS
FN:HANNAH SACKS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MICHAEL STULBERG
FN:MICHAEL STULBERG
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CASEY M. SMITH
FN:CASEY M. SMITH
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:SHANA SCOGIN
FN:SHANA SCOGIN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JOAN SLONCZEWSKI
FN:JOAN SLONCZEWSKI
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:KENYON COLLEGE
FN:KENYON COLLEGE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212641</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107085</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-microbial-biorealm</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
