<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103131</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103131</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087447</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Boycott Fever</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Boykott-Fieber</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Fièvre de Boycott</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Febre Do Boycott</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Febbre Di Boicottaggio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πυρετός μποϊκοταρίσματος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fiebre Del Boicoteo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A developing sense of working-class community paved the way for a string of boycotts in the mid-1880s. Boycotts were a way to win concessions from an employer by convincing other workers not to patronize his business. The movement peaked in 1886 with campaigns across the country; that year, there were 150 boycotts in New York State alone. This 1887 cartoon in the satirical weekly  Life  commented on the ubiquity of the boycott. "Whereas," reads one boy, representing a committee of disgruntled candy-cart customers, "we find we don't git red color enough in our strawberry cream, nor enough yaller in our wanilla, . . . to say nothin' o' the small measure of peanuts we gits for a cent; therefore, be it resolved . . . that all the stands in the city is boycotted until these things is righted."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine sich entwickelnde Richtung der 
Arbeiterklassegemeinschaft pflasterte die Methode für eine 
Zeichenkette von Boykotts im mid-1880s. Boykotts waren eine 
Methode, Zugeständnisse von einem Arbeitgeber zu gewinnen, indem sie 
andere Arbeiter nicht patronize sein Geschäft überzeugten. Die
Bewegung ragte 1886 mit Kampagnen über dem Land empor; daß 
Jahr, dort 150 Boykotts im Staat New-York alleine waren. Diese 
Karikatur 1887 in der satirical wöchentlichen Lebensdauer 
kommentierte die Allgegenwart des Boykotts. "während," einen 
Jungen liest, einen Ausschuß der disgruntled Süßigkeit-Karre Kunden
vertretend, "wir finden uns nicht git rote Farbe genug in unserer 
Erdbeerecreme noch genügend yaller in unserem wanilla. . 
. nothin ' O ' das kleine Maß der Erdnüsse sagen wir 
gits für einen Cent; folglich sei es behoben. . . 
daß alle Standplätze in der Stadt boykottiert wird, bis diese 
Sachen ist berichtigt."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un sens se développant de la communauté de 
classe ouvrier a préparé le terrain pour une chaîne de caractères 
des boycotts dans le mid-1880s. Les boycotts étaient une voie 
de gagner des concessions d'un employeur en convainquant d'autres 
ouvriers de ne pas patronner ses affaires. Le mouvement a fait 
une pointe en 1886 avec des campagnes à travers le pays ; que 
l'année, là étaient 150 boycotts dans seul l'état de New-York. 
Ce dessin animé 1887 dans la vie hebdomadaire satirique a 
présenté ses observations sur l'ubiquité du boycott. "tandis 
que," lit un garçon, représentant un comité des clients contrariés
de sucrerie-chariot, "nous nous trouvons pas  couleur rouge de git 
assez en notre crème de fraise, ni assez de yaller dans notre 
wanilla. . . pour dire le nothin 'o 'la petite 
mesure d'arachides nous gits pour un cent ; donc, que ce soit 
résolu. . . que tous les stands dans la ville est 
boycottés jusqu'à ce que ces choses soit redressées."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um sentido tornando-se da comunidade do 
working-class pavimentou a maneira para uma corda dos boycotts no 
mid-1880s. Os boycotts eram uma maneira ganhar concessões de um
empregador convencendo outros trabalhadores não patronize seu 
negócio. O movimento peaked em 1886 com campanhas através do 
país; que o ano, lá era 150 boycotts no estado de New York 
sozinho. Este cartoon 1887 na vida semanal satirical comentou no
ubiquity do boycott. "visto que," lê um menino, representando 
um comitê de clientes disgruntled do doce-carro, "nós 
encontramos-nos não  cor vermelha do git bastante em nosso creme do 
strawberry, nem bastante yaller em nosso wanilla. . . 
para dizer o nothin ' o ' a medida pequena dos amendoins nós 
gits para um centavo; , seja conseqüentemente ele resolveu. 
. . que todos os carrinhos na cidade boycotted até 
que estas coisas estiverem endireitadas."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un senso di sviluppo della Comunità della classe 
operaia ha aperto la strada per una serie di boicottaggi nel 
mid-1880s. I boicottaggi erano un modo vincere le concessioni da
un datore di lavoro convincendo altri operai non patronize il suo 
commercio. Il movimento ha alzato in 1886 con le campagne 
attraverso il paese; che l'anno, là era 150 boicottaggi a New 
York Dichiari da solo. Questo fumetto 1887 nella vita 
settimanale satirical ha commentato l'ubiquità del boicottaggio. 
"mentre," legge un ragazzo, rappresentante un comitato dei 
clienti disgruntled del caramella-carrello, "li troviamo non colore 
rosso del git abbastanza in nostra crema della fragola, né abbastanza
yaller nel nostro wanilla. . . per dire nothin 'o 
'la piccola misura delle arachidi noi gits per un centesimo; 
quindi, sia risolto. . . che tutti i basamenti
nella città è boicottato fino a radrizzare queste cose."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια αναπτυσσόμενη αίσθηση της κοινότητας εργατικών 
τάξεων προετοιμάζω το έδαφος για μια συμβολοσειρά των 
μποϊκοταρισμάτων στα μέσα της 1880s. Τα μποϊκοταρίσματα 
ήταν ένας τρόπος να κερδηθούν οι παραχωρήσεις από έναν 
εργοδότη με να πείσουν άλλους εργαζομένους όχι η επιχείρησή 
του. Η μετακίνηση όξυνε το 1886 με τις εκστρατείες σε 
ολόκληρη τη χώρα  εκείνο το έτος, υπήρξαν 150 
μποϊκοταρίσματα στο κράτος της Νέας Υόρκης μόνο. Αυτά τα 
κινούμενα σχέδια 1887 στη σατυρική εβδομαδιαία ζωή σχολίασαν 
την πανταχού παρουσία του μποϊκοταρίσματος. "Εκτιμώντας 
ότι," διαβάζει ένα αγόρι, που αντιπροσωπεύει μια επιτροπή των 
δυσαρεστημένων πελατών καραμέλα-κάρρων, "βρίσκουμε ότι όχι 
git κόκκινο χρώμα αρκετοί στην κρέμα φραουλών μας, ούτε 
αρκετός yaller στο wanilla μας. .. για να πει 
nothin "το ο" το μικρό μέτρο των φυστικιών εμείς gits για 
ένα σεντ  επομένως, είτε επιλυμένος. .. ότι 
όλες οι στάσεις στην πόλη μποϊκοτάρονται μέχρι αυτά τα 
πράγματα διορθώνονται."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un sentido que se convertía de la comunidad de la
clase obrera pavimentó la manera para una cadena de boicoteos en el 
mid-1880s. Los boicoteos eran una manera de ganar concesiones de
un patrón convenciendo a otros trabajadores que no patronicen su 
negocio. El movimiento enarboló en 1886 con campañas a través
del país; que el año, allí era 150 boicoteos en el estado de 
Nueva York solamente. Esta historieta 1887 en la vida semanal 
satírica comentó respecto a la ubicuidad del boicoteo. 
"mientras que," lee a un muchacho, representando a un comité de
los clientes contrariedades del caramelo-carro, "nos encontramos no  
color rojo del git bastante en nuestra crema de la fresa, ni bastante 
yaller en nuestro wanilla. . . para decir el nothin 
' o ' la medida pequeña de cacahuetes nosotros gits para un centavo; 
por lo tanto, sea resuelto. . . que todos los 
soportes en la ciudad están boicoteados hasta que se enderezan estas 
cosas."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087447</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103131</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/boycott-fever</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
