<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108090</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108090</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087376</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Altared States: Marriage Ends an Organizer's Career</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Altared Zustände: Verbindung beendet die 
Karriere eines Organisators</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">États d'Altared : Le mariage termine la 
carrière d'un organisateur</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Estados De Altared: A união termina a 
carreira de um organizer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Altared Dichiara: L'unione conclude 
la carriera dell'organizzatore</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κράτη Altared: Ο γάμος τελειώνει τη 
σταδιοδρομία ενός διοργανωτή</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Estados De Altared: La unión termina la 
carrera de un organizador</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1889, Knights of Labor General Investigator Leonora Barry surprised the union by recommending that the Woman's Department, which she headed, be disbanded. "There can be no separation or distinction of wage workers on account of sex," she argued, "and a separate department for the interests of women is a direct contradiction of this." The Knights rejected her recommendations, and Barry continued her organizing work. What finally halted Barry's organizing efforts--and the work of the union's Woman's Department--was her marriage in 1890 to Obadiah Read Lake, a St. Louis Knight and printer. Terrence V. Powderly, the head of the Knights, had not always fully supported Barry's efforts and his readiness to see her marriage as the equivalent of her death (as this letter to a fellow Knight revealed) showed the limitations of the Knights' commitment to women's full participation. Although Barry's labor organizing ended, she remained active in temperance, women's suffrage, and other progressive causes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1889 überraschten Ritter des Arbeitsgenerals 
Investigator Leonora Barry den Anschluß, indem sie empfahlen, daß 
die Abteilung der Frau, die sie vorangeht, aufgelöst wird. "es 
kann keine Trennung oder Unterscheidung der Lohnarbeiter wegen des 
Geschlechtes geben," argumentierte sie, "und eine unterschiedliche 
Abteilung für die Interessen der Frauen ist ein direkter Widerspruch 
von diesem." Die Ritter wiesen ihre Empfehlungen zurück, und 
Barry setzte ihre organisierende Arbeit fort. Was schließlich 
Barrys organisierende Bemühungen anhielt -- und die Arbeit der 
Abteilung der Frau des Anschlußes -- war ihre Verbindung 1890 zu 
Obadiah gelesenem See, zu einem St. Louis Ritter und zum Drucker. 
Terrence V. Powderly, der Kopf der Ritter, hatte nicht immer 
völlig Bemühungen und seine Schnelligkeit Barrys, ihre Verbindung zu
sehen geunterstützt, während das Äquivalent ihres Todes (wie dieses
Zeichen zu einem Gefährteritter aufgedeckt) die Beschränkungen der 
Verpflichtung der Ritter zur vollen Teilnahme der Frauen zeigte. 
Obgleich Arbeit Barrys das Organisieren beendete, blieb sie im 
temperance, im Stimmrecht der Frauen und in anderen progressiven 
Ursachen aktiv.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1889, les chevaliers du Général de travail 
Investigator Leonora Barry ont étonné l'union en recommandant que le
service de la femme, qu'elle dirige, soit congédié. "il ne 
peut y avoir aucune séparation ou distinction des ouvriers de salaire
à cause de sexe," elle a discuté, "et un service séparé pour les 
intérêts des femmes est une contradiction directe de ceci." 
Les chevaliers ont rejeté ses recommandations, et Barry a 
continué son travail d'organisation. Ce qui a finalement 
stoppé les efforts d'organisation de Barry -- et le travail du 
service de la femme des syndicats -- était son mariage en 1890 au lac
lu par Obadiah, à un chevalier de St Louis et à l'imprimante. 
Terrence V. Powderly, le chef des chevaliers, n'avait pas 
toujours pleinement approuvé les efforts et sa promptitude de Barry 
de voir son mariage pendant que l'équivalent de sa mort (comme cette 
lettre à un chevalier de camarade indiqué) montrait les limitations 
de l'engagement des chevaliers à la pleine participation des femmes. 
Bien que l'organisation du travail de Barry ait terminé, elle 
est restée active dans la modération, le suffrage des femmes, et 
d'autres causes progressives.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1889, os knights do general labor Investigator 
Leonora Barry surpreenderam a união recomendando que o departamento 
da mulher, que dirige, disbanded. "não pode haver nenhuma 
separação ou distinção de trabalhadores do salário no cliente do 
sexo," discutiu, "e um departamento separado para os interesses das 
mulheres é um contradiction direto deste." Os knights 
rejeitaram suas recomendações, e Barry continuou seu trabalho 
organizando. O que parou finalmente esforços organizando de 
Barry -- e o trabalho do departamento da mulher da união -- era sua 
união em 1890 ao lago lido Obadiah, a um knight do St. Louis e à 
impressora. Terrence V. Powderly, cabeça dos knights, não 
tinha suportado sempre inteiramente sua prontidão de Barry esforços 
e ver sua união enquanto o equivalente de sua morte (como esta letra 
a um knight do companheiro revelado) mostrou as limitações do 
compromisso dos knights' à participação cheia das mulheres. 
Embora organizar do trabalho de Barry terminasse, remanesceu 
ativa no temperance, no suffrage das mulheres, e em outras causas 
progressivas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1889, i cavalieri del General Di lavoro 
Investigator Leonora Barry hanno sorprendo l'unione suggerendo che il 
reparto della donna, che dirige, è disperso. "non ci può 
essere separazione o distinzione degli operai dello stipendio a causa 
del sesso," ha discusso, "e un reparto separato per gli interessi 
delle donne è una contraddizione diretta di questo." I 
cavalieri hanno rifiutato le sue raccomandazioni e Barry ha continuato
il suo lavoro d'organizzazione. Che cosa infine ha fermato gli 
sforzi d'organizzazione del Barry -- ed il lavoro del reparto della 
donna del sindacato -- era la sua unione in 1890 al lago colto 
Obadiah, ad un cavaliere de St. Louis ed alla stampante. 
Terrence V. Powderly, la testa dei cavalieri, sempre 
completamente non aveva sostenuto gli sforzi e la sua prontezza del 
Barry vedere la sua unione mentre l'equivalente della sua morte (come 
questa lettera ad un cavaliere del collega rivelatore) ha mostrato le 
limitazioni dell'impegno dei cavalieri a partecipazione completa delle
donne. Anche se l'organizzazione di lavoro del Barry si è 
conclusa, è rimasto attiva in temperance, nel suffrage delle donne ed
in altre cause progressive.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1889, οι ιππότες του γενικού ανακριτή Leonora 
Barry εργασίας εξέπληξαν την ένωση με τη σύσταση ότι το τμήμα
της γυναίκας, που διεύθυνε, απολύεται. "Δεν μπορεί να 
υπάρξει καμία χωρισμός ή διάκριση των εργαζομένων αμοιβών εξ 
αιτίας του φύλου," υποστήριξε, "και ένα χωριστό τμήμα για τα 
συμφέροντα των γυναικών είναι μια άμεση αντίφαση αυτού." 
Οι ιππότες απέρριψαν τις συστάσεις της, και ο Barry την 
συνέχισε που οργανώνει την εργασία. Αυτό που σταμάτησε 
τελικά την οργάνωση του Barry προσπάθειες -- και η εργασία του 
τμήματος της γυναίκας της ένωσης -- ήταν ο γάμος της το 1890 
διαβασμένη την Obadiah λίμνη, ένα ST Louis Knight και 
τον εκτυπωτή. Terrence Θ*Β. Powderly, ο προϊστάμενος 
των ιπποτών, όχι πάντα πλήρως είχε υποστηρίξει τις προσπάθειες 
του Barry και την ετοιμότητά του να δει το γάμο της 
δεδομένου ότι το αντίτιμο του θανάτου της (ως αυτήν την επιστολή
σε έναν συντροφικό ιππότη αποκαλυφθέντα) εμφάνισε τους 
περιορισμούς της δέσμευσης των ιπποτών για την πλήρη συμμετοχή 
των γυναικών. Αν και η οργάνωση εργασίας του Barry 
τελείωσε, παρέμεινε ενεργός στη μετριοπάθεια, την ψήφο των 
γυναικών, και άλλες προοδευτικές αιτίες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1889, los caballeros de general de trabajo 
Investigator Leonora Barry sorprendieron la unión recomendando que el
departamento de la mujer, que ella dirigió, esté disuelto. "no
puede haber separación o distinción de los trabajadores del salario 
a causa de sexo," ella discutió, "y un departamento separado para los
intereses de mujeres es una contradicción directa de esto." Los
caballeros rechazaron sus recomendaciones, y Barry continuó su 
trabajo de ordenación. Qué finalmente paró los esfuerzos de 
ordenación de Barry -- y el trabajo del departamento de la mujer de 
la unión -- estaba su unión en 1890 al lago leído Obadiah, a un 
caballero de St. Louis y a la impresora. Terrence V. Powderly, 
la pista de los caballeros, no había utilizado siempre completamente 
los esfuerzos y su preparación de Barry de ver su unión mientras que
el equivalente de su muerte (como esta carta a un caballero del 
compañero revelado) mostró las limitaciones de la consolidación de 
los caballeros a la participación completa de las mujeres. 
Aunque la ordenación del trabajo de Barry terminó, ella 
seguía siendo activa en temperance, el sufragio de las mujeres, y 
otras causas progresivas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087376</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108090</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/altared-states-marriage-ends-an-organizers-career</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
