<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106653</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106653</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086997</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Nat Turner rebellion.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der nationale Turner Aufstand.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La rébellion nationale de Turner.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A rebelião nat de Turner.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Ribellione Nazionale Del Turner.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η εθνική εξέγερση τορναδόρων.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La rebelión nacional de Turner.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1831 a slave named Nat Turner led a rebellion in Southhampton County, Virginia. A religious leader and self-styled Baptist minister, Turner and a group of followers killed some sixty white men, women, and children on the night of August 21. Turner and 16 of his conspirators were captured and executed, but the incident continued to haunt Southern whites. Blacks were randomly killed all over Southhampton County; many were beheaded and their heads left along the roads to warn others. In the wake of the uprising planters tightened their grip on slaves and slavery. This woodcut was published in an 1831 account of the slave uprising.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1831 führte ein Sklave, der Nat Turner benannt wurde, 
einen Aufstand in der Southhampton Grafschaft, Virginia. Ein 
frommer Führer und self-styled ein Baptistminister, ein Turner und 
eine Gruppe Nachfolger beendeten ca. sechzig weiße Männer, Frauen 
und Kinder auf der Nacht von August 21. Turner und 16 seiner 
Verschwörer wurden erfaßt und durchgeführt, aber das Ereignis fuhr 
fort, südliches Weiß zu frequentieren. Schwarze waren nach dem
zufall beendete ganz Übersouthhampton Grafschaft; viele wurden 
und ihre Köpfe nach links entlang den Straßen enthauptet, um andere 
zu warnen. Unmittelbar nach Aufstieg zogen die Pflanzer ihren 
Griff auf Sklaven und Sklaverei fest. Dieses woodcut wurde in 
einem Konto 1831 des Sklavenaufstiegs veröffentlicht.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1831 Nat nommé slave Turner a mené une 
rébellion dans le comté de Southhampton, la Virginie. Un 
ministre religieux d'amorce et de baptiste de art de l'auto-portrait-styled, 
Turner et un groupe de palpeurs ont détruit environ soixante 
hommes, femmes, et enfants blancs la nuit août de 21. 
Turner et 16 de ses conspirateurs ont été capturés et 
exécutés, mais l'incident a continué à hanter des blancs 
méridionaux. Les noirs étaient aléatoirement partout comté 
détruit de Southhampton ; beaucoup ont été décapités et 
leurs têtes à gauche le long des routes pour avertir d'autres. 
À la suite du soulèvement les planteurs ont serré leur 
poignée sur des esclaves et l'esclavage. Cette gravure sur bois a 
été éditée dans un compte 1831 du soulèvement slave.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1831 um escravo nomeado Nat Turner conduziu a uma 
rebelião no condado de Southhampton, Virgínia. Um líder 
religioso e um ministro self-styled do baptist, um Turner e um grupo 
dos seguidores mataram uns sessenta homens, mulheres, e crianças 
brancos na noite agosto de 21. Turner e 16 de seus conspirators 
foram capturados e executados, mas o incident continuou a assombrar 
brancos do sul. Os pretos eram aleatòria condado toda excedente
matado de Southhampton; muitos beheaded e suas cabeças à 
esquerda ao longo das estradas para advertir outras. Na vigília
do uprising os plantadores apertaram seu aperto em escravos e em 
slavery. Este woodcut foi publicado em um cliente 1831 do 
uprising slave.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1831 uno schiavo chiamato Nat Turner ha condotto una 
ribellione nella contea di Southhampton, la Virginia. Un 
capo religioso e un ministro Battista self-styled, un 
Turner e un gruppo dei seguicamme hanno ucciso circa sessanta uomini, 
donne e bambini bianchi sulla notte del 21 agosto. Turner e 16 
dei suoi conspirators sono stati bloccati ed eseguito stati, ma 
l'avvenimento ha continuato a frequentare i bianchi del sud. I 
neri erano a caso dappertutto contea uccisa di Southhampton; 
molti sono stati decapitati e le loro teste a sinistra lungo le 
strade per avvertire altre. Come conseguenza della rivolta 
le piantatrici hanno stretto la loro presa sugli schiavi e sullo 
slavery. Questo woodcut è stato pubblicato in un cliente 1831 
della rivolta slave.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1831 ένας σκλάβος που ονομάστηκε τον εθνικό 
τορναδόρο οδήγησε μια εξέγερση Southhampton στο νομό, 
Βιρτζίνια. Ένας θρησκευτικός ηγέτης και ένας 
μόνος-ορισμένος βαπτιστικός υπουργός, ένας τορναδόρος και μια 
ομάδα οπαδών σκότωσαν περίπου εξήντα λευκούς άνδρες, γυναίκες,
και τα παιδιά στη νύχτα τις 21, τορναδόρος και 16 Αυγούστου 
των συνωμοτών του συλλήφθηκαν και εκτελέσθηκαν, αλλά το γεγονός 
συνέχισε να συχνάζει τα νότια λευκά. Οι Μαύροι σκοτώθηκαν 
τυχαία σε όλο το νομό Southhampton  πολλοί αποκεφαθηκαν 
και τα κεφάλια τους αημένος κατά μήκος των δρόμων για να 
προειδοποιήσουν άλλους. Αμέσως μετά την έγερση οι 
καλλιεργητές έσφιγξαν το πιάσιμό τους στους σκλάβους και τη 
σκλαβιά. Αυτή η ξυλογραφία δημοσιεύθηκε σε έναν απολογισμό
1831 της έγερσης σκλάβων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1831 un esclavo nombrado Nat Turner condujo una 
rebelión en el condado de Southhampton, Virginia. Un arranque 
de cinta religioso y un ministro self-styled del Bautista, un Turner y
un grupo de seguidores mataron a unos sesenta hombres, mujeres, y 
niños blancos en la noche del de agosto 21. Capturaron y fueron
ejecutados a Turner y 16 de sus conspirators, pero el incidente 
continuó frecuentando blancos meridionales. Los negros eran 
aleatoriamente condado todo excesivo matado de Southhampton; 
muchos fueron decapitados y sus cabezas a la izquierda a lo 
largo de los caminos para advertir otros. En la estela de la 
sublevación los plantadores apretaron su apretón en esclavos y 
esclavitud. Este woodcut fue publicado en una cuenta 1831 de la 
sublevación auxiliar.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086997</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106653</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-nat-turner-rebellion</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
