<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105100</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105100</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086261</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Human Agency, Social Action and Classroom Practices: What happens when teachers move over to allow students to pave their own path towards enacting change?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschliche Agentur, Sozialtätigkeit und 
Klassenzimmer-Praxis: Was geschieht, wenn Lehrer rüber 
umziehen, um Kursteilnehmern zu erlauben, ihren eigenen Pfad in 
Richtung zum Verordnen der Änderung zu pflastern?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Agence humaine, action sociale et pratiques en 
matière de salle de classe : Que se produit quand les 
professeurs se déplacent plus de pour permettre à des étudiants de 
paver leur propre voie d'accès vers décréter le changement ?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Agência humana, ação social e práticas da sala
de aula: Que acontece quando os professores se movem sobre para 
permitir que os estudantes pavimentem seu próprio trajeto para 
decretar a mudança?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Agenzia umana, azione sociale e pratiche 
dell'aula: Che cosa accade quando gli insegnanti si muovono 
sopra per permettere che gli allievi pavimentino il loro proprio 
percorso verso la promulgazione del cambiamento?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρώπινη αντιπροσωπεία, κοινωνικές ενέργεια και 
πρακτικές τάξεων: Αυτό που συμβαίνει πότε οι δάσκαλοι 
κινούνται για να επιτρέψουν στους σπουδαστές για να στρώσουν το 
μονοπάτι τους προς τη θέσπιση της αλλαγής;</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Agencia humana, acción social y prácticas de la 
sala de clase: ¿Qué sucede cuando los profesores se mueven 
encima para permitir que los estudiantes pavimenten su propio camino 
hacia decretar el cambio?</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Vanessa Brown's work focuses on the students and classroom practices of her ninth grade English/Language Arts classes. It grew out of the tensions that arose when her beliefs about the juxtaposition of social action and classroom practices collided with the realities of socio-economic status, personal agency, social and emotional stability and student choice and voice. Through the stories of three urban high school youth who actually represent hundreds of others with similar stories, she contributes to and challenges the discourse regarding critical pedagogy in urban education. Her video interlaces both music and photos to represent the dual nature of the students' lives, which is both static and shifting.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Arbeit des Vanessa Brauns konzentriert auf die 
Kursteilnehmer- und Klassenzimmerpraxis ihrer 9. Grad English/Language
kunstkategorien. Sie wuchs aus den Spannkräften heraus, die 
entstanden, als ihr Glaube über die Nebeneinanderstellung der 
Sozialtätigkeit und Klassenzimmerpraxis mit den Wirklichkeiten des 
sozioökonomischen Status, der persönlichen Agentur, der Sozial- und 
emotionalen Stabilität und der Kursteilnehmerwahl und der -stimme 
zusammenstieß. Durch die Geschichten der städtischen High 
School drei Jugend, die wirklich Hunderte von anderen mit ähnlichen 
Geschichten darstellen, trägt sie zu bei und fordert die Darlegung 
betreffend ist kritisches pedagogy in der städtischen Ausbildung 
heraus. Ihr Bildschirm verschachtelt Musik und Fotos, um den 
Doppelsinn der Lebensdauern der Kursteilnehmer darzustellen, der 
statisch und Verschieben ist.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le travail du brun de Vanessa se concentre sur les 
pratiques en matière d'étudiants et de salle de classe de ses 
neuvième classes d'arts de la catégorie English/Language. Il 
s'est développé hors des tensions qui ont surgi quand sa croyance au
sujet de la juxtaposition des pratiques en matière sociales d'action 
et de salle de classe s'est heurtée les réalités du mode 
socio-économique, l'agence personnelle, la stabilité et le choix 
social et émotif et la voix d'étudiant. Par les histoires de 
la jeunesse urbaine du lycée trois qui représentent réellement des 
centaines de d'autres avec les histoires semblables, elle contribue à
et défie le discours concernant la pédagogie critique dans 
l'éducation urbaine. Son vidéo entrelace la musique et les 
photos pour représenter la nature duelle des vies des étudiants, qui
est statique et décalage.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O trabalho do marrom de Vanessa focaliza nas práticas dos
estudantes e da sala de aula de suas nonas classes de artes da classe 
English/Language. Cresceu fora das tensões que se levantaram 
quando sua opinião sobre a justaposição de práticas sociais da 
ação e da sala de aula colidiu com as realidades do status 
socio-economic, agência pessoal, estabilidade e escolha social e 
emocional e voz do estudante. Com as histórias da juventude 
urbana da High School três que representam realmente centenas de 
outras com as histórias similares, contribui a e desafia o discurso a
respeito do pedagogy crítico na instrução urbana. Seu vídeo 
entrelaça  a música e as fotos para representar a natureza dupla das
vidas dos estudantes, que é  de estática e deslocar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il lavoro del colore marrone di Vanessa mette a fuoco 
sulle pratiche dell'aula e degli allievi dei suoi noni codici 
categoria di arti del grado English/Language. Si è sviluppato 
dai tensionamenti che hanno presentato quando la sua credenza circa la
giustapposizione delle pratiche sociali dell'aula e di azione si è 
scontrata con le realtà di condizione socio-economica, agenzia 
personale, stabilità e scelta sociale ed impressionabile e voce 
dell'allievo. Con le storia della gioventù urbana della High 
School tre che realmente rappresentano le centinaia di altre con le 
storia simili, contribuisce a e sfida il discorso per quanto riguarda 
il pedagogy critico nella formazione urbana. Il suo video 
intreccia sia la musica che le foto per rappresentare la natura doppia
delle vite degli allievi, che è sia statica che spostare.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η εργασία της Vanessa Brown's εστιάζει στους 
σπουδαστές και τις πρακτικές τάξεων της ένατης τάξης της 
αγγλικά/των κλάσεων γλωσσικών τεχνών. Αυξήθηκε από τις 
εντάσεις που προέκυψαν όταν συγκρούστηκαν οι πεποιθήσεις της για 
την αντιπαράθεση των κοινωνικών πρακτικών ενέργειας και τάξεων με
τις πραγματικότητες της κοινωνικοοικονομικής θέσης, της προσωπικής
αντιπροσωπείας, της κοινωνικής και συναισθηματικής σταθερότητας 
και της επιλογής και της φωνής σπουδαστών. Μέσω των 
ιστοριών της αστικής νεολαίας γυμνασίου τρία που αντιπροσωπεύουν
πραγματικά τις εκατοντάδες άλλες με τις παρόμοιες ιστορίες, 
συμβάλλει και προκαλεί την ομιλία σχετικά με την κρίσιμη 
παιδαγωγική στην αστική εκπαίδευση. Το βίντεό της 
συμπλέκει και τη μουσική και τις φωτογραφίες για να 
αντιπροσωπεύσει τη διπλή φύση των ζωών των σπουδαστών, η οποία 
είναι και στατική και μετατοπιζόμενη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El trabajo del marrón de Vanessa se centra en las 
prácticas de los estudiantes y de la sala de clase de sus novenas 
clases de artes del grado English/Language. Creció fuera de las
tensiones que se presentaron cuando su creencia sobre la 
yuxtaposición de las prácticas sociales de la acción y de la sala 
de clase chocó con las realidades del estatus socioeconómico, 
agencia personal, estabilidad y opción social y emocional y voz del 
estudiante. Con las historias de la juventud urbana de la High 
School secundaria tres que representan realmente centenares de otros 
con historias similares, ella contribuye a y desafía el discurso con 
respecto a pedagogy crítico en la educación urbana. Su vídeo 
entrelaza música y las fotos para representar la naturaleza dual de 
las vidas de los estudiantes, que es estática y el cambiar de puesto.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:VANESSA BROWN
FN:VANESSA BROWN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086261</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105100</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/human-agency-social-action-and-classroom-practices-what-happens-when-teachers-move-over-to-allow-students-to-pave-their-own-path-towards-enacting-change-1</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
