<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105228</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105228</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086315</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"If You Believe the Negro Has a Soul": "Back to Africa" with Marcus Garvey</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"wenn Sie glauben, hat der Schwarze eine Seele": 
"zurück zu Afrika" mit Marcus Garvey</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"si vous croyez le nègre a une âme" : "de 
nouveau à l'Afrique" avec Marcus Garvey</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"se você acredita o negro tem uma alma": 
"traseiro a África" com Marcus Garvey</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"se credete il negro ha un'anima": "di nuovo 
all'Africa" con Marcus Garvey</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Εάν θεωρείτε ο νέγρος έχει μια ψυχή": "Πίσω 
στην Αφρική" με το Marcus Garvey</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"si usted cree el negro tiene un alma": "de 
nuevo a África" con Marcus Garvey</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Black Nationalist Marcus Garvey recognized that his Universal Negro Improvement Association (UNIA) would find its most enthusiastic audience in the United States, despite the organization's professed worldwide mission. After fighting World War I, ostensibly to defend democracy and self-determination, thousands of African-American soldiers returned home to find intensified discrimination, segregation, racial violence, and hostile relations with white Americans. Sensing growing frustration, Garvey used his considerable charisma to attract thousands of disillusioned black working-class and lower middle-class followers and became the most popular black leader in America in the early 1920s. The UNIA, committed to notions of racial purity and separatism, insisted that salvation for African Americans meant building an autonomous, black-led nation in Africa. To this end, the movement offered in its "Back to Africa" campaign a powerful message of black pride and economic self-sufficiency. In Garvey's 1921 speech, "If You Believe the Negro Has a Soul," he emphasized the inevitability of racial antagonism and the hopelessness of interracial coexistence.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Schwarzes nationalistisches Marcus Garvey erkannte,
daß seine Universalschwarze-Verbesserung Verbindung (UNIA) seine 
enthusiastischsten Publikum in den Vereinigten Staaten finden würde, 
trotz der erklärten weltweiten Mission der Organisation. 
Nachdem sie den Ersten Weltkrieg, um gekämpft hatten Demokratie
und Self-determination anscheinend zu verteidigen, kamen Tausenden der
Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Soldaten nach Hause zurück, um verstärkte
Unterscheidung, Abtrennung, rassische Gewalttätigkeit und feindliche 
Relationen mit weißen Amerikanern zu finden. Wachsende 
Frustration erfassend, verwendete Garvey sein beträchtliches 
Charisma, um Tausenden der ernüchterten schwarzen Arbeiterklasse und 
der untereren Mittelklassenachfolger anzuziehen und stand dem 
populärsten schwarzen Führer in Amerika in den frühen zwanziger 
Jahren. Das UNIA, festgelegt an den Begriffen der rassischen 
Reinheit und des Separatismus, beharrte, daß Rettung für 
afrikanische Amerikaner das Aufbauen einer autonomen bedeutete, 
schwarz-führenden Nation in Afrika. Zu diesem Zweck bot die 
Bewegung in seiner "zurück zu Afrika" Kampagne eine leistungsfähige 
Meldung des schwarzen Stolzes und der ökonomischen Selbstüberhebung 
an. In Garveys Rede 1921 ", wenn Sie glauben, daß der Schwarze 
eine Seele hat," hob er die Unvermeidlichkeit des rassischen 
Antagonismus und die Hoffnungslosigkeit der interracial Koexistenz 
hervor.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Marcus nationaliste noir Garvey a identifié que 
son association universelle d'amélioration de nègre (UNIA) 
trouverait ses assistances plus enthousiastes aux Etats-Unis, en 
dépit de la mission mondiale professée de l'organisation. 
Après le combat de la Première Guerre Mondiale, pour défendre
en apparence la démocratie et le art de l'auto-portrait-determination, les milliers
de soldats afro-américains sont retournés à la maison pour trouver la 
discrimination intensifiée, la ségrégation, la violence raciale, et
les relations hostiles avec les Américains blancs. Sentant 
l'anéantissement croissant, Garvey a employé son charisme 
considérable pour attirer des milliers de classe ouvrier noir 
désillusionné et de sectateurs inférieurs de classe moyen et est 
allé bien à l'amorce noire la plus populaire en Amérique au début 
des années 20. L'UNIA, commis aux notions de la pureté et du 
séparatisme raciaux, a insisté sur le fait que le salut pour les 
Américains africains a signifié établir une nation autonome et 
noir-menée en Afrique. À cet effet, le mouvement a offert dans
sa campagne "de nouveau à Afrique" un message puissant de fierté 
noire et de art de l'auto-portrait-sufficiency économique. Dans la parole 
1921 de Garvey, "si vous croyez que le nègre a une âme," il a 
souligné l'inévitabilité de l'antagonisme racial et le désespoir 
de la coexistence interracial.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Marcus nacionalista preto Garvey reconheceu que sua
associação universal da melhoria do negro (UNIA) encontraria suas 
audiências mais entusiásticas nos estados unidos, apesar da missão 
worldwide professada da organização. Após ter lutado o 
world.war.i, para defender ostensibly a democracia e o 
self-determination, os milhares de soldados Africano-Americanos 
retornaram para casa para encontrar a discriminação intensified, o 
segregation, a violência racial, e relações hostis com americanos 
brancos. Detetando a frustração crescente, Garvey usou seu 
charisma considerável atrair milhares do working-class preto 
disillusioned e de uns seguidores mais baixos do middle-class e 
assentou bem no líder preto o mais popular em América nos 1920s 
adiantados. O UNIA, cometido às noções do purity e do 
separatism raciais, insistiu que o salvation para americanos africanos
significou construir uma nação autônoma, preto-conduzida em 
África. A esta extremidade, o movimento ofereceu em sua 
"traseiro campanha de África" uma mensagem poderosa do orgulho preto 
e do self-sufficiency econômico. No discurso 1921 de Garvey, 
"se você acreditasse que o negro tem uma alma," emfatizou o 
inevitability do antagonism racial e o hopelessness do coexistence 
interracial.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Marcus nazionalista nero Garvey ha riconosciuto che
il suo negro universale associazione di miglioramento che (UNIA) 
troverebbe i relativi pubblici più entusiastici in unito 
Dichiara, malgrado la missione in tutto il mondo professata 
dell'organizzazione. Dopo il world.war.i di combattimento, 
difendere apparentemente la democrazia ed il self-determination, i 
migliaia dei soldati Africano-Americani hanno ritornato a casa per 
trovare la distinzione intensificata, la segregazione, la violenza 
razziale ed i rapporti ostili con gli Americani bianchi. 
Percependo la frustrazione crescente, Garvey ha usato il suo 
charisma considerevole per attrarre i migliaia della classe operaia 
nera disillusa e dei seguicamme più bassi della classe media ed ha 
stato bene al capo nero più popolare in America nell'inizio 
degli anni 20. Il UNIA, impegnato nelle nozioni della purezza e 
del separatism razziali, ha insistito che la salvezza per gli 
Americani africani ha significato lo sviluppo della nazione autonoma e
nero-condotta in Africa. A questo scopo, il movimento ha offerto
nella relativa "di nuovo campagna all'Africa" un messaggio potente di 
orgoglio nero e di autosufficienza economica. Nel discorso 1921 
del Garvey, "se credete che il negro abbia un'anima," ha dato risalto 
all'inevitabilità dell'antagonismo razziale ed al hopelessness della 
coesistenza interracial.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο μαύρος εθνικιστικός Marcus Garvey αναγνώρισε 
ότι η καθολική ένωση βελτίωσης νέγρων του (UNIA) θα έβρισκε 
της το πιό ενθουσιώδητο ακροατήριο στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες, παρά
τη φανερή παγκόσμια αποστολή της οργάνωσης. Μετά από να 
διεξαγάγουν τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι, για να υπερασπίσουν 
φαινομενικά τη δημοκρατία και την αυτοδιάθεση, χιλιάδες 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικοί στρατιώτες επέστρεψαν το σπίτι για να 
βρούν την ενταμένη διάκριση, το διαχωρισμό, τη φυλετική βία, και
τις εχθρικές σχέσεις με λευκούς Αμερικανούς. Η αισθαμένος 
αυξανόμενη απογοήτευση, Garvey χρησιμοποίησε το ιδιαίτερο 
χάρισμά του για να προσελκύσει χιλιάδες απογοητευμένη μαύρη 
εργατική τάξη και χαμηλότεροι οπαδοί μεσαίων τάξεων και έγινε ο
δημοφιλέστερος μαύρος ηγέτης στην Αμερική στις αρχές της 
δεκαετίας του '20. Το UNIA, δεσμευμένο στις έννοιες της 
φυλετικών αγνότητας και του αυτονομισμού, επέμεινε ότι η σωτηρία
για αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς σήμανε ένα αυτόνομο, 
μαύρος-οδηγημένο έθνος στην Αφρική. Για αυτόν τον λόγο, η 
μετακίνηση πρόσφερε στην εκστρατεία "πίσω της Αφρικής τησ" ένα 
ισχυρό μήνυμα της μαύρης υπερηφάνειας και της οικονομικής 
αυτάρκειας. Στην ομιλία του 1921 Garvey, "εάν θεωρείτε
ότι ο νέγρος έχει μια ψυχή," υπογράμμισε το αναπόφευκτο του 
φυλετικού ανταγωνισμού και την απόγνωση της διαφυλετικής 
συνύπαρξης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Marcus nacionalista negro Garvey reconoció que su 
asociación universal de la mejora del negro (UNIA) encontraría a sus
audiencias más entusiásticas de los Estados Unidos, a pesar de la 
misión mundial profesada de la organización. Después de 
luchar Primera Guerra Mundial, aparentemente para defender democracia y 
la autodeterminación, los millares de soldados Africano-Americanos 
volvieron a casa para encontrar la discriminación intensificada, la 
segregación, la violencia racial, y relaciones hostiles con los 
americanos blancos. Detectando la frustración cada vez mayor, 
Garvey utilizó su carisma considerable para atraer a millares de 
clase obrera negra desilusionada y de seguidores más bajos de la 
clase media y sintió bien al arranque de cinta negro más popular de 
América en los años 20 tempranos. El UNIA, confiado a las 
nociones de la pureza y del separatism raciales, insistió que la 
salvación para los americanos africanos significó la construcción 
de una nación autónoma, negro-conducida en África. Con este 
fin, el movimiento ofreció en su "de nuevo campaña de África" un 
mensaje de gran alcance del orgullo negro y de la autosuficiencia 
económica. En el discurso 1921 de Garvey, "si usted cree que el
negro tiene un alma," él acentuó la inevitabilidad del antagonismo 
racial y la desesperación de la coexistencia interracial.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086315</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105228</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/if-you-believe-the-negro-has-a-soul-back-to-africa-with-marcus-garvey</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
