<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107886</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107886</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202556</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Literature Biography Project</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Literatur-Biographie-Projekt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Projet de Biographie de Littérature</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Projeto Da Biografia Da Literatura</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Progetto Di Biografia Della Letteratura</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πρόγραμμα βιογραφιών λογοτεχνίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Proyecto De la Biografía De la Literatura</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">For this project, students will learn to develop the various processes used in researching and writing a biographical research paper, including brainstorming, notetaking, outlining, creating a bibliography, and writing the final draft. This project is designed to act as an independent study geared toward AG or Level 3 and Level 4 students, but each step in the research process can also be taught directly to students in the classroom.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Für dieses Projekt erlernen Kursteilnehmer, die 
verschiedenen Prozesse zu entwickeln, die wenn sie erforschen und 
schreiben ein biographisches Forschung Papier, einschließlich 
Geistesstörung verwendet werden und notetaking, umreißen, erstellen 
eine Bibliographie, und schreiben den abschließenden Entwurf. 
Dieses Projekt ist konzipiert, um als eine unabhängige Studie 
zu dienen, die in Richtung zu AG oder Stufe 3 und waagerecht 
ausgerichtete 4 Kursteilnehmer übersetzt wird, aber jeder Jobstep im 
Forschung Prozeß kann direkt auch unterrichtet werden den 
Kursteilnehmern im Klassenzimmer.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pour ce projet, les étudiants apprendront à 
développer les divers processus utilisés en recherchant et en 
écrivant un papier biographique de recherches, y compris la séance 
de réflexion, notetaking, traçant les grandes lignes, créant une 
bibliographie, et écrivant le projet définitif. Ce projet est 
conçu pour agir en tant qu'étude indépendante adaptée vers l'AG ou
le niveau 3 et les 4 étudiants de niveau, mais on peut également 
enseigner chaque étape dans le procédé de recherches directement 
aux étudiants dans la salle de classe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Para este projeto, os estudantes aprenderão 
desenvolver os vários processos usados em pesquisar e em escrever um 
papel de pesquisa biographical, including o brainstorming, notetaking,
esboçando, criando uma bibliografia, e escrevendo o esboço final. 
Este projeto é projetado agir como um estudo independente 
engrenado para o AG ou o nível 3 e 4 estudantes nivelados, mas cada 
etapa no processo da pesquisa pode também ser ensinada diretamente 
aos estudantes na sala de aula.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Per questo progetto, gli allievi impareranno 
sviluppare i vari processi usati nella ricerca e nella scrittura della
pubblicazione biographical, compreso "brainstorming", notetaking, 
descrivendo, creando una bibliografia e scrivendo la brutta copia 
definitiva. Questo progetto è destinato per fungere da studio 
indipendente innestato verso AG o Livello 3 e 4 allievi Livelli, ma 
ogni punto nel processo di ricerca può anche essere insegnato 
direttamente agli allievi nell'aula.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Για αυτό το πρόγραμμα, οι σπουδαστές θα μάθουν να 
αναπτύσσουν τις διάφορες διαδικασίες που χρησιμοποιούνται στην 
έρευνα και το γράψιμο μιας βιογραφικής ερευνητικής εργασίας, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένου του "brainstorming", notetaking, 
περιγράφοντας, δημιουργώντας μια βιβλιογραφία, και γράφοντας το 
τελικό σχέδιο. Αυτό το πρόγραμμα έχει ως σκοπό να 
ενεργήσει ως ανεξάρτητη μελέτη που συνδέεται προς τον άργυρο ή 
το επίπεδο 3 και το επίπεδο 4 τους σπουδαστές, αλλά κάθε βήμα 
στην ερευνητική διαδικασία μπορεί επίσης να διδαχθεί άμεσα στους
σπουδαστές στην τάξη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Para este proyecto, los estudiantes aprenderán 
desarrollar los varios procesos usados en investigar y escribir un 
papel de investigación biográfico, incluyendo la reunión de 
reflexión, notetaking, contorneando, creando una bibliografía, y 
escribiendo el bosquejo final. Este proyecto se diseña para 
actuar como estudio independiente engranado hacia el AG o el nivel 3 y 
los 4 estudiantes llanos, pero cada paso de progresión en el proceso 
de la investigación se puede también enseñar directamente a los 
estudiantes en la sala de clase.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:SANDRA DAIL
FN:SANDRA DAIL
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202556</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107886</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/literature-biography-project</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
