<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106649</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106649</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201236</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Designing an Earth System Course</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Konzipieren eines Masse System Kurses</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Concevoir un cours de système de la terre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Projetando um curso do sistema da terra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Progettazione del corso del sistema della terra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σχεδιασμός μιας σειράς μαθημάτων γήινων συστημάτων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Diseñar un curso del sistema de la tierra</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Starting Point module describes the process of putting together a course in Earth System Science course. Users will find information on what an ESS course is, why this approach is useful and how to actually create the class. This module supports faculty efforts to structure Earth system science education not only to the needs of geoscience majors, but a variety of different audiences, from non-science majors to pre-service teachers.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Ausgangspunktmodul beschreibt den Prozeß 
von einen Kurs in Masse System Wissenschaft Kurs zusammen einsetzen. 
Benutzer finden Informationen über, einen welchen ESS Kurs ist,
warum diese Annäherung nützlich ist und wie man wirklich die 
Kategorie erstellt. Dieses Modul unterstützt 
Lehrkörperbemühungen, Masse System Wissenschaft Ausbildung nicht nur
zu den Notwendigkeiten der geoscience Majoren zu strukturieren, aber 
eine Vielzahl der unterschiedlichen Publikum, von den 
Nichtwissenschaft Majoren Vorservice Lehrern.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce module de point de départ décrit le processus
de remonter un cours dans le cours de la Science de système de la 
terre. Les utilisateurs trouveront l'information sur quel cours 
d'ESS est, pourquoi cette approche est utile et comment créer 
réellement la classe. Ce module supporte des efforts de corps 
enseignant de structurer l'éducation de la science de système de la 
terre non seulement aux besoins des commandants de geoscience, mais 
une variété de différentes assistances, des professeurs de 
pré-service de commandants de la non-science.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este módulo do ponto começar descreve o processo
de unir um curso no curso da ciência do sistema da terra. Os 
usuários encontrarão a informação em que curso de ESS é, porque 
esta aproximação é útil e como criar realmente a classe. 
Este módulo suporta esforços da faculdade estruturar a 
instrução da ciência do sistema da terra não somente às 
necessidades de majores do geoscience, mas uma variedade de 
audiências diferentes, dos professores do pre-serviço dos majores da
non-ciência.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo modulo del punto di partenza descrive il 
processo di unire un corso nel corso di scienza del sistema della 
terra. Gli utenti troveranno le informazioni su ché corso di 
ESS è, perchè questo metodo è utile e come realmente creare il 
codice categoria. Questo modulo sostiene gli sforzi della 
facoltà strutturare la formazione di scienza del sistema della terra 
non soltanto ai bisogni dei maggiori di geoscience, ma una varietà di
pubblici differenti, dagli insegnanti di pre-servizio dei maggiori di 
non-scienza.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η ενότητα αφετηρίας περιγράφει τη διαδικασία 
μαζί μια σειρά μαθημάτων στη σειρά μαθημάτων επιστήμης γήινων 
συστημάτων. Οι χρήστες θα βρούν τις πληροφορίες για αυτό 
που μια σειρά μαθημάτων ESS είναι, γιατί αυτή η προσέγγιση 
είναι χρήσιμη και πώς να δημιουργήσει πραγματικά την κλάση. 
Αυτή η ενότητα υποστηρίζει τις προσπάθειες σχολής να 
κτίσει την εκπαίδευση επιστήμης γήινων συστημάτων όχι μόνο στις
ανάγκες των ταγματαρχών geoscience, αλλά ποικίλα διαφορετικά 
ακροατήρια, από τους ταγματάρχες μη-επιστήμης στους 
επαγγελματικούς δασκάλους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este módulo del punto de partida describe el 
proceso de juntar un curso en curso de la ciencia del sistema de la 
tierra. Los utilizadores encontrarán la información sobre es 
un qué curso de ESS, porqué este acercamiento es útil y cómo crear
realmente la clase. Este módulo utiliza esfuerzos de la 
facultad de estructurar la educación de la ciencia del sistema de la 
tierra no solamente a las necesidades de los comandantes del 
geoscience, pero una variedad de diversas audiencias, de profesores 
del pre-servicio de los comandantes de la no-ciencia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:RUSSANNE LOW
FN:RUSSANNE LOW
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201236</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106649</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/designing-an-earth-system-course</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
