<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107725</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107725</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200302</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A Moment of Silence: The Magnificent Pompeii Worm</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Moment der Ruhe: Die Ausgezeichnete 
Pompeji Endlosschraube</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un moment de silence : Le Ver Magnifique de 
Pompeii</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um momento do silêncio: O Sem-fim 
Magnífico De Pompeii</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un momento di silenzio: La Vite senza fine 
Magnifica De Pompeii</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια στιγμή της σιωπής: Το θαυμάσιο σκουλήκι της 
Πομπηίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un momento del silencio: El Gusano 
Magnífico De Pompeii</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This two-minute radio program from Indiana University discusses the magnificent Pompeii worm. The Pompeii worm resides in tubes near hydrothermal vents along the seafloor. While in the tube, the worm's tail end might be immersed in temperatures as hot as 178 degrees Fahrenheit, while its head rests in cooler water, as moderate as 72 degrees Fahrenheit. This web site features the script for the radio vignette and includes a link to hear the audio version.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Zweiminute Radioprogramm von der Indiana 
Universität behandelt die ausgezeichnete Pompeji Endlosschraube. 
Die Pompeji Endlosschraube befindet sich in den Gefäßen nahe 
hydrothermalen Entlüftungsöffnungen entlang dem seafloor. 
Während im Gefäß, konnte das Endstückende der Endlosschraube
in den Temperaturen untergetaucht werden, die wie 178 Grade Fahrenheit
So heiß sind, während sein Kopf im kühleren Wasser stillsteht, so 
gemäßigt wie 72 Grade Fahrenheit. Diese Web site kennzeichnet 
den Index für das Radiovignette und schließt ein Link ein, um die 
Audioversion zu hören.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce programme de radio de deux-minute d'université
de l'Indiana discute le ver magnifique de Pompeii. Le ver de 
Pompeii réside dans des tubes près des évents hydrothermiques le 
long du seafloor. Tandis que dans le tube, l'extrémité de la 
queue du ver pourrait être immergée dans les températures aussi 
chaudes que 178 degrés de Fahrenheit, alors que sa tête se repose 
dans l'eau plus fraîche, aussi modérée que 72 degrés de 
Fahrenheit. Ce site Web comporte la séquence type pour la 
vignette par radio et inclut un lien pour entendre la version 
sonore.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este programa do rádio de dois-minuto da 
universidade de Indiana discute o sem-fim magnífico de Pompeii. 
O sem-fim de Pompeii reside nos tubos perto dos respiradouros 
hydrothermal ao longo do seafloor. Quando no tubo, a extremidade
da cauda do sem-fim pôde immersed nas temperaturas tão quentes 
quanto 178 graus de Fahrenheit, quando sua cabeça descansar em uma 
água mais fresca, tão moderada quanto 72 graus de Fahrenheit. 
Este Web site caracteriza o certificado para o vignette de 
rádio e inclui uma ligação para ouvir a versão audio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo programma della radio di due-minuto 
dall'università dell'Indiana discute la vite senza fine magnifica de 
Pompeii. La vite senza fine de Pompeii risiede in tubi vicino 
agli sfiati idrotermali lungo il seafloor. Mentre nel tubo, 
l'estremità della coda della vite senza fine potrebbe essere immersa 
nelle temperature calde quanto 178 gradi di Fahrenheit, mentre la 
relativa testa si riposa in acqua più fredda, moderata quanto 72 
gradi di Fahrenheit. Questo Web site caratterizza lo scritto per
il vignette radiofonico ed include un collegamento per sentire la 
versione audio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το δύο-μικρό ραδιο πρόγραμμα από το 
πανεπιστήμιο του Ινδιάνα συζητά το θαυμάσιο σκουλήκι της 
Πομπηίας. Το σκουλήκι της Πομπηίας κατοικεί στους σωλήνες 
κοντά στις υδροθερμικές διεξόδους κατά μήκος του θαλάσσιου 
πυθμένα. Ενώ στο σωλήνα, το τέλος ουρών του σκουληκιού να 
βυθιστεί στις θερμοκρασίες τόσο καυτές όπως 178 βαθμούς 
fahrenheit, ενώ το κεφάλι του στηρίζεται στο πιό δροσερό 
ύδωρ, τόσο μέτριο όπως 72 βαθμούς fahrenheit. Αυτός 
ο ιστοχώρος χαρακτηρίζει το αρχείο εντολών για το ραδιο σύντομο 
χρονογράφημα και περιλαμβάνει μια σύνδεση για να ακούσει την 
ηχητική έκδοση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este programa de la radio del dos-minuto de la 
universidad de Indiana discute el gusano magnífico de Pompeii. 
El gusano de Pompeii reside en tubos cerca de respiraderos 
hidrotérmicos a lo largo del seafloor. Mientras que en el tubo,
el extremo de la cola del gusano se pudo sumergir en las temperaturas 
tan calientes como 178 grados de Fahrenheit, mientras que su cabeza se
reclina en un agua más fresca, tan moderada como 72 grados de 
Fahrenheit. Este Web site ofrece la escritura para el vignette 
de radio e incluye una conexión para oír la versión audio.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:A MOMENT OF SCIENCE
FN:A MOMENT OF SCIENCE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:INDIANA UNIVERSITY
FN:INDIANA UNIVERSITY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200302</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107725</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/a-moment-of-silence-the-magnificent-pompeii-worm</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
