<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104723</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104723</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086344</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"It Couldn't Go On Like This:" Jim Vacarella Describes Events Leading Up to the Kent State Shootings</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Sie Könnte Nicht So Weitergehen:" Jim 
Vacarella beschreibt die Fälle, die bis zum Kent Zustand Shootings 
führen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Elle Ne pourrait pas Continuer Comme Ceci :" 
Jim Vacarella décrit des événements amenant à l'état 
Shootings de Kent</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Não poderia Ir Sobre Como Esta:" Jim 
Vacarella descreve os eventos que conduzem ao estado Shootings de 
Kent</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Non potrebbe Accendere Come Questa:" Jim 
Vacarella descrive gli eventi che portano alla Risonanza 
Dichiara Shootings</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Δεν θα μπορούσε να συνεχιστεί όπως αυτό:" Jim Vacarella Describes Events που καταλήγει στους 
κρατικούς πυροβολισμούς του Κεντ</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"No podría Continuar Como Esto:" Jim 
Vacarella describe los acontecimientos que conducen al estado 
Shootings de Kent</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Jim Vacarella was a student at Kent State University when the National Guard arrived on campus in 1970. Like hundreds of other campuses across the country, Kent State witnessed an upsurge in student activism following the American invasion of Cambodia in 1970. The Guardsmen arrived when students burned down the Reserve Officers Training Corps (ROTC) building, and Vacarella remembered that their arrival was met with hostility _ along with thrown rocks and bottles _ from angered students. Two days later, four students were killed when Guardsmen opened fire during an anti-war demonstration.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Jim Vacarella war ein Kursteilnehmer an der Kent 
Landesuniversität, als der nationale Schutz auf Campus 1970 ankam. 
Wie Hunderte anderer Campus über dem Land, zeugte Kent Zustand 
eine Aufwallung im Kursteilnehmeraktivismus, welche der amerikanischen
Invasion von Kambodscha 1970 folgt. Die Wachposten kamen an, als
Kursteilnehmer hinunter das Gebäude des Reserve-Offizier-Training 
Korps (ROTC) brannten, und Vacarella erinnerte daran, daß ihre 
Ankunft Feindseligkeit _ zusammen mit geworfenen Felsen und Flaschen _
von verärgerten Kursteilnehmern getroffen wurde. Zwei Tage 
später, wurden vier Kursteilnehmer beendet, als Wachposten Feuer 
während einer Antikriegsdemonstration öffneten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jim Vacarella était un étudiant à l'université
de l'Etat de Kent quand la garde nationale est arrivée sur le campus 
en 1970. Comme des centaines de d'autres campus à travers le 
pays, l'état de Kent était témoin d'une croissance dans l'activisme
d'étudiant suivant l'invasion américaine du Cambodge en 1970. 
Les gardes sont arrivés quand les étudiants ont brûlé en bas
du bâtiment des corps de formation d'officiers de réserve (ROTC), et
Vacarella s'est rappelé que leur arrivée a été rencontrée 
l'hostilité _ le long avec les roches et les bouteilles jetées _ des
étudiants irrités. Deux jours plus tard, quatre étudiants ont
été détruits quand les gardes ont ouvert le feu pendant une 
démonstration pacifiste.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jim Vacarella era um estudante na universidade de 
estado de Kent quando o protetor nacional chegou no campus em 1970. 
Como centenas de outros campuses através do país, o estado de 
Kent testemunhou um upsurge no activism do estudante que segue a 
invasão americana de Cambodia em 1970. Os guardsmen chegaram 
quando os estudantes se queimaram abaixo o edifício do corpo de 
treinamento de oficiais de reserva (ROTC), e Vacarella recordou que 
sua chegada estêve encontrada com com hostilidade _ junto com rochas 
e frascos jogados _ dos estudantes irritados. Dois dias mais 
tarde, quatro estudantes foram matados quando os guardsmen abriram o 
fogo durante uma demonstração anti-war.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Jim Vacarella era un allievo a Risonanza 
Dichiara l'università quando la protezione nazionale è 
arrivato sulla città universitaria in 1970. Come le centinaia 
di altre città universitarie attraverso il paese, Risonanza 
Dichiara ha testimoniato un aumento nel activism dell'allievo 
che segue l'invasione americana della Cambogia in 1970. I 
guardsmen sono arrivato quando gli allievi si sono bruciati giù gli 
ufficiali della riserva che addestrano il Corpo (ROTC) che 
costruisce e Vacarella si è ricordato di che il loro arrivo è stato 
incontrato ostilità _ con le roccie e le bottiglie gettate _ dagli 
allievi fatti arrabbiare. Due giorni più successivamente, 
quattro allievi sono stati uccisi quando i guardsmen hanno aperto il 
fuoco durante la dimostrazione pacifista.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Jim Vacarella ήταν σπουδαστής στο κρατικό 
πανεπιστήμιο του Κεντ όταν έφθασε η εθνική φρουρά στην 
πανεπιστημιούπολη το 1970. Όπως τις εκατοντάδες άλλων 
πανεπιστημιουπόλεων σε ολόκληρη τη χώρα, το κράτος του Κεντ 
βεβαίωσε μια άνοδο στον ακτιβισμό σπουδαστών μετά από την 
αμερικανική εισβολή της Καμπότζης το 1970. Οι φύλακες 
έφθασαν όταν θυμήθηκαν οι σπουδαστές που καηκαν κάτω από τους 
ανώτερους υπαλλήλους επιφύλαξης που εκπαιδεύουν Σώμα 
(ROTC) να χτίσουν, και Vacarella ότι η άφιξή τους 
συναντήθηκε με την εχθρότητα _ μαζί με τους ριγμένους βράχους και
τα μπουκάλια _ από τους θυμωμένους σπουδαστές. Δύο ημέρες 
αργότερα, τέσσερις σπουδαστές σκοτώθηκαν όταν άνοιξαν οι 
φύλακες την πυρκαγιά κατά τη διάρκεια μιας αντιπολεμικής 
επίδειξης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Jim Vacarella era un estudiante en la universidad 
de estado de Kent cuando el protector nacional llegó en campus en 
1970. Como centenares de otros campus a través del país, el 
estado de Kent atestiguó un aumento en el activismo del estudiante 
que seguía la invasión americana de Camboya en 1970. Los 
guardsmen llegaron cuando los estudiantes se quemaron abajo del 
edificio del cuerpo de entrenamiento de oficiales de reserva (ROTC), y
Vacarella recordó que su llegada fue resuelta con hostilidad _ junto 
con rocas y botellas lanzadas _ de estudiantes encolerizados. 
Dos días más adelante, mataron a cuatro estudiantes cuando los
guardsmen abrieron el fuego durante una demostración pacifista.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086344</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104723</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/it-couldnt-go-on-like-this-jim-vacarella-describes-events-leading-up-to-the-kent-state-shootings</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
