<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107057</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107057</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212058</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Sea Vent Viewer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Seeentlüftungsöffnung Projektor</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Visualisateur D'Évent de Mer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Visor Do Respiradouro Do Mar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Visore Dello Sfiato Del Mare</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εμφάνιση διεξόδων θάλασσας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Espectador Del Respiradero Del Mar</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This web site serves as an educational overview of National Science Foundation (NSF) earth and environmental science research focusing on hydrothermal vent systems. It features an interactive viewer which allows users to explore hydrothermal vent systems with the touch of a mouse. Dragging the cursor around the screen moves the field of view while clicking on numbered items reveals informational pages about each inhabitant.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Web site dient als pädagogischer Überblick
über die Masse des National Science Foundation (NSF) und 
Klimawissenschaft Forschung, die auf hydrothermale Entlüftungssysteme
konzentrieren. Sie kennzeichnet einen interaktiven Projektor, 
der Benutzern erlaubt, hydrothermale Entlüftungssysteme mit der Note 
einer Maus zu erforschen. Das Schleppen des Cursors um den 
Bildschirm verschiebt auffangene der Ansicht, während das Klicken 
auf numerierten Einzelteilen informatorische Seiten über jeden 
Einwohner aufdeckt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site Web sert de vue d'ensemble éducative de 
la terre du National Science Foundation (NSF) et de la recherche 
environnementale de la science se concentrant sur les circuits de mise
à l'air libre hydrothermiques. Il comporte un visualisateur 
interactif qui permet à des utilisateurs d'explorer les circuits de 
mise à l'air libre hydrothermiques avec le contact d'une souris. 
Traîner le curseur autour de l'écran déplace le champ visuel 
tandis que cliquer sur les éléments numérotés indique 
les pages informationnelles au sujet de chaque habitant.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Web site serve como uma vista geral 
educacional da terra do National Science Foundation (NSF) e da 
pesquisa ambiental da ciência que focalizam em sistemas de 
respiradouro hydrothermal. Caracteriza um visor interativo que 
permita que os usuários explorem sistemas de respiradouro 
hydrothermal com o toque de um rato. Arrastar o cursor em torno 
da tela move o campo de vista quando estalar em artigos numerados 
revelar páginas informativas sobre cada habitante.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Web site serve da descrizione educativa 
della terra di National Science Foundation (NSF) e della ricerca 
ambientale di scienza che mettono a fuoco sui sistemi di sfiato 
idrotermali. Caratterizza un visore interattivo che permette che
gli utenti esplorino i sistemi di sfiato idrotermali con il tocco di 
mouse. Trascinare il cursore intorno allo schermo sposta il 
campo di visibilità mentre scattarsi sugli articoli numerati rivela 
le pagine informative circa ogni abitante.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος χρησιμεύει ως μια εκπαιδευτική 
επισκόπηση της εθνικής γης ιδρύματος επιστήμης (NSF) και της 
περιβαλλοντικής έρευνας επιστήμης που εστιάζουν στα συστήματα 
υδροθερμικών διεξόδων. Χαρακτηρίζει μια διαλογική εμφάνιση 
που επιτρέπει στους χρήστες για να ερευνήσει τα συστήματα 
υδροθερμικών διεξόδων με την αφή ενός ποντικιού. Το 
σύρσιμο του δρομέα γύρω από την οθόνη κινεί το οπτικό πεδίο 
χτυπώντας στα αριθμημένα αντικείμενα αποκαλύπτει ενημερωτικές 
σελίδες για κάθε κάτοικο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este Web site sirve como descripción educativa de
la tierra del National Science Foundation (NSF) y de la investigación
ambiental de la ciencia que se centran en sistemas de respiradero 
hidrotérmicos. Ofrece un espectador interactivo que permita que
los utilizadores exploren sistemas de respiradero hidrotérmicos con 
el tacto de un ratón. La fricción del cursor alrededor de la 
pantalla mueve el campo visual mientras que el hacer clic en items 
numerados revela las paginaciones informativas sobre cada habitante.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:NATIONAL SCIENCE FOUNDATION
FN:NATIONAL SCIENCE FOUNDATION
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212058</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107057</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/sea-vent-viewer</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
