<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104559</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104559</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205304</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Representing History: Cambodia - Through the Shadows</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Darstellen Von von Geschichte: Kambodscha - 
durch die Schatten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Représentation de l'Histoire : Le Cambodge 
- par les ombres</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Representando O History: Cambodia - através
das sombras</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Rappresentare Storia: La Cambogia - 
attraverso le ombre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αντιπροσώπευση της ιστορίας: Καμπότζη - μέσω των
σκιών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Representación De Historia: Camboya - a 
través de las sombras</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This unit introduces students to the modern history of Cambodia in the context of the Cold War. It examines the relationship between Cambodia and Vietnam and the way both countries became drawn into the power struggle between the US and Western capitalism and the Sino Soviet communist axis in the east. Through viewing and discussion of the video and investigating the web resources, students can begin to understand the conventions of documentary in offering access to a version of the truth.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Maßeinheit stellt Kursteilnehmer zur 
modernen Geschichte von Kambodscha im Kontext des kalten Krieges vor. 
Sie überprüft das Verhältnis zwischen Kambodscha und Vietnam 
und die Methode beide Länder wurden in den Energie Kampf zwischen den
US und dem westlichen Kapitalismus und der Sino sowjetischen 
kommunistischen Mittellinie im Osten gezogen. Durch Betrachtung 
und Diskussion über den Bildschirm und das Nachforschen der 
Web-Betriebsmittel, können Kursteilnehmer anfangen, die 
Vereinbarungen des Dokumentarfilms in anbietenzugriff zu einer Version
der Wahrheit zu verstehen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette unité présente des étudiants à 
l'histoire moderne du Cambodge dans le contexte de la guerre froide. 
Elle examine le rapport entre le Cambodge et le Vietnam et la 
voie les deux pays sont devenus tirés dans la lutte de puissance 
entre les USA et le capitalisme occidental et l'axe communiste 
soviétique Sino dans l'est. Par le visionnement et la 
discussion du vidéo et d'étudier les ressources de Web, les 
étudiants peuvent commencer à comprendre les conventions du 
documentaire dans l'accès d'offre à une version de la vérité.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta unidade introduz estudantes ao history 
moderno de Cambodia no contexto da guerra fria. Examina o 
relacionamento entre Cambodia e Vietnam e a maneira ambos os países 
tornaram-se drawn no esforço da potência entre os E. U. e o 
capitalismo ocidental e a linha central comunista soviética de Sino 
no leste. Com a visão e a discussão do vídeo e de investigar 
os recursos do Web, os estudantes podem começar a compreender as 
convenções do documentary no acesso oferecendo a uma versão da 
verdade.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa unità introduce gli allievi alla storia 
moderna della Cambogia nel contesto della guerra fredda. Esamina
il rapporto fra la Cambogia ed il Vietnam ed il modo entrambi i paesi 
sono diventato tirati nella lotta di potenza fra gli Stati Uniti ed il
capitalismo occidentale e l'asse comunista sovietico di Sino nell'est.
Con l'osservazione e la discussione sul video e su studio delle 
risorse di Web, gli allievi possono cominciare a capire le convenzioni
del documentary nell'accesso d'offerta ad una versione della verità.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η μονάδα εισάγει τους σπουδαστές στη σύγχρονη 
ιστορία της Καμπότζης στα πλαίσια του ψυχρού πολέμου. 
Εξετάζει τη σχέση μεταξύ της Καμπότζης και του Βιετνάμ και 
του τρόπου που και οι δύο χώρες έγιναν συρμένες στην προσπάθεια 
δύναμης μεταξύ των ΗΠΑ και της δυτικής κεφαλαιοκρατίας και το 
sino σοβιετικό κομμουνιστικό άξονα στην ανατολή. Μέσω 
της όψης και η συζήτηση του βίντεο και της έρευνας των στοιχείων 
συμπεριφοράς Ιστού, σπουδαστές μπορεί να αρχίσει να καταλαβαίνει
τις συμβάσεις του ντοκιμαντέρ στην προσφορά της πρόσβασης σε μια 
έκδοση της αλήθειας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta unidad introduce a estudiantes a la historia 
moderna de Camboya en el contexto de la guerra fría. Examina el
lazo entre Camboya y Vietnam y la manera ambos países llegaron a ser 
exhaustos en la lucha de la potencia entre los E.E.U.U. y el 
capitalismo occidental y el eje comunista soviético de Sino en el 
este. Con la visión y la discusión del vídeo y de investigar 
los recursos del Web, los estudiantes pueden comenzar a entender las 
convenciones del documentary en el acceso de ofrecimiento a una 
versión de la verdad.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205304</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104559</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/representing-history-cambodia-through-the-shadows</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
