<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103474</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103474</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087093</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"There Was Never Any Pay-day For the Negroes": Jourdon Anderson Demands Wages</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"es gab nie jeden möglichen Zahltag für die 
Schwarzen": Jourdon Anderson Nachfrage-Löhne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"il n'y avait jamais n'importe quel jour de paie 
pour les nègres" : Salaires des Demandes de Jourdon Anderson</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"havia nunca todo o pay-day para os negroes": 
Salários Das Demandas De Jourdon Anderson</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"ci non era mai alcun giorno di paga per i 
negroes": Stipendi Delle Domande Di Jourdon Anderson</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Δεν υπήρξε ποτέ οποιοδήποτε pay-day για τους 
νέγρουσ": Το Jourdon Αντερσον απαιτεί τις αμοιβές</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"nunca había cualquier día de paga para los 
negros": Salarios De las Demandas De Jourdon Anderson</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">As slavery collapsed at the close of the Civil War, former slaves quickly explored freedom's possibilities by establishing churches that were independent of white control, seeking education in Freedmen's Bureau schools, and even building and maintaining their own schools. Many took to the roads as they sought opportunities to work and to reconstitute their families. Securing their liberty meant finding the means of support to obtain land or otherwise benefit from their own labor, as Jourdon Anderson made clear in this letter to his former owner. He addressed Major Anderson from Ohio, where he had secured good wages for himself and schooling for his children. Many freedpeople argued that they were entitled to land in return for their years of unpaid labor and looked to the federal government to help achieve economic self-sufficiency. Black southerners understood the value of their own labor and looked for economic independence and a free labor market in their battle over the meaning of emancipation in post-Civil War America.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während Sklaverei am Abschluß des Bürgerkrieges
einstürzte, erforschten ehemalige Sklaven schnell Möglichkeiten der 
Freiheit, indem sie Kirchen herstellten, die das Unabhängige der 
weißen Steuerung waren, Ausbildung in den Büroschulen der Freedmens 
suchten, und im gleichmäßigen Gebäude und ihre eigenen Schulen 
beibehalten. Viele nahmen zu den Straßen, während sie 
Gelegenheiten, ihre Familien zu bearbeiten suchten und wieder 
herzustellen. Ihre Freiheit sichern bedeutet, die Mittel des 
Supports finden, Land oder anders Nutzen von ihren Selbst zu erreichen
Arbeit, wie Jourdon Anderson seinem ehemaligen Inhaber klar in diesem 
Zeichen bildete. Er adressierte Hauptanderson von Ohio, in dem 
er gute Löhne für gesichert hatte und schulend für seine Kinder. 
Viel argumentierte freedpeople, daß sie zum Land in der 
Rückkehr für ihre Jahre der unbezahlten Arbeit erlaubt wurden und 
schaute zur Bundesregierung, um zu helfen, ökonomische 
Selbstüberhebung zu erzielen. Schwarze southerners verstanden 
den Wert ihrer eigenen Arbeit und suchten ökonomischer 
Unabhängigkeit und nach einem freien Arbeitsmarkt in ihrer Schlacht 
über der Bedeutung der Emanzipation im PfostenZivilkrieg Amerika.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant que l'esclavage s'effondrait à l'issue de
la guerre civile, les anciens esclaves ont rapidement exploré les 
possibilités de la liberté par l'établissement des églises qui 
étaient indépendant de la commande blanche, recherchant l'éducation
dans les écoles du bureau des freedmen's, et le bâtiment égal et 
mettant à jour leurs propres écoles. Beaucoup ont pris aux 
routes pendant qu'elles recherchaient des occasions de travailler et 
reconstituer leurs familles. Fixant leur liberté signifiée 
trouvant les moyens du support d'obtenir la terre ou autrement 
l'avantage de leurs propres travail, comme Jourdon Anderson a fait 
clairement dans cette lettre à son ancien propriétaire. Il a 
adressé Anderson principal d'Ohio, où il avait fixé de bons 
salaires pour se et instruisant pour ses enfants. Beaucoup de le
freedpeople a argué du fait qu'ils ont eu droit à la terre en 
échange pour leurs années de travail impayé et a regardé au 
gouvernement fédéral pour aider à réaliser art de l'auto-portrait-sufficiency 
économique. Les habitants du sud noirs ont compris la valeur de 
leur propre travail et ont recherché l'indépendance économique et 
un marché du travail libre dans leur bataille au-dessus de la 
signification de l'émancipation dans la guerre poteau-Civile 
Amérique.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Enquanto o slavery desmoronou no fim da guerra 
civil, os escravos anteriores exploraram rapidamente possibilidades da
liberdade estabelecendo as igrejas que eram independent do controle 
branco, procurando a instrução em escolas do departamento dos 
freedmen, e no edifício uniforme e mantendo suas próprias escolas. 
Muitos fizeram exame às estradas enquanto procuraram 
oportunidades de trabalhar e reconstitute suas famílias. 
Fixando sua liberdade significada encontrando os meios da 
sustentação obter a terra ou de outra maneira o benefício do seus 
próprios trabalho, como Jourdon Anderson fêz claramente nesta letra 
a seu proprietário anterior. Dirigiu-se a Anderson principal de
Ohio, onde tinha fixado salários bons para himself e educando para 
suas crianças. Muito o freedpeople discutiu que estiveram 
intitulados à terra no retorno por seus anos de trabalho por pagar e 
olhou ao governo federal para ajudar conseguir o self-sufficiency 
econômico. Os southerners pretos compreenderam o valor de seu 
próprio trabalho e procuraram a independência econômica e um 
mercado labor livre em sua batalha sobre o meaning do emancipation na 
guerra borne-Civil América.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Mentre lo slavery è sprofondato alla fine della 
guerra civile, gli ex schiavi hanno esplorato rapidamente le 
possibilità della libertà stabilendo le chiese che erano 
indipendente da controllo bianco, cercante la formazione nelle scuole 
dell'ufficio dei freedmen ed in costruzione perfino ed effettuante le 
loro proprie scuole. Molti hanno preso alle strade mentre hanno 
cercato le occasioni funzionare e ricostituire le loro famiglie. 
L'assicurazione della loro libertà ha significato 
l'individuazione dei mezzi di supporto per ottenere la terra o al 
contrario il beneficio dal loro proprio lavoro, poichè Jourdon 
Anderson ha fatto chiaramente in questa lettera al suo ex 
proprietario. Ha richiamato Anderson principale dall'Ohio, in 
cui gli aveva assicurato i buoni stipendi per ed istruendo per i suoi 
bambini. Molto il freedpeople ha sostenuto che sono stati 
autorizzati a terra in cambio dei loro anni del lavoro non 
pagato ed ha osservato al governo federale per contribuire a 
realizzare l'autosufficienza economica. I southerners neri hanno
capito il valore del loro proprio lavoro ed hanno cercato 
l'indipendenza economica e un mercato di lavoro libero della loro 
battaglia sopra il significato dell'emancipazione nella guerra 
alberino-Civile America.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δεδομένου ότι η σκλαβιά κατέρρευσε στον περίβολο του 
εμφύλιου πολέμου, οι προηγούμενοι σκλάβοι διερεύνησαν γρήγορα 
τις δυνατότητες της ελευθερίας με την καθιέρωση των εκκλησιών που 
ήταν ανεξάρτητες από τον άσπρο έλεγχο, επιδιώκων την εκπαίδευση
στα σχολεία γραφείων των απελευθέρων, και χτίζοντας ακόμη και και
συντηρώντας τα σχολεία τους. Πολλοί πήραν στους δρόμους 
δεδομένου ότι επιδίωξαν τις ευκαιρίες να απασχοληθούν και να 
ανασυγκροτηθούν οι οικογένειές τους. Εξασφαλίζοντας την 
ελευθερία τους που σημαίνουν βρίσκοντας τα μέσα της υποστήριξης 
να ληφθεί το έδαφος ή ειδάλλως να ωφεληθεί από την εργασία 
τους, ως Jourdon Αντερσον σαφές σε αυτήν την επιστολή στον 
προηγούμενο ιδιοκτήτη του. Εξέτασε σημαντικό Αντερσον από 
το Οχάιο, όπου είχε εξασφαλίσει τις καλές αμοιβές για τον και 
εκπαιδεύοντας για τα παιδιά του. Πολύ freedpeople 
υποστήριξε ότι είχαν δικαίωμα για να προσγειωθούν σε αντάλλαγμα 
για τα έτη απλήρωτης εργασίας τους και κοίταξε στην ομοσπονδιακή 
κυβέρνηση για να βοηθήσει να επιτύχει την οικονομική αυτάρκεια. 
Οι μαύροι νότιοι κατάλαβαν την αξία της εργασίας τους και 
έψαξαν την οικονομική ανεξαρτησία και μια ελεύθερη αγορά 
εργασίας στη μάχη τους πέρα από την έννοια της χειραφέτησης 
στον μετα-αστικό πόλεμο Αμερική.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mientras que la esclavitud se derrumbó en el 
cierre de la guerra civil, los esclavos anteriores exploraron 
rápidamente las posibilidades de la libertad estableciendo las 
iglesias que eran independiente del control blanco, buscando la 
educación en las escuelas de la oficina de los freedmen, y el 
edificio uniforme y manteniendo sus propias escuelas. Muchos 
llevaron los caminos mientras que buscaron oportunidades de trabajar y
de reconstituir a sus familias. Asegurando su libertad 
significada encontrando los medios de la ayuda de obtener la pista o 
de otra manera la ventaja sus el propios trabajo, como Jourdon 
Anderson hizo claramente en esta carta a su propietario anterior. 
Él trató Anderson importante de Ohio, en donde él había 
asegurado los buenos salarios para se y enseñando para sus niños. 
Mucho el freedpeople discutió que les dieran derecho a la pista
en la vuelta por sus años del trabajo sin pagar y miraba al gobierno 
federal para ayudar a alcanzar autosuficiencia económica. Los 
southerners negros entendían el valor de su propio trabajo y buscaron
independencia económica y un mercado de trabajo libre en su batalla 
sobre el significado de la emancipación en la guerra poste-Civil 
América.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087093</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103474</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/there-was-never-any-pay-day-for-the-negroes-jourdon-anderson-demands-wages</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
