<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103741</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103741</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087142</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Trouble So Hard": Singing of Slavery and Freedom</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Mühe So Stark": Singen der Sklaverei und 
der Freiheit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Ennui Tellement Dur" : Chant de l'esclavage
et de la liberté</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Problema Assim Duramente": Cantar do 
slavery e da liberdade</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Difficoltà Così Duro": Canto dello 
slavery e della libertà</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Πρόβλημα τόσο σκληρό": Τραγούδι της σκλαβιάς 
και της ελευθερίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Apuro Tan Difícilmente": El cantar de la 
esclavitud y de la libertad</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Spirituals and work songs, rooted in both the slavery era and the West African societies from which most African-American slaves were originally taken, provided cultural sustenance to African Americans in the midst of intense racial oppression. Folklorists first began collecting traditional southern music in the late-19th century. In the 1920s and 1930s, John Lomax (and other members of his family) recorded southern musicians (African-American, white, and Mexican-American) for the Library of Congress. "Trouble So Hard," sung by Dock Reed, Henry Reed, and Vera Hall in Livingston, Alabama, in 1937, was reminiscent in style of the slavery era, when the congregation sang without hymnbooks or musical accompaniment. The style of singing--the lead singer's call and the congregation's increasingly loud and forceful response--had its roots in African religious practice.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Angelegenheiten- und Arbeitsliede, verwurzelt in 
der Sklavereiära und in den afrikanischen Westgesellschaften, von 
denen die meisten Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Sklaven ursprünglich 
genommen wurden, zur Verfügung gestelltes kulturelles sustenance zu 
den afrikanischen Amerikanern in der Mitte der intensiven rassischen 
Unterdrückung. Folkloristen fingen zuerst an, traditionelle 
südliche Musik im des späten 19. jahrhunderts Jahrhundert zu 
sammeln. In den zwanziger Jahren und in den dreißiger Jahren 
speicherten John Lomax (und andere Bauteile seiner Familie) südliche 
Musiker (Afrikanisch-Amerikanisch, weiß und Mexikanisch-Amerikanisch)
für die Bibliothek des Kongresses. "bemühen Sie also stark," 
gesungen durch Dock Reed, Henry-Schilf, und Vera Hall in Livingston, 
Alabama, 1937, war in der Art der Sklavereiära erinnernd, als die 
Versammlung ohne hymnbooks oder musikalische Begleitung sang. 
Die Art des Singens -- der Aufruf und der Versammlung des 
Leitung Sängers in zunehmendem Maße laut und starke Antwort -- hatte
seine Wurzeln in der afrikanischen frommen Praxis.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Chansons de chant religieux et de travail, 
enracinées dans l'ère d'esclavage et les sociétés africaines 
occidentales desquelles la plupart des esclaves afro-américains ont été
initialement pris, sustentation culturelle fournie aux Américains 
africains au milieu de l'oppression raciale intense. Les 
folkloristes ont commencé la première fois à rassembler la musique 
méridionale traditionnelle en fin du 19me siècle. Dans les 
années 20 et les années 30, John Lomax (et d'autres membres de sa 
famille) ont enregistré les musiciens méridionaux (Afro-Américain, 
blanc, et Mexicain-Américain) pour la bibliothèque du congrès. 
"préoccupez ainsi dur," chanté par Dock Reed, roseau d'Henry, 
et Vera Hall en Livingston, Alabama, en 1937, était réminiscent dans
le modèle de l'ère d'esclavage, quand le rassemblement a chanté 
sans hymnbooks ou accompagnement musical. Le modèle du chant --
l'appel et le rassemblement du chanteur principal réponse de plus en 
plus forte et puissante -- a eu ses racines dans la pratique 
religieuse africaine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Canções do espiritual e do trabalho, enraizadas
  na era do slavery e nas sociedades africanas ocidentais de que a 
maioria de escravos Africano-Americanos foram feitos exame 
originalmente, sustenance cultural fornecido aos americanos africanos 
no meio do oppression racial intenso. Os folklorists começaram 
primeiramente a coletar a música do sul tradicional no século 
late-19th. Nos 1920s e nos 1930s, John Lomax (e outros membros 
de sua família) gravaram músicos do sul (Africano-Americano, branco,
e Mexicano-Americano) para a biblioteca do congress. "incomode 
assim que duramente," cantado por Doca Lingüeta, lingüeta do Henry, 
e Vera Salão em Livingston, Alabama, em 1937, era reminiscent no 
estilo da era do slavery, quando o congregation cantou sem hymnbooks 
ou acompanhamento musical. O estilo de cantar -- o atendimento e
o congregation de singer de ligação resposta cada vez mais alta e 
forceful -- teve suas raizes na prática religiosa africana.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Canzoni del lavoro e dello spiritual, sradicate 
sia nell'era di slavery che nelle società africane ad ovest da cui la
maggior parte dei schiavi Africano-Americani originalmente sono stati 
presi, sustenance culturale fornito al oppression razziale in mezzo a
intenso africano degli Americani. I folklorists in primo luogo 
hanno cominciato a raccogliere la musica del sud tradizionale nel fine
del 19esimo secolo. Negli anni 20 e nei 1930s, John Lomax (ed 
altri membri della sua famiglia) hanno registrato i musicisti del 
sud (Africano-Americano, bianco e messicano-american) per la libreria 
del congresso. "disturbisi in modo da duro," cantato da Dock 
Reed, canna di henry e Vera Corridoio in Livingston, Alabama, in 1937,
era rievocativo nello stile dell'era di slavery, quando il 
congregation ha cantato senza hymnbooks o accompagnamento musicale. 
Lo stile di canto -- la chiamata ed il congregation del cantante
di cavo risposta sempre più forte e valida -- ha avuto relative 
radici nella pratica religiosa africana.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τραγούδια Spirituals και εργασίας, που ριζοβολούν 
και στην εποχή σκλαβιάς και στις δυτικές αφρικανικές κοινωνίες 
από τις οποίες οι περισσότεροι αφρικανικός-αμερικανικοί σκλάβοι 
λήφθηκαν αρχικά, παρεχόμενο πολιτιστικό μέσο συντήρησης σε 
αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς στη μέση της έντονης φυλετικής κατοχής.
Folklorists άρχισαν αρχικά την παραδοσιακή νότια 
μουσική στο late-19th αιώνα. Στη δεκαετία του '20 και τη 
δεκαετία του '30, John Lomax (και άλλα μέλη της οικογένειάς
του) κατέγραψαν τους νότιους μουσικούς (αφρικανικός-Αμερικανός, 
λευκό, και Μεξικανοαμερικάνος) για τη βιβλιοθήκη του συνεδρίου. 
"Το πρόβλημα τόσο σκληρό," τραγουδημένος από τον κάλαμο 
αποβαθρών, Henry Reed, και τη Βέρα Hall σε Livingston, 
Αλαμπάμα, το 1937, ήταν ενθυμίζον στο ύφος της εποχής 
σκλαβιάς, όταν τραγούδησε η κοινότητα χωρίς τα hymnbooks ή 
μουσικό συμπλήρωμα. Το ύφος του τραγουδιού -- η κλήση του 
τραγουδιστή μολύβδου και η δυνατή και ισχυρή απάντηση της 
κοινότητας όλο και περισσότερο -- είχε τις ρίζες του στην 
αφρικανική θρησκευτική πρακτική.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Canciones del espiritual y del trabajo, arraigadas
en la era y las sociedades africanas del oeste de las cuales la 
mayoría de los esclavos Africano-Americanos fueron tomados 
originalmente, sustenance cultural proporcionado de la esclavitud a 
los americanos africanos en el medio de la opresión racial intensa. 
Los folklorists primero comenzaron a recoger música meridional 
tradicional en el siglo de fines del siglo diecinueve. En los 
años 20 y los años 30, Juan Lomax (y otros miembros de su familia) 
registraron a músicos meridionales (Africano-Americano, blanco, y 
Mexicano-Americano) para la biblioteca del congreso. "preocupe 
así que difícilmente," cantado por Dock Reed, caña del Henrio, y 
Vera Pasillo en Livingston, Alabama, en 1937, era evocador en el 
estilo de la era de la esclavitud, cuando la congregación cantó sin 
hymnbooks o el acompañamiento musical. El estilo de cantar -- 
de terminal de componente la congregación del cantante la llamada y 
respuesta cada vez más ruidosa y poderosa -- tenía sus raíces en 
práctica religiosa africana.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087142</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103741</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/trouble-so-hard-singing-of-slavery-and-freedom</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
