<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107403</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107403</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086310</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Ideas in Conflict: Opposing Views of the Cripple Creek Strike</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ideen in der $überschneidung: 
Entgegensetzende Ansichten des Krüppel-Nebenfluss-Schlages</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Idées en conflit : Vues d'opposition de la 
grève de crique d'estropié</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Idéias no conflito: Vistas opondo-se da 
batida do creek do aleijado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Idee in conflitto: Viste avversarie del 
colpo dell'insenatura del cripple</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ιδέες σε σύγκρουση: Οι αντιτιθέμενες όψεις 
ακρωτηριάζουν την απεργία κολπίσκου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ideas en conflicto: Vistas de oposición de 
la huelga del cala del lisiado</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Some of the sharpest and most violent class struggles in American history were fought in the hard rock mining towns of the nineteenth-century West. In Cripple Creek, Colorado, for example, violent conflict broke out in 1903 between members of the Western Federation of Miners (WFM) and corporate mining interests determined to crush the union. Before it was over, thirty men had been killed in numerous gun battles. The civil war was not only fought with fists, bullets, and dynamite in the streets and mines of Cripple Creek; it also was a war of words waged in the press. In June, 1904, the Mine Owners' Association and the WFM submitted these statements to eastern newspapers, expressing opposing viewpoints on the purpose of the strike.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Einige der schärfsten und heftigsten Kategorie 
Kämpfe in der amerikanischen Geschichte wurden in den 
gewinnenstädten des harten Felsens des 19.-Jahrhunderts nach Westen 
gekämpft. Im Krüppel-Nebenfluß brach Kolorado z.B. heftige 
$überschneidung 1903 zwischen Bauteilen der westlichen Vereinigung 
der Bergmänner (WFM) und den korporativen gewinneninteressen, die 
festgestellt wurden, um den Anschluß zu zerquetschen aus. Bevor
es rüber sein, waren dreißig Männer in den zahlreichen 
Gewehrschlachten beendet worden. Der Bürgerkrieg wurde nicht 
nur mit den Fäusten, Gewehrkugeln und Dynamit in den Straßen und 
in den Gruben des Krüppel-Nebenflusses gekämpft; es war auch 
ein Krieg der Wörter, die in der Presse unternommen wurden. Im 
Juni 1904, gaben die Verbindung der Grube Inhaber und das WFM diese 
Anweisungen bei den östlichen Zeitungen ein und drückten 
entgegensetzende Veranschaulichungen betreffend den Schlag aus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Certaines des luttes de classe les plus marquées 
et les plus violentes dans l'histoire américaine ont été combattues
dans les villes d'extraction de roche dure du dix-neuvième-siècle à
l'ouest. Dans la crique d'estropié, le Colorado, par exemple, 
conflit violent a éclaté en 1903 entre les membres de la 
fédération occidentale des mineurs (WFM) et les intérêts 
d'extraction de corporation déterminés pour écraser l'union. 
Avant qu'il plus de, trente hommes avaient été détruits dans 
de nombreuses fusillades. La guerre civile a été non 
seulement combattue avec des poings, des balles, et la dynamite dans 
les rues et les mines de la crique d'estropié ; c'était 
également une guerre des mots faits dans la presse. En juin, 
1904, l'association des propriétaires de mine et le WFM ont soumis 
ces rapports aux journaux orientaux, exprimant des points de vue 
d'opposition sur le but de la grève.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Algumas das lutas de classes as mais afiadas e as 
mais violentas no history americano foram lutadas nas cidades minando 
da rocha dura do décimo-século para o oeste. No creek do 
aleijado, Colorado, para o exemplo, conflito violento quebrou para 
fora em 1903 entre membros do federation ocidental dos mineiros (WFM) 
e os interesses minando incorporados determinados esmagar a união. 
Antes que sobre, trinta homens foram matados em batalhas 
numerosas do injetor. A guerra civil foi lutada não somente com
os punhos, as balas, e a dinamite nas ruas e nas minas do creek do 
aleijado; era também uma guerra das palavras empreendidas na 
imprensa. Em junho, 1904, a associação dos proprietários da 
mina e o WFM submeteram estas indicações aos jornais orientais, 
expressando viewpoints opondo-se na finalidade da batida.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Alcune delle lotte di codice categoria più 
marcate e più violente nella storia americana sono state combattute 
nelle città estraenti della roccia dura del diciannovesimo-secolo 
verso ovest. Nell'insenatura del cripple, Colorado, per esempio,
conflitto violento ha scoppiato in 1903 fra i membri della federazione
occidentale dei minatori (WFM) e gli interessi estraenti corporativi 
determinati per schiacciare l'unione. Prima che finito, trenta 
uomini erano stati uccisi nelle battaglie numerose della pistola. 
La guerra civile è stata combattuta non soltanto con i pugni, 
le pallottole e la dinamite nelle vie e nelle miniere dell'insenatura 
del cripple; egualmente era una guerra delle parole intraprese 
nella pressa. In giugno, del 1904, l'associazione dei 
proprietari della miniera ed il WFM hanno presentato queste istruzione
ai giornali orientali, esprimenti i punti di vista avversari sullo 
scopo del colpo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μερικές από τις αιχμηρότερες και βιαιότερες πόλεις 
μεταλλείας προσπάθειες κλάσης στην αμερικανική ιστορία πάλεψαν 
στις σκληρού βράχου της δύσης δέκατος-αιώνα. Cripple 
στον κολπίσκο, Κολοράντο, παραδείγματος χάριν, η βίαια σύγκρουση
ξέσπησε το 1903 μεταξύ των μελών της δυτικής ομοσπονδίας των 
ανθρακωρύχων (WFM) και τα εταιρικά ενδιαφέροντα μεταλλείας 
αποφάσισαν να συντρίψουν την ένωση. Προτού να τελειώσει, 
τριάντα άτομα ήταν σκοτωμένων στις πολυάριθμες μάχες πυροβόλων 
όπλων. Ο εμφύλιος πόλεμος όχι μόνο διεξήχθη με τις 
πυγμές, τις σφαίρες, και το δυναμίτη στις οδούς και τα ορυχεία 
Cripple του κολπίσκου  ήταν επίσης ένας πόλεμος των 
λέξεων στον Τύπο. Τον Ιούνιο, το 1904, η ένωση των 
ιδιοκτητών ορυχείου και το WFM υπέβαλαν αυτές τις δηλώσεις 
στις ανατολικές εφημερίδες, εκφράζοντας τις αντιτιθέμενες απόψεις
στο σκοπό της απεργίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Algunas de las luchas de clase más sostenidas y 
más violentas de la historia americana fueron luchadas en las 
ciudades que minaban de la roca dura del diecinueveavo-siglo al oeste.
En el cala del lisiado, Colorado, por ejemplo, conflicto 
violento explotó en 1903 entre los miembros de la federación 
occidental de los mineros (WFM) y los intereses que minaban 
corporativos determinados para machacar la unión. Antes de que 
encima, habían matado a treinta hombres en batallas numerosas del 
arma. La guerra civil fue luchada no solamente con los puños, 
los puntos negros, y la dinamita en las calles y las minas del cala 
del lisiado; también era una guerra de las palabras emprendidas
en la prensa. En junio de 1904, la asociación de los 
propietarios de la mina y el WFM sometieron estas declaraciones a los 
periódicos del este, expresando puntos de vista de oposición en el 
propósito de la huelga.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086310</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107403</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/ideas-in-conflict-opposing-views-of-the-cripple-creek-strike</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
