<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107032</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107032</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207801</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Transition from Practitioner to Professor: The Struggle of New Faculty to find their Place in the World of Academia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Übergang von Praktiker zu Professor: 
Der Kampf der neuen Lehrkörpers, zum ihres Platzes in der Welt 
der Akademie zu finden</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La transition du praticien au professeur : 
La lutte du nouveau corps enseignant pour trouver leur endroit 
dans le monde du milieu universitaire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A transição do practitioner ao professor: 
O esforço da faculdade nova para encontrar seu lugar no mundo 
do academia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La transizione dal professionista al professore: 
La lotta di nuova facoltà per trovare il loro posto nel mondo 
dell'accademia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η μετάβαση από τον επαγγελματία στον καθηγητή: Η
προσπάθεια της νέας ικανότητας να βρεί τη θέση τους στον κόσμο 
του ακαδημαϊκού κόσμου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La transición del médico al profesor: La 
lucha de la nueva facultad para encontrar su lugar en el mundo de la 
academia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Becoming a college professor brings both the feeling of self-accomplishment and discernment regarding this prestigious achievement. Most doctoral candidates are practitioners in the field of public education and will hopefully transition from a principalship to the office of a college professor. While this journey is filled with personal attainment, some of the doctoral graduates experience a variety of struggles along the way to their positions in higher education. This study examined this journey for some of those who have made the move. Note: This module has been peer-reviewed, accepted, and sanctioned by the National Council of the Professors of Educational Administration (NCPEA) as a scholarly contribution to the knowledge base in educational administration.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Stehen eines Hochschulprofessors holt das 
Gefühl der Selbst-Vollendung und die Einsicht betreffend ist diese 
prestigevolle Ausführung. Die meisten Doktoranwärter sind 
Praktiker in auffangene des Unterrichtswesen- und 
Willenshoffnungsvoll Überganges von einem principalship zum Büro 
eines Hochschulprofessors. Während diese Reise mit 
persönlicher Erreichung gefüllt wird, erfahren einige der 
Doktorabsolvent eine Vielzahl von Kämpfen entlang der Methode in ihre
Positionen in der höheren Ausbildung. Diese Studie überprüfte
diese Reise für einige von denen, die die Maßnahme getroffen haben. 
Anmerkung: Dieses Modul ist vom Nationalrat der 
Professoren der pädagogischen Leitung (NCPEA) als gelehrter Beitrag 
zur Informationsbank in der pädagogischen Leitung Gleich-wiederholt 
worden, angenommen worden und sanktioniert worden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Aller bien à un professeur d'université apporte 
le sentiment de art de l'auto-portrait-accomplishment et le discernement concernant
cet accomplissement prestigieux. La plupart des candidats 
doctoraux sont des praticiens dans le domaine de la transition 
d'éducation publique et de volonté si tout va bien d'un 
principalship au bureau d'un professeur d'université. Tandis 
que ce voyage est rempli d'accomplissement personnel, certains des 
diplômés doctoraux éprouvent une variété de luttes le long de la 
voie dans leurs positions dans une éducation plus élevée. 
Cette étude a examiné ce voyage pour certaines de ceux qui ont
entrepris la démarche. Note : Ce module pair-a été 
passé en revue, reçu, et sanctionné par le Conseil national des 
professeurs de la gestion éducative (NCPEA) comme contribution 
savante à la base de connaissance dans la gestion éducative.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Assentar bem em um professor da faculdade traz  o 
sentimento da self-realização e o discernment a respeito desta 
realização prestigiosa. A maioria de candidatos doctoral são 
practitioners no campo da transição da instrução pública e da 
vontade esperançosamente de um principalship ao escritório de um 
professor da faculdade. Quando esta viagem for enchida com a 
realização pessoal, alguns dos graduados doctoral experimentam uma 
variedade dos esforços ao longo da maneira a suas posições em uma 
instrução mais elevada. Este estudo examinou esta viagem para 
alguma daquelas que fizeram o movimento. Nota: Este 
módulo par-foi revisto, aceitado, e sanctioned pelo conselho nacional
dos professores da administração educacional (NCPEA) como uma 
contribuição scholarly à base de conhecimento na administração 
educacional.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Stare bene ad un professore dell'università porta
sia la sensibilità della auto-realizzazione che il discernment per 
quanto riguarda questo successo prestigious. La maggior parte 
dei candidati di laurea sono professionisti nel campo della 
transizione di volontà e di formazione pubblica eventualmente da un 
principalship all'ufficio di un professore dell'università. 
Mentre questo viaggio è riempito di raggiungimento personale, 
alcuni dei laureati di laurea avvertono una varietà di lotte lungo il
modo alle loro posizioni nell'istruzione superiore. Questo 
studio ha esaminato questo viaggio per alcuni di coloro che ha fatto 
il movimento. Nota: Questo modulo pari-è stato rivisto, 
accettato stato e sanctioned dal Consiglio nazionale dei professori 
della gestione educativa (NCPEA) come contributo da studioso alla base
di conoscenza nella gestione educativa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Να γίνει καθηγητής κολλεγίων φέρνει και το συναίσθημα
της μόνος-ολοκλήρωσης και της διάκρισης σχετικά με αυτό το 
προσδίδον γόητρο επίτευγμα. Οι περισσότεροι διδακτορικοί 
υποψήφιοι είναι επαγγελματίες στον τομέα της δημόσιας 
εκπαίδευσης και ενδεχομένως μετάβαση από ένα principalship στο
γραφείο ενός καθηγητή κολλεγίων. Ενώ αυτό το ταξίδι 
γεμίζουν με την προσωπική επίτευξη, μερικοί από τους 
διδακτορικούς πτυχιούχους δοκιμάζουν ποικίλες προσπάθειες κατά 
μήκος του τρόπου στις θέσεις τους στην τριτοβάθμια εκπαίδευση. 
Αυτή η μελέτη εξέτασε αυτό το ταξίδι για μερικούς από 
εκείνους που έχουν κάνει την κίνηση. Σημείωση: Αυτή 
η ενότητα όμοιος-έχει αναθεωρηθεί, έχει γίνει αποδεκτή, και 
έχει εγκριθεί από το εθνικό Συμβούλιο των καθηγητών της 
εκπαιδευτικής διοίκησης (NCPEA) ως μορφωμένη συμβολή στη βάση 
γνώσεων στην εκπαιδευτική διοίκηση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sentir bien a un profesor de la universidad trae 
la sensación de la uno mismo-realizacio'n y el discernimiento con 
respecto a este logro prestigioso. La mayoría de los candidatos
doctorales son médicos en el campo de la transición de la educación
pública y de la voluntad esperanzadamente de un principalship a la 
oficina de un profesor de la universidad. Mientras que este 
viaje se llena del logro personal, algunos de los graduados doctorales
experimentan una variedad de luchas a lo largo de la manera a sus 
posiciones en una educación más alta. Este estudio examinó 
este viaje para algunos de los que han hecho el movimiento. 
Nota: Este módulo par-ha sido repasado, validado, y 
sancionado por el consejo nacional de los profesores de la 
administración educativa (NCPEA) como contribución de estudiante a 
la base de conocimiento en la administración educativa.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:J. CRAIG COLEMAN
FN:J. CRAIG COLEMAN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:EFFIE CHRISTIE
FN:EFFIE CHRISTIE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MARY CULVER
FN:MARY CULVER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:DEBORAH ERICKSON
FN:DEBORAH ERICKSON
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JOHN HUNT
FN:JOHN HUNT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:FRANKIE WILLIAMS
FN:FRANKIE WILLIAMS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:GARY KINSEY
FN:GARY KINSEY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:SAMUEL SMITH
FN:SAMUEL SMITH
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JANET TAREILO
FN:JANET TAREILO
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207801</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution 2.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107032</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-transition-from-practitioner-to-professor-the-struggle-of-new-faculty-to-find-their-place-in-the-world-of-academia</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
