<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108227</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108227</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087021</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Poisonous Occupations in Illinois": Physician Alice Hamilton Explores the "Dangerous Trades" at the Turn of the Century</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die giftigen Besetzungen in Illinois": Arzt
Alice Hamilton erforscht den "gefährlichen Handel" an der 
Jahrhundertwende</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"les métiers toxiques en Illinois" : Le 
médecin Alice Hamilton explore "les commerces dangereux" à la fin du
siècle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"as ocupações venenosas em Illinois": O 
médico Alice Hamilton explora "os comércios perigosos" na volta do 
século</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"le occupazioni tossiche in Illinois": Il 
medico Alice Hamilton esplora "i commerci pericolosi" alla fine del 
secolo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Τα δηλητηριώδη επαγγέλματα στο Ιλλινόισ": Ο 
παθολόγος Alice Χάμιλτον ερευνά τα "επικίνδυνα εμπόρια" στο 
γύρισμα του αιώνα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"las ocupaciones venenosas en Illinois": El 
médico Alicia Hamilton explora los "comercios peligrosos" al final 
del siglo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Nineteenth-century laborers faced a variety of work-related ailments: from rheumatism and pneumonia to lead palsy and carbon monoxide poisoning. Yet governments rarely regulated workplace conditions and the United States lagged far behind industrialized European nations in such regulation. In the Progressive era, however, a movement to regulate dangerous industrial working conditions arose, and one of its most prominent leaders was a physician named Alice Hamilton. In this selection from her 1943 autobiography, Hamilton described her residency at Jane Addams's Hull House in the late 1890s and her participation in the Illinois Occupational Disease Commission.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">19.-Jahrhundert Arbeiter stellten eine Vielzahl 
der arbeiten-in Verbindung stehenden Unpäßlichkeiten gegenüber: 
vom Rheumatism und von Pneumonie, zum von von Lähmung und von 
von Kohlenmonoxidvergiftung zu führen. Dennoch Regierungen 
verlangsamten selten geregelte Arbeitsplatzzustände und die 
Vereinigten Staaten weit hinter industrialisierten europäischen 
Nationen in solcher Regelung. In der progressiven Ära jedoch 
entstand eine Bewegung, zum der gefährlichen industriellen 
Arbeitsbedingungen zu regeln, und einer seiner vorstehendsten Führer 
war ein Arzt, der Alice Hamilton benannt wurde. In dieser 
Auswahl von ihrer Autobiographie 1943, beschrieb Hamilton ihren 
Sitz Jane Addamss am Rumpf-Haus im späten 1890s und an 
ihrer Teilnahme in der Illinois Berufskrankheit-Kommission.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les travailleurs de Dix-neuvième-siècle ont fait
face à une variété de maux travailler-connexes : du 
rhumatisme et de la pneumonie pour mener la paralysie et 
l'empoisonnement d'oxyde de carbone. Pourtant les états 
rarement réglés de lieu de travail de gouvernements et les 
Etats-Unis ont traîné loin derrière des nations européennes 
industrialisées dans un tel règlement. Dans l'ère 
progressive, cependant, un mouvement pour régler des conditions de 
travail industrielles dangereuses a surgi, et une de ses amorces plus 
en avant était un médecin nommé Alice Hamilton. Dans cette 
sélection à partir de sa autobiographie 1943, Hamilton a décrit son
implantation à la Chambre de coque de Jane Addams vers la fin de 
1890s et sa participation dans la Commission de maladie 
professionnelle de l'Illinois.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">os laborers de Décimo-século enfrentaram uma 
variedade de ailments trabalh-relacionados: do rheumatism e do 
pneumonia para conduzir ao palsy e ao envenenamento de monóxido de 
carbono. Contudo as condições raramente reguladas do workplace
dos governos e os estados unidos retardaram-se distante atrás das 
nações européias industrialized em tal regulamento. Na era 
progressiva, entretanto, um movimento para regular condições de 
funcionamento industriais perigosas levantou-se, e um de seus líderes
mais proeminentes era um médico nomeado Alice Hamilton. Nesta 
seleção de seu autobiography 1943, Hamilton descreveu seu residency 
na casa do hull de Jane Addams no 1890s atrasado e na sua 
participação no commission da doença ocupacional de Illinois.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">i lavoratori di Diciannovesimo-secolo hanno 
affrontato una varietà di ailments funzion-relativi: da 
rheumatism e da polmonite per condurre paralisi ed avvelenamento di 
ossido di carbonio. Tuttavia i governi hanno regolato raramente 
gli stati del posto di lavoro ed unito Dichiara ritardato 
lontano dietro le nazioni europee industrializzate in tale 
regolazione. Nell'era progressiva, tuttavia, un movimento per 
regolare le condizioni di lavoro industriali pericolose ha presentato 
ed uno dei relativi capi più prominenti era un medico chiamato
Alice Hamilton. In questa selezione dal suo autobiography 1943, 
Hamilton ha descritto il suo residency alla Camera del guscio di Jane 
Addams verso la fine di 1890s e la sua partecipazione nella 
Commissione di malattia professionale dell'Illinois.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα laborers δέκατος-αιώνα αντιμετώπισαν ποικίλες 
σχετικές με την εργασία ασθένειες: από το ρευματισμό και 
την πνευμονία για να οδηγήσει την παράλυση και τη δηλητηρίαση 
μονοξειδίου άνθρακα. Ακόμα οι κυβερνήσεις ρύθμισαν σπάνια 
τους όρους εργασιακών χώρων και οι Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες 
καθυστέρησαν μακριά πίσω από βιομηχανοποιημένα ευρωπαϊκά έθνος
σε τέτοιο κανονισμό. Στην προοδευτική εποχή, εντούτοις, μια
μετακίνηση για να ρυθμίσει τις επικίνδυνες βιομηχανικές συνθήκες 
εργασίας προέκυψε, και ένας από τους πιό προεξέχοντες ηγέτες 
του ήταν ένας παθολόγος που ονομάστηκε την Alice Χάμιλτον. 
Σε αυτήν την επιλογή από την αυτοβιογραφία του 1943 της, 
το Χάμιλτον περιέγραψε την αρμοστεία της στο σπίτι του Hull της
Jane Addams's προς το τέλος 1890s και της συμμετοχής της 
στην Επιτροπή επαγγελματικών ασθενειών του Ιλλινόις.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">los trabajadores del Diecinueveavo-siglo hicieron 
frente a una variedad de dolencias trabajar-relacionadas: del 
reumatismo y de la pulmonía para conducir parálisis y el 
envenenamiento de monóxido de carbono. Con todo las condiciones
raramente reguladas del lugar de trabajo de los gobiernos y los 
Estados Unidos se retrasaron lejos detrás de naciones europeas 
industrializadas en tal regulación. En la era progresiva, sin 
embargo, un movimiento para regular condiciones de trabajo 
industriales peligrosas se presentó, y uno de sus arranques de cinta 
más prominentes era médico nombrado Alicia Hamilton. En esta 
selección de su autobiografía 1943, Hamilton describió su 
implantación en la casa del casco de Jane Addams en el último 1890s 
y su participación en la Comisión de enfermedad profesional de 
Illinois.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087021</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108227</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-poisonous-occupations-in-illinois-physician-alice-hamilton-explores-the-dangerous-trades-at-the-turn-of-the-century</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
