<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104219</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104219</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086836</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Smoked continuously from Trepassey to Wales."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ununterbrochen geraucht von Trepassey nach Wales."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"fumé sans interruption de Trepassey au Pays de 
Gales."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"fumado continuamente de Trepassey ao wales."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"fumato continuamente da Trepassey nel Galles."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Καπνισμένος συνεχώς από Trepassey στην Ουαλία."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"fumado continuamente de Trepassey a País de 
Gales."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the 1920s, advertisements sought to create consumer demand by manufacturing new wants. Some advertisements associated products with a desirable lifestyle, while others, like this 1928 cigarette advertisement, made use of celebrity endorsements. Here, aviator Amelia Earhart, the first woman to successfully fly solo across the Atlantic, testifies to the pacifying virtues of Lucky Strikes. Although advertisers suggested that everybody needed the latest of everything, most families set their own priorities and purchased the things they wanted most.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In den zwanziger Jahren wünscht die Reklameanzeigen, die 
gesucht werden, um Verbrauchernachfrage zu erstellen, indem sie neu 
herstellen. Einige Reklameanzeigen verbanden Produkte mit einem 
wünschenswerten Lebensstil, während andere, wie diese 
Zigarettereklameanzeige 1928, Berühmtheitaufschriften gebrauchten. 
Hier bezeugt Flieger Amelia Earhart, die erste Frau, zum über 
den Atlantik erfolgreich allein zu fliegen, zu den beruhigenden 
Tugenden der glücklichen Schläge. Obgleich Inserenten 
vorschlugen, daß jeder das späteste von alles benötigte, legten die
meisten Familien ihre eigenen Prioritäten fest und kauften die 
Sachen, die sie die meisten wünschten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans les années 20, les annonces recherchées pour créer
la demande du consommateur à la fabrication nouvelle veut. 
Quelques annonces ont associé des produits à un style de vie 
souhaitable, alors que d'autres, comme cette publicité 1928 de 
cigarette, se servaient des approbations de célébrité. Ici, 
l'aviateur Amelia Earhart, la première femme à voler avec succès en
solo à travers l'Océan atlantique, témoigne aux vertus apaisantes 
des grèves chanceuses. Bien que les annonceurs aient proposé
que tout le monde ait eu besoin du plus en retard de tout, la plupart 
des familles ont établi leurs propres priorités et ont acheté les 
choses qu'elles ont voulu les la plupart.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nos 1920s, as propagandas procuradas criar a demanda de 
consumidor manufaturando novo querem. Algumas propagandas 
associaram produtos com um lifestyle desejável, quando outras, como 
esta propaganda 1928 do cigarro, empregaram endossos da celebridade. 
Aqui, o aviador Amelia Earhart, primeira mulher a voar com 
sucesso só através do Atlântico, testifies aos virtues pacifying de
batidas afortunadas. Embora os publicitários sugerissem que 
todos necessitou o mais atrasado de tudo, a maioria de famílias 
ajustaram suas próprias prioridades e compraram as coisas que 
quiseram a maioria.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Negli anni 20, le pubblicità cercate per creare la 
domanda di beni di consumo producendo nuova desidera. Alcune 
pubblicità hanno associato i prodotti con un lifestyle desiderabile, 
mentre altre, come questa pubblicità 1928 della sigaretta, hanno 
usato le approvazioni di celebrity. Qui, il aviator Amelia 
Earhart, la prima donna da volare con successo da solo attraverso 
l'Atlantico, testimonia alle virtù pacifying dei colpi fortunati. 
Anche se i advertisers hanno suggerito che ognuno ha avuto 
bisogno del più ritardato di tutto, la maggior parte delle famiglie 
hanno stabilito le loro proprie priorità ed hanno comprato le cose 
che hanno desiderato la maggior parte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στη δεκαετία του '20, οι διαφημίσεις που επιδιώκονται 
για να δημιουργήσουν την καταναλωτική ζήτηση με την κατασκευή νέα
θέλουν. Μερικές διαφημίσεις σύνδεσαν τα προϊόντα με έναν 
επιθυμητό τρόπο ζωής, ενώ άλλοι, όπως αυτήν την διαφήμιση 
τσιγάρων του 1928, χρησιμοποίησαν τις επικυρώσεις 
προσωπικοτήτων. Εδώ, ο αεροπόρος Amelia Earhart, η 
πρώτη γυναίκα για να πετάξει επιτυχώς σόλο πέρα από τον 
Ατλαντικό, πιστοποιεί στις αρετές ειρήνευσης των Lucky 
Strike. Αν και οι δηαφημιστές πρότειναν ότι καθένας 
χρειάστηκε τον πιό πρόσφατο όλων, οι περισσότερες οικογένειες 
έθεσαν τις προτεραιότητές τους και αγόρασαν τα πράγματα που 
θέλησαν των περισσότερων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En los años 20, los anuncios intentados para crear 
demanda del consumidor fabricando nueva desean. Algunos anuncios
asociaron productos a una forma de vida deseable, mientras que otros, 
como este anuncio 1928 del cigarrillo, hicieron uso endosos de la 
celebridad. Aquí, el aviador Amelia Earhart, la primera mujer a
volar con éxito a solas a través del Atlántico, atestigua a las 
virtudes que pacifican de huelgas afortunadas. Aunque los 
publicistas sugirieron que todos necesitara el más último de todo, 
la mayoría de las familias fijaron sus propias prioridades y 
compraron las cosas que desearon la mayoría.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086836</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104219</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/smoked-continuously-from-trepassey-to-wales</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
