<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107201</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107201</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087284</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"A condition we can ill afford": Debating the Equal Pay Act of 1963</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"eine Bedingung, die wir Dose Kranke" uns leisten:
Debattieren der gleiche Bezahlung Tat von 1963</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"une condition que nous défectuosité de bidon 
nous permettons" : Discussion de l'acte d'égalité de salaires 
de 1963</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"uma circunstância que nós mal da lata temos 
recursos para": Debatendo o ato do pagamento igual de 1963</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"una circostanza che ill della latta ci 
permettiamo": Dibattere la Legge di parità salariale di 1963</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ένας όρος μπορούμε άρρωστος να αντέξουμε 
οικονομικά": Συζήτηση του νόμου ίσης αμοιβής του 1963</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"una condición que enfermedad de la lata 
producimos": Discutir el acto de la igualdad de salario de 1963</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Recommendations by the National War Labor Board during World War II to pay male and female workers equal wages yielded few changes in the gender wage gap. Women continued to receive less money for comparable work, and into the 1960s want ads characterized jobs as "male" or "female" with resulting salary differences based on gender. The Equal Pay Act (EPA) made it illegal to pay men and women differently for similar work. Although the EPA was passed in 1963, it was debated in workplaces and courtrooms for decades thereafter. In this Senate hearing testimony, union leader Murray Plopper argued that the "race against the Communist bloc of nations" demanded an end to gender discrimination. Plopper used specific examples of retail clerks' working conditions and earnings to argue for passage of the law. He also noted that "women work because they must" and challenged the provisions of the law that would exempt small stores.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Empfehlungen durch das nationale Krieg-Arbeit 
Brett während des Zweiten Weltkrieges, die männlichen und weiblichen
Arbeiter zu zahlen gleiche Löhne erbrachten wenige Änderungen im 
Geschlechtlohnabstand. Frauen fuhren fort, weniger Geld für 
vergleichbare Arbeit zu empfangen, und in die sechziger Jahre 
wünschen Sie ADS gekennzeichnete Jobs als "Mann" oder "Frau" mit den 
resultierenden Gehalt Unterschieden, die auf Geschlecht basieren. 
Die gleiche Bezahlung Tat (EPA) bildete es ungültig, Männer 
und Frauen für ähnliche Arbeit anders als zu zahlen. Obgleich 
das EPA 1963 geführt wurde, wurde es in den Arbeitsplätzen und in 
den Gerichtssälen für Dekaden danach debattiert. In diesem 
Senathörfähigkeit Zeugnis argumentierte Anschlußführer Murray 
Plopper, daß das "Rennen gegen den kommunistischen Block von 
Nationen" ein Ende zur Geschlechtunterscheidung verlangte. 
Plopper verwendete spezifische Beispiele der Arbeitsbedingungen 
und des Einkommens der Kleinsekretärinnen, um für Durchgang des 
Gesetzes zu argumentieren. Er beachtete auch, daß "Frauen 
arbeiten, weil sie" müssen und die Bestimmungen des Gesetzes 
herausforderten, das kleine Speicher befreien würde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les recommandations par l'office national de 
travail de guerre pendant la deuxième guerre mondiale de payer les 
ouvriers de sexe masculin et féminins les salaires égaux ont 
rapporté peu de changements de l'écart salarial de genre. Les 
femmes ont continué à recevoir moins d'argent pour le travail 
comparable, et dans les années 60 voulez les travaux caractérisés 
par ADS en tant que le "mâle" ou "femelle" avec des différences 
résultantes de salaire basées sur le genre. La Loi d'égalité
de salaires (EPA) l'a rendu illégal pour payer des hommes et des 
femmes différemment le travail semblable. Bien que l'EPA ait 
été passé en 1963, il a été discuté dans les lieux de travail et
les auditoires de tribunal pendant des décennies ensuite. Dans 
ce témoignage d'audition de sénat, le Chef Murray Plopper des 
syndicats a argué du fait que la "course contre le bloc communiste 
des nations" a exigé une extrémité à la discrimination de genre. 
Plopper a employé des exemples spécifiques des conditions et 
des revenus du travail des vendeurs au détail pour plaider pour le 
passage de la loi. Il a également noté que les "femmes 
travaillent parce qu'elles doivent" et ont défié les dispositions de
la loi qui exempterait de petites mémoires.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As recomendações pela placa nacional do trabalho
da guerra durante a segunda guerra mundial pagar os trabalhadores 
masculinos e fêmeas salários iguais renderam poucas mudanças na 
abertura de salário do gender. As mulheres continuaram a 
receber menos dinheiro para o trabalho comparável, e nos 1960s queira
trabalhos caracterizados ads como o "macho" ou a "fêmea" com as 
diferenças resultantes do salário baseadas no gender. O ato do
pagamento igual (EPA) fêz ilegal para pagar diferentemente homens e 
mulheres pelo trabalho similar. Embora o EPA fosse passado em 
1963, foi debatido nos workplaces e nos courtrooms por décadas depois
disso. Neste testimony do hearing do senate, o líder Murray 
Plopper da união discutiu que a "raça de encontro ao bloc comunista 
das nações" exijiu uma extremidade à discriminação do gender. 
Plopper usou exemplos específicos de condições e de salário 
de funcionamento de caixeiros de varejo discutir para a passagem da 
lei. Anotou também que as "mulheres trabalham porque devem" e 
desafiaram as provisões da lei que exempt lojas pequenas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le raccomandazioni dal Bordo Di lavoro di 
guerra nazionale durante la seconda guerra mondiale pagare gli operai 
maschii e femminili stipendi uguali hanno reso pochi cambiamenti nello
spacco di stipendio di genere. Le donne hanno continuato a 
ricevere meno soldi per lavoro paragonabile e negli anni 60 desideri i
lavori caratterizzati ads come "il maschio" o "femmina" con le 
differenze risultanti di stipendio basate sul genere. La Legge 
di parità salariale (EPA) lo ha reso illegale per pagare diversamente
gli uomini e le donne lavoro simile. Anche se il EPA è stato 
passato in 1963, è stato dibattuto da allora in poi in posti di 
lavoro ed in aule di tribunale per le decadi. In questa testimonianza 
di udienza del senato, il capo Murray Plopper del sindacato ha 
sostenuto che "la corsa contro il blocco comunista delle nazioni" ha 
richiesto un'estremità a distinzione di genere. Plopper ha 
usato gli esempi specifici delle condizioni di lavoro e dei guadagni 
degli impiegati al minuto per parlare a favore del passaggio della 
legge. Egualmente ha notato che "le donne lavorano perché 
devono" ed hanno sfidato le disposizioni della legge che esenterebbe i
piccoli depositi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι συστάσεις από το εθνικό συμβούλιο πολεμικής 
εργασίας κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ για να 
πληρώσουν στους άνδρες και γυναίκες εργαζομένους τις ίσες 
αμοιβές παρήγαγαν λίγες αλλαγές στο χάσμα αμοιβών γένους. 
Οι γυναίκες συνέχισαν να λαμβάνουν τα λιγότερα χρήματα για 
τη συγκρίσιμη εργασία, και στη δεκαετία του '60 θελήστε 
χαρακτηρισμένες τις αγγελίες εργασίες ως "αρσενικό" ή "θηλυκό" 
με τις προκύπτουσες διαφορές μισθών βασισμένες στο γένος. Ο
νόμος ίσης αμοιβής (EPA) το κατέστησε παράνομο να πληρώσει 
τους άνδρες και τις γυναίκες διαφορετικά για την παρόμοια 
εργασία. Αν και το EPA πέρασαν το 1963, συζητήθηκε 
στους εργασιακούς χώρους και τα δικαστήρια για δεκαετίες έκτοτε. 
Σε αυτήν την κατάθεση ακρόασης Συγκλήτου, ο ηγέτης 
Murray Plopper ένωσης υποστήριξε ότι η "φυλή ενάντια στην 
κομμουνιστική ομάδα των εθνών" απαίτησε ένα τέλος στη διάκριση 
γένους. Το Plopper χρησιμοποίησε τα συγκεκριμένα 
παραδείγματα των συνθηκών εργασίας των λιανικών υπαλλήλων και των
αποδοχών για να υποστηρίξει τη μετάβαση του νόμου. Επίσης 
σημείωσε ότι "οι γυναίκες εργάζονται επειδή πρέπει" και 
προκάλεσαν τις διατάξεις του νόμου που θα απάλλασσε τα μικρά 
καταστήματα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las recomendaciones por la tarjeta nacional del 
trabajo de la guerra durante la Segunda Guerra Mundial de pagar a 
trabajadores masculinos y femeninos los salarios iguales rindieron 
pocos cambios en el boquete de salario del género. Las mujeres 
continuaron recibiendo menos dinero para el trabajo comparable, y en 
los años 60 desee los trabajos caracterizados ads como "varón" o 
"hembra" con las diferencias del sueldo que resultan basadas en 
género. El acto de la igualdad de salario (EPA) hizo ilegal 
pagar hombres y a mujeres diferentemente trabajo similar. Aunque
el EPA fue pasado en 1963, fue discutido en lugares de trabajo y 
salas de tribunal por décadas después de eso. En este testimonio de 
la audiencia del senado, el arranque de cinta Murray Plopper de la 
unión discutió que la "raza contra el bloque comunista de naciones" 
exigiera un extremo a la discriminación del género. Plopper 
utilizó ejemplos específicos de las condiciones y de las ganancias 
de trabajo de los vendedores al por menor para discutir para el paso 
de la ley. Él también observó que las "mujeres trabajan 
porque deben" y desafiaron las provisiones de la ley que eximiría 
almacenes pequeños.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087284</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107201</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-condition-we-can-ill-afford-debating-the-equal-pay-act-of-1963</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
