<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106370</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106370</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201648</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Extreme Global Makeover</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Extreme Globale Umarbeitung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Restauration Globale Extrême</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Makeover Global Extremo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Makeover Globale Estremo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ακραίο σφαιρικό Makeover</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Makeover Global Extremo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Modernization is an important issue in the New York State Global History and Geography curriculum. Students are expected to understand how modernization may impact such areas as society, politics, the economy, and the environment. In the Global History and Geography curriculum, a study of historical examples of modernization includes examples of attempts to transform society, such as the Meiji Restoration or Kemal Ataturk. In this lesson, two PBS WIDE ANGLE documentaries -- "To Have and Have Not" (2002) and "1-800-INDIA" (2005) -- will enable students to examine the effects of modernization on two Asian countries: China and India.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Modernisierung ist eine wichtige Ausgabe im Staat-
New-Yorkglobalen Geschichte und Geographielehrplan. 
Kursteilnehmer werden erwartet, zu verstehen, wie Modernisierung
solche Bereiche wie Gesellschaft, Politiken, die Wirtschaft und die 
Umgebung auswirken kann. Im globalen Geschichte und 
Geographielehrplan schließt eine Studie der historischen Beispiele 
der Modernisierung Beispiele von Versuchen, Gesellschaft, wie die 
Meiji Wiederherstellung oder das Kemal Ataturk umzuwandeln ein. 
In dieser Lektion aktivieren zwei PBS Weitwinkeldokumentarfilme 
-- "haben und haben nicht" (2002) und "1-800-INDIA" (2005) -- 
Kursteilnehmer, die Effekte der Modernisierung auf zwei asiatischen 
Ländern zu überprüfen: China und Indien.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La modernisation est une question importante dans 
le programme d'études global d'histoire et de géographie de l'état 
de New-York. On s'attend à ce que des étudiants comprennent 
comment la modernisation peut effectuer des zones telles que la 
société, la politique, l'économie, et l'environnement. Dans 
le programme d'études global d'histoire et de géographie, une étude
des exemples historiques de modernisation inclut des exemples des 
tentatives de transformer la société, telle que la restauration ou 
le Kemal Ataturk de Meiji. Dans cette leçon, deux documentaires
GRANDS-ANGULAIRES de PBS -- "pour avoir et Démuni" (2002) et 
"1-800-INDIA" (2005) -- permettront à des étudiants d'examiner les 
effets de la modernisation sur deux pays asiatiques : La Chine 
et l'Inde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O modernization é uma edição importante no 
curriculum global do history e da geografia do estado de New York. 
Os estudantes esperam-se compreender como o modernization pode 
impactar áreas como a sociedade, a política, a economia, e o 
ambiente. No curriculum global do history e da geografia, um 
estudo de exemplos históricos do modernization inclui exemplos das 
tentativas de transformar a sociedade, tal como a restauração de 
Meiji ou o Kemal Ataturk. Nesta lição, dois documentaries 
LARGOS do ÂNGULO de PBS -- "para ter e ter não" (2002) e 
"1-800-INDIA" (2005) -- permitirão estudantes de examinar os efeitos 
do modernization em dois países asian: China e India.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'ammodernamento è un'edizione importante a New 
York Dichiara il programma di studi globale di geografia e di 
storia. Gli allievi si pensano che capiscano come 
l'ammodernamento può avere effetto su tali zone come la società, le 
politiche, l'economia e l'ambiente. Nel programma di studi 
globale di geografia e di storia, uno studio sugli esempi storici di 
ammodernamento include gli esempi dei tentativi di trasformare la 
società, quali il ripristino di Meiji o il Kemal Ataturk. In 
questa lezione, due documentaries GRANDANGOLARI di PBS -- "avere ed 
avere non" (2002) e "1-800-INDIA" (2005) -- permetteranno agli allievi
di esaminare gli effetti di ammodernamento su due paesi asiatici: 
La Cina e l'India.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο εκσυγχρονισμός είναι ένα σημαντικό ζήτημα στο 
κρατικών σφαιρικό ιστορίας και γεωγραφίας της Νέας Υόρκης 
πρόγραμμα σπουδών. Οι σπουδαστές αναμένονται για να 
καταλάβουν πώς ο εκσυγχρονισμός μπορεί να επηρεάσει τέτοιες 
περιοχές όπως την κοινωνία, την πολιτική, την οικονομία, και το 
περιβάλλον. Στο σφαιρικό πρόγραμμα σπουδών ιστορίας και 
γεωγραφίας, μια μελέτη των ιστορικών παραδειγμάτων του 
εκσυγχρονισμού περιλαμβάνει τα παραδείγματα των προσπαθειών να 
μετασχηματιστεί η κοινωνία, όπως η αποκατάσταση Meiji ή το 
Kemal Ataturk. Σε αυτό το μάθημα, δύο ντοκιμαντέρ 
PBS WIDE.ANGLE -- "για να έχουν και να έχει όχι" (2002) 
και "την 1-800-ΙΝΔΊΑ" (2005) -- θα επιτρέψουν στους σπουδαστές 
για να εξετάσουν τα αποτελέσματα του εκσυγχρονισμού σε δύο 
ασιατικές χώρες: Κίνα και Ινδία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La modernización es una edición importante en el
plan de estudios global de la historia y de la geografía del estado 
de Nueva York. Se espera que los estudiantes entiendan cómo la 
modernización puede afectar las áreas tales como sociedad, 
políticas, la economía, y el ambiente. En el plan de estudios 
global de la historia y de la geografía, un estudio de ejemplos 
históricos de la modernización incluye ejemplos de tentativas de 
transformar a sociedad, tal como la restauración o el Kemal Ataturk 
de Meiji. En esta lección, dos documentaries GRANANGULARES de 
PBS -- "tener y tener no" (2002) y "1-800-INDIA" (2005) -- permitirán
a estudiantes examinar los efectos de la modernización en dos países
asiáticos: China y la India.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:YOLANDA BETANCES
FN:YOLANDA BETANCES
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201648</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106370</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/extreme-global-makeover</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
