<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104200</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104200</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085237</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Chinese Exclusion Act</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Chinesische Ausschluss-Tat</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Acte Chinois d'Exclusion</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ato Chinês Da Exclusão</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Legge Cinese Di Esclusione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κινεζικός νόμος αποκλεισμού</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Acto Chino De la Exclusión</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Starting with the Gold Rush, Chinese migrated to California and other regions of the United States in search of work. As several photographs show, many Chinese found work in the gold mines and on the railroads. They accepted $32.50 a month to work on the Union Pacific in Wyoming in 1870 for the same job that paid white workers $52 a month. This led to deep resentment by the whites, who felt the Chinese were competing unfairly for jobs. White labor unions blamed the Chinese for lower wages and lack of jobs, and anti-Chinese feelings grew. The cartoon "You Know How It Is Yourself" expresses this sentiment. Several political cartoons in this topic are graphic representations of racism and conflicts between whites and Chinese. "Won't They Remain Here in Spite of the New Constitution?" shows a demonized figure of political corruption protecting Chinese cheap labor, dirty politicians, capital, and financiers. "The Tables Turned" shows Denis Kearney (head of the Workingman's Party of California, a union that had criticized Chinese laborers) in jail, being taunted by Chinese men. In 1880, President Rutherford B. Hayes signed the Chinese Exclusion Treaty, which placed strict limitations on the number of Chinese allowed to enter the United States and the number allowed to become naturalized citizens. In 1882, Congress passed the Chinese Exclusion Act, which prohibited immigration from China (The Act was not repealed until 1943). The two-part cartoon from the July-December 1882 issue of The Wasp reflects how some citizens saw the situation. After the Act was passed, anti-Chinese violence increased. One illustration depicts the Rock Springs Massacre of 1885, a Wyoming race riot in which 28 Chinese were killed by British and Swedish miners. The "Certificate of Residence" document illustrates that Chinese individuals were required to prove their residence in the United States prior to the passage of the Exclusion Act. The poster offering a reward for Wong Yuk, a Chinese man, makes it clear that the United States was actively deporting Chinese. Despite discrimination and prejudice, this first wave of immigrants established thriving communities. Photographs taken in San Francisco's Chinatown show prosperous businesses, such as the "Chinese Butcher and Grocery Shop." Wealthy merchants formed active business associations, represented by the image "Officers of the Chinese Six Companies." The Chinese celebrated their heritage by holding cultural festivals, as shown in the photograph from 1896. The photographs "Children of High Class," "Golden Gate Park," and "Chinese Passengers on Ferry" are evidence that some Chinese adopted Western-style clothing while others wore more traditional attire.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Beginnend mit den Goldanstürmen zog Chinese zu 
Kalifornien und zu anderen Regionen der Vereinigten Staaten auf der 
Suche nach Arbeit fort. Da einige Fotographien darstellen, 
fanden viele Chinesen Arbeit in den Goldminen und über die 
Eisenbahnen. Sie nahmen $32.50 ein Monat an, um auf dem 
Anschluß Pazifik in Wyoming 1870 für den gleichen Job zu arbeiten, 
der weißen Arbeitern $52 einen Monat zahlte. Dieses führte zu 
tiefen Groll durch das Weiß, das glaubte, daß die Chinesen unfairly 
für Jobs konkurrierten. Weiße Arbeiterverbände tadelten die 
Chinesen für niedrigere Löhne und Mangel an Jobs, und 
Anti-Chinesische Gefühle wuchsen. Die Karikatur "Sie können, 
sie sich" ausdrückt dieses Gefühl ist. Einige politische 
Karikaturen in diesem Thema sind graphische Darstellungen von 
Rassismus und von $überschneidungen zwischen Weiß und Chinesen. 
"nicht bleiben sie hier trotz der neuen Beschaffenheit?" 
stellt dar, daß a die Abbildung der politischen Korruption 
chinesische preiswerte Arbeit, schmutzige Politiker, Kapital und 
Finanziere schützend demonized. "die Tabellen drehten" 
Erscheinen Denis Kearney (Kopf der Partei des Workingmans von 
Kalifornien, ein Anschluß, der chinesische Arbeiter kritisiert 
hatte), im Gefängnis und waren taunted durch Chinese Männer. 
1880 unterzeichnete Präsident Rutherford B. Hayes den 
chinesischen Ausschluss-Vertrag, der strenge Beschränkungen auf die 
Zahl dem Chinesen plazierte, der die Vereinigten Staaten betreten 
gelassen wurde und die Zahl, die werden lassen wurde, Bürger 
einbürgerte. 1882 führte Kongreß die chinesische 
Ausschluss-Tat, die Immigration von China verbot (die Tat wurde nicht 
bis 1943 widerrufen). Die zweiteilige Karikatur von der 
Juli-Dezember 1882 Ausgabe der Wespe reflektiert, wie einige Bürger 
die Situation sahen. Nachdem die Tat geführt wurde, die 
Anti-Chinesische Gewalttätigkeit erhöht. Eine Abbildung stellt
das Felsen-Frühlinge Blutbad von 1885, einen Wyoming Rennenaufstand 
bildlich dar, in dem 28 Chinesen von British und von den schwedischen 
Bergmännern beendet wurden. Das "Bescheinigung des Wohnsitzes" 
Dokument veranschaulicht, daß chinesische Einzelpersonen benoetigt 
wurden, ihren Wohnsitz in den Vereinigten Staaten vor dem Durchgang 
der Ausschluss-Tat zu prüfen. Das Plakat, das eine Belohnung 
für Wong Yuk, ein chinesischer Mann anbietet, bildet es freien Raum, 
daß die Vereinigten Staaten aktiv Chinesen verbannten. Trotz 
der Unterscheidung und des Vorurteils stellte diese erste Welle der 
Immigranten emporkommende Gemeinschaften her. Die Fotographien, 
die in den wohlhabenden Geschäften des Erscheinens Chinatown San 
Franciscos, wie dem "chinesischen Metzger und dem 
Lebensmittelgeschäft genommen werden, kaufen." Wohlhabende 
Kaufleute bildeten die aktiven Wirtschaftsverbände, dargestellt durch
das Bild "Offiziere der chinesischen sechs Firmen." Der Chinese 
feierte ihr Erbe, indem er kulturelle Festivals anhielt, wie in der 
Fotographie von 1896 gezeigt. Die Fotographien "Kinder der hohen
Kategorie," "Golden Gate Park," und "chinesische Passagiere auf 
Fähre" sind Beweis diese etwas chinesische angenommene Westlich-Art 
Kleidung, während andere traditionellere Kleidung trugen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Commençant par les précipitations d'or, le 
Chinois a passé à la Californie et à d'autres régions des 
Etats-Unis à la recherche du travail. Car plusieurs 
photographies montrent, beaucoup de Chinois ont trouvé le travail 
dans les mines d'or et sur les chemins de fer. Ils ont reçu 
$32.50 par mois pour travailler à l'union Pacifique au Wyoming en 
1870 pour le même travail qui a payé aux ouvriers blancs $52 un 
mois. Ceci a mené au ressentiment profond par les blancs, qui 
ont jugé que les Chinois concurrençaient injustement pour les 
travaux. Les syndicats blancs ont blâmé les Chinois par 
salaires et manque inférieurs des travaux, et les sentiments 
anti-Chinois se sont développés. Le dessin animé "vous savez 
il est vous-même" exprime ce sentiment. Plusieurs dessins 
animés politiques dans ce sujet sont les représentations graphiques 
du racisme et des conflits entre les blancs et le Chinois. "ils 
ne resteront pas ici malgré la nouvelle constitution?" montre 
qu'a demonized la figure de la corruption politique protégeant la 
main d'oeuvre à prix réduit chinoise, les politiciens modifiés, le 
capital, et les financiers. "les Tableaux ont tourné" les 
expositions Denis Kearney (tête de la partie de l'ouvrier de la 
Californie, une union qui avait critiqué les travailleurs chinois) en
prison, étant taunted par des hommes de Chinese. En 1880, le 
Président Rutherford B. Hayes a signé le Traité chinois 
d'exclusion, qui a placé des limitations strictes sur le nombre de 
chinois permis d'entrer dans les Etats-Unis et le nombre permis de 
devenir a naturalisé des citoyens. En 1882, le congrès a 
passé l'acte chinois d'exclusion, qui a interdit l'immigration de 
Chine (la Loi n'a pas été abrogée jusqu'en 1943). Le dessin 
animé en deux parties de l'issue de Juillet-Décembre 1882 de la 
guêpe reflète comment quelques citoyens ont vu la situation. 
Après que l'acte ait été passé, violence anti-Chinoise 
accrue. Une illustration dépeint le Massacre de ressorts de 
roche de 1885, une émeute de course du Wyoming dans laquelle 28 
Chinois ont été détruits par British et mineurs suédois. Le 
"certificat le document de résidence" illustre que des individus 
chinois ont été requis de prouver leur résidence aux Etats-Unis 
avant le passage de l'acte d'exclusion. L'affiche offrant une 
récompense pour Wong Yuk, un homme chinois, indique clairement que 
les Etats-Unis expulsaient activement des Chinois. En dépit de 
la discrimination et du préjudice, cette première vague des 
immigrés a établi les communautés prospèrees. Les 
photographies prises dans les show business prospères de Chinatown de
San Francisco, tels que "le boucher et l'épicerie chinois font des 
emplettes." Les négociants riches ont formé des associations 
de gens d'affaires actives, représentées par l'image "officiers des 
six compagnies chinoises." Le Chinois a célébré leur 
héritage en tenant des festivals culturels, comme montré dans la 
photographie de 1896. Les photographies "enfants de la classe 
élevée," "Golden Gate Park," et "passagers chinois sur le bac" sont 
évidence du cet habillement adopté chinois d'Occidental-modèle 
tandis que d'autres portaient un vêtement plus traditionnel.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Começando com as arremetidas do ouro, o chinês 
migrou a Califórnia e a outras regiões dos estados unidos na busca 
do trabalho. Porque diversas fotografias mostram, muitos 
chineses encontraram o trabalho nas minas de ouro e nas estradas de 
ferro. Aceitaram $32.50 um o mês para trabalhar na união o 
Pacífico em Wyoming em 1870 para o mesmo trabalho que pagou aos 
trabalhadores brancos $52 um mês. Isto conduziu ao resentment 
profundo pelos brancos, que sentiram que os chineses estavam 
competindo unfairly para trabalhos. As uniões labor brancas 
responsabilizaram os chineses por uns salários e por uma falta mais 
baixos dos trabalhos, e os sentimentos anti-Chineses cresceram. 
O cartoon "você sabe é você mesmo" expressa este sentiment. 
Diversos cartoons políticos neste tópico são 
respresentações gráficas do racism e dos conflitos entre brancos e 
chinês. "não remanescerão aqui apesar do constitution novo?" 
mostra que a demonized a figura do corruption político que 
protege o trabalho barato chinês, políticos sujos, capital, e 
financeiros. "as tabelas giraram" as mostras Denis Kearney 
(cabeça do partido de Califórnia, uma união do workingman que 
criticasse laborers chineses) na cadeia, sendo taunted por homens de 
Chinês. Em 1880, o presidente Rutherford B. Hayes assinou o 
tratado chinês da exclusão, que colocou limitações estritas no 
número do chinês permitido incorporar os estados unidos e o número 
permitido se tornar naturalizou cidadãos. Em 1882, o congress 
passou o ato chinês da exclusão, que proibiu o immigration de China 
(o ato não repealed até 1943). O cartoon two-part da 
introdução de Julho-Dezembro 1882 da vespa reflete como alguns 
cidadãos viram a situação. Depois que o ato foi passado, 
violência anti-Chinesa aumentada. Uma ilustração descreve o 
massacre de 1885, um motim das molas da rocha da raça de Wyoming em 
que 28 chineses foram matados por Britânico e por mineiros suecos. 
O "certificado o original da residência" ilustra que os 
indivíduos chineses estiveram requeridos provar sua residência nos 
estados unidos antes da passagem do ato da exclusão. O poster 
que oferece uma recompensa para Wong Yuk, um homem chinês, faz-lhe o 
espaço livre que os estados unidos deporting ativamente chineses. 
Apesar da discriminação e do preconceito, esta primeira onda 
dos immigrants estabeleceu comunidades prosperando. As 
fotografias feitas exame em negócios prósperos da mostra de 
Chinatown do San Francisco, tais como "o carniceiro e o mantimento 
chineses compram." Os comerciantes ricos deram forma às 
associações de negócio ativas, representadas pela imagem "oficiais 
das seis companhias chinesas." O chinês comemorou seu heritage 
prendendo festivals cultural, como mostrado na fotografia de 1896. 
As fotografias "crianças da classe elevada," "Golden Gate 
Park," e "passageiros chineses na balsa" são evidência essa alguma 
roupa adotada chinesa do Ocidental-estilo quando outras desgastaram um
attire mais tradicional.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Cominciando dagli sbalzi dell'oro, il cinese 
ha migrato alla California ed altre regioni del unito Dichiara 
alla ricerca di lavoro. Poichè parecchie fotografie mostrano, 
molto il cinese ha trovato il lavoro nelle miniere di oro e sulle
ferrovie. Hanno accettato $32.50 un il mese per lavorare 
all'unione il Pacifico nel Wyoming in 1870 per lo stesso lavoro che ha
pagato ad operai bianchi $52 un mese. Ciò ha condotto a rancore
profondo dai bianchi, che hanno ritenuto che il cinese stava 
competendo unfairly per i lavori. I sindacati di lavoro bianchi
hanno incolpato del cinese gli stipendi e la mancanza più bassi 
di lavori e le sensibilità di anti-cinese si sono sviluppate. 
Il fumetto "sapete è voi stessi" esprime questo sentimento. 
Parecchi fumetti politici in questo soggetto sono 
rappresentazioni grafiche del razzismo e dei conflitti fra i bianchi 
ed il cinese. "non rimarranno qui nonostante la nuova 
costituzione?" mostra che la a demonized la figura della 
corruzione politica che protegge il lavoro poco costoso 
cinese, i politici sporchi, il capitale ed i finanzieri. "le
Tabelle hanno girato" le esposizioni Denis Kearney (testa del partito 
della California, un'unione del workingman che aveva criticato i 
lavoratori cinesi) in prigione, essendo taunted dall'uomo 
cinese. In 1880, il presidente Rutherford B. Hayes ha 
firmato il Trattato cinese di esclusione, che ha disposto le 
limitazioni rigorose sul numero di cinese permesso entrare nel 
unito Dichiara ed il numero permesso stare bene ai cittadini 
naturalizzati. In 1882, il congresso ha passato la Legge 
cinese di esclusione, che ha proibito l'immigrazione dalla Cina 
(la Legge non è stata abrogata fino al 1943). Il fumetto in due
parti dall'emissione di Luglio-Dicembre 1882 della vespa riflette come
alcuni cittadini hanno visto la situazione. Dopo che la Legge 
sia passata, violenza di anti-cinese aumentata. 
Un'illustrazione descrive il massacre di 1885, un tumulto delle 
molle della roccia della corsa del Wyoming in cui il cinese 28 
è stato ucciso da British e dai minatori svedesi. "il 
certificato il documento della residenza" illustra che gli individui 
cinesi sono stati tenuti a risultare che la loro residenza in 
unito Dichiara prima del passaggio della Legge di esclusione. 
Il manifesto che offre una ricompensa per Wong Yuk, un uomo 
cinese, indica chiaramente che unito Dichiara attivamente
deporting il cinese. Malgrado distinzione ed il 
pregiudizio, questa prima onda degli immigranti ha stabilito le 
Comunità prospere. Le fotografie prese nei commerci prosperosi 
di esposizione di Chinatown de San Francisco, quali "il macellaio e la
drogheria cinesi acquistano." I commercianti ricchi hanno 
formato le associazioni attive di affari, rappresentate dall'immagine 
"ufficiali delle sei aziende cinesi." Il cinese ha 
celebrato la loro eredità dai festival culturali della 
tenuta, come indicato nella fotografia da 1896. Le 
fotografie "bambini di alto codice categoria," "Golden Gate Park," e 
"passeggeri cinesi sul traghetto" sono prova che i certi vestiti 
adottati cinesi di Occidentale-stile mentre altre hanno portato 
l'abbigliamento più tradizionale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αρχίζοντας από τη χρυσή βιασύνη, τα κινέζικα 
μετανάστευσαν σε Καλιφόρνια και άλλες περιοχή των Ηνωμένων 
Πολιτειών σε αναζήτηση της εργασίας. Όπως διάφορες 
φωτογραφίες εμφανίζουν, πολλοί Κινέζοι βρήκαν την εργασία στα 
χρυσά ορυχεία και για τους σιδηροδρόμους. Αποδέχθηκαν 
$32.50 μηνιαίως για να λειτουργήσουν στην ένωση Ειρηνικός στο 
Wyoming το 1870 για την ίδια εργασία που πλήρωσε τους 
λευκούς εργαζομένους $52 μηνιαίως. Αυτό οδήγησε στη 
βαθιά δυσαρέσκεια από τα λευκά, τα οποία αισθάνθηκαν ότι οι 
Κινέζοι ανταγωνίζονταν άδικα για τις εργασίες. Τα λευκά 
εργατικά συνδικάτα κατηγόρησαν τους Κινέζους για τις χαμηλότερες 
αμοιβές και την έλλειψη εργασιών, και τα αντι-κινεζικά 
συναισθήματα αυξήθηκαν. Τα κινούμενα σχέδια "εσείς ξέρουν 
πώς είναι οι ίδιοι" εκφράζουν αυτό το συναίσθημα. Διάφορα
πολιτικά κινούμενα σχέδια σε αυτό το θέμα είναι γραφικές 
αντιπροσωπεύσεις του ρατσισμού και των συγκρούσεων μεταξύ των 
λευκών και κινέζικων. "Παραμένουν εδώ παρά το νέο 
σύνταγμα;" εμφανίζει ότι το α ο αριθμός της πολιτικής 
δωροδοκίας που προστατεύει την κινεζική φτηνή εργασία, τους 
βρώμικους πολιτικούς, το κεφάλαιο, και τους χρηματοδότες. 
"Τους πίνακες που γυρίζουν" παρουσιάζουν Denis Kearney 
(προϊστάμενος του συμβαλλόμενου μέρους του Workingman 
Καλιφόρνιας, μια ένωση που είχε επικρίνει τα κινεζικά 
laborers) στη φυλακή, όντας από τα κινεζικά άτομα. Το 
1880, ο Πρόεδρος Rutherford B. Hayes υπέγραψε την 
κινεζική Συνθήκη αποκλεισμού, η οποία τοποθέτησε τους ακριβείς 
περιορισμούς αριθμός των κινέζικων που επιτράπηκε για να μπεί 
στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες και ο αριθμός επέτρεψε να γίνει 
πολιτογραφημένοι πολίτες. Το 1882, το συνέδριο πέρασε τον
κινεζικό νόμο αποκλεισμού, ο οποίος απαγόρευσε τη μετανάστευση 
από την Κίνα (ο νόμος δεν ακυρώθηκε έως το 1943). Τα 
διμερή κινούμενα σχέδια από τονΔεκέμβριο του 1882 ζήτημα της 
σφήκας απεικονίζουν πώς μερικοί πολίτες εβλέίδαν την 
κατάσταση. Αφότου πέρασαν το νόμο, αντι-κινεζική βία 
αυξανόμενη. Μια απεικόνιση απεικονίζει τη σφαγή ανοίξεων 
βράχου 1885, μια φυλετική ταραχή του Wyoming στην οποία 
28 Κινέζος σκοτώθηκε από τους βρετανικούς και σουηδικούς 
ανθρακωρύχους. Το έγγραφο "πιστοποιητικών της κατοικίασ" 
διευκρινίζει ότι τα κινεζικά άτομα έπρεπε για να αποδείξουν την 
κατοικία τους στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες πριν από μετάβαση του 
νόμου αποκλεισμού. Η αφίσα που προσφέρει ανταμοιβή για 
Wong Yuk, ένα κινεζικό άτομο, το καθιστά σαφές ότι οι 
Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες απήλαυναν ενεργά τα κινέζικα. Παρά τη 
διάκριση και την προκατάληψη, αυτό το πρώτο κύμα των μεταναστών 
ίδρυσε τις αναπτυγμένος κοινότητες. Οι φωτογραφίες που 
λαμβάνονται σε Chinatown του Σαν Φρανσίσκο εμφανίζουν 
ακμάζουσες επιχειρήσεις, όπως το "κινεζικό κατάστημα χασάπηδων 
και παντοπωλείων." Οι πλούσιοι έμποροι διαμόρφωσαν τις 
ενεργές επιχειρησιακές ενώσεις, που αντιπροσωπεύθηκαν από την 
εικόνα "ανώτεροι υπάλληλοι των κινεζικών έξι επιχειρήσεων." 
Οι Κινέζοι γιόρτασαν την κληρονομιά τους με να οργανώσουν τα
πολιτιστικά φεστιβάλ, όπως φαίνεται στη φωτογραφία από 1896. 
Οι φωτογραφίες "παιδιά της υψηλής κλάσης," "χρυσό πάρκο 
πυλών," και "κινεζικοί επιβάτες στο πορθμείο" είναι στοιχεία 
ότι κάποιος κινεζικός υιοθετημένος ιματισμός δυτικός-ύφους ενώ
άλλοι φόρεσαν την παραδοσιακότερη ενδυμασία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Comenzando con las acometidas del oro, el chino 
emigró a California y a otras regiones de los Estados Unidos en la 
búsqueda del trabajo. Pues varias fotografías muestran, muchos
chinos encontraron el trabajo en las minas de oro y sobre los 
ferrocarriles. Validaron $32.50 por mes para trabajar en la 
unión el Pacífico en Wyoming en 1870 para el mismo trabajo que pagó
a trabajadores blancos $52 un mes. Esto condujo al resentimiento
profundo por los blancos, que se sentían que los chinos competían 
unfairly para los trabajos. Los sindicatos blancos culparon a 
chinos por salarios y una carencia más bajos de trabajos, y las 
sensaciones contra-Chinas crecieron. La historieta "usted sabe 
es usted mismo" expresa este sentimiento. Varias historietas 
políticas en este asunto son representaciones gráficas del racismo y
de los conflictos entre los blancos y el chino. "no 
permanecerán aquí a pesar de la nueva constitución?" muestra 
que a demonized la figura de la corrupción política que protegía el
trabajo barato chino, políticos sucios, el capital, y a financieros. 
"los vectores dieron vuelta" a las demostraciones Denis Kearney 
(jefe del partido de California, una unión del workingman que había 
criticado a trabajadores chinos) en cárcel, siendo taunted por los 
hombres chinese. En 1880, presidente Rutherford B. Hayes firmó 
el tratado chino de la exclusión, que puso limitaciones terminantes 
en el número del chino permitido entrar en los Estados Unidos y el 
número permitido convertirse naturalizó a ciudadanos. En 1882,
el congreso pasó el acto chino de la exclusión, que prohibió la 
inmigración de China (el acto no fue abrogado hasta 1943). La 
historieta bipartita de la aplicación de Julio-Diciembre 1882 la 
avispa refleja cómo algunos ciudadanos vieron la situación. 
Después de que el acto fuera pasado, violencia contra-China 
creciente. Una ilustración representa la Masacre de 1885, un
alboroto de los resortes de la roca de la raza de Wyoming en el cual a
los mineros suecos mataron a 28 chinos British y. El 
"certificado el documento de la residencia" ilustra que requirieron a 
los individuos chinos probar su residencia en los Estados Unidos antes
del paso del acto de la exclusión. El cartel que ofrece una 
recompensa por Wong Yuk, hombre chino, le hace el claro que los 
Estados Unidos deportaban activamente chino. A pesar de la
discriminación y el prejudicar, esta primera onda de inmigrantes 
estableció a comunidades prósperas. Las fotografías tomadas 
en los negocios prósperos de la demostración de Chinatown de San 
Francisco, tales como el "carnicero y la tienda de comestibles chinos 
hacen compras." Los comerciantes ricos formaron las asociaciones
de negocio activas, representadas por la imagen "oficiales de las seis
compañías chinas." El chino celebró su herencia llevando a 
cabo festivales culturales, según lo mostrado en la fotografía a 
partir de 1896. Las fotografías "niños de la alta clase," 
"Golden Gate Park," y los "pasajeros chinos encendido Balsean"
son evidencia esa un poco de ropa adoptada china del Occidental-estilo
mientras que otras desgastaron un traje más tradicional.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085237</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104200</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/chinese-exclusion-act</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
