<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103627</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103627</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213170</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Whose Fault is it Anyway?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wer Störung ist es irgendwie?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">À qui défaut est il de toute façon ?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">De quem falha é ele de qualquer maneira?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Di chi difetto è comunque esso?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ποιά βλάβη είναι οπωσδήποτε;</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿De quién incidente es él de todos modos?</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This game has students simulate the propagation of S and P waves after an earthquake and use the lag between these to determine where in the simulation the earthquake occurred. Students stand in lines holding hands with those at the ends working as seismometers to record how long it takes P- and S-waves to reach them. On this Starting Point page, users can access information about the exercise's learning goals, context for use, teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment ideas, references and topics covered.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Spiel läßt Kursteilnehmer die Ausbreitung von S 
simulieren und P bewegt nachdem ein Erdbeben wellenartig und benutzt 
den Sträfling zwischen diesen, um festzustellen, wo in der Simulation
das Erdbeben auftrat. Kursteilnehmer stehen in den Zeilen, die 
Hände mit denen an den Enden anhalten, die als seismometers arbeiten,
um zu speichern, wie lang es p nimmt und S-wellenartig bewegt, um sie 
zu erreichen. Auf dieser Ausgangspunktseite können Benutzer auf
Informationen über die erlernenziele der Übung, Kontext für 
Gebrauch-, die Unterrichtenumfaßten anmerkungen und Spitzen, 
Lehrmittel, Einschätzung Ideen, Referenzen und Themen zugreifen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce jeu fait simuler à des étudiants la propagation de S 
et P ondule après qu'un tremblement de terre et emploie le retard 
entre ces derniers pour déterminer où dans la simulation le 
tremblement de terre s'est produit. Les étudiants se tiennent 
dans les lignes tenant des mains avec ceux aux extrémités 
travaillant comme sismomètres pour enregistrer combien de temps il 
prend le p et S-ondule pour les atteindre. À cette page de 
point de départ, les utilisateurs peuvent accéder aux informations 
sur les buts d'étude de l'exercice, contexte pour les extrémités 
d'utilisation, d'enseignement les notes et, le matériel didactique, 
les idées d'évaluation, les références et les sujets couverts.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este jogo manda estudantes simular a propagação de S e P
acena depois que um terremoto e usa a retardação entre estes 
determinar onde na simulação o terremoto ocorreu. Os 
estudantes estão nas linhas que prendem as mãos com as aquelas nas 
extremidades que trabalham como seismometers para gravar quanto tempo 
faz exame do p e S-acena para os alcançar. Nesta página do 
ponto começar, os usuários podem alcançar a informação sobre os 
objetivos de aprendizagem do exercício, contexto para as pontas do 
uso, ensinar as notas e, os materiais de ensino, as idéias da 
avaliação, as referências e os tópicos cobertos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo gioco fa simulare agli allievi la propagazione 
della S e la P fluttua dopo che un terremoto ed usa il ritardo fra 
questi per determinare dove nella simulazione il terremoto si è 
presentato. Gli allievi si levano in piedi nelle righe mani 
della tenuta con quelle alle estremità che lavorano come 
seismometers per registrare quanto tempo prende la p e S-fluttua per 
raggiungerla. A questa pagina del punto di partenza, gli utenti 
possono accedere alle informazioni sugli obiettivi imparanti 
dell'esercitazione, contesto per le punte di istruzione, di uso note 
e, i materiali didattici, le idee di valutazione, i riferimenti ed i 
soggetti coperti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το παιχνίδι έχει τους σπουδαστές να μιμηθούν τη 
διάδοση των κυμάτων του s και π μετά από έναν σεισμό και να 
χρησιμοποιήσουν την καθυστέρηση μεταξύ αυτών για να καθορίσει 
όπου στην προσομοίωση ο σεισμός εμφανίστηκε. Οι σπουδαστές 
στέκονται στις γραμμές που κρατούν τα χέρια με εκείνους στις 
άκρες που λειτουργούν ως σεισμόμετρα για να καταγράψουν πόσο 
καιρό πολύ παίρνει το π - και s-ky'mata για να φθάσει σε τους. 
Σε αυτήν την σελίδα αφετηρίας, οι χρήστες μπορούν να έχουν
πρόσβαση στις πληροφορίες για τους στόχους εκμάθησης της άσκησης,
πλαίσιο για τη χρήση, τις σημειώσεις και τις άκρες διδασκαλίας, 
τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, τις ιδέες αξιολόγησης, τις αναφορές και τα
θέματα που καλύπτονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este juego hace que los estudiantes simulen la 
propagación de S y P agita después de que un terremoto y utiliza el 
retraso entre éstos para determinarse dónde en la simulación el 
terremoto ocurrió. Los estudiantes están parados en las 
líneas que llevan a cabo las manos con ésos en los extremos que 
trabajan como seismometers para registrar cuánto tiempo toma el p y 
S-agita para alcanzarlos. En esta paginación del punto de 
partida, los utilizadores pueden tener acceso a la información sobre 
las metas que aprenden del ejercicio, contexto para las extremidades 
del uso, de la enseñanza las notas y, los materiales didácticos, las
ideas del gravamen, las referencias y los asuntos cubiertos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ERIC MULLER
FN:ERIC MULLER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213170</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103627</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/whose-fault-is-it-anyway</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
