<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107255</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107255</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202594</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A Road Map to Reading</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Straßenkarte zum Messwert</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une carte de route à la lecture</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um mapa de estrada à leitura</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un programma di strada a lettura</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένας οδικός χάρτης στην ανάγνωση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una correspondencia de camino a la lectura</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Students struggle with informational texts and websites. Understanding the structure of these texts is essential to efficient information gathering. The "Road Map" is a pre-reading strategy. Like the road map in your atlas, this mapping activity will help students visualize the layout of the text before they start reading so they will have an idea of where they are going (or where to find the information they are looking for) when they start reading. This lesson will also address active-reading strategies students can use to find information for research in print and electronic sources.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kursteilnehmerkampf mit informatorischen Texten 
und Web site. Die Struktur dieser Texte zu verstehen ist zur 
leistungsfähigen Informationen Versammlung wesentlich. Die 
"Straßenkarte" ist eine Vormesswertstrategie. Wie die 
Straßenkarte in Ihrem Atlas, helfen dieser abbildenaktivität Wille 
Kursteilnehmern, den Plan des Textes sichtbar zu machen, bevor sie 
anfangen zu lesen, also sie eine Idee haben, von der sie gehen (oder 
von wo man nach die Informationen findet, die sie suchen), wenn sie 
anfangen zu lesen. Diese Lektion adressiert auch 
Aktivmesswertstrategien, die Kursteilnehmer verwenden können, um 
Informationen für Forschung im Druck und in den elektronischen 
Quellen zu finden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Lutte d'étudiants avec les textes et les sites 
Web informationnels. L'arrangement la structure de ces textes 
est essentiel au rassemblement efficace de l'information. La 
"carte de route" est une stratégie de pré-lecture. Comme la 
carte de route dans votre atlas, cette volonté traçante d'activité 
aident des étudiants à visualiser la disposition du texte avant 
qu'ils commencent à lire ainsi ils auront une idée d'où ils vont 
(ou d'où trouver l'information qu'ils recherchent) quand ils 
commencent à lire. Cette leçon adressera également des 
stratégies d'actif-lecture que les étudiants peuvent employer pour 
trouver l'information pour la recherche dans la copie et les sources 
électroniques.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esforço dos estudantes com textos e Web site 
informativos. Compreender a estrutura destes textos é essencial
ao recolhimento eficiente da informação. De "o mapa estrada" 
é uma estratégia da pre-leitura. Como o mapa de estrada em seu
atlas, esta vontade traçando da atividade ajuda a estudantes 
visualizar a disposição do texto antes que comecem ler assim que 
terão uma idéia de onde estejam indo (ou de onde encontrar a 
informação que estão procurando) quando começam ler. Esta 
lição dirigir-se-á também a estratégias que da ativo-leitura os 
estudantes podem se usar encontrar a informação para a pesquisa na 
cópia e em fontes eletrônicas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lotta degli allievi con i testi ed i Web site 
informativi. Capire la struttura di questi testi è essenziale 
alla riunione efficiente delle informazioni. "il programma 
di strada" è una strategia della pre-lettura. Come il programma
di strada nel vostro atlante, questa volontà di tracciato di 
attività aiuta gli allievi a prevedere la disposizione del testo 
prima che cominci leggere in modo da avranno un'idea di dove stanno 
andando (o di dove trovare le informazioni che stanno cercando) quando
cominciano leggere. Questa lezione egualmente richiamerà le 
strategie che della attivo-lettura gli allievi possono usare per 
trovare le informazioni per ricerca in stampa e nelle sorgenti 
elettroniche.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι σπουδαστές αγωνίζονται με τα ενημερωτικά κείμενα 
και τους ιστοχώρους. Η κατανόηση της δομής αυτών των 
κειμένων είναι ουσιαστική στην αποδοτική συλλογή πληροφοριών. 
Ο "οδικός χάρτησ" είναι μια στρατηγική προανάγνωσης. 
Όπως τον οδικό χάρτη στον άτλαντά σας, αυτή η 
δραστηριότητα χαρτογράφησης θα βοηθήσει τους σπουδαστές να 
απεικονίσουν το σχεδιάγραμμα του κειμένου προτού να αρχίσουν 
έτσι θα έχουν μια ιδέα όπου πηγαίνουν (ή πού να βρεθούν οι 
πληροφορίες ψάχνουν) πότε αρχίζουν. Αυτό το μάθημα θα 
εξετάσει επίσης την ενεργός-ανάγνωση οι σπουδαστές ότι 
στρατηγικών μπορούν να χρησιμοποιήσουν για να βρούν τις 
πληροφορίες για την έρευνα στην τυπωμένη ύλη και τις ηλεκτρονικές
πηγές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Lucha de los estudiantes con los textos y los Web 
site informativos. Entender la estructura de estos textos es 
esencial para la reunión eficiente de la información. La 
"correspondencia de camino" es una estrategia de la pre-lectura. 
Como la correspondencia de camino en su atlas, esta voluntad de 
la actividad que asocia ayuda a estudiantes a visualizar la 
disposición del texto antes de que comiencen a leer así que tendrán
una idea de donde van (o de donde encontrar la información que están
buscando) cuando comienzan a leer. Esta lección también 
tratará estrategias de la activo-lectura que los estudiantes pueden 
utilizar para encontrar la información para la investigación en la 
impresión y fuentes electrónicas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ELIZABETH HUBBE
FN:ELIZABETH HUBBE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MELISSA THIBAULT
FN:MELISSA THIBAULT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202594</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107255</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/a-road-map-to-reading</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
