<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107191</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107191</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086274</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Believe It Is Because I Am a Poor Indian": Samsom Occom's Life as an Indian Minister</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ich glaube, daß es ist, weil ich ein armer 
Inder" bin: Samsom Occoms Leben als indischer Minister</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"je crois qu'elle est puisque je suis un pauvre 
Indien" : La vie de Samsom Occom en tant que ministre indien</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"eu acredito que é porque eu sou um indian 
deficiente": Vida de Samsom Occom como um ministro indian</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"credo che sia Poiché sono un Povero 
indiano": Vita di Samsom Occom come Ministro indiano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"πιστεύω ότι είναι επειδή είμαι φτωχός Ινδόσ": 
Ζωή Occom Samsom ως ινδικό Υπουργό</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"creo que es porque soy un indio pobre": 
Vida de Samsom Occom como ministro indio</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">By the beginning of the eighteenth century Mohegan Indians had lost vast amounts of their land to the English colonists. They found it hard to continue with their traditional tribal economy; some turned to alcohol for escape and others found an answer in Christianity. Evangelical ministers converted Mohegan Samsom Occom to Christianity during the Great Awakening in the late 1730s and 1740s. He attended the Reverend Eleazer Wheelock's school and trained as a missionary and teacher for his people, first in New London, Connecticut, and then moving to Montauk on Long Island as an ordained Presbyterian minister. Occom composed a short autobiography where he described the difficulties of making a living, his experience as an Indian minister, and his poor treatment at the hands of the religious establishment.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Durch den Anfang von achtzehntem Jahrhundert 
Mohegan hatten die Inder beträchtliche Mengen ihres Landes zu den 
englischen Kolonisten verloren. Sie fanden es hart, mit ihrer 
traditionellen Stammes- Wirtschaft fortzufahren; einige, die zum
Spiritus für Entweichen gedreht wurden und andere fanden eine Antwort
im Christentum. Evangelische Minister wandelten Mohegan Samsom 
Occom in Christentum während des großen Weckens im späten 1730s und
im 1740s um. Er bediente das Reverend Eleazer Wheelocks die 
Schule und bildete als Missionar und Lehrer für seine Leute, zuerst 
in neuem London, in Connecticut und auf Montauk auf Long Island als 
ordinierten presbyterianischen Minister dann in bewegen aus. 
Occom bestand eine kurze Autobiographie, in der er die 
Schwierigkeiten des Bildens eines Lebens, seiner Erfahrung als 
indischer Minister und seiner schlechten Behandlung an den Händen der
frommen Einrichtung beschrieb.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Par le début du dix-huitième Mohegan de siècle 
les Indiens avaient détruit de vastes quantités de leur terre aux 
colons anglais. Ils ont eu du mal à continuer leur économie 
tribale traditionnelle ; certains tournés à l'alcool pour 
l'évasion et d'autres ont trouvé une réponse dans le christianisme.
Les ministres évangéliques ont converti Mohegan Samsom Occom 
en christianisme pendant le grand réveil vers la fin de 1730s et de 
1740s. Il est allé à l'école d'Eleazer le Wheelock de 
Révérend et s'est exercé en tant qu'un missionnaire et professeur 
pour ses personnes, d'abord à nouveaux Londres, Connecticut, et puis 
se déplacer à Montauk sur la longue île en tant que ministre 
presbytérien ordonné. Occom a composé une autobiographie 
courte où il a décrit les difficultés de faire une vie, son 
expérience en tant que ministre indien, et son traitement faible aux 
mains de l'établissement religieux.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Pelo começo de décimo oitavo Mohegan do século 
os indians tinham perdido quantidades vastas de sua terra aos colonos 
ingleses. Encontraram duro continuar com sua economia tribal 
tradicional; alguns girados para o álcool para o escape e 
outros encontraram uma resposta no christianity. Os ministros 
evangelical converteram Mohegan Samsom Occom ao christianity durante 
awakening grande no 1730s e no 1740s atrasados. Atendeu à 
escola de Reverend Eleazer o Wheelock e treinou-a como um missionário
e um professor para seus povos, primeiramente em Londres, em 
Connecticut, e então em mover-se novos para Montauk no console longo 
como um ministro presbyterian ordained. Occom compôs um 
autobiography curto onde descrevesse as dificuldades de fazer uma 
vida, sua experiência como um ministro indian, e seu tratamento 
deficiente nas mãos do estabelecimento religioso.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dall'inizio di diciottesimo Mohegan di secolo gli 
indiani avevano perso i grandi importi della loro terra ai 
colonizzatori inglesi. Lo hanno trovato duro continuare con la 
loro economia tribale tradizionale; alcuni girati verso alcool 
per la fuga ed altri hanno trovato una risposta nel christianity. 
I ministri evangelical hanno convertito Mohegan Samsom Occom
in christianity durante il risveglio grande verso la fine di 1730s e 
di 1740s. Ha assistito alla scuola di Reverend Eleazer il 
Wheelock ed ha addestrato come un missionario ed insegnante per la 
sua gente, in primo luogo a nuovi Londra, Connecticut ed allora 
muoversi verso Montauk sull'isola lunga come ministro presbyterian
ordained. Occom ha composto un autobiography corto in cui ha 
descritto le difficoltà di fare una vita, la sua esperienza come 
ministro indiano ed il suo povero trattamento alle mani 
dell'istituzione religiosa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Από την αρχή του δέκατου όγδοου αιώνα Mohegan 
Ινδοί είχαν χάσει τα απέραντα ποσά εδάφους τους στους αγγλικούς
αποίκους. Βρήκαν για να συνεχιστούν δύσκολο με την 
παραδοσιακή φυλετική οικονομία τους  μερικοί γύρισαν στο 
οινόπνευμα για τη διαφυγή και άλλοι βρήκαν μια απάντηση στο 
χριστιανισμό. Οι εβαγγελικοί υπουργοί μετέτρεψαν Mohegan 
Samsom Occom στο χριστιανισμό κατά τη διάρκεια του μεγάλου 
ξυπνήματος προς το τέλος 1730s και 1740s. Παρακολούθησε
το Αιδεσιμότατος σχολείο Eleazer Wheelock και εκπαίδευσε ως 
ιεραπόστολος και δάσκαλος για τους ανθρώπους του, πρώτα στο νέο 
Λονδίνο, το Κοννέκτικατ, και έπειτα την κίνηση προς Montauk στο
μακρύ νησί ως ορισμένο Πρεσβυτεριανό υπουργό. Το Occom 
σύνθεσε μια κοντή αυτοβιογραφία όπου περιέγραψε τις δυσκολίες 
προς το ζειν, την εμπειρία του ως ινδικό υπουργό, και τη φτωχή 
επεξεργασία του στα χέρια της θρησκευτικής καθιέρωσης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Por el principio de décimo octavo Mohegan del 
siglo los indios habían perdido cantidades extensas de su pista a los
colonos ingleses. Encontraron duro continuar con su economía 
tribal tradicional; algunos dados vuelta al alcohol para el 
escape y otros encontraron una respuesta en cristianismo. Los 
ministros evangélicos convirtieron Mohegan Samsom Occom al 
cristianismo durante gran despertar en el últimos 1730s y 1740s. 
Él atendió a la escuela de Reverend Eleazer el Wheelock y 
entrenó como un misionario y profesor para su gente, primero en 
Londres, Connecticut, y después trasladarse nuevos a Montauk en la 
isla larga como ministro presbyterian ordained. Occom compuso 
una autobiografía corta donde él describió las dificultades de 
hacer una vida, su experiencia como ministro indio, y su tratamiento 
pobre en las manos del establecimiento religioso.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086274</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107191</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-believe-it-is-because-i-am-a-poor-indian-samsom-occoms-life-as-an-indian-minister</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
