<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105113</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105113</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086054</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Dame Shirley" Describes Life at a California Gold Mining Camp in the Sierra Nevada Mountains, 1851</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Dame Shirley" beschreibt das Leben an einem 
Kalifornien Goldgewinnenlager in der Sierra Nevada Berge, 1851</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"dame Shirley" décrit la vie à un camp 
d'extraction d'or de la Californie en sierra les montagnes de Nevada, 
1851</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">o "dame Shirley" descreve a vida em um acampamento
minando do ouro de Califórnia no sierra montanhas de nevada, 1851</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"il dame Shirley" descrive la vita ad un 
accampamento estraente dell'oro della California nella sierra le 
montagne di Nevada, 1851</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η κυρία Shirley" περιγράφει τη ζωή σε ένα χρυσό 
στρατόπεδο μεταλλείας Καλιφόρνιας στην οροσειρά βουνά της 
Νεβάδας, 1851</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"dama Shirley" describe vida en un campo que mina 
del oro de California en el sierra montañas de Nevada, 1851</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The author of this letter, who used the pseudonym "Dame Shirley," was Louise Amelia Knapp Smith Clapp (1819-1906). The letter was written to Clapp's sister, Molly, in Massachusetts, but was subsequently published as one of a series of twenty-three in the  Pioneer , a California literary magazine. Clapp's subject in the "Shirley letters," as they are called, was life at the gold mining camps of mid-19th-century California. Clapp knew about life in the world of California gold mining from first-hand experience. With her husband, a doctor, Clapp left the East Coast for California in 1849. At first the couple settled in San Francisco, but in 1851 they left for the Sierra Nevada mountains so that Dr. Clapp could regain his health in the mountain air. In the Sierra Nevadas, they spent more than a year at two gold mining camps, Rich Bar and Indian Bar, on the Feather River. As the self-conscious tone of these letters suggests, Clapp aspired to be a literary writer. As a woman, her perspective on life in the nearly all-male camps was unique. The letters allegedly provided material for Bret Harte's stories. Today we can appreciate them for their historical value as observations of life during the California gold rush.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Autor dieses Zeichens, der das Pseudonym "Dame
Shirley benutzte," war Louise Amelia Knapp Smith Clapp (1819-1906). 
Der Schwester Clapps, Molly der Brief wurde, in Massachusetts 
geschrieben, aber wurde nachher als eine einer Reihe von 
dreiundzwanzig im Pionier, eine Kalifornien literarische Zeitschrift 
veröffentlicht. Thema Clapps in den "Shirley Zeichen,", da sie 
benannt werden, Leben an den Goldgewinnenlagern von mid-19th-century 
Kalifornien waren. Clapp kannte in dem Leben in der Welt des 
Kalifornien Goldes gewinnend von der aus erster Hand bezogenen 
Erfahrung aus. Mit ihrem Ehemann ließ ein Doktor, Clapp die 
Ostküste für Kalifornien 1849. Zuerst die Paare, die in San 
Francisco, aber in 1851 verließen sie vereinbart wurden, für die 
Sierra Nevada Berge, damit Dr. Clapp seine Gesundheit in der 
Gebirgsluft wiedergewinnen konnte. In der Sierra Nevadas, 
wendeten sie mehr als ein Jahr bei zwei Goldgewinnenlagern, reicher 
Stab und indischer Stab, auf dem Feder-Fluß auf. Da der 
selbstbewußte Ton dieser Zeichen vorschlägt, strebte Clapp, ein 
literarischer Verfasser zu sein. Als Frau war ihre Perspektive 
auf dem Leben in den fast Allmannlagern eindeutig. Die Zeichen 
stellten angeblich Material für Bret Hartes Geschichten zur 
Verfügung. Heute können wir sie für ihren historischen Wert 
schätzen wie Beobachtungen des Lebens während der Kalifornien 
Goldanstürme.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'auteur de cette lettre, qui a utilisé le 
pseudonyme "dame Shirley," était Louise Amelia Knapp Smith Clapp 
(1819-1906). La lettre a été écrite à la soeur de Clapp, 
molly, dans le Massachusetts, mais a été ultérieurement éditée en
tant qu'une d'une série de vingt-trois dans le pionnier, un magazine 
littéraire de la Californie. Le sujet de Clapp dans les 
"lettres de Shirley," car ils s'appellent, étaient la vie aux camps 
d'extraction d'or de mid-19th-century la Californie. Clapp a su 
la vie dans le monde de l'or de la Californie extrayant d'une 
expérience de première main. Avec son mari, un docteur, Clapp 
a laissé la côte est pour la Californie en 1849. D'abord les 
couples arrangés dans San Francisco, mais dans 1851 ils sont partis
pour la sierra montagnes de Nevada de sorte que Dr. Clapp ait pu 
regagner sa santé à l'air de montagne. En sierra Nevadas, ils 
ont dépensé plus qu'une année à deux camps d'extraction d'or, 
barre riche et barre indienne, sur le fleuve de plume. Car la 
tonalité de art de l'auto-portrait-conscious de ces lettres suggère, Clapp a 
aspiré pour être un auteur littéraire. En tant que femme, sa 
perspective la vie dans presque les camps de tout-mâle était seule. 
Les lettres ont fourni prétendument le matériel pour des 
histoires de Bret Harte. Aujourd'hui nous pouvons les apprécier
pour leur valeur historique comme des observations de la vie pendant 
les précipitations d'or de la Californie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O autor desta letra, que usou o pseudonym "dame 
Shirley," era Louise Amelia Knapp Smith Clapp (1819-1906). A 
letra foi escrita à irmã de Clapp, molly, em Massachusetts, mas 
publicada subseqüentemente como uma de uma série de vinte e três no
pioneiro, um compartimento literário de Califórnia. O assunto 
de Clapp de "nas letras Shirley," porque são chamados, eram vida nos 
acampamentos minando do ouro de mid-19th-century Califórnia. 
Clapp soube sobre a vida no mundo do ouro de Califórnia que 
mina da experiência first-hand. Com seu marido, um doutor, 
Clapp deixou a costa do leste para Califórnia em 1849. Início 
nos pares estabelecidos em San Francisco, mas em 1851 sairam para o 
sierra montanhas de nevada de modo que o Dr. Clapp pudesse regain sua 
saúde no ar da montanha. No sierra Nevadas, gastaram mais do 
que um ano em dois acampamentos minando do ouro, barra rica e barra 
indian, no rio da pena. Porque o tom self-conscious destas 
letras sugere, Clapp aspired ser um escritor literário. Como 
uma mulher, seu perspective na vida quase nos acampamentos do 
todo-macho era original. As letras forneceram alegada o material
para histórias de Bret Harte. Hoje nós podemos apreciá-los 
para seu valor histórico como observações da vida durante as 
arremetidas do ouro de Califórnia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'autore di questa lettera, che ha usato lo 
pseudonimo "il dame Shirley," era Louise Amelia Knapp Smith Clapp 
(1819-1906). La lettera è stata scritta alla sorella del Clapp,
molly, in Massachusetts, ma successivamente è stata pubblicata come 
una di una serie di ventitre nel pioniere, uno scomparto letterario 
della California. L'oggetto del Clapp "nelle lettere di 
Shirley," poichè sono chiamati, era vita agli accampamenti estraenti 
dell'oro di mid-19th-century la California. Clapp ha saputo 
circa vita nel mondo dell'oro della California che estrae 
dall'esperienza di prima mano. Con il suo marito, un medico, 
Clapp ha lasciato il litorale orientale per la California in 1849. 
Inizialmente le coppie depositate a San Francisco, ma in 1851 
hanno andato per la sierra montagne di Nevada in modo che il Dott. 
Clapp potesse riguadagnare la sua salute nell'aria della montagna. 
Nella sierra Nevadas, hanno speso più di un anno a 
due accampamenti estraenti dell'oro, barra ricca e barra indiana, sul 
fiume della piuma. Poichè il tono self-conscious di queste 
lettere suggerisce, Clapp ha aspirato essere un produttore letterario.
Come donna, la sua prospettiva su vita quasi negli accampamenti 
del tutto-maschio era unica. Le lettere presunto hanno fornito 
il materiale per le storia di Bret Harte. Oggi possiamo 
apprezzarli per il loro valore storico come osservazioni di vita 
durante gli sbalzi dell'oro della California.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο συντάκτης αυτής της επιστολής, που κυρία Shirley 
χρησιμοποίησε των ψευδωνύμων "," ήταν Louise Amelia Knapp 
Smith Clapp (1819-1906). Η επιστολή γράφτηκε στην 
αδελφή Clapp, Molly, στη Μασαχουσέτη, αλλά δημοσιεύθηκε στη 
συνέχεια ως μια από μια σειρά είκοσι τριών στον πρωτοπόρο, ένα 
λογοτεχνικό περιοδικό Καλιφόρνιας. Το θέμα του Clapp στις
"επιστολές Shirley," καθώς καλούνται, ήταν ζωή στα χρυσά 
στρατόπεδα μεταλλείας τα μέσα τουαιώνα Καλιφόρνια. Το 
Clapp ήξερε για τη ζωή στον κόσμο της χρυσής μεταλλείας 
Καλιφόρνιας από την από πρώτο χέρι εμπειρία. Με το 
σύζυγό της, ένας γιατρός, Clapp άφησε την ανατολική ακτή για
Καλιφόρνια το 1849. Πρώτα στο ζεύγος που εγκαταστάθηκε 
στο Σαν Φρανσίσκο, αλλά το 1851 έφυγαν για την οροσειρά βουνά 
της Νεβάδας έτσι ώστε ο Δρ Clapp να μπορεί να επανακτήσει την 
υγεία του στον αέρα βουνών. Στην οροσειρά Nevadas, 
πέρασαν ένα περισσότερο από έτος σε δύο χρυσά στρατόπεδα 
μεταλλείας, πλούσια ράβδος και ινδική ράβδος, στον ποταμό 
φτερών. Όπως ο ενσυνείδητος τόνος αυτών των επιστολών 
προτείνει, Clapp επεδίωξε να είναι λογοτεχνικός συγγραφέας. 
Σαν γυναίκα, η προοπτική της στη ζωή στα σχεδόν 
όλος-αρσενικά στρατόπεδα ήταν μοναδική. Οι επιστολές 
παρείχαν σύμφωνα με τους ισχυρισμούς το υλικό για τις ιστορίες 
Bret Harte. Σήμερα μπορούμε να τους εκτιμήσουμε για την
ιστορική αξία τους ως παρατηρήσεις της ζωής κατά τη διάρκεια της
χρυσής βιασύνης Καλιφόρνιας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El autor de esta carta, que utilizó el seudónimo
"dama Shirley," era Louise Amelia Knapp Smith Clapp (1819-1906). 
La letra fue escrita a la hermana de Clapp, molly, en 
Massachusetts, pero publicada posteriormente como una de una serie de 
veintitrés en el pionero, un compartimiento literario de California. 
El tema de Clapp en las "cartas de Shirley," como se llaman, era
vida en los campos que minaban del oro de mid-19th-century California.
Clapp sabía sobre vida en el mundo del oro de California que 
minaba de experiencia de primera mano. Con su marido, un doctor,
Clapp dejó la costa del este para California en 1849. Al 
principio los pares colocados en San Francisco, pero en 1851 se fueron
para el sierra montañas de Nevada de modo que el Dr. Clapp pudiera 
recuperar su salud en el aire de la montaña. En el sierra 
Nevadas, pasaron más que un año en dos campos que minaban del oro, 
barra rica y barra india, en el río de la pluma. Pues el tono 
tímido de estas cartas sugiere, Clapp aspiró ser programa de 
escritura literario. Como mujer, su perspectiva el vida en los 
campos del todo-varo'n era casi única. Las cartas alegado 
proporcionaron al material para las historias de Bret Harte. 
Podemos apreciarlas hoy para su valor histórico como las 
observaciones de la vida durante las acometidas del oro de California.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086054</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105113</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/dame-shirley-describes-life-at-a-california-gold-mining-camp-in-the-sierra-nevada-mountains-1851</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
