<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103093</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103093</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087245</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Women's Annual Earnings Are Substantially Lower than Those of Men": Statistical Studies on Women Workers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"jährliches Einkommen der Frauen ist im 
wesentlichen niedriger als die der Männer": Statistische 
Untersuchungen über Frau-Arbeiter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"les revenus annuels des femmes sont sensiblement 
inférieurs à ceux des hommes" : Études statistiques sur des 
ouvrières de femmes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">das "o salário anual mulheres é substancialmente
mais baixo do que aqueles dos homens": Estudos estatísticos em 
trabalhadores das mulheres</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"i guadagni annuali delle donne sono 
sostanzialmente più bassi di quelli degli uomini": Studi 
statistici sugli operai delle donne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Οι ετήσιες αποδοχές των γυναικών είναι ουσιαστικά 
χαμηλότερες από εκείνοι των ανδρών": Στατιστικές μελέτες 
για τους εργαζομένους γυναικών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">las "ganancias anuales de las mujeres son 
substancialmente más bajas que las de hombres": Estudios 
estadísticos en trabajadores de las mujeres</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">During World War II, a number of states passed legislation to combat salary inequities suffered by women workers. Many unions also adopted standards to insure that female employees received the same salaries as males who performed similar jobs. The Equal Pay Act of 1963, the first Federal legislation guaranteeing equal pay for equal work, prohibited firms engaged in interstate commerce from paying workers according to wage rates determined by sex. The following year, Title VII of the landmark Civil Rights Act of 1964 further prevented sex discrimination in employment. Many jobs traditionally identified as women's work, however, continued to pay lower salaries than those historically classified as jobs for men. The following studies included in testimony to a 1970 Congressional hearing investigating employment discrimination against women presented a statistical snapshot of women workers. The battle for equal pay for work of comparable worth emerged as the "issue of the eighties," in the words of Eleanor Holmes Norton, chairwoman of the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC). By the end of the 1980s, the EEOC had initiated lawsuits against more than 40 states for employment discrimination. More than 1,700 localities passed legislation to address pay inequity.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während des Zweiten Weltkrieges führte eine 
Anzahl von Zuständen Gesetzgebung zu den Kampfgehalt 
Ungerechtigkeiten, die durch Frauarbeiter erlitten wurden. Viele
Anschlüße nahmen auch Standards an, um zu versichern, daß weibliche
Angestellte die gleichen Gehälter wie Männer empfingen, die 
ähnliche Jobs durchführten. Die gleiche Bezahlung Tat von 
1963, die erste Bundesgesetzgebung, die gleicher Bezahlung für 
gleiche Arbeit, verbotene Unternehmen garantiert, engagierte sich im 
landesweiten Handel vom Zahlen der Arbeiter entsprechend den 
Lohnkinetik, die durch Geschlecht festgestellt wurden. Das 
folgende Jahr, Titel VII der Grenzstein Zivilrecht-Tat der weiteren 
verhinderten Unterscheidung des Geschlechtes 1964 in der 
Beschäftigung. Viele Jobs traditionsgemäß gekennzeichnet, wie
Arbeit der Frauen jedoch fortfuhr, niedrigere Gehälter, als die zu 
zahlen historisch eingestuft als Jobs für Männer. Die 
folgenden Studien, die im Zeugnis zu einer Kongreßhörfähigkeit 1970
nachforschenden Diskriminierung bei der Anstellung gegen Frauen 
eingeschlossen waren, stellten einen statistischen Snapshot der 
Frauarbeiter dar. Die Schlacht für gleiche Bezahlung für 
Arbeit von Wert aufgetaucht wie die "Ausgabe der Achtziger Jahre," in 
den Wörtern von Eleanor Holmes Norton, Vorsitzendes der gleichen 
Beschäftigungsmöglichkeit-Kommission (EEOC). Ende der 
achtziger Jahre hatte das EEOC Prozesse gegen mehr als 40 Zustände 
für Diskriminierung bei der Anstellung initialisiert. Mehr als 
1.700 Stellen führten Gesetzgebung zur Adresse Bezahlung 
Ungerechtigkeit.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant la deuxième guerre mondiale, un certain 
nombre d'états ont passé la législation aux injustices de salaire 
de combat souffertes par des ouvrières de femmes. Beaucoup de 
syndicats ont également adopté des normes pour assurer que les 
employés féminins ont reçu les mêmes salaires que les mâles qui 
ont exécuté les travaux semblables. La Loi d'égalité de 
salaires de 1963, la première législation fédérale garantissant la
salaire égal, les sociétés interdites s'est engagée dans le 
commerce entre Etats de payer des ouvriers selon des salaires horaires
déterminés par le sexe. L'année suivante, titre VII de la Loi
de droits civiques de borne limite de la discrimination de sexe 1964 
empêchée encore dans l'emploi. Beaucoup de travaux 
traditionnellement identifiés comme le travail des femmes, cependant,
a continué à payer des salaires inférieurs que ceux historiquement 
classifiés comme travaux pour les hommes. Les études suivantes
incluses dans le témoignage à une discrimination à l'embauche 
d'investigation de l'audition 1970 congressionnelle contre des femmes 
ont présenté un instantané statistique des ouvrières de femmes. 
La bataille pour l'égalité de salaires pour le travail de 
valeur émergé comme la "question des années '80," dans les mots 
d'Eleanor Holmes Norton, présidente de la Commission égale d'offre 
d'emploi (EEOC). Vers la fin des années 80, l'EEOC avait lancé
des procès contre plus de 40 états pour la discrimination à 
l'embauche. Plus de 1.700 localités ont passé la législation 
à l'injustice de salaire d'adresse.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Durante a segunda guerra mundial, um número de 
estados passaram a legislação aos inequities do salário do combate 
sofridos por trabalhadores das mulheres. Muitas uniões adotaram
também padrões para segurar que os empregados fêmeas receberam os 
mesmos salários que os machos que executaram trabalhos similares. 
O ato de 1963, a primeira legislação federal do pagamento 
igual que garante o pagamento igual para o trabalho igual, firmas 
proibidas acoplou no comércio interstate de pagar trabalhadores de 
acordo com as taxas de salário determinadas pelo sexo. O 
seguinte ano, título VII do ato das direitas civis do marco da 
discriminação de sexo 1964 impedida mais adicional no emprego. 
Muitos trabalhos identificados tradicional como o trabalho das 
mulheres, entretanto, continuou a pagar uns salários mais baixos do 
que aqueles classificados historicamente como trabalhos para homens. 
Os seguintes estudos incluídos no testimony a uma 
discriminação de emprego investigando do hearing 1970 congressional 
de encontro às mulheres apresentaram um instantâneo estatístico de 
trabalhadores das mulheres. A batalha para o pagamento igual 
para o trabalho de comparável worth emerso como a "introdução dos 
eighties," nas palavras de Eleanor Holmes Norton, chairwoman do 
commission igual da oportunidade de emprego (EEOC). Para o fim 
dos 1980s, o EEOC tinha iniciado lawsuits de encontro a mais de 40 
estados para a discriminação de emprego. Mais de 1.700 
localities passaram a legislação ao inequity do pagamento do 
endereço.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Durante la seconda guerra mondiale, un certo 
numero dichiara la legislazione passata alle ingiustizie di 
stipendio di combattimento sofferte dagli operai delle donne. 
Molti sindacati egualmente hanno adottato gli standard per 
assicurare che gli impiegati femminili hanno ricevuto gli stessi 
stipendi dei maschi che hanno effettuato i lavori simili. La 
Legge di 1963, la prima legislazione federale di parità salariale che
garantisce la parità salariale per lavoro uguale, ditte proibite si 
è agganciata nel commercio da uno stato all'altro dal pagamento degli
operai secondo i tassi di stipendio determinati dal sesso. Il 
seguente anno, titolo VII della Legge di diritti civili del limite di 
ulteriore discriminazione in base al sesso evitata 1964 
nell'occupazione. Molti lavori identificati tradizionalmente 
come il lavoro delle donne, tuttavia, ha continuato a pagare gli 
stipendi più bassi che quelli classificati storicamente come lavori 
per gli uomini. I seguenti studi inclusi nella testimonianza ad 
una distinzione di occupazione di studio di udienza congressuale 1970 
contro le donne hanno presentato una fotografia istantanea statistica 
degli operai delle donne. La battaglia per parità salariale per
lavoro di paragonabile degno emerso come "l'emissione degli anni '80,"
nelle parole di Eleanor Holmes Norton, chairwoman della Commissione 
uguale di possibilità d'impiego (EEOC). Per la fine degli anni 
80, il EEOC aveva iniziato le cause contro più di 40 dichiarano 
per distinzione di occupazione. Più di 1.700 località ha 
passato la legislazione all'ingiustizia di paga di indirizzo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ, διάφορα 
κράτη πέρασαν τη νομοθεσία στις αδικίες μισθών αγώνα που 
υποφέρονται από τους εργαζομένους γυναικών. Πολλές ενώσεις
υιοθέτησαν επίσης τα πρότυπα για να ασφαλίσουν ότι η γυναίκα 
υπάλληλοι έλαβε τους ίδιους μισθούς με τα αρσενικά που εκτέλεσαν
τις παρόμοιες εργασίες. Ο νόμος ίσης αμοιβής του 1963, η
πρώτη ομοσπονδιακή νομοθεσία που εγγυάται την ίση αμοιβή για την
όμοια εργασία, απαγόρευσε τις εταιρίες που συμμετέχθηκαν στο 
διακρατικό εμπόριο από την πληρωμή των εργαζομένων σύμφωνα με τα
ποσοστά αμοιβών που καθορίστηκαν από το φύλο. Το επόμενο 
έτος, τίτλος VII του νόμου αστικών δικαιωμάτων ορόσημων των 
περαιτέρω διακρίσεων λόγω φύλου του 1964 στην απασχόληση. 
Πολλές εργασίες που προσδιορίστηκαν παραδοσιακά ως εργασία 
των γυναικών, εντούτοις, συνέχισαν να πληρώνουν τους χαμηλότερους
μισθούς από εκείνοι που ταξινομήθηκαν ιστορικά ως εργασίες για 
τους άνδρες. Οι ακόλουθες μελέτες που περιλήφθηκαν στην 
κατάθεση σε μια διάκριση απασχόλησης έρευνας ακρόασης του 1970
του Κογκρέσου ενάντια στις γυναίκες παρουσίασαν ένα στατιστικό 
στιγμιότυπο των εργαζομένων γυναικών. Η μάχη για την ίση 
αμοιβή για την εργασία της συγκρίσιμης αξίας προέκυψε ως "ζήτημα
της δεκαετίας του '80," στις λέξεις Eleanor Holmes Norton, 
πρόεδρος της ίσης Επιτροπής ευκαιρίας απασχόλησης (EEOC). 
Μέχρι το τέλος της δεκαετίας του '80, το EEOC είχε 
αρχίσει τις δίκες ενάντια σε περισσότερα από 40 κράτη για τη 
διάκριση απασχόλησης. Περισσότερες από 1.700 τοποθεσίες 
πέρασαν τη νομοθεσία στη διεύθυνση πληρώνουν την αδικία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Durante la Segunda Guerra Mundial, un número de 
estados aprobaron la legislación a las injusticias del sueldo del 
combate sufridas por los trabajadores de las mujeres. Muchas 
uniones también adoptaron estándares para asegurar que los empleados
femeninos recibieron los mismos sueldos que los varones que realizaron
trabajos similares. El acto de 1963, la primera legislación 
federal de la igualdad de salario que garantizaba la igualdad de 
salario para el trabajo igual, las firmas prohibidas enganchó a 
comercio de un estado a otro de pagar a trabajadores según las 
tarifas de salario determinadas por el sexo. El año siguiente, 
título VII del acto de las derechas civiles de la señal de la 
discriminación de sexo prevenida adicional 1964 en el empleo. 
Muchos trabajos identificados tradicionalmente a medida que el 
trabajo de las mujeres, sin embargo, continuó pagando sueldos más 
bajos que ésos clasificados históricamente como trabajos para los 
hombres. Los estudios siguientes incluidos en testimonio a una 
discriminación de empleo de la audiencia que investigaba del congreso
1970 contra mujeres presentaron una foto estadística de los 
trabajadores de las mujeres. La batalla para la igualdad de 
salario para el trabajo de comparable digno de emergido como la 
"aplicación los años ochenta," en las palabras de Eleanor Holmes 
Norton, presidente de la Comisión igual de posibilidad de empleo 
(EEOC). Para el final de los años 80, el EEOC había iniciado 
pleitos contra más de 40 estados para la discriminación de empleo. 
Más de 1.700 lugares aprobaron la legislación a la injusticia 
de la paga del direccionamiento.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087245</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103093</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/womens-annual-earnings-are-substantially-lower-than-those-of-men-statistical-studies-on-women-workers</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
