<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105270</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105270</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086242</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Hollis Watkins Describes Police Intimidation in the Voter Registration Campaign</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hollis Watkins beschreibt Polizei-Einschüchterung
in der Wähler-Registrierung-Kampagne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Hollis Watkins décrit l'intimidation de police 
dans la campagne d'enregistrement d'électeur</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Hollis Watkins descreve a intimidação das 
polícias na campanha do registo do eleitor</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Hollis Watkins descrive l'intimidazione della 
polizia nella campagna di registro dell'elettore</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Hollis Watkins περιγράφει τον εκφοβισμό 
αστυνομίας στην εκστρατεία εγγραφής ψηφοφόρων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Hollis Watkins describe la intimidación del 
policía en la campaña del registro del votante</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Student Non-Violent Coordinating Committee (SNCC) enlisted young people and local leaders to register and encourage southern African-Americans to vote during the Civil Rights Movement of the 1960's. Because the young organizers faced tremendous risks by challenging segregation and encouraging people to vote, the group earned a reputation as the "shock troops" of the Civil Rights Movement. Hollis Watkins joined SNCC in the early 1960's and canvassed potential voters in the area of McComb, Mississippi. He also participated in direct actions, for which he served time in jail. Watkins remembered the risks SNCC organizers faced when working alone and in pairs, and the support they received from the African-American community.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die eingetragenen jungen Leute des 
Kursteilnehmer-Nicht-Heftigen Koordinationsausschusses (SNCC) und die 
lokalen Führer, zum der südlichen Afrikanisch-Amerikaner zu 
registrieren und anzuregen, während der Zivilrecht-Bewegung der 
sechziger Jahre zu wählen. Weil die jungen Organisatoren enorme
Gefahren durch schwierige Abtrennung und anregenleute 
gegenüberstellten, um zu wählen, erwarb die Gruppe ein Renommee als 
der "Schlag troops" von der Zivilrecht-Bewegung. Hollis Watkins 
verbindendes SNCC in den frühen sechziger Jahren und in den 
erörterten möglichen Wählern im Bereich von McComb, Mississippi. 
Er nahm auch an den direkten Tätigkeiten teil, für die er Zeit
im Gefängnis diente. Watkins erinnerte sich die an Gefahren 
SNCC Organisatoren, die gegenübergestellt wurden, wenn Sie alleine 
und in den Paaren und im Support arbeiten, die sie von der 
Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Gemeinschaft empfingen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les jeunes enrôlés Non-Violents du Comité de 
coordination d'étudiant (SNCC) et les amorces locales pour 
enregistrer et encourager des Afro-Américains méridionaux à voter 
pendant le mouvement de droits civiques des années 60. Puisque 
les jeunes organisateurs ont fait face à des risques énormes par 
ségrégation provocante et personnes encourageantes pour voter, le 
groupe a gagné une réputation comme "choc s'assemble" du mouvement 
de droits civiques. Hollis SNCC jointif par Watkins au début 
des années 60 et les électeurs potentiels prospectés dans la zone 
de McComb, Mississippi. Il a également participé aux actions 
directes, auxquelles il a servi le temps en prison. Watkins 
s'est rappelé les organisateurs des risques SNCC faits face en 
travaillant seul et dans les paires, et le support qu'ils ont reçu de
la communauté afro-américaine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os povos novos alistados Non-Violentos de comitê 
de coordenação do estudante (SNCC) e os líderes locais para 
registar e incentivar Africano-Americanos do sul votar durante o 
movimento das direitas civis dos 1960's. Porque os organizers 
novos enfrentaram riscos tremendos por segregation challenging e por 
povos incentivando para votar, o grupo ganhou uma reputação como o 
"choque agrupa-se" do movimento das direitas civis. Hollis SNCC 
juntado Watkins nos 1960's adiantados e nos eleitores potenciais 
canvassed na área de McComb, Mississippi. Participou também 
nas ações diretas, para que serviu ao tempo na cadeia. Watkins
recordou os organizers dos riscos SNCC enfrentados ao trabalhar 
sozinho e em pares, e a sustentação que receberam da comunidade 
Africano-Americana.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I giovani arruolati Non-Violenti del comitato di 
coordinazione dell'allievo (SNCC) ed i capi locali per 
registrare e consigliare agli Africano-Americani del sud votare 
durante il movimento di diritti civili degli anni 60. Poiché 
gli organizzatori giovani hanno affrontato i rischi tremendi dalla 
segregazione challenging e dalla gente consigliante per votare, il 
gruppo ha guadagnato una reputazione come "la scossa si aduna" del 
movimento di diritti civili. Hollis Watkins ha unito SNCC 
all'inizio degli anni '60 ed ha saggiato l'opinione degli elettori 
potenziali nella zona di McComb, Mississippi. Egualmente ha 
partecipato alle azioni dirette, per cui ha servito il tempo in 
prigione. Watkins si è ricordato degli organizzatori di rischi 
SNCC affrontati quando funzionano da solo e negli accoppiamenti e nel 
supporto che hanno ricevuto dalla Comunità Africano-Americana.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η μη βίαια συντονιστική επιτροπή σπουδαστών (SNCC) 
στρατολόγησε τους νέους και τους τοπικούς ηγέτες για να εγγραφεί 
και να ενθαρρύνει νότιους αφρικανικός-Αμερικανούς για να ψηφίσει 
κατά τη διάρκεια του Κινήματος αστικών δικαιωμάτων της δεκαετίας
του '60. Επειδή οι νέοι διοργανωτές αντιμετώπισαν τους 
τεράστιους κινδύνους με την πρόκληση του διαχωρισμού και την 
ενθάρρυνση των ανθρώπων για να ψηφίσουν, η ομάδα κέρδισε μια 
φήμη ως "στρατεύματα κλονισμού" του Κινήματος αστικών 
δικαιωμάτων. Το Hollis Watkins ένωσε SNCC στις αρχές
της δεκαετίας του '60 και δοκίμασε τη γνώμη των πιθανών ψηφοφόρων
στον τομέα McComb, Μισισιπής. Συμμετείχε επίσης στις 
άμεσες ενέργειες, για τις οποίες εξυπηρέτησε το χρόνο στη 
φυλακή. Το Watkins θυμήθηκε τους διοργανωτές κινδύνων 
SNCC αντιμέτωπους κατά να εργαστεί μόνο και ανά τα ζευγάρια, 
και την υποστήριξη που έλαβαν από την αφρικανικός-αμερικανική 
κοινότητα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La gente joven alistada No-Violenta del comité 
del estudiante que coordina (SNCC) y los arranques de cinta locales 
para colocar y para animar a Africano-Americanos meridionales que 
voten durante el movimiento de las derechas civiles de los años 60. 
Porque los organizadores jóvenes hicieron frente a enormes 
riesgos por la segregación desafiadora y la gente que animaba para 
votar, el grupo ganó una reputación como el "choque marcha" del 
movimiento de las derechas civiles. Hollis SNCC unido Watkins en
los años 60 tempranos y los votantes potenciales solicitados votos en
el área de McComb, Mississippi. Él también participó en las 
acciones directas, para las cuales él sirvió tiempo en cárcel. 
Watkins recordó a organizadores de los riesgos SNCC hechos 
frente al trabajar solamente y en los pares, y la ayuda que recibieron
de la comunidad Africano-Americana.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086242</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105270</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/hollis-watkins-describes-police-intimidation-in-the-voter-registration-campaign</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
