<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108103</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108103</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209768</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Animatic Dialog Recording</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Animatic Dialog-Aufnahme</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Enregistrement de Dialogue d'Animatic</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Gravação Do Diálogo De Animatic</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Registrazione Di Dialogo Di Animatic</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Καταγραφή διαλογικού παραθύρου Animatic</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Grabación Del Diálogo De Animatic</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An animatic is a movie of the storyboards. This is used for timing our motion picture. It also helps us judge if the movie will be a success. To create an animatic, the storyboard, the film score, the dialog and the sound effects are put into an editing program to create a movie which we can show to investors. Later, when we record the voices for the animated version of this motion picture, the actors will watch the animatic to help understand the action and the timing of the dialog. </string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein animatic ist ein Film der storyboards. 
Dieses wird für die zeitliche Regelung unserer Bewegung 
Abbildung verwendet. Es hilft uns auch zu urteilen, wenn der 
Film ein Erfolg ist. Um ein animatic zu erstellen, werden das 
storyboard, die Filmkerbe, der Dialog und die stichhaltigen Effekte in
ein bearbeitendes Programm gesetzt um einen Film zu erstellen den wir 
zeigen können den Investoren. Später wenn wir die Stimmen für
die lebhafte Version dieser Bewegung Abbildung speichern, überwachen 
die Schauspieler das animatic, um zu helfen, die Tätigkeit und die 
Zeitbegrenzung des Dialogs zu verstehen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un animatic est un film des storyboards. 
Ceci est utilisé pour chronométrer notre film 
cinématographique. Il nous aide également à juger si le film 
sera un succès. Pour créer un animatic, le storyboard, les 
points de film, le dialogue et les effets sains sont mis dans un 
programme d'édition pour créer un film que nous pouvons montrer aux 
investisseurs. Plus tard, quand nous enregistrons les voix pour 
la version animée de ce film cinématographique, les acteurs 
observeront l'animatic pour aider à comprendre l'action et la 
synchronisation du dialogue.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um animatic é um filme dos storyboards. 
Isto é usado cronometrando nosso retrato de movimento. 
Ajuda-nos também julgar se o filme for um sucesso. Para 
criar um animatic, o storyboard, a contagem da película, o diálogo e
os efeitos sadios são postos em um programa de edição para criar um
filme que nós possamos mostrar aos investors. Mais tarde, 
quando nós gravamos as vozes para a versão animated deste retrato de
movimento, os atores prestarão atenção ao animatic para ajudar 
compreender a ação e o sincronismo do diálogo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un animatic è un film degli storyboards. 
Ciò è usata per cronometrare il nostro cinema. 
Egualmente li aiuta a giudicare se il film sarà un 
successo. Per creare un animatic, lo storyboard, il segno della 
pellicola, il dialogo e gli effetti sani sono messi in un programma di
stampa per creare un film che possiamo mostrare agli 
investitori. Più successivamente, quando registriamo le voci 
per la versione animata di questo cinema, gli attori guarderanno il 
animatic per contribuire a capire l'azione e la sincronizzazione del 
dialogo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένας animatic είναι ένας κινηματογράφος των 
storyboards. Αυτό χρησιμοποιείται για το συγχρονισμό μας 
την ταινία. Μας βοηθά επίσης να κρίνουμε εάν ο 
κινηματογράφος θα είναι μια επιτυχία. Για να δημιουργήσουν 
έναν animatic, το storyboard, το αποτέλεσμα ταινιών, το 
διαλογικό παράθυρο και τα υγιή αποτελέσματα τίθενται σε ένα να 
επιμεληθούν πρόγραμμα για να δημιουργήσει ένας κινηματογράφος που
μπορούμε να εμφανίσουμε στους επενδυτές. Αργότερα, όταν 
καταγράφουμε τις φωνές για τη ζωντανεψοντη έκδοση αυτής της 
ταινίας, οι δράστες θα προσέξουν τον animatic για να βοηθήσουν 
να καταλάβουν την ενέργεια και το συγχρονισμό του διαλογικού 
παραθύρου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un animatic es una película de los storyboards. 
Esto se utiliza por medir el tiempo de nuestra película. 
También nos ayuda a juzgar si la película es un éxito. 
Para crear un animatic, el storyboard, la cuenta de la 
película, el diálogo y los efectos sonoros se ponen en un programa 
que corrige para crear una película que poder mostrar a los 
inversionistas. Más adelante, cuando registramos las voces para
la versión animada de esta película, los agentes mirarán el 
animatic para ayudar a entender la acción y la sincronización del 
diálogo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209768</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">GNU Free Documentation License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108103</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/animatic-dialog-recording</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
