<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104925</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104925</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086226</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Hear Taft's Speech "On Popular Unrest"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hören Sie Rede Tafts "Auf Populärer 
Ruhelosigkeit"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Entendez Le Discours de Taft "Sur Le Malaise 
Populaire"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ouça O Discurso De Taft "No Unrest Popular"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Senta Il Discorso Del Taft "Su Agitazione 
Popolare"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ακούστε την ομιλία Taft "στη λαϊκή ανησυχία"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Oiga El Discurso De Taft "En Malestar Popular"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the 1912 presidential election, Republican incumbent William Howard Taft faced not one but three opponents: moderate Democratic Governor Woodrow Wilson, former President Theodore Roosevelt leading the breakaway Bull Moose party, and Socialist Party stalwart Eugene Debs, running for the fourth time. Voter interest, already piqued by the unusual campaign and the candidates' slashing attacks on one another, was further heightened by the availability of sound recordings of campaign addresses. Though his administration had adopted some anti-trust policies, Taft generally embraced a non-interventionist approach to the problems that plagued American society in 1912. When asked by reporters in 1912 how he would relieve the nation's severe unemployment, Taft replied, "God knows," a position not calculated to win over many working-class voters. Taft's attitudes were well captured in this recorded selection from one of his campaign speeches, entitled "On Popular Unrest" (which was recorded in a studio on wax cylinder). When the votes were tallied, Taft placed a distant third behind Wilson and Roosevelt.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In der Präsidentenwahl 1912 stellte 
republikanischer Amtsinhaber William Howard Taft nicht eine aber drei 
Konkurrenten gegenüber: moderieren Sie demokratischen Regler 
Woodrow Wilson, ehemaliger Präsident Theodore Roosevelt, welches die 
abgespaltene Bull ElchPartei und sozialistische Partei
kraftvolles Eugene Debs führt und für das vierte mal laufen. 
Wählerinteresse, piqued bereits durch die ungewöhnliche 
Kampagne und die schneidenden Angriffe auf einem andere der Anwärter,
wurden weiter durch die Verwendbarkeit der Tonaufnahmen der Kampagne 
Adressen erhöht. Obwohl seine Leitung etwas Antitrustpolitik 
angenommen hatte, umfaßte Taft im Allgemeinen eine 
Nichtinterventionist Annäherung zu den Problemen, die amerikanische 
Gesellschaft 1912 quälten. Als von Reportern 1912, wie er die 
strenge Arbeitslosigkeit der Nation, entlasten würde Taft gefragt, 
antwortete, "Gott weiß," eine Position, die nicht errechnet wurde, um
über vielen Arbeiterklassewählern zu gewinnen. Haltung Tafts 
wurde gut in dieser gespeicherten Auswahl von einer seiner Wahlreden 
erfaßt, erlaubt "auf populärer Ruhelosigkeit" (die in einem Studio 
auf Wachszylinder gespeichert wurde). Als die Stimmen gebucht 
wurden, plazierte Taft ein entferntes drittes hinter Wilson und 
Roosevelt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans l'élection 1912 présidentielle, le candidat
sortant républicain William Howard Taft a fait face à non un 
mais trois adversaires : modérez le Gouverneur démocratique 
Woodrow Wilson, l'ancien Président Theodore Roosevelt menant la 
partie détachée d'orignaux de Bull, et le parti socialiste Eugene 
vigoureux Debs, fonctionnant pour la quatrième fois. 
L'intérêt d'électeur, piqued déjà par la campagne peu 
commune et les attaques de réduction sur une des autres des 
candidats, ont été encore intensifiées par la disponibilité des 
enregistrements sonores des adresses de campagne. Bien que sa 
gestion ait adopté quelques politiques anti-trust, Taft a 
généralement embrassé une approche de non-interventionniste aux 
problèmes qui ont infesté la société américaine en 1912. 
Une fois demandé par des journalistes en 1912 comment il 
soulagerait le chômage grave de la nation, Taft a répondu, "Dieu 
sait," une position non calculée pour gagner au-dessus de beaucoup 
d'électeurs de classe ouvrière. Les attitudes de Taft ont 
été bien capturées dans cette sélection enregistrée à partir 
d'un de ses discours de campagne, intitulé "sur le malaise populaire"
(qui a été enregistré dans un studio sur le cylindre de cire). 
Quand les voix ont été comptées, Taft a placé un troisième 
éloigné derrière Wilson et Roosevelt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Na eleição 1912 presidencial, o encarregado 
republicano William Howard Taft enfrentou não um mas três oponentes:
modere o regulador democrático Woodrow Wilson, presidente 
anterior Theodore Roosevelt que conduz ao partido breakaway dos alces 
de Bull, e ao partido socialist Eugene stalwart Debs, funcionando para
a quarta vez. O interesse do eleitor, piqued já pela campanha 
incomun e os ataques slashing em um outros dos candidatos, heightened 
mais mais pela disponibilidade de gravações sadias de endereços da 
campanha. Embora sua administração tinha adotado algumas 
políticas anti-trust, Taft embraced geralmente uma aproximação do 
non-non-interventionist aos problemas que flagelaram a sociedade 
americana em 1912. Quando perguntado por repórteres em 1912 
como aliviaria o desemprego severo da nação, Taft respondeu, "deus 
sabe," uma posição não calculada para ganhar sobre muitos eleitores
do working-class. As atitudes de Taft foram capturadas bem nesta
seleção gravada de um de seus discursos de campanha, intitulado "no 
unrest popular" (que foi gravado em um estúdio no cilindro da cera). 
Quando os votos foram registrados, Taft colocou um terceiro 
distante atrás de Wilson e de Roosevelt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nell'elezione presidenziale 1912, il incumbent 
Repubblicano William Howard Taft ha affrontato non un ma tre avversari:
moderi il regolatore democratico Woodrow Wilson, l'ex presidente
Theodore Roosevelt che conduce il partito staccato delle alci del Bull
ed il partito socialista Eugene vigoroso Debs, funzionante per il 
tempo di quarto. L'interesse dell'elettore, già piqued 
dalla campagna insolita e gli attacchi riducenti ad uno un altro dei 
candidati, più ulteriormente sono stati intensificati dalla 
disponibilità delle registrazioni del suono degli indirizzi di 
campagna. Benchè la sua gestione adotti alcune politiche 
antitrust, Taft ha abbracciato generalmente un metodo 
dell'non-interventista ai problemi che hanno contagiato la società 
americana in 1912. Una volta chiesto dai reporter in 1912 
come allevierebbe la disoccupazione severa della nazione, Taft ha 
risposto, "dio sa," una posizione non calcolata per vincere sopra 
molti elettori della classe operaia. Gli atteggiamenti del Taft 
sono stati bloccati bene in questa selezione registrata da uno dei 
suoi discorsi di campagna, denominato "su agitazione popolare" (che è
stata registrata in un studio sul cilindro della cera). Quando i
voti sono stati coincisi, Taft ha disposto un terzo distante dietro 
Wilson e Roosevelt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στην προεδρική εκλογή του 1912, δημοκρατικός 
επιβεβλημένος William Howard Taft αντιμετώπισε όχι έναν 
αλλά τρεις αντιπάλους: συγκρατήστε το δημοκρατικό κυβερνήτη
Woodrow Wilson, προηγούμενος Πρόεδρος Theodore Roosevelt
που οδηγεί το αποσπασθέν συμβαλλόμενο μέρος αλκών του Bull, 
και το Σοσιαλιστικό Κόμμα stalwart Eugene Debs, που τρέχει
για την τέταρτη φορά. Το ενδιαφέρον ψηφοφόρων, ήδη από την
ασυνήθιστη εκστρατεία και οι επιθέσεις κοψίματος των υποψηφίων 
στο ένα άλλη, υψώθηκαν περαιτέρω από τη διαθεσιμότητα των υγιών
καταγραφών των διευθύνσεων εκστρατείας. Αν και η διοίκησή 
του είχε υιοθετήσει μερικές αντιτράστ πολιτικές, Taft 
αγκαλίασε γενικά μια προσέγγιση μη-οπαδών του παρεμβατισμού στα 
προβλήματα που μόλυναν την αμερικανική κοινωνία το 1912. 
Όταν ρωτιέται από τους δημοσιογράφους το 1912 πώς θα 
ανακούφιζε την αυστηρή ανεργία του έθνους, Taft απάντησε, "ο 
Θεός ξέρει," μια θέση που δεν υπολογίζεται για να κερδίσει πέρα 
από πολλούς ψηφοφόρους εργατικών τάξεων. Οι τοποθετήσεις 
του Taft συλλήφθηκαν καλά σε αυτήν την καταγραμμένη επιλογή 
από μια από τις ομιλίες εκστρατείας του, που τιτλοφορήθηκε "στη 
λαϊκή ανησυχία" (που καταγράφηκε σε ένα στούντιο στον κύλινδρο 
κεριών). Όταν οι ψηφοφορίες, Taft τοποθέτησε ένα 
απόμακρο τρίτο πίσω από Wilson και Roosevelt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En la elección presidencial 1912, el titular 
republicano Guillermo Howard Taft hizo frente a no un sino tres 
opositores: modere el gobernador democrático Woodrow Wilson, 
presidente anterior Theodore Roosevelt que conduce el partido 
disidente de los alces de Bull, y el partido socialista Eugene robusto
Debs, ejecutándose para la cuarta vez. El interés del votante,
piqued ya por la campaña inusual y los ataques de reducción radical 
contra uno otros de los candidatos, fueron aumentados más a fondo por
la disponibilidad de las grabaciones de sonidos de los 
direccionamientos de la campaña. Aunque su administración 
había adoptado algunas políticas anticompetitivas, Taft abrazó 
generalmente un acercamiento del no-intervencionista a los problemas 
que plagaron a sociedad americana en 1912. Cuando era preguntado
por los reporteros en 1912 cómo él relevaría el desempleo severo de
la nación, Taft contestó, "dios sabe," una posición no calculada 
para ganar sobre muchos votantes de la clase obrera. Las 
actitudes de Taft fueron capturadas bien en esta selección registrada
a partir del uno de sus discursos de campaña, dado derecho "en el 
malestar popular" (que fue registrado en un estudio en el cilindro de 
la cera). Cuando los votos fueron marcados, Taft colocó un 
tercer distante detrás de Wilson y de Roosevelt.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086226</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104925</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/hear-tafts-speech-on-popular-unrest</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
