<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105560</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105560</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203314</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">In Full Bloom</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In der Vollen Blüte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En Pleine Floraison</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Na Flor Cheia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In Piena Fioritura</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στην πλήρη άνθιση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En La Plena Floración</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This website offers a brief overview of Red Tide and the toxic algae responsible for it. Several words and phrases within the summary are hyperlinked to more detailed explanations on remote sites. A data activity in which students in grades 9-12 can analyze graphs with real data from 1997-2000 is included at the bottom of the site. This activity conforms to national science correlation standards for grades 9-12 (as indicated on the website).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Web site bietet einen kurzen Überblick 
über rote Gezeiten und giftigen die Algen, die für sie 
verantwortlich sind an. Einige Wörter und Phrasen innerhalb der
Zusammenfassung sind hyperlinked zu den ausführlicheren Erklärungen 
zu den Remotesites. Eine Datenaktivität, in der Kursteilnehmer 
in den Graden 9-12 Diagramme mit realen Daten von 1997-2000 
analysieren können, ist an der Unterseite der Sites enthalten. 
Diese Aktivität paßt sich an nationale Wissenschaft 
Wechselbeziehungstandards für Grade 9-12 an (wie auf der Web site 
angezeigt).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site Web offre une brève vue d'ensemble de 
marée rouge et des algues toxiques responsables de lui. 
Plusieurs mots et expressions dans le sommaire sont hyperlinked 
à des explications plus détaillées sur les sites à distance. 
Une activité de données dans laquelle les étudiants dans les 
catégories 9-12 peuvent analyser des graphiques avec de vraies 
données de 1997-2000 est incluse au bas du site. Cette 
activité se conforme aux normes nationales de corrélation de la 
science pour des catégories 9-12 (comme indiqué sur le site Web).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Web site oferece uma vista geral breve da 
maré vermelha e das algas tóxicas responsáveis para ele. 
Diversas palavras e frases dentro do sumário são hyperlinked a
umas explanações mais detalhadas em locais remotos. Uma 
atividade dos dados em que os estudantes nas classes 9-12 podem 
analisar gráficos com dados reais de 1997-2000 é incluída no fundo 
do local. Esta atividade conforma-se aos padrões nacionais da 
correlação da ciência para classes 9-12 (como indicado no Web 
site).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Web site offre una breve descrizione della 
marea rossa e delle alghe tossiche responsabili di esso. 
Parecchie parole e frasi all'interno del sommario sono 
hyperlinked alle spiegazioni più dettagliate sui luoghi a distanza. 
Un'attività di dati in cui gli allievi nei gradi 9-12 possono 
analizzare i grafici con i dati reali da 1997-2000 è inclusa alla 
parte inferiore del luogo. Questa attività è conforme agli 
standard nazionali di correlazione di scienza per i gradi 9-12 (come 
indicato sul Web site).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος προσφέρει μια συνοπτική επισκόπηση 
της κόκκινης παλίρροιας και των τοξικών αλγών αρμόδιων για την. 
Διάφορες λέξεις και φράσεις μέσα στην περίληψη είναι στις 
πιό λεπτομερείς εξηγήσεις στις απομακρυσμένες περιοχές. Μια
δραστηριότητα στοιχείων στην οποία οι σπουδαστές στους βαθμούς 
9-12 μπορούν να αναλύσουν τις γραφικές παραστάσεις με τα 
πραγματικά στοιχεία από το 1997-2000 συμπεριλαμβάνεται στο 
κατώτατο σημείο της περιοχής. Αυτή η δραστηριότητα 
προσαρμόζεται στα εθνικά πρότυπα συσχετισμού επιστήμης για τους 
βαθμούς 9-12 (όπως υποδεικνύεται στον ιστοχώρο).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este Web site ofrece una descripción abreviada de
la marea roja y de las algas tóxicas responsables de él. 
Varias palabras y frases dentro del resumen son hyperlinked a 
explicaciones más detalladas en sitios alejados. Una actividad 
de los datos en la cual los estudiantes en grados 9-12 pueden analizar
gráficos con datos verdaderos a partir de 1997-2000 es incluida en el
fondo del sitio. Esta actividad se conforma con los estándares 
nacionales de la correlación de la ciencia para los grados 9-12 
(según lo indicado en el Web site).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:THE BRIDGE
FN:THE BRIDGE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:SEA GRANT MARINE ADVISORY SERVICES; VIRGINIA INSTITUTE OF MARINE SCIENCE; COLLEGE OF WILLIAM AND MARY
FN:SEA GRANT MARINE ADVISORY SERVICES; VIRGINIA INSTITUTE OF MARINE SCIENCE; COLLEGE OF WILLIAM AND MARY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203314</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105560</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/in-full-bloom</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
