<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105445</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105445</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974125</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Lifting the Spirit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Anheben des Geistes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Levage de l'esprit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Levantando o espírito</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sollevamento dello spirito</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανύψωση του πνεύματος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Elevación del alcohol</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Freedom of religion or belief is an increasingly relevant topic in human society. Lifting the Spirit: Human Rights and Freedom of Religion or Belief provides comprehensive and thought-provoking lessons about the human right to freedom of religion or belief without surveying world religions or endorsing any particular belief. Lifting the Spirit relates the worship, observances, practices, and teachings of all religions and beliefs to fundamental human rights principles. It provides background information, ideas for taking action, and interactive exercises to help people learn about the freedom of religion or belief: a right that is guaranteed in Article 18 of the Universal Declaration of Human Rights. Designed for use in secondary classrooms, religious institutions, and youth advocacy organizations around the world, both the content and organization of Lifting the Spirit aim to be adaptable to many different national and cultural settings.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Freiheit der Religion oder des Glaubens ist ein in
zunehmendem Maße relevantes Thema in der menschlichen Gesellschaft. 
Anheben des Geistes: Menschliche Rechte und Freiheit der 
Religion oder des Glaubens stellt die kompletten und 
Gedanke-erregenden Lektionen über das menschliche Recht zur Freiheit 
der Religion oder des Glaubens ohne überblickenweltreligionen oder 
zum Indossieren jedes bestimmten Glaubens zur Verfügung. Das 
Anheben des Geistes steht die Anbetung, die Befolgungen, die Praxis 
und den Unterricht aller Religionen und Glaubens auf grundlegenden 
Grundregeln der menschlichen Rechte in Verbindung. Es liefert 
Hintergrundinformationen, Ideen für das Ergreifen von von Maßnahmen,
und interaktive Übungen zu den Hilfe Leuten erlernen über die 
Freiheit der Religion oder des Glaubens: ein Recht, das in 
Artikel 18 der Universalerklärung der menschlichen Rechte garantiert 
wird. Konzipiert für Gebrauch in den Sekundärklassenzimmern, 
in den frommen Anstalten und in den Jugendbefürwortung Organisationen
um die Welt, zielen der Inhalt und die Organisation des Anhebens des 
Geistes darauf ab, zu vielen unterschiedlichen nationalen und 
kulturellen Einstellungen anpassungsfähig zu sein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La liberté religieuse ou la croyance est un sujet
de plus en plus approprié dans la société humaine. Levage de 
l'esprit : Les droits de l'homme et la liberté religieuse ou la
croyance fournit des leçons complètes et pensée-provoquantes au 
sujet du droit de l'homme à la liberté religieuse ou la croyance 
sans religions examinantes du monde ou à approuver n'importe quelle 
croyance particulière. Le levage de l'esprit associe le culte, 
les observances, les pratiques, et les enseignements de toutes les 
religions et croyance aux principes fondamentaux de droits de l'homme.
Il fournit l'information de fond, idées pour agir, et les 
exercices interactifs aux personnes d'aide se renseignent sur la 
liberté religieuse ou la croyance : une droite qui est garantie
en article 18 de la déclaration universelle des droits de l'homme. 
Conçu pour l'usage dans les salles de classe secondaires, les 
établissements religieux, et les organismes de recommandation de la 
jeunesse autour du monde, la teneur et l'organisation de soulever 
l'esprit visent à être adaptables à beaucoup de différentes 
configurations nationales et culturelles.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A liberdade de religião ou de opinião é um 
tópico cada vez mais relevante na sociedade humana. Levantando 
o espírito: As direitas humanas e a liberdade de religião ou 
de opinião fornecem lições detalhadas e pensamento-provocando sobre
a direita humana à liberdade de religião ou de opinião sem 
religiões examinando do mundo ou a endossar toda a opinião 
particular. Levantar o espírito relaciona a adoração, os 
observances, as práticas, e os ensinos de todas as religiões e 
opinião aos princípios fundamentais das direitas humanas. 
Fornece a informação de fundo, idéias para fazer exame da 
ação, e os exercícios interativos aos povos da ajuda aprendem sobre
a liberdade de religião ou de opinião: uma direita que seja 
garantida no artigo 18 da declaração universal de direitas humanas. 
Projetado para o uso em salas de aula secundárias, em 
instituições religiosas, e em organizações do advocacy da 
juventude em torno do mundo,  o índice e a organização de levantar 
o espírito apontam ser adaptable a muitos ajustes nacionais e 
cultural diferentes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La libertà della religione o della credenza è un
soggetto sempre più relativo nella società umana. Sollevamento
dello spirito: I diritti dell'uomo e la libertà della religione
o della credenza fornisce le lezioni complete e diprovocazioni circa 
il diritto dell'uomo alla libertà della religione o della credenza 
senza religioni d'esame del mondo o a firmare tutta la credenza 
particolare. Il sollevamento dello spirito collega il culto, i 
rispetti, le pratiche e gli insegnamenti di tutte le religioni e 
credenza ai principii fondamentali di diritti dell'uomo. 
Fornisce le informazioni di base, idee per agire e le 
esercitazioni interattive alla gente di aiuto imparano circa la 
libertà della religione o della credenza: una destra che è 
garantita in articolo 18 della dichiarazione universale dei diritti 
dell'uomo. Progettato per uso in aule secondarie, nelle 
istituzioni religiose e nelle organizzazioni di avvocatura della 
gioventù intorno al mondo, sia il contenuto che l'organizzazione di 
sollevamento dello spirito mirano ad essere adattabili a molte 
regolazioni nazionali e culturali differenti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ελευθερία της θρησκείας ή της πεποίθησης είναι ένα
όλο και περισσότερο σχετικό θέμα στην ανθρώπινη κοινωνία. 
Ανύψωση του πνεύματος: Τα ανθρώπινα δικαιώματα και η 
ελευθερία της θρησκείας ή της πεποίθησης παρέχουν περιεκτικό και
την σκέψη-πρόκληση των μαθημάτων για το ανθρώπινο δικαίωμα στην 
ελευθερία της θρησκείας ή της πεποίθησης χωρίς την έρευνα των 
παγκόσμιων θρησκειών ή επικύρωση οποιασδήποτε ιδιαίτερης 
πεποίθησης. Η ανύψωση του πνεύματος αφορά αρχές τη 
λατρεία, τις τηρήσεις, τις πρακτικές, και τις διδασκαλίες όλων 
των θρησκειών και των πεποιθήσεων τις θεμελιώδεις των ανθρώπινων 
δικαιωμάτων. Παρέχει τις βασικές πληροφορίες, τις ιδέες για
τη λήψη μέτρων, και τις διαλογικές ασκήσεις για να βοηθήσει τους 
ανθρώπους να μάθουν για την ελευθερία της θρησκείας ή της 
πεποίθησης: ένα δικαίωμα που είναι εγγυημένο στο άρθρο 
18 της καθολικής Διακήρυξης των ανθρώπινων δικαιωμάτων. 
Σχεδιασμένος για τη χρήση στις δευτεροβάθμιες τάξεις, τα 
θρησκευτικά όργανα, και τις οργανώσεις υπεράσπισης 
νεολαίας σε όλο τον κόσμο, και το περιεχόμενο και οργάνωση της 
ανύψωσης του στόχου πνευμάτων να είναι προσαρμόσιμος σε πολλές 
διαφορετικές εθνικές και πολιτιστικές τιμές των παραμέτρων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Libertad o la creencia es un asunto cada vez más 
relevante en sociedad humana. Elevación del alcohol: Los 
derechos humanos y libertad o la creencia proporciona a lecciones 
comprensivas y pensamiento-que provocan sobre el derecho humano 
libertad o la creencia sin religiones del mundo que examinan o a 
endosar cualquier creencia determinada. La elevación del 
alcohol relaciona la adoración, las observancias, las prácticas, y 
las enseñanzas de todas las religiones y creencia con los principios 
fundamentales de los derechos humanos. Proporciona a la 
información de fondo, ideas para tomar la acción, y los ejercicios 
interactivos a la gente de la ayuda aprenden sobre libertad o la 
creencia: una derecha que está garantizada en el artículo 18 
del declaración universal de derechos humanos. Diseñado para 
el uso en salas de clase secundarias, instituciones religiosas, y 
organizaciones de la defensa de la juventud alrededor del mundo, el 
contenido y la organización de levantar el alcohol apuntan ser 
adaptables a muchas diversas configuraciones nacionales y culturales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974125</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105445</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/lifting-the-spirit</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
