<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104975</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104975</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211388</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Observe River Erosion Creating Waterfalls and Chasms</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Beobachten Sie Fluss-Abnutzung, Wasserfälle und 
Abgründe herzustellen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Observez l'érosion de fleuve créer des chutes 
d'eau et des abîmes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Observe a erosão do rio criar cachoeiras e 
chasms</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Osservi l'erosione del fiume creare le cascate ed 
i chasms</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παρατηρήστε τη διάβρωση ποταμών τους καταρράκτες και 
τα χάσματα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Observe la erosión del río el crear de las 
cascadas y de los chasms</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This animation illustrates the processes involved in waterfall formation. Related features such as chasms and plunge pools, as well as headward erosion and migration are also portrayed. Users can stop, play, fast forward and rewind the animation at any time. This visualization is one of several animations in a series developed as a component of Exploring Earth, a website that supports the textbook Earth Science.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Animation veranschaulicht die Prozesse, die 
in Wasserfallanordnung mit einbezogen werden. In Verbindung 
stehende Merkmale wie Abgründe und Messfingerpools, sowie headward 
Abnutzung und Migration werden auch geschildert. Benutzer 
können stoppen, spielen, schnelles Vorwärts und die Animation 
jederzeit rückspulen. Diese Sichtbarmachung ist eine einiger 
Animationen in einer Serie, die als Bestandteil der erforschenden 
Masse, eine Web site entwickelt wird, die die Lehrbuch Geowissenschaft
unterstützt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette animation illustre les processus impliqués 
dans la formation de chute d'eau. Des dispositifs relatifs tels 
que des abîmes et des regroupements de plongeon, aussi bien que 
l'érosion de headward et le transfert sont également dépeints. 
Les utilisateurs peuvent s'arrêter, jouer, vers l'avant rapide 
et rebobiner l'animation à tout moment. Cette visualisation est
l'une de plusieurs animations d'une série développée comme 
composant de la terre l'explorant, un site Web qui supporte la science
de la terre de manuel.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este animation ilustra os processos envolvidos na 
formação da cachoeira. As características relacionadas tais 
como chasms e pools do mergulho, as.well.as a erosão do headward e a 
migração portrayed também. Os usuários podem parar, jogar, 
para diante rápido e rebobinar o animation em em qualquer altura que.
Este visualization é um de diversos animations em uma série 
desenvolvida como um componente da terra explorando, um Web site que 
suporte a ciência de terra do textbook.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa animazione illustra i processi addetti alla
formazione della cascata. Le caratteristiche relative quali i 
chasms e gli stagni di immersione, così come erosione di headward ed 
espansione egualmente sono ritratte. Gli utenti possono 
arrestarsi, giocare, di andata veloce e riavvolgere in qualunque 
momento la animazione. Questa visualizzazione è una di 
parecchie animazioni in serie sviluppata come componente di terra 
d'esplorazione, un Web site che sostiene le scienze della terra del 
manuale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η ζωτικότητα επεξηγεί τις διαδικασίες που 
περιλαμβάνονται στο σχηματισμό καταρρακτών. Τα σχετικά 
χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα όπως οι λίμνες χασμάτων και κατάδυσης,
καθώς επίσης και headward η διάβρωση και η μετανάστευση 
απεικονίζονται επίσης. Οι χρήστες μπορούν να σταματήσουν, 
να παίξουν, να διαβιβάζουν γρήγορα και να ξανατυλίξουν τη 
ζωτικότητα οποιαδήποτε στιγμή. Αυτή η απεικόνιση είναι μια
από διάφορες ζωτικότητες σε μια σειρά που αναπτύσσεται ως 
συστατικό τη γη, ένας ιστοχώρος που υποστηρίζει τη γήινη 
επιστήμη εγχειριδίων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta animación ilustra los procesos implicados en
la formación de la cascada. Las características relacionadas 
tales como chasms y piscinas de la zambullida, así como la erosión 
del headward y la migración también se retratan. Los 
utilizadores pueden parar, jugar, delantero rápido y rebobinar la 
animación en cualquier momento. Esta visualización es una de 
varias animaciones en una serie desarrollada como componente de la 
tierra que explora, un Web site que utilice la geología del libro de 
textos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211388</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104975</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/observe-river-erosion-creating-waterfalls-and-chasms</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
