<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/849678493</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>849678493</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206087</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Solar System Exploration</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Solarsystem Erforschung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Exploration de Système Solaire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Exploração Do Sistema Solar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Esplorazione Del Sistema Solare</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εξερεύνηση ηλιακών συστημάτων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Exploración De la Sistema Solar</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features lesson plans on electro-magnetism, energy, exploration, gravity, pioneers, landforms, life, light, math ratios, matter, measurement, modeling, origin, planet surfaces, rocks and minerals, the scientific method, and triangulation. Classroom and informal learning activities focus on meteorites, comets, the sun, planet change and constancy, the search for life in the solar system, and missions to outer planets.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">kennzeichnet Lektionpläne auf Elektromagnetismus, 
Energie, Erforschung, Schwerkraft, Pioniere, landforms, Leben, Licht, 
Matheverhältnisse, Stoff, Messen, Formung, Ursprung, Planet 
Oberflächen, Felsen und Mineralien, die wissenschaftliche Methode und
Triangulation. Klassenzimmer und formlose Lernenaktivitäten 
konzentrieren auf Meteorite, Kometen, die Sonne, Planet Änderung und 
Beständigkeit, die Suche nach dem Leben im Solarsystem und Missionen 
zu den äußeren Planeten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">comporte des plans de leçon sur 
l'électromagnétisme, l'énergie, l'exploration, la pesanteur, les 
pionniers, les formes de relief, la vie, la lumière, les taux de maths, la
matière, la mesure, modeler, l'origine, les surfaces de planète, les
roches et les minerais, la méthode scientifique, et triangulation. 
La salle de classe et l'étude sans cérémonie se concentrent 
sur des météorites, des comètes, le soleil, changement et constance
de planète, la recherche pendant la vie dans le système solaire, et 
des missions aux planètes extérieures.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">caracteriza plantas da lição no 
electro-magnetism, a energia, a exploração, a gravidade, os 
pioneiros, os landforms, a vida, a luz, as relações do math, a 
matéria, a medida, modelar, a origem, as superfícies do planeta, as 
rochas e os minerais, o método científico, e triangulation. A 
sala de aula e as atividades de aprendizagem informais focalizam em 
meteorites, cometas, o sol, mudança e constancy do planeta, a busca 
para a vida no sistema solar, e missões aos planetas exteriores.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">caratterizza i programmi di lezione su 
elettromagnetismo, energia, esplorazione, gravità, pionieri, 
landforms, vita, luce, rapporti di per la matematica, materia, misura,
modellare, origine, superfici del pianeta, roccie e minerali, il 
metodo scientifico e triangulation. L'aula e le attività 
imparanti informali mettono a fuoco sui meteoriti, comete, il sole, 
cambiamento e costanza del pianeta, la ricerca di vita nel sistema 
solare e missioni ai pianeti esterni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χαρακτηρίζει τα σχέδια μαθήματος για τον 
ηλεκτρομαγνητισμό, την ενέργεια, την εξερεύνηση, τη βαρύτητα, τους
πρωτοπόρους, landforms, τη ζωή, το φως, math τις αναλογίες, 
το θέμα, τη μέτρηση, τη διαμόρφωση, την προέλευση, τις επιφάνειες
πλανητών, τους βράχους και τα μεταλλεύματα, την επιστημονική 
μέθοδο, και triangulation. Η τάξη και οι άτυπες 
δραστηριότητες εκμάθησης εστιάζουν στους μετεωρίτες, τους 
κομήτες, τον ήλιο, την αλλαγή και τη σταθερότητα πλανητών, την 
αναζήτηση της ζωής στο ηλιακό σύστημα, και τις αποστολές στους 
εξωτερικούς πλανήτες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece planes de la lección en electromagnetismo, 
energía, exploración, gravedad, los pioneros, los landforms, vida, 
luz, las relaciones de transformación de la matemáticas, materia, 
medida, el modelar, origen, las superficies del planeta, las rocas y 
los minerales, el método científico, y triangulación. La sala
de clase y las actividades que aprenden informales se centran en los 
meteoritos, los cometas, el sol, cambio y constancia del planeta, la 
búsqueda para la vida en la Sistema Solar, y las misiones en los 
planetas externos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206087</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>849678493</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/solar-system-exploration</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
