<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108763</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108763</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086869</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Susie King Taylor Assists the First South Carolina Volunteers, 1862-1864</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Susie König Taylor Assists die ersten 
Südcarolina Freiwilliger, 1862-1864</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Roi Taylor Assists de Susie les premiers 
volontaires du sud de la Caroline, 1862-1864</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Rei Alfaiate Ajudar de Susie os primeiros 
voluntários de carolina sul, 1862-1864</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Re Taylor Assists di Susie i primi volontari della
Carolina del Sud, 1862-1864</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο βασιλιάς taylor Susie βοηθά τους πρώτους 
εθελοντές της νότιας Καρολίνας, 1862-1864</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Rey Taylor Assists de Susie los primeros 
voluntarios de Carolina del Sur, 1862-1864</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Susie King Taylor was born a slave in Savannah, Georgia, in 1848. In the summer of 1862, only 14 years old, she taught school to liberated slaves on St. Simon's Island, Georgia, behind Union lines. As this section of her  Reminiscences  began, King met Captain C.T. Trowbridge who, along with fellow Union officers, arrived on the island to gather black troops for what would become the First South Carolina Volunteers, the 33rd Regiment. When Trowbridge and the Volunteers left St. Simon's Island, King accompanied them. Initially taken as a laundress, her duties expanded to include clerical work and nursing. For the next few years, King assisted as the troops traveled and battled through South Carolina, Georgia, and Florida. Taylor met her husband, Edward Taylor, a sergeant in the 33rd Regiment, on St. Simon's Island. After the war, the Taylors settled in Savannah. Later, after her husband died in an accident, King moved to Boston, where she remarried. She died in 1912.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Susie König Taylor war ein Sklave in der Savanne,
Georgia, 1848 geboren. Am Sommer von 1862, nur 14 Jahre alt, 
unterrichtete sie befreiten Sklaven auf Str. Simons Insel, Georgia 
Schule, hinter Anschlußzeilen. Während dieses Kapitel ihrer 
Erinnerungen anfing, traf König Kapitän C.T. Trowbridge, der, 
zusammen mit Gefährteanschlußoffizieren, auf der Insel ankam, um zu 
erfassen schwarze Truppen für was den ersten Südcarolina 
Freiwilligern stehen würde, das 33rd Regiment. Als Trowbridge 
und die Freiwilliger Str. Simons Insel verließen, begleitete König 
sie. Als laundress zuerst genommen, erweiterten ihre Aufgaben, 
um Verwaltungsarbeit und Krankenpflege einzuschließen. Für die
nächsten Jahre unterstützte König, während die Truppen durch 
Südcarolina, Georgia und Florida reisten und kämpften. 
Schneider traf ihren Ehemann, Edward Schneider, ein 
Sergeant im 33rd Regiment, auf Str. Simons Insel. Nach dem
Krieg rechneten die Schneider in der Savanne ab. Später nachdem
ihr Ehemann in einem Unfall starb, zog König nach Boston um, in dem 
sie remarried. Sie starb 1912.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Roi Taylor de Susie est né un slave dans 
la savane, la Géorgie, en 1848. En été de 1862, seulement 14 
ans de , elle a enseigné l'école aux esclaves libérés sur l'île 
de rue Simon, la Géorgie, derrière des lignes des syndicats. 
Pendant que cette section de ses réminiscences commençait, le 
roi a rencontré capitaine C.T. Trowbridge qui, avec des dirigeants 
syndicaux de camarade, est arrivé sur l'île pour recueillir les 
troupes noires pour ce qui irait bien aux premiers volontaires 
Du sud de la Caroline, le trente-troisième régiment. 
Quand Trowbridge et les volontaires ont quitté l'île de rue 
Simon, le roi les a accompagnés. Au commencement pris en tant 
que blanchisseuse, ses fonctions ont augmenté pour inclure le travail de
bureau et les soins. Pendant les années à venir, le roi a 
aidé pendant que les troupes voyageaient et luttaient par la Caroline
Du sud, la Géorgie, et la Floride. Le tailleur a 
rencontré son mari, le tailleur d'Edouard, un sergent dans le 
trente-troisième régiment, sur l'île de rue Simon. Après la 
guerre, les tailleurs ont soldé le compte dans la savane. Plus 
tard, après que son mari soit mort dans un accident, le roi s'est 
déplacé à Boston, où elle remarried. Elle est morte en 1912.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O rei Alfaiate de Susie foi carregado um escravo 
no savannah, Geórgia, em 1848. No verão de 1862, somente 14 
anos velho, ensinou a escola aos escravos liberated no console do St. 
Simon, Geórgia, atrás das linhas da união. Enquanto esta 
seção de seus reminiscences começou, o rei encontrou-se com o 
capitão C.T. Trowbridge que, junto com oficiais de união do 
companheiro, chegou no console para recolher tropas pretas para o que 
assentaria bem nos primeiros voluntários de carolina sul, o 3ó 
regiment. Quando Trowbridge e os voluntários sairam do console 
do St. Simon, o rei acompanhou-o. Feito exame inicialmente como 
laundress, seus deveres expandiram para incluir o trabalho de 
escritório e os cuidados. Por poucos anos seguintes, o rei 
ajudou enquanto as tropas viajaram e battled através de carolina sul,
de Geórgia, e de Florida. O alfaiate encontrou-se com seu 
marido, alfaiate de Edward, um sergeant no 3ó regiment, no console do
St. Simon. Após a guerra, os alfaiates estabeleciram-se no 
savannah. Mais tarde, depois que seu marido morreu em um 
acidente, o rei moveu-se para Boston, onde remarried. Morreu em 
1912.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il re Taylor di Susie è stato sopportato uno 
schiavo in savanna, la Georgia, in 1848. di estate di 1862, 
vecchio soltanto 14 anni, ha insegnato la scuola agli schiavi liberati
sull'isola della st Simon, la Georgia, dietro le righe del sindacato. 
Mentre questa sezione delle sue reminiscenze ha cominciato, il 
re ha venuto a contatto del capitano C.T. Trowbridge che, con gli 
ufficiali del sindacato del collega, è arrivato sull'isola per 
riunire le truppe nere per che cosa stare bene ai primi 
volontari della Carolina del Sud, il trentatreesimo regiment. 
Quando Trowbridge ed i volontari hanno lasciato l'isola della st
Simon, il re li ha accompagnati. Inizialmente preso come i 
laundress, le sue funzioni si sono espanse per includere il lavoro 
d'ufficio e la professione d'infermiera. Per i prossimi anni, il
re ha aiutato mentre le truppe hanno attraversato e combattuto through
Carolina del Sud, la Georgia e Florida. Il sarto ha venuto a 
contatto del suo marito, sarto di Edward, un sergeant nel 
trentatreesimo regiment, sull'isola della st Simon. Dopo la 
guerra, i sarti si sono depositati in savanna. Più 
successivamente, dopo che il suo marito morisse in un incidente, il re
si è mosso verso Boston, in cui remarried. È morto in 1912.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο βασιλιάς taylor Susie γεννήθηκε ένας σκλάβος 
στη σαβάνα, Γεωργία, το 1848. Το καλοκαίρι 1862, μόνο 
14 ετών, δίδαξε το σχολείο στους ελευθερωμένους σκλάβους στο 
νησί του ST simon, Γεωργία, πίσω από τις γραμμές ένωσης. 
Δεδομένου ότι αυτό το τμήμα reminiscences της άρχισε, ο 
βασιλιάς συνάντησε τον καπετάνιο C.T. Trowbridge που, μαζί 
με τους συντροφικούς ανώτερους υπαλλήλους ένωσης, έφθασε στο 
νησί για να συλλέξει τα μαύρα στρατεύματα για αυτό που θα 
γινόταν οι πρώτοι εθελοντές της νότιας Καρολίνας, το 33$ο 
σύνταγμα. Όταν Trowbridge και οι εθελοντές άφησαν το 
νησί του ST simon, ο βασιλιάς τους συνόδευσε. Αρχικά 
λήφθεία ως πλύντρια, τα καθήκοντά της επεκτάθηκαν για να 
περιλάβουν τη γραφείου εργασία και την περιποίηση. Για τα 
επόμενα μερικά έτη, ο βασιλιάς που βοηθήθηκε ως στρατεύματα 
ταξίδεψε και μαχόταν μέσω της νότιας Καρολίνας, της Γεωργίας, 
και της Φλώριδας. Taylor συνάντησε το σύζυγό της, 
Edward Taylor, ένας λοχίας στο 33$ο σύνταγμα, στο νησί του 
ST simon. Μετά από τον πόλεμο, το Taylors 
εγκατέστησε στη σαβάνα. Αργότερα, μετά από το σύζυγό της 
πέθανε σε ένα ατύχημα, βασιλιάς που κινήθηκε προς τη Βοστώνη, 
όπου. Πέθανε το 1912.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Rey Taylor de Susie nació un esclavo en la 
sabana, Georgia, en 1848. En el verano de 1862, solamente 14 
años de viejo, ella enseñó la escuela a los esclavos liberados en 
la isla del St. Simon, Georgia, detrás de líneas de la unión. 
Mientras que esta sección de sus reminiscencias comenzó, el 
rey satisfizo a capitán C.T. Trowbridge que, junto con oficiales de 
unión del compañero, llegó en la isla para recolectar a tropas 
negras para qué sintió bien a los primeros voluntarios de Carolina 
del Sur, el 33ro regimiento. Cuando Trowbridge y los voluntarios
salieron de la isla del St. Simon, el rey los acompañó. Tomado
inicialmente como laundress, sus deberes se ampliaron para incluir el 
trabajo y el oficio de enfermera de oficina. Por los años 
próximos, el rey asistió mientras que las tropas viajaron y lucharon
a través de Carolina del Sur, de Georgia, y de la Florida. La 
personalización satisfizo a su marido, personalización de Edward, 
sargento en el 33ro regimiento, en la isla del St. Simon. 
Después de la guerra, las personalizaciones colocaron en 
sabana. Más adelante, después de que su marido muriera en un 
accidente, el rey se trasladó a Boston, en donde ella remarried. 
Ella murió en 1912.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086869</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108763</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/susie-king-taylor-assists-the-first-south-carolina-volunteers-1862-1864</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
