<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103800</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103800</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087086</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Zimmerman Telegram: Bringing America Closer to War</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Zimmerman Telegramm: Holen von von 
Amerika näeher an Krieg</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Télégramme de Zimmerman : Apporter 
l'Amérique plus près de la guerre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Telegrama De Zimmerman: Trazendo América 
mais perto da guerra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Telegramma Di Zimmerman: Portare 
l'America più vicino alla guerra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το τηλεγράφημα Zimmerman: Φέρνοντας Αμερική 
πιό κοντά στον πόλεμο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Telegrama De Zimmerman: Traer América 
más cercano a guerra</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">At the end of January 1917, the German government--desperate to break the stalemated trench warfare--announced that it would resume unrestricted submarine attacks. The United States broke diplomatic relations with Germany and further events pushed the nation even closer to war. On March 1, newspapers published a telegram from German foreign minister Arthur Zimmermann to the Mexican government, proposing a German-Mexican alliance against the United States. (For attacking the United States, the Mexicans would recoup lost territory in Texas, New Mexico, and Arizona.) Intercepted by the British, the telegram was published widely in American newspapers and inflamed popular opinion against the Germans.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Am Ende Januar 1917, die deutsche Regierung -- 
hoffnungslos die ausgeschaltete Grabenkriegsführung brechen -- 
verkündet, daß sie uneingeschränkte Unterwasserangriffe wieder 
aufnehmen würde. Die Vereinigten Staaten brachen diplomatische 
Relationen mit Deutschland und weitere Fälle drückten die Nation 
sogar näeher an Krieg. An März 1, veröffentlichten Zeitungen 
ein Telegramm vom deutschen Außenminister Arthur Zimmermann zur 
mexikanischen Regierung und schlugen ein Deutsch-Mexikanisches 
Bündnis gegen die Vereinigten Staaten vor. (für das In Angriff
nehmen der Vereinigten Staaten, würde der Mexikaner verlorene Gegend 
in Texas, in New-Mexico und im Arizona. wiedereinbringen) 
Abgefangen durch die Briten, wurde das Telegramm weit in den 
amerikanischen Zeitungen veröffentlicht und populäre Meinung gegen 
die Deutschen entflammte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">À fin janvier 1917, le gouvernement allemand -- 
désespéré pour casser la guerre interrompue de fossé -- annoncé 
qu'elle reprendrait des attaques submersibles sans restriction. 
Les Etats-Unis ont cassé des relations diplomatiques avec 
l'Allemagne et d'autres événements ont poussé la nation même plus 
près de la guerre. Mars 1, les journaux ont édité un 
télégramme de ministre des affaires étrangères allemand Arthur 
Zimmermann au gouvernement mexicain, proposant une alliance 
Allemand-Mexicaine contre les Etats-Unis. (pour attaquer les 
Etats-Unis, le Mexicain récupérerait le territoire perdu le Texas, 
au Nouveau-Mexique, et en Arizona.) Arrêté par les Anglais, le
télégramme a été édité largement en journaux américains et a 
enflamé l'opinion populaire contre les Allemands.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No fim de janeiro 1917, o governo alemão -- 
desesperado para quebrar a guerra interrompida da trincheira -- 
anunciado que recomeçaria ataques submarinos irrestritos. Os 
estados unidos quebraram relações diplomatic com Germany e uns 
eventos mais adicionais empurraram a nação mesmo mais perto da 
guerra. Março em 1, os jornais publicaram um telegrama do 
ministro extrangeiro alemão Arthur Zimmermann ao governo mexicano, 
propondo um alliance Alemão-Mexicano de encontro aos estados unidos. 
(para atacar os estados unidos, o mexicano recoup território 
perdido em Texas, em Novo México, e em arizona.) Interceptado 
pelos Ingleses, o telegrama foi publicado extensamente em jornais 
americanos e inflamed a opinião popular de encontro aos alemães.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Alla conclusione di gennaio del 1917, il governo 
tedesco -- disperato rompere la guerra interrotta della trincea -- 
annunciato che riprenderebbe gli attacchi sottomarini senza 
restrizione. Unito Dichiara ha rotto i rapporti 
diplomatici con la Germania ed ulteriori eventi hanno spinto la 
nazione anche più vicino alla guerra. Il 1 marzo, i giornali 
hanno pubblicato un telegramma dal ministro straniero Arthur 
Zimmermann del tedesco al governo messicano, proponente un'alleanza 
di German-messicano contro unito Dichiara. (per d'attacco 
unito Dichiara, il mexicans recupererebbe il territorio perso 
il Texas, nel Nuovo Messico ed in Arizona.) Intercettato dai 
Britannici, il telegramma è stato pubblicato ampiamente in giornali 
americani ed ha infiammato l'opinione popolare contro i 
tedeschi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στο τέλος τον Ιανουαρίου του 1917, η γερμανική 
κυβέρνηση -- απελπισμένη για να σπάσουν την ακινητοποιημένη 
εχθροπραξία τάφρων -- ανήγγειλε ότι θα επανελάμβανε τις 
απεριόριστες υποβρύχιες επιθέσεις. Οι Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες 
έσπασαν τις διπλωματικές σχέσεις με τη Γερμανία και τα περαιτέρω 
γεγονότα ωθώ το έθνος ακόμα πιό κοντά στον πόλεμο. την 1η
Μαρτίου, οι εφημερίδες δημοσίευσαν ένα τηλεγράφημα από το 
γερμανικό υπουργό Εξωτερικών αρθούρος Zimmermann στη 
μεξικάνικη κυβέρνηση, προτείνω μια γερμανικός-μεξικάνικη 
συμμαχία ενάντια στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες. (Για να επιτεθούν
στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες, οι μεξικανοί θα αποζημίωναν χαμένο 
έδαφος στο Τέξας, το New Mexico, και την Αριζόνα.) 
Παρεμποδισμένο από τους Βρετανούς, το τηλεγράφημα 
δημοσιεύθηκε ευρέως στις αμερικανικές εφημερίδες και την άκαυστη 
δημοφιλή άποψη ενάντια στους Γερμανούς.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">A finales de enero de 1917, el gobierno alemán --
desesperado romper la guerra estancada del foso -- anunciado que 
reasumiría ataques submarinos sin restricción. Los Estados 
Unidos rompieron relaciones diplomáticas con Alemania y otros 
acontecimientos empujaron la nación incluso más cercano a guerra. 
De marcha la 1, los periódicos publicaron un telegrama del 
Ministro de Asuntos Exteriores alemán Arturo Zimmermann al gobierno 
mexicano, proponiendo una alianza Alema'n-Mexicana contra los Estados 
Unidos. (para atacar los Estados Unidos, el mexicano 
recuperaría el territorio perdido en Tejas, New México, y el 
Arizona.) Interceptado por los Británicos, el telegrama fue 
publicado extensamente en periódicos americanos e inflamó la 
opinión popular contra los alemanes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087086</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103800</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-zimmerman-telegram-bringing-america-closer-to-war</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
