<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106047</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106047</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204520</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Interdisciplinary integrated unit on DNA and genetics Part A: Science</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Interdisziplinäre integrierte Maßeinheit auf DNA
und Genetik zerteilen A: Wissenschaft</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'unité intégrée interdisciplinaire sur l'ADN 
et la génétique pièce A : La Science</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A unidade integrada interdisciplinary no DNA e os 
genetics peça A: Ciência</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'unità integrata interdisciplinare su DNA e la 
genetica parte A: Scienza</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διεπιστημονική ενσωματωμένη μονάδα στο DNA και το 
μέρος Α γενετικής: Επιστήμη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La unidad integrada interdisciplinaria en la DNA y
las genéticas pieza A: Ciencia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Part of an interdisciplinary week-long unit on DNA and genetics with activities in science, math, and language arts. This lesson is Part A: Science. Students complete a teacher-made scavenger hunt as an introduction to DNA and genetics, then watch a short video and use their science books to learn more about the topic. Students work in pairs to investigate DNA, genetics, and cloning through internet research and compile their information in the form of their own internet scavenger hunt.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Teil einer interdisziplinären Woche-langen 
Maßeinheit auf DNA und der Genetik mit Aktivitäten in der 
Wissenschaft, in Mathe und in den Sprachenkünsten. Diese 
Lektion ist Teil A: Wissenschaft. Kursteilnehmer führen 
eine Lehrer-gebildete Reinigerjagd als Einleitung zu DNA und zur 
Genetik durch, dann überwachen einen kurzen Bildschirm und benutzen 
ihre Wissenschaft Bücher, um mehr über das Thema zu erlernen. 
Kursteilnehmer arbeiten in den Paaren, um DNA, Genetik und 
Klonen durch Internet-Forschung nachzuforschen und ihre Informationen 
in Form von ihrer eigenen Internet-Reinigerjagd zu kompilieren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une partie d'une unité d'une semaine 
interdisciplinaire sur l'ADN et de la génétique avec des activités 
en science, maths, et arts de langage. Cette leçon est la 
partie A : La Science. Les étudiants terminent une chasse
professeur-faite à Scavenger comme introduction à l'ADN et à la 
génétique, puis observent un vidéo court et emploient leurs livres 
de la science pour apprendre plus au sujet du sujet. Les 
étudiants travaillent dans les paires pour étudier l'ADN, la 
génétique, et le clonage par la recherche d'Internet et pour 
compiler leur information sous forme de leur propre chasse à 
Scavenger d'Internet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Parte de uma unidade semana-longa 
interdisciplinary no DNA e do genetics com atividades na ciência, no 
math, e nas artes da língua. Esta lição é a parte A: 
Ciência. Os estudantes terminam uma caça professor-feita
do SCAVENGER como uma introdução ao DNA e ao genetics, então 
prestam atenção a um vídeo curto e usam seus livros da ciência 
aprender mais sobre o tópico. Os estudantes trabalham em pares 
para investigar o DNA, o genetics, e o cloning com a pesquisa do 
Internet e para compilar sua informação no formulário de sua 
própria caça do SCAVENGER do Internet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Parte di un'unità settimana-lunga 
interdisciplinare su DNA e della genetica con le attività nella 
scienza, nel per la matematica e nelle arti di linguaggio. 
Questa lezione fa parte A: Scienza. Gli allievi 
completano un pulitore insegnante-fatto cercano come 
introduzione a DNA ed alla genetica, allora guardano un video corto ed
usano i loro libri di scienza per imparare più circa il soggetto. 
Gli allievi lavorano negli accoppiamenti per studiare il DNA, la
genetica e la clonazione con la ricerca del Internet e compilare le 
loro informazioni sotto forma d'il loro proprio pulitore del Internet 
cerca.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μέρος μιας διεπιστημονικής μίας εβδομάδας μονάδας στο
DNA και της γενετικής με τις δραστηριότητες στην επιστήμη, 
math, και τις γλωσσικές τέχνες. Αυτό το μάθημα είναι 
μέρος Α: Επιστήμη. Οι σπουδαστές ολοκληρώνουν ένα 
δάσκαλος-γίνοντα κυνήγι οδοκαθαριστών ως εισαγωγή στο DNA και 
τη γενετική, κατόπιν ρολόι ένα σύντομο βίντεο και χρησιμοποιούν
τα βιβλία επιστήμης τους για να μάθουν περισσότεροι για το θέμα. 
Οι σπουδαστές εργάζονται ανά τα ζευγάρια για να ερευνήσουν 
το DNA, τη γενετική, και την κλωνοποίηση μέσω της έρευνας 
Διαδικτύου και να μεταγλωττίσουν τις πληροφορίες τους υπό μορφή 
του κυνηγιού οδοκαθαριστών Διαδικτύου τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Parte de una unidad semana-larga 
interdisciplinaria en la DNA y de genética con actividades en 
ciencia, matemáticas, y artes del lenguaje. Esta lección es la
parte A: Ciencia. Los estudiantes terminan una caza 
profesor-hecha del limpiador como introducción a la DNA y a la 
genética, entonces miran un vídeo corto y utilizan sus libros de la 
ciencia para aprender más sobre el asunto. Los estudiantes 
trabajan en pares para investigar la DNA, la genética, y la 
reproducción con la investigación del Internet y para compilar su 
información en la forma de su propia caza del limpiador del Internet.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JANE LENTZ
FN:JANE LENTZ
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JIMMY WHITE
FN:JIMMY WHITE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:TORI GOLDRICK
FN:TORI GOLDRICK
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MARLENE SMITH
FN:MARLENE SMITH
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204520</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106047</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/interdisciplinary-integrated-unit-on-dna-and-genetics-part-a-science</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
