<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103127</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103127</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086665</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">No laughing matter.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kein lachender Stoff.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Aucune matière riante.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nenhuma matéria rindo.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nessuna materia ridente.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κανένα θέμα γέλιου.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ninguna materia que ríe.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Many Americans blamed themselves for their troubles during the early years of the Great Depression. Middle-income workers, while financially better prepared for the economic hard times than were most workers, were psychologically vulnerable and often felt shame at even modest economic setbacks. With men out of work and deeply depressed, women also found it difficult to keep going. Mama</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Viele Amerikaner tadelten sich für ihre Mühen während 
der frühen Jahre des großen Tiefstands. Mittlere 
Einkommenarbeiter, wenn finanziell besserer vorbereitet während der 
ökonomischen harten Zeiten als die meisten waren Arbeiter, waren 
psychologisch verletzbar und glaubten häufig Schande an den 
gleichmäßigen bescheidenen ökonomischen Hindernissen. Wenn 
die Männer aus Arbeit heraus und tief niedergedrückt sind, fanden 
Frauen es auch schwierig zu gehen zu halten. Mutter</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Beaucoup d'Américains se sont blâmés de leurs ennuis 
pendant les premières années de la grande dépression. Les 
ouvriers moyens de revenu, tandis que financièrement meilleur 
disposé pour les périodes difficiles économiques que n'étaient la 
plupart des ouvriers, étaient psychologiquement vulnérables et ont 
souvent senti la honte à de même reculs économiques modestes. 
Les hommes sans emploi et étant profondément enfoncé, les 
femmes l'ont également trouvé difficile à continuer à aller. 
Maman</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Muitos americanos responsabilizaram-se por seus problemas 
durante os anos adiantados do depression grande. Os 
trabalhadores médios da renda, quando financeira melhor preparado por
os tempos duros econômicos do que eram a maioria de trabalhadores, 
eram psicològica vulneráveis e sentiam frequentemente o shame em 
setbacks econômicos modestos uniformes. Com os homens fora do 
trabalho e comprimidos profundamente, as mulheres encontraram também 
difícil de manter-se ir. Mama</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Molti Americani si sono incolpati di le loro difficoltà 
durante i primi anni della depressione grande. Gli operai 
centrali di reddito, mentre finanziariamente migliore per i tempi duri
economici della maggior parte dei operai, erano psicologicamente 
vulnerabili e spesso hanno ritenuto la vergogna alle persino 
battute d'arresto economiche modeste. Con gli uomini senza 
lavoro e profondamente depressi, le donne egualmente lo hanno trovato 
difficile continuare a andare. Mama</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πολλοί Αμερικανοί κατηγορήθηκαν για τα προβλήματά 
τους κατά τη διάρκεια των πρώτων ετών της μεγάλης οικονομικής 
κρίσης. Οι μεσαίου εισοδήματος εργαζόμενοι, ενώ οικονομικά
προετοιμάζεται καλύτερα για τους οικονομικούς σκληρούς χρόνους 
από ήταν οι περισσότεροι εργαζόμενοι, ήταν ψυχολογικά τρωτοί 
και αισθάνθηκαν συχνά την ντροπή ακόμη και στις μέτριες 
οικονομικές οπισθοδρομήσεις. Με τους άνδρες άνεργους και που
πιέστηκαν βαθειά, οι γυναίκες το βρήκαν επίσης δύσκολο να 
συνεχίσουν. Μαμά</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Muchos americanos se culparon por sus apuros durante los 
años de la gran depresión. Los trabajadores medios de la 
renta, mientras que financieramente son mejor preparado por los 
tiempos duros económicos que la mayoría de los trabajadores, eran 
psicologicamente vulnerables y sentían a menudo vergüenza en los 
reveses económicos modestos uniformes. Con los hombres sin 
trabajo y presionados profundamente, las mujeres también encontraron 
difícil de guardar el ir. Mama</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086665</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103127</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/no-laughing-matter</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
