<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103715</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103715</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206409</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Voices from the Days of Slavery: Former Slaves Tell Their Stories</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Stimmen von den Tagen der Sklaverei: 
Ehemalige Sklaven Erklären Ihre Geschichten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Voix des jours de l'esclavage : Les Anciens 
Esclaves Indiquent Leurs Histoires</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Vozes dos dias do slavery: Os Escravos 
Anteriores Dizem Suas Histórias</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Voci dai giorni di slavery: Gli Schiavi 
Precedenti Dicono Alle Loro Storia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Φωνές από τις ημέρες της σκλαβιάς: Οι 
προηγούμενοι σκλάβοι λένε τις ιστορίες τους</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Voces a partir de los días de la esclavitud: 
Los Esclavos Anteriores Cuentan Sus Historias</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features interviews with 23 former slaves (the oldest was 130 at the time of the interview). These nearly 7 hours of recordings provide a glimpse of what life was like for slaves and freedmen. The former slaves discuss how they felt about slavery, slaveholders, their families, and freedom. Several sing songs they learned during the time of their enslavement.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Merkmale Interviews mit 23 ehemaligen Sklaven (das
älteste war 130 zu der Zeit des Interviews). Diese fast 7 
Stunden der Aufnahmen liefern einen Blick, welcher Lebensdauer wie 
für Sklaven und Freedmen war. Die ehemaligen Sklaven behandeln,
wie sie über Sklaverei, slaveholders, ihre Familien und Freiheit 
fühlten. Mehrere singen Liede, die sie während der Zeit ihres 
enslavement erlernten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">entrevues de dispositifs avec 23 anciens esclaves 
(le plus vieux était 130 au moment de l'entrevue). Ces presque 
7 heures des enregistrements fournissent un aperçu de quelle vie 
était comme pour des esclaves et des freedmen. Les anciens 
esclaves discutent ce qu'ils ont pensé de l'esclavage, des 
slaveholders, de leurs familles, et de la liberté. Plusieurs 
chantent des chansons qu'elles ont apprises pendant la période de 
leur asservissement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">entrevistas das características com os 23 
escravos anteriores (o mais velho era 130 na altura da entrevista). 
Estas quase 7 horas das gravações fornecem um glimpse de que 
vida era como para escravos e freedmen. Os escravos anteriores 
discutem como sentiram sobre o slavery, os slaveholders, as suas 
famílias, e a liberdade. Diversos cantam canções que 
aprenderam durante a época de seu enslavement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">interviste delle caratteristiche con 23 schiavi 
precedenti (il più vecchio era 130 ai tempi dell'intervista). 
Queste quasi 7 ore delle registrazioni forniscono un glimpse di 
che vita era come per gli schiavi ed i freedmen. Gli ex schiavi 
discutono come hanno ritenuto circa slavery, gli slaveholders, le loro
famiglie e la libertà. Vari cantano le canzoni che hanno 
imparato durante il periodo del loro enslavement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χαρακτηρίζει τις συνεντεύξεις με 23 προηγούμενους 
σκλάβους (ο παλαιότερος ήταν 130 κατά την διάρκεια της 
συνέντευξης). Αυτές οι σχεδόν 7 ώρες των καταγραφών 
παρέχουν μια αναλαμπή ποιας ζωής ήταν όπως για τους σκλάβους και
τους απελευθέρους. Οι προηγούμενοι σκλάβοι συζητούν πώς 
αισθάνθηκαν για τη σκλαβιά, τα slaveholders, τις οικογένειές 
τους, και την ελευθερία. Αρκετοί τραγουδούν τα τραγούδια που
έμαθαν κατά τη διάρκεια του χρόνου της υποδούλωσής τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">entrevistas de las características con 23 
esclavos anteriores (el más viejo era 130 a la hora de la 
entrevista). Estas casi 7 horas de grabaciones proporcionan a 
una ojeada de qué vida era como para esclavos y freedmen. Los 
esclavos anteriores discuten cómo se sentían sobre esclavitud, 
slaveholders, sus familias, y la libertad. Varios cantan 
canciones que aprendieron durante la época de su enslavement.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206409</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103715</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/voices-from-the-days-of-slavery-former-slaves-tell-their-stories</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
