<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107880</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107880</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086778</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Reading the Fine Print: The Grandfather Clause in Louisiana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ablesen des feinen Druckes: Die 
großväterliche Klausel in Louisiana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Lecture de la copie fine : La clause 
première génération en Louisiane</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Lendo a cópia fina: A cláusula de primeira
geração em Louisiana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lettura della stampa fine: La clausola di 
prima generazione in Luisiana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανάγνωση της λεπτής τυπωμένης ύλης: Η ρήτρα 
διατήρησης οικογενειακών επιχειρήσεων στη Λουιζιάνα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Lectura de la impresión fina: La cláusula 
de abuelo en Luisiana</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the post-Reconstruction era, Southern states mobilized a vast campaign of suffrage restriction--fraud, registration laws, and literary tests--in an effort to disempower African Americans and maintain Democratic party dominance. Although these restrictions were most often directed at black voters, those that barred voting on the basis of literacy or ownership of property also affected poor whites. Many northerners supported suffrage restriction as well. Between 1889 and 1913, nine states outside the South added restrictions requiring voters to read English, and ostensible reforms like the secret ballot were often directed at pushing out foreign-born and illiterate voters. One form of voting restriction aimed specifically at African Americans was the Grandfather clause that allowed men to register to vote only if they could have voted in 1867 (before African Americans were allowed to vote in the South) or descended from an 1867 voter. This excerpt from the Louisiana law of 1898 was typical of many such restrictions. The cumulative effect of the different restriction efforts was to reduce overall voting levels by more than a third and black voting rates by almost two thirds.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In der Pfosten-Rekonstruktion Ära mobilisierten 
südliche Zustände eine beträchtliche Kampagne der 
Stimmrechtbeschränkung -- Betrug, Registrierunggesetze und 
literarische Tests -- in einer Bemühung disempower zu den 
afrikanischen Amerikanern und behalten demokratische 
Parteiherrschaft bei. Obgleich diese Beschränkungen häufig
an den schwarzen Wählern verwiesen wurden, die, daß das abgehaltene 
Wählen auf der Grundlage von Bildungsgrad oder Besitz der Eigenschaft
auch schlechtes Weiß beeinflußte. Viele northerners 
unterstützten Stimmrechtbeschränkung außerdem. Zwischen 1889 
und 1913 wurden neun Zustände außerhalb der hinzugefügten 
Südbeschränkungen, die Wähler benötigen, Englisch zu lesen, und 
scheinbare Verbesserungen wie der geheime Stimmzettel häufig am 
Hinausschieben der foreign-born und unwissenden Wähler verwiesen. 
Ein Formular wählende Beschränkung zielte spezifisch auf 
afrikanische Amerikaner war die großväterliche Klausel ab, die 
Männern erlaubte zu registrieren, um zu wählen nur wenn sie 1867 
gewählt haben konnten (bevor afrikanischen Amerikanern erlaubt 
wurden, im Süden zu wählen) oder von einem Wähler 1867 abstieg. 
Dieses Excerpt vom Louisiana Gesetz von 1898 war von vielen 
solchen Beschränkungen typisch. Der kumulative Effekt der 
unterschiedlichen Beschränkung Bemühungen sollte wählende Stufen 
des Gesamten durch mehr als ein drittes verringern und wählende 
Kinetik durch fast zwei an dritter Stelle schwärzen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans l'ère de poteau-Reconstruction, les états 
méridionaux ont mobilisé une vaste campagne de la restriction de 
suffrage -- fraude, lois d'enregistrement, et essais littéraires -- 
dans un effort aux Américains africains de disempower et mettent à 
jour la dominance de parti démocratique. Bien que ces 
restrictions le plus souvent aient été dirigées aux électeurs 
noirs, ceux que le vote barré sur la base de l'instruction ou de la 
propriété de la propriété a également affecté des blancs pâles.
Beaucoup de habitants du Nord ont supporté la restriction de suffrage
aussi bien. Entre 1889 et 1913, neuf états en dehors des 
restrictions ajoutées du sud exigeant des électeurs de lire 
l'anglais, et réformes apparentes comme le vote secret ont été 
souvent dirigés à éliminer les électeurs nés à l'étranger et 
illettrés. Une forme de restriction de vote a visé 
spécifiquement les Américains africains était la clause première 
génération qui a permis à des hommes de s'enregistrer pour voter 
seulement s'ils pourraient avoir voté en 1867 (avant que des 
Américains africains ont été permis de voter dans les Sud) 
ou est descendue d'un électeur 1867. Cet extrait de la loi de 
la Louisiane de 1898 était typique de beaucoup de telles 
restrictions. L'effet cumulatif des différents efforts de 
restriction devait réduire les niveaux de vote de combinaison par 
plus qu'un troisième et noircir des cadences de vote par presque deux
troisièmement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Na era do borne-post-Reconstruction, os estados do
sul mobilized uma campanha vasta da limitação do suffrage -- fraud, 
leis do registo, e testes literários -- em um esforço aos americanos
africanos do disempower e mantêm o dominance do partido democrático.
Embora estas limitações fossem dirigidas o mais frequentemente
em eleitores pretos, aqueles que votar barrado na base do literacy ou 
na posse da propriedade afetou também brancos deficientes. 
Muitos northerners suportaram a limitação do suffrage também.
Entre 1889 e 1913, nove estados fora das limitações 
adicionadas sul que requerem eleitores ler o inglês, e as reformas 
ostensible como a cédula secreta foram dirigidos frequentemente em 
eliminar eleitores foreign-born e illiterate. Um formulário da 
limitação votando apontou especificamente em americanos africanos 
era a cláusula de primeira geração que permitiu que os homens 
registassem para votar somente se poderiam ter votado em 1867 (antes 
que estiveram permitidos aos americanos africanos votar no sul) ou 
desceu de um eleitor 1867. Este excerpt da lei de Louisiana de 
1898 era típico de muitas tais limitações. O efeito 
cumulativo dos esforços diferentes da limitação devia reduzir 
níveis votando do macacão por mais do que um terceiros e enegrecer 
taxas votando por quase dois em terceiro lugar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nell'era di alberino-Ricostruzione, del sud 
dichiara ha mobilitato una campagna ampia della limitazione di 
suffrage -- frode, leggi di registro e prove letterarie -- in uno 
sforzo agli Americani africani del disempower ed effettuano la 
dominanza del partito democratico. Anche se queste limitazioni 
sono state dirette il più spesso agli elettori neri, quelli che il 
voto escluso in base al literacy o alla proprietà della proprietà 
egualmente ha interessato i poveri bianchi. Molti 
northerners hanno sostenuto la limitazione di suffrage pure. Fra
1889 e 1913, nove dichiarano fuori delle limitazioni aggiunte del
sud che richiedono agli elettori di leggere l'inglese e le riforme 
apparenti come la scheda elettorale segreta sono state dirette spesso 
ad eliminare gli elettori foreign-born ed illetterati. Una forma
della limitazione di voto ha mirato specificamente agli Americani 
africani era la clausola di prima generazione che ha permesso che gli 
uomini registrassero per votare soltanto se potessero votare in 1867 
(prima che agli Americani africani fossero permessi votare nel sud) o 
che ha disceso da un elettore 1867. Questo brano dalla legge 
della Luisiana di 1898 era tipico di molte tali limitazioni. 
L'effetto cumulativo degli sforzi differenti di limitazione 
doveva ridurre i livelli di voto del camice da più di un terzi ed 
annerire i tassi di voto da quasi due terzo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στην εποχή μετα-αναδημιουργίας, τα νότια κράτη 
κινητοποίησαν μια απέραντη εκστρατεία του περιορισμού ψήφου -- 
απάτη, νόμοι εγγραφής, και λογοτεχνικές δοκιμές -- σε μια 
προσπάθεια στο disempower αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί και διατηρούν 
τη δημοκρατική κυριαρχία συμβαλλόμενων μερών. Αν και αυτοί 
οι περιορισμοί ο συχνότερα κατευθύνθηκαν στους μαύρους 
ψηφοφόρους, εκείνοι που έφραξαν να ψηφίσουν βάσει της βασικής 
εκπαίδευσης ή της ιδιοκτησίας της περιουσίας είχαν επιπτώσεις 
επίσης στα φτωχά λευκά. Πολύς υποστηριγμένος βόρειοι 
περιορισμός ψήφου επίσης. Μεταξύ 1889 και 1913, εννέα
κράτη έξω από το νότο πρόσθεσαν τους περιορισμούς που απαιτούν 
τους ψηφοφόρους για να διαβάσουν τα αγγλικά, και οι φαινομενικές 
μεταρρυθμίσεις όπως τη μυστική ψήφο κατευθύνθηκαν συχνά στην 
εκδίωξη των ξένος-γεννημένων και αναλφάβητων ψηφοφόρων. Μια
μορφή της ψηφοφορίας του περιορισμού που στόχευσε συγκεκριμένα σε
αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς ήταν η ρήτρα διατήρησης οικογενειακών 
επιχειρήσεων που επέτρεψε στα άτομα για να καταχωρήσει για να 
ψηφίσει μόνο εάν θα μπορούσαν να έχουν ψηφίσει το 1867 
(προτού είχαν την άδεια αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί για να ψηφίσουν 
στο νότο) ή κατέβηκε από έναν ψηφοφόρο 1867. Αυτό το 
απόσπασμα από το νόμο της Λουιζιάνας 1898 ήταν χαρακτηριστικό
πολλών τέτοιων περιορισμών. Η αθροιστική επίδραση των 
διαφορετικών προσπαθειών περιορισμού ήταν να μειωθούν τα γενικά 
επίπεδα ψηφοφορίας από μιας περισσότερο από διαλοές τις τρίτες 
και μαύρες ψηφοφορίας από σχεδόν τα δύο τρίτα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En la era de la poste-Reconstruccio'n, los estados
meridionales movilizaron una campaña extensa de la restricción del 
sufragio -- fraude, leyes del registro, y pruebas literarias -- en un 
esfuerzo a los americanos africanos del disempower y mantienen la 
dominación del partido democrático. Aunque estas restricciones
fueron dirigidas lo más a menudo posible en los votantes negros, 
ésos que la votación barrada en base de la instrucción o de la 
propiedad de la característica también afectó blancos pobres. 
Muchos northerners utilizaron la restricción del sufragio 
también. Entre 1889 y 1913, nueve estados fuera de las 
restricciones agregadas del sur que requerían a votantes leer 
inglés, y las reformas aparentes como la balota secreta fueron 
dirigidos a menudo en eliminar a votantes foreign-born y analfabetos. 
Una forma de restricción de votación apuntó a los americanos 
africanos era específicamente la cláusula de abuelo que permitió 
que los hombres se colocaran para votar solamente si habrían podido 
votar en 1867 (antes de que se permitió a los americanos africanos 
votar en el sur) o descendió de un votante 1867. Este extracto 
de la ley de Luisiana de 1898 era típico de muchas tales 
restricciones. El efecto acumulativo de los diversos esfuerzos 
de la restricción era reducir niveles de votación del guardapolvo 
por más que terceros y ennegrecer tarifas de votación por casi dos 
tercero.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086778</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107880</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/reading-the-fine-print-the-grandfather-clause-in-louisiana</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
