<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103316</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103316</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086669</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">No Rest for the Weary: Children in the Coal Mines</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kein Rest für das träge: Kinder in den 
Kohlengruben</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Aucun repos pour le las : Enfants dans les 
mines de houille</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nenhum descanso para o cansado: Crianças nas
minas de carvão</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nessun resto per lo Stancato: Bambini nelle
miniere di carbone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κανένα υπόλοιπο για τον κουρασμένο: Παιδιά στα 
ορυχεία άνθρακα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ningún resto para el cansado: Niños en las 
minas de carbón</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">For early twentieth-century Progressive reformers committed to social justice, widespread child labor--especially in coal mines, textile mills, and department stores--was particularly disturbing. And as with other Progressive crusades, the expos was a favorite tool. Probably the most influential and certainly the most widely read of the Progressive-era exposs of child labor was John Spargo's  The Bitter Cry of the Children  (1906). Spargo was a British granite cutter who became a union organizer and socialist and gained his formal education through extension courses at Oxford and Cambridge. In 1901, he emigrated to the United States where he became a leader of the conservative wing of the American Socialist Party. In the following excerpt, Spargo described work at the coal breaker, the area outside the mine where coal was sorted and graded, mostly by young children.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Für frühes Zwanzigstjahrhundert die progressiven 
Reformer, die an der Sozialgerechtigkeit festgelegt wurden, 
störte weitverbreitete Kinderarbeit -- besonders in den Kohlengruben,
in den Textiltausendsteln und in den Abteilung Speichern -- besonders.
Und wie mit anderen progressiven Kreuzzügen, waren die Expos 
ein Lieblingshilfsmittel. Vermutlich war das einflußreichste 
und zweifellos weit gelesen von den Progressiv-Ära exposs der 
Kinderarbeit John Spargos der bittere Schrei der Kinder (1906). 
Spargo war ein britischer Granitscherblock, der einem 
Anschlußorganisator und -sozialisten stand und seine formale 
Ausbildung durch Extension Kurse in Oxford und in Cambridge gewann. 
1901 wanderte er in die Vereinigten Staaten aus, in denen er ein
Führer des konservativen Flügels der amerikanischen sozialistischen 
Partei wurde. Im folgenden Excerpt beschrieb Spargo 
Arbeit am Kohleunterbrecher, den Bereich außerhalb der Grube, in der 
Kohle sortiert und geordnet wurde, meistens durch junge Kinder.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pour les réformateurs progressifs de 
vingtième-siècle tôt commis à la justice sociale, le travail des 
enfants répandu -- particulièrement dans des mines de houille, des 
moulins de textile, et de grands magasins -- dérangeait en 
particulier. Et comme avec d'autres croisades progressives, les 
expos étaient un outil préféré. Le plus influent 
probablement et certainement le plus largement lu des exposs de 
Progressif-ère du travail des enfants était le cri amer de John 
Spargo des enfants (1906). Spargo était un coupeur britannique 
de granit qui est allé bien à un organisateur et à un socialiste 
des syndicats et a gagné son enseignement conventionnel par des cours
d'extension à Oxford et à Cambridge. En 1901, il a émigré 
aux Etats-Unis où il est devenu une amorce de l'aile conservatrice du
parti socialiste américain. Dans l'extrait suivant, Spargo a 
décrit le travail au briseur de charbon, la zone en dehors de la mine
où du charbon a été trié et évalué, la plupart du temps par les 
enfants en bas âge.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Para os reformers progressivos de vigésimo-século
adiantado cometidos à justiça social, o trabalho de criança 
difundido -- especial em minas de carvão, em moinhos de textile, e em
lojas de departamento -- estava perturbando particularmente. E 
como com outros crusades progressivos, as expos eram uma ferramenta 
favorita. Provavelmente o mais influential e certamente lido o 
mais extensamente dos exposs da Progressivo-era do trabalho de 
criança era o grito amargo de John Spargo das crianças (1906). 
Spargo era um cortador britânico do granito que assentasse bem 
em um organizer e em um socialist da união e ganhasse sua instrução
formal com os cursos da extensão em Oxford e em Cambridge. Em 
1901, emigrated aos estados unidos onde se transformou um líder da 
asa conservadora do partido socialist americano. No seguinte 
excerpt, Spargo descreveu o trabalho no disjuntor de carvão, a área 
fora da mina onde o carvão foi classificado e classificado, na maior 
parte por crianças novas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Per i reformers progressivi di ventesimo-secolo in 
anticipo impegnati in giustizia sociale, il lavoro diffuso del 
bambino -- especially nelle miniere di carbone, nei laminatoi della 
tessile e nei grandi magazzini -- stava disturbandosi specialmente. 
E come con altri crusades progressivi, i expos erano uno 
strumento favorito. Probabilmente l'più influente e certamente 
il più ampiamente colto dei exposs di Progressivo-era del lavoro
del bambino era John che l'amaro dello Spargo Grida dei 
bambini (1906). Spargo era una taglierina britannica del granito
che ha stato bene ad un organizzatore e ad un socialista del sindacato
ed ha guadagnato la sua educazione scolastica con i corsi di 
estensione a Oxford e Cambridge. In 1901, ha emigrato al unito 
Dichiara dove è diventato un capo dell'ala conservatrice 
del partito socialista americano. Nel seguente brano, Spargo ha 
descritto il lavoro all'interruttore del carbone, la zona fuori della 
miniera in cui il carbone è stato ordinato e si classificato, 
principalmente dai bambini in giovane età.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Για τους πρώτους προοδευτικούς μεταρρυθμιστές 
εικοστός-αιώνα δεσμευμένους στην κοινωνική δικαιοσύνη, η 
διαδεδομένη παιδική εργασία -- ειδικά στα ορυχεία άνθρακα, τους 
υφαντικούς μύλους, και τα καταστήματα τμημάτων -- ήταν ιδιαίτερα
ενοχλητική. Και όπως με άλλες προοδευτικές σταυροφορίες, τα
EXPO ήταν ένα αγαπημένο εργαλείο. Πιθανώς ο επιδρύτερος
και βεβαίως ευρύτατα διαβασμένη της προοδευτικός-εποχής exposs
της παιδικής εργασίας ήταν κραυγή John Spargo η πικρή των 
παιδιών (1906). Το Spargo ήταν ένας βρετανικός κόπτης
γρανίτη που έγινε διοργανωτής και σοσιαλιστής ένωσης και κέρδισε
τη βασική εκπαίδευσή του μέσω των σειρών μαθημάτων επέκτασης 
στην Οξφόρδη και το Καίμπριτζ. Το 1901, μετανάστευσε στις 
Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες όπου έγινε ηγέτης συντηρητικό φτερό του 
αμερικανικού Σοσιαλιστικού Κόμματος. Στο ακόλουθο 
απόσπασμα, Spargo περιέγραψε την εργασία στο διακόπτη άνθρακα,
η περιοχή έξω από το ορυχείο όπου ο άνθρακας ταξινομήθηκε και 
βαθμολογήθηκε, συνήθως από τα μικρά παιδιά.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Para los reformadores progresivos del 
vige'simo-siglo temprano confiados a la justicia social, el trabajo de
niño extenso -- especialmente en minas de carbón, molinos del 
textil, y almacenes grandes -- disturbaba determinado. Y como 
con otras cruzadas progresivas, las expos eran una herramienta 
preferida. Probablemente el más influyente y leído lo más 
extensamente posible de los exposs de la Progresivo-era del trabajo de
niño era ciertamente el grito amargo de Juan Spargo de los niños 
(1906). Spargo era un cortador británico del granito que 
sintió bien a un organizador y a un socialista de la unión y ganó 
su enseñanza convencional con cursos de la extensión en Oxford y 
Cambridge. En 1901, él emigró a los Estados Unidos en
donde él hizo un arranque de cinta del ala conservadora del partido 
socialista americano. En el extracto siguiente, Spargo 
describió el trabajo en los cortacircuítos del carbón, el área 
fuera de la mina en donde el carbón fue clasificado y calificado, 
sobre todo por los niños jóvenes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086669</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103316</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/no-rest-for-the-weary-children-in-the-coal-mines</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
