<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106667</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106667</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211197</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Mountains and Mass Wasting</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Berge und Massenvergeuden</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Montagnes et gaspillage de masse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Montanhas e desperdiçar maciço</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Montagne e sprecare totale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βουνά και μαζική σπατάλη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Montañas y el perder total</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This lecture discusses physical and chemical processes that break down rocks and rock debris transportation mechanisms. Physical weathering includes abrasion, fragmentation, frost wedging, and thermal expansion and contraction. Chemical weathering includes solution, oxidation and hydration, and hydrolysis. The lecture notes are supported by images such as photographs, satalite photos, and diagrams depicting glacial features and frost wedging.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser Vortrag behandelt die körperlichen und 
chemischen Prozesse, die hinunter Felsen brechen und 
Rückstandtransporteinheiten schaukeln. Körperlicher Weathering
enthält Abnutzung, Zerteilung, der zwängende Frost und thermische 
Expansion und Kontraktion. Chemischer Weathering schließt 
Lösung, Oxidation und Hydratation und Hydrolyse ein. Die 
Vortraganmerkungen werden durch Bilder wie Fotographien, satalite 
Fotos und Diagramme, die Glazial- Merkmale und das Frostzwängen 
bildlich darstellen unterstützt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette conférence discute les processus physiques 
et chimiques qui décomposent des roches et des mécanismes de 
transport de débris de roche. La désagrégation physique inclut 
l'abrasion, la fragmentation, le gel coinçant, et la dilatation 
thermique et la contraction. La désagrégation de produit chimique 
inclut la solution, l'oxydation et l'hydration, et l'hydrolyse. 
Les notes de conférence sont supportées par des images telles 
que des photographies, des photos de satalite, et des diagrammes 
dépeignant les dispositifs et le coincement glaciaires de gel.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este lecture discute os processos físicos e 
químicos que quebram abaixo rochas e balançam mecanismos do 
transporte dos restos. O weathering físico inclui a abrasão, a
fragmentação, a geada que wedging, e expansão térmica e 
contração. O weathering químico inclui a solução, a 
oxidação e o hydration, e o hydrolysis. As notas do lecture 
são suportadas por imagens tais como fotografias, fotos do satalite, 
e diagramas que descrevem características e wedging glacial da geada.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa conferenza discute i processi fisici e 
chimici che suddividono le roccie ed i meccanismi del trasporto dei 
residui della roccia. Il weathering fisico include l'abrasione, 
frammentazione, gelo che incuneano ed espansione termica e 
contrazione. Il weathering chimico include la soluzione, 
ossidazione ed idratazione ed idrolisi. Le note di conferenza 
sono sostenute dalle immagini quali le fotografie, le foto del 
satalite e gli schemi che descrivono le caratteristiche ed incuneare 
glaciali di gelo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η διάλεξη συζητά τις φυσικές και χημικές 
διαδικασίες που χωρίζουν τους βράχους και τους μηχανισμούς 
μεταφορών συντριμμιών βράχου. Η φυσική διάβρωση 
περιλαμβάνει το γδάρσιμο, τον τεμαχισμό, τον παγετό 
ενσφηνώνοντας, και τη θερμική επέκταση και τη συστολή. Η 
χημική διάβρωση περιλαμβάνει τη λύση, την οξείδωση και την 
υδάτωση, και την υδρόλυση. Οι σημειώσεις διάλεξης 
υποστηρίζονται από τις εικόνες όπως οι φωτογραφίες, satalite 
φωτογραφίες, και διαγράμματα απεικονίζοντας τα παγετώδη 
χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα και να ενσφηνώσουν παγετού.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta conferencia discute los procesos físicos y 
químicos que analizan rocas y mecanismos del transporte de los 
escombros de la roca. El desgaste por la acción atmosférica 
físico incluye la abrasión, fragmentación, helada que acuña, y 
extensión termal y contracción. El desgaste por la acción 
atmosférica químico incluye la solución, oxidación e hidración, e
hidrólisis. Las notas de la conferencia son utilizadas por 
imágenes tales como fotografías, fotos del satalite, y diagramas que
representan características y acuñar glaciales de la helada.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211197</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106667</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/mountains-and-mass-wasting</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
