<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104137</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104137</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211257</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration: Research Homepage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nationale ozeanische und atmosphärische Leitung: 
Forschung Homepage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Gestion océanique et atmosphérique nationale : 
Homepage de Recherches</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Administração oceanic e atmosférica nacional: 
Homepage Da Pesquisa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gestione oceanica ed atmosferica nazionale: 
Homepage Di Ricerca</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εθνική ωκεάνεια και ατμοσφαιρική διοίκηση: 
Ερευνητική αρχική σελίδα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Administración oceánica y atmosférica nacional:
Homepage De la Investigación</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) Research, conducted primarily through the NOAA Office of Oceanic and Atmospheric Research, drives the NOAA environmental products and services that protect life and property and promote sustainable economic growth. Research, conducted by in-house laboratories and by extramural programs, focuses on enhancing understanding of the environmental phenomena such as tornadoes, hurricanes, climate variability, solar flares, changes in the ozone, El Nino/La Nina events, fisheries productivity, ocean currents, deep sea thermal vents, and coastal ecosystem health. NOAA research also develops innovative technologies and observing systems. This clearinghouse website contains an explanation of various types of research conducted by NOAA. Users can access hot research topics, NOAA products and research organizations. This site also contains image galleries and photo albums chronicling NOAA research.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die nationale ozeanische und atmosphärische 
Leitung (NOAA) Forschung, geleitet hauptsächlich durch das NOAA Büro
der ozeanischen und atmosphärischen Forschung, treibt die NOAA 
Klimaprodukte und die Dienstleistungen an, die das Leben und 
Eigenschaft schützen und stützbares Wirtschaftswachstum fördern. 
Forschung, geleitet durch interne Labors und durch extramural 
Programme, Foki auf dem Erhöhen des Verständnisses der 
Klimaphänomene wie Tornados, Hurrikane, Klimaveränderlichkeit, 
Sonneneruptionen, Änderungen im Ozon, EL Nino/La Nina in den Fällen,
in der Fischereiproduktivität, in den Ozeanströmen, in den tiefes 
Seethermischen Entlüftungsöffnungen und in der 
Küstenoekosystemgesundheit. NOAA Forschung entwickelt auch 
erfinderische Technologien und Beobachtensysteme. Diese 
Verrechnungszentraleweb site enthält eine Erklärung der 
verschiedenen Typen der Forschung geleitet von NOAA. Benutzer 
können heiße Forschung Themen, NOAA Produkte und auf Forschung 
Organisationen zugreifen. Diese Site enthält auch die 
Bildgalerien und Fotoalben, die NOAA Forschung aufzeichnen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La recherche océanique et atmosphérique 
nationale de la gestion (NOAA), conduite principalement par le bureau 
de NOAA de la recherche océanique et atmosphérique, pilote les 
produits environnementaux et les services de NOAA qui protègent la 
vie et la propriété et favorisent la croissance économique 
soutenable. Recherche, conduite par les laboratoires internes et
par les programmes extra-muros, foyers sur mettre en valeur 
l'arrangement des phénomènes environnementaux tels que des 
tornades, ouragans, variabilité de climat, éruptions 
chromosphériques, changements de l'ozone, des événements du EL 
Nino/La Nina, de la productivité de pêche, des courants d'océan, 
des évents thermiques de mer profonde, et de la santé côtière 
d'écosystème. La recherche de NOAA développe également des 
technologies innovatrices et des systèmes d'observer. Ce site 
Web de chambre de compensation contient une explication de divers 
types de recherche conduits par NOAA. Les utilisateurs peuvent 
accéder à des sujets chauds de recherches, à des produits de NOAA 
et à des organismes de recherches. Ce site contient également 
des galeries d'image et des albums photos faisant la chronique de la 
recherche de NOAA.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A pesquisa oceanic e atmosférica nacional da 
administração (NOAA), conduzida primeiramente através do 
escritório de NOAA da pesquisa oceanic e atmosférica, dirige os 
produtos ambientais e os serviços de NOAA que protegem a vida e a 
propriedade e promovem o crescimento econômico sustainable. 
Pesquisa, conduzida por laboratórios in-house e pelos programas
extramural, focos em realçar a compreensão dos fenômenos ambientais
tais como furacões, furacões, variability do clima, alargamentos 
solares, mudanças no ozônio, em eventos do EL Nino/La Nina, em 
produtividade dos fisheries, em correntes do oceano, em respiradouros 
térmicos do mar profundo, e na saúde litoral do ecosystem. A 
pesquisa de NOAA desenvolve também tecnologias inovativas e sistemas 
observar. Este Web site do clearinghouse contem uma explanação
dos vários tipos de pesquisa conduzidos por NOAA. Os usuários 
podem alcançar tópicos quentes da pesquisa, produtos de NOAA e 
organizações de pesquisa. Este local contem também as 
galerias da imagem e os albums de foto que chronicling a pesquisa de 
NOAA.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La ricerca oceanica ed atmosferica nazionale della
gestione (NOAA), condotta soprattutto attraverso l'ufficio di NOAA di 
ricerca oceanica ed atmosferica, guida i prodotti ambientali ed i 
servizi di NOAA che proteggono la vita e la proprietà e promuovono lo
sviluppo economico sostenibile. Ricerca, condotta dai laboratori
interni e dai programmi extramural, fuochi sull'aumento della 
comprensione dei fenomeni ambientali quali i cicloni, uragani, 
variabilità di clima, chiarori solari, cambiamenti nell'ozono, negli 
eventi di EL Nino/La Nina, nel rendimento delle industrie della pesca,
nelle correnti dell'oceano, negli sfiati termici del mare profondo e 
nella salute litoranea di ecosistema. La ricerca di NOAA 
egualmente sviluppa le tecnologie innovarici e sistemi di 
osservazione. Questo Web site della stanza di compensazione 
contiene una spiegazione di vari tipi di ricerche condotti da NOAA. 
Gli utenti possono accedere ai soggetti caldi di ricerca, ai 
prodotti di NOAA ed agli organismi di ricerca. Questo luogo 
egualmente contiene le gallerie di immagine e gli album di foto che 
chronicling la ricerca di NOAA.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η εθνική ωκεάνεια και ατμοσφαιρική έρευνα διοίκησης 
(NOAA), διεύθυνε πρώτιστα μέσω του γραφείου NOAA της 
ωκεάνειας και ατμοσφαιρικής έρευνας, οδηγεί τα περιβαλλοντικές 
προϊόντα NOAA και τις υπηρεσίες που προστατεύουν τη ζωή και 
την ιδιοκτησία και προωθούν τη βιώσιμη οικονομική ανάπτυξη. 
Η έρευνα, που πραγματοποιείται από τα εσωτερικά εργαστήρια 
και από τα συμπληρωματικά προγράμματα, εστιάζει στην ενίσχυση της
κατανόησης των περιβαλλοντικών φαινομένων όπως οι ανεμοστρόβιλοι,
τυφώνες, μεταβλητότητα κλίματος, ηλιακές φλόγες, αλλαγές στο 
όζον, τα γεγονότα Ελ Νίνιο/Λα Νίνα, την παραγωγικότητα αλιείας, 
τα ωκεάνια ρεύματα, τις θερμικές διεξόδους μεγάλων θαλασσίων 
βαθών, και την παράκτια υγεία οικοσυστήματος. Η έρευνα 
NOAA αναπτύσσει επίσης τις καινοτόμες τεχνολογίες και 
παρατήρηση των συστημάτων. Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος γραφείων 
συμψηφισμού περιέχει μια εξήγηση των διάφορων τύπων ερευνών που 
πραγματοποιούνται από NOAA. Οι χρήστες μπορούν να έχουν 
πρόσβαση στα καυτά ερευνητικά θέματα, τα προϊόντα NOAA και 
τις ερευνητικές οργανώσεις. Αυτή η περιοχή περιέχει επίσης
τις στοές εικόνας και τα λευκώματα φωτογραφιών εξιστορώντας κατά
γράμμα την έρευνα NOAA.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La investigación oceánica y atmosférica 
nacional de la administración (NOAA), conducida sobre todo a través 
de la oficina de NOAA de la investigación oceánica y atmosférica, 
conduce los productos ambientales y los servicios de NOAA que protegen
vida y la característica y promueven desarrollo económico 
sostenible. Investigación, conducida por los laboratorios 
internos y por los programas extramural, focos en realzar la 
comprensión de los fenómenos ambientales tales como tornados, 
huracanes, variabilidad del clima, flamas solares, cambios en el 
ozono, acontecimientos del EL Nino/La Nina, productividad de las 
industrias pesqueras, corrientes del océano, respiraderos termales 
del mar profundo, y salud costera del ecosistema. La 
investigación de NOAA también desarrolla tecnologías innovadoras y 
los sistemas de la observación. Este Web site de la cámara de 
compensación contiene una explicación de los varios tipos de 
investigación conducidos por NOAA. Los utilizadores pueden 
tener acceso a asuntos calientes de la investigación, a productos de 
NOAA y a organizaciones de investigación. Este sitio también 
contiene las galerías de la imagen y los álbumes de foto chronicling
la investigación de NOAA.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211257</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104137</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/national-oceanic-and-atmospheric-administration-research-homepage</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
