<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108162</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108162</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087009</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The old plantation home."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die alte Plantage Haupt."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"la vieille plantation à la maison."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"a plantação velha home."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la vecchia piantagione domestica."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Το παλαιό σπίτι φυτειών."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"la vieja plantación casera."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Planters romanticized life on the plantation, often representing themselves as stern but loving parents who had to look after their slaves, who were depicted as childlike and in need of disciplined guidance. The plantation as the perfect extended family was a common theme of pro-slavery prints both before and after the Civil War. This postwar lithograph by the popular firm of Currier and Ives portrayed the slave quarters as a carefree world, basking in the glow of the planter's benevolence. In reality, of course, the harsh life of a slave bore little resemblance to this romanticized image.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Pflanzer romanticized das Leben auf der Plantage und 
häufig stellten sich als Heck aber liebevolle Eltern dar, die um ihre
Sklaven sich kümmern mußten, die als kindliche und mangels 
disziplinierte Anleitung bildlich dargestellt wurden. Die 
Plantage als die vollkommene ausgedehnte Familie war ein geläufiges 
Thema der Pro-Sklaverei Drucke beide vorher und nachher der 
Bürgerkrieg. Diese Nachkriegslithographie durch das populäre 
Unternehmen von Currier und von Ives schilderte die Sklavenviertel als
sorglose Welt und aalte sich im Glühen der Wohltätigkeit des 
Pflanzers. In der Wirklichkeit selbstverständlich die rauhe 
Lebensdauer einer Sklavenausbohrung romanticized wenig Ähnlichkeit zu
diesem Bild.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les planteurs romanticized la vie sur la plantation, se 
représentant souvent comme poupe mais parents affectueux qui ont dû 
s'occuper de leurs esclaves, qui ont été dépeints en tant que 
conseils enfantins et nécessitant disciplinés. La plantation 
en tant que famille étendu parfait était un thème commun des copies
de pro-esclavage tous les deux avant et après la guerre civile. 
Cette lithographie d'après-guerre par la société populaire de
Currier et d'Ives a dépeint les quarts slaves comme monde 
insousiant, se dorant dans la lueur de la bienveillance du planteur. 
En réalité, naturellement, la vie dure d'un alésage 
slave peu de ressemblance à ceci romanticized l'image.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os plantadores romanticized a vida na plantação, 
representando-se frequentemente como o stern mas os pais loving que 
tiveram que olhar após seus escravos, que foram descritos enquanto 
childlike e na necessidade da orientação disciplinada. A 
plantação como a família prolongada perfeita era um tema comum de 
cópias do pro-pro-slavery ambos before.and.after a guerra civil. 
Este lithograph postwar pela firma popular de Currier e de Ives 
portrayed os quartos slave como um mundo carefree, basking no fulgor 
do benevolence do plantador. Na realidade, naturalmente, a vida 
áspera de um furo slave pouca semelhança a esta romanticized a 
imagem.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le piantatrici romanticized la vita sulla piantagione, 
rappresentantesi spesso come la poppa ma genitori loving che hanno 
dovuto occuparsi dei loro schiavi, che sono stati descritti come 
consiglio childlike e necessitante disciplinato. La piantagione 
come la famiglia estesa perfetta era un tema comune delle stampe di 
pro-pro-slavery entrambi prima e dopo la guerra civile. Questa 
litografia dopoguerra dalla ditta popolare di Currier e di Ives ha 
ritratto i quarti slave come mondo carefree, basking 
nell'incandescenza del benevolence della piantatrice. In 
realtà, naturalmente, la durata dura di un foro slave poca 
rassomiglianza a questa romanticized l'immagine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι καλλιεργητές η ζωή στη φυτεία, αντιπροσωπεμένος 
συχνά ως αυστηρούς αλλά αγαπώντας γονείς που έπρεπε να 
φροντίσουν τους σκλάβους τους, οι οποίοι απεικονίστηκαν όπως 
παιδιάστικους και που έχουν ανάγκη από πειθαρχημένη καθοδήγηση. 
Η φυτεία ως τέλεια εκτεταμένη οικογένεια ήταν ένα κοινό 
θέμα των pro-slavery τυπωμένων υλών και οι δύο πριν και μετά 
από τον εμφύλιο πόλεμο. Αυτό το μεταπολεμικό lithograph 
από τη δημοφιλή εταιρία currier και Ives απεικόνισε τα 
τέταρτα σκλάβων ως ξένοιαστο κόσμο, poy στην πυράκτωση της 
καλοκαγαθίας του καλλιεργητή. Στην πραγματικότητα, φυσικά, η
σκληρή ζωή ενός σκλάβου άντεξε λίγη ομοιότητα σε αυτό η 
εικόνα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los plantadores romanticized vida en la plantación, 
representándose a menudo como popa pero padres cariñosos que 
tuvieron que ocuparse de sus esclavos, que fueron representados 
mientras que infantil y en necesidad de la dirección disciplinada. 
La plantación como la familia extendida perfecta era un tema 
común de las impresiones de la favorable-esclavitud ambos antes y 
después la guerra civil. Esta litografía de la posguerra por 
la firma popular de Currier y de Ives retrató los cuartos auxiliares 
como mundo despreocupado, tomando el sol en el resplandor de la 
benevolencia del plantador. En realidad, por supuesto, la vida 
áspera de un alesaje auxiliar poca semejanza a esto romanticized 
imagen.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087009</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108162</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-old-plantation-home</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
