<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108688</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108688</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209843</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Constructing the Incenter and Incircle of a triangle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Konstruieren des Incenter und des Incircle aus 
einem Dreieck</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Construire l'Incenter et l'Incircle avec d'une 
triangle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Construir o Incenter e o Incircle de um 
triângulo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Costruzione il Incenter ed il Incircle con 
triangolo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατασκευή του Incenter και του Incircle ενός 
τριγώνου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Construir el Incenter y el Incircle de un 
triángulo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate how to construct the incenter and incircle of triangle using compass and straightedge. It starts with a given triangle, and using animation that can be run continuously or single step, shows how to first construct the incenter, then using that point, construct the incircle of the given triangle. The text on the page contains written step-by-step instructions that can be printed. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die zeigen, wie man das incenter und das incircle aus 
Dreieck mit Kompaß und Lineal konstruiert. Es beginnt mit einem
gegebenen Dreieck, und mit Animation, die ununterbrochen laufen 
gelassen werden kann oder Einzelschritt, konstruieren Erscheinen wie 
zu zuerst das incenter konstruieren Sie, dann das Verwenden dieses 
Punktes, das incircle aus dem gegebenen Dreieck. Der Text auf 
der Seite enthält geschriebene schrittweisee Anweisungen, die 
gedruckt werden können. Applet kann zum vollen Bildumfang für 
Gebrauch mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. 
Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von 
jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den 
benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein 
Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven 
Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent comment construire l'incenter et l'incircle avec de la
triangle à l'aide de la boussole et de la règle. Elle commence
par une triangle donnée, et en utilisant l'animation qui peut être 
exécutée sans interruption ou pas à pas, les expositions comment à
d'abord construisez l'incenter, puis utiliser ce point, construisent 
l'incircle avec de la triangle donnée. Le texte à la page 
contient les instructions pas à pas écrites qui peuvent être 
imprimées. L'applet peut être agrandi à la taille de plein 
écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de classe. Le 
après utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant peut lui 
accéder encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la maison ou 
dans la bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion exigée. 
Cette ressource est un composant du projet interactif de manuel 
de la géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem como construir o incenter e o incircle do triângulo usando
o compasso e o straightedge. Começa com um triângulo dado, e 
usando o animation que pode ser funcionado continuamente ou única 
etapa, as mostras como a primeiramente construa o incenter, a seguir 
usar esse ponto, constroem o incircle do triângulo dado. O 
texto na página contem as instruções passo a passo escritas que 
podem ser imprimidas. O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de 
tela cheia para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. O depois 
de uso na sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo 
o web browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma 
sessão requerido. Este recurso é um componente do projeto 
interativo do textbook da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano come costruire il incenter ed il incircle con triangolo per
mezzo della bussola e dello straightedge. Comincia con un dato 
triangolo ed usando la animazione che può essere funzionata 
continuamente o singolo punto, le esposizioni come ad in primo luogo 
costruisca il incenter, quindi usando quel punto, costruiscono il 
incircle con dato triangolo. Il testo alla pagina contiene le 
istruzioni graduali scritte che possono essere stampate. Il 
applet può essere ingrandito al formato di schermo pieno per uso con 
un proiettore dell'aula. La post-utilizzazione nell'aula, 
allievo può accederle ancora da tutto il web browser nel paese o 
nella libreria senza l'inizio attività richiesto. Questa 
risorsa è un componente del progetto interattivo del manuale della 
geometria di riferimento aperto di per la matematica a 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν πώς να κατασκευάσουν το incenter και incircle 
του τριγώνου χρησιμοποιώντας την πυξίδα και straightedge. 
Αρχίζει με ένα δεδομένο τρίγωνο, και χρησιμοποιώντας τη 
ζωτικότητα που μπορεί να οργανωθεί συνεχώς ή ενιαίο βήμα, 
επιδεικνύει πώς κατασκευάστε αρχικά το incenter, κατόπιν 
χρησιμοποιώντας εκείνο το σημείο, κατασκευάστε το incircle του 
δεδομένου τριγώνου. Το κείμενο στη σελίδα περιέχει τις 
γραπτές βαθμιαίες οδηγίες που μπορούν να τυπωθούν. Το 
Applet μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη 
χρήση με έναν προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση στην 
τάξη, ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από 
οποιοδήποτε ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς 
την άδεια εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο 
συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος 
εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran cómo construir el incenter y el incircle de triángulo 
usando el compás y la regla. Comienza con un triángulo dado, y
con la animación que se puede ejecutar continuamente o solo paso de 
progresión, las demostraciones cómo a primero construya el incenter,
después usar esa punta, construyen el incircle del triángulo dado. 
El texto en la paginación contiene las instrucciones paso a 
paso escritas que pueden ser impresas. El applet se puede 
agrandar a la talla de la pantalla completa para el uso con un 
proyector de la sala de clase. El uso posterior en la sala de 
clase, estudiante puede tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier web 
browser en el país o en la biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. 
Este recurso es un componente del proyecto interactivo del libro
de textos de la geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas
en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209843</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108688</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/constructing-the-incenter-and-incircle-of-a-triangle</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
