<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104344</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104344</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207221</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Eleanor Roosevelt: American Visionary</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eleanor Roosevelt: Amerikanischer Visionär</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Eleanor Roosevelt : Visionnaire Américain</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Eleanor Roosevelt: Visionary Americano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Eleanor Roosevelt: Visionario Americano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Eleanor Roosevelt: Αμερικανικός οραματιστής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Eleanor Roosevelt: Visionario Americano</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features photos and artifacts from the life of one of the most dynamic and controversial First Ladies in U.S. history. She was the first First Lady to hold regular press conferences and to routinely travel the nation. She held prestigious positions throughout her life, serving as delegate to the newly founded United Nations, draftee of the Universal Declaration of Human Rights, and chair of the first Presidential Commission on the Status of Women.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Merkmale Fotos und Kunstprodukte von der 
Lebensdauer von einer der dynamischsten und umstrittensten ersten 
Damen in der VEREINIGTE STAATEN Geschichte. Sie war die erste 
erste Dame, zum der regelmäßigen Pressekonferenzen anzuhalten und 
routinemäßig zu reisen die Nation. Sie hielt prestigevolle 
Positionen während ihrer Lebensdauer an und diente als Delegierter zu
den eben gegründeten Nationen, Wehrdienstpflichtiger der 
Universalerklärung der menschlichen Rechte und des Stuhls der ersten 
Präsidentenkommission auf dem Status der Frauen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">photos et objets façonnés de dispositifs de la 
vie d'une premières des dames les plus dynamiques et les plus 
controversées dans l'histoire des ETATS-UNIS. Elle était la 
première première Madame pour tenir des conférences de presse 
régulières et à voyager par habitude la nation. Elle a tenu 
des positions prestigieuses durant toute sa vie, servant de 
déléguée aux Nations Unies nouvellement fondées, recrue de la 
déclaration universelle des droits de l'homme, et de la chaise de la 
première Commission présidentielle sur le mode des femmes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fotos e artifacts das características da vida de 
uma primeiras das senhoras as mais dinâmicas e as mais controversas 
no history de ESTADOS UNIDOS. Era a primeira primeira senhora 
para prender conferências de imprensa regulares e a viajar 
rotineiramente a nação. Prendeu posições prestigiosas 
durante todo sua vida, servindo como delegado às nações unidas 
recentemente fundadas, draftee da declaração universal de direitas 
humanas, e cadeira do primeiro commission presidencial no status de 
mulheres.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">foto e manufatti delle caratteristiche dalla 
durata di una prime delle signore più dinamiche e più discutibili 
nella storia degli STATI UNITI. Era la prima prima signora per 
tenere le conferenze stampa normali e da viaggiare ordinariamente la 
nazione. Ha tenuto le posizioni prestigious durante la sua vita,
servente da delegato alle Nazioni Unite recentemente fondate, draftee 
della dichiarazione universale dei diritti dell'uomo e della sedia 
della prima Commissione presidenziale sulla condizione delle donne.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">φωτογραφίες και χειροποίητα αντικείμενα 
χαρακτηριστικών γνωρισμάτων από τη ζωή μια από τις δυναμικότερες
και αμφισβητούμενες πρώτες κυρίες στην ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ ιστορία. 
Ήταν η πρώτη πρώτη κυρία για να οργανώσει τις τακτικές 
συνεντεύξεις τύπου και για να ταξιδεψει συνήθως το έθνος. 
Υποστήριξε τις προσδίδουσες γόητρο θέσεις καθ' όλη τη 
διάρκεια της ζωής της, που χρησιμεύει ως ο εκπρόσωπος στα 
πρόσφατα ιδρυμένα Ηνωμένα Έθνη, draftee της καθολικής 
Διακήρυξης των ανθρώπινων δικαιωμάτων, και της καρέκλας της 
πρώτης προεδρικής Επιτροπής στη θέση των γυναικών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">fotos y artefactos de las características a 
partir de la vida de una de las primeras señoras más dinámicas y 
más polémicas de la historia de ESTADOS UNIDOS. Ella era la 
primera primera señora para llevar a cabo ruedas de prensa regulares 
y a viajar rutinariamente la nación. Ella llevó a cabo 
posiciones prestigiosas a través de su vida, sirviendo como delegado 
a los Naciones Unidas nuevamente fundados, recluta del declaración 
universal de derechos humanos, y de la silla de la primera Comisión 
presidencial respecto al estatus de mujeres.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207221</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104344</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/eleanor-roosevelt-american-visionary</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
