<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104017</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104017</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203673</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Life on Earth...and Elsewhere?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Leben auf Masse... und anderwohin?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La vie sur terre... et ailleurs ?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Vida na terra... e em outra parte?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Vita su terra... ed altrove?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ζωή στη γη... και αλλού;</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿Vida en la tierra... y a otra parte?</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The hands-on activities in this Educator Resource Guide lay the conceptual groundwork for understanding the field of astrobiology. What is Life? What does Life need to live? What makes a world habitable? What can Life tolerate? Is there Life on other worlds? All five fundamental questions are addressed with complete activities, each including background reading, recommended procedure, activity guide, questions for reflection, blackline masters, and a math extension.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Blindeinschub Aktivitäten in dieser 
Erzieher-Hilfsmittel-Anleitung legen die Begriffsgrundlage für das 
Verstehen auffangene von astrobiology. Was ist Leben? 
Was benötigt das Leben, um zu leben? Was bildet eine Welt
bewohnbar? Was kann das Leben zulassen? Gibt es Leben auf 
anderen Welten? Alle fünf grundlegenden Fragen werden mit 
kompletten Aktivitäten, jeder einschließlich Hintergrundmesswert, 
empfohlener Prozedur, Aktivität Anleitung, Fragen für Reflexion, 
blackline Meistern und einer Matheextension adressiert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les activités à commande manuelle de ce guide de 
ressource d'éducateur étendent le fond conceptuel pour 
l'arrangement la zone de l'astrobiology. Quelle est la vie ? 
De que la vie a-t-elle besoin pour vivre ? Que rend un 
monde habitable ? Que la vie peut-elle tolérer ? Y a-t-il
la vie sur d'autres mondes ? Chacune des cinq questions 
fondamentales est adressé avec des activités complètes, chacune 
comprenant la lecture de fond, le procédé recommandé, le guide 
d'activité, des questions pour la réflexion, des maîtres de 
blackline, et une extension de maths.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As atividades hands-on nesta guia do recurso do educador 
colocam o groundwork conceptual para compreender o campo do 
astrobiology. Que é vida? Que a vida necessita viver? 
Que faz um mundo habitable? Que pode a vida tolerar? 
Há uma vida em outros mundos? Todas as cinco perguntas 
fundamentais são dirigidas com atividades completas, cada uma 
including a leitura do fundo, procedimento recomendado, guia da 
atividade, perguntas para a reflexão, mestres do blackline, e uma 
extensão do math.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le attività hands-on in questa guida delle risorse 
dell'educatore pongono il fondamento concettuale per capire il campo 
del astrobiology. Che cosa è vita? Di che cosa la vita ha
bisogno per vivere? Che cosa rende un mondo abitabile? Che
cosa può la vita tollerare? È ci vita su altri mondi? 
Tutte e cinque le domande fondamentali sono indirizzate con le 
attività complete, ciascuno compreso la lettura della priorità 
bassa, la procedura suggerita, la guida di attività, le domande per 
la riflessione, i supervisori di blackline e un'estensione di per la 
matematica.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι εμπράγματες δραστηριότητες σε αυτόν τον οδηγό των 
στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς εκπαιδευτικών βάζουν την εννοιολογική 
προκαταρκτική εργασία για την κατανόηση του πεδίου του 
astrobiology. Τι είναι ζωή; Τι η ζωή χρειάζεται για
να ζήσει; Αυτό που καθιστά έναν κόσμο κατοικήσιμο; 
Τι μπορεί η ζωή να ανεχτεί; Υπάρχει ζωή σε άλλους 
κόσμους; Και τα πέντε θεμελιώδη ζητήματα εξετάζονται με τις
πλήρεις δραστηριότητες, κάθε μια συμπεριλαμβανομένης της 
ανάγνωσης υποβάθρου, συνιστώμενη διαδικασία, οδηγός 
δραστηριότητας, ερωτήσεις για την αντανάκλαση, κύριοι 
blackline, και μια επέκταση math.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las actividades con manos en esta guía del recurso del 
educador ponen la base conceptual para entender el campo del 
astrobiology. ¿Cuál es vida? ¿Qué la vida necesita para 
vivir? ¿Qué hace un mundo habitable? ¿Qué puede la vida 
tolerar? ¿Hay vida en otros mundos? Las cinco preguntas 
fundamentales se tratan con actividades completas, cada uno incluyendo
la lectura del fondo, procedimiento recomendado, la guía de la 
actividad, las preguntas para la reflexión, los amos del blackline, y
una extensión de la matemáticas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CHRIS RANDALL
FN:CHRIS RANDALL
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:TERC
FN:TERC
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203673</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104017</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/life-on-earth-and-elsewhere</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
