<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107166</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107166</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202528</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Creating Community in the Classroom: Part 3 (Monitoring Progress)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erstellen der Gemeinschaft im Klassenzimmer: 
Teil 3 (Fortschritt Überwachend)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Créer la Communauté dans la salle de classe : 
Partie 3 (Surveillant Le Progrès)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Criando a comunidade na sala de aula: Parte 
3 (Que Monitora O Progresso)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Creazione della Comunità nell'aula: Parte 3
(Progresso Della Verifica e Controllo)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δημιουργία της Κοινότητας στην τάξη: Μέρος 3 
(πρόοδος ελέγχου)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Crear a comunidad en la sala de clase: Parte
3 (Que vigila Progreso)</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This series of lessons is designed to help develop a sense of classroom community through use of group goal-setting, decision-making, brainstorming, peer feedback, positive reinforcement, and positive peer pressure. The lessons will help students create and maintain a supportive environment for learning. Part 1 focused on goal-setting process and practice. In Part 2, students applied knowledge of the goal-setting process and cooperatively created a plan to work on short-term group goals. In part 3, students will monitor the effects of their plan by determining whether short term goals are being achieved.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Reihe Lektionen ist konzipiert, um zu 
helfen, eine Richtung der Klassenzimmergemeinschaft durch Gebrauch von
Gruppe Ziel-Einstellung, Beschlußfassung, Geistesstörung, 
Gleichfeedback, positiver Verstärkung und positivem Gleichdruck zu 
entwickeln. Die Lektionen willen helfen Kursteilnehmern, eine 
unterstützende Umgebung für das Lernen zu erstellen und 
beizubehalten. Zerteilen Sie 1 gerichtet auf 
Ziel-einstellenprozeß und Praxis. In Teil 2, in den 
Kursteilnehmern angewendetes Wissen des Ziel-einstellenprozesses und 
kooperativ erstellt einem Plan, zum auf kurzfristigen Gruppe Zielen zu
arbeiten. In Teil 3, überwachen Kursteilnehmer die Effekte 
ihres Planes, indem sie feststellen, ob kurze Bezeichnung Ziele 
erzielt werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette série de leçons est conçue pour aider à 
développer un sens de la communauté de salle de classe par 
l'utilisation du but-réglage de groupe, de la prise de décision, de 
la séance de réflexion, du feedback de pair, du renfort positif, et 
de la pression positive de pair. Les leçons veulent aident des 
étudiants à créer et mettre à jour un environnement de support 
pour l'étude. Pièce 1 concentré sur le processus et la 
pratique deréglage. Dans la partie 2, les étudiants la 
connaissance appliquée du processus deréglage et coopérativement 
créée un plan à travailler sur des buts à court terme de groupe. 
Dans la partie 3, les étudiants surveilleront les effets de 
leur plan en déterminant si des buts courts de limite sont 
réalisés.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta série das lições é projetada ajudar 
desenvolver um sentido da comunidade da sala de aula com o uso do 
objetivo-ajuste do grupo, da tomada de decisão, do brainstorming, do 
feedback do par, do reforço positivo, e da pressão positiva do par. 
As lições querem ajudam a estudantes criar e manter um 
ambiente de suporte para aprender. Peça 1 focalizado no 
processo e na prática deajuste. Na parte 2, nos estudantes 
conhecimento aplicado do processo deajuste e criado cooperativa uma 
planta a trabalhar em objetivos a curto prazo do grupo. Na parte
3, os estudantes monitorarão os efeitos de sua planta determinando se
os objetivos curtos do termo estão sendo conseguidos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa serie di lezioni è destinata per 
contribuire a sviluppare un senso della Comunità dell'aula con uso di
obiettivo-regolazione del gruppo, di risoluzione, di "brainstorming", 
di risposte del pari, del rinforzo positivo e della pressione positiva
del pari. Le lezioni vogliono aiutano gli allievi a creare ed 
effettuare un ambiente di appoggio per imparare. Parte 1 messo a
fuoco sul processo e sulla pratica diregolazione. Nella parte 2,
gli allievi hanno applicato la conoscenza del processo diregolazione 
ed in cooperazione hanno creato un programma per lavorare agli 
obiettivi di breve durata del gruppo. Nella parte 3, gli allievi
controlleranno gli effetti del loro programma determinando se gli 
obiettivi corti di termine stiano realizzandi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η σειρά μαθημάτων έχει ως σκοπό να βοηθήσει να 
αναπτύξει μια αίσθηση της κοινότητας τάξεων μέσω της χρήσης της 
στόχος-τιμής τών παραμέτρων ομάδας, της λήψης αποφάσεων, του 
"brainstorming", της όμοιας ανατροφοδότησης, της θετικής 
ενίσχυσης, και της θετικής όμοιας πίεσης. Τα μαθήματα θα 
βοηθήσουν τους σπουδαστές να δημιουργήσουν και να διατηρήσουν ένα
ενθαρρυντικό περιβάλλον για την εκμάθηση. Το μέρος 1 
εστίασε στην στόχος-τιμή τών παραμέτρων της διαδικασίας και της 
πρακτικής. Στο μέρος 2, οι σπουδαστές εφάρμοσαν τη γνώση 
της στόχος-θέτοντας διαδικασίας και δημιούργησαν συνεταιριστικά 
ένα σχέδιο για να εργαστούν στους βραχυπρόθεσμους στόχους 
ομάδας. Στο μέρος 3, οι σπουδαστές θα ελέγξουν τα 
αποτελέσματα του σχεδίου τους με τον καθορισμό εάν οι 
βραχυπρόθεσμοι στόχοι επιτυγχάνονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta serie de lecciones se diseña para ayudar a 
desarrollar un sentido de la comunidad de la sala de clase con el uso 
de meta-fijar del grupo, de la toma de decisión, de la reunión de 
reflexión, del feedback del par, del refuerzo positivo, y de la 
presión positiva del par. Las lecciones quieren ayudan a 
estudiantes a crear y a mantener un ambiente de apoyo para aprender. 
Pieza 1 centrado en proceso y práctica meta-que fijan. En
la parte 2, estudiantes conocimiento aplicado del proceso meta-que 
fija y cooperativo creado un plan a trabajar en metas a corto plazo 
del grupo. En la parte 3, los estudiantes vigilarán los efectos
de su plan determinándose si se están alcanzando las metas a corto 
plazo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAT NYSTROM
FN:PAT NYSTROM
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202528</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107166</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/creating-community-in-the-classroom-part-3-monitoring-progress</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
