<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104378</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104378</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974018</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Budget Maze</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Etat-Labyrinth</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Labyrinthe de Budget</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Maze Do Orçamento</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Labirinto Del Preventivo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Λαβύρινθος προϋπολογισμών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Laberinto Del Presupuesto</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the new Gotham Gazette game, you are a knight, setting out to rescue funding for yourself or your community. The decisions you make along the way will determine whether you fail or succeed, how many points you acquire and whether you are a budget apprentice, a journeyman or -- at the apex-- a master of the budget.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im neuen Gotham Zeitungspiel sind Sie ein Ritter 
und legen dar, um die Finanzierung für selbst oder Ihre Gemeinschaft 
zu retten. Die Entscheidungen, die Sie entlang der Methode 
treffen, stellen, ob Sie ausfallen oder folgen fest, wieviele Punkte 
Sie erwerben und ob Sie ein Etatlehrling, ein Facharbeiter oder -- an 
der Spitze -- ein Meister des Etats sind.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans le nouveau jeu de gazette de Gotham, vous 
êtes un chevalier, se mettant à sauver le placement pour vous-même 
ou votre communauté. Les décisions que vous prenez le long de 
la voie détermineront si vous échouez ou réussissez, combien points
vous saisissez et si vous êtes un apprenti de budget, un compagnon ou
-- à l'apex -- un maître du budget.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No jogo novo do gazette de Gotham, você é um 
knight, ajustando-se para fora para salvar financiar para yourself ou 
sua comunidade. As decisões que você faz ao longo da maneira 
determinarão se você falha ou sucede, quantos pontos você adquire e
se você é um aprendiz do orçamento, um journeyman ou -- no apex -- 
um mestre do orçamento.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nel nuovo gioco del gazette di Gotham, siete un 
cavaliere, precisante per salvare costituire un fondo per per lei o la
vostra Comunità. Le decisioni che prendete lungo il modo 
determineranno se veniate a mancare o riusciate, quanti punti 
acquistate e se siete un apprendista del preventivo, un operaio 
qualificato o -- all'apex -- un supervisore del preventivo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στο νέο παιχνίδι εφημερίδων Gotham, είστε ένας 
ιππότης, που καθορίζει να διασώσετε τη χρηματοδότηση για σας ή 
την κοινότητά σας. Οι αποφάσεις που λαμβάνετε κατά μήκος 
του τρόπου θα καθορίσουν εάν αποτυγχάνετε ή πετυχαίνετε, πόσα 
σημεία αποκτάτε και εάν είστε μαθητευόμενος προϋπολογισμών, 
τεχνίτης ή -- στην κορυφή -- κύριος του προϋπολογισμού.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En el nuevo juego de la gaceta de Gotham, usted es
un caballero, precisando para rescatar el financiamiento para se o su 
comunidad. Las decisiones que usted toma a lo largo de la manera
se determinarán si usted falla o tiene éxito, cuántas puntas usted 
adquiere y si usted es aprendiz del presupuesto, un oficial o -- en el
ápice -- un amo del presupuesto.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:GAIL ROBINSON, EDITOR-IN-CHIEF
FN:GAIL ROBINSON, EDITOR-IN-CHIEF
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974018</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104378</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/budget-maze</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
