<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104148</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104148</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087415</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Automobiles and milady's mood.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Automobile und Stimmung der miladys.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Automobiles et humeur des milady.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Automóveis e modo dos milady.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Automobili ed umore dei milady.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτοκίνητα και διάθεση της μιλέδης.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Automóviles y humor de los milady.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The single most important product in the early twentieth-century culture of consumption was the automobile, and the number of cars produced more than tripled during the 1920s. Like many other products, however, marketing cars to consumers effectively became as important as manufacturing them efficiently. This 1927 advertisement for Paige-Jewett cars suggests how manufacturers and advertising firms used colors and new styles to differentiate their products from those of competitors. Buying became confused with self-expression as consumers were urged to purchase products as a way to display individual taste and distinction.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das einzelne wichtigste Produkt in der frühen 
Zwanzigstjahrhundert Kultur des Verbrauchs war das Automobil, und die 
Zahl Autos produzierte mehr als verdreifacht während der zwanziger 
Jahre. Wie viele andere Produkte jedoch wurden Marketing-Autos 
zu den Verbrauchern effektiv so wichtig wie Herstellung sie 
leistungsfähig. Diese Reklameanzeige 1927 für Paige-Jewett 
Autos schlägt vor, wie Hersteller und Bekanntmachenunternehmen Farben
und neue Arten verwendeten, um ihre Produkte von denen der 
Konkurrenten zu unterscheiden. Kaufen wurde mit Selbst-Ausdruck 
konfus, wie Verbraucher gedrängt wurden, Produkte als Methode zu 
kaufen, einzelnen Geschmack und Unterscheidung anzuzeigen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le produit le plus important simple dans la culture tôt 
de vingtième-siècle de la consommation était l'automobile, et le 
nombre de voitures a produit plus que triplé pendant les années 20. 
Comme beaucoup d'autres produits, cependant, les voitures de 
vente aux consommateurs pertinemment sont devenues aussi importantes 
que la fabrication ils efficacement. Cette publicité 1927 pour 
des voitures de Paige-Jewett suggère comment les constructeurs et les
sociétés de la publicité ont employé des couleurs et de nouveaux 
modèles pour différencier leurs produits de ceux des concurrents. 
Les achats sont devenus confus avec la libre expression comme des 
consommateurs ont été invités à acheter des produits comme voie 
d'afficher le goût et la distinction individuels.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O único produto o mais importante na cultura adiantada de
vigésimo-século do consumo era o automóvel, e o número dos carros 
produziu triplicado mais do que durante os 1920s. Como muitos 
outros produtos, entretanto, os carros do marketing aos consumidores 
tornaram-se eficazmente tão importantes quanto o manufacturing eles 
eficientemente. Esta propaganda 1927 para carros de Paige-Jewett
sugere como os fabricantes e as firmas anunciar usaram cores e estilos
novos diferenciar seus produtos daqueles dos concorrentes. A 
compra tornou-se confused com self-expressão como os consumidores 
foram incitados comprar produtos como uma maneira indicar o gosto e a 
distinção individuais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il singolo prodotto più importante nella coltura in 
anticipo di ventesimo-secolo di consumo era l'automobile ed il numero 
di automobili ha prodotto più di quanto triplicato durante gli anni 
20. Come molti altri prodotti, tuttavia, gli automobili di 
vendita ai consumatori sono diventato efficacemente efficientemente 
importanti quanto il manufacturing loro. Questa pubblicità 1927
per gli automobili di Paige-Jewett suggerisce come i fornitori e le 
ditte di pubblicità hanno usato i colori ed i nuovi stili per 
differenziare i loro prodotti da quelli dei competitori. 
L'acquisto è stato confuso con l'auto-espressione i consumatori
sono stati invitati a comprare i prodotti come modo visualizzare il 
gusto e la distinzione specifici.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το ενιαίο σημαντικότερο προϊόν στον πρόωρο πολιτισμό
εικοστός-αιώνα της κατανάλωσης ήταν το αυτοκίνητο, και ο αριθμός
αυτοκινήτων παρήγαγε περισσότερο από τριπλασιασμένος κατά τη 
διάρκεια της δεκαετίας του '20. Όπως πολλά άλλα προϊόντα,
εντούτοις, που εμπορεύονται τα αυτοκίνητα στους καταναλωτές 
έγιναν αποτελεσματικά τόσο σημαντικά όπως κατασκευαστικά τους 
αποτελεσματικά. Αυτή η διαφήμιση του 1927 για τα 
αυτοκίνητα παηγε- Jewett προτείνει πώς οι κατασκευαστές και οι 
διαφημιστικές εταιρίες χρησιμοποίησαν τα χρώματα και τις νέες 
μορφές για να διαφοροποιήσουν τα προϊόντα τους από εκείνους των 
ανταγωνιστών. Η αγορά έγινε ταραγμένη με την μόνος-έκφραση
όπως οι καταναλωτές ωθήθηκαν για να αγοράσουν τα προϊόντα ως 
τρόπο να παρουσιαστεί η μεμονωμένες προτίμηση και η διάκριση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El solo producto más importante de la cultura temprana 
del vige'simo-siglo de la consumición era el automóvil, y el número
de coches produjo más que triplicado durante los años 20. Como
muchos otros productos, sin embargo, los coches de la 
comercialización a los consumidores llegaron a ser con eficacia tan 
importantes como la fabricación ellos eficientemente. Este 
anuncio 1927 para los coches de Paige-Jewett sugiere cómo los 
fabricantes y las firmas de la publicidad utilizaron colores y nuevos 
estilos para distinguir sus productos de los de competidores. La
compra llegó a ser confusa con la uno mismo-expresio'n como 
impulsaron a los consumidores comprar productos como manera de 
visualizar gusto y la distinción individuales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087415</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104148</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/automobiles-and-miladys-mood</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
