<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103619</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103619</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206100</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Planet Quest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Planet Suche</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Recherche de Planète</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quest Do Planeta</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ricerca Del Pianeta</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αναζήτηση πλανητών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Búsqueda Del Planeta</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is devoted to the search for new worlds. This search is being conducted over the next 15 years through a series of NASA missions using the most sensitive instruments ever made. Learn how scientists discover planets and determine whether a planet is habitable. Search the atlas of planets to see what planets have been discovered thus far (102) or tour the multimedia gallery. Resources for teachers and learning activities for students are provided.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">wird der Suche nach neuen Welten gewidmet. 
Diese Suche wird über die folgenden 15 Jahre durch eine Reihe 
die NASA Missionen mit den empfindlichsten überhaupt gebildeten 
Instrumenten geleitet. Erlernen Sie, wie Wissenschaftler 
Planeten entdecken und stellen Sie fest, ob ein Planet bewohnbar ist. 
Suchen Sie den Atlas der Planeten, um zu sehen welche Planeten 
bis jetzt entdeckt worden sind (102) oder die Multimediagalerie zu 
bereisen. Betriebsmittel für Lehrer und Lernenaktivitäten für
Kursteilnehmer werden zur Verfügung gestellt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est consacré à la recherche de nouveaux mondes. 
Cette recherche est conduite au cours des 15 années à venir 
par une série de missions de la NASA à l'aide des instruments les 
plus sensibles jamais faits. Apprenez comment les scientifiques 
découvrent des planètes et déterminez si une planète est 
habitable. Recherchez l'atlas des planètes pour voir quelles 
planètes ont été découvertes jusqu'ici (102) ou pour voyager la 
galerie de multimédia. Des ressources pour des professeurs et 
l'étude pour des étudiants sont fournies.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é devotado à busca para mundos novos. Esta 
busca está sendo conduzida sobre os 15 anos seguintes com uma série 
de missões da NASA usando os instrumentos os mais sensíveis feitos 
sempre. Aprenda como os cientistas descobrem planetas e 
determine se um planeta é habitable. Procurare o atlas dos 
planetas para ver que planetas foram descobertos assim distante (102) 
ou para excursionar a galeria dos multimedia. Os recursos para 
professores e as atividades de aprendizagem para estudantes são 
fornecidos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è dedicato alla ricerca di nuovi mondi. 
Questa ricerca sta conducenda nel corso dei 15 anni futuri con 
una serie di missioni della NASA per mezzo degli strumenti più 
sensibili fatti mai. Impari come gli scienziati scoprono i 
pianeti e determini se un pianeta sia abitabile. Cerchi 
l'atlante dei pianeti per vedere che pianeti sono stati scoperti 
finora (102) o per fare un giro della galleria di multimedia. Le
risorse per le attività imparare e degli insegnanti per gli allievi 
sono fornite.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">αφιερώνεται στην αναζήτηση των νέων κόσμων. 
Αυτή η αναζήτηση διεξάγεται κατά τη διάρκεια των επόμενων 
15 ετών μέσω μιας σειράς αποστολών της NASA χρησιμοποιώντας
τα πιό ευαίσθητα όργανα που γίνονται πάντα. Μάθετε πώς οι
επιστήμονες ανακαλύπτουν τους πλανήτες και καθορίζουν εάν ένας 
πλανήτης είναι κατοικήσιμος. Ψάξτε τον άτλαντα των 
πλανητών για να δείτε ποιοι πλανήτες έχουν ανακαλυφθεί 
ως εδώ (102) ή περιοδεύουν τη στοά πολυμέσων. Τα 
στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς για τους δασκάλους και οι δραστηριότητες 
εκμάθησης για τους σπουδαστές παρέχονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">se dedica a la búsqueda para los mundos nuevos. 
Esta búsqueda se está conduciendo durante los 15 años 
próximos con una serie de misiones de la NASA usando los instrumentos
más sensibles hechos siempre. Aprenda cómo los científicos 
descubren los planetas y determínese si un planeta es habitable. 
Busque el atlas de los planetas para ver qué planetas se han 
descubierto hasta el momento (102) o para viajar la galería de las 
multimedias. Los recursos para las actividades de los profesores
y el aprender para los estudiantes se proporcionan.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206100</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103619</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/planet-quest</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
