<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103388</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103388</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087521</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Open Educational Resources: Toward a New Educational Paradigm</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Öffnen Sie Pädagogische Betriebsmittel: In
Richtung zu einem neuen pädagogischen Paradigma</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ouvrez Les Ressources Éducatives : Vers un 
nouveau paradigme éducatif</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Abra Recursos Educacionais: Para um paradigm
educacional novo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Apra Le Risorse Educative: Verso un nuovo 
paradigma educativo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανοικτά εκπαιδευτικά στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς: Προς
ένα νέο εκπαιδευτικό παράδειγμα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Abra Los Recursos Educativos: Hacia un nuevo
paradigma educativo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The purpose of open educational resources (OER) is to provide centralized access to materials and support the conditions under which new OER can be created globally and across disciplines. This article highlights the challenges to realizing these possibilities, discusses models that are emerging to address them, and calls for future research into OER use and reuse as a necessary next step in sustaining OER.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Zweck der geöffneten pädagogischen 
Betriebsmittel (OER) ist, zentralisierten Zugriff zu den Materialien 
zur Verfügung zu stellen und die Bedingungen zu unterstützen, unter 
denen neues OER Disziplinen global und über erstellt werden kann. 
Dieser Artikel markiert die Herausforderungen zur Verwirklichung
dieser Möglichkeiten, behandelt Modelle, die auftauchen, um zu ihnen 
zu sprechen, und verlangt zukünftige Forschung in OER Gebrauch und 
Wiederverwendung als notwendiger folgender Jobstep in unterstützendem
OER.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le but des ressources éducatives ouvertes (OER) 
est fournir l'accès centralisé aux matériaux et de supporter les 
conditions dans lesquelles nouvel OER peut être créé globalement et
à travers des disciplines. Cet article met en valeur les défis
à réaliser ces possibilités, discute les modèles qui émergent 
pour s'adresser à eux, et nécessite la future recherche dans 
l'utilisation d'OER et la réutilisation comme prochaine étape 
nécessaire dans OER soutenant.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A finalidade dos recursos educacionais abertos 
(OER) é fornecer o acesso centralizado aos materiais e suportar as 
circunstâncias sob que OER novo pode ser criado global e através das
disciplinas. Este artigo destaca os desafios a realizar estas 
possibilidades, discute os modelos que estão emergindo para se 
dirigir lhes, e chama-se para a pesquisa futura no uso de OER e reusar
como uma etapa seguinte necessária em OER sustentando.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lo scopo delle risorse educative aperte (OER) è 
di fornire l'accesso centralizzato ai materiali e sostenere le 
circostanze in cui nuovo OER può essere creato globalmente ed 
attraverso le discipline. Questo articolo evidenzia le sfide a 
realizzare queste possibilità, discute i modelli che stanno emergendo
per richiamarli e richiede ricerca futura su uso di OER e 
riutilizzazione come punto seguente necessario in OER sostenente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο σκοπός των ανοικτών εκπαιδευτικών στοιχείων 
συμπεριφοράς (OER) είναι να παρασχεθεί η συγκεντρωμένη 
πρόσβαση στα υλικά και να υποστηριχθούν οι όροι κάτω από τους 
οποίους νέο OER μπορεί να δημιουργηθεί συνολικά και στις 
πειθαρχίες. Αυτό το άρθρο δίνει έμφαση στις προκλήσεις 
στην πραγματοποίηση αυτών των δυνατοτήτων, συζητά τα μοντέλα που 
προκύπτουν για να τους εξετάσουν, και απαιτεί τη μελλοντική 
έρευνα στη χρήση OER και την επαναχρησιμοποίηση ως απαραίτητο 
επόμενο βήμα στη στήριξη OER.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El propósito de los recursos educativos abiertos 
(OER) es proporcionar al acceso centralizado a los materiales y 
utilizar las condiciones bajo las cuales OER nuevo se puede crear 
global y a través de disciplinas. Este artículo destaca los 
desafíos a realizar estas posibilidades, discute los modelos que 
están emergiendo para tratarlos, y llama para la investigación 
futura en uso de OER y la reutilización como paso de progresión 
siguiente necesario en OER que sostiene.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:LISA PETRIDES AND CYNTHIA JIMES
FN:LISA PETRIDES AND CYNTHIA JIMES
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087521</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103388</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/matters/open-educational-resources-toward-a-new-educational-paradigm-1</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
