<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104936</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104936</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206380</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">John Snow -- Pioneer in the field of epidemiology</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">John Schnee -- Pionier in auffangene der 
Epidemiologie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Neige de John -- pionnier dans le domaine de 
l'épidémiologie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Neve de John -- pioneiro no campo do epidemiology</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Neve del John -- pioniere nel campo di 
epidemiologia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θ*Ιοχν Snow -- πρωτοπόρος στον τομέα της 
επιδημιολογίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Nieve de Juan -- pionero en el campo de la 
epidemiología</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">looks at the career of the first modern bacterial epidemiologist. In 1854 Snow correlated, through painstaking documentation, cases of cholera with customers of one of two water companies serving London. His efforts proved his theory of cholera transmission. His creative use of the scientific information of his time is an example for those interested in disease prevention and control.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Blicke auf die Karriere des ersten modernen 
bakteriellen Kenners der epidemischen Krankheiten. Im Schnee 
1854 aufeinander bezogen, durch sorgfältige Unterlagen, Fälle von 
der Cholera mit Kunden von einer von zwei Wasserfirmen, die London 
dienen. Seine Bemühungen prüften seine Theorie der 
Choleraübertragung. Sein kreativer Gebrauch von der 
Fachinformation seiner Zeit ist ein Beispiel für die interessiert an 
Krankheitverhinderung und -steuerung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">regards à la carrière du premier épidémiologue
bactérien moderne. Dans la neige 1854 corrélée, par la 
documentation soigneuse, cas du choléra avec des clients d'une de 
deux compagnies de l'eau servant Londres. Ses efforts ont 
prouvé sa théorie de transmission de choléra. Sa utilisation 
créatrice d'information scientifique de son temps est un exemple pour
ceux intéressé à l'empêchement et à la commande de la maladie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">olhares na carreira do primeiro epidemiólogo 
bacteriano moderno. Na neve 1854 correlacionada, através da 
documentação painstaking, casos do cholera com os clientes de uma de
duas companhias da água que servem a Londres. Seus esforços 
provaram sua teoria da transmissão do cholera. Seu uso creativo
da informação científica de seu tempo é um exemplo para aqueles 
interessado na prevenção e no controle da doença.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">sguardi alla carriera del primo epidemiologo 
batterico moderno. In neve 1854 correlata, attraverso 
documentazione scrupolosa, casi di colera con i clienti di una di due 
aziende dell'acqua che servono Londra. I suoi sforzi hanno 
dimostrato la sua teoria della trasmissione del colera. Il suo 
uso creativo dell'informazione scientifica del suo tempo è un esempio
per quelli interessato alla prevenzione ed al controllo di malattia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει τη σταδιοδρομία του πρώτου σύγχρονου 
βακτηριακού επιδημιολόγου. Το 1854 το χιόνι συσχέτισε, 
μέσω της προσεκτικής τεκμηρίωσης, τις περιπτώσεις της χολέρας με 
τους πελάτες της μιας από δύο επιχειρήσεις ύδατος που 
εξυπηρετούν το Λονδίνο. Οι προσπάθειές του απέδειξαν τη 
θεωρία του μετάδοσης χολέρας. Η δημιουργική χρήση του των 
επιστημονικών πληροφοριών του χρόνου του είναι ένα παράδειγμα 
για εκείνους ενδιαφερόμενους στην πρόληψη και τον έλεγχο 
ασθενειών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">miradas en la carrera del primer epidemiólogo 
bacteriano moderno. En la nieve 1854 correlacionada, a través 
de la documentación cuidadosa, casos del cólera con los clientes de 
una de dos compañías del agua que sirven Londres. Sus 
esfuerzos probaron su teoría de la transmisión del cólera. Su
uso creativo de la información científica de su tiempo es un ejemplo
para ésos interesado en la prevención y el control de la enfermedad.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206380</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104936</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/john-snow-pioneer-in-the-field-of-epidemiology</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
