<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103145</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103145</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973945</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Physics Games: The Integrated Circuit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Physik-Spiele: Die Integrierte Schaltung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jeux de Physique : Le Circuit intégré</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogos Da Física: O Circuito Integrado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giochi Di Fisica: Il Circuito integrato</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παιχνίδια φυσικής: Το ολοκληρωμένο κύκλωμα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Juegos De la Física: El Circuito Integrado</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Play a game and find out about a Nobel Prize awarded discovery or work! Integrated circuits can be found in almost every modern electrical device such as computers, cars, television sets, CD players, cellular phones, etc. But what is an integrated circuit and what is the history behind it? Learn about Nobel Laureate Jack Kilby and his part in the invention that is the basis of all modern technology.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spielen Sie ein Spiel und finden Sie über eine 
zugesprochene Entdeckung oder eine Arbeit des Nobelpreises heraus! 
Integrierte Schaltungen können in fast jeder modernen 
elektrischen Einheit wie Computern, Autos, Fernsehern, CD-Spielern, 
zellularen Telefonen, usw. gefunden werden. Aber was ist eine 
integrierte Schaltung und was ist die Geschichte hinter ihr? 
Erlernen Sie über Nobel Laureatus Jack Kilby und sein Teil in 
der Erfindung, die die Grundlage aller modernen Technologie ist.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jouez un jeu et découvrez au sujet d'une 
découverte ou d'un travail attribuée de prix Nobel ! Des 
circuits intégrés peuvent être trouvés dans presque chaque 
dispositif électrique moderne tel que des ordinateurs, des voitures, 
des téléviseurs, des joueurs de CD, des téléphones cellulaires, 
etc... Mais quel est un circuit intégré et qu'est-elle 
l'histoire derrière elle ? Renseignez-vous sur le lauréat Jack
Kilby Nobel et sa partie dans l'invention qui est la base de toute la 
technologie moderne.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogue um jogo e encontre-o para fora sobre uma 
descoberta ou um trabalho concedido do prêmio de nobel! Os 
circuitos integrados podem ser encontrados em quase cada dispositivo 
elétrico moderno tal como computadores, carros, jogos de televisão, 
jogadores de CD, telefones celulares, etc.. Mas que são um 
circuito integrado e que é o history atrás dele? Aprenda sobre
o laureate Jack Kilby de Nobel e a sua parte na invenção que é a 
base de toda a tecnologia moderna.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gioc un gioco e scopra circa una scoperta o un 
lavoro ricevuta del premio Nobel! I circuiti integrati possono 
essere trovati in quasi ogni dispositivo elettrico moderno quali i 
calcolatori, gli automobili, i televisori, i giocatori di CD, i 
telefoni cellulari, ecc. Ma che cosa è un circuito integrato e 
che cosa è la storia dietro esso? Impari circa il laureate Jack
Kilby Nobel e la sua parte nell'invenzione che è la base di tutta la 
tecnologia moderna.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παίξτε ένα παιχνίδι και ανακαλύψτε για μια 
απονεμημένη βραβείο ανακάλυψη ή μια εργασία Νόμπελ! Τα 
ολοκληρωμένα κυκλώματα μπορούν να βρεθούν σχεδόν σε κάθε 
σύγχρονη ηλεκτρική συσκευή όπως οι υπολογιστές, τα αυτοκίνητα, 
τα τηλεοπτικά σύνολα, τα CD, τα κυψελοειδή τηλέφωνα, κ.λπ.... 
Αλλά τι είναι ένα ολοκληρωμένο κύκλωμα και ποια είναι η 
ιστορία πίσω από το; Μάθετε για το δαφνοστεφή Jack 
Kilby Νόμπελ και το μέρος του στην εφεύρεση που είναι η βάση 
όλης της σύγχρονης τεχνολογίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Juegue un juego y descubra sobre un 
descubrimiento o un trabajo concedido del premio Nobel! Los 
circuitos integrados se pueden encontrar en casi cada dispositivo 
eléctrico moderno tal como ordenadores, coches, televisiones, 
lectores de cd, teléfonos portátiles, etc. ¿Pero cuál es un 
circuito integrado y cuál es la historia detrás de ella? 
Aprenda sobre el laureado Gato Kilby Nobel y su parte en la 
invención que es la base de toda la tecnología moderna.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973945</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103145</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/physics-games-the-integrated-circuit</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
