<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107262</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107262</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202697</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Round and Round It Goes; Water, Where It Stops Nobody Knows</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Rund und rund geht es; Wasser, In dem Es 
Niemand Stoppt, Weiß</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Rond et rond il disparaît ; l'Eau, Où Elle
N'arrête Personne Sait</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Redondo e redondo vai; A Água, Onde Não 
para Ninguém Sabe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Rotondo e rotondo va; L'Acqua, In cui Non 
arresta Nessuno Sa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο κύκλος και ο κύκλος αυτό πηγαίνουν  Το ύδωρ, 
όπου δεν σταματά κανενός ξέρει</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Redondo y redondo va; El Agua, Donde No para
A Nadie Sabe</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The hydrologic cycle is the process, powered by the sun, which identifies the constant, endless movement of water from the atmosphere to the earth to the ground water, to the rivers to the oceans and back into the atmosphere. This experimental lab lesson will show the process of the hydrologic cycle as it relates to the earth's atmosphere by showing three different scenarios, the first scenario (the control), container A, shows the hydrologic cycle with no contaminates. The second scenario, container B, shows the hydrologic cycle with the earth's soil contaminated. The third scenario, container C, demonstrates the hydrologic cycle with the air polluted. These three situations will give the student an idea of how the atmosphere and the growth of plant life are affected by different contaminants in the earth. This lesson will, in fact, investigate the hydrologic cycle experimentally.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die hydrologische Schleife ist der Prozeß, 
angeschaltet durch die Sonne, die die konstante, endlose Bewegung des 
Wassers von der Atmosphäre zur Masse zum Grundwasser, zu den Flüssen
zu den Ozeanen und zurück in die Atmosphäre kennzeichnet. 
Diese experimentelle Laborlektion zeigt den Prozeß der 
hydrologischen Schleife, wie sie auf der Atmosphäre der Masse in 
Verbindung steht, indem sie drei unterschiedliche Drehbücher zeigen, 
das erste Drehbuch (die Steuerung), Behälter A, Erscheinen, welche 
die hydrologische Schleife ohne verschmutzt. Das zweite 
Drehbuch, Behälter B, zeigt die hydrologische Schleife mit dem 
verschmutzten Boden der Masse. Das dritte Drehbuch, Behälter C,
zeigt die hydrologische Schleife mit der beschmutzten Luft. 
Diese drei Situationen geben dem Kursteilnehmer eine Idee von, 
wie die Atmosphäre und das Wachstum des Betriebslebens durch 
unterschiedliche Verschmutzer in der Masse beeinflußt wird. 
Diese Lektion forscht tatsächlich die hydrologische Schleife 
experimentell nach.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le cycle hydrologique est le processus, actionné 
par le soleil, qui identifie le mouvement constant et sans fin de 
l'eau de l'atmosphère à la terre aux eaux souterraines, vers les 
fleuves vers les océans et de nouveau dans l'atmosphère. Cette
leçon expérimentale de laboratoire montrera le processus du cycle 
hydrologique comme elle associe à l'atmosphère de la terre en 
montrant trois scénarios différents, le premier scénario (la 
commande), le récipient A, expositions que le cycle hydrologique sans
souille. Le deuxième scénario, le récipient B, montre le 
cycle hydrologique avec le sol de la terre souillé. Le 
troisième scénario, le récipient C, démontre le cycle hydrologique
avec de l'air pollué. Ces trois situations donneront à 
l'étudiant une idée de la façon dont l'atmosphère et la croissance
de la flore sont affectées par différents contaminants dans la 
terre. Cette leçon, en fait, étudiera le cycle hydrologique 
expérimentalement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O ciclo hydrologic é o processo, powered pelo 
sol, que identifica o movimento constante, infinito da água da 
atmosfera à terra à água à terra, aos rios aos oceanos e à parte 
traseira na atmosfera. Esta lição experimental do laboratório
mostrará o processo do ciclo hydrologic como se relaciona à 
atmosfera da terra mostrando três scenarios diferentes, o primeiro 
scenario (o controle), recipiente A, mostras que o ciclo hydrologic 
com nenhum contamina. O segundo scenario, recipiente B, mostra o
ciclo hydrologic com o solo da terra contaminado. O terceiro 
scenario, recipiente C, demonstra o ciclo hydrologic com o ar 
polluted. Estas três situações dão ao estudante uma idéia 
de como a atmosfera e o crescimento da vida de planta são afetados 
por contaminadores diferentes na terra. Esta lição, no fato, 
investigará o ciclo hydrologic experimental.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il ciclo idrologico è il processo, alimentato dal
sole, che identifica il movimento costante e infinito di acqua 
dall'atmosfera alla terra all'acqua sotterranea, ai fiumi agli oceani 
e nuovamente dentro l'atmosfera. Questa lezione sperimentale del
laboratorio mostrerà il processo del ciclo idrologico come si 
riferisce all'atmosfera della terra mostrando tre piani d'azione 
differenti, il primo piano d'azione (il controllo), il contenitore A, 
esposizioni che il ciclo idrologico senza contamina. Il secondo 
piano d'azione, il contenitore B, mostra il ciclo idrologico con il 
terreno della terra contaminato. Il terzo piano d'azione, il 
contenitore C, dimostra il ciclo idrologico con l'aria inquinante. 
Queste tre situazioni daranno all'allievo un'idea di come 
l'atmosfera e lo sviluppo di vita della pianta sono influenzati dagli 
agenti inquinanti differenti nella terra. Questa lezione, 
infatti, studierà sperimentalmente il ciclo idrologico.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο υδρολογικός κύκλος είναι η διαδικασία, που 
τροφοδοτείται από τον ήλιο, ο οποίος προσδιορίζει τη σταθερή, 
ατελείωτη μετακίνηση του ύδατος από την ατμόσφαιρα στη γη στο 
υπόγειο νερό, στους ποταμούς στους ωκεανούς και πίσω στην 
ατμόσφαιρα. Αυτό το πειραματικό μάθημα εργαστηρίων θα 
εμφανίσει τη διαδικασία του υδρολογικού κύκλου όπως αφορά τη 
γήινη ατμόσφαιρα με την εμφάνιση τριών διαφορετικών σεναρίων, το
πρώτο σενάριο (ο έλεγχος), εμπορευματοκιβώτιο Α, εμφανίζει ότι ο
υδρολογικός κύκλος χωρίς μολύνει. Το δεύτερο σενάριο, 
εμπορευματοκιβώτιο β, εμφανίζει υδρολογικό κύκλο με το γήινο 
χώμα μολυσμένο. Το τρίτο σενάριο, εμπορευματοκιβώτιο γ, 
καταδεικνύει τον υδρολογικό κύκλο με τον αέρα μολυσμένο. 
Αυτές οι τρεις καταστάσεις θα δώσουν στο σπουδαστή μια ιδέα
για το πώς η ατμόσφαιρα και η αύξηση της ζωής εγκαταστάσεων 
επηρεάζονται από τους διαφορετικούς μολυσματικούς παράγοντες στη 
γη. Αυτό το μάθημα, στην πραγματικότητα, θα ερευνήσει τον 
υδρολογικό κύκλο πειραματικά.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El ciclo hidrológico es el proceso, accionado por
el sol, que identifica el movimiento constante, sin fin del agua de la
atmósfera a la tierra al agua subterránea, a los ríos a los 
océanos y nuevamente dentro de la atmósfera. Esta lección 
experimental del laboratorio mostrará el proceso del ciclo 
hidrológico como se relaciona con la atmósfera de la tierra 
mostrando tres diversos decorados, el primer decorado (el control), 
envase A, demostraciones que el ciclo hidrológico sin contamina. 
El segundo decorado, envase B, muestra el ciclo hidrológico con
el suelo de la tierra contaminado. El tercer decorado, envase C,
demuestra el ciclo hidrológico con el aire contaminado. Estas 
tres situaciones darán a estudiante una idea de cómo la atmósfera y
el crecimiento de la vida de planta son afectados por diversos 
contaminantes en la tierra. Esta lección, en hecho, 
investigará el ciclo hidrológico experimental.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:GEOL 130
FN:GEOL 130
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202697</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107262</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/round-and-round-it-goes-water-where-it-stops-nobody-knows</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
