<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/1784445160</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>1784445160</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205477</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Using Podcasts to Enrich Students' Listening Repertoire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Verwenden von von Podcasts, um hörendes 
Repertoire der Kursteilnehmer anzureichern</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Utilisation de Podcasts pour enrichir le 
répertoire d'écoute des étudiants</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Usando Podcasts enriquecer o repertoire escutando 
dos estudantes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Usando Podcasts per arricchire il repertorio 
ascoltante degli allievi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Χρησιμοποίηση Podcasts για να εμπλουτίσει το 
ρεπερτόριο ακούσματος των σπουδαστών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Usar Podcasts para enriquecer el repertorio que 
escucha de los estudiantes</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Designed for ESOL students, this lesson is also suitable for high school students and adults. Students are shown how to navigate websites of major broadcasting networks in English, such as KQED, CNN, BBC, DW, ABC, and other educational websites. It focuses on how to search for podcasts by topics, such as news, science, nature, environment, technology, health, culture, music, art, business, sports, politics etc. to enrich students'?? listening repertoire and develop their aural comprehension skills in English.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Konzipiert für ESOL Kursteilnehmer, ist diese 
Lektion auch für High School Kursteilnehmer und Erwachsene 
verwendbar. Kursteilnehmer werden gezeigt, wie man Web site der 
übertragenden Hauptnetze auf englisch, wie KQED, CNN, BBC, DW, ABC 
und andere pädagogische Web site steuert. Sie konzentriert auf,
wie man nach podcasts durch Themen, wie Nachrichten, Wissenschaft, 
Natur, Umgebung, Technologie, Gesundheit, Kultur, Musik, kunst, 
Geschäft, Sport, Politik sucht, etc., zum Kursteilnehmer 
anzureichern?? hörendes Repertoire und entwickeln ihre 
Ohrenerfassenfähigkeiten auf englisch.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Conçu pour des étudiants d'ESOL, cette leçon 
est également appropriée aux étudiants et aux adultes de lycée. 
Des étudiants sont montrés comment diriger des sites Web des 
réseaux d'annonce principaux en anglais, tel que KQED, CNN, 
BBC, DW, ABC, et d'autres sites Web éducatifs. Elle se 
concentre sur la façon rechercher des podcasts par des sujets, tels 
que les nouvelles, la science, la nature, l'environnement, la 
technologie, la santé, la culture, la musique, l'art, les affaires, 
les sports, la politique etc. pour enrichir les étudiants ? ? 
le répertoire d'écoute et développent leurs qualifications 
auditives de compréhension en anglais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Projetado para estudantes de ESOL, esta lição é
também apropriada para estudantes e adultos da High School. Os 
estudantes são mostrados como navigate Web site de redes transmitindo
principais em inglês, tal como KQED, CNN, BBC, DW, ABC, e outros Web 
site educacionais. Focaliza em como procurarar por podcasts por 
tópicos, tais como a notícia, a ciência, a natureza, o ambiente, a 
tecnologia, a saúde, a cultura, a música, a arte, o negócio, os 
esportes, a política etc. para enriquecer estudantes?? o 
repertoire escutando e desenvolve suas habilidades aural da 
compreensão em inglês.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Progettato per gli allievi di ESOL, questa lezione
è egualmente adatta ad allievi e ad adulti della High School. 
Gli allievi sono indicati come traversare i Web site delle reti 
di radiodiffusione importanti in inglese, quali KQED, il CNN, BBC, DW,
il ABC ed altri Web site educativi. Mette a fuoco su come 
cercare i podcasts dai soggetti, quali le notizie, la scienza, la 
natura, l'ambiente, la tecnologia, la salute, la coltura, la musica, 
l'arte, il commercio, gli sport, la politica ecc. per arricchire gli 
allievi?? il repertorio ascoltante e sviluppa le loro abilità 
sonore di comprensione in inglese.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σχεδιασμένο για τους σπουδαστές ESOL, αυτό το 
μάθημα είναι επίσης κατάλληλο για τους σπουδαστές και τους 
ενηλίκους γυμνασίου. Οι σπουδαστές εμφανίζονται πώς να 
πλοηγήσουν τους ιστοχώρους σημαντικών δικτύων ραδιοφωνικής 
αναμετάδοσης στα αγγλικά, όπως KQED, CNN, το BBC, DW, 
ABC, και άλλοι εκπαιδευτικοί ιστοχώροι. Εστιάζει στο πώς
να ψάξει για τα podcasts από τα θέματα, όπως οι ειδήσεις, την 
επιστήμη, τη φύση, το περιβάλλον, την τεχνολογία, την υγεία, τον 
πολιτισμό, τη μουσική, την τέχνη, την επιχείρηση, τον αθλητισμό, 
την πολιτική κ.λπ. για να εμπλουτίσει το ρεπερτόριο ακούσματος 
?? των σπουδαστών και να αναπτύξει τις ακουστικές δεξιότητες 
κατανόησής τους στα αγγλικά.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Diseñado para los estudiantes de ESOL, esta 
lección es también conveniente para los estudiantes y los adultos de
la High School secundaria. Muestran los estudiantes cómo 
navegar Web site de redes que difunden importantes en inglés, tal 
como KQED, CNN, BBC, DW, ABC, y otros Web site educativos. ¿Se 
centra en cómo buscar para podcasts por asuntos, tales como noticias,
ciencia, naturaleza, ambiente, tecnología, salud, cultura, música, 
arte, negocio, deportes, política etc. para enriquecer a los 
estudiantes?? el repertorio que escucha y desarrolla sus 
habilidades aurales de la comprensión en inglés.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205477</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>1784445160</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/using-podcasts-to-enrich-studentsa8099-listening-repertoire</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
