<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108380</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108380</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086352</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"It Was All Men Talking:" Cathy Wilkerson on 1960s Campus Organizing</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Es War Alle Sprechenden Männer:" Cathy 
Wilkerson auf sechziger Jahren verbieten Organisierens</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"C'était Tous les Hommes Parlant :" Cathy 
Wilkerson les années 60 consignent l'organisation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Era Todos os Homens Que Falam:" Cathy 
Wilkerson em 1960s retem organizar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Era Tutti gli Uomini Che Comunicano:" Cathy
Wilkerson sugli anni 60 campus l'organizzazione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ήταν όλα τα άτομα που μιλούν:" Θ*Θατχυ 
Wilkerson στην οργάνωση πανεπιστημιουπόλεων της δεκαετίας του 
'60</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Era Todos los Hombres Que hablaban:" Cathy 
Wilkerson el los años 60 consigna la ordenación</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Many of those who took part in the student movement of the 1960's drew their inspiration from the African-American struggle for freedom. That was true for Cathy Wilkerson, who became involved in the civil rights movement and Students for a Democratic Society (SDS) in 1963 while at Swarthmore College. She described her experience as a college student listening to Civil Rights leader Gloria Richardson as the event that changed her life. Wilkerson went on to work in the SDS national office and edited the SDS newspaper,  New Left Notes.  In 1968, she moved to Washington DC to open a SDS regional office, and later became a Weatherman. [The material in brackets was added to the transcript shortly after the recorded interview.]</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Viele von denen, die an der Kursteilnehmerbewegung
der sechziger Jahre teilnahmen, zeichneten ihre Inspiration vom 
Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Kampf für Freiheit. Das war für 
Cathy Wilkerson zutreffend, das in den Zivilrechten Bewegung und 
Kursteilnehmer für eine demokratische Gesellschaft (SDS) in 1963 
während an der Swarthmore Hochschule beteiligt wurde. Sie 
beschrieb ihre Erfahrung als Student, der auf Zivilrechtführer Gloria
Richardson als der Fall hört, der ihre Lebensdauer änderte. 
Wilkerson fuhr fort, im SDS nationalen Büro zu arbeiten und 
bearbeitete die SDS Zeitung, neue linke Anmerkungen. 1968 zog 
sie auf Washington Gleichstrom um, um ein SDS regionales Büro zu 
öffnen und wurde später ein Weatherman. [ das Material in den 
Haltewinkeln wurde der Abschrift kurz nach dem gespeicherten 
Interview. hinzugefügt ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Beaucoup de ceux qui ont participé au mouvement 
d'étudiant des années 60 ont tiré leur inspiration de la lutte 
afro-américaine pour la liberté. C'était vrai pour Cathy 
Wilkerson, qui est devenu impliqué dans les droits civiques mouvement
et étudiants pour une société démocratique (SDS) dans 1963 tandis 
qu'à l'université de Swarthmore. Elle a décrit son 
expérience en tant qu'étudiante d'université écoutant le Chef 
Gloria Richardson de droits civiques comme événement qui a changé 
sa vie. Wilkerson a continué pour fonctionner dans le bureau 
national de SDS et a édité le journal de SDS, nouvelles notes 
gauches. En 1968, elle s'est déplacée à DC de Washington pour
ouvrir un bureau régional de SDS, et plus tard est devenue un 
Météorologue. [ le matériel entre parenthèses a été ajouté 
à la transcription peu de temps après l'entrevue enregistrée. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Muita daquelas que fizeram exame da parte no 
movimento do estudante dos 1960's desenhou sua inspiração do 
esforço Africano-Americano para a liberdade. Isso era 
verdadeiro para Cathy Wilkerson, que se tornou involvido nas direitas 
civis movimento e estudantes para uma sociedade democrática (SDS) em 
1963 quando na faculdade de Swarthmore. Descreveu sua 
experiência como um estudante de faculdade que escuta chefes dos 
direitos civis Gloria Richardson como o evento que mudou sua vida. 
Wilkerson foi sobre trabalhar no escritório nacional do SDS e 
editou o jornal do SDS, notas esquerdas novas. Em 1968, moveu-se
para a C.C. de Washington para abrir um escritório regional do SDS, e
transformou-se mais tarde um weatherman. [ o material nos 
suportes foi adicionado ao transcript logo depois que a entrevista 
gravada. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Molti di coloro che ha partecipato al movimento 
dell'allievo degli anni 60 hanno dissipato la loro ispirazione dalla 
lotta Africano-Americana per la libertà. Quello era allineare 
per Cathy Wilkerson, che è stato implicato nei diritti civili 
movimento ed allievi per una società democratica (SDS) in 1963 mentre
all'università di Swarthmore. Ha descritto la sua esperienza 
come allievo di università che ascolta il capo Gloria 
Richardson di diritti civili come l'evento che ha cambiato la sua 
vita. Wilkerson ha continuato a funzionare nell'ufficio 
nazionale di SDS ed ha stampato il giornale di SDS, nuove note di 
sinistra. In 1968, si è mossa verso DC di Washington per aprire
un ufficio regionale di SDS e più successivamente è diventato un 
weatherman. [ il materiale tra parentesi è stato aggiunto alla 
trascrizione subito dopo l'intervista registrata. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πολλοί από εκείνους που συμμετείχαν στη μετακίνηση 
σπουδαστών της δεκαετίας του '60 έσυραν την έμπνευσή τους από 
την αφρικανικός-αμερικανική προσπάθεια για την ελευθερία. 
Αυτός ίσχυε για την Cathy Wilkerson, η οποία 
αναμίχθηκε στη μετακίνηση και τους σπουδαστές αστικών δικαιωμάτων
για μια δημοκρατική κοινωνία (SDS) το 1963 ενώ στο κολλέγιο 
Swarthmore. Περιέγραψε την εμπειρία της ως σπουδαστή 
κολλεγίων που ακούει τον ηγέτη Gloria Richardson αστικών 
δικαιωμάτων ως γεγονός που άλλαξε τη ζωή της. Το 
Wilkerson πήγε για να λειτουργήσει στο εθνικό γραφείο SDS 
και επιμελήθηκε τη SDS εφημερίδα, νέες αριστερές σημειώσεις. 
Το 1968, κινήθηκε προς την Ουάσιγκτον DC για να ανοίξει
ένα περιφερειακό γραφείο SDS, και έγινε αργότερα 
μετεωρολόγος. [ Το υλικό εντός παρενθέσεως προστέθηκε 
στο αντίγραφο αμέσως μετά από την καταγραμμένη συνέντευξη. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Muchos de los que participaron en el movimiento 
del estudiante de los años 60 trazaron su inspiración de la lucha 
Africano-Americana para la libertad. Eso era verdad para Cathy 
Wilkerson, que llegó a estar implicado en las derechas civiles 
movimiento y estudiantes para una sociedad democrática (SDS) en 1963 
mientras que en la universidad de Swarthmore. Ella describió su
experiencia como estudiante de universidad que escuchaba el arranque 
de cinta de las derechas civiles Gloria Richardson como el 
acontecimiento que cambió su vida. Wilkerson continuó trabajar
en la oficina nacional del SDS y corrigió el periódico del SDS, 
nuevas notas izquierdas. En 1968, ella se trasladó a la C.C. de
Washington para abrir una oficina regional del SDS, e hizo más 
adelante meteorólogo. [ el material en corchetes fue agregado a
la transcripción poco después la entrevista registrada. ]</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086352</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108380</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/it-was-all-men-talking-cathy-wilkerson-on-1960s-campus-organizing</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
