<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103542</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103542</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087254</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Writing the Emancipation Proclamation."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">", die Emanzipation-Proklamation schreibend."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"écrivant la proclamation d'émancipation."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"escrevendo o proclamation do emancipation."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"scrivendo la proclamazione di emancipazione."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Γράφοντας την προκήρυξη Χειραφέτησης."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"escribiendo la proclamación de la 
emancipación."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Although many Northerners, including Abraham Lincoln, initially hoped to prosecute the war without interfering with slavery as it existed, pressure from slaves who fled to Union lines, abolitionist sentiment in the North, and a deteriorating military situation pushed Lincoln to consider abolishing slavery. In September 1862 Lincoln issued a preliminary Emancipation Proclamation. He signed the final edict on January 1, 1863. In this caricature by Baltimore pro-South Democrat Adalbert Johann Volck, an inebriated Lincoln, surrounded by symbols of Satanism and paintings honoring John Brown and slave rebellions, trod on the Constitution as he drafted the proclamation.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Obgleich viel Northerners, einschließlich Abraham 
Lincoln, zuerst hoffte, den Krieg zu verfolgen, ohne Sklaverei zu 
behinderen, während es existierte, drückten Druck von den Sklaven, 
die zu den Anschlußzeilen flohen, abolitionist Gefühl im Norden und 
eine verschlechternde militärische Situation Lincoln, um Sklaverei, 
abzuschaffen zu erwägen. Im September 1862 gab Lincoln eine 
einleitende Emanzipation-Proklamation heraus. Er unterzeichnete 
den abschließenden Erlaß an Januar 1, 1863. In dieser 
Karikatur durch Baltimore Pro-Süden Demokraten Adalbert Johann Volck,
ein inebriated Lincoln, umgeben durch Symbole von Satanism und von 
Anstrichen, welche John die braunen und Sklavenaufstände ehren, trat 
auf der Beschaffenheit, während er die Proklamation zeichnete.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bien que beaucoup de Habitants du Nord, y compris Abraham 
Lincoln, aient au commencement espéré poursuivre la guerre sans 
gêner l'esclavage pendant qu'il existait, la pression des esclaves 
qui se sont sauvés aux lignes des syndicats, le sentiment 
d'abolitionniste dans le nord, et une situation militaire 
détériorante ont poussé Lincoln pour considérer supprimer 
l'esclavage. En septembre 1862 Lincoln a émis une proclamation 
préliminaire d'émancipation. Il a signé l'édit final janvier
1, 1863. Dans cette caricature par le démocrate Adalbert Johann
Volck, Lincoln enivré de Baltimore pro-sud, entouré par des 
symboles de Satanism et de peintures honorant des rébellions brunes 
et slaves de John, a marché sur la constitution pendant qu'il 
dessinait la proclamation.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Embora muito Northerners, including Abraham Lincoln, 
esperasse inicialmente prosecute a guerra sem interferir com o slavery
enquanto existiu, a pressão dos escravos que fujiram às linhas da 
união, o sentiment do abolitionist no norte, e uma situação militar
deteriorando-se empurraram Lincoln para considerar abolishing o 
slavery. Em setembro 1862 Lincoln emitiu um proclamation 
preliminar do emancipation. Assinou o edict final janeiro em 1, 
1863. Neste caricature pela democrata Adalbert Johann Volck do 
pro-Sul de Baltimore, um Lincoln inebriated, cercado por símbolos de 
Satanism e de pinturas que honram rebeliões marrons e slave de John, 
pisou no constitution enquanto esboçou o proclamation.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Anche se molto Northerners, compreso Abraham Lincoln, 
inizialmente ha sperato di proseguire la guerra senza interferire con 
lo slavery mentre ha esistito, la pressione dagli schiavi che sono 
fuggito alle righe del sindacato, il sentimento di abolitionist nel 
nord e una situazione militare deteriorantesi hanno spinto Lincoln per
studiare la possibilità di abolire lo slavery. Nel mese di 
settembre del 1862 Lincoln ha pubblicato una proclamazione preliminare 
di emancipazione. Ha firmato il edict finale il 1 gennaio 1863. 
In questo caricature dalla carbossimetilazione Adalbert Johann 
Volck, Lincoln inebriated di pro-Sud de Baltimora, circondata dai 
simboli di Satanism e delle pitture che honoring le ribellioni 
marroni e slave del John, ha percorso sulla costituzione mentre ha 
disegnato la proclamazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αν και πολλοί βόρειοι, συμπεριλαμβανομένου του 
Abraham Λίνκολν, ήλπισαν αρχικά να διώξουν ποινικώς τον 
πόλεμο χωρίς παρεμπόδιση τη σκλαβιά όπως υπήρξε, πίεση από 
τους σκλάβους που τρεπόμενος σε φυγή στις γραμμές ένωσης, το 
συναίσθημα ρεφορμιστών στο Βορρά, και μια επιδεινωμένος 
στρατιωτική κατάσταση ώθησαν το Λίνκολν για να θεωρήσουν τη 
σκλαβιά. Τον Σεπτέμβριο του 1862 το Λίνκολν εξέδωσε μια 
προκαταρκτική προκήρυξη Χειραφέτησης. Υπέγραψε το τελικό 
διάταγμα την 1η Ιανουαρίου, 1863. Σε αυτήν την 
καρικατούρα από τη Βαλτιμόρη υπέρ-νότια ο δημοκράτης Adalbert
Johann Volck, το Λίνκολν, που περιβλήθηκε από τα σύμβολα 
Satanism και των έργων ζωγραφικής που τιμούν John Brown 
και τις εξεγέρσεις σκλάβων, που προχωρήθηκαν στο σύνταγμα 
δεδομένου ότι σύνταξε την προκήρυξη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Aunque mucho Northerners, incluyendo Abraham Lincoln, 
esperaba inicialmente procesar la guerra sin interferir con esclavitud
mientras que existió, la presión de los esclavos que huyeron a las 
líneas de la unión, el sentimiento del abolitionist en el norte, y 
una situación militar que deterioraba empujaron Lincoln para 
considerar el suprimir de esclavitud. En septiembre de 1862 
Lincoln publicó una proclamación preliminar de la emancipación. 
Él firmó el decreto final 1 de enero de 1863. En 
este caricature del demócrata Adalbert Johann Volck, una Lincoln 
embriagada del favorable-Sur de Baltimore, rodeada por símbolos de 
Satanism y de las pinturas que honraban las rebeliones marrones y 
auxiliares de Juan, pisó en la constitución mientras que él 
bosquejó la proclamación.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087254</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103542</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/writing-the-emancipation-proclamation</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
