<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102987</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102987</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204627</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Picturing" America at the turn of the twentieth century</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Amerika an der Jahrhundertwende zwanzigste ", 
darstellend"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"décrivant" l'Amérique à la fin du vingtième 
siècle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"retratando" América na volta do vigésimo 
século</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"descrivendo" l'America alla fine del ventesimo 
secolo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Απεικονίζοντασ" την Αμερική στο γύρισμα του εικοστού 
αιώνα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"representando" América al final del vigésimo 
siglo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Students link together the literature and the history of the United States at the turn of the twentieth century. Questions guide students as they study visual documents. Students also read the teacher's choice of two widely anthologized short stories and an excerpt from a best-selling novel of the period. Two exercises will raise student awareness of the impact that visual images have on their lives: one that is based on internet advertising and a second that results in a student-produced scrapbook.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kursteilnehmer binden die Literatur und die 
zusammen Geschichte der Vereinigten Staaten an der Jahrhundertwende 
zwanzigste. Fragen Anleitungkursteilnehmer, wie sie 
Sichtdokumente studieren. Kursteilnehmer lasen auch die Wahl des
Lehrers von zwei anthologized weit kurze Geschichten und ein Excerpt 
von einem gut-verkaufenden Roman der Periode. Zwei Übungen 
werfen Kursteilnehmerbewußtsein der Auswirkung auf, die Sichtbilder 
auf ihren Lebensdauern haben: ein das auf dem 
Internet-Bekanntmachen und einer Sekunde dieser Resultate in einem 
Kursteilnehmer-produzierten Scrapbook basiert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les étudiants joignent ensemble la littérature 
et l'histoire des Etats-Unis à la fin du vingtième siècle. 
Étudiants de guide de questions comme ils étudient les 
documents visuels. Les étudiants ont également lu le choix du 
professeur de deux anthologized largement des histoires courtes et un 
extrait d'un roman devente de la période. Deux exercices 
soulèveront la conscience d'étudiant de l'impact que les images 
visuelles ont leurs vies : un qui est basé sur la publicité 
d'Internet et une seconde cette des résultats dans un album 
étudiant-produit.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os estudantes ligam junto a literatura e o history
dos estados unidos na volta do vigésimo século. Estudantes da 
guia das perguntas como estudam originais visuais. Os estudantes
leram também a escolha do professor de dois anthologized extensamente
histórias curtas e um excerpt de uma novela melhor-vendendo do 
período. Dois exercícios levantarão a consciência do 
estudante do impacto que as imagens visuais têm em suas vidas: 
um que é baseado em anunciar do Internet e em um segundo esse 
resultados em um scrapbook estudante-produzido.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli allievi collegano insieme la letteratura e la 
storia del unito Dichiara alla fine del ventesimo secolo. 
Allievi della guida di domande come studiano i documenti visivi.
Gli allievi egualmente hanno letto la scelta dell'insegnante di 
due ampiamente anthologized le storia corte e un brano da un romanzo 
migliore-vendente del periodo. Due esercitazioni solleveranno la
consapevolezza dell'allievo dell'effetto che le immagini visive hanno 
sulle loro vite: uno che è basato sulla pubblicità del 
Internet e su un secondo quel risultati in un album allievo-prodotto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι σπουδαστές συνδέουν τη λογοτεχνία και ιστορία των 
Ηνωμένων Πολιτειών στο γύρισμα του εικοστού αιώνα. Οι 
ερωτήσεις καθοδηγούν τους σπουδαστές δεδομένου ότι μελετούν τα 
οπτικά έγγραφα. Οι σπουδαστές διάβασαν επίσης ότι η 
επιλογή του δασκάλου δύο ευρέως οι σύντομες ιστορίες και ένα 
απόσπασμα από ένα με εμπορική επιτυχία μυθιστόρημα της 
περιόδου. Δύο ασκήσεις θα βελτιώσουν την πληροφόρηση 
σπουδαστών επίδρασης που οι οπτικές εικόνες ασκούν στις ζωές 
τους: ένας που είναι βασισμένος στο διαδίκτυο που 
διαφημίζει και ένα δευτερόλεπτο που οδηγεί σε ένα 
σπουδαστής-παραχθέν λεύκωμα αποκομμάτων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los estudiantes conectan juntas la literatura y la
historia de los Estados Unidos al final del vigésimo siglo. 
Estudiantes de la guía de las preguntas como estudian 
documentos visuales. Los estudiantes también leyeron la opción
del profesor de dos anthologized extensamente historias cortas y un 
extracto de una novela mejor-vendedora del período. Dos 
ejercicios levantarán el conocimiento del estudiante del impacto que 
las imágenes visuales tienen en sus vidas: uno que se basa en 
la publicidad del Internet y un segundo ese los resultados en un libro
de recuerdos estudiante-producido.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:SCOTT CULCLASURE
FN:SCOTT CULCLASURE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204627</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102987</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/picturing-america-at-the-turn-of-the-twentieth-century</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
