<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108351</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108351</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205898</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology of Arts</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie von künsten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie des arts</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia das artes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia delle arti</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία των τεχνών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología de artes</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">invites children of all ages to explore the science of music through movies, questions, and online exhibits. Compose, mix, and play with music in ways you probably haven't before. Find out what makes sad music sad, why some songs get stuck in your head, and how opera singers are able to sing notes that seem to last forever.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">lädt Kinder alles Alters ein, die Wissenschaft 
von Musik durch Filme, Fragen und Onlineausstellungen zu erforschen. 
Bestehen Sie, mischen Sie und Spiel mit Musik in den Methoden, 
die Sie vermutlich nicht vorher haben. Finden Sie heraus, was 
traurige Musik traurig bildet, warum einige Liede in Ihrem Kopf 
gehaftet erhalten und wie Oper Sänger können, Anmerkungen zu singen,
die Letztem für immer scheinen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">invite des enfants de tous les âges à explorer 
la science de la musique par des films, des questions, et des objets 
exposés en ligne. Composez, mélangez, et jeu à la musique des
voies que vous n'avez pas probablement avant. Découvrez ce qui 
rend la musique triste triste, pourquoi quelques chansons se coincent 
dans votre tête, et comment des chanteurs d'opéra peuvent chanter 
les notes qui semblent au bout pour toujours.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">convida crianças de todas as idades explorar a 
ciência da música através dos filmes, das perguntas, e das 
exibições em linha. Componha, misture, e jogo com a música 
nas maneiras que você não tem provavelmente antes. Encontre 
para fora o que fazem a música sad sad, porque algumas canções 
começam furado em sua cabeça, e como singers da ópera pode  cantar 
as notas que parecem ao último para sempre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">invita i bambini di tutte le età ad esplorare la 
scienza di musica attraverso i film, le domande e le 
esposizioni in linea. Componga, mescoli e gioco con musica nei 
modi che probabilmente non avete prima. Scopra che cosa rende la
musica triste triste, perchè alcune canzoni rimangono incastrato in 
vostra testa e come cantanti di opera può cantare le note che 
sembrano per sempre all'ultimo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">προσκαλεί τα παιδιά όλων των ηλικιών για να ερευνήσει
την επιστήμη της μουσικής μέσω των κινηματογράφων, των ερωτήσεων,
και των σε απευθείας σύνδεση εκθεμάτων. Συνθέστε, αναμίξτε,
και παίξτε με τη μουσική στους τρόπους που δεν έχετε πιθανώς 
πριν. Ανακαλύψτε τι καθιστά τη λυπημένη μουσική λυπημένη, 
γιατί μερικά τραγούδια παίρνουν κολλημένα στο κεφάλι σας, και 
πώς οι τραγουδιστές οπερών είναι σε θέση να τραγουδήσουν τις 
σημειώσεις που φαίνονται να διαρκούν για πάντα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">invita a niños de todas las edades que exploren 
la ciencia de la música a través de películas, de preguntas, y de 
objetos expuestos en línea. Componga, mézclese, y juego con 
música de maneras que usted no tiene probablemente antes. 
Descubra qué hace música triste triste, porqué algunas 
canciones consiguen pegado en su cabeza, y cómo los cantantes de la 
ópera puede cantar las notas que se parecen al último por siempre.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205898</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108351</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/science-and-technology-of-arts</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
