<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107117</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107117</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086415</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Looking a Gift Horse in the Mouth: Workers Protest Carnegie Library</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Schauen eines Geschenk-Pferds in der Öffnung: 
Arbeiter-Protestcarnegie Bibliothek</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Regarder un cheval de cadeau dans la bouche : 
Bibliothèque de Carnegie de Protestation d'Ouvriers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Olhando um cavalo do presente na boca: 
Biblioteca De Carnegie Do Protesto Dos Trabalhadores</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Osservare un cavallo del regalo nella bocca: 
Libreria Di Carnegie Di Protesta Degli Operai</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα άλογο δώρων στο στόμα: Οι εργαζόμενοι 
διαμαρτύρονται τη βιβλιοθήκη Carnegie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mirar un caballo del regalo en la boca: 
Biblioteca De Carnegie De la Protesta De los Trabajadores</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In his essay "Wealth," published in the  North American Review  in 1889, industrialist Andrew Carnegie argued that individual capitalists were bound by duty to play a broader cultural and social role and thus improve the world. (The essay later became famous under the title "The Gospel of Wealth.") But not everyone agreed with Carnegie's perspective. As shown by this newspaper article from 1901, the philanthropic gestures of such captains of industry as Andrew Carnegie were not always greeted with enthusiasm by the workers whose low-paid toil effectively underwrote such extravagant "gifts."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In seinem Versuch "Fülle," veröffentlichte in 
der nordamerikanischen Zusammenfassung 1889, argumentierte 
Industrieller Andrew Carnegie, daß einzelne Kapitalisten durch 
Aufgabe gesprungen wurden, um eine ausgedehntere kulturelle und 
Sozialrolle zu spielen und die Welt folglich zu verbessern. (der
Versuch wurde später unter dem Namen "das Evangelium von Fülle." 
berühmt) Aber nicht jeder stimmte mit Perspektive Carnegies 
überein. Wie durch diesen Zeitungsartikel von 1901, wurden die 
menschenfreundlichen Gesten solcher Kapitäne der Industrie wie Andrew
Carnegie gezeigt nicht immer mit Begeisterung von den Arbeitern 
gegrüßt deren niedrig-zahlende Mühe unterschrieb effektiv 
solche extravagant "Geschenke."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans son essai "richesse," a édité dans la revue
américaine du nord en 1889, l'industriel Andrew Carnegie a argué
du fait que différents capitalistes ont été liés par le devoir 
pour jouer un plus large rôle culturel et social et pour améliorer 
ainsi le monde. (l'essai plus tard est devenu célèbre sous le 
titre "l'evangile de la richesse.") Mais pas chacun était 
conforme à la perspective de Carnegie's. Comme montré par cet 
article de journal de 1901, les gestes philanthropiques de tels 
capitaines d'industrie comme Andrew Carnegie n'ont pas été toujours 
salués avec enthousiasme par les ouvriers dont le travail dur 
sous-payé a pertinemment garanti de tels "cadeaux exagérés."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em seu essay "riqueza," publicou na revisão 
norte-americana em 1889, o industrialista Andrew Carnegie discutiu que
os capitalistas individuais estiveram limitados pelo dever para jogar 
um papel cultural e social mais largo e para melhorar assim o mundo. 
(o essay se tornou mais tarde famoso sob o título "o gospel da 
riqueza.") Mas não todos concordou com o perspective de 
Carnegie. Como mostrado por este artigo de jornal de 1901, os 
gestos philanthropic de tais capitães da indústria como Andrew 
Carnegie não foram cumprimentados sempre com entusiasmo pelos 
trabalhadores cuja a labuta baixo-paga subscreveu eficazmente tais 
"presentes extravagant."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nel suo saggio "ricchezza," ha pubblicato nella 
revisione nordamericana in 1889, l'industriale Andrew Carnegie ha 
sostenuto che i diversi capitalisti sono stati limitati tramite il 
dovere per svolgere un più vasto ruolo culturale e sociale e per 
migliorare così il mondo. (il saggio più successivamente è 
diventato famoso sotto il titolo "il gospel di ricchezza.") Ma 
non tutto ha accosentito con la prospettiva del Carnegie. 
Come indicato da questo articolo di stampa da 1901, i gestures 
filantropici di tali capitani di industria come Andrew Carnegie non 
greeted sempre con entusiasmo dagli operai di cui il lavoro 
basso-low-paid ha sottoscritto efficacemente tali "regali esagerati."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στο δοκίμιό του "πλούτος," δημοσιευμένος στη 
βορειοαμερικανική αναθεώρηση το 1889, ο βιομήχανος Andrew 
Carnegie υποστήριξε ότι οι μεμονωμένοι κεφαλαιοκράτες 
δεσμεύθηκαν από το καθήκον να διαδραματιστεί ένας ευρύτερος 
πολιτιστικός και κοινωνικός ρόλος και να βελτιωθεί έτσι ο 
κόσμος. (Το δοκίμιο έγινε αργότερα διάσημο υπό τον τίτλο 
"το Ευαγγέλιο του πλούτου.") Αλλά όχι ο καθένας συμφώνησε 
με την προοπτική Carnegie. Όπως εμφανίζεται από αυτό το 
άρθρο εφημερίδων από το 1901, οι φιλανθρωπικές χειρονομίες 
τέτοιων καπετάνιων της βιομηχανίας όπως ο Andrew Carnegie 
χαιρετήθηκε όχι πάντα με τον ενθουσιασμό από τους εργαζομένους ο
των οποίων χαμηλόμισθος κόπος ασφάλισε αποτελεσματικά τέτοια 
υπερβολικά "δώρα."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En su ensayo "abundancia," publicó en la 
revisión norteamericana en 1889, el industrial Andrew Carnegie 
discutió que los capitalistas individuales fueran limitados por deber
para desempeñar un papel cultural y social más amplio y para mejorar
así el mundo. (el ensayo llegó a ser más adelante famoso bajo
título "el Evangelio de la abundancia.") Pero no cada uno 
convino con la perspectiva de Carnegie. Según lo mostrado por 
este artículo periodístico a partir de 1901, los gestos 
filantrópicos de tales capitanes de la industria como Andrew Carnegie
no fueron saludados siempre con entusiasmo por los trabajadores que 
trabajo bajo-pagado subscribió con eficacia tales "regalos 
extravagantes."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086415</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107117</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/looking-a-gift-horse-in-the-mouth-workers-protest-carnegie-library</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
