<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103759</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103759</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086213</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Hard, Dirty Work Should Be Paid For": A Laundry Worker Argues for a Minimum Wage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Stark, Sollte Schmutzige Arbeit Für Zahlend 
Sein": Ein Wäscherei-Arbeiter argumentiert für einen minimalen
Lohn</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Dur, Le Travail Modifié Devrait Être Payé 
Pour" : Un ouvrier de blanchisserie plaide pour un salaire 
minimum</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Duramente, O Trabalho Sujo Deve Ser Pago Para": 
Um trabalhador da lavanderia discute para um salário mínimo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Duro, Il Lavoro Sporco Dovrebbe Essere Paid Per":
Un operaio della lavanderia parla a favore di uno stipendio 
minimo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η "σκληρή, βρώμικη εργασία πρέπει να πληρωθεί": 
Ένας εργαζόμενος πλυντηρίων υποστηρίζει έναν βασικό μισθό</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Difícilmente, El Trabajo Sucio Debe Ser Pagado 
Para": Un trabajador del lavadero discute para un salario 
mínimo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Fair Labor Standards Act, signed into law on June 25, 1938, as the last major piece of New Deal legislation, outlawed child labor and guaranteed covered workers a minimum wage of 40 cents an hour and a maximum 40-hour work week. Although more than 22 million workers benefited, conservative forces in Congress saw to it that the Act exempted many others--including agricultural workers, public employees, and domestic workers--from its provisions. The landmark law, nevertheless, helped establish a precedent for the Federal regulation of work conditions. In the following testimony to a Senate subcommittee, Ruth Green, a worker in an interstate company serving business laundry needs, argued that despite efforts by her union to raise wages, a federal law mandating a minimum wage of at least 75 cents an hour was needed to insure adequate wages during hard times. In addition, she maintained that competition from non-unionized laundries made it difficult for the union to obtain "decent contracts." On October 26, 1949, President Harry S. Truman signed into law the Fair Labor Standards Amendments of 1949, which established the new minimum at 75 cents an hour. Some groups, however, remained excluded from the Act"s protection.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die angemessenen Richtlinien für angemessene 
Arbeitsbedingungen fungieren, unterzeichnet in Gesetz an Juni 25, 
1938, als das letzte Hauptstück von Gesetzgebung des neuen Abkommens,
von geächteter Kinderarbeit und von garantierten bedeckten Arbeitern 
ein minimaler Lohn von 40 Cents ein Stunde und eine Woche Arbeit des 
Maximums 40-hour. Obgleich mehr als 22 Million geförderte 
Arbeiter, konservative Kräfte im Kongreß es achteten, daß die Tat 
viele andere -- einschließlich landwirtschaftliche Arbeiter, 
allgemeine Angestellte und inländische Arbeiter -- von seinen 
Bestimmungen befreite. Das Grenzsteingesetz dennoch geholfen, 
einen Präzedenzfall für die Bundesverordnung der Arbeit herzustellen
bedingt. Im folgenden Zeugnis zu einer Senatunterausschuß, war 
Ruth Grün, ein Arbeiter Notwendigkeiten einer in den 
zwischenstaatlichen Firmaumhüllunggeschäft Wäscherei, argumentiert 
dem trotz der Bemühungen durch ihren Anschluß, Löhne anzuheben, ein
Bundesgesetz eines minimalen Lohnes von mindestens 75 Cents ein Stunde
Mandat unterstellendes erforderlich, ausreichende Löhne während der 
harten Zeiten zu versichern. Zusätzlich behielt sie bei, daß 
Konkurrenz von die Wäschereien non-unionized, die es schwierig 
gebildet wurden, damit der Anschluß erreicht "annehmbare Verträge." 
An Oktober 26, 1949, Präsident Harry S. Truman unterzeichnete 
in Gesetz die angemessenen Richtlinie- für angemessene 
Arbeitsbedingungenänderungen von 1949, die das neue Minimum bei 75 
Cents ein Stunde herstellten. Einige Gruppen blieben jedoch vom 
Act"s Schutz ausgeschlossen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les normes de travail justes agissent, signé dans
la loi 25 juin 1938, comme dernier morceau principal de législation 
de nouvelle affaire, de travail des enfants proscrit et d'ouvriers 
couverts garantis un salaire minimum de 40 cents par heure et une 
semaine de travail du maximum 40-hour. Bien que plus de 22 
millions d'ouvriers bénéficiés, les forces conservatrices dans le 
congrès aient assuré la Loi a exempté beaucoup d'autres -- 
comprenant les ouvriers agricoles, les employés publics, et les 
ouvriers domestiques -- de ses dispositions. La loi de borne 
limite, néanmoins, aidée à établir un précédent pour le 
règlement fédéral du travail conditionne. Dans le témoignage
suivant à un sous-comité de sénat, le vert de Ruth, un 
ouvrier dans les besoins d'un état à un autre d'une blanchisserie 
d'affaires de portion de compagnie, discutés cela en dépit des 
efforts par son union d'augmenter des salaires, une loi fédérale 
exigeant un salaire minimum au moins de 75 cents par heure était 
nécessaire pour assurer les salaires adéquats pendant des périodes 
difficiles. En outre, elle a mis à jour que la concurrence des 
blanchisseries de non-syndiquer l'a rendu difficile pour que l'union 
obtienne "les contrats décents." 26 octobre 1949, le 
Président Harry S. Truman a signé dans la loi les amendements justes
de normes de travail de 1949, qui ont établi le nouveau minimum à 75
cents par heure. Quelques groupes, cependant, sont demeurés 
exclus de la protection d'Act"s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os padrões labor justos agem, assinado na lei 
junho em 25, 1938, como a última parte principal de legislação do 
negócio novo, de trabalho de criança outlawed e de trabalhadores 
cobertos garantidos um salário mínimo de 40 centavos um a hora e uma
semana do trabalho do máximo 40-hour. Embora mais de 22 milhão
trabalhadores beneficiados, forças conservadoras no congress lhe 
vissem que o ato exempted muito outro -- including trabalhadores 
agriculturais, empregados públicos, e trabalhadores domésticos -- de
suas provisões. A lei do marco, não obstante, ajudada 
estabelecer um precedent para o regulamento federal do trabalho 
condiciona. No seguinte testimony a uma subcomissão do senate, 
o verde de Ruth, um trabalhador nas necessidades interstate de uma 
lavanderia do negócio do serving da companhia, discutidas isso apesar
dos esforços por sua união levantar salários, uma lei federal 
exijindo um salário mínimo ao menos de 75 centavos um a hora era 
needed segurar salários adequados durante épocas duras. Além,
manteve que a competição de non-unionized as lavanderias feitas lhe 
difícil para que a união obtenha "contratos decent." Outubro 
em 26, 1949, presidente Harry S. Truman assinou na lei as emendas 
justas dos padrões labor de 1949, que estabeleceram o mínimo novo em
75 centavos um a hora. Alguns grupos, entretanto, remanesceram 
excluídos da proteção de Act"s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli standard Di lavoro giusti si comportano, 
firmato in legge il 25 giugno 1938, come l'ultima parte principale di 
legislazione di nuovo affare, del lavoro proscritto del bambino e
degli operai coperti garantiti uno stipendio minimo di 40 centesimi un
l'ora e una settimana del lavoro di massimo 40-hour. Anche se 
più di 22 milione operai avvantaggiati, forze conservatrici nel 
congresso si sono assicurati che la Legge esenti molti altre -- 
compreso gli operai agricoli, gli impiegati pubblici e gli operai 
domestici -- dalle relative disposizioni. La legge del limite, 
tuttavia, contribuita a stabilire un precedente per la regolazione 
federale di lavoro condiziona. Nella seguente testimonianza ad 
un sottocomitato del senato, il verde di Ruth, un operaio nei bisogni 
da uno stato all'altro dell'azienda del serving della lavanderia di 
affari, discussi quello malgrado gli sforzi dalla sua unione sollevare
gli stipendi, una legge federale affidante uno stipendio in mandato 
minimo almeno di 75 centesimi un l'ora era necessario assicurare gli 
stipendi sufficienti durante i periodi duri. In più, ha 
effettuato che la concorrenza da non-unionized le lavanderie rese esso
difficile affinchè l'unione ottenesse "i contratti decent." Il 
26 ottobre 1949, il presidente Harry S. Truman ha firmato in legge le 
correzioni Di lavoro giuste di standard di 1949, che hanno stabilito 
il nuovo minimo a 75 centesimi un l'ora. Alcuni gruppi, 
tuttavia, sono rimasto esclusi dalla protezione di Act"s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο δίκαιος νόμος προτύπων εργασίας, που υπογράφηκε στο
νόμο σχετικά με στις 25 Ιουνίου ..1938, ως τελευταίο 
σημαντικό κομμάτι της νέας νομοθεσίας διαπραγμάτευσης, πρόγραψε 
την παιδική εργασία και εγγυήθηκε στους καλυμμένους εργαζομένους 
έναν βασικό μισθό 40 σεντ μια ώρα και μια μέγιστη εβδομάδα 
εργασίας 40-ώρας. Αν και περισσότεροι από 22 εκατομμύριο
εργαζόμενοι ωφελήθηκαν, οι συντηρητικές δυνάμεις στο συνέδριο 
εβλέίδαν σε το ότι ο νόμος απάλλαξε πολλοί άλλοι -- 
συμπεριλαμβανομένων των γεωργικών εργαζομένων, των δημόσιων 
υπαλλήλων, και των εσωτερικών εργαζομένων -- από τις παροχές του.
Ο νόμος ορόσημων, εντούτοις, που ενισχύεται να καθιερώσει 
ένα προηγούμενο για τον ομοσπονδιακό κανονισμό των όρων 
εργασίας. Στην ακόλουθη κατάθεση σε μια υποεπιτροπή 
Συγκλήτου, η Ruth Green, ένας εργαζόμενος ανάγκες στις 
διακρατικές επιχείρησης εξυπηρετώντας επιχειρησιακών πλυντηρίων, 
υποστήριξε ότι παρά τις προσπάθειες από την ένωσή της να 
αυξηθούν οι αμοιβές, ένας ομοσπονδιακός νόμος που εξουσιοδοτεί 
έναν βασικό μισθό τουλάχιστον 75 σεντ μια ώρα απαιτήθηκε για 
να ασφαλίσει τις επαρκείς αμοιβές κατά τη διάρκεια των σκληρών 
χρόνων. Επιπλέον, υποστήριξε ότι ο ανταγωνισμός από τα 
μη-συνδικαλιστικά πλυντήρια το κατέστησε δύσκολο για την ένωση να
συναφθούν οι "κόσμιες συμβάσεις." Στις 26 Οκτωβρίου 
..1949, ο Πρόεδρος Harry S. Truman υπέγραψε στο νόμο 
τις δίκαιες τροποποιήσεις προτύπων εργασίας του 1949, οι 
οποίες καθιέρωσαν το νέο ελάχιστο σε 75 σεντ μια ώρα. 
Μερικές ομάδες, εντούτοις, παρέμειναν αποκλεισμένες από 
την προστασία Act"s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los estándares de trabajo justos actúan, firmado
en ley 25 de junio de 1938, como el pedazo principal pasado de 
legislación del nuevo reparto, de trabajo de niño proscrito y de 
trabajadores cubiertos garantizados un salario mínimo de 40 centavos 
por hora y una semana del trabajo del máximo 40-hour. Aunque 
más de 22 millones de trabajadores beneficiados, las fuerzas 
conservadoras en congreso vieron a él que el acto eximió muchos 
otros -- incluyendo trabajadores agrícolas, empleados públicos, y 
trabajadores domésticos -- de sus provisiones. La ley de la 
señal, sin embargo, ayudada a establecer un precedente para la 
regulación federal del trabajo condiciona. En el testimonio 
siguiente a un subcomité del senado, el verde de Ruth, trabajador en 
las necesidades de un estado a otro de la compañía de la porción de
un lavadero del negocio, discutidas eso a pesar de esfuerzos por su 
unión de levantar salarios, una ley federal asignando un salario por 
mandato mínimo por lo menos de 75 centavos por hora era necesario 
asegurar salarios adecuados durante épocas duras. Además, ella
mantuvo que la competición de non-unionized los lavaderos hechos le 
difícil para que la unión obtenga "contratos decentes." De 
octubre el 26 de 1949, presidente Harry S. Truman firmó en ley las 
enmiendas justas de los estándares de trabajo de 1949, que 
establecieron el nuevo mínimo en 75 centavos por hora. Algunos 
grupos, sin embargo, seguían excluidos de la protección de Act"s.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086213</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103759</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/hard-dirty-work-should-be-paid-for-a-laundry-worker-argues-for-a-minimum-wage</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
