<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105161</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105161</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207252</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Working in Paterson: Occupational Heritage in an Urban Setting</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Arbeiten in Paterson: Berufliches Erbe in 
einer städtischen Einstellung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Travailler dans Paterson : Héritage 
professionnel dans une configuration urbaine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Trabalhar em Paterson: Heritage ocupacional 
em um ajuste urbano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Funzionando in Paterson: Eredità 
professionale in una regolazione urbana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εργασία σε Paterson: Επαγγελματική κληρονομιά 
σε μια αστική τιμή τών παραμέτρων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Trabajo en Paterson: Herencia ocupacional en
una configuración urbana</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">presents 3882 photos and 470 interview excerpts from a 1994 study of occupational culture in the cradle of the Industrial Revolution in the U.S. Founded in 1791, Paterson, New Jersey, became a leading manufacturer of silk, railroad locomotives, firearms, and other products. Learn how its industrial heritage is reflected in Paterson today. Explore business life along one street. Hear interviews with retired workers.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geschenke 3882 Fotos und 470 Interviewexcerpts von
einer Studie 1994 der beruflichen Kultur in der Aufnahmevorrichtung 
der industriellen Revolution in den VEREINIGTEN STAATEN, die 1791, 
Paterson, Neu-Jersey gegründet wurden, wurden ein führender 
Hersteller der Seide, der Eisenbahnlokomotiven, der Feuerwaffen und 
anderer Produkte. Erlernen Sie, wie sein industrielles Erbe in 
Paterson heute reflektiert wird. Erforschen Sie das Geschäft 
Leben entlang einer Straße. Hören Sie Interviews mit 
pensionierten Arbeitern.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les présents 3882 photos et 470 extraits 
d'entrevue d'une étude 1994 de culture professionnelle dans le 
berceau de la révolution industrielle aux ETATS-UNIS fondés en 1791,
Paterson, New Jersey, sont devenus un principal constructeur de soie, 
de locomotives de chemin de fer, d'armes à feu, et d'autres produits.
Apprenez comment son héritage industriel est reflété dans 
Paterson aujourd'hui. Explorez la vie d'affaires le long d'une 
rue. Entendez les entrevues avec les ouvriers retraités.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">os presentes 3882 fotos e 470 excerpts da 
entrevista de um estudo 1994 da cultura ocupacional no berço da volta
industrial nos ESTADOS UNIDOS fundados em 1791, Paterson, Novo-Jersey,
transformaram-se um fabricante principal da seda, das locomotivas da 
estrada de ferro, dos firearms, e dos outros produtos. Aprenda 
como seu heritage industrial é refletido em Paterson hoje. 
Explore a vida de negócio ao longo de uma rua. Ouça 
entrevistas com trabalhadores aposentados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">i presenti 3882 foto e 470 brani di intervista da 
uno studio 1994 su coltura professionale nella culla della rivoluzione
industriale negli STATI UNITI fondati in 1791, Paterson, Nuovo-Jersey,
si sono transformati in in un fornitore principale di seta, di 
locomotive della ferrovia, di firearms e di altri prodotti. 
Impari come la relativa eredità industriale è riflessa oggi in
Paterson. Esplori la vita di affari lungo una via. Senta 
le interviste con gli operai pensionati.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρουσιάζει 3882 φωτογραφίες και 470 αποσπάσματα 
συνέντευξης από μια μελέτη του 1994 του επαγγελματικού 
πολιτισμού στο λίκνο της βιομηχανικής επανάστασης στις ΗΠΑ που 
ιδρύθηκαν το 1791, Paterson, Νιου Τζέρσεϋ, έγιναν κύριος 
κατασκευαστής του μεταξιού, των ατμομηχανών σιδηροδρόμου, των 
πυροβόλων, και άλλων προϊόντων. Μάθετε πώς η βιομηχανική 
κληρονομιά της απεικονίζεται σε Paterson σήμερα. 
Ερευνήστε την επιχειρησιακή ζωή κατά μήκος μιας οδού. 
Ακούστε τις συνεντεύξεις με τους συνταξιούχους εργαζομένους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">los presentes 3882 fotos y 470 extractos de la 
entrevista de un estudio 1994 de la cultura ocupacional en la 
horquilla de la revolución industrial en los ESTADOS UNIDOS fundados 
en 1791, Paterson, Nuevo-Jersey, se convirtieron en fabricante 
principal de la seda, de las locomotoras del ferrocarril, de los armas
de fuego, y de otros productos. Aprenda cómo su herencia 
industrial se refleja en Paterson hoy. Explore la vida de 
negocio a lo largo de una calle. Oiga las entrevistas con los 
trabajadores jubilados.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207252</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105161</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/working-in-paterson-occupational-heritage-in-an-urban-setting</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
