<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108272</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108272</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211972</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Road Maps: a guide to learning system dynamics</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Straßenkarten: eine Anleitung zu 
erlernensystem Dynamik</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cartes de Route : un guide de dynamique 
d'étude de système</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Mapas De Estrada: uma guia à dinâmica de 
aprendizagem do sistema</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Programmi Di Strada: una guida al dynamics 
imparante del sistema</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οδικοί χάρτες: ένας οδηγός για τη δυναμική 
συστημάτων εκμάθησης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Correspondencias De Camino: una guía a la 
dinámica del sistema que aprende</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">MIT System Dynamics Education Project developed Road Maps, a series of self-guides, modeling and selected literature to help students and teachers learn the principles of system dynamics. This site is part of that project, and provides listings of articles and other webpages containing discussion of Road Maps publications. Road Maps are a series of self-guides that use modeling exercises and selected literature to provide a resource for learning about the principles and practices of system dynamics.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">MIT System Dynamik-Ausbildung Projekt entwickelte 
Straßenkarten, eine Reihe Selbst-Anleitungen, Formung und 
ausgewählte Literatur, Kursteilnehmern und Lehrern zu helfen, die 
Grundregeln der System Dynamik zu erlernen. Diese Site ist ein 
Teil dieses Projektes und liefert Listen der Artikel und anderer 
Webseiten, die Diskussion über Straßenkartepublikationen enthalten. 
Straßenkarten sind Reihen Selbst-Anleitungen, die die Formung 
von von Übungen und von von ausgewählter Literatur verwenden, um ein
Hilfsmittel für das Lernen über die Grundregeln und die Praxis der 
System Dynamik zur Verfügung zu stellen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cartes de route développées par projet 
d'éducation de dynamique de système de MIT, des séries de 
art de l'auto-portrait-guides, modeler et littérature choisie d'aider des 
étudiants et des professeurs à apprendre les principes de la 
dynamique de système. Ce site fait partie de ce projet, et 
fournit des listes des articles et d'autres pages Web contenant la 
discussion des publications de cartes de route. Les cartes de 
route sont des séries de art de l'auto-portrait-guides qui utilisent modeler les 
exercices et la littérature choisie pour fournir une ressource pour 
se renseigner sur les principes et les pratiques de la dynamique de 
système.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Mapas de estrada desenvolvidos projeto da 
instrução da dinâmica do sistema do MIT, uma série das self-guias,
modelar e literatura selecionada ajudar a estudantes e a professores 
aprender os princípios da dinâmica do sistema. Este local é 
parte desse projeto, e fornece listas dos artigos e dos outros Web 
pages que contêm a discussão de publicações dos mapas de estrada. 
Os mapas de estrada são umas séries das self-guias que usam 
modelar exercícios e a literatura selecionada para fornecer um 
recurso para aprender sobre os princípios e as práticas da dinâmica
do sistema.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Mappe sviluppate progetto della strada di 
formazione di dynamics del sistema del MIT, una serie di auto-guide, 
modello e letteratura selezionata aiutare gli allievi e gli insegnanti
ad imparare i principii dei dynamics del sistema. Questo luogo 
fa parte di quel progetto e fornisce gli elenchi degli articoli e di 
altri Web pagi che contengono la discussione sulle pubblicazioni dei 
programmi di strada. I programmi di strada sono una serie di 
auto-guide che usano la modellistica le esercitazioni e della 
letteratura selezionata per fornire una risorsa per imparare circa i 
principii e le pratiche dei dynamics del sistema.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το πρόγραμμα εκπαίδευσης δυναμικής συστημάτων MIT 
ανέπτυξε τους οδικούς χάρτες, μια σειρά μόνος-οδηγών, που 
διαμορφώνει και επέλεξε τη λογοτεχνία για να βοηθήσει τους 
σπουδαστές και τους δασκάλους να μάθουν τις αρχές της δυναμικής 
συστημάτων. Αυτή η περιοχή είναι μέρος εκείνου του 
προγράμματος, και παρέχει τις λίστες των άρθρων και άλλα 
webpages που περιέχουν τη συζήτηση του δρόμου χαρτογραφούν τις 
δημοσιεύσεις. Οι οδικοί χάρτες είναι μια σειρά 
μόνος-οδηγών που χρησιμοποιούν τις ασκήσεις διαμόρφωσης και την 
επιλεγμένη λογοτεχνία για να παρέχουν ένα στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς 
για την εκμάθηση για τις αρχές και τις πρακτικές της δυναμικής 
συστημάτων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Correspondencias de camino desarrolladas proyecto 
de la educación de la dinámica del sistema del MIT, una serie de uno
mismo-gui'as, el modelar y literatura seleccionada de ayudar a 
estudiantes y a profesores a aprender los principios de las dinámicas
del sistema. Este sitio es parte de ese proyecto, y proporciona 
a listados de los artículos y de otros Web pages que contienen la 
discusión de las publicaciones de las correspondencias de camino. 
Las correspondencias de camino son series de uno mismo-gui'as 
que utilicen modelar ejercicios y la literatura seleccionada para 
proporcionar a un recurso para aprender sobre los principios y las 
prácticas de las dinámicas del sistema.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211972</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108272</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/road-maps-a-guide-to-learning-system-dynamics</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
