<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106552</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106552</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087370</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"All That Is Passed Away": A Young Indian Praises U.S. Government Policy in the Late 19th century</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Alles, Das Weg" Geführt Wird: Ein junger 
Inder preist VEREINIGTE STAATEN Regierung Politik im des späten 19. 
jahrhunderts Jahrhundert</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Tout Ce qui Est passé Loin" : Un jeune 
Indien félicite la politique de gouvernement des ETATS-UNIS vers la 
fin du 19ème siècle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Tudo Que É passado Afastado": Um indian 
novo elogia a política do governo de ESTADOS UNIDOS no 1ø século 
atrasado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Tutto Che Sia passato Via": Un indiano 
giovane elogia la politica di governo degli STATI UNITI verso la fine 
del diciannovesimo secolo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Όλα αυτά περνούν μακριά": Ένας νέος Ινδός 
εγκωμιάζει την πολιτική ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ κυβέρνησης προς το τέλος του 
19$ου αιώνα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Todo Que Se pasa Lejos": Un indio joven 
elogia la política del gobierno de ESTADOS UNIDOS en la a fines del 
siglo XIX</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Federal officials and reformers regarded education as the linchpin in the government's efforts to Americanize and assimilate Native Americans, which became the dominant federal policy starting in 1887. They placed the greatest stock in off-reservation boarding schools, because they removed Indian youths from their home environment and culture. The U.S. Training and Industrial School founded in 1879 at Carlisle Barracks, Pennsylvania, was the model for most of these schools. Ellis B. Childers, a Creek Indian student at Carlisle, wrote approvingly in his school newspaper about the visit of a large delegation of educated Indians to the school in 1882.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bundesbeamte und Reformer betrachtete 
Ausbildung als der Vorstrecker in den Bemühungen der Regierung, 
gebürtige Amerikaner zu amerikanisieren und anzupassen, die die 
dominierende Bundespolitik wurden, die 1887 beginnt. Sie legten 
den größten Vorrat in Wegreservierung Internate, weil sie indische 
Jugend von ihrer familiären Umgebung und von Kultur löschten. 
Das VEREINIGTE STAATEN Training und die Gewerbeschule, die 1879 
an den Carlisle Kasernen, Pennsylvania gegründet wurden, waren das 
Modell für die meisten diesen Schulen. Ellis B. Childers, ein 
indischer Kursteilnehmer des Nebenflusses in Carlisle, schrieb 
anerkennend in seine Schulezeitung über den Besuch einer großen 
Delegation der gebildeten Inder zur Schule 1882.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Fonctionnaires fédéraux et éducation 
considérée par réformateurs comme clavette d'essieu dans les efforts
du gouvernement d'américaniser et assimiler les Américains 
indigènes, qui sont devenus la politique fédérale dominante 
commençant en 1887. Ils ont placé les plus grandes actions 
dans les internats de hors fonction-réservation, parce qu'ils ont 
retiré les jeunesses indiennes de leur environnement familial et 
culture. La formation des ETATS-UNIS et l'école industrielle 
fondées en 1879 aux casernes de Carlisle, Pennsylvanie, étaient le 
modèle pour la plupart de ces écoles. Ellis B. Childers, un 
étudiant indien de crique à Carlisle, a écrit avec approbation en 
son journal d'école au sujet de la visite d'une grande délégation 
des Indiens instruits à l'école en 1882.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Oficiais federais e instrução considerada 
reformers como o linchpin nos esforços do governo americanize e 
assimilate os americanos nativos, que se transformaram a política 
federal dominante que começa em 1887. Colocaram o estoque o 
mais grande em escolas boarding do fora-off-reservation, porque 
removeram as juventudes indian de seus ambiente home e cultura. 
O treinamento de ESTADOS UNIDOS e a escola industrial fundados 
em 1879 em barracks de Carlisle, Pensilvânia, eram o modelo para a 
maioria destas escolas. Ellis B. Childers, um estudante indian 
do creek em Carlisle, escreveu approvingly em seu jornal da escola 
sobre a visita de um delegation grande de indians educados à escola 
em 1882.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Funzionari federali e formazione considerata 
reformers come la chiave di volta negli sforzi del governo americanize
ed assimilare gli Americani natali, che si sono transformati in nella 
politica federale dominante che comincia in 1887. Hanno disposto
le azione più grandi nei collegi di fuori-prenotazione, perché hanno
rimosso le gioventù indiane dal loro ambiente familiare e coltura. 
L'addestramento degli STATI UNITI e la scuola industriale 
fondati in 1879 ai barracks de Carlisle, Pensilvania, erano il modello
per la maggior parte di queste scuole. Ellis B. Childers, un 
allievo indiano dell'insenatura a Carlisle, ha scritto approvingly in 
suo giornale della scuola circa la chiamata di grande delegazione 
degli indiani istruiti alla scuola in 1882.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι ομοσπονδιακοί ανώτεροι υπάλληλοι και οι 
μεταρρυθμιστές θεώρησαν την εκπαίδευση ως περόνη τροχού στις 
κυβερνητικές προσπάθειες σε Americanize και αφομοιώνουν 
εγγενείς Αμερικανούς, το οποίο έγινε η κυρίαρχη ομοσπονδιακή 
πολιτική που αρχίζει το 1887. Τοποθέτησαν το μέγιστο 
απόθεμα στα σχολεία τροφής από-επιφύλαξης, επειδή αφαίρεσαν τις
ινδικές νεολαίες από το οικογενειακό περιβάλλον και τον 
πολιτισμό τους. Η ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ κατάρτιση και το βιομηχανικό 
σχολείο που ιδρύθηκαν το 1879 στις αποδοκιμασίες της Καρλάιλ, 
Πενσυλβανία, ήταν το μοντέλο για τα περισσότερα από αυτά τα 
σχολεία. Ellis Β. Childers, ένας ινδικός σπουδαστής 
κολπίσκου στην Καρλάιλ, έγραψε επιδοκιμαστικά στη σχολική 
εφημερίδα του για την επίσκεψη μιας μεγάλης αντιπροσωπείας 
μορφωμένων Ινδών στο σχολείο το 1882.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Funcionarios federales y educación mirada 
reformadores como la pezonera en los esfuerzos del gobierno de 
americanize y de asimilar a los americanos nativos, que hicieron la 
política federal dominante que comenzaba en 1887. Colocaron la 
acción más grande en colegios de internos de la 
apagado-reservacio'n, porque quitaron juventudes indias de su ambiente
familiar y cultura. El entrenamiento de ESTADOS UNIDOS y la 
escuela industrial fundados en 1879 en los cuarteles de Carlisle, 
Pennsylvania, eran el modelo para la mayoría de estas escuelas. 
Ellis B. Childers, estudiante indio del cala en Carlisle, 
escribió approvingly en su periódico de la escuela sobre la visita 
de una delegación grande de indios educados a la escuela en 1882.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087370</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106552</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/all-that-is-passed-away-a-young-indian-praises-u-s-government-policy-in-the-late-19th-century</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
