<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108211</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108211</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086918</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Collapse of the Only Thing in the Garvey Movement Which Was Original or Promising": Du Bois on Garvey</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"der Einsturz der einzigen Sache in der Garvey 
Bewegung, die ursprünglich oder" versprechend war: Du Bois auf 
Garvey</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"l'effondrement de la seule chose dans le mouvement
de Garvey qui était initial ou promettant" : Du Bois sur 
Garvey</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"o colapso da única coisa no movimento de Garvey 
que era original ou prometendo": Du Bois em Garvey</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"il crollo di unica cosa nel movimento di Garvey 
che era originale o promettente": Du Bois su Garvey</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η κατάρρευση του μόνου πράγματος στη μετακίνηση 
Garvey που ήταν αρχική ή ελπιδοφόροσ": Θ*δu Bois σε 
Garvey</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"el derrumbamiento de la única cosa en el 
movimiento de Garvey que era original o de promesa": Du Bois en 
Garvey</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">After fighting World War I, ostensibly to defend democracy and the right of self-determination, thousands of African-American soldiers returned home to face intensified discrimination, segregation, and racial violence. Drawing on this frustration, Marcus Garvey attracted thousands of disillusioned black working-class and lower middle-class followers to his Universal Negro Improvement Association (UNIA). The UNIA, committed to notions of racial purity and separatism, insisted that salvation for African Americans meant building an autonomous, black-led nation in Africa. The Black Star Line, an all-black shipping company chartered by the UNIA, was the movement's boldest and most important project, and many African Americans bought shares of stock in the company. For all its grandeur and promise, however, the Black Star Line was soon beset by financial and legal problems, largely resulting from Garvey's mismanagement. The company folded only a few years after its founding. The company's collapse was detailed in an essay by black intellectual W. E. B. Du Bois, who cast doubt on Garvey's trustworthiness and suspicion on UNIA's overall program.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nachdem sie den Ersten Weltkrieg, um gekämpft 
hatten Demokratie und das Recht von Self-determination anscheinend zu 
verteidigen, kamen Tausenden der Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Soldaten 
nach Hause zu Gesicht verstärkter Unterscheidung, zur Abtrennung und 
zur rassischen Gewalttätigkeit zurück. Zeichnend auf diese 
Frustration, zog Marcus Garvey Tausenden der ernüchterten schwarzen 
Arbeiterklasse und der untereren Mittelklassenachfolger zu seiner 
Universalschwarze-Verbesserung Verbindung an (UNIA). Das UNIA, 
festgelegt an den Begriffen der rassischen Reinheit und des 
Separatismus, beharrte, daß Rettung für afrikanische Amerikaner 
das Aufbauen einer autonomen bedeutete, schwarz-führenden Nation in 
Afrika. Die schwarze Stern-Zeile, eine all-schwarze 
Verschiffenfirma, die durch das UNIA gechartert wurde, war das 
fetteste und wichtigste Projekt der Bewegung, und viele afrikanische 
Amerikaner kauften Kapitalanteile in der Firma. Für seine ganze
Herrlichkeit und Versprechung jedoch wurde die schwarze Stern-Zeile 
bald durch die finanziellen und zugelassenen Probleme belagert, und 
das groß resultiert aus Misswirtschaft Garveys. Nach seiner 
Gründung die Firma faltete nur einige Jahre. Der Einsturz der 
Firma wurde in einem Versuch von schwarzem intellektuellem W. E. B. Du
Bois genau geschildert, das Zweifel auf trustworthiness Garveys und 
Misstrauen auf UNIAs gesamtem Programm warf.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Après le combat de la Première Guerre Mondiale, 
pour défendre en apparence la démocratie et la droite de 
art de l'auto-portrait-determination, les milliers de soldats afro-américains sont 
revenus à la maison à la discrimination intensifiée par visage, à 
la ségrégation, et à la violence raciale. Dessinant sur cet 
anéantissement, Marcus Garvey a attiré des milliers de classe 
ouvrière noire désillusionnée et de sectateurs inférieurs de 
classe moyenne à son association universelle d'amélioration de 
nègre (UNIA). L'UNIA, commis aux notions de la pureté et du 
séparatisme raciaux, a insisté sur le fait que le salut pour les 
Américains africains a signifié établir une nation autonome et 
noir-menée en Afrique. Le noir Tiennent le premier rôle la ligne, une 
compagnie maritime tout-noire privilégiée par l'UNIA, étaient le 
projet le plus gras et le plus important du mouvement, et beaucoup 
d'Américains africains ont acheté des parts des actions à la 
compagnie. Pour toutes sa splendeur et promesse, cependant, le 
noir Tiennent le premier rôle la ligne a été bientôt assailli par des 
problèmes financiers et légaux, résultant en grande partie de la 
gestion mauvaise de Garvey. La compagnie a plié seulement 
quelques années après sa fondation. L'effondrement de la 
compagnie a été détaillé dans un essai par W. E. B. Du Bois 
intellectuel noir, qui a moulé le doute sur la fidélité de Garvey 
et le soupçon sur le programme global d'UNIA.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Após ter lutado o world.war.i, para defender 
ostensibly a democracia e a direita do self-determination, os milhares
de soldados Africano-Americanos retornaram para casa à 
discriminação intensified cara, ao segregation, e à violência 
racial. Desenhando nesta frustração, Marcus Garvey atraiu 
milhares do working-class preto disillusioned e de uns seguidores mais
baixos do middle-class a sua associação universal da melhoria do 
negro (UNIA). O UNIA, cometido às noções do purity e do 
separatism raciais, insistiu que o salvation para americanos africanos
significou construir uma nação autônoma, preto-conduzida em 
África. A linha preta da estrela, uma companhia de transporte 
todo-preta fretada pelo UNIA, era o projeto o mais bold(realce) e o 
mais importante do movimento, e muitos americanos africanos compraram 
partes de estoque na companhia. Para todos seus grandeur e 
promessa, entretanto, a linha preta da estrela beset logo pelos 
problemas financeiros e legais, resultando pela maior parte do 
mismanagement de Garvey. A companhia dobrou somente alguns anos 
após seu fundar. O colapso da companhia foi detalhado em um 
essay por W. intelectual preto E. B. Du Bois, que moldou a dúvida no 
trustworthiness de Garvey e a suspeita no programa total de UNIA.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dopo il world.war.i di combattimento, difendere 
apparentemente la democrazia e la destra di self-determination, i 
migliaia dei soldati Africano-Americani hanno ritornato a casa a 
distinzione intensificata faccia, alla segregazione ed alla violenza 
razziale. Dissipando su questa frustrazione, Marcus Garvey ha 
attratto i migliaia della classe operaia nera disillusa e dei 
seguicamme più bassi della classe media alla sua associazione 
universale di miglioramento del negro (UNIA). Il UNIA, impegnato
nelle nozioni della purezza e del separatism razziali, ha insistito 
che la salvezza per gli Americani africani ha significato lo 
sviluppo della nazione autonoma e nero-condotta in Africa. La 
riga nera della stella, un'azienda di trasporto tutto-nera istituita 
dal UNIA, era il progetto più GRASSETTO e più importante del 
movimento e molti Americani africani hanno comprato le parti delle 
azione nell'azienda. Per tutti i relativi grandeur e promessa, 
tuttavia, la riga nera della stella presto è stata assalita dai 
problemi finanziari e legali, in gran parte derivanti dalla cattiva 
gestione del Garvey. L'azienda ha piegato soltanto alcuni anni 
dopo relativo fondare. Il crollo dell'azienda è stato 
dettagliato in un saggio da W. E. B. Du Bois intellettuale nero, che 
ha lanciato il dubbio sul trustworthiness del Garvey ed il sospetto 
sul programma generale del UNIA.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μετά από να διεξαγάγουν τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι, για 
να υπερασπίσουν φαινομενικά τη δημοκρατία και το δικαίωμα της 
αυτοδιάθεσης, χιλιάδες αφρικανικός-αμερικανικοί στρατιώτες 
επέστρεψαν το σπίτι ενταμένη στην πρόσωπο διάκριση, το 
διαχωρισμό, και τη φυλετική βία. Επισύροντας την προσοχή σε
αυτήν την απογοήτευση, ο Marcus Garvey προσέλκυσε χιλιάδες 
απογοητευμένη μαύρη εργατική τάξη και χαμηλότεροι οπαδοί 
μεσαίων τάξεων στην καθολική ένωση βελτίωσης νέγρων του 
(UNIA). Το UNIA, δεσμευμένο στις έννοιες της φυλετικών 
αγνότητας και του αυτονομισμού, επέμεινε ότι η σωτηρία για 
αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς σήμανε ένα αυτόνομο, μαύρος-οδηγημένο 
έθνος στην Αφρική. Η μαύρη γραμμή αστεριών, μια 
όλος-μαύρη ναυτιλιακή εταιρία που ναυλώθηκε από το UNIA, 
ήταν το pjo' ψολδεστ και σημαντικότερο πρόγραμμα της 
μετακίνησης, και πολλοί αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί αγόρασαν τις 
μετοχές του αποθέματος στην επιχείρηση. Για όλες το 
μεγαλείο και την υπόσχεσή της, εντούτοις, η μαύρη γραμμή 
αστεριών περιβλήθηκε σύντομα από τα οικονομικά και νομικά 
προβλήματα, κατά ένα μεγάλο μέρος ως αποτέλεσμα της 
κακοδιαχείρισης Garvey. Η επιχείρηση δίπλωσε μόνο μερικά
έτη μετά από την ίδρυσή της. Η κατάρρευση της επιχείρησης
εκτέθηκε λεπτομερώς σε ένα δοκίμιο από μαύρο διανοητικό Θ*Ω. Ε.
Β. du Bois, το οποίο δημιούργησε αμφιβολία για την 
εμπιστοσύνη και την υποψία Garvey στο γενικό πρόγραμμα UNIA.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Después de luchar Primera Guerra Mundial, 
aparentemente para defender democracia y la derecha de la 
autodeterminación, los millares de soldados Africano-Americanos 
volvieron a casa a la discriminación intensificada cara, a la 
segregación, y a la violencia racial. Trazando en esta 
frustración, Marcus Garvey atrajo a millares de clase obrera negra 
desilusionada y de seguidores más bajos de la clase media a su 
asociación universal de la mejora del negro (UNIA). El UNIA, 
confiado a las nociones de la pureza y del separatism raciales, 
insistió que la salvación para los americanos africanos significó 
la construcción de una nación autónoma, negro-conducida en África.
La línea negra de la estrella, una compañía de envío 
todo-negra cargada por el UNIA, era el proyecto más en negrilla y 
más importante del movimiento, y muchos americanos africanos 
compraron partes de la acción en la compañía. Para todo su 
grandeur y promesa, sin embargo, la línea negra de la estrella pronto
fue sitiada por los problemas financieros y legales, resultando en 
gran parte de la mala gestión de Garvey. La compañía plegable
solamente algunos años después de su fundar. El derrumbamiento
de la compañía fue detallado en un ensayo por W. intelectual negro 
E. B. Du Bois, que echó duda en el trustworthiness de Garvey y la 
suspicacia en el programa total de UNIA.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086918</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108211</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-collapse-of-the-only-thing-in-the-garvey-movement-which-was-original-or-promising-du-bois-on-garvey</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
