<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103732</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103732</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206799</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">GEODE</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">GEODE</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">GEODE</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">GEODE</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">GEODE</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">GEODE</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">GEODE</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">lets students display on maps a range of data: population, transportation, political boundaries, oil, water, other natural resources, and more. Students can explore geographic relationships by combining and co-displaying these data on maps of Africa, the Americas, Asia, the Middle East, and other parts of the world.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">läßt Kursteilnehmerbildschirmanzeige auf Karten 
eine Strecke der Daten: Bevölkerung, Transport, politische 
Grenzen, Öl, Wasser, andere Naturresourcen und mehr. 
Kursteilnehmer können geographische Verhältnisse erforschen, 
indem sie diese Daten bezüglich der Karten von Afrika, von Amerika, 
von Asien, von Mittlere Osten und von anderen Teilen der Welt 
kombinieren und Co-anzeigen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">laisse l'affichage d'étudiants sur des cartes un 
intervalle des données : population, transport, bornes 
politiques, pétrole, eau, d'autres ressources naturelles, et plus. 
Les étudiants peuvent explorer des rapports géographiques en 
combinant et Co-en affichant ces données sur des cartes de l'Afrique,
des Amériques, de l'Asie, du le Moyen-Orient, et d'autres régions du
monde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">deixa o indicador dos estudantes em mapas uma 
escala dos dados: população, transporte, limites políticos, 
óleo, água, outros recursos naturais, e mais. Os estudantes 
podem explorar relacionamentos geográficos combinando e co-indicando 
estes dados em mapas de África, dos Americas, de Ásia, de o Oriente 
Médio, e de outras partes do mundo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">lascia la visualizzazione degli allievi sui 
programmi una gamma di dati: popolazione, trasporto, contorni 
politici, petrolio, acqua, altre risorse naturali e più. Gli 
allievi possono esplorare i rapporti geografici unendo e 
co-visualizzando questi dati sui programmi dell'Africa, dei Americas, 
dell'Asia, di Medio Oriente e di altre parti del mondo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">αφήνει την παρουσίαση σπουδαστών στους χάρτες μια 
σειρά των στοιχείων: πληθυσμός, μεταφορά, πολιτικά όρια, 
έλαιο, ύδωρ, άλλα φυσικά στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς, και 
περισσότεροι. Οι σπουδαστές μπορούν να ερευνήσουν τις 
γεωγραφικές σχέσεις με το συνδυασμό και την ομο-παρουσίαση αυτών 
των στοιχείων όσον αφορά τους χάρτες της Αφρικής, της Αμερικής, 
της Ασίας, της Μέσης Ανατολής, και άλλων μερών του κόσμου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">deja la visualización de los estudiantes en 
correspondencias un rango de datos: población, transporte, 
límites políticos, aceite, agua, otros recursos naturales, y más. 
Los estudiantes pueden explorar lazos geográficos combinando y 
co-visualizando estos datos sobre correspondencias de África, de las 
Américas, de Asia, de el Oriente Medio, y de otras partes del mundo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206799</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103732</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/geode</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
