<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104350</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104350</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087157</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">United We Stand? Tom Watson on Interracial Southern Populism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Vereinigt Stehen Wir? Tom Watson auf 
Interracial südlichem Populismus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Uni Nous Nous tenons ? Tom Watson 
sur le Populisme méridional d'Interracial</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Unido Nós Estamos? Tom Watson em 
Interracial Populism do sul</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Unito Ci leviamo in piedi? Tom Watson su 
Interracial Populism del sud</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ενωμένοι στεκόμαστε; Θ*Τομ Watson στο 
διαφυλετικό νότιο λαϊκισμό</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿Unido Estamos parados? Tom Watson en el 
Populismo meridional de Interracial</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Just as the question of race divided the Southern Populist movement, so has it divided historians. Some scholars point to the uniquely interracial qualities of the Populist movement, while others emphasize the ways that racial divisions limited the success of southern agrarian radicals. Part of the difficulty in resolving the dispute is the complexity and ambiguity of race relations in Southern Populism. In his famous essay on "The Negro Question in the South," published in 1892, Tom Watson, a Southern Populist who was elected to the U.S. Congress from Georgia in 1890, made one of the strongest cases for an alliance of black and white farmers. Yet Watson was calling for a strategic political alliance, not a fully integrated society, and his commitment to interracialism did not survive the defeat of the Populist movement. After the turn of the century, Watson led efforts to disfranchise African Americans, publishing demagogic attacks on them as well as on Catholics and Jews.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gerade da die Frage des Rennens die südliche 
Volksbewegung teilte, hat sie so geteilte Historiker. Einige 
Gelehrte zeigen auf die eindeutig interracial Qualitäten der 
Volksbewegung, während andere die Methoden hervorheben, denen 
rassische Abteilungen den Erfolg der südlichen landwirtschaftlichen 
Radikale begrenzten. Der Teil der Schwierigkeit, wenn er die 
Debatte behebt, ist die Kompliziertheit und die Mehrdeutigkeit der 
Rennenrelationen im südlichen Populismus. In seinem 
berühmten Versuch auf "der Schwarze-Frage im Süden," 
veröffentlichte 1892, Tom Watson, ein südlicher Populist, der zum 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Kongreß von Georgia 1890 gewählt wurde, gebildet 
eine der stärksten Argumente für ein Bündnis der schwarzen und 
weißen Landwirte. Dennoch verlangte Watson ein strategisches 
politisches Bündnis, nicht eine völlig integrierte Gesellschaft, und
seine Verpflichtung gegenüber interracialism überlebte nicht die 
Niederlage der Volksbewegung. Nachdem die Jahrhundertwende, 
Watson Bemühungen disfranchise zu den afrikanischen Amerikanern 
führte und demagogic Angriffe auf ihnen sowie auf Katholischen und 
Juden veröffentlichte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Juste comme la question de la course divisait le 
mouvement populiste méridional, l'a ainsi les historiens divisés. 
Quelques disciples se dirigent aux qualités seulement 
interracial du mouvement populiste, alors que d'autres soulignent les 
manières dont les divisions raciales ont limité le succès des 
radicaux agraires méridionaux. Une partie de la difficulté en 
résolvant le conflit est la complexité et l'ambiguïté des 
relations inter-raciales dans le Populisme méridional. Dans 
son essai célèbre sur "la question de nègre dans les Sud,"
a édité en 1892, Tom Watson, un populiste méridional qui a 
été élu au congrès des ETATS-UNIS de la Géorgie en 1890, fait un 
des points de droit les plus forts pour une alliance des fermiers 
noirs et blancs. Pourtant Watson nécessitait une alliance 
politique stratégique, pas une société entièrement intégrée, et 
son engagement à l'interracialism n'a pas survécu la défaite du 
mouvement populiste. Après que le tournant du siècle, Watson 
ait mené des efforts aux Américains africains de disfranchise, 
éditant des attaques démagogiques sur elles aussi bien que sur des 
catholiques et des juifs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Apenas porque a pergunta da raça dividiu o 
movimento populist do sul, tem-no assim historians divididos. 
Alguns scholars apontam às qualidades excepcionalmente 
interracial do movimento populist, quando outros emfatizarem as 
maneiras que as divisões raciais limitaram o sucesso de radicais 
agrarian do sul. A parte da dificuldade em resolver a disputa é
a complexidade e a ambigüidade de relações de raça em Populism do 
sul. Em seu essay famoso "na pergunta do negro no sul," publicou
em 1892, Tom Watson, um populist do sul que fosse elegido ao congress 
de ESTADOS UNIDOS de Geórgia em 1890, feito uma dos argumentos os 
mais fortes para um alliance de fazendeiros pretos e brancos. 
Contudo Watson estava chamando-se para um alliance político 
estratégico, não uma sociedade inteiramente integrada, e seu 
compromisso ao interracialism não sobreviveu a derrota do movimento 
populist. Depois que a volta do século, Watson conduziu a 
esforços aos americanos africanos do disfranchise, publicando ataques
demagogic neles as.well.as em catholics e jews.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Appena poichè la domanda della corsa ha diviso il
movimento populistico del sud, così lo ha storici divisi. 
Alcuni eruditi indicano alle qualità unicamente interracial del
movimento populistico, mentre altri danno risalto ai modi che le 
divisioni razziali hanno limitato il successo dei radicali agrari del 
sud. La parte della difficoltà nella risoluzione della disputa 
è la complessità e l'ambiguità dei rapporti di corsa in Populism 
del sud. Nel suo saggio famoso "sulla domanda del negro nel 
sud," ha pubblicato in 1892, Tom Watson, un populist del sud che è 
stato scelto al congresso degli STATI UNITI dalla Georgia in 1890, 
fatto uno degli argomenti più forti per un'alleanza dei coltivatori 
neri e bianchi. Tuttavia Watson stava richiedendo un'alleanza 
politica strategica, non una società completamente integrata ed il 
suo impegno al interracialism non è sopravvissuto la sconfitta del 
movimento populistico. Dopo che la girata del secolo, Watson 
conduca gli sforzi agli Americani africani del disfranchise, 
pubblicanti gli attacchi demagogic loro così come sui cattolici e gli
ebrei.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ακριβώς όπως το θέμα της φυλής διαίρεσε τη νότια 
λαϊκιστική μετακίνηση, έτσι την έχει διαιρεμένοι ιστορικοί. 
Μερικοί μελετητές δείχνουν τις μεμονωμένα διαφυλετικές 
ιδιότητες της λαϊκιστικής μετακίνησης, ενώ άλλοι υπογραμμίζουν 
τους τρόπους ότι τα φυλετικά τμήματα περιόρισαν την επιτυχία των
νότιων αγροτικών ριζοσπαστών. Μέρος της δυσκολίας στην 
επίλυση της διαφωνίας είναι η πολυπλοκότητα και η ασάφεια των 
φυλετικών σχέσεων στο νότιο λαϊκισμό. Στο διάσημο 
δοκίμιό του "στην ερώτηση νέγρων στο νότο," δημοσιευμένος το 
1892, Tom Watson, νότιος ένας λαϊκιστικός ποιος 
εκλέχτηκε στο ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ συνέδριο από τη Γεωργία το 1890, 
καμένος ένα από τα πιό σημαντικά ζητήματα για μια συμμαχία των 
μαύρων και λευκών αγροτών. Ακόμα Watson απαιτούσε μια 
στρατηγική πολιτική συμμαχία, όχι μια πλήρως ενσωματωμένη 
κοινωνία, και η δέσμευσή του για το interracialism δεν επέζησε 
της ήττας της λαϊκιστικής μετακίνησης. Μετά από τη στροφή
του αιώνα, Watson οδήγησε τις προσπάθειες αφρικανικοί 
Αμερικανοί, που δημοσιεύουν τις δημαγωγικές επιθέσεις σε τους 
καθώς επίσης και στους Καθολικούς και τους Εβραίους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Apenas pues la cuestión de la raza dividió el 
movimiento populista meridional, lo tiene tan los historiadores 
divididos. Algunos eruditos señalan a las calidades únicamente
interracial del movimiento populista, mientras que otros acentúan las
maneras que las divisiones raciales limitaron el éxito de radicales 
agrarios meridionales. La parte de la dificultad en la 
resolución del conflicto es la complejidad y la ambigüedad de las 
relaciones de raza en Populismo meridional. En su ensayo famoso
en "la pregunta del negro en el sur," publicó en 1892, Tom Watson, 
populist meridional que fue elegido al congreso de ESTADOS UNIDOS de 
Georgia en 1890, hecho uno de los casos más fuertes para una alianza 
de granjeros negros y blancos. Con todo Watson llamaba para una 
alianza política estratégica, no sociedad completamente integrada, y
su consolidación con el interracialism no sobrevivió la derrota del 
movimiento populista. Después de que la vuelta del siglo, 
Watson condujera esfuerzos a los americanos africanos del 
disfranchise, publicando ataques demagógicos contra ellos así como 
en católicos y judíos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087157</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104350</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/united-we-stand-tom-watson-on-interracial-southern-populism</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
