<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107056</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107056</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086871</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Suspended Judgment": A  Times  Editorial on the  Maine  Tragedy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Verschobenes Urteil": Zeiten redaktionell 
auf der Maine Tragödie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Jugement Suspendu" : Périodes éditoriales
sur la tragédie du Maine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Julgamento Suspendido": Épocas editorial 
na tragédia de Maine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Giudizio Sospeso": Periodi editoriali sulla
tragedia della Maine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ανασταλμένη κρίση": Ένα χρονικό κύριο άρθρο 
στην τραγωδία του Maine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Juicio Suspendido": Épocas editoriales en 
la tragedia de Maine</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">On February 15, 1898, an explosion ripped through the American battleship  Maine , anchored in Havana harbor, sinking the ship and killing 260 sailors. Americans responded with outrage, assuming that Spain, which controlled Cuba as a colony, had sunk the ship. By April, 1898, the slogan "Remember the  Maine " carried the U.S. into war with Spain. In the midst of the hysteria, few Americans paid much attention to the report issued two weeks before the U.S. entry into the war by a Court of Inquiry appointed by President McKinley. The report stated that the committee could not definitively assign blame to Spain for the sinking of the  Maine . Most historians have focused on the role of sensationalist newspapers in fomenting public support for U.S. entry into war with Spain, and perhaps even causing it by deliberately misleading the American public about the  Maine  explosion. But not all newspapers engaged in sensationalist coverage of the incident. This New York  Times  editorial, dated February 17, 1898, sounded a note of caution about blaming the Spanish government for the explosion.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Auf Februar 15, 1898, einer Explosion zerrissen 
durch das amerikanische Linienschiff Maine, befestigt im Havana Hafen,
das Schiff sinkend und beenden 260 Seeleute. Amerikaner 
reagierten mit dem Verbrechen und nahmen dieses Spanien an, dem 
kontrolliertes Kuba als Kolonie, das Schiff gesunken hatte. Bis 
zum April 1898, erinnern sich der Slogan ", daß das Maine" die 
VEREINIGTEN STAATEN in Krieg mit Spanien trug. In der Mitte der 
Hysterie, lenkten wenige Amerikaner viel Aufmerksamkeit auf den 
Report herausgaben zwei Wochen bevor der VEREINIGTE STAATEN Eintrag in
den Krieg durch eine Untersuchungskommission ernannt vom Präsidenten 
McKinley. Der Report gab an, daß der Ausschuß nicht Schuld 
nach Spanien für das Sinken des Maines endgültig zuweisen könnte. 
Die meisten Historiker haben auf die Rolle der sensationalist 
Zeitungen in dem Anfachen des allgemeinen Supports für VEREINIGTE 
STAATEN Eintrag in Krieg mit Spanien konzentriert, und ihn 
möglicherweise sogar, verursachend, indem sie absichtlich die 
amerikanische Öffentlichkeit über die Maine Explosion irreführten. 
Aber nicht alle Zeitungen engagierten sich in der sensationalist
Dichte des Ereignisses. Dieses New York setzt Zeit 
redaktionelles fest, datiert Februar 17, 1898, klang eine Anmerkung 
von Vorsicht über das Tadeln der spanischen Regierung für die 
Explosion.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">15 février 1898, une explosion déchirée par le
cuirassé américain Maine, ancré dans le port de La Havane, 
descendant le bateau et détruisant 260 marins. Les Américains 
ont répondu avec l'outrage, assumant la cette Espagne, que le Cuba 
commandé en tant que colonie, était descendu le bateau. En 
avril, 1898, le slogan "se rappellent que le Maine" a porté les 
ETATS-UNIS dans la guerre avec l'Espagne. Au milieu de 
l'hystérie, peu d'Américains ont prêté beaucoup d'attention à 
l'état ont émis deux semaines avant que l'entrée des ETATS-UNIS 
dans la guerre par une cour d'enquête désignée par le Président 
McKinley. L'état a déclaré que le comité ne pourrait pas 
définitivement assigner le blâme en Espagne pour la descente du 
Maine. La plupart des historiens se sont concentrés sur le 
rôle des journaux sensationnalistes en fomentant le soutien public de 
l'entrée des ETATS-UNIS dans la guerre avec l'Espagne, et en le 
causant peut-être même en trompant délibérément le public 
américain au sujet de l'explosion du Maine. Mais non tous les 
journaux se sont engagés dans l'assurance sensationnaliste de l'incident. 
Ce New York chronomètre éditorial, daté du 17 février 1898,
a retenti une note d'attention au sujet de blâmer le gouvernement 
espagnol de l'explosion.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fevereiro em 15, 1898, em uma explosão rasgada 
através do cruzador de batalha americano Maine, escorado no porto de 
Havana, afundando o navio e matando 260 sailors. Os americanos 
responderam com o ultraje, supondo esse Spain, que Cuba controlada 
como uma colônia, tinha afundado o navio. Por abril, 1898, o 
slogan "recorda que o Maine" carregou os ESTADOS UNIDOS na guerra com 
o Spain. No meio do hysteria, poucos americanos pagaram muita 
atenção ao relatório emitiram duas semanas antes que a entrada de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS na guerra por uma corte de inquérito apontada pelo 
presidente McKinley. O relatório indicou que o comitê não 
poderia definitively atribuir a culpa a Spain para se afundar do 
Maine. A maioria de historians focalizaram no papel de jornais 
do sensationalist em fomentar a sustentação pública para a entrada 
de ESTADOS UNIDOS na guerra com o Spain, e talvez mesmo em causá-la 
deliberadamente misleading o público americano sobre a explosão de 
Maine. Mas não todos os jornais acoplaram na cobertura do 
sensationalist do incident. Esta New York cronometra editorial, 
datado fevereiro 17, 1898, soou uma nota do cuidado sobre 
responsabilizar o governo espanhol pela explosão.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il 15 febbraio 1898, un'esplosione strappata 
tramite il battleship americano Maine, ancorata nel porto de Avana, 
affondante la nave e mortale 260 marinai. Gli Americani hanno 
risposto con l'oltraggio, ammettente la quella Spagna, che la Cuba 
controllata come colonia, aveva affondato la nave. Entro aprile,
del 1898, lo slogan "si ricorda di che la Maine" ha trasportato gli 
STATI UNITI nella guerra con la Spagna. In mezzo a il hysteria, 
pochi Americani ha prestato molta attenzione al rapporto ha pubblicato
due settimane prima che l'entrata degli STATI UNITI nella guerra da 
una corte dell'inchiesta nominata dal presidente McKinley. Il 
rapporto ha dichiarato che il comitato non potrebbe definitivo 
assegnare la colpa in Spagna per l'abbassamento della Maine. La 
maggior parte dei storici hanno messo a fuoco sul ruolo dei giornali 
di sensationalist nel fomentare il sostegno pubblico l'entrata degli 
STATI UNITI nella guerra con la Spagna e forse persino nel causarlo 
deliberatamente fuorviando il pubblico americano circa l'esplosione 
della Maine. Ma non tutti i giornali si sono agganciati nel 
riempimento di sensationalist dell'avvenimento. Questa New York 
cronometra editoriale, datato 17 febbraio 1898, ha suonato una nota 
dell'attenzione circa incolpare del governo spagnolo l'esplosione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στις 15 Φεβρουαρίου ..1898, μια έκρηξη έσχισε 
μέσω του αμερικανικού θωρηκτού Maine, που δέθηκε στο λιμάνι 
της Αβάνας, που βυθίζει το σκάφος και που σκοτώνει 260 
ναυτικούς. Αμερικανοί αποκρίθηκαν με την προσβολή, 
υποθέτοντας ότι η Ισπανία, που έλεγξε την Κούβα ως αποικία, 
είχε βυθίσει το σκάφος. Μέχρι τον Απρίλιο, 1898, το 
σύνθημα "θυμούνται ότι το Maine" έφερε τις ΗΠΑ στον πόλεμο με 
την Ισπανία. Στη μέση της υστερίας, λίγοι Αμερικανοί 
έδωσαν πολλή προσοχή στην έκθεση που παρουσιάστηκε δύο 
εβδομάδες πριν από την ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ είσοδο μέσα σε τον πόλεμο από
ένα δικαστήριο της έρευνας που διορίστηκε από τον Πρόεδρο 
McKinley. Η έκθεση δήλωσε ότι η επιτροπή δεν θα μπορούσε
να αναθέσει οριστικά την επίπληξη στην Ισπανία για τη βύθιση του 
Maine. Οι περισσότεροι ιστορικοί έχουν εστιάσει στο ρόλο
των sensationalist εφημερίδων στην ενθάρρυνση της δημόσιας 
υποστήριξης για την ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ είσοδο μέσα σε τον πόλεμο με την 
Ισπανία, και ίσως προκαλώντας το ακόμη και με σκόπιμα να 
παραπλανήσουν το αμερικανικό κοινό για την έκρηξη του Maine. 
Αλλά δεν συμμετείχαν όλες οι εφημερίδες στην 
sensationalist κάλυψη του γεγονότος. Αυτό το κύριο άρθρο
New York Times, της 17ης Φεβρουαρίου ..1898, ήχησε μια 
σημείωση της προσοχής για την επίπληξη της ισπανικής κυβέρνησης 
για την έκρηξη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">15 de febrero de 1898, una explosión rasgada a
través del acorazado americano Maine, asegurado en el puerto de La 
Habana, hundiendo la nave y matando a 260 marineros. Los 
americanos respondieron con el ultraje, si se asume esa España, que 
Cuba controlada como colonia, había hundido la nave. Por abril 
de 1898, el lema "recuerda que el Maine" llevó los ESTADOS UNIDOS en 
guerra con España. En el medio de la histeria, pocos americanos
prestaron mucha atención al informe publicaron dos semanas antes de 
que la entrada de ESTADOS UNIDOS en la guerra por una corte de la 
pregunta designada por presidente McKinley. El informe indicó 
que el comité no podría asignar definitivo culpa a España para 
hundirse del Maine. La mayoría de los historiadores se han 
centrado en el papel de los periódicos del sensationalist en fomentar
la ayuda pública para la entrada de ESTADOS UNIDOS en guerra con 
España, y quizás incluso causarla deliberadamente engañando al 
público americano sobre la explosión de Maine. Pero no todos 
los periódicos engancharon a la cobertura del sensationalist del 
incidente. Esta Nueva York mide el tiempo de editorial, fechado 
17 de febrero de 1898, sonaba una nota de la precaución sobre 
culpar el gobierno español por la explosión.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086871</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107056</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/suspended-judgment-a-times-editorial-on-the-maine-tragedy</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
