<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106067</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106067</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207152</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Fugitive from Labor Cases: Henry Garnett and Moses Honner</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Flüchtling von den Arbeitsfällen: Henry 
Garnett und Moses Honner</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Fugitif des cas de travail : Henry Garnett 
et Moïse Honner</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fugitive dos casos labor: Henry Garnett e 
Moses Honner</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fuggitivo dai casi Di lavoro: Henry Garnett
e Moses Honner</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πρόσφυγας από τις περιπτώσεις εργασίας: Θ*Χενρυ 
Garnett και Μωυσής Honner</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fugitivo de casos de trabajo: Henrio Garnett
y Moses Honner</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">encourages students to analyze historic documents related to two fugitive slave cases and determine the impact events of the period 1850 to 1860 had on them. The Henry Garnett and Moses Honner cases demonstrates the political crisis in the 1850s arising over the issue of slavery and the necessity for the enactment of the 13th, 14th, and 15th Amendments to the U.S. Constitution. This lesson correlates to the National History Standards and the National Standards for Civics and Social Sciences.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">regt Kursteilnehmer an, die historischen Dokumente
zu analysieren, die auf zwei Flüchtlingsklavenfällen in Verbindung 
gestanden werden und die Auswirkung Fälle der Periode 1850 bis 1860 
festzustellen hatte auf ihnen. Die Fälle des Henrys Garnett und
Moseses Honner zeigt die politische Krise im 1850s, das über der 
Ausgabe der Sklaverei und der Notwendigkeit für den Erlaß der 13., 
14. und 15. Änderungen zur VEREINIGTE STAATEN Beschaffenheit 
entsteht. Diese Lektion bezieht mit den nationalen Geschichte 
Standards und den nationalen Standards für Gemeinschaftskunde und 
Sozialwissenschaften aufeinander.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">encourage des étudiants à analyser les documents
historiques liés à deux cas slaves de fugitif et déterminer 
les événements d'impact de la période 1850 à 1860 a eu sur eux. 
Les cas d'Henry Garnett et de Moïse Honner démontre la crise 
politique dans le 1850s surgissant au-dessus de la question de 
l'esclavage et de la nécessité pour l'établissement des 13èmes, 
14èmes, et 15èmes amendements à la constitution des ETATS-UNIS. 
Cette leçon se corrèle avec les normes nationales d'histoire 
et les normes nationales pour l'éducation civique et les sciences 
sociales.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">incentiva estudantes analisar os originais 
historic relacionados a dois exemplos slave do fugitive e determinar 
os eventos do impacto do período 1850 a 1860 teve neles. Os 
exemplos do Henry Garnett e do Moses Honner demonstram a crise 
política no 1850s que levanta-se sobre a introdução do slavery e a 
necessidade para o enactment das 1ás, 1âs, e 1äs emendas ao 
constitution de ESTADOS UNIDOS. Esta lição correlaciona aos 
padrões nacionais do history e aos padrões nacionais para o civics e
ciências sociais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">consiglia agli allievi analizzare i documenti 
storici relativi a due casi slave del fuggitivo e determinare gli 
eventi di effetto dei periodi 1850 - 1860 ha avuta su loro. I 
casi di henry Garnett e del Moses Honner dimostra la crisi politica 
nel 1850s che presenta sopra l'emissione di slavery e la necessità 
per la promulgazione delle tredicesime, quattordicesime e quindicesime
correzioni alla costituzione degli STATI UNITI. Questa lezione 
correla agli standard nazionali di storia ed agli standard nazionali 
per civics e le scienze sociali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ενθαρρύνει τους σπουδαστές για να αναλύσει τα ιστορικά
έγγραφα σχετικά με δύο περιπτώσεις σκλάβων προσφύγων και να 
καθορίσει τα γεγονότα αντίκτυπου της περιόδου 1850 έως 1860
είχε σε τους. Ο Henry Garnett και οι περιπτώσεις του 
Μωυσή Honner καταδεικνύουν την πολιτική κρίση στο 1850s που 
προκύπτουν πέρα από το ζήτημα της σκλαβιάς και την ανάγκη για τη
θέσπιση των 13$ων, 14$ων, και 15$ων τροποποιήσεων στο ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΌ 
σύνταγμα. Αυτό το μάθημα συσχετίζει στα εθνικά πρότυπα 
ιστορίας και τα εθνικά πρότυπα για Civics και τις κοινωνικές 
επιστήμες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">anima a estudiantes que analicen los documentos 
históricos relacionados con dos casos auxiliares del fugitivo y 
determinar los acontecimientos del impacto del período 1850 a 1860 
tenía en ellos. Los casos del Henrio Garnett y de Moses Honner 
demuestran la crisis política en el 1850s que se presenta sobre la 
aplicación la esclavitud y la necesidad para la promulgación de las 
décimotercero, 14tas, y décimo quintas enmiendas a la constitución 
de ESTADOS UNIDOS. Esta lección correlaciona a los estándares 
nacionales de la historia y a los estándares nacionales para el 
civics y las ciencias sociales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207152</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106067</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/fugitive-from-labor-cases-henry-garnett-and-moses-honner</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
