<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107304</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107304</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203687</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Light at the Bottom of the Deep, Dark Ocean?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Licht an der Unterseite des tiefen, dunklen 
Ozeans?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Lumière au bas de l'océan profond et foncé ?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Luz no fundo do oceano profundo, escuro?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Luce alla parte inferiore dell'oceano profondo e 
scuro?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Φως στο κατώτατο σημείο του βαθιού, σκοτεινού 
ωκεανού;</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿Luz en el fondo del océano profundo, oscuro?</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Ocean Explorer interactive, hands-on lesson plan (PDF) leads students on an exploration of deepwater adaptations by addressing the focus question: What types of adaptations enable deep-sea fishes to survive and collect food in the darkness of the deep ocean? In the activity, students search for Skittles in a dark room while wearing goggles covered in blue cellophane to simulate deepwater feeding. This lesson plan includes a reproducible student handout and links to reference resources.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser interaktive Ozean-Forscher, Blindeinschub 
Lektionplan (pdf) führt Kursteilnehmer auf einer Erforschung von 
Hochseeanpassungen, indem er die Fokusfrage adressiert: Welche 
Typen von Anpassungen aktivieren Tiefseefische zu überleben und 
Nahrung in der Schwärzung des tiefen Ozeans zu sammeln? In der 
Aktivität suchen Kursteilnehmer nach Skittles in einem dunklen Raum 
beim Tragen der Schutzbrillen, die im blauen Zellophan bedeckt werden,
um das Hochseeeinziehen zu simulieren. Dieser Lektionplan 
schließt ein reproduzierbares Handbuch und Links zu den 
Bezugshilfsmitteln ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cet explorateur d'océan interactif, le plan à commande 
manuelle de leçon (pdf) mène des étudiants sur une exploration des 
adaptations en eau profonde en adressant la question de foyer : 
Quels types d'adaptations permettent aux poissons hauturiers de 
survivre et de rassembler la nourriture dans l'obscurité de l'océan 
profond ? Dans l'activité, les étudiants recherchent Skittles 
dans une salle foncée tout en portant des lunettes couvertes dans la 
cellophane bleue pour simuler l'alimentation en eau profonde. Ce
plan de leçon inclut une aumône et des liens d'étudiant 
reproductible aux sources de référence.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este explorador do oceano interativo, a planta hands-on da
lição (pdf) conduz a estudantes em uma exploração de adaptações 
deepwater dirigindo-se à pergunta do foco: Que tipos de 
adaptações permitem peixes deep-sea de sobreviver e coletar o 
alimento na escuridão do oceano profundo? Na atividade, os 
estudantes procuraram por Skittles em um quarto escuro ao desgastar os
óculos de proteção cobertos no cellophane azul para simular a 
alimentação deepwater. Esta planta da lição inclui um 
handout e as ligações de estudante reproducible aos recursos de 
referência.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo esploratore dell'oceano interattivo, programma 
hands-on di lezione (pdf) conduce gli allievi su un'esplorazione degli
adattamenti di acque profonde rivolgere la domanda del fuoco: 
Che tipi di adattamenti permettono ai pesci di alto mare di 
sopravvivere e raccogliere l'alimento nella nerezza dell'oceano 
profondo? Nell'attività, gli allievi cercano Skittles in una 
stanza scura mentre portano gli occhiali di protezione coperti in 
cellofan blu per simulare l'alimentazione di acque profonde. 
Questo programma di lezione include una dispensa ed i 
collegamenti di allievo riproducibile alle risorse di riferimento.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σπουδαστές μολύβδων αυτών των ωκεάνιοι εξερευνητών 
διαλογικοί, εμπράγματοι σχεδίων μαθήματος (PDF) σε μια 
εξερεύνηση των σε βαθιά νερά προσαρμογών με την εξέταση της 
ερώτησης εστίασης: Ποιοι τύποι προσαρμογών επιτρέπουν στα 
βαθύβια ψάρια για να επιζήσουν και να συλλέξουν των τροφίμων στο 
σκοτάδι του βαθιού ωκεανού; Στη δραστηριότητα, αναζήτηση 
σπουδαστών skittles σε ένα σκοτεινό δωμάτιο φορώντας τα 
προστατευτικά δίοπτρα που καλύπτονται στο μπλε σελοφάν για να 
μιμηθεί τη σε βαθιά νερά σίτιση. Αυτό το σχέδιο μαθήματος
περιλαμβάνει ένα αναπαραγώγιμο φυλλάδιο και τις συνδέσεις 
σπουδαστών με τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς αναφοράς.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este explorador del océano interactivo, el plan con manos
de la lección (pdf) conduce a estudiantes en una exploración de 
adaptaciones profundas tratando la pregunta del foco: ¿Qué 
tipos de adaptaciones permiten a pescados de alta mar sobrevivir y 
recoger el alimento en la oscuridad del océano profundo? En la 
actividad, los estudiantes buscan para Skittles en un cuarto oscuro 
mientras que desgastan los anteojos cubiertos en celofán azul para 
simular la alimentación profunda. Este plan de la lección 
incluye un folleto y conexiones de estudiante reproductivo a los 
recursos de referencia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:OCEAN EXPLORER
FN:OCEAN EXPLORER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:NOAA
FN:NOAA
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203687</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107304</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/light-at-the-bottom-of-the-deep-dark-ocean</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
