<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106011</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106011</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086358</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"It's Our Sons and Daughters:" Voices of the New York City Labor Movement In Opposition to the Gulf War</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"es ist unsere Söhne und Töchter:" Stimmen
der New York City Arbeiterbewegung in der Opposition zum Golf-Krieg</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"c'est nos fils et filles :" Voix du 
mouvement de travail de New York City en opposition à la guerre du 
Golfe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"é nossos filhos e filhas:" Vozes do 
movimento labor de New York City na oposição à guerra de golfo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"è i nostri figli e figlie:" Voci del 
movimento Di lavoro de New York City nell'opposizione alla guerra di 
golfo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Είναι οι γιοι και οι κόρες μας:" Φωνές του 
Κινήματος εργασίας πόλεων της Νέας Υόρκης στην αντίθεση στον 
πόλεμο του Κόλπου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"es nuestros hijos e hijas:" Voces del 
movimiento de trabajo de New York City en la oposición a la guerra 
del Golfo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">When Saddam Hussein invaded Kuwait in 1990, President Bush, whose popularity at home was flagging, opted to respond with massive military force even though many Americans, including Congressional leaders, believed economic sanctions would be effective. Bush initiated a massive, deadly air assault on January 15, 1991, and a brief ground assault followed four weeks later. The Gulf War killed thousands of Iraqi civilians and devastated most of the country's infrastructure, including hospitals and water systems. Many Americans who had previously questioned military action supported the war effort once it began, but many did not. In a break with their stance during previous wars, including World War II and Vietnam, many unions opposed military action in Kuwait. The union members recorded here articulated their reasons for opposing the war at an anti-war protest.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Als Saddam Hussein Kuwait 1990 eindrang, entschied
Präsident Bush, dessen Popularität zu Hause kennzeichnete, mit 
massiver militärischer Kraft zu reagieren, obwohl viele Amerikaner, 
einschließlich Kongreßführer glaubten, Wirtschaftssanktionen würde
sein wirkungsvoll. Bush initialisiert einen massiven, tödlichen
Luftangriff an Januar 15, 1991, und ein kurzer Grundangriff folgte 
vier Wochen später. Die beendeten Tausenden des Golf-Krieges 
der irakischen Zivilisten und verwüstet die meisten der 
Infrastrukturs des Landes, einschließlich Krankenhäuser und 
Wassersysteme. Viele Amerikaner, die vorher militärische 
Tätigkeit gefragt hatten, unterstützten die Kriegbemühung, einmal, 
das sie anfing, aber viele nicht. In einem Bruch mit ihrer 
Position während der vorhergehenden Kriege, einschließlich den 
Zweiten Weltkrieg und Vietnam, setzten viele Anschlüße 
militärischer Tätigkeit in Kuwait entgegen. Die 
Anschlußbauteile, die hier gespeichert wurden, artikulierten ihre 
Gründe für das Entgegensetzen des Krieges an einem 
Antikriegsprotest.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Quand Saddam Hussein a envahi le Kowéit en
1990, le Président Bush, dont la popularité à la maison diminuait, 
a choisi de répondre avec la force militaire massive quoique beaucoup
d'Américains, y compris les amorces congressionnelles, aient cru des 
sanctions économique serait pertinent. Bush lance un assaut 
massif et mortel d'air 15 janvier 1991, et un bref assaut au sol a 
suivi quatre semaines plus tard. Les milliers détruits de la 
guerre du Golfe de civils irakiens et dévastés la majeure partie de 
l'infrastructure du pays, y compris des hôpitaux et des systèmes de 
l'eau. Beaucoup d'Américains qui avaient précédemment remis 
en cause l'action militaire ont supporté l'effort de guerre par le 
passé qu'il a commencé, mais beaucoup pas . Dans une rupture 
avec leur position pendant des guerres précédentes, y compris la 
deuxième guerre mondiale et le Vietnam, beaucoup de syndicats se sont
opposés à l'action militaire au Kowéit. Les travailleurs 
syndiqués enregistrés ici ont articulé leurs raisons de s'opposer 
à la guerre à une protestation pacifiste.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quando Saddam Hussein invadiu Kuwait em 1990, o 
presidente Bush, cuja a popularidade na HOME estava embandeirando, 
opted responder com força militar maciça mesmo que muitos 
americanos, including líderes congressionais, acreditassem sanctions 
econômicos seria eficaz. Bush inicía um assalto maciço, 
mortal do ar janeiro em 15, 1991, e um assalto à terra breve seguiu 
quatro semanas mais tarde. Os milhares matados da guerra de 
golfo de civis iraqi e devastated a maioria do infrastructure do 
país, including hospitais e sistemas da água. Muitos 
americanos que tinham questionado previamente a ação militar 
suportaram o esforço da guerra uma vez que começou, mas muitos não 
. Em uma ruptura com seu stance durante guerras precedentes, 
including a segunda guerra mundial e o Vietnam, muitas uniões 
opuseram a ação militar em Kuwait. Os membros de união 
gravados aqui articularam suas razões para opôr a guerra em um 
protesto anti-war.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Quando Saddam Hussein ha invaso il Kuwait in 1990,
il presidente Bush, di cui la popolarità nel paese stava diminendo, 
ha scelto rispondere con forza militare voluminosa anche se molti 
Americani, compreso i capi congressuali, hanno creduto sanzioni
economiche sarebbe efficace. Bush inizia un assalto voluminoso e
mortale dell'aria il 15 gennaio 1991 e un breve assalto al suolo ha 
seguito più successivamente quattro settimane. I migliaia 
uccisi di guerra di golfo dei civili iracheni e devastanti la maggior 
parte dell'infrastruttura del paese, compreso gli ospedali ed i 
sistemi dell'acqua. Molti Americani che precedentemente avevano 
messo in discussione l'azione militare hanno sostenuto lo sforzo di 
guerra ha cominciato una volta che, ma molti non. In una rottura
con la loro posizione durante le guerre precedenti, compreso la 
seconda guerra mondiale ed il Vietnam, molti sindacati hanno opposto 
l'azione militare nel Kuwait. I membri del sindacato registrati 
qui hanno articolato i loro motivi per opporre la guerra ad una 
protesta pacifista.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Όταν ο Σαντάμ εισέβαλε Χουσεΐν στο Κουβέιτ το 
1990, ο Πρόεδρος Bush, η ο οποίος δημοτικότητα στο σπίτι 
σημαιοστόλιζε, επέλεξε για να αποκριθεί με την ογκώδη στρατιωτική
δύναμη ακόμα κι αν πολλοί Αμερικανοί, συμπεριλαμβανομένων των του
Κογκρέσου ηγετών, εθεώρησαν ότι οι οικονομικές κυρώσεις θα ήταν
αποτελεσματικές. Ο Μπους άρχισε μια ογκώδη, θανάσιμη 
εναέρια επίθεση στις 15 Ιανουαρίου ..1991, και μια συνοπτική
επίγεια επίθεση ακολουθούμενη τέσσερις εβδομάδες αργότερα. 
Ο πόλεμος του Κόλπου σκότωσε χιλιάδες ιρακινοί πολίτες και
κατάστρεψε την μεγαλύτερη μέρος της υποδομής της χώρας, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένων των νοσοκομείων και των συστημάτων ύδατος. 
Πολλοί Αμερικανοί που είχαν εξετάσει προηγουμένως τη 
στρατιωτική ενέργεια υποστήριξαν την πολεμική προσπάθεια μόλις 
άρχισαν, αλλά πολλοί όχι. Σε ένα σπάσιμο με τη θέση τους 
κατά τη διάρκεια των προηγούμενων πολέμων, συμπεριλαμβανομένου 
του παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ και του Βιετνάμ, πολλές ενώσεις 
αντέταξαν τη στρατιωτική ενέργεια στο Κουβέιτ. Τα μέλη 
ένωσης που καταγράφηκαν εδώ άρθρωσαν τους λόγους τους για τον 
πόλεμο σε μια αντιπολεμική διαμαρτυρία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cuando Saddam Hussein invadió Kuwait en 1990, 
presidente Bush, que renombre en el país señalaba por medio de una 
bandera, optó responder con la fuerza militar masiva aunque muchos 
americanos, incluyendo arranques de cinta del congreso, creyeron las 
sanciones económicas sería eficaz. Bush inició un asalto 
masivo, mortal del aire 15 de enero de 1991, y un asalto de tierra 
abreviado siguió cuatro semanas más adelante. Los millares 
matados de la guerra del Golfo de civiles iraquíes y devastados la 
mayoría de la infraestructura del país, incluyendo hospitales y 
sistemas del agua. Muchos americanos que habían preguntado 
previamente la acción militar utilizaron el esfuerzo de la guerra que
comenzó una vez, pero muchos no . En una rotura con su postura 
durante guerras anteriores, incluyendo la Segunda Guerra Mundial y 
Vietnam, muchas uniones opusieron la acción militar en Kuwait. 
Los miembros de unión registrados aquí articularon sus razones
de oponer la guerra en una protesta pacifista.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086358</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106011</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/its-our-sons-and-daughters-voices-of-the-new-york-city-labor-movement-in-opposition-to-the-gulf-war</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
