<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105883</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105883</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206391</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">United States v. Thomas Cooper: A Violation of the Sedition Law</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Vereinigte Staaten V. Thomas Faßbinder: 
Eine Verletzung des Sedition-Gesetzes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Tonnelier des Etats-Unis v. Thomas : Une 
violation de la loi de sedition</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Cooper unido dos estados v. Thomas: Uma 
violação da lei do sedition</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Unito Dichiara il cooper del v. Thomas: 
Una violazione della legge di sedition</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες V. Thomas Cooper: Μια 
παραβίαση του νόμου στασιασμού</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fabricante de vinos de Estados Unidos v. Thomas: 
Una violación de la ley de la sedición</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Presents facsimiles of 8 printed and hand-written documents surrounding the case of Thomas Cooper, a lawyer and newspaper editor in Sunbury, Pennsylvania, who was indicted, prosecuted, and convicted of violating the Sedition Act after he published a broadside in 1799 that sharply criticized President John Adams. The case is famous in the annals of the Bill of Right's First Amendment. This lesson correlates to the National History Standards and the National Standards for Civics and Social Sciences.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Stellt die Faksimiles von 8 gedruckt und von den 
handgeschriebenen Dokumenten, die den Kasten des Thomas Faßbinders, 
des Rechtsanwalts und des Zeitungsverlegers in Sunbury, Pennsylvania 
umgeben dar, das des Verletzens der Sedition-Tat angeklagt, verfolgt 
und überführt wurde, nachdem er eine Breitseite 1799 
veröffentlichte, das scharf Präsidenten John Adams kritisierte. 
Der Fall ist in den Annalen der Verfassung erste Änderung 
berühmt. Diese Lektion bezieht mit den nationalen Geschichte 
Standards und den nationalen Standards für Gemeinschaftskunde und 
Sozialwissenschaften aufeinander.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Présente des fac-similés de 8 imprimés et de 
documents manuscrits entourant la caisse de tonnelier de Thomas, d'un 
avocat et d'éditeur de journal à Sunbury, Pennsylvanie, qui a été 
accusée, poursuivie, et condamnée de violer la Loi de sedition 
après qu'il ait édité un flanc en 1799 qui a vivement 
critiqué le Président John Adams. Le cas est célèbre dans 
les annales de la déclaration des droits le premier amendement. 
Cette leçon se corrèle avec les normes nationales d'histoire 
et les normes nationales pour l'éducation civique et les sciences 
sociales.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Apresenta as fac-símiles de 8 impressas e dos 
originais escritos à mão que cercam a caixa do cooper de Thomas, de 
um advogado e do editor de jornal em Sunbury, Pensilvânia, que foi 
processada, prosecuted, e convicted de violating o ato do sedition 
depois que publicou um broadside em 1799 que criticou agudamente o 
presidente John Adams. O caso é famoso nos annals da conta da 
primeira emenda de direita. Esta lição correlaciona aos 
padrões nacionais do history e aos padrões nacionais para o civics e
ciências sociais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Presenta i facsimili di 8 stampati e dei documenti 
scritti a mano che circondano la cassa del cooper del Thomas, di un 
avvocato e dell'editore di giornale a Sunbury, Pensilvania, che è 
stata incriminata, proseguito stata ed è condannato stata di 
violazione della Legge di sedition dopo che abbia pubblicato un 
attacco in 1799 che ha criticato acutamente il presidente John 
Adams. Il caso è famoso negli annali della fattura della prima 
correzione della destra. Questa lezione correla agli standard 
nazionali di storia ed agli standard nazionali per civics e le scienze
sociali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παρουσιάζει facsimiles 8 τυπωμένων και χειρόγραφων 
εγγράφων που περιβάλλουν την περίπτωση του Thomas Cooper, 
ενός δικηγόρου και ενός επεξεργαστή εφημερίδων στο Sunbury, 
Πενσυλβανία, η οποία κατηγορήθηκε, διήχθη, και καταδικάστηκε της 
παραβίασης του νόμου στασιασμού αφότου δημοσίευσε broadside το
1799 που επέκρινε αισθητά τον Πρόεδρο John Adams. Η 
περίπτωση είναι διάσημη στα χρονικά του Bill της πρώτης 
τροποποίησης του δικαιώματος. Αυτό το μάθημα συσχετίζει στα
εθνικά πρότυπα ιστορίας και τα εθνικά πρότυπα για Civics και 
τις κοινωνικές επιστήμες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Presenta los facsímiles de 8 impresos y de 
documentos manuscritos que rodean la caja de fabricante de vinos de 
Thomas, de un abogado y de redactor en Sunbury, Pennsylvania, que fue 
procesada, procesada, y condenada por la violación del acto de la 
sedición después de que él publicara un costado en 1799 que 
criticó sostenidamente a presidente Juan Adams. El caso es 
famoso en los anales de la cuenta de la primera enmienda de la 
derecha. Esta lección correlaciona a los estándares nacionales
de la historia y a los estándares nacionales para el civics y las 
ciencias sociales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206391</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105883</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/united-states-v-thomas-cooper-a-violation-of-the-sedition-law</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
