<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105180</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105180</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087291</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"A Decent Home . . . for Every American Family": Postwar Housing Shortage Victims Testify before Congress</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Ein Annehmbares Haus. . . für 
jede amerikanische Familie ": Nachkriegsgehäuse-Mangel-Opfer 
bezeugen vor Kongreß</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Une Maison Décente. . . pour 
chaque famille américaine ": Les victimes d'après-guerre de 
manque de logement témoignent devant le congrès</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Uma HOME Decent. . . para cada 
família americana ": As vítimas postwar da falta de carcaça 
testify antes do congress</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Una Sede Decent. . . per ogni 
famiglia americana ": Le vittime dopoguerra della carenza 
edilizia testimoniano prima del congresso</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Μια κόσμιη"Οικία". .. για κάθε 
αμερικανική οικογένεια ": Τα μεταπολεμικά θύματα έλλειψης 
κατοικίας πιστοποιούν πριν από το συνέδριο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Un Hogar Decente. . . para cada
familia americana ": Las víctimas de la posguerra de la escasez
de cubierta atestiguan antes de congreso</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">New home construction declined dramatically during the Great Depression as rents rose, reaching an all-time high in 1940. A persistent housing shortage continuing into the early 1950s forced families to separate and apartment dwellers to "double-up." The housing reform movement, largely ineffectual in the 1920s and 1930s, gathered strength in the postwar period. Labor and veteran groups pressured Congress and the White House to enact a comprehensive housing policy with money for public housing and continued wartime rent control. President Harry S. Truman, echoing reformers, wrote to Congress, "A decent standard of housing for all is one of the irreducible obligations of modern civilization." Despite opposition from real estate interests, the Housing Act of 1949 passed. Although the Act called for the construction of 810,000 units of public housing over six years--and two additional housing acts in 1961 and 1965 promised substantial increases--by the mid-1960s, more people lived in substandard housing than in 1949. In addition, many blamed public housing itself for destroying neighborhoods and fostering social problems. In the following 1947 testimony before a joint Congressional committee, including Frank L. Sundstrom, Representative of New Jersey, created by anti-housing reform legislators to stall action, New Jersey spokespersons for tenants quoted the proposed Taft-Ellender-Wagner legislation and described housing conditions, while a number of tenants related their own difficult living situations.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Neuer Hauptaufbau sank drastisch während des 
großen Tiefstands, während Mieten stiegen und erreichte eine 
all-time Höhe 1940. Ein hartnäckiger Gehäusemangel, der in 
die frühen fünfziger Jahre fortfährt, erzwang Familien sich zu 
trennen und die Wohnung Bewohner "doppelt-oben." Die 
Gehäusereformbewegung, das groß wirkungslos in den zwanziger Jahren 
und in den dreißiger Jahren, erfaßte Stärke in der Nachkriegszeit. 
Arbeit und Veteran Gruppen gedrueckter Kongreß und das Weiße 
Haus, zum einer kompletten Gehäusepolitik mit Geld für Gasthaus und 
anhaltende Kriegmietesteuerung zu verordnen. Alle Präsident 
Harry S. Truman, Echo ausgeben Reformer, schrieb dem Kongreß, 
"ein annehmbarer Standard der Unterbringung für ist eine der nicht 
reduzierbaren Verpflichtungen der modernen Zivilisation." Trotz 
der Opposition von den Immobilieninteressen, überschritt die 
Gehäuse-Tat von 1949. Obgleich die Tat, die den Aufbau von 
810.000 Maßeinheiten allgemeinem Gehäuse über sechs Jahren verlangt
wurde -- und zwei zusätzliche Gehäusetaten 1961 und 1965 versprachen
erhebliche Zunahmen -- bis zum den Mid-1960s, mehr Leute im nicht der 
Norm entsprechenden Gehäuse als 1949 lebte. Zusätzlich 
tadelten viele allgemeines Gehäuse selbst für zerstörende 
Nachbarschaften und das Fördern von von Sozialproblemen. Im 
folgenden Zeugnis 1947 vor einem gemeinsamen Kongreßausschuß, 
einschließlich aufrichtiges L. Sundstrom, veranschlug der 
Repräsentant von Neu-Jersey, hergestellt von den Anti-Gehäuse 
Verbesserunggesetzgebern, um Tätigkeit, Neu-Jersey Sprecher 
festzuklemmen für Pächter die vorgeschlagene Taft-Ellender-Wagner 
Gesetzgebung und beschrieb Gehäusezustände, während eine Anzahl von
Pächtern ihre eigenen schwierigen lebenden Situationen in Verbindung 
stand.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La nouvelle construction à la maison a diminué 
excessivement pendant la grande dépression pendant que les loyers 
montaient, atteignant une haute absolue en 1940. Un manque de 
logement persistant continuant dans le début des années 50 a forcé 
des familles à séparer et des habitants d'appartement "doubles-vers 
le haut." Le mouvement de réforme de logement, en grande partie
inefficaces dans les années 20 et les années 30, force recueillie 
dans l'après-guerre. Le congrès pressurisé par groupes de 
travail et de vétéran et la Maison Blanche  pour décréter une 
politique de logement complète avec de l'argent pour la taverne et le
contrôle des loyers continu de temps de guerre. Le Président 
Harry S. Truman, réformateurs de faire écho, a écrit au congrès, 
"un niveau décent de loger pour tout est l'un des engagements 
irréductibles de la civilisation moderne." En dépit de 
l'opposition des intérêts de immobiliers, la Loi de logement de 1949
a passé. Bien que l'acte nécessité la construction de 810.000
unités de logement public sur six ans -- et deux actes 
supplémentaires de logement en 1961 et 1965 ont promis des 
augmentations substantielles -- par le milieu des années 60, plus de 
personnes ait vécu dans le logement inférieur qu'en 1949. En 
outre, beaucoup ont blâmé le logement public lui-même des 
voisinages détruisants et de stimuler des problèmes sociaux. 
Dans le témoignage 1947 suivant devant un comité 
congressionnel commun, y compris L. Sundstrom franc, le représentant 
de New Jersey, créé par des législateurs de réforme 
d'anti-logement pour caler l'action, porte-parole de New Jersey pour 
des locataires a cité la législation proposée de 
Taft-Ellender-Wagner et a décrit des états de logement, alors 
qu'un certain nombre de locataires rapportaient leurs propres 
situations vivantes difficiles.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A construção home nova declinou dramàtica 
durante o depression grande enquanto os aluguéis se levantaram, 
alcançando uma elevação absoluta em 1940. Uma falta de 
carcaça persistente que continua nos 1950s adiantados forçou 
famílias a separar e moradores do apartamento "dobro-acima." O 
movimento de reforma da carcaça, pela maior parte ineffectual nos 
1920s e nos 1930s, força recolhida no período postwar. 
Congress exercido pressão sobre grupos do trabalho e do veteran
e a casa branca para decretar uma política de carcaça detalhada com 
dinheiro para a carcaça pública e o controle de aluguel continuado 
do wartime. O presidente Harry S. Truman, reformers ecoando, 
escreveu ao congress, "um padrão decent de abrigar para todo é uma 
das obrigações irreducible da civilização moderna." Apesar 
da oposição dos interesses da propriedade real, o ato da carcaça de
1949 passou. Embora o ato chamado para a construção de 810.000
unidades da carcaça pública sobre seis anos em -- e dois atos 
adicionais da carcaça em 1961 e em 1965 prometeram aumentos 
substanciais -- pelos mid-1960s, mais povos vivesse na carcaça 
substandard do que em 1949. Além, muitos responsabilizaram a 
carcaça pública própria vizinhanças destruindo e promover 
problemas sociais. No seguinte testimony 1947 antes de um 
comitê congressional comum, including L. frank Sundstrom, o 
representante de Novo-Jersey, criado por legislators da reforma da 
anti-carcaça para parar a ação, spokespersons de Novo-Jersey para 
tenants citou a legislação proposta de Taft-Ellender-Wagner e 
descreveu condições de carcaça, quando um número de tenants 
relacionaram suas próprias situações vivas difíceis.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La nuova costruzione domestica ha declinato 
drammaticamente durante la depressione grande mentre gli affitti sono 
aumentato, raggiungente un high assoluto in 1940. Una carenza 
edilizia persistente che continua nell'inizio degli anni cinquanta ha 
forzato le famiglie separare e gli abitanti dell'appartamento 
"doppi-in su." Il movimento di riforma dell'alloggiamento, in 
gran parte inefficaci negli anni 20 e nei 1930s, resistenza 
riunita nel periodo. Congresso pressured gruppi del 
veterano e di lavoro e la Casa Bianca per promulgare una 
politica edilizia completa con soldi per osteria e controllo dei 
canoni d'affitto continuato di wartime. Il presidente Harry S. 
Truman, reformers echeggianti, ha scritto al congresso, "un livello 
decent di alloggio per tutto è uno degli obblighi irriducibili di 
civilizzazione moderna." Malgrado opposizione dagli interessi 
del bene immobile, la legge sugli alloggi di 1949 ha passato. 
Anche se la Legge richiesta la costruzione di 810.000 unità di 
edilizia popolare in sei anni in -- e le due leggi sugli alloggi 
supplementari in 1961 ed in 1965 hanno promesso gli aumenti notevoli 
-- entro i mid-1960s, più gente ha vissuto in alloggiamento inferiore
alla media che in 1949. In più, molti hanno incolpato 
dell'edilizia popolare in se distruggere le vicinanze e la 
promozione dei problemi sociali. Nella seguente testimonianza 
1947 prima di un comitato congressuale unito, compreso L. Sundstrom 
franco, il rappresentante della Nuovo-Jersey, creato dai legislatori 
di riforma dell'anti-alloggiamento per arrestarsi l'azione, 
spokespersons della Nuovo-Jersey per gli inquilini ha citato la 
legislazione proposta di Taft-Ellender-Wagner ed ha descritto le 
condizioni di alloggio, mentre un certo numero di inquilini hanno 
riferito le loro proprie situazioni viventi difficili.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η νέα βασική κατασκευή μειώθηκε εντυπωσιακά κατά τη 
διάρκεια της μεγάλης οικονομικής κρίσης καθώς τα μισθώματα 
αυξήθηκαν, φθάνοντας όλων των εποχών σε έναν υψηλό το 1940. 
Μια επίμονη έλλειψη κατοικίας που συνεχίζεται στην πρόωρη 
δεκαετία του '50 ανάγκασε τις οικογένειες για να χωρίσει και τους 
κατοίκους διαμερισμάτων "διπλός-επάνω." Το κίνημα 
μεταρρύθμισης κατοικίας, κατά ένα μεγάλο μέρος άκαρπο στη 
δεκαετία του '20 και τη δεκαετία του '30, μαζευμένη δύναμη στη 
μεταπολεμική περίοδο. Οι ομάδες εργασίας και παλαιμάχων 
πίεσαν το συνέδριο και το λευκό οίκο για να θεσπίσουν μια 
περιεκτική στεγαστική πολιτική με τα χρήματα για τη δημόσια 
κατοικία και συνέχισαν τον εν καιρώ πολέμου έλεγχο μισθώματος. 
Ο Πρόεδρος Harry S. Truman, αντηχώντας 
μεταρρυθμιστές, έγραψε στο συνέδριο, "κόσμιος ένας πρότυπος της 
κατοικίας για όλους είναι μια από τις αμείωτες υποχρεώσεις του 
σύγχρονου πολιτισμού." Παρά την αντίθεση από τα 
ενδιαφέροντα ακίνητων περιουσιών, ο νόμος κατοικίας του 1949 
πέρασε. Αν και ο νόμος απαίτησε την κατασκευή 810.000 
μονάδων της δημόσιας κατοικίας πάνω από έξι έτη -- και 
πρόσθετη κατοικία δύο ενεργούν το 1961 και οι το 1965 
υποσχεμένες ουσιαστικές αυξήσεις -- μέχρι τα μέσα τησδεκαετίας 
του '60, περισσότεροι άνθρωποι έζησαν στην κάτω του μετρίου 
κατοικία απ'ό,τι το 1949. Επιπλέον, πολλοί κατηγόρησαν 
τηνμέσος δημόσια κατοικία η ίδια για την καταστροφή των 
γειτονιών και την ενθάρρυνση κοινωνικών των προβλημάτων. 
Στην ακόλουθη κατάθεση του 1947 ενώπιον μιας μικτής του 
Κογκρέσου επιτροπής, συμπεριλαμβανομένου του Frank L. 
Sundstrom, αντιπρόσωπος του Νιου Τζέρσεϋ, που δημιουργήθηκε με 
την αντι-στέγαση των νομοθετών μεταρρύθμισης στην ενέργεια 
στάβλων, οι εκπρόσωποι του Νιου Τζέρσευ! για τους μισθωτές 
ανέφεραν την προτεινόμενη νομοθεσία ταφτ-ελλενδερ- Wagner και 
περιέγραψαν τους όρους κατοικίας, ενώ διάφοροι μισθωτές 
αφορούσαν τις δύσκολες καταστάσεις διαβίωσής τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La nueva construcción casera declinó 
dramáticamente durante la gran depresión como se levantaron los 
alquileres, alcanzando un colmo absoluto en 1940. Una escasez de
cubierta persistente que continuaba en los comienzos de los años 50 
forzó a las familias separarse y a habitantes del apartamento 
"dobles-para arriba." El el movimiento de reforma de la 
cubierta, en gran parte ineficaces en los años 20 y los años 30, 
fuerza recolectada en la posguerra. Congreso ejercido presión 
sobre grupos del trabajo y del veterano y la casa blanca para decretar
una política de cubierta comprensiva con el dinero para la cubierta 
pública y el control de alquileres continuado del tiempo de guerra. 
Presidente Harry S. Truman, reformadores el producir eco, 
escribió al congreso, "un estándar decente de contener para todo es 
una de las obligaciones irreducibles de la civilización moderna." 
A pesar de la oposición de intereses de las propiedades 
inmobiliarias, el acto de la cubierta de 1949 pasó. Aunque el 
acto llamado para la construcción de 810.000 unidades de cubierta 
pública sobre seis años -- y dos actos adicionales de la cubierta en
1961 y 1965 prometieron aumentos substanciales -- por los mediados de 
los años sesenta, más gente vivió en la cubierta inferior al nivel 
normal que en 1949. Además, muchos culparon la cubierta 
pública sí mismo por vecindades que destruían y fomentar problemas 
sociales. En el testimonio siguiente 1947 ante un comité del 
congreso común, incluyendo L. franco Sundstrom, el representante de 
Nuevo-Jersey, creado por los legisladores de la reforma de la 
contra-cubierta para atascar la acción, portavoces de Nuevo-Jersey 
para los arrendatarios cotizó la legislación propuesta de 
Taft-Ellender-Wagner y describió condiciones de cubierta, mientras 
que un número de arrendatarios relacionaron sus propias situaciones 
vivas difíciles.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087291</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105180</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-decent-home-for-every-american-family-postwar-housing-shortage-victims-testify-before-congress</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
