<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108452</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108452</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086338</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Inventing Homosexuality: Chicago Vice Crusaders Confront Sexual "Perversion" in the Theater</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erfindung Von von Homosexualität: Chicago 
Vizekreuzfahrer konfrontieren sexuelle "Perversion" im Theater</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Inventer l'Homosexualité : Les croisés 
vice de Chicago confrontent la "perversion" sexuelle dans le 
théâtre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Inventando O Homosexuality: Os cruzados vice
de Chicago confrontam o "perversion sexual" no teatro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Inventare Omosessualità: I crociati vice 
del Chicago confrontano "il perversion" sessuale nel teatro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εφεύρεση της ομοφυλοφυλίας: Οι σταυροφόροι 
κακίας του Σικάγου αντιμετωπίζουν τη σεξουαλική "διαστροφή" στο 
θέατρο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Inventar Homosexualidad: Los vice cruzados 
de Chicago enfrentan la "perversión sexual" en el teatro</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">From the Civil War through the 1920s, there were numerous clubs, saloons, and dance halls, in New York and other American cities, known for transvestism (men or women dressing as the opposite sex), for male prostitution, or as places that catered to a "gay crowd"--meaning men and women interested in a less conventional evening's entertainment. In the 1920s, due in part to Prohibition and the emergence of speakeasies, homosexuality became even more open. At the same time, psychologists, physicians, and social reformers had been at work for several decades attempting to study, classify, categorize, and label human sexual behavior. Working to establish "norms" for human behavior, they increasingly treated such gathering places as a danger. A 1911 report from a Chicago vice commission on "The Social Evil in Chicago" managed to mix disapproval, fascination, and paranoia, suggesting that "sex perverts" were a small minority but that their "secret language" pervaded ordinary entertainment.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Vom Bürgerkrieg durch die zwanziger Jahre, gab es
zahlreiche Vereine, Saloons und Tanzhallen, in New York und in anderen
amerikanischen Städte, bekannt für transvestism (die Männer oder 
Frauen, die als das gegenüberliegende Geschlecht ankleiden), für 
männliche Prostitution oder als Plätze, die einer "homosexuellen 
Masse" boten -- die Bedeutung Männer und Frauen, die an der 
Unterhaltung eines weniger herkömmlichen Abends interessiert wurden. 
In den zwanziger Jahren, die im Teil zum Verbot und im 
Hervortreten von Speakeasies passend sind, wurde Homosexualität sogar
mehr geöffnet. Gleichzeitig waren Psychologen, Ärzte und 
SozialReformer an der Arbeit für einige Dekaden gewesen, die 
versuchen, menschliches sexuelles Verhalten zu studieren, einzustufen,
zu kategorisieren und zu beschriften. Arbeitend, um "Normen" 
für menschliches Verhalten herzustellen, behandelten sie in 
zunehmendem Maße solche erfassenplätze wie eine Gefahr. Ein 
Report 1911 von einer Chicago Vizekommission auf "dem Sozialübel in 
Chicago" handhatte, Mißbilligung, Faszination und den Paranoia zu 
mischen und vorschlug, daß "Geschlecht Perverts" eine kleine 
Minorität waren, aber daß ihre "geheime Sprache" gewöhnliche 
Unterhaltung pervaded.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">De la guerre civile par les années 20, il y avait
de nombreux clubs, salles, et halls de danse, à New York et d'autres 
villes américaines, connus pour le transvestism (des hommes ou des 
femmes s'habillant comme sexe opposé), pour la prostitution mâle, ou
comme endroits qui ont approvisionné "à une foule gaie" -- des 
hommes et des femmes de signification intéressés au divertissement 
d'une soirée moins conventionnelle. Dans les années 20, dues 
en partie de la prohibition et l'apparition des bars clandestins, 
l'homosexualité est devenue bien plus ouverte. En même temps, 
les psychologues, les médecins, et les réformateurs sociaux avaient 
été au travail pendant plusieurs décennies essayant d'étudier, 
classifier, classer par catégorie, et étiqueter le comportement 
sexuel humain. Travaillant pour établir des "normes" pour le 
comportement humain, elles ont de plus en plus traité des endroits 
sourcilleux tels qu'un danger. Un état 1911 d'une commission 
vice de Chicago sur "le mal social Chicago" est parvenu à mélanger 
la désapprobation, la fascination, et la paranoïa, suggérant que 
les "pervertis de sexe" aient été une petite minorité mais que leur
"langage secret" a infiltré le divertissement ordinaire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Da guerra civil com os 1920s, havia clubes 
numerosos, saloons, e salões da dança, em New York e em outras 
cidades americanas, conhecidas para o transvestism (os homens ou as 
mulheres que se vestem como o sexo oposto), para a prostituição 
masculina, ou como os lugares que catered "a uma multidão gay" -- os 
homens e as mulheres do meaning interessados no entertainment de uma 
noite mais menos convencional. Nos 1920s, devidos na parte à 
proibição e no emergence dos speakeasies, o homosexuality 
transformou-se mesmo mais aberto. Ao mesmo tempo, os 
psicólogos, os médicos, e os reformers sociais tinham estado no 
trabalho por diversas décadas que tentam estudar, classificar, 
categorizar, e etiquetar o comportamento sexual humano. 
Trabalhando para estabelecer "normas" para o comportamento 
humano, trataram cada vez mais lugares de recolhimento como um perigo.
Um relatório 1911 de um commission vice de Chicago "no evil 
social em Chicago" controlou misturar a desaprovação, o fascínio, e
o paranoia, sugerindo que do "os pervertidos sexo" eram um minority 
pequeno mas que sua "língua secreta" pervaded o entertainment 
ordinário.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dalla guerra civile con gli anni 20, ci erano 
randelli numerosi, saloni e corridoi di ballo, a New York ed altre 
città americane, conosciute per il transvestism (uomini o donne che 
si vestono come il sesso opposto), per prostituzione maschio, o come 
posti che hanno approvvigionato "ad una folla di gay" -- 
uomini e donne di significato interessati all'intrattenimento della 
sera meno convenzionale. Negli anni 20, dovuti in parte alla 
proibizione e l'emersione degli speakeasies, l'omosessualità è 
diventato ancor più aperta. Allo stesso tempo, gli psicologi, i
medici ed i reformers sociali erano stati sul lavoro per parecchie 
decadi che tentano di studiare, classificare, categorizzare ed 
identificare il comportamento sessuale umano. Lavorando per 
stabilire "le norme" per comportamento umano, sempre più hanno 
trattato tali posti riunire come pericolo. Un rapporto 
1911 da una commissione vice del Chicago "sulla malvagità sociale in 
Chicago" è riuscito a mescolare la disapprovazione, il fascino ed il 
paranoia, suggerente che "i pervertiti del sesso" erano una piccola 
minoranza ma che il loro "linguaggio segreto" ha pervaduto 
l'intrattenimento ordinario.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Από τον εμφύλιο πόλεμο μέσω της δεκαετίας του '20, 
υπήρξαν πολυάριθμες λέσχες, αίθουσες, και αίθουσες χορού, στη 
Νέα Υόρκη και άλλες αμερικανικές πόλεις, γνωστές για το 
διασεξουαλισμό (άνδρες ή γυναίκες που ντύνουν ως αντίθετο 
φύλο), για την αρσενική πορνεία, ή ως θέσεις που τροφοδότησαν σε
ένα "ομοφυλοφιλικό πλήθοσ" -- σημαίνοντας τους άνδρες και τις 
γυναίκες ενδιαφερόμενους στην ψυχαγωγία ενός λιγότερο συμβατικού
βραδιού. Στη δεκαετία του '20, που οφείλονται εν μέρει στην 
απαγόρευση και την εμφάνιση των speakeasies, η ομοφυλοφυλία 
έγινε ακόμα ανοικτότερη. Συγχρόνως, οι ψυχολόγοι, οι 
παθολόγοι, και οι κοινωνικοί μεταρρυθμιστές ήταν στην εργασία για
αρκετές δεκαετίες που προσπαθούν να μελετήσουν, να ταξινομήσουν, 
να ταξινομήσουν, και ονομάζουν την ανθρώπινη σεξουαλική 
συμπεριφορά. Λειτουργώντας για να καθιερώσουν "τους κανόνεσ"
για την ανθρώπινη συμπεριφορά, μεταχειρίστηκαν όλο και 
περισσότερο τέτοιες θέσεις συλλογής όπως έναν κίνδυνο. 
Μια έκθεση του 1911 από την επιτροπή κακίας του Σικάγου 
σχετικά με "το κοινωνικό κακό στο Σικάγο" κατόρθωσε να αναμίξει 
την αποδοκιμασία, τη γοητεία, και την παράνοια, που προτείνει ότι
οι "διεστραμμένοι φύλων" ήταν μια μικρή μειονότητα αλλά ότι η 
"μυστική γλώσσα τουσ" εισχώρησε στη συνηθισμένη ψυχαγωγία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">De la guerra civil con los años 20, había clubs 
numerosos, salones, y los pasillos de la danza, en Nueva York y otras 
ciudades americanas, conocidas para el transvestism (los hombres o las
mujeres que visten como el sexo opuesto), para la prostitución 
masculina, o como lugares que abastecieron a una "muchedumbre 
gay" -- los hombres y las mujeres del significado interesados 
en la hospitalidad de una tarde menos convencional. En los años
20, debidos en parte a la prohibición y la aparición de bares, la 
homosexualidad llegó a estar aún más abierta. En el mismo 
tiempo, los psicólogos, los médicos, y los reformadores sociales 
habían estado en el trabajo por varias décadas que procuraban 
estudiar, clasificar, categorizar, y etiquetar comportamiento sexual 
humano. Trabajando para establecer "normas" para el 
comportamiento humano, trataron cada vez más los lugares de acopio 
tales como un peligro. Un informe 1911 de una vice comisión de 
Chicago en "el mal social en Chicago" manejó mezclar la 
desaprobación, la fascinación, y la paranoia, sugiriendo que los 
"pervertidos del sexo" eran una minoría pequeña pero que su 
"lenguaje secreto" impregnó la hospitalidad ordinaria.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086338</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108452</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/inventing-homosexuality-chicago-vice-crusaders-confront-sexual-perversion-in-the-theater</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
