<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108606</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108606</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086720</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Part of the Government Activity": Testimony from an African-American Taxpayer Unable to Vote in Alabama</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Teil der Regierung Aktivität": Zeugnis von
einem Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Steuerzahler nicht imstande, in 
Alabama zu wählen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">une "partie de l'activité de gouvernement" : 
Témoignage d'un contribuable afro-américain incapable de voter en
Alabama</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"parte da atividade do governo": Testimony 
de um taxpayer Africano-Americano incapaz de votar em Alabama</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"parte dell'attività di governo": 
Testimonianza da un contribuente Africano-Americano incapace 
votare nell'Alabama</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Μέρος της κυβερνητικής δραστηριότητασ": 
Κατάθεση από έναν αφρικανικός-αμερικανικό φορολογούμενο 
ανίκανο να ψηφίσει στην Αλαμπάμα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"parte de la actividad del gobierno": 
Testimonio de un contribuyente Africano-Americano incapaz votar 
en Alabama</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Although the 15th Amendment, ratified in 1870, guaranteed citizens the right to vote regardless of race, by 1957 only 20 percent of eligible African Americans voted, due in part to intimidation and discriminatory state requirements such as poll taxes and literacy tests. The Civil Rights Act of 1957, the first such Act since 1875, ostensibly sought to remedy the situation, but in its final weakened form, the legislation served more as a symbol. For example, an amendment allowed officials charged with denying voting rights to be tried by juries, service on which was restricted in the South to whites only. The law, however, also created the U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, an independent government agency of six commissioners formed to investigate charges of civil rights deprivations, collect information on discrimination, and advise the President and Congress on the topic. In the following 1958 hearing, a taxpaying African American related roadblocks he encountered when trying to register to vote.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Obgleich die 15. Änderung, bestätigt 1870, 
Bürgern das Recht, unabhängig davon Rennen, durch 1957 nur 20 
Prozent geeignete afrikanische Amerikaner zu wählen garantierte, die 
gewählt wurden, im Teil zur Einschüchterung und in den 
diskriminierenden Zustandanforderungen wie Gemeindeabgaben und 
Bildungsgradtests passend. Die Zivilrecht-Tat von 1957, die 
erste solche Tat seit 1875, anscheinend gesucht, die Situation zu 
beheben, aber in seiner abschließenden geschwächten Form, die 
Gesetzgebung diente mehr als Symbol. Z.B. erlaubte eine 
Änderung die Beamten, die mit dem Verweigern der wählenden Rechte, 
von den Jurys versucht zu werden aufgeladen wurden, an denen Service 
im Süden nur zum Weiß eingeschränkt wurde. Das Gesetz jedoch 
erstellte auch die VEREINIGTE STAATEN Kommission auf Zivilrechten, 
eine unabhängige Regierungsagentur von sechs Beauftragten, die 
gebildet wurden, um Ladungen des Zivilrechtentzugs nachzuforschen, 
Informationen über Unterscheidung zu sammeln, und den Präsidenten 
und den Kongreß auf dem Thema zu beraten. In der folgenden 
Hörfähigkeit 1958 taxpaying afrikanische amerikanische in Verbindung
stehende Straßensperren, die er antraf, als versuchend zu 
registrieren, um zu wählen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bien que le 15ème amendement, ratifié en 1870, 
ait garanti des citoyens la droite de voter indépendamment de la 
course, par 1957 seulement 20 pour cent d'Américains africains 
éligibles votés, dus en partie de l'intimidation et des conditions 
discriminatoires d'état telles que des impôts locaux et des essais 
d'instruction. La Loi de droits civiques de 1957, la première 
un tel acte depuis 1875, en apparence recherché à remédier à de la
situation, mais sous sa forme affaiblie finale, la législation a 
servi davantage de symbole. Par exemple, un amendement a permis 
des fonctionnaires chargés de nier le droit de vote d'être essayé 
par les jurys, le service sur lesquels a été limité dans les 
Sud aux blancs seulement. La loi, cependant, a 
également créé la Commission des ETATS-UNIS sur des droits 
civiques, un organisme gouvernemental indépendant de six commissaires
formés pour étudier des frais des privations de droits civiques, 
pour rassembler l'information sur la discrimination, et pour informer 
le président et le congrès sur le sujet. Dans l'audition 1958 
suivante, barrages de route relatifs américains africains 
imposables qu'il a rencontrés en essayant de s'enregistrer pour 
voter.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Embora a 1ä emenda, ratificada em 1870, 
garantisse cidadãos a direita votar não obstante a raça, por 1957 
somente 20 por cento dos americanos africanos elegíveis votados, 
devidos na parte à intimidação e em exigências discriminatory do 
estado tais como impostos de votação e testes do literacy. O 
ato de 1957, o primeiro das direitas civis tal ato desde 1875, 
procurado ostensibly remediar a situação, mas em seu formulário 
enfraquecido final, a legislação serviu mais como um símbolo. 
O exemplo, uma emenda permitiu os oficiais carregados com negar 
direitas votando ser tentado por júris, presta serviços de 
manutenção em qual foi restringido no sul aos brancos somente. 
A lei, entretanto, criou também o commission em direitas civis,
uma agência de ESTADOS UNIDOS de governo independente de seis 
comissários dados forma para investigar cargas de deprivations das 
direitas civis, para coletar a informação na discriminação, e para
recomendar o presidente e o congress no tópico. No seguinte 
hearing 1958, roadblocks que relacionados americanos africanos 
taxpaying encontrou ao tentar registar para votar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Anche se la quindicesima correzione, ratificata in
1870, ha garantito i cittadini la destra votare senza riguardo alla 
corsa, da 1957 soltanto 20 per cento degli Americani africani 
eleggibili votati, dovuto in parte all'intimidazione e discriminatorio
dichiari i requisiti quali le tasse di scrutinio e le prove 
di literacy. La Legge di 1957, la prima di diritti civili tale 
Legge dal 1875, cercato apparentemente di rimediare la situazione, ma 
nella relativa forma indebolita finale, la legislazione ha servito di 
più da simbolo. Per esempio, una correzione ha permesso i 
funzionari caricati del negare i diritti di voto essere provato dalle 
giurie, il servizio di cui è stato limitato nel sud ai bianchi 
soltanto. La legge, tuttavia, egualmente ha creato la 
Commissione sui diritti civili, un ente governativo degli STATI UNITI 
indipendente di sei commissari formati per studiare le spese delle 
privazioni di diritti civili, per raccogliere le informazioni su 
distinzione e per raccomandare il presidente ed il congresso sul 
soggetto. Nella seguente udienza 1958, blocchi stradali che 
relativi americani africani taxpaying ha incontrato quando prova a 
registrare per votare.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αν και η 15$η τροποποίηση, που επικυρώθηκε το 1870, 
εγγυήθηκε στους πολίτες το δικαίωμα να ψηφίσει ανεξάρτητα από τη
φυλή, μέχρι το 1957 μόνο 20 τοις εκατό επιλέξιμων αφρικανικών
Αμερικανών που ψηφίστηκαν, που οφείλονται εν μέρει στον εκφοβισμό
και τις μεροληπτικές κρατικές απαιτήσεις όπως οι κεφαλικοί φόροι
και οι δοκιμές βασικής εκπαίδευσης. Ο νόμος αστικών 
δικαιωμάτων του 1957, ο πρώτα τέτοιος νόμος από 1875, 
επιδιωκόμενος φαινομενικά να διορθώσει την κατάσταση, αλλά με 
τελική αποδυναμωμένη μορφή του, η νομοθεσία εχρησίμευσε 
περισσότερων ως ένα σύμβολο. Παραδείγματος χάριν, μια 
τροποποίηση επέτρεψε στους ανώτερους υπαλλήλους υπεύθυνους για 
την άρνηση των δικαιωμάτων ψήφου που δοκιμάζονται από τις 
κριτικές επιτροπές, η υπηρεσία στις οποίες περιορίστηκε στο νότο
στα λευκά μόνο. Ο νόμος, εντούτοις, επίσης δημιούργησε την
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ Επιτροπή στα αστικά δικαιώματα, μια ανεξάρτητη 
κυβερνητική αντιπροσωπεία έξι Επιτρόπων που διαμορφώθηκαν για να 
ερευνήσουν τις δαπάνες των στερήσεων αστικών δικαιωμάτων, να 
συλλέξουν τις πληροφορίες για τη διάκριση, και να συμβουλεψουν τον 
Πρόεδρο και το συνέδριο για το θέμα. Στην ακόλουθη ακρόαση 
του 1958, φορολογούμενα αφρικανικά αμερικανικά σχετικά 
οδοφράγματα αντιμετώπισε κατά την προσπάθεια να καταχωρήσει για 
να ψηφίσει.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Aunque la décimo quinta enmienda, ratificada en 
1870, garantizó a ciudadanos la derecha de votar sin importar la 
raza, por 1957 solamente 20 por ciento de americanos africanos 
elegibles votados, debidos en parte a la intimidación y requisitos 
discriminatorios del estado tales como impuestos de encuesta y pruebas
de la instrucción. El acto de 1957, el primer de las derechas 
civiles tal acto desde 1875, aparentemente intentado remediar la 
situación, pero en su forma debilitada final, la legislación sirvió
más como símbolo. Por ejemplo, una enmienda permitió a 
funcionarios cargados con negar derechos al voto de ser intentado por 
los jurados, el servicio en quienes fue restringido en el sur a los 
blancos solamente. La ley, sin embargo, también creó a 
Comisión en las derechas civiles, una agencia de ESTADOS UNIDOS de 
estatal independiente de seis comisiones formadas para investigar las 
cargas de privaciones de las derechas civiles, para recoger la 
información sobre la discriminación, y para aconsejar al presidente 
y al congreso sobre el asunto. En la audiencia siguiente 1958, 
barricadas relacionadas americanas africanas taxpaying que él 
encontró al intentar colocarse para votar.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086720</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108606</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/part-of-the-government-activity-testimony-from-an-african-american-taxpayer-unable-to-vote-in-alabama</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
