<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106262</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106262</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086883</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The A-Bomb Won't Do What You Think!": An Argument Against Reliance on Nuclear Weapons</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Die Ein-Bombe Tut Nicht, Was Sie!" Denken: 
Ein Argument gegen Vertrauen auf Kernwaffen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"l'Un-Panne Ne fera pas Ce que Vous Pensez!" : 
Un argument contre la confiance dans les armes nucléaires</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"A Um-Bomba Não fará O que Você Pensa!": 
Um argumento de encontro ao reliance em armas nucleares</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"La Un-Bomba Non farà Che cosa Pensate!": Un
argomento contro ricorso alle armi nucleari</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η α-βόμβα δεν θα κάνει τι σκέφτεστε!": Ένα 
όρισμα ενάντια στην εμπιστοσύνη στα πυρηνικά όπλα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"La Uno-Bomba No hará Lo que Usted Piensa!": 
Un argumento contra confianza en las armas nucleares</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">For four years after the U.S. dropped atom bombs on Hiroshima and Nagasaki to end World War II, America held a monopoly on the production of atomic weapons. During this period, debate centering on the use of nuclear bombs in future wars proliferated among government officials, scientists, religious leaders, and in the popular press. In the following article from  Collier's , former Navy lieutenant commander William H. Hessler, using data from the Strategic Bombing Survey, argued that saturation bombing of urban areas during World War II, while devastating for civilians, did not achieve war aims. A future atomic war, therefore, might well destroy cities but fail to stop enemy aggression. Furthermore, with a much higher urban concentration than the Soviet Union, the U.S. had more to lose from atomic warfare. The article, while providing detailed explanations of the bomb's destructive capability, demonstrated the lack of information available regarding the long-term medical and ecological effects of radioactivity. Hessler's prose also evoked both the fascination that gadgetry of atomic warfare held for Americans of the time and the fear many felt about the risks involved in putting this technology to use. On September 24, 1949, one week after publication of this article, news that the Russians had conducted atom bomb tests shocked the nation. The following April, a National Security Council report to President Harry S. Truman advised development of a hydrogen bomb--some 1,000 times more destructive than an atom bomb--and a massive buildup of non-nuclear defenses. The subsequent outbreak of war in Korea in June 1950 justified to many a substantial increase in defense spending.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Für vier Jahre nach den VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
fallengelassenen Atombomben auf Hiroschima und Nagasaki, zum des 
Zweiten Weltkrieges zu beenden, hielt Amerika ein Monopol in die 
Produktion der Atomwaffen an. Während dieser Periode vermehrte 
sich die Debatte, die auf dem Gebrauch der Kernbomben in den 
zukünftigen Kriegen zentriert, unter Regierungsbeamten, 
Wissenschaftler, fromme Führer und in der populären Presse stark. 
Im folgenden Artikel vom Colliers, argumentierte ehemaliger 
Marineleutnantkommandant William H. Hessler mit Daten von der 
strategischen Bombardierung-Übersicht, daß Sättigung Bombardierung 
der städtischen Bereiche während des Zweiten Weltkrieges, beim 
Verwüsten für Zivilisten, nicht Kriegziele erzielte. Ein 
zukünftiger Atomkrieg konnte folglich hervorquellen zerstören 
Städte aber nicht können feindlichen Angriff stoppen. 
Ausserdem mit einer viel höheren städtischen Konzentration als
der Sowjet-Anschluß, hatten die VEREINIGTEN STAATEN mehr, zum von der
Atomkriegsführung zu verlieren. Der Artikel, beim Zur 
Verfügung stellen die genau geschilderten Erklärungen der 
zerstörenden Fähigkeit der Bombe, demonstriert dem Mangel an 
Informationen vorhanden, die langfristigen medizinischen und 
ökologischen Effekte von Radioaktivität betrachtend. Prosa 
Hesslers erwähnte auch die Faszination, die gadgetry von der 
Atomkriegsführung für Amerikaner der Zeit anhielt und die Furcht 
viele über die Gefahren glaubte, die wenn sie diese Technologie zum 
Gebrauch mit einbezogen wurden, setzte. An September 24, 1949, 
eine Woche nach Publikation dieses Artikels, Nachrichten, daß die 
Russen geleitet hatten, entsetzten Atombombetests die Nation. 
Der folgende April, riet ein Staatssicherheit Ratreport zum 
Präsidenten Harry S. Truman Entwicklung einer Wasserstoffbombe -- 
einigen 1.000mal zerstörender als eine Atombombe -- und einer 
massiven Anhäufung der nicht nuklearen Verteidigung. Der 
folgende Ausbruch des Krieges in Korea im Juni 1950 schloß zu vielen 
eine erhebliche Zunahme der Verteidigungausgabe aus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant quatre années après les bombes atomiques 
lâchées par ETATS-UNIS sur Hiroshima et Nagasaki pour terminer la 
deuxième guerre mondiale, l'Amérique a tenu un monopole sur la 
production des armes atomiques. Pendant cette période, la 
discussion portant sur l'utilisation des pannes nucléaires dans de 
futures guerres a proliféré parmi des fonctionnaires de 
gouvernement, scientifiques, amorces religieuses, et dans la presse 
populaire. Dans l'article suivant de Collier, ancien 
commandant de lieutenant de marine William H. Hessler, en utilisant 
des données de l'enquête stratégique de bombardement, a argué du 
fait que le bombardement de saturation des zones urbaines pendant la 
deuxième guerre mondiale, tout en dévastant pour des civils, n'a pas
réalisé des objectifs de guerre. Une future guerre atomique 
pourrait, donc, jaillir détruisent des villes mais n'arrêtent pas 
l'agression ennemie. En outre, avec une concentration urbaine 
beaucoup plus élevée qu'Union Soviétique, les ETATS-UNIS ont eu plus à 
détruire de la guerre atomique. L'article, alors que fournir 
détaillait des explications de la capacité destructive de la panne, 
a démontré le manque d'information disponible considérant les 
effets médicaux et écologiques à long terme de la radioactivité. 
La prose de Hessler a également évoqué la fascination que 
l'accessoire de la guerre atomique a tenue pour des Américains du 
temps et la crainte beaucoup s'est senti au sujet des risques 
impliqués en mettant cette technologie à l'utilisation. 
24 septembre 1949, une semaine après publication de cet 
article, nouvelles que les Russes avaient conduit les essais de bombe 
atomique ont choqué la nation. Avril suivant, un état du 
Conseil de sécurité nationale au Président Harry S. Truman a 
informé le développement d'une bombe à hydrogène -- environ 1.000 
fois plus destructive qu'une bombe atomique -- et un habillage massif 
des défenses non-nucléaires. La manifestation ultérieure de 
guerre en Corée en juin 1950 a justifié aux beaucoup d'une 
augmentation substantielle des dépenses pour la défense.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Por quatro anos após as bombas de átomo deixadas 
cair ESTADOS UNIDOS em Hiroshima e em Nagasaki para terminar a segunda
guerra mundial, América prendeu um monopólio na produção de armas 
atômicas. Durante este período, o debate que centra-se no uso 
de bombas nucleares nas guerras futuras proliferated entre oficiais de
governo, cientistas, líderes religiosos, e na imprensa popular. 
No seguinte artigo do collier, o capitão-de-corveta anterior 
William da marinha H. Hessler, usando dados do exame estratégico do 
bombardeio, discutiu que o bombardeio do saturation de áreas urbanas 
durante a segunda guerra mundial, ao devastating para civis, não 
conseguiu alvos da guerra. Uma guerra atômica futura, pôde 
conseqüentemente jorrar destrói cidades mas não para o aggression 
inimigo. Além disso, com uma concentração urbana muito mais 
elevada do que a Soviete-união, os ESTADOS UNIDOS tiveram mais a 
perder da guerra atômica. O artigo, quando fornecer detalhou 
explanações da potencialidade destrutiva da bomba, demonstrou a 
falta da informação disponível considerando os efeitos médicos e 
ecological a longo prazo do radioactivity. A prosa de Hessler 
evoked também  o fascínio que gadgetry da guerra atômica prendeu 
para americanos do tempo e o medo muitos sentiu sobre os riscos 
envolvidos em pôr esta tecnologia ao uso. Setembro em 24, 1949,
uma semana após a publicação deste artigo, notícia que os russians
tinham conduzido os testes da bomba de átomo chocaram a nação. 
O seguinte abril, um relatório do conselho de segurança 
nacional ao presidente Harry S. Truman recomendou o desenvolvimento de
uma bomba de hidrogênio -- umas 1.000 vezes mais destrutiva do que 
uma bomba de átomo -- e um acúmulo maciço de defesas non-nuclear. 
O outbreak subseqüente da guerra em Coreia em junho 1950 
justificou aos muitos um aumento substancial na despesa de defesa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Per quattro anni dopo le bombe atomiche cadute gli 
STATI UNITI su Hiroshima e su Nagasaki per concludere la seconda 
guerra mondiale, l'America ha tenuto un monopolio sulla produzione 
delle armi atomiche. Durante questo periodo, il dibattito che 
concentra sull'uso delle bombe nucleari nelle guerre future ha 
proliferato fra i funzionari di governo, gli scienziati, capi 
religiosi e nella pressa popolare. Nel seguente articolo dal 
collier, l'ex comandante di tenente del blu marino William H. Hessler,
usando i dati dall'indagine strategica del bombardamento, ha sostenuto
che il bombardamento di saturazione delle aree urbane durante la 
seconda guerra mondiale, mentre devastava per i civili, non ha 
realizzato gli obiettivi di guerra. Una guerra atomica futura, 
quindi, ha potuto scaturire distrugge le città ma non riesce ad
arrestare l'aggressione nemica. Ancora, con un addensamento 
urbano molto più alto che l'Soviet-unione, gli STATI UNITI hanno 
avuti più da perdere da guerra atomica. L'articolo, mentre 
fornire ha dettagliato le spiegazioni della possibilità distruttiva 
della bomba, ha dimostrato la mancanza di informazioni disponibile 
considerando gli effetti medici ed ecologici di lunga durata di 
radioattività. La prosa del Hessler egualmente ha evocato sia 
il fascino che gadgetry di guerra atomica ha tenuto per gli Americani 
del tempo che il timore molti ha ritenuto circa i rischi addetti a 
mettere questa tecnologia all'uso. Il 24 settembre 1949, una 
settimana dopo la pubblicazione di questo articolo, notizie che i 
Russi avevano condotto le prove della bomba atomica hanno scosso la 
nazione. Seguente aprile, un rapporto del Consiglio di sicurezza
nazionale al presidente Harry S. Truman ha raccomandato lo sviluppo di
una bomba all'idrogeno -- circa 1.000 volta più distruttiva di una 
bomba atomica -- e un'accumulazione voluminosa delle difese non 
nucleari. Lo scoppio successivo di guerra in Corea in giugno 
1950 ha giustificato ai molti un aumento notevole in spesa della
difesa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Για τέσσερα έτη μετά από τις πεταγμένες οι ΗΠΑ 
βόμβες ατόμων στη Χιροσίμα και το Ναγκασάκι για να τελειώσει τον 
παγκόσμιο πόλεμο ΙΙ, η Αμερική κράτησε ένα μονοπώλιο στην 
παραγωγή των ατομικών όπλων. Κατά τη διάρκεια αυτής της 
περιόδου, συζητήστε να στραφεί στη χρήση των πυρηνικών βομβών 
στους μελλοντικούς πολέμους πολλαπλασιάστηκε μεταξύ των 
κυβερνητικών ανώτερων υπαλλήλων, επιστήμονες, θρησκευτικοί 
ηγέτες, και στο δημοφιλή Τύπο. Στο ακόλουθο άρθρο από του 
ανθρακωρύχου, προηγούμενος διοικητής William H. Hessler 
υπολοχαγών ναυτικού, που χρησιμοποιεί τα στοιχεία από τη 
στρατηγική βομβαρδίζοντας έρευνα, υποστήριξε εκείνο τον 
βομβαρδισμό κορεσμού των αστικών περιοχών κατά τη διάρκεια του 
παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ, καταστρεπτικό για τους πολίτες, δεν 
επέτυχε τους πολεμικούς στόχους. Ένας μελλοντικός ατομικός
πόλεμος, επομένως, καλά να καταστρέψει τις πόλεις αλλά 
αποτυγχάνει να σταματήσει την εχθρική επιθετικότητα. 
Επιπλέον, με μια πολύ υψηλότερη αστική συγκέντρωση από τη 
Σοβιετική Ένωση, οι ΗΠΑ είχαν περισσότερους που χάνουν από την 
ατομική εχθροπραξία. Το άρθρο, παρέχοντας τις λεπτομερείς 
εξηγήσεις της καταστρεπτικής ικανότητας της βόμβας, κατέδειξε την
έλλειψη πληροφοριών διαθέσιμη σχετικά με τα μακροπρόθεσμα 
ιατρικά και οικολογικά αποτελέσματα της ραδιενέργειας. Η 
πεζογραφία του Hessler προκάλεσε επίσης και τους δύο η γοητεία
ότι τα εξαρτήματα της ατομικής εχθροπραξίας κράτησαν για 
Αμερικανούς του χρόνου και του φόβου πολλών που έγιναν αισθητών 
για τους κινδύνους που περιλαμβάνονται στην τοποθέτηση αυτής της 
τεχνολογίας στη χρήση. Στις 24 Σεπτεμβρίου ..1949, μια 
εβδομάδα μετά από τη δημοσίευση αυτού του άρθρου, ειδήσεις ότι
οι Ρώσοι είχαν διευθύνει τις δοκιμές βομβών ατόμων συγκλόνισε 
το έθνος. Ο επόμενος Απρίλιος, μια εθνική έκθεση του 
Συμβουλίου Ασφαλείας στον Πρόεδρο Harry S. Truman 
συμβούλεψε την ανάπτυξη μιας βόμβας υδρογόνου -- περίπου 1.000
χρόνοι πιό καταστρεπτικοί από μια βόμβα ατόμων -- και μια 
ογκώδη συγκέντρωση των μη πυρηνικών υπερασπίσεων. Το 
επόμενο ξέσπασμα του πολέμου στην Κορέα τον Ιούνιο του 1950 
δικαιολόγησε σε πολλοί μια ουσιαστική αύξηση στα αμυντικά έξοδα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Por cuatro años después de las bombas atómicas 
caídas ESTADOS UNIDOS en Hiroshima y Nagasaki para terminar la 
Segunda Guerra Mundial, América llevó a cabo un monopolio en la 
producción de armas atómicas. Durante este período, el 
discusión que se centraba en el uso de bombas nucleares en las 
guerras futuras proliferó entre los oficiales del gobierno, 
científicos, arranques de cinta religiosos, y en la prensa popular. 
En el artículo siguiente del collier, comandante de teniente 
anterior de la Marina de guerra Guillermo H. Hessler, usando datos de la 
encuesta sobre estratégica el bombardeo, discutió que el bombardeo 
de la saturación de áreas urbanas durante la Segunda Guerra Mundial,
mientras que devastaba para los civiles, no alcanzó punterías de la 
guerra. Una guerra atómica futura, por lo tanto, pudo manar 
destruye ciudades pero no puede parar la agresión enemiga. 
Además, con una concentración urbana mucho más alta que la 
Soviet-unio'n, los ESTADOS UNIDOS tenían más a perder de la guerra 
atómica. El artículo, mientras que el proporcionar detalló 
las explicaciones de la capacidad destructiva de la bomba, demostró 
la carencia de la información disponible mirando los efectos médicos
y ecológicos a largo plazo de la radiactividad. La prosa de 
Hessler también evocó la fascinación que gadgetry de la guerra 
atómica sostuvo para los americanos del tiempo y el miedo muchos se 
sentía sobre los riesgos implicados en poner esta tecnología al uso.
24 de septiembre de 1949, una semana después de la 
publicación de este artículo, noticias que los rusos habían 
conducido las pruebas de la bomba atómica dieron una sacudida 
eléctrica la nación. El abril siguiente, un informe del 
consejo de la seguridad nacional a presidente Harry S. Truman 
aconsejó el desarrollo de una bomba de hidrógeno -- unas 1.000 veces
más destructiva que una bomba atómica -- y una acumulación masiva 
de defensas no nucleares. El brote subsecuente de guerra en 
Corea en junio 1950 alineó a muchos un aumento substancial en los 
gastos para defensa.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086883</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106262</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-a-bomb-wont-do-what-you-think-an-argument-against-reliance-on-nuclear-weapons</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
