<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108601</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108601</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087410</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"As much land as they can handle": Johann Bolzius Writes to Germany About Slave Labor in Carolina and Georgia, 1750</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"so viel Land, wie sie handhaben können": 
Johann Bolzius schreibt nach Deutschland über Sklavenarbeit in 
Carolina und in Georgia, 1750</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"autant terre qu'elles peuvent manipuler" : 
Johann Bolzius écrit en Allemagne au sujet de travail 
Slave en Caroline et la Géorgie, 1750</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"tanta terra como podem segurar": Johann 
Bolzius escreve a Germany sobre o trabalho slave em Carolina e em 
Geórgia, 1750</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"tanta terra come possono maneggiare": 
Johann Bolzius scrive in Germania circa il Lavoro slave in
Carolina e la Georgia, 1750</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Όσο έδαφος μπορούν να χειριστούν": Θ*Ιοχανν 
Bolzius Writes στη Γερμανία για την εργασία σκλάβων στην 
Καρολίνα και τη Γεωργία, 1750</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"tanta pista como pueden dirigir": Johann 
Bolzius escribe a Alemania sobre trabajo auxiliar en Carolina y 
Georgia, 1750</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Wealthy planters from the Caribbean island of Barbados settled in Carolina in the late seventeenth century and turned Carolina's farms into large plantations that concentrated on growing rice. This transformation was enabled by the many enslaved Africans in the colonies who had grown rice as free men and women in West Africa; scholars have traced the origins of Carolina and Georgia's rice culture back to those African rice fields. In this letter, Johann Martin Bolzius described rice cultivation's highly skilled but backbreaking labor, and the colonies' task system of work. Each slave was assigned a particular duty and, after completing the day's tasks, might have some time to him or herself. Bolzius had left Halle, Germany, in 1733 on route to the new colony of Georgia where he lived upriver from Savannah. He wrote this letter in the form of a questionnaire, providing a vivid description of agriculture and life in the new colony.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wohlhabende Pflanzer von der karibischen Insel von
Barbados vereinbarten in Carolina im späten seventeenth Jahrhundert 
und machten Bauernhöfe Carolinas zu große Plantagen, die auf 
wachsenden Reis sich konzentrierten. Diese Transformation wurde 
von den vielen versklavten Afrikanern in den Kolonien aktiviert, die 
Reis als freie Männer und Frauen in Westafrika angebaut hatten; 
Gelehrte haben die Ursprung von Carolina nachvollzogen und 
Reiskultur Georgia zurück zu jenen afrikanischer Reis fängt
auf. In diesem Zeichen beschrieb Johann Martin Bolzius der 
erfahrene aber backbreaking Reisbearbeitung in hohem Grade Arbeit und 
das Aufgabesystem der Kolonien der Arbeit. Jeder Sklave wurde 
eine bestimmte Aufgabe zugewiesen und, nachdem man die Aufgaben des 
Tages durchgeführt hatte, einige Zeit zu haben konnte. Bolzius 
hatte linkes Halle, Deutschland, 1733 auf Weg zur neuen Kolonie von 
Georgia, in der er upriver von der Savanne lebte. Er schrieb 
diesen Brief in Form eines Fragebogens und stellte eine klare 
Beschreibung der Landwirtschaft und des Lebens in die neue Kolonie 
bereit.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les planteurs riches de l'île des Caraïbes des 
Barbades se sont établis en Caroline vers la fin du dix-septième 
siècle et ont transformé les fermes de la Caroline en grandes 
plantations qui se sont concentrées sur le riz croissant. Cette
transformation a été permise par les nombreux Africains asservis 
dans les colonies qui avaient cultivé le riz en tant que les hommes 
et femmes libres en Afrique occidentale ; les disciples ont 
tracé les origines culture de la Caroline et de la Géorgie de riz de
nouveau à ces gisements africains de riz. Dans cette lettre, 
Johann Martin Bolzius a décrit la culture de riz travail fortement 
habile mais épuisant, et les colonies chargent le système du 
travail. Chacun slave a été assigné un devoir 
particulier et, après avoir fini le jour charge, pourrait 
avoir une certaine heure à se. Bolzius a eu Halle gauche, 
Allemagne, en 1733 sur l'itinéraire à la nouvelle colonie de la 
Géorgie où il a vécu upriver de la savane. Il a écrit cette 
lettre sous forme de questionnaire, fournissant une description vive 
d'agriculture et de vie dans la nouvelle colonie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os plantadores ricos do console do Cararibe de 
Barbados estabeleciram-se em Carolina no décimo séptimo século 
atrasado e giraram-se fazendas de Carolina nas plantações grandes 
que concentraram no arroz crescente. Esta transformação foi 
permitida por muitos africanos enslaved nas colônias que tinham 
crescido o arroz como homens e mulheres livres em África ocidental; 
os scholars seguiram as origens parte traseira da cultura do 
arroz de Carolina e de Geórgia 2 aqueles campos africanos do arroz. 
Nesta letra, Johann Martin Bolzius descreveu cultivation do 
arroz trabalho altamente hábil mas backbreaking, e o sistema da 
tarefa das colônias do trabalho. Cada escravo foi atribuído um
dever particular e, após ter terminado as tarefas do dia, pôde ter 
alguma hora a ele ou a ela mesma. Bolzius teve Halle esquerdo, 
Germany, em 1733 na rota à colônia nova de Geórgia onde viveu 
upriver do savannah. Escreveu esta letra no formulário de um 
questionário, fornecendo uma descrição vívida da agricultura e a 
vida na colônia nova.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le piantatrici ricche dall'isola caraibica delle 
Barbados si sono depositate in Carolina verso la fine del 
diciassettesimo secolo ed hanno trasformato nei poderi della Carolina 
le grandi piantagioni che si sono concentrate su riso crescente. 
Questa trasformazione è stata permessa dai molti Africani 
asserviti nelle colonie che avevano coltivato il riso come gli uomini 
e donne liberi in Africa ad ovest; gli eruditi hanno seguito le 
origini coltura del riso della Georgia e della Carolina di nuovo a 
quei giacimenti africani del riso. In questa lettera, Johann 
Martin Bolzius ha descritto la coltura del riso lavoro altamente
esperto ma backbreaking ed il sistema di operazione delle colonie di 
lavoro. Ad ogni schiavo è stato assegnato un dovere particolare
e, dopo avere completato le mansioni del giorno, ha potuto avere certo
tempo a sè. Bolzius ha avuto Halle di sinistra, Germania, in 
1733 sull'itinerario alla nuova colonia della Georgia in cui ha 
vissuto upriver dalla savanna. Ha scritto questa lettera sotto 
forma d'un questionario, fornente una descrizione chiara 
dell'agricoltura e della vita nella nuova colonia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι πλούσιοι καλλιεργητές από το καραϊβικό νησί των 
Μπαρμπάντος εγκατέστησαν στην Καρολίνα προς το τέλος του δέκατου 
έβδομου αιώνα και μετέτρεψαν τα αγροκτήματα της Καρολίνας σε 
μεγάλες φυτείες που επικεντρώθηκαν στην ανάπτυξη του ρυζιού. 
Αυτός ο μετασχηματισμός επιτράπηκε από τους πολλούς 
υποδουλωμένους Αφρικανούς στις αποικίες που είχαν αυξηθεί το 
ρύζι ως ελεύθερους άνδρες και γυναίκες στη δυτική Αφρική  
οι μελετητές έχουν επισημάνει την προέλευση του πολιτισμού 
ρυζιού της Καρολίνας και της Γεωργίας πίσω σε εκείνα τα 
αφρικανικά πεδία ρυζιού. Σε αυτήν την επιστολή, ο Johann
Martin Bolzius περιέγραψε το πολύ καλά καταρτισμένο αλλά 
κοπιαστικό εργατικό δυναμικό της καλλιέργειας ρυζιού, και το 
στοιχειώδες σύστημα των αποικιών της εργασίας. Σε κάθε 
σκλάβο ανατέθηκε ένα ιδιαίτερο καθήκον και, μετά από να 
ολοκληρώσει τις υποχρεώσεις της ημέρας, να έχει κάποιο χρόνο σε 
τον ή ο ίδιος. Το Bolzius είχε αποχωρήσει από το 
halle, Γερμανία, το 1733 στη διαδρομή στη νέα αποικία της 
Γεωργίας όπου έζησε upriver από τη σαβάνα. Έγραψε 
αυτήν την επιστολή υπό μορφή ερωτηματολογίου, που παρέχει μια 
ζωηρή περιγραφή της γεωργίας και της ζωής στη νέα αποικία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los plantadores ricos de la isla del Caribe de 
Barbados colocaron en Carolina en el último decimoséptimo siglo y 
dieron vuelta a las granjas de Carolina en las plantaciones grandes 
que se concentraron en el arroz creciente. Esta transformación 
fue permitida por los muchos africanos esclavizados en las colonias 
que habían producido el arroz como hombres y mujeres libres en 
África del oeste; los eruditos han rastreado los orígenes 
cultura del arroz de Carolina y de Georgia de nuevo a esos campos 
africanos del arroz. En esta carta, Johann Martin Bolzius 
describió la cultivación del arroz trabajo altamente experto pero 
backbreaking, y el sistema de la tarea de las colonias del trabajo. 
Asignaron un deber determinado y, después de terminar las 
tareas del día, pudo tener cada esclavo cierta hora a él o a ella 
misma. Bolzius tenía Halle izquierda, Alemania, en 1733 en la 
ruta a la nueva colonia de Georgia en donde él vivió upriver de la 
sabana. Él escribió esta letra en la forma de un cuestionario,
proporcionando a una descripción viva de la agricultura y a vida en 
la nueva colonia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087410</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108601</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/as-much-land-as-they-can-handle-johann-bolzius-writes-to-germany-about-slave-labor-in-carolina-and-georgia-1750</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
