<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104931</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104931</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087058</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The street of the gamblers (by day)."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die Straße der Spieler (bis zum Tag)."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"la rue des joueurs (par jour)."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"a rua dos gamblers (pelo dia)."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la via dei gamblers (di giorno)."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η οδός των παικτών (μέχρι την ημέρα)."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"la calle de los jugadores (por día)."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">By 1890, 200,000 Chinese immigrants, mostly men, lived in the United States, usually working under harsh and dangerous conditions. Chinese immigrants faced hostility that sometimes spilled over into violence. In 1882 Congress, responding to the demands of white workers, passed the Chinese Exclusion Act, which severely restricted immigration by Chinese into the U.S. San Francisco's Chinese community was the largest in the nation in 1890, with 25,833 people. Arnold Genthe's turn-of-the-century photographs of San Francisco's Chinatown provide information about the Chinese community, but his characterizations often convey a distorted and ominous message. Despite its title, this photograph of Ross Alley, taken some time around the Chinese New Year holiday, is significant for depicting the unusual daytime congestion resulting from the seasonal unemployment of many Chinatown workers after the holiday.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bis zum 1890 wohnten 200.000 chinesische Immigranten, 
meistens Männer, in den Vereinigten Staaten und normalerweise 
arbeiteten unter den rauhen und gefährlichen Bedingungen. 
Chinesische Immigranten stellten Feindseligkeit gegenüber, die 
manchmal rüber in Gewalttätigkeit verschüttet wurde. den 
Kongreß 1882 reagierend auf die Nachfragen der weißen Arbeiter, 
geführt die chinesische Ausschluss-Tat, die streng eingeschränkte 
Immigration durch Chinese in des VEREINIGTE STAATEN San Franciscos 
chinesische die Gemeinschaft in der Nation 1890 das größte war, mit 
25.833 Leuten. Arnold Genthes Jahrhundertwendefotographien von 
Chinatown San Franciscos liefern Informationen über die chinesische 
Gemeinschaft, aber seine Kennzeichnungen übermitteln häufig eine 
verzerrte und ominöse Meldung. Trotz seines Namens ist diese 
Fotographie der Ross Gasse, einige Zeit um den chinesischen Feiertag 
des neuen Jahres gedauert, für das Bildlich darstellen der 
ungewöhnlichen Tagesansammlung bedeutend, resultierend aus der 
Saisonarbeitslosigkeit vieler Chinatown Arbeiter nach dem Feiertag.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">À côté de 1890, 200.000 immigrés chinois, la plupart 
du temps hommes, ont habité aux Etats-Unis, habituellement 
travaillant dans des conditions dures et dangereuses. Les 
immigrés chinois ont fait face à l'hostilité qui parfois s'est 
renversée plus de dans la violence. En le congrès 1882, 
répondant aux demandes des ouvriers blancs, passées l'acte chinois 
d'exclusion, qui l'immigration sévèrement restreinte par Chinese 
dans la communauté chinoise des ETATS-UNIS San Francisco était la 
plus grande dans la nation en 1890, avec 25.833 personnes. Les 
photographies de tourner-de-le-siècle d'Arnold Genthe de Chinatown de
San Francisco fournissent des informations au sujet de la 
communauté chinoise, mais ses caractérisations donnent souvent un 
message tordu et sinistre. En dépit de son titre, cette 
photographie de ruelle de Ross, prise un certain temps autour des 
vacances chinoises de nouvelle année, est significative pour 
dépeindre l'encombrement peu commun de journée résultant du 
chômage saisonnier de beaucoup d'ouvriers de Chinatown après les 
vacances.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Por 1890, 200.000 immigrants chineses, na maior parte 
homens, viveram nos estados unidos, geralmente trabalhando sob 
circunstâncias ásperas e perigosas. Os immigrants chineses 
enfrentaram a hostilidade que derramou às vezes sobre na violência. 
No congress 1882, respondendo às demandas dos trabalhadores 
brancos, passadas o ato chinês da exclusão, que o immigration 
severamente restrito por Chinês na comunidade chinesa de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS San o Francisco era o maior na nação em 1890, com 25.833 
povos. As fotografias de gir-$$$-$$$-SÉCULO de Arnold Genthe de
Chinatown do San Francisco fornecem a informação sobre a comunidade 
chinesa, mas suas caracterizações fazem saber frequentemente a uma 
mensagem distorcida e ominous. Apesar de seu título, esta 
fotografia da aléia de Ross, feita exame alguma hora em torno do 
feriado chinês do ano novo, é significativa para descrever o 
congestion incomun do dia resultando do desemprego seasonal de muitos 
trabalhadores de Chinatown após o feriado.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Entro 1890, 200.000 immigranti cinesi, principalmente
uomini, hanno vissuto in unito Dichiara, solitamente 
funzionando nelle circostanze dure e pericolose. Gli immigranti 
cinesi hanno affrontato l'ostilità che a volte si è rovesciata 
sopra nella violenza. Nel congresso 1882, rispondente alle 
richieste degli operai bianchi, passate alla Legge cinese di 
esclusione, che l'immigrazione severamente limitata dal cinese 
nella Comunità cinese degli STATI UNITI San Francisco era il 
più grande nella nazione in 1890, con 25.833 genti. Le 
fotografie di gir-de-$$$-SECOLO di Arnold Genthe di Chinatown de San 
Francisco forniscono le informazioni sulla Comunità cinese, ma 
le sue descrizioni trasportano spesso un messaggio storto ed ominous. 
Malgrado il relativo titolo, questa fotografia del vicolo di 
Ross, occors un certo tempo intorno alla festa cinese di nuovo 
anno, è significativa per la descrizione della congestione insolita 
di giorno derivando dalla disoccupazione stagionale di molti operai di
Chinatown dopo la festa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Από 1890, 200.000 κινεζικοί μετανάστες, συνήθως 
άτομα, ζω στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες, συνήθως εργαζόμενος υπό τους 
σκληρούς και επικίνδυνους όρους. Οι κινεζικοί μετανάστες 
αντιμετώπισαν την εχθρότητα που ανέτρεψε μερικές φορές στη βία. 
Στο συνέδριο του 1882, που ανταποκρίνεται στα αιτήματα των
λευκών εργαζομένων, πέρασε τον κινεζικό νόμο αποκλεισμού, που η 
σοβαρά περιορισμένη μετανάστευση από τα κινέζικα στην ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ
Σαν Φρανσίσκο κινεζική κοινότητα ήταν η μεγαλύτερη στο έθνος το 
1890, με 25.833 ανθρώπους. Οι φωτογραφίες 
στροφή-$$$-Ο-ΑΙΏΝΑ Genthe Arnold Chinatown του Σαν 
Φρανσίσκο παρέχουν τις πληροφορίες για την κινεζική κοινότητα, 
αλλά οι χαρακτηρισμοί του μεταβιβάζουν συχνά ένα διαστρεβλωμένο 
και δυσοίωνο μήνυμα. Παρά τον τίτλο της, αυτή η φωτογραφία
του Ross Alley, που λαμβάνεται κάποιος χρόνος γύρω από τις 
κινεζικές νέες διακοπές έτους, είναι σημαντική για την 
απεικόνιση της ασυνήθιστης πρωινής συμφόρησης ως αποτέλεσμα της 
εποχιακής ανεργίας πολλών εργαζομένων Chinatown μετά από τις 
διακοπές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Antes de 1890, 200.000 inmigrantes chinos, sobre todo 
hombres, vivieron en los Estados Unidos, generalmente trabajando bajo 
condiciones ásperas y peligrosas. Los inmigrantes chinos 
hicieron frente a la hostilidad que se derramó a veces encima en 
violencia. En el congreso 1882, respondiendo a las demandas de 
los trabajadores blancos, pasadas el acto chino de la exclusión, que 
la inmigración seriamente restricta de chinese en la comunidad china 
de ESTADOS UNIDOS el San Francisco era la más grande de la nación en
1890, con 25.833 personas. Las fotografías del dar 
vuelta-de-$$$-SIGLO de Arnold Genthe de Chinatown de San Francisco 
proporcionan a la información sobre la comunidad china, pero sus 
caracterizaciones transportan a menudo un mensaje torcido y siniestro.
A pesar de su título, esta fotografía del callejón de Ross, 
tomada una cierta hora alrededor del día de fiesta chino del Año 
Nuevo, es significativa para representar la congestión inusual del 
día resultando del desempleo estacional de muchos trabajadores de 
Chinatown después del día de fiesta.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087058</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104931</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-street-of-the-gamblers-by-day</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
