<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107845</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107845</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087262</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Your People Live Only Upon Cod": An Algonquian Response to European Claims of Cultural Superiority</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Ihre Leute Leben Nur Nach Kabeljau": Eine 
Algonquian Antwort zu den europäischen Ansprüchen der kulturellen 
Überlegenheit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Vos Personnes Vivent Seulement Sur La Morue" : 
Une réponse d'Algonquian aux réclamations européennes de la 
supériorité culturelle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Seus Povos Vivem Somente Em cima Do Bacalhau": 
Uma resposta de Algonquian às reivindicações européias do 
superiority cultural</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"La Vostra Gente Vive Soltanto Su Merluzzo": 
Una risposta di Algonquian ai reclami europei di superiorità 
culturale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Οι άνθρωποί σας ζουν μόνο επάνω στο βακαλάο": 
Μια απάντηση Algonquian στις ευρωπαϊκές αξιώσεις της 
πολιτιστικής ανωτερότητας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Su Gente Vive Solamente Sobre Bacalao": Una
respuesta de Algonquian a las demandas europeas de la superioridad 
cultural</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">From the start of colonization, Indians and Europeans viewed each other across a wide cultural gulf. Sure about the superiority of their civilization, European missionaries and teachers tried to convert Indians to Christianity and the European way of life. Some Indians did adopt new ways after disease and violence had decimated their communities; others rejected the European entreaties and pointed out the arrogance of these claims of cultural superiority. French priest Chrestian LeClerq traveled among the eastern Algonquian people who lived in what are now the Maritime Provinces of Canada. He recorded a Micmac leader's eloquent response to these attempts at "reform" that pointed out how difficult Europeans found it to live in Indian country. If France was such a terrestrial paradise, he asked, why were colonists making their way across the Atlantic to live in the forests of North America?</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Von Anfang an der Besiedlung, sahen sich Inder und
Europäer über einem breiten kulturellen Golf an. Sicher über 
die Überlegenheit ihrer Zivilisation, europäischen Missionare und 
Lehrer versuchte, Inder in Christentum und die europäische Lebensart 
umzuwandeln. Einige Inder nahmen neue Methoden an, nachdem 
Krankheit und Gewalttätigkeit ihre Gemeinschaften dezimiert hatten; 
andere wiesen die europäischen Begehren zurück und 
unterstrichen die Arroganz dieser Ansprüche der kulturellen 
Überlegenheit. Französischer Priester Chrestian LeClerq reiste
unter den östlichen Algonquian Leuten, die lebten in, was jetzt die 
Seeprovinzen von Kanada sind. Er speicherte die redegewandte 
Antwort eines Micmacführers zu diesen Versuchen "an der 
Verbesserung", die unterstrich, wie schwierige Europäer sie fanden, 
um im indischen Land zu leben. Wenn Frankreich solch ein 
terrestrisches Paradies war, er, warum baten Kolonisten bildeten ihre 
Methode über dem Atlantik, in den Wäldern von Nordamerika zu leben?</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dès le début de colonisation, les Indiens et les
Européens se sont visualisés à travers un golfe culturel large. 
Sûr au sujet de la supériorité de leur civilisation, 
missionnaires européens et professeurs a essayé de convertir des 
Indiens en christianisme et façon de vivre européenne. 
Quelques Indiens ont adopté de nouvelles voies après que la 
maladie et la violence aient décimé leurs communautés ; 
d'autres ont rejeté les supplications européennes et ont 
précisé l'arrogance de ces réclamations de la supériorité 
culturelle. Le prêtre français Chrestian LeClerq a voyagé 
parmi les personnes orientales d'Algonquian qui ont vécu dans ce qui 
sont maintenant les provinces maritimes du Canada. Il a 
enregistré la réponse éloquente d'une amorce de micmac à ces 
tentatives de "réforme" qui a précisé comment Européens difficiles
l'ont trouvée pour vivre dans le pays indien. Si la France 
était un paradis si terrestre, il, pourquoi les colons ont-ils 
demandé faisaient-ils leur voie à travers l'Océan atlantique de 
vivre dans les forêts de l'Amérique du nord ?</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Do começo da colonização, os indians e Europeus
viram-se através de um golfo cultural largo. Certo sobre o 
superiority de seus civilização, missionários europeus e 
professores tentou converter indians ao christianity e à maneira de 
vida européia. Alguns indians adotaram maneiras novas depois 
que a doença e a violência tinham dizimado suas comunidades; 
outros rejeitaram os entreaties europeus e indicaram o arrogance
destas reivindicações do superiority cultural. O priest 
francês Chrestian LeClerq viajou entre os povos orientais de 
Algonquian que viveram em o que são agora as províncias marítimas 
de Canadá. Gravou a resposta eloquent de um líder do micmac a 
estas tentativas na "reforma" que indicou como Europeus difíceis a 
encontraram para viver no país indian. Se France fosse um 
paradise tão terrestrial, ele pediram, por que os colonos faziam sua 
maneira através do Atlântico viver nas florestas de America do 
Norte?</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dall'inizio di colonizzazione, gli indiani ed 
Europei si sono osservati attraverso un golfo culturale largo. 
Sicuro circa la superiorità della loro civilizzazione, 
missionari europei ed insegnanti ha provato a convertire gli indiani
in christianity ed in modo di vivere europeo. Alcuni indiani 
hanno adottato i nuovi modi dopo che la malattia e la violenza 
avessero decimato le loro Comunità; altri hanno rifiutato i 
entreaties europei ed hanno precisato il arrogance di questi reclami 
di superiorità culturale. Il priest francese Chrestian LeClerq 
ha viaggiato fra la gente orientale di Algonquian che ha vissuto in 
che cosa ora sono le province marittime del Canada. Ha 
registrato una risposta eloquente del capo del micmac a questi
tentativi di "riforma" che ha precisato come Europei difficili la 
hanno trovata per vivere in paese indiano. Se la Francia fosse 
così paradise terrestre, lui hanno chiesto, perchè i colonizzatori 
stavano facendo il loro modo attraverso l'Atlantico vivere nelle 
foreste dell'America del Nord?</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Από την έναρξη της αποίκισης, Ινδοί και οι Ευρωπαίοι 
εμφάνισαν ο ένας τον άλλον πέρα από έναν ευρύ πολιτιστικό 
κόλπο. Βέβαιος για την ανωτερότητα του πολιτισμού, των 
ευρωπαϊκών ιεραποστόλων και των δασκάλων τους προσπάθησε να 
μετατρέψει Ινδούς στο χριστιανισμό και τον ευρωπαϊκό τρόπο της 
ζωής. Μερικοί Ινδοί υιοθέτησαν τους νέους τρόπους μετά 
από την ασθένεια και η βία είχε αποδεκατίσει τις κοινότητές 
τους  άλλοι απέρριψαν ευρωπαϊκά entreaties και 
επισήμαναν την υπεροψία αυτών των αξιώσεων της πολιτιστικής 
ανωτερότητας. Ο γαλλικός ιερέας Chrestian LeClerq 
ταξίδεψε μεταξύ των ανατολικών ανθρώπων Algonquian που έζησαν 
σε αυτά που είναι τώρα οι θαλάσσιες επαρχίες του Καναδά. 
Κατέγραψε την εύγλωττη απάντηση ενός ηγέτη Micmac σε 
αυτές τις προσπάθειες "στη μεταρρύθμιση" που επισήμανε πώς οι 
δύσκολοι Ευρωπαίοι την βρήκαν για να ζήσουν στην ινδική χώρα. 
Εάν η Γαλλία ήταν ένας τέτοιος επίγειος παράδεισος, 
αυτός ρώτησαν, γιατί οι άποικοι έκαναν τον τρόπο τους πέρα από
τον Ατλαντικό να ζήσουν στα δάση της Βόρειας Αμερικής;</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Del comienzo de la colonización, los indios y 
europeos se vieron a través de un golfo cultural ancho. Seguro 
sobre la superioridad de su civilización, misionarios europeos y 
profesores intentó convertir a indios al cristianismo y a la manera 
de la vida europea. Algunos indios adoptaron nuevas maneras 
después de que la enfermedad y la violencia hubieran diezmado a sus 
comunidades; otros rechazaron los entreaties europeos y 
precisaron la arrogancia de estas demandas de la superioridad 
cultural. El sacerdote francés Chrestian LeClerq viajó entre 
la gente del este de Algonquian que vivió en cuáles ahora son las 
provincias marítimos de Canadá. Él registró la respuesta 
elocuente de un arranque de cinta del micmac a estas tentativas en la 
"reforma" que precisó cómo europeos difíciles la encontraron para 
vivir en país indio. ¿Si Francia era un paraíso tan terrestre,
él pidieron, por qué los colonos hacían su manera a través del 
Atlántico de vivir en los bosques de Norteamérica?</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087262</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107845</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/your-people-live-only-upon-cod-an-algonquian-response-to-european-claims-of-cultural-superiority</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
