<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108376</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108376</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086797</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Sadie's Servant Room Blues": 1920s Domestic Work in Song</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Bedienstet-Raum-Blau Sadies": zwanziger 
Jahre inländische Arbeit im Lied</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Bleus de Pièce de l'Domestique de Sadie" : 
travail domestique des années 20 dans la chanson</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">De "Azuis Do Quarto Do Empregado Sadie": 
trabalho doméstico dos 1920s na canção</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Azzurri Della Stanza Del Servo Del Sadie": 
lavoro domestico degli anni 20 nella canzone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Μπλε δωματίων υπαλλήλων Sadie": εσωτερική 
εργασία της δεκαετίας του '20 στο τραγούδι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Azul Del Sitio Del Criado De Sadie": 
trabajo doméstico de los años 20 en la canción</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Domestic service was the most common category of employment for women before World War II; it was particularly important for black women, who were excluded from most other occupations. By 1920 some 40 percent of all domestic workers were African American--and more than 70 percent of all wage-earning African-American women worked as servants or laundresses. The struggles of domestic workers were sometimes recorded in songs like Hattie Burleson's 1928 "Sadie's Servant Room Blues," a musical version of common complaints of domestic workers about long hours, low pay, and lack of privacy.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Inländischer Service war die geläufigste 
Kategorie der Beschäftigung für Frauen vor dem Zweiten Weltkrieg; 
es war für schwarze Frauen besonders wichtig, die von den 
meisten anderen Besetzungen ausgeschlossen wurden. Durch 1920 
irgendwelche 40 Prozent alles Hausangestellts waren Arbeiter 
afrikanischer Amerikaner -- und mehr als 70 Prozent aller 
Lohn-erwerbenden Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Frauen arbeiteten als 
Bedienstete oder laundresses. Die Kämpfe der inländischen 
Arbeiter wurden manchmal in den Lieden wie Hattie Burlesons 1928 
"Bedienstet-Raum-Blau Sadies," eine musikalische Version der 
geläufigen Beanstandungen der inländischen Arbeiter über lange 
Stunden, niedrige Bezahlung und Mangel an Privatleben gespeichert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le service domestique était la catégorie la plus
commune de l'emploi pour des femmes avant la deuxième guerre mondiale
; il était particulièrement important pour les femmes noires, 
qui ont été exclues de la plupart des autres métiers. Par 
1920 environ 40 pour cent de tout le domestique les ouvriers étaient 
Américain africain -- et plus de 70 pour cent de toutes les femmes 
afro-américaines salaire-gagnantes ont travaillé comme domestiques ou 
blanchisseuses. Les luttes des ouvriers domestiques ont été 
parfois enregistrées dans les chansons comme 1928 de Hattie Burleson 
"les bleus de pièce de l'domestique de Sadie," une version musicale 
des plaintes communes des ouvriers domestiques au sujet de longues 
heures, bas salaire, et manque d'intimité.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O serviço doméstico era a categoria a mais comum
de emprego para mulheres antes da segunda guerra mundial; era 
particularmente importante para as mulheres pretas, que foram 
excluídas de a maioria outras de ocupações. Por 1920 uns 40 
por cento de todo o domestic os trabalhadores eram americano africano 
-- e mais de 70 por cento de todas as mulheres Africano-Americanas 
salário-ganhando trabalharam como empregados ou laundresses. Os
esforços de trabalhadores domésticos foram gravados às vezes nas 
canções como 1928 de Hattie Burleson "azuis do quarto do empregado 
de Sadie," uma versão musical de queixas comuns de trabalhadores 
domésticos sobre horas longas, pagamento baixo, e falta da 
privacidade.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il servizio domestico era la categoria più comune
di occupazione per le donne prima della seconda guerra mondiale; 
era particolarmente importante per le donne nere, che sono state
escluse dalla maggior parte delle altre occupazioni. Da 1920 
circa 40 per cento di tutto il domestic operai erano americano 
africano -- e più di 70 per cento di tutte le donne 
Africano-Americane stipendio-guadagnanti hanno lavorato come i servi o
laundresses. Le lotte degli operai domestici a volte sono state 
registrate nelle canzoni come 1928 di Hattie Burleson "azzurri della 
stanza del servo del Sadie," una versione musicale dei reclami comuni 
degli operai domestici circa le ore lunghe, paga bassa e mancanza di 
segretezza.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η εσωτερική υπηρεσία ήταν η πιό κοινή κατηγορία 
απασχόλησης για τις γυναίκες πριν από τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο ΙΙ  
ήταν ιδιαίτερα σημαντικό για τις μαύρες γυναίκες, οι 
οποίες αποκλείστηκαν από τα περισσότερα άλλα επαγγέλματα. 
Μέχρι το 1920 περίπου 40 τοις εκατό όλων των 
εσωτερικών εργαζομένων ήταν αφρικανικός Αμερικανός -- και 
περισσότερα από 70 τοις εκατό όλων των μισθωτών 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικών γυναικών ελειτούργησαν ως υπάλληλοι ή 
πλύντριες. Οι προσπάθειες των εσωτερικών εργαζομένων 
καταγράφηκαν μερικές φορές στα τραγούδια όπως το 1928 "μπλε 
Hattie Burleson δωματίων υπαλλήλων Sadie," μια μουσική 
έκδοση των κοινών καταγγελιών των εσωτερικών εργαζομένων για τις 
πολλές ώρες, χαμηλή αμοιβή, και έλλειψη μυστικότητας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El servicio doméstico era la categoría más 
común del empleo para las mujeres antes de la Segunda Guerra Mundial;
era determinado importante para las mujeres negras, que fueron 
excluidas de la mayoría de las otras ocupaciones. Por un 1920 
ciertos 40 por ciento de todo el domestic los trabajadores eran 
americano africano -- y más de 70 por ciento de todas las mujeres 
Africano-Americanas de salario-ganancia trabajaron como criados o 
laundresses. Las luchas de trabajadores domésticos fueron 
registradas a veces en canciones como 1928 de Hattie Burleson "los 
azul del sitio del criado de Sadie," una versión musical de quejas 
comunes de trabajadores domésticos sobre largases horas, paga baja, y
carencia de la aislamiento.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086797</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108376</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/sadies-servant-room-blues-1920s-domestic-work-in-song</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
