<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103500</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103500</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086066</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Dedicated to the men of the South who suffered exile, imprisonment and death for the daring service they rendered our country as citizens of the Invisible Empire."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"eingesetzt den Männern des Südens, der Exil, 
Gefangenschaft und Tod für den verwegenen Service erlitt, übertrugen
sie unser Land als Bürger des unsichtbaren Reiches."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"consacré aux hommes des Sud qui ont 
souffert l'exil, l'emprisonnement et la mort pour le service audacieux
ils ont rendu notre pays comme citoyens de l'empire invisible."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"dedicado aos homens do sul que sofreu o exile, o 
aprisionamento e a morte para o serviço audaz renderam nosso país 
como cidadãos do império invisível."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"dedicato agli uomini del sud che ha sofferto il 
exile, l'imprigionamento e la morte per il servizio daring hanno reso 
il nostro paese come cittadini dell'impero invisibile."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Αφιερωμένος στα άτομα του νότου που υπέστησαν τον 
εξόριστο, τη φυλάκιση και το θάνατο για την τολμώντας υπηρεσία 
έδωσαν τη χώρα μας ως πολίτες της αόρατης αυτοκρατορίας."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"dedicado a los hombres del sur que sufrió 
exilio, el encarcelamiento y la muerte para el servicio atrevido 
rindieron nuestro país como ciudadanos del imperio invisible."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Started by Confederate veterans in 1866 and led by prominent planters, the Ku Klux Klan grew quickly during Radical Reconstruction. Hooded Klansmen terrorized individuals and freedpeoples organizations, breaking up meetings, shooting and lynching Union League leaders, and driving people away from the polls across the South. In its nighttime whippings, killings, and rapes, the Klan targeted freedpeople who showed signs of independence, such as those who bought or rented their own land, or community leaders, such as teachers. The criminal, terrorist nature of the organization was later glossed over. By the turn of the century, popular novels like Thomas Dixon, Jr.'s  The Traitor , published in 1907, transformed the bloody record of the Ku Klux Klan (here softened by the euphemism Invisible Empire") into tales of gallantry</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Begonnen durch Confederate Veterane 1866 und durch 
vorstehende Pflanzer geführt, wuchs das Ku Klux Klan schnell während
der radikalen Rekonstruktion. Mit Kapuze Klansmen terrorized 
Einzelpersonen und freedpeoples Organisationen und brachen herauf die 
Sitzungen, Schießen und Lynchenanschluß-Ligaführer, und Leute weg 
von den Abstimmungen über dem Süden antreibend. In seinen 
Nachtzeit whippings Tötungen und Raub, zielte das Klan freedpeople, 
das Zeichen von Unabhängigkeit, wie die zeigte, die ihr eigenes Land 
kauften oder mieteten, oder Gemeinschaftsführer, wie Lehrer. 
Der Verbrecher, Terroristnatur der Organisation wurde später 
rüber poliert. Durch die Jahrhundertwende, mögen populäre 
Romane Thomas Dixon, der Traitor jr., veröffentlicht 1907, 
umwandelten den blutigen Satz des Ku Klux Klan (hier erwichen durch 
das Euphemismus unsichtbare Reich") in Geschichten des Edelmuts</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Commencé par des vétérans de Confederate en 1866 et 
mené par les planteurs en avant, le Ku Klux Klan s'est développé 
rapidement pendant la reconstruction radicale. Individus 
terrorisés par klansmen à capuchon et organismes de 
freedpeoples, se cassant vers le haut des amorces de réunions, de tir
et de lyncher des syndicats de ligue, et pilotant des personnes loin 
par les balayages à travers les Sud. Dans ses 
whippings de nuit, massacres, et viols, le Klan a visé le freedpeople
qui a montré des signes de l'indépendance, de ce type qui ont 
acheté ou ont loué leur propre terre, ou les amorces de la 
communauté, telles que des professeurs. Le criminel, nature de 
terroriste de l'organisation plus tard a été annoté plus de. 
Au tournant du siècle, les romans populaires aiment Thomas 
Dixon, le traître du Jr., édité en 1907, ont transformé 
l'enregistrement sanglant du Ku Klux Klan (ici ramolli par l'empire 
invisible d'euphémisme") en contes de galantery</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Começado por veterans de Confederado em 1866 e conduzido 
por plantadores proeminentes, o Ku Klux Klan cresceu rapidamente 
durante o reconstruction radical. Os klansmen hooded terrorized 
indivíduos e organizações dos freedpeoples, quebrando acima dos 
líderes das reuniões, disparar e lynching da união da liga, e 
dirigindo povos afastado das votações através do sul. Em seus
whippings do nighttime, matanças, e violações, o Klan alvejou o 
freedpeople que mostrou sinais da independência, tais como aqueles 
que compraram ou alugaram sua própria terra, ou os líderes da 
comunidade, tais como professores. O criminoso, natureza do 
terrorista da organização foi anotado mais tarde sobre. Pela 
volta do século, as novelas populares gostam de Thomas Dixon, traitor
do Jr., publicado em 1907, transformaram o registro sangrento do Ku 
Klux Klan (amaciado aqui pelo império invisível do euphemism") em 
tales do gallantry</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Cominciato dai veterani del Confederate in 1866 e condotto
dalle piantatrici prominenti, il Ku Klux Klan si è sviluppato 
rapidamente durante la ricostruzione radicale. I klansmen hooded
terrorized gli individui e le organizzazioni dei freedpeoples, 
rompendosi sui capi di fucilazione e lynching di riunioni, del
sindacato della lega e guidando la gente via dallo scrutinio 
attraverso il sud. Nei relativi whippings di notte, uccisioni e 
violenze, il Klan ha designato il freedpeople che ha mostrato i segni 
di indipendenza, come coloro che ha comprato o affittato la loro 
propria terra, o i capi come bersaglio della Comunità, quali 
gli insegnanti. Il criminale, la natura del terrorista 
dell'organizzazione più successivamente è stato lucidato sopra. 
Dalla girata del secolo, i romanzi popolari gradiscono Thomas 
Dixon, il traitor del Jr., pubblicato in 1907, hanno trasformato il 
record sanguinante del Ku Klux Klan (qui ammorbidito dall'impero 
invisibile di eufemismo") nei racconti di gallantry</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αρχισμένο από τους ομόσπονδους παλαιμάχους το 1866 
και οδηγημένο από τους προεξέχοντες καλλιεργητές, το Ku Klux
Klan αυξήθηκε γρήγορα κατά τη διάρκεια της ριζικής 
αναδημιουργίας. Με κουκούλα Klansmen ετρομοκράτησε τα 
άτομα και freedpeoples τις οργανώσεις, που χωρίζουν τις 
συνεδριάσεις, πυροβολισμός και που λυντσάρουν τους ηγέτες ένωσης 
ένωσης, και που οδηγούν τους ανθρώπους μακρυά από τις ψηφοφορίες
πέρα από το νότο. Στο νυχτερινούς κτύπημα, τις δολοφονίες,
και τους βιασμούς του, το Klan στόχευσε freedpeople που 
εμφάνισε σημάδια της ανεξαρτησίας, όπως εκείνοι που αγόρασαν ή 
νοικίασαν το έδαφός τους, ή τους κοινοτικούς ηγέτες, όπως οι 
δάσκαλοι. Ο εγκληματίας, τρομοκρατική φύση της οργάνωσης 
σχολιάστηκε αργότερα. Από τη στροφή του αιώνα, τα δημοφιλή
μυθιστορήματα όπως τον Thomas Dixon, ο νεώτερος προδότης, 
δημοσίευσαν το 1907, μετασχημάτισαν το αιματηρό αρχείο του 
Ku Klux Klan (που μαλακώνεται εδώ από την αόρατη 
αυτοκρατορία ευφημισμού") στις ιστορίες gallantry</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Comenzado por los veteranos de Confederate en 1866 y 
conducido por los plantadores prominentes, el Ku Klux Klan creció 
rápidamente durante la reconstrucción radical. Los klansmen 
encapuchados terrorized individuos y organizaciones de los 
freedpeoples, rompiéndose encima de los arranques de cinta de las 
reuniones, el tirar y el lynching de la unión de la liga, y 
conduciendo a gente lejos de las encuestas a través del sur. En
sus whippings de la noche, matanzas, y las violaciones, el Klan 
apuntó al freedpeople que mostró muestras de la independencia, tales
como los que compraron o alquilaron su propia pista, o a arranques de 
cinta de la comunidad, tales como profesores. Lustraron al 
criminal, naturaleza del terrorista de la organización más adelante 
encima. Por la vuelta del siglo, las novelas populares tienen 
gusto de Thomas Dixon, el traidor del Jr., publicado en 1907, 
transformaron el expediente sangriento del Ku Klux Klan (aquí 
ablandado por el imperio invisible del eufemismo") en cuentos del 
gallantry</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086066</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103500</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/dedicated-to-the-men-of-the-south-who-suffered-exile-imprisonment-and-death-for-the-daring-service-they-rendered-our-country-as-citizens-of-the-invisible-empire</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
