<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106163</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106163</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209921</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Right triangle </string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Rechtes Dreieck</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bonne triangle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Triângulo direito</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giusto triangolo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σωστό τρίγωνο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Triángulo derecho</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate the three types of triangle: acute, obtuse and right. The applet shows a triangle that is initially right (one angle 90 degrees) which the user can reshape by dragging any vertex. There is a message changes in real time while the triangle is being dragged that tells if the triangle is an acute, right or obtuse triangle and gives the reason why. By experimenting with the triangle student can develop an intuitive sense of the difference between these three classes of triangle. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die die drei Typen des Dreiecks zeigen: akut, stumpf 
und recht. Der applet zeigt ein Dreieck, das zuerst recht ist 
(ein Winkel 90 Grad) welches der Benutzer umgestalten kann, indem er 
jeden möglichen Gipfel schleppt. Es gibt eine Meldung 
Änderungen in der Istzeit, während das Dreieck geschleppt wird, das 
erklärt, wenn das Dreieck ein akutes ist, rechtes oder Dreieck und 
gibt den Grund warum stumpfes. Indem er mit Dreieck 
experimentiert, kann der Kursteilnehmer eine intuitive Richtung des 
Unterschiedes zwischen diesen drei Kategorien des Dreiecks entwickeln.
Applet kann zum vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit einem 
Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. Nachgebrauch im 
Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von jedem möglichem web 
browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den benötigten LOGON 
wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Bestandteil des 
Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent les trois types de triangle : aigu, obtus et 
droit. L'applet montre une triangle qui est au commencement 
exacte (un angle 90 degrés) ce que l'utilisateur peut restructurer en
traînant n'importe quel sommet. Il y a des changements d'un 
message de temps réel tandis qu'on traîne la triangle qui triangle 
dit si la triangle est une aiguë, bonne ou obtuse et donne la raison 
pour laquelle. Par l'expérimentation avec la triangle 
l'étudiant peut développer un sens intuitif de la différence entre 
ces trois classes de triangle. L'applet peut être agrandi à la
taille de plein écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de 
classe. Le après utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant
peut lui accéder encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la 
maison ou dans la bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion 
exigée. Cette ressource est un composant du projet interactif 
de manuel de la géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem os três tipos de triângulo: agudo, obtuse e 
direito. O applet mostra um triângulo que seja inicialmente 
direito (um ângulo 90 graus) qual o usuário pode reshape arrastando 
todo o vertex. Há umas mudanças de uma mensagem no tempo real 
quando o triângulo for arrastado que diz se o triângulo for um 
agudo, triângulo direito ou obtuse e dá a razão porque. 
Experimentando com o triângulo o estudante pode desenvolver um 
sentido intuitive da diferença entre estas três classes do 
triângulo. O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de tela cheia 
para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. O depois de uso na 
sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo o web 
browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma sessão 
requerido. Este recurso é um componente do projeto interativo 
do textbook da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano i tre tipi di triangoli: acuto, ottuso e di destra. 
Il applet mostra un triangolo che è inizialmente di destra (un 
angolo 90 gradi) quale l'utente può rimodellare trascinando tutto il 
vertice. Ci sono cambiamenti del messaggio in tempo reale mentre
il triangolo sta trascinando che dice a se il triangolo è un acuto, 
giusto o triangolo ottuso e dà la ragione per la quale. 
Sperimentando con il triangolo l'allievo può sviluppare un 
senso intuitivo della differenza fra questi tre codici categoria del 
triangolo. Il applet può essere ingrandito al formato di 
schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore dell'aula. La 
post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può accederle ancora da tutto 
il web browser nel paese o nella libreria senza l'inizio attività 
richiesto. Questa risorsa è un componente del progetto 
interattivo del manuale della geometria di riferimento aperto di per 
la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν τους τρεις τύπους τριγώνων: οξύς, οξύς και 
σωστός. Το applet εμφανίζει ένα τρίγωνο που είναι 
αρχικά σωστό (μια γωνία 90 βαθμοί) που ο χρήστης μπορεί να 
αναδιαμορφώσει με το σύρσιμο οποιουδήποτε vertex. Υπάρχει
ένα μήνυμα αλλάζει στον πραγματικό χρόνο ενώ το τρίγωνο 
σέρνεται που λέει εάν το τρίγωνο είναι ένα οξύ, σωστό ή οξύ 
τρίγωνο και δίνει το λόγο για τον οποίο. Με τον 
πειραματισμό με το τρίγωνο ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να αναπτύξει μια 
διαισθητική αίσθηση της διαφοράς μεταξύ αυτών των τριών κλάσεων
του τριγώνου. Το Applet μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες 
μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με έναν προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά
από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε
τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη 
βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το
στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού 
προγράμματος εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού 
σε http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran los tres tipos de triángulo: agudo, obtuso y 
derecho. El applet muestra un triángulo que inicialmente 
correcto (un ángulo 90 grados) cuál el utilizador puede restructurar
arrastrando cualquier cima. Hay cambios de un mensaje en tiempo 
real mientras que se está arrastrando el triángulo que dice si el 
triángulo es un agudo, derecho u obtuso triángulo y da la razón por
la que. Experimentando con el triángulo el estudiante puede 
desarrollar un sentido intuitivo de la diferencia entre estas tres 
clases del triángulo. El applet se puede agrandar a la talla de
la pantalla completa para el uso con un proyector de la sala de clase.
El uso posterior en la sala de clase, estudiante puede tenerle 
acceso otra vez de cualquier web browser en el país o en la 
biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. Este recurso es un 
componente del proyecto interactivo del libro de textos de la 
geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas en 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209921</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106163</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/right-triangle</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
